<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104805</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104805</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206805</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Zimmermann Telegram</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Zimmermann Telegramm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Télégramme de Zimmermann</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Telegrama De Zimmermann</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Telegramma Di Zimmermann</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το τηλεγράφημα Zimmermann</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Telegrama De Zimmermann</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is lesson plan aims to help students understand the causes of World War I and why the U.S. intervened. In January of 1917, British cryptographers deciphered a telegram from German Foreign Minister Arthur Zimmermann to the German Minister to Mexico, von Eckhardt, offering U.S. territory to Mexico in return for joining the German cause. This telegram helped draw the United States into the war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Lektionplanziele, zum der Kursteilnehmer 
zu helfen, die Ursachen des Ersten Weltkrieges zu verstehen und warum 
die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN eingriffen. Im Januar von 1917, 
dechiffroren britische Verschlüsseler ein Telegramm vom deutschen 
Außenminister Arthur Zimmermann zum deutschen Minister nach Mexiko, 
von Eckhardt und boten VEREINIGTE STAATEN Gegend nach Mexiko in der 
Rückkehr für das Verbinden der deutschen Ursache an. Dieser 
Telegramm geholfene abgehobene Betrag die Vereinigten Staaten in den 
Krieg.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est les objectifs de plan de leçon pour aider des
étudiants à comprendre les causes de la Première Guerre Mondiale et
pourquoi les ETATS-UNIS sont intervenus. En janvier de 1917, les
cryptographes britanniques ont déchiffré un télégramme de ministre
des affaires étrangères allemand Arthur Zimmermann au ministre 
allemand au Mexique, von Eckhardt, offrant le territoire des 
ETATS-UNIS au Mexique en échange pour joindre la cause allemande. 
Cette aspiration aidée par télégramme les Etats-Unis dans la 
guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">são os alvos da planta da lição para ajudar a 
estudantes compreender as causas do world.war.i e porque os ESTADOS 
UNIDOS intervieram. Em janeiro de 1917, os criptógrafos 
britânicos decifraram um telegrama do ministro extrangeiro alemão 
Arthur Zimmermann ao ministro alemão a México, von Eckhardt, 
oferecendo o território de ESTADOS UNIDOS a México no retorno para 
juntar a causa alemão. Esta tração ajudada telegrama os 
estados unidos na guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è gli obiettivi di programma di lezione per 
aiutare gli allievi a capire le cause del world.war.i e perchè gli 
STATI UNITI hanno intervenuto. In gennaio di 1917, i crittografi
britannici hanno decifrato un telegramma dal Ministro straniero 
Arthur Zimmermann del tedesco al Ministro tedesco nel Messico, von 
Eckhardt, offrente il territorio degli STATI UNITI nel Messico in 
cambio dell'unire la causa tedesca. Questo di tiraggio aiutato 
telegramma unito Dichiara nella guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι στόχοι σχεδίων μαθήματος να ενισχυθούν οι 
σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν τις αιτίες του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι και 
γιατί οι ΗΠΑ επενέβησαν. Τον Ιανουάριο του 1917, 
βρετανικά cryptographers αποκρυπτογράφησαν ένα τηλεγράφημα από
το γερμανικό ξένο Υπουργό αρθούρος Zimmermann στο γερμανικό 
Υπουργό στο Μεξικό, βον Eckhardt, που προσφέρει το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
έδαφος στο Μεξικό σε αντάλλαγμα για την ένωση της γερμανικής 
αιτίας. Αυτό το τηλεγράφημα που ενισχύεται σύρω τις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες στον πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">son las punterías del plan de la lección para 
ayudar a estudiantes a entender las causas de la Primera Guerra 
Mundial y porqué intervinieron los ESTADOS UNIDOS. En enero de 
1917, los criptógrafos británicos descifraron un telegrama del 
Ministro de Asuntos Exteriores alemán Arturo Zimmermann al ministro 
alemán a México, von Eckhardt, ofreciendo el territorio de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS a México en la vuelta para ensamblar la causa alemana. 
Este drenaje ayudado telegrama los Estados Unidos en la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206805</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104805</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-zimmermann-telegram</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
