<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106888</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106888</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973922</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chemistry Games: Conductive Polymers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chemie-Spiele: Leitende Polymer-Plastiken</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Chimie : Polymères Conducteurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Do Chemistry: Polímeros Condutores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Chimica: Polimeri Conduttivi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια χημείας: Αγώγιμα πολυμερή σώματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Química: Polímeros 
Conductores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! We have been taught that plastics, unlike metals, do not conduct electricity. Plastic is used as insulation around the copper wires in ordinary electrical cables. Yet, the 2000 Nobel Laureates in Chemistry: Alan Heeger, Alan G. MacDiarmid and Hideki Shirakawa, were rewarded for their revolutionary discovery that plastic can, after certain modifications, be made electrically conductive.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Wir sind unterrichtet worden, daß Plastik, anders als Metalle, 
nicht Elektrizität leitet. Plastik wird als Isolierung um die 
kupfernen Leitungen in den gewöhnlichen elektrischen Kabeln benutzt. 
Jedoch die Nobel Laureaten 2000 in der Chemie: Alan 
Heeger, Alan G. MacDiarmid und Hideki Shirakawa, wurden für ihre 
revolutionäre Entdeckung belohnt, die Plastik, nach bestimmten 
Änderungen kann, leitend elektrisch gebildet werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! On nous a
enseigné que les plastiques, à la différence des métaux, ne 
conduisent pas l'électricité. Le plastique est utilisé comme 
isolation autour des fils de cuivre en câbles électriques 
ordinaires. Cependant, les lauréats 2000 Nobel en chimie : 
Alan Heeger, Alan G. MacDiarmid et Hideki 
Shirakawa, ont été récompensés de leur découverte 
révolutionnaire que le plastique peut, après certaines 
modifications, être rendu électriquement conductrice.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Nós 
fomos ensinados que os plásticos, ao contrário dos metais, não 
conduzem a eletricidade. O plástico é usado como a isolação 
em torno dos fios de cobre em cabos elétricos ordinários. 
Ainda, os laureates 2000 de Nobel no chemistry: Alan 
Heeger, Alan G. MacDiarmid e Hideki Shirakawa, foram recompensados 
para sua descoberta revolucionária que o plástico pode, após 
determinadas modificações, ser feito eletricamente condutora.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Siamo stati insegnati che la 
plastica, diverso dei metalli, non conduce l'elettricità. La 
plastica è usata come isolamento intorno ai legare di rame in cavi 
elettrici ordinari. Tuttavia, i laureates 2000 Nobel nella 
chimica: Alan Heeger, Alan G. MacDiarmid e Hideki Shirakawa, 
sono stati ricompensati della loro scoperta rivoluzionaria che la 
plastica può, dopo determinate modifiche, essere resa elettricamente 
conduttiva.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! 
Έχουμε διδαχθεί ότι τα πλαστικά, αντίθετα από τα μέταλλα,
δεν διευθύνουν την ηλεκτρική ενέργεια. Το πλαστικό 
χρησιμοποιείται ως μόνωση γύρω από τα καλώδια χαλκού στα 
συνηθισμένα ηλεκτρικά καλώδια. Ακόμα, οι 2000 δαφνοστεφές 
Νόμπελ στη χημεία: Ο Alan Heeger, ο Alan G. 
MacDiarmid και Hideki Shirakawa, ανταμείφθηκαν για την 
επαναστατική ανακάλυψή τους ότι το πλαστικό μπορεί, μετά από 
ορισμένες τροποποιήσεις, να γίνει ηλεκτρικά αγώγιμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Nos han 
enseñado que los plásticos, desemejante de los metales, no conducen 
electricidad. El plástico se utiliza como aislante alrededor de
los alambres de cobre en cables eléctricos ordinarios. 
Todavía, los laureados 2000 Nobel en química: Alan 
Heeger, Alan G. MacDiarmid e Hideki Shirakawa, fueron recompensados 
por su descubrimiento revolucionario que el plástico se puede, 
después de ciertas modificaciones, hacer eléctricamente conductor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973922</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106888</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chemistry-games-conductive-polymers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
