<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105032</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105032</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086140</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploring the Table of Isotopes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschen der Tabelle der Isotope</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorer le Tableau des isotopes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explorando a tabela dos isotopes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplorazione della Tabella degli isotopi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξερεύνηση του πίνακα των ισοτόπων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explorar el vector de isótopos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The following information will help you understand the Periodic Table of the Isotopes. 

Elements: Each element has a fixed number of positively charged protons in its nucleus and an equal number of electrons orbiting the nucleus. For example, hydrogen (H) has one proton and one electron, but lead (Pb) has 82 protons and 82 electrons. There are about 115 known elements of which 82 are naturally abundant. 

Isotopes: The nucleus contains both protons and neutrons. An element has a fixed number of protons but may exist with various numbers of neutrons. The sum of the protons and neutrons is the mass number. For example, helium exists as 3He(2 protons and one neutron) or as 4He (2 protons and 2 neutrons). The two forms of helium are called isotopes of helium. Isotopes of an element have the same chemical properties but different weights. Some elements have many isomers. Tin (Sn) has about 38 known isotopes. ~</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die folgenden Informationen helfen Ihnen, die 
periodische Tabelle der Isotope zu verstehen. Elemente: 
Jedes Element hat eine örtlich festgelegte Anzahl von positiv 
belasteten Protonen in seinem Kern und eine gleiche Anzahl von den 
Elektronen, die den Kern in Umlauf bringen. Z.B. hat Wasserstoff
(H) ein Proton und ein Elektron, aber Leitung (Pb) hat 82 Protone und 
82 Elektronen. Es gibt ungefähr 115 bekannte Elemente, von 
denen 82 natürlich reichlich vorhanden sind. Isotope: Der
Kern enthält Protone und Neutronen. Ein Element hat, eine 
örtlich festgelegte Anzahl von Protonen aber kann mit den 
verschiedenen Anzahlen von Neutronen existieren. Die Summe der 
Protone und der Neutronen ist die Massenzahl. Z.B. existiert 
Helium als Protone 3He(2 und ein Neutron) oder als 4He (2 Protone und 
2 Neutronen). Die zwei Formulare des Heliums werden Isotope des 
Heliums genannt. Isotope eines Elements haben die gleichen 
chemischen Eigenschaften aber die unterschiedlichen Gewichte. 
Einige Elemente haben viele Isomere. Zinn (Sn) hat 
ungefähr 38 das bekannte Isotope ~</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'information suivante vous aidera à comprendre 
le Tableau périodique des isotopes. Éléments : Chaque 
élément a un nombre fixe de protons franchement chargés à son 
noyau et un nombre égal d'électrons satellisant le noyau. Par 
exemple, l'hydrogène (h) a un proton et un électron, mais le fil de 
sortie (Pb) a 82 protons et 82 électrons. Il y a environ 115 
éléments connus dont 82 sont naturellement abondants. Isotopes
: Le noyau contient des protons et des neutrons. Un 
élément a un nombre fixe de protons mais peut exister avec de divers
nombres des neutrons. La somme des protons et des neutrons est 
le nombre de masse. Par exemple, l'hélium existe en tant que 
les protons 3He(2 et un neutron) ou comme 4He (2 protons et 2 
neutrons). Les deux formes de l'hélium s'appellent les isotopes
de l'hélium. Les isotopes d'un élément ont les mêmes 
propriétés chimiques mais différents poids. Quelques 
éléments ont beaucoup d'isomères. L'étain (Sn) a le ~ connu 
d'environ 38 isotopes</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A seguinte informação ajudar-lhe-á compreender 
a tabela periódica dos isotopes. Elementos: Cada elemento
tem um número fixo de protons positivamente carregados em seu núcleo
e um número igual dos elétrons que orbitam o núcleo. Para o 
exemplo, o hidrogênio (h) tem um proton e um elétron, mas a 
ligação (pb) tem 82 protons e 82 elétrons. Há 
aproximadamente 115 elementos sabidos de que 82 são naturalmente 
abundantes. Isotopes: O núcleo contem  protons e 
nêutrons. Um elemento tem um número fixo dos protons mas pode 
existir com vários números dos nêutrons. A soma dos protons e
dos nêutrons é o número maciço. Para o exemplo, o helium 
existe como os protons 3He(2 e o um nêutron) ou como 4He (2 protons e
2 nêutrons). Os dois formulários do helium são chamados 
isotopes do helium. Os isotopes de um elemento têm as mesmas 
propriedades químicas mas pesos diferentes. Alguns elementos 
têm muitos isomers. A lata (sn) tem o ~ sabido de 
aproximadamente 38 isotopes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le seguenti informazioni li aiuteranno a capire la
Tabella periodica degli isotopi. Elementi: Ogni elemento 
ha un numero fisso di protoni positivamente caricati nel relativo 
nucleo e un numero uguale di elettroni che orbitano intorno al nucleo.
Per esempio, l'idrogeno (H) ha un protone ed un elettrone, ma il
cavo (Pb) ha 82 protoni e 82 elettroni. Ci sono circa 115 
elementi conosciuti di cui 82 sono naturalmente abbondanti. 
Isotopi: Il nucleo contiene sia i protoni che i neutroni. 
Un elemento ha un numero fisso di protoni ma può esistere con i
vari numeri di neutroni. La somma dei protoni e dei neutroni è 
il numero totale. Per esempio, l'elio esiste come i protoni 
3He(2 ed un neutrone) o come 4He (2 protoni e 2 neutroni). Le 
due forme di elio sono chiamate isotopi di elio. Gli isotopi di 
un elemento hanno le stesse proprietà chimiche ma pesi differenti. 
Alcuni elementi hanno molti isomeri. La latta (Sn) ha ~ 
conosciuto dei circa 38 isotopi</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ακόλουθες πληροφορίες θα σας βοηθήσουν να 
καταλάβετε τον περιοδικό πίνακα των ισοτόπων. Στοιχεία: 
Κάθε στοιχείο έχει έναν σταθερό αριθμό θετικά χρεωμένων 
πρωτονίων στον πυρήνα του και έναν ίσο αριθμό ηλεκτρονίων που 
βάζουν τον πυρήνα σε τροχιά. Παραδείγματος χάριν, το 
υδρογόνο (H) έχει ένα πρωτόνιο και ένα ηλεκτρόνιο, αλλά ο 
μόλυβδος (Pb) έχει 82 πρωτόνια και 82 ηλεκτρόνια. 
Υπάρχουν περίπου 115 γνωστά στοιχεία των οποίων 82 
είναι φυσικά άφθονα. Ισότοπα: Ο πυρήνας περιέχει και
τα πρωτόνια και τα νετρόνια. Ένα στοιχείο έχει έναν 
σταθερό αριθμό πρωτονίων αλλά μπορεί να υπάρξει με τους 
διάφορους αριθμούς νετρονίων. Το ποσό των πρωτονίων και των
νετρονίων είναι ο μαζικός αριθμός. Παραδείγματος χάριν, το
ήλιο υπάρχει ως πρωτόνια 3He(2 και ένα νετρόνιο) ή ως 4He 
(2 πρωτόνια και 2 νετρόνια). Οι δύο μορφές του ηλίου 
καλούνται ισότοπα του ηλίου. Τα ισότοπα ενός στοιχείου 
έχουν τις ίδιες χημικές ιδιότητες αλλά τα διαφορετικά βάρη. 
Μερικά στοιχεία έχουν πολλά ισομερή. Ο κασσίτερος 
(Sn) έχει περίπου 38 γνωστά ισότοπα ~</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La información siguiente le ayudará a entender 
el vector periódico de los isótopos. Elementos: Cada 
elemento tiene un número fijo de protones positivamente cargados en 
su núcleo y un número igual de los electrones que mueven en órbita 
alrededor del núcleo. Por ejemplo, el hidrógeno (h) tiene un 
protón y un electrón, pero el terminal de componente (Pb) tiene 82 
protones y 82 electrones. Hay cerca de 115 elementos sabidos de 
los cuales 82 son naturalmente abundantes. Isótopos: El 
núcleo contiene los protones y los neutrones. Un elemento tiene
un número fijo de protones pero puede existir con varios números de 
neutrones. La suma de los protones y de los neutrones es el 
número total. Por ejemplo, el helio existe como los protones 
3He(2 y un neutrón) o como 4He (2 protones y 2 neutrones). Las 
dos formas de helio se llaman los isótopos del helio. Los 
isótopos de un elemento tienen las mismas características químicas 
pero diversos pesos. Algunos elementos tienen muchos isómeros. 
La lata (sn) tiene ~ sabido de cerca de 38 isótopos</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086140</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105032</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/exploring-the-table-of-isotopes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
