<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108076</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108076</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211423</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">One Nation: Two Futures?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Nation: Zwei Zukunft?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Nation : Deux Futurs ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma Nação: Dois Futuros?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una Nazione: Due Futuri?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα έθνος: Δύο μέλλοντα;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Nación: ¿Dos Futuros?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Since the mid-l970s, economic reforms have transformed China from one of the most egalitarian societies into one of the most unequal in the world. Wide disparities currently exist between the income levels of a relatively few rich and middle-class Chinese and their fellow citizens who number in the hundreds of millions. This "wealth gap" is particularly acute when one compares the incomes of urban and rural residents, between Chinese living in the interior of the country and those living in the rapidly developing cities on China's eastern coast.

The causes of the growing income gap include previous governmental policies that favored city dwellers over farmers, the uneven regional patterns of foreign investment, and the massive outflow of displaced farmers to China's already overcrowded cities in pursuit of manufacturing jobs.

Recently, the Chinese government, in recognition of the potential for social instability, and in the face of growing unrest amongst China's poor, has made the elimination of economic and social inequalities a top priority. Plans are in motion to build a more "harmonious society" through the delivery of improved educational and health services to those who appear to have been left behind in China's rush to modernize its economy.

This lesson, using clips from the WIDE ANGLE film "To Have and Have Not" (2002), can be used after a lesson on the Communist Revolution and Mao's rule. A basic knowledge of China's geography, of the tenets of Chinese Communism, and of Mao's efforts to redirect the course of China's future by means of the Cultural Revolution, is required for the successful completion of the lesson.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Seit dem mid-l970s haben ökonomische Verbesserungen China
von einer der gleichmacherischsten Gesellschaften in eine von den 
ungleichsten in der Welt umgewandelt. Breite Verschiedenheiten 
existieren aktuell zwischen den Einkommensniveaus von 
verhältnismäßig wenige Rich und Mittelklasse-, die chinesisch sind 
und ihre Mitbürger, die in den Hunderten von Millionen numerieren. 
Dieser "Fülleabstand" ist, wenn man die Einkommen der 
städtischen und landwirtschaftlichen Bewohner vergleicht, zwischen 
chinesischem Leben innerhalb des Landes besonders akut und die, die in
den schnell sich entwickelnden Städte auf östlichen Ursachen 
coast.The Chinas des wachsenden Einkommenabstandes leben, schließen 
vorhergehende Regierungspolitik, die Stadtbewohner über Landwirten, 
die ungleichen regionalen Muster der Auslandsanlage und den massiven 
Ausfluß der verlegten Landwirte zu Chinas bereits überfüllten 
Städte in der Verfolgung der Herstellung jobs.Recently, die 
chinesische Regierung, in der Anerkennung des Potentials für 
Sozialinstabilität und angesichts der wachsenden Ruhelosigkeit unter 
Armen Chinas bevorzugte, hat gebildet die Beseitigung von den 
ökonomischen und Sozialverschiedenheiten eine obere Priorität ein. 
Pläne sind in der Bewegung, zum einer "harmonischeren 
Gesellschaft" durch die Anlieferung des verbesserten pädagogischem 
und Gesundheitswesens zu denen aufzubauen, die scheinen, nach in den 
Anstürmen Chinas gelassen worden zu sein, um seine economy.This 
Lektion zu modernisieren und verwenden befestigt vom Weitwinkelfilm ",
um zu haben und zu haben nicht" (2002), kann nach einer Lektion auf 
der kommunistischen Umdrehung- und Maosrichtlinie verwendet werden. 
Ein grundlegendes Wissen von Geographie Chinas, der 
Lehren des chinesischen Kommunismus und der Bemühungen 
Maos, den Kurs von Zukunft Chinas mittels der kulturellen Umdrehung 
umzuadressieren, wird für die erfolgreiche Beendigung der Lektion 
benoetigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Depuis le mid-l970s, les réformes économiques ont 
transformé la Chine d'une des sociétés les plus égalitaires en une
des plus inégale au monde. Les disparités larges existent 
actuel entre les niveaux de revenu de l'relativement peu de riches et 
classe moyen chinois et leurs citoyens de camarade qui numérotent 
dans les centaines de millions. Cet "intervalle de richesse" est
particulièrement aigu quand on compare les revenus des résidants 
urbains et ruraux, entre la vie chinoise à l'intérieur du pays et 
ceux qui vivent dans les villes se développantes rapidement sur les 
causes orientales du coast.The de la Chine de l'intervalle croissant 
de revenu incluent les politiques gouvernementales précédentes qui 
ont favorisé des habitants de ville au-dessus des fermiers, les 
configurations régionales inégales de l'investissement étranger, et
la sortie massive des fermiers déplacés aux villes déjà 
surchargées de la Chine à la poursuite de la fabrication 
jobs.Recently, le gouvernement chinois, dans l'identification du 
potentiel pour l'instabilité sociale, et face au malaise croissant 
parmi les pauvres de la Chine, a fait l'élimination des inégalités 
économiques et sociales une première priorité. Les plans sont
dans le mouvement pour établir société "une" plus harmonieuse par 
la livraison d'éducatif amélioré et des services de santé à ceux 
qui semblent avoir été laissés dans les précipitations de la Chine
pour moderniser son leçon d'economy.This, à l'aide des clips du film
GRAND-ANGULAIRE "pour avoir et de Démuni" (2002), peuvent être 
utilisés après une leçon sur la règle communiste de révolution et
de Mao. Une connaissance de base de la géographie de la Chine, 
des principes du communisme chinois, et des efforts de Mao de 
réorienter le cours du futur de la Chine au moyen de la révolution 
culturelle, est exigée pour l'accomplissement réussi de la leçon.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Desde o mid-l970s, as reformas econômicas transformaram 
China de uma das sociedades as mais egalitarian em um do mais desigual
no mundo. Os disparities largos existem atualmente entre os 
níveis de renda do relativamente pouco rich e middle-class chineses e
seus cidadãos do companheiro que numeram nas centenas dos milhões. 
Esta da "abertura riqueza" é particularmente aguda quando uma 
compara as rendas de residentes urbanos e rurais, entre a vida chinesa
no interior do país e aquelas que vivem nas cidades ràpidamente 
tornando-se em causas orientais de coast.The de China da abertura 
crescente da renda incluem as políticas governamentais precedentes 
que favoreceram moradores da cidade sobre fazendeiros, os testes 
padrões regionais desiguais do investimento extrangeiro, e o outflow 
maciço de fazendeiros deslocados às cidades já overcrowded de China
na perseguição do manufacturing jobs.Recently, o governo chinês, no
recognition do potencial para a instabilidade social, e na cara do 
unrest crescente amongst pobres de China, fizeram o elimination de 
desigualdades econômicos e sociais uma prioridade superior. As 
plantas estão no movimento para construir uma sociedade "mais 
harmonious" com a entrega de serviços melhorados educacionais e de 
saúde àquelas que parecem ter sido deixadas atrás em arremetidas de
China para modernizar sua lição de economy.This, usando-se grampeam 
da película LARGA do ÂNGULO "para ter e para ter não" (2002), pode 
ser usado após uma lição na régua comunista da volta e do Mao. 
Um conhecimento básico da geografia de China, dos tenets do 
communism chinês, e de esforços de Mao dirigir de novo o curso do 
futuro de China por meio da volta cultural, é requerido para a 
conclusão bem sucedida da lição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dal mid-l970s, le riforme economiche hanno trasformato la 
Cina da una delle società più egalitarie in una dei più disuguali 
nel mondo. Le disparità larghe attualmente esistono fra i 
livelli di reddito di un relativamente poco cinese della classe 
media e ricco e dei loro cittadini del collega che numerano nelle 
centinaia di milioni. Questo "spacco di ricchezza" è 
particolarmente acuto quando uno confronta i redditi dei residenti 
urbani e rurali, fra il cinese che vive all'interno del paese e 
quelli che vivono nelle città velocemente di sviluppo sulle cause 
orientali di coast.The della Cina dello spacco crescente di reddito 
includono le politiche governative precedenti che hanno favorito gli 
abitanti della città sopra i coltivatori, i modelli regionali 
irregolari dell'investimento straniero e l'uscita voluminosa dei 
coltivatori spostati alle città già sovraccaricate della Cina 
nell'inseguimento di manufacturing jobs.Recently, il governo 
cinese, nel riconoscimento del potenziale per instabilità sociale
e di fronte ad agitazione crescente fra il povero della Cina, 
hanno fatto l'eliminazione delle diseguaglianze economiche e sociali 
una massima priorità. I programmi sono nel movimento per 
sviluppare una società "" più armoniosa con la consegna dei servizi 
medico-sanitari migliorati ed educativi a coloro che sembra essere 
lasciato negli sbalzi della Cina per modernizzare la relativa lezione 
di economy.This, usando ferma dalla pellicola GRANDANGOLARE "per avere
ed avere non" (2002), può essere usato dopo una lezione sulla regola 
comunista del Mao e di giro. Una conoscenza di base di geografia
della Cina, dei tenets di comunismo cinese e degli sforzi del Mao 
riorientare il corso di futuro della Cina per mezzo della rivoluzione 
culturale, è richiesta per il completamento riuscito della lezione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από τα μέσα της l970s, οι οικονομικές 
μεταρρυθμίσεις έχουν μετασχηματίσει την Κίνα από μια από τις 
egalitarian κοινωνίες σε ένας από τον ανισότερο στον κόσμο. 
Οι ευρείες διαφορές υπάρχουν αυτήν την περίοδο μεταξύ των 
εισοδηματικών επιπέδων σχετικά λίγη πλούσιοι και μεσαία τάξη 
κινέζικα και οι συντροφικοί πολίτες τους που αριθμούν στις 
εκατοντάδες των εκατομμυρίων. Αυτό το "χάσμα πλούτου" 
είναι ιδιαίτερα οξύ όταν συγκρίνει το ένα τα εισοδήματα των 
αστικών και αγροτικών κατοίκων, μεταξύ της κινεζικής διαβίωσης 
στο εσωτερικό της χώρας και εκείνων που ζουν στις γρήγορα 
αναπτυσσόμενες πόλεις στην ανατολική ακτή της Κίνας Οι 
αιτίες του αυξανόμενου εισοδηματικού χάσματος περιλαμβάνουν τις 
προηγούμενες κυβερνητικές πολιτικές που ευνόησαν τους κατοίκους 
πόλεων πέρα από τους αγρότες, τα ανώμαλα περιφερειακά πρότυπα 
της ξένης επένδυσης, και την ογκώδη εκροή των μετατοπισμένων 
αγροτών στις επιβαρυνμένες πόλεις της Κίνας ήδη στην αναζήτηση 
των εργασιών κατασκευής Πρόσφατα, η κινεζική κυβέρνηση, σε 
αναγνώριση της δυνατότητας για την κοινωνική αστάθεια, και παρά 
την ανάπτυξη της ανησυχίας μεταξύ των φτωχών της Κίνας, έχει 
κάνει την αποβολή των οικονομικών και κοινωνικών ανισοτήτων μια 
κορυφαία προτεραιότητα Τα σχέδια είναι στην κίνηση για να 
χτίσουν μια "αρμονικότερη κοινωνία" μέσω της παράδοσης των 
βελτιωμένων εκπαιδευτικών και υγειονομικών υπηρεσιών σε εκείνοι 
που εμφανίζονται να αφήνονται πίσω στη βιασύνη της Κίνας για να 
εκσυγχρονίσουν την οικονομία του Αυτό το μάθημα, που 
χρησιμοποιεί τους συνδετήρες από την ταινία WIDE.ANGLE "που 
έχει και που έχει όχι" (2002), μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί μετά 
από ένα μάθημα στην κομμουνιστικούς επανάσταση και τον κανόνα 
Mao. Μια βασική γνώση της γεωγραφίας της Κίνας, των 
αρχών του κινεζικού κομμουνισμού, και προσπαθειών Mao να 
επαναπροσανατολιστεί η πορεία του μέλλοντος της Κίνας με τη 
βοήθεια της πολιτιστικής επανάστασης, απαιτείται για την επιτυχή 
ολοκλήρωση του μαθήματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Desde el mid-l970s, las reformas económicas han 
transformado China a partir de la una de las sociedades más 
igualitarias en una del más desigual del mundo. Las 
disparidades amplias existen actualmente entre los niveles de ingresos
del relativamente pocos ricos y clase media chinos y sus ciudadanos 
del compañero que numeren en los centenares de millones. Este 
"boquete de la abundancia" es determinado agudo cuando uno compara las
rentas de residentes urbanos y rurales, entre la vida china en el 
interior del país y ésos que viven en las ciudades rápidamente que 
se convierten en las causas del este de coast.The de China del boquete
cada vez mayor de la renta incluyen las políticas gubernamentales 
anteriores que favorecieron habitantes de la ciudad sobre granjeros, 
los modelos regionales desiguales de la inversión extranjera, y la 
salida masiva de granjeros desplazados a las ciudades ya atestadas de 
China en la búsqueda de la fabricación jobs.Recently, el gobierno 
chino, en el reconocimiento del potencial para la inestabilidad 
social, y en la cara del malestar cada vez mayor entre los pobres de 
China, han hecho la eliminación de desigualdades económicas y 
sociales una prioridad superior. Los planes están en el 
movimiento para construir sociedad a una "más armoniosa" con la 
salida de los servicios médicos educativos y mejorados a las que 
aparezcan haber sido dejadas detrás en las acometidas de China para 
modernizar su lección de economy.This, usando acortan de la película
GRANANGULAR "para tener y tener no" (2002), puede ser utilizado 
después de una lección en la regla comunista de la revolución y de 
Mao. Un conocimiento básico de la geografía de China, de los 
tenets del comunismo chino, y de los esfuerzos de Mao de volver a 
dirigir el curso del futuro de China por medio de la revolución 
cultural, se requiere para la terminación acertada de la lección.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MELVIN MASKIN
FN:MELVIN MASKIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211423</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108076</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/one-nation-two-futures</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
