<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108603</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108603</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201359</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Analyzing Populations with Maps Using the U.S. - Mexico Demographic Data Viewer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Analysieren der Bevölkerungen mit Karten mit den US. - 
Mexiko Demographischer Daten-Projektor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Analyse des populations avec des cartes en utilisant les 
États-Unis. - Visualisateur Démographique de Données du 
Mexique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Analisando populações com mapas usando os E. U.. - Visor
Demográfico Dos Dados De México</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Analizzare le popolazioni con i programmi usando gli Stati 
Uniti. - Visore Demografico Di Dati Del Messico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: 
Αναλύοντας τους πληθυσμούς με τους χάρτες που χρησιμοποιούν 
τις ΗΠΑ - δημογραφική εμφάνιση στοιχείων του Μεξικού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Analizar a poblaciones con las correspondencias usando 
los E.E.U.U.. - Espectador Demográfico De los Datos De México</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, users are guided through a series of simple steps as they learn how to use a very powerful tool, the US-Mexico Demographic Data Viewer. Users find regions on a map, states within each region, and counties within each state. They describe and compare the geographical and socioeconomic characteristics of selected regions within the United States and Mexico. They analyze the data for variables that describe population characteristics to produce color-coded maps that demonstrate the results of the analyses for the various sub-divisions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität werden Benutzer durch eine 
Reihe einfache Jobsteps geführt, während sie erlernen, wie man ein 
sehr leistungsfähiges Hilfsmittel, den Uns-Mexiko demographischen 
Daten-Projektor benutzt. Benutzer finden Regionen auf einer 
Karte, Zustände innerhalb jeder Region und Grafschaften innerhalb 
jedes Zustandes. Sie beschreiben und vergleichen die 
geographischen und sozioökonomischen Eigenschaften der ausgewählten 
Regionen innerhalb der Vereinigten Staaten und des Mexikos. Sie 
analysieren die Daten für Variablen, die Bevölkerung Eigenschaften 
beschreiben, um farbunterlegte Karten zu produzieren, die die 
Resultate der Analysen für die verschiedenen Unterteilungen zeigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, des utilisateurs sont 
guidés par une série d'étapes simples pendant qu'ils apprennent 
comment utiliser un outil très puissant, le visualisateur 
démographique de données du Nous-Mexique. Les utilisateurs 
trouvent des régions sur une carte, des états dans chaque région, 
et des comtés dans chaque état. Ils décrivent et comparent 
les caractéristiques géographiques et socio-économiques des 
régions choisies dans les Etats-Unis et le Mexique. Ils 
analysent les données pour les variables qui décrivent des 
caractéristiques de population pour produire les cartes de code à 
couleurs qui démontrent les résultats des analyses pour les diverses
subdivisions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os usuários estão guiados com 
uma série de etapas simples enquanto aprendem como usar uma 
ferramenta muito poderosa, o visor demográfico dos dados de 
Nos-México. Os usuários encontram regiões em um mapa, estados
dentro de cada região, e condados dentro de cada estado. 
Descrevem e comparam as características geográficas e 
socioeconomic de regiões selecionadas dentro dos estados e do México
unidos. Analisam os dados para as variáveis que descrevem 
características da população para produzir os mapas color-coded que
demonstram os resultados das análises para as várias subdivisões.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli utenti sono guidati con 
una serie di punti semplici mentre imparano come utilizzare uno 
strumento molto potente, il visore demografico degli Stati Uniti di dati. 
Gli utenti trovano le regioni su un programma, dichiara 
all'interno di ogni regione e le contee all'interno di ciascuno 
dichiarano. Descrivono e confrontano il geografico e le 
caratteristiche socioeconomiche delle regioni selezionate all'interno 
del unito Dichiara ed il Messico. Analizzano i dati per 
le variabili che descrivono le caratteristiche della popolazione per 
produrre i programmi color-coded che dimostrano i risultati delle 
analisi per le varie suddivisioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι χρήστες καθοδηγούνται 
μέσω μιας σειράς απλών βημάτων δεδομένου ότι μαθαίνουν πώς να 
χρησιμοποιήσουν ένα πολύ ισχυρό εργαλείο, η δημογραφική 
εμφάνιση στοιχείων εμάς-Μεξικό. Οι χρήστες βρίσκουν τις 
περιοχές σε έναν χάρτη, τα κράτη μέσα σε κάθε περιοχή, και τους
νομούς μέσα σε κάθε κράτος. Περιγράφουν και συγκρίνω τα 
γεωγραφικά και κοινωνικοοικονομικά χαρακτηριστικά των επιλεγμένων 
περιοχών μέσα στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες και το Μεξικό. 
Αναλύουν τα στοιχεία για τις μεταβλητές που περιγράφουν τα 
χαρακτηριστικά πληθυσμών για να παραγάγουν τους κωδικοποιημένους 
διά χρώματος χάρτες που καταδεικνύουν τα αποτελέσματα των 
αναλύσεων για τις διάφορες υποδιαιρέσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, dirigen a los utilizadores con 
una serie de pasos de progresión simples mientras que aprenden cómo 
utilizar una herramienta muy de gran alcance, el espectador 
demográfico de los datos de Nosotros-Me'xico. Los utilizadores 
encuentran regiones en una correspondencia, estados dentro de cada 
región, y condados dentro de cada estado. Describen y comparan 
las características geográficas y socioeconómicas de regiones 
seleccionadas dentro de los Estados Unidos y del México. 
Analizan los datos para las variables que describen 
características de la población para producir las correspondencias 
color-coded que demuestran los resultados de los análisis para las 
varias subdivisiones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT DOWNS
FN:ROBERT DOWNS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201359</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108603</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-analyzing-populations-with-maps-using-the-u-s-mexico-demographic-data-viewer</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
