<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105645</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105645</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087044</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The (Second) Greatest Teacher of All Time": Father Coughlin's Followers Fight Back</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der (an zweiter Stelle) größte Lehrer aller 
Zeit": Nachfolger Vater Coughlins Kämpfen Zurück</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"(en second lieu) le plus grand professeur de 
toute l'heure" : Les Sectateurs de Coughlin de Père Battent En 
retraite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"(em segundo) o professor o mais grande de toda a 
hora": Os Seguidores De Coughlin Do Pai Lutam Para trás</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"(in secondo luogo) l'insegnante più grande di 
tutto il tempo": I Seguicamme Del Coughlin Del Padre Combattono 
Indietro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο (δεύτερος) μέγιστος δάσκαλος όλου του χρόνου": 
Οι οπαδοί Coughlin πατέρων παλεύουν πίσω</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"(en segundo lugar) el profesor más grande de 
toda la hora": Los Seguidores De Coughlin Del Padre Luchan 
Detrás</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Father Charles Coughlin occupied both a strange and a familiar place in American politics during the 1930s. Politically radical, a passionate democrat, he nevertheless was a bigot who freely vented angry, irrational charges and assertions. A Catholic priest, he broadcast weekly radio sermons that by 1930 drew as many as forty-five million listeners. By the mid-1930s, Coughlin's growing extremism, his increasing determination to cast political problems in terms of free-floating conspiracy, and his persistent attacks on a popular president, Franklin D. Roosevelt, made many of his fellow Catholics nervous. John Ryan, a fellow Catholic priest, had long been active as a social reformer and university educator. In a September 1936 radio speech, he denounced Coughlin for his attacks on FDR. Ryan's address provoked a host of letters; these three typical letters to Ryan reflected the character of Coughlin's devoted support and the capitulation to hatred that characterized Coughlin's movement in the late 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vater Charles Coughlin besetzte ein merkwürdiges 
und ein vertrauter Platz in der amerikanischen Politik während des 
dreißiger Jahre politisch Radikals, ein leidenschaftlicher Demokrat, 
war er dennoch ein Frömmler, der frei die verärgerten, 
vernunftwidrigen Ladungen und die Behauptungen lüftete. Ein 
katholischer Priester, übertrug er wöchentliche Radiopredigten, die 
durch 1930 bis zu wie forty-five Million Zuhörer zeichneten. 
Bis zum den Mid-1930s Coughlins bildeten wachsender Extremismus,
seine zunehmende Ermittlung, zum der politischen Probleme in frei-sich
hin- und herbewegender Verschwörung ausgedrückt zu werfen und seine 
hartnäckigen Angriffe auf einem populären Präsidenten, Franklin D. 
Roosevelt, viele von seinen Gefährtekatholischen nervös. John 
Ryan, ein Mitkatholischer Priester, war lang als SozialReformer 
und Universitätserzieher aktiv gewesen. In einer September 1936
Radiorede kündigte er Coughlin für seine Angriffe auf FDR. 
Adresse Ryans erregte einen Hauptrechner der Zeichen; 
diese drei typischen Zeichen zu Ryan teilten das Zeichen von 
Coughlins gewidmetem Support und den Capitulation an Haß mit, der 
Bewegung Coughlins in den späten dreißiger Jahren kennzeichnete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le père Charles Coughlin a occupé un étrange et
un endroit familier dans la politique américaine pendant des années 
30 le radical politiquement, un démocrate passionné, il néanmoins 
était un bigot qui a librement exhalé les frais et les affirmations 
fâchés et irrationnels. Un prêtre catholique, il a annoncé 
les sermons par radio hebdomadaires qui par 1930 ont dessiné l'autant
d'en tant que million d'auditeurs forty-five. Par le milieu des 
années 30, l'extrémisme croissant de Coughlin, sa détermination 
croissante pour mouler des problèmes politiques en termes de 
conspiration libre-flottante, et ses attaques persistantes sur un 
président populaire, Franklin D. Roosevelt, ont rendu beaucoup de ses
catholiques de camarade nerveux. John Ryan, un prêtre 
catholique de camarade, avait longtemps été en activité en tant 
qu'un réformateur et éducateur sociaux d'université. Dans un 
discours par radio de septembre 1936, il a dénoncé Coughlin pour ses
attaques sur le FDR. L'adresse de Ryan a provoqué une foule de 
lettres ; ces trois lettres typiques à Ryan ont reflété le 
caractère du support consacré de Coughlin et la capitulation à la 
haine qui a caractérisé le mouvement de Coughlin vers la fin des 
années 30.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O pai Charles Coughlin ocupou  um estranho e um 
lugar familiar na política americana durante dos 1930s. o radical 
polìtica, uma democrata passionate, não obstante era um bigot que 
exalasse livremente cargas e afirmações irritadas, irrational. 
Um priest catholic, transmitiu os sermons de rádio semanais que
por 1930 desenharam o tanto como como milhão ouvintes forty-five. 
Pelos mid-1930s, o extremism crescente de Coughlin, sua 
determinação crescente para moldar problemas políticos nos termos 
de livre-flutuar o conspiracy, e seus ataques persistentes em um 
presidente popular, Franklin D. Roosevelt, fizeram muitos de seus 
catholics do companheiro nervosos. John Ryan, um priest catholic
do companheiro, tinha sido por muito tempo ativo como um educador 
social do reformer e da universidade. Em um discurso de rádio 
de setembro 1936, denounced Coughlin para seus ataques no FDR. O
endereço de Ryan provocou um anfitrião das letras; estas três
letras típicas a Ryan refletiram o caráter da sustentação devotada
de Coughlin e o capitulation ao hatred que caracterizou o movimento de
Coughlin nos 1930s atrasados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il padre Charles Coughlin ha occupato sia uno 
sconosciuto che un posto esperto nella politica americana durante di 
1930s. il radicale politicamente, una carbossimetilazione 
appassionata, tuttavia era un bigot che ha scaricato liberamente le 
spese e le asserzioni arrabbiate e irrazionali. Un priest 
cattolico, ha trasmesso per radio i sermons radiofonici settimanali 
che da 1930 hanno dissipato l'altretanto come milione ascoltatori 
forty-five. Entro i mid-1930s, l'estremismo crescente del 
Coughlin, la sua determinazione aumentante per lanciare i problemi 
politici in termini di cospirazione digalleggiante ed i suoi attacchi 
persistenti ad un presidente popolare, Franklin D. Roosevelt, hanno 
reso molti dei suoi cattolici del collega nervosi. John Ryan, un
priest cattolico del collega, lungamente era stato attivo come 
educatore sociale dell'università e del reformer. In un 
discorso radiofonico di settembre 1936, ha denunciato Coughlin per i 
suoi attacchi al FDR. L'indirizzo del Ryan ha provocato una 
miriade di lettere; queste tre lettere tipiche a Ryan hanno 
riflesso il carattere del supporto dedicato del Coughlin ed il 
capitulation ad odio che ha caratterizzato il movimento del Coughlin 
verso la fine dei 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πατέρας Charles Coughlin κατέλαβε και μια 
παράξενη και γνωστή θέση στην αμερικανική πολιτική κατά τη 
διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '30 Πολιτικά ριζικός, ένας 
εμπαθής δημοκράτης, εντούτοις ήταν φανατικός που αέρισε 
ελεύθερα τις υς, παράλογους δαπάνες και τους ισχυρισμούς. 
Ένας καθολικός ιερέας, μετέδωσε ραδιοφωνικά τα εβδομαδιαία
ραδιο κηρύγματα που μέχρι το 1930 έσυραν τουλάχιστον σαράντα 
πέντε εκατομμύριο ακροατές. Μέχρι τα μέσα τησδεκαετίας του
'30, ο αυξανόμενος εξτρεμισμός Coughlin, η αυξανόμενη 
αποφασιστικότητά του να πετάξει τα πολιτικά προβλήματα από την 
άποψη να ελεύθερος-επιπλεύσουν της συνωμοσίας, και οι επίμονες 
επιθέσεις του σε έναν δημοφιλή Πρόεδρο, Franklin Δ. 
Roosevelt, κατέστησαν πολλών από τους συντροφικούς Καθολικούς 
του νευρικών. Θ*Ιοχν Ryan, ένας συντροφικός καθολικός 
ιερέας, ήταν από καιρό ενεργός ως κοινωνικό μεταρρυθμιστή και 
πανεπιστημιακό εκπαιδευτικό. Σε μια ραδιο ομιλία Σεπτεμβρίου
1936, κατήγγειλε Coughlin για τις επιθέσεις του σε FDR. 
Η διεύθυνση του Ryan προκάλεσε έναν πλήθο των επιστολών 
αυτά τα τρία χαρακτηριστικά γράμματα σε Ryan απεικόνισαν
το χαρακτήρα της αφιερωμένης υποστήριξης Coughlin και τη 
συνθηκολόγηση στην έχθρα που χαρακτήρισε τη μετακίνηση Coughlin
προς το τέλος της δεκαετίας του '30.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El padre Charles Coughlin ocupó un extraño y un 
lugar familiar en política americana durante de los años 30 el 
radical político, demócrata apasionado, él sin embargo era un 
fanático que expresó libremente cargas y aserciones enojadas, 
irracionales. Un sacerdote católico, él difundió los sermones
de radio semanales que por 1930 trazaron tanto como millón de 
módulos de escucha forty-five. Por los mediados de los años 
treinta, el extremismo cada vez mayor de Coughlin, su determinación 
de aumento para echar problemas políticos en términos de 
libre-flotar la conspiración, y sus ataques persistentes contra un 
presidente popular, Franklin D. Roosevelt, hicieron a muchos de sus 
católicos del compañero nerviosos. Juan Ryan, sacerdote 
católico del compañero, había sido de largo activo como un 
reformador y educador sociales de la universidad. En un discurso
de radio de septiembre 1936, él denunci Coughlin para sus ataques 
contra el FDR. El direccionamiento de Ryan provocó un ordenador
principal de cartas; estas tres cartas típicas a Ryan 
reflejaron el carácter de la ayuda dedicada de Coughlin y la 
capitulación al odio que caracterizó el movimiento de Coughlin en 
los últimos años 30.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087044</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105645</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-second-greatest-teacher-of-all-time-father-coughlins-followers-fight-back</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
