<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206785</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">All History Is Local: Students as Archivists</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alle Geschichte Ist Lokal: Kursteilnehmer 
als Archivare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Toute l'histoire Est Locale : Étudiants 
comme archivistes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Todo o History É Local: Estudantes como 
arquivistas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tutta la Storia È Locale: Allievi come 
archivisti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όλη η ιστορία είναι τοπική: Σπουδαστές ως 
αρχειοφύλακες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Toda la Historia Es Local: Estudiantes como 
archivistas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells how students at the Arkansas School for Mathematics and Statisticsematics and Science and Technologys analyzed archival materials, developed digital collections, and made their projects available online in the Arkansas Memory Project. This learning activity, modeled after the Library of Congress's American Memory project, is designed so that teachers and students from other states and communities may adapt it to create their own local history Memory Projects.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt wie Kursteilnehmer an der Arkansas Schule
für Mathematik und Statisticsematics und Wissenschaft und Technologys
archivalische Materialien analysierten, entwickelte digitale 
Ansammlungen und gebildet ihre Projekte vorhanden online im Arkansas 
Speicher-Projekt. Diese Lernenaktivität, geformt nach der 
Bibliothek des amerikanischen Speicherprojektes des Kongresses, ist 
konzipiert, damit Lehrer und Kursteilnehmer von anderen Zuständen und
Gemeinschaften sie anpassen können, um ihre eigenen lokalen 
Geschichte Speicher-Projekte zu erstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit que des étudiants à l'école de l'Arkansas 
pour des mathématiques et Statisticsematics et la Science et 
Technologys ont analysé les matériaux archivistiques, collections 
digitales développées, et fait leurs projets accessibles en ligne 
dans la mémoire de l'Arkansas projetez. Cette étude, modelée 
après la bibliothèque du projet américain de la mémoire du 
congrès, est conçue de sorte que les professeurs et les étudiants 
d'autres états et les communautés puissent l'adapter pour créer 
leurs propres projets locaux de mémoire d'histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz como estudantes na escola de Arkansas para a 
matemática e Statisticsematics e a ciência e Technologys analisaram 
materiais archival, coleções digitais desenvolvidas, e feito seus 
projetos disponíveis em linha no projeto da memória de Arkansas. 
Esta atividade de aprendizagem, modelada após a biblioteca do 
projeto americano da memória do congress, é projetada de modo que os
professores e os estudantes de outros estados e as comunidades possam 
a adaptar para criar seus próprios projetos locais da memória do 
history.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a come allievi alla scuola dell'Arkansas per 
la matematica e Statisticsematics e la scienza e Technologys hanno 
analizzato i materiali archivistici, collezioni digitali sviluppate e 
reso ai loro progetti accessibili in linea nella memoria dell'Arkansas
proiettisi. Questa attività imparante, modellistica dopo la 
libreria del progetto americano di memoria del congresso, è 
progettata in modo che gli insegnanti e gli allievi da altro 
dichiari e le Comunità possano adattarle per creare i loro 
propri progetti locali di memoria di storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει πώς οι σπουδαστές στο σχολείο του Αρκάνσας για 
τα μαθηματικά και Statisticsematics και την επιστήμη και 
Technologys ανέλυσαν τα αρχειακά υλικά, αναπτυγμένες ψηφιακές 
συλλογές, και καμένος τα προγράμματά τους απευθείας προσβάσιμα 
στο πρόγραμμα μνήμης του Αρκάνσας. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα 
εκμάθησης, που διαμορφώνεται μετά από το αμερικανικό πρόγραμμα 
μνήμης βιβλιοθήκης του συνεδρίου, σχεδιάζεται έτσι ώστε οι 
δάσκαλοι και οι σπουδαστές από άλλες κράτη και κοινότητες 
μπορούν να το προσαρμόσουν για να δημιουργήσουν τα τοπικά 
προγράμματα μνήμης ιστορίας τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice cómo los estudiantes en la escuela de 
Arkansas para las matemáticas y Statisticsematics y la ciencia y 
Technologys analizaban los materiales archival, colecciones digitales 
desarrolladas, y hecho sus proyectos accesibles en línea en la 
memoria de Arkansas proyecte. Esta actividad que aprende, 
modelada después de la biblioteca del proyecto americano de la 
memoria del congreso, se diseña de modo que los profesores y los 
estudiantes de otros estados y las comunidades puedan adaptarla para 
crear sus propios proyectos locales de la memoria de la historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206785</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106270</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/all-history-is-local-students-as-archivists</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
