<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102908</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102908</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200549</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Astronomy Picture of the Day: Earth At Night</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Astronomie-Abbildung des Tages: Masse 
Nachts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Image d'astronomie du jour : La Terre La 
nuit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Retrato da astronomia do dia: Terra Na 
Noite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Immagine di astronomia del giorno: Terra 
Alla Notte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικόνα αστρονομίας της ημέρας: Γη τη νύχτα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuadro de la astronomía del día: Tierra En
La Noche</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">NASA Astronomy Photo of the Day website hosted this photo of Earth at night in November 2000. The photo shows what Earth looks like at night with urban centers highlighted by concentrations of city lights. The image is a composite of hundreds of satellite photographs taken by orbiting Defense Meteorological Satellites Program satellites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die NASA Astronomie-Foto der Tagesweb site 
bewirtete dieses Foto von Masse nachts im November 2000. Das 
Foto zeigt, welche Masse aussehen wie nachts mit städtischen Mitten 
durch Konzentrationen der Stadtlichter markierten. Das Bild ist 
eine Zusammensetzung von Hunderten der Satellitenfotographien, die 
durch umkreisende Verteidigung-meteorologische 
Satellit-Programmsatelliten genommen werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La photo d'astronomie de la NASA du site Web de 
jour a accueilli cette photo de la terre la nuit en novembre 2000. 
La photo montre quels ressembler de la terre à la nuit avec les
centres urbains ont mis en valeur par des concentrations des lumières
de ville. L'image est un composé des centaines de photographies
satellites prises par les satellites météorologiques de programme de
satellites de la défense orbitale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A foto da astronomia da NASA do Web site do dia 
hospedou esta foto da terra na noite em novembro 2000. A foto 
mostra que olhares da terra como na noite com centros urbanos 
destacaram por concentrações de luzes da cidade. A imagem é 
um composto das centenas das fotografias satellite feitas exame por 
satélites meteorológicos do programa dos satélites da defesa 
orbiting.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La foto di astronomia della NASA del Web site di 
giorno ha ospitato questa foto di terra alla notte nel mese di 
novembre del 2000. La foto mostra che assomigli della terra alla
notte con le agglomerazioni urbane hanno evidenziato dalle 
concentrazioni delle luci della città. L'immagine è un 
composto delle centinaia delle fotografie satelliti prese dai 
satelliti meteorologici di programma dei satelliti della difesa 
orbiting.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η φωτογραφία αστρονομίας της NASA του ιστοχώρου 
ημέρας φιλοξένησε αυτήν την φωτογραφία της γης τη νύχτα τον 
Νοέμβριο του 2000. Η φωτογραφία εμφανίζει ποια γη μοιάζει με
τη νύχτα τα αστικά κέντρα που τονίζονται με από τις 
συγκεντρώσεις των φώτων πόλεων. Η εικόνα είναι ένα 
σύνθετο των εκατοντάδων των δορυφορικών φωτογραφιών που 
λαμβάνονται από τους βάζοντας σε τροχιά δορυφόρους προγράμματος 
αμυντικών μετεωρολογικούς δορυφόρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La foto de la astronomía de la NASA del Web site 
del día recibió esta foto de la tierra en la noche en noviembre de 
2000. La foto muestra qué parecer de la tierra en noche con los
centros urbanos destacaron por concentraciones de las luces de la 
ciudad. La imagen es un compuesto de centenares de fotografías 
basadas en los satélites tomadas por los satélites meteorológicos 
del programa de los satélites de la defensa orbiting.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:R. SIMON
FN:R. SIMON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200549</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102908</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/astronomy-picture-of-the-day-earth-at-night</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
