<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107918</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107918</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>2083464674</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tapping the Roots of American Music</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Klopfen der Wurzeln der amerikanischen Musik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tapement des racines de la musique américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Batendo as raizes da música americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Derivazione delle radici leggermente di musica 
americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τρύπημα των ριζών της αμερικανικής μουσικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Golpear ligeramente las raíces de la música 
americana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Teacher's Guide for using the American Roots Music documentary series in the classroom. The resources offered here are designed to help you use the PBS American Roots Music video series and companion Web site in middle school and high school social studies and history classes. American Roots Music may be taped off-air and used for up to a year following broadcast, or you may choose to purchase it through Shop PBS for Teachers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anleitung des Lehrers für das Verwenden des 
Amerikaners verwurzelt dokumentarische Serie der Musik im 
Klassenzimmer. Die Betriebsmittel, die hier angeboten werden, 
sind konzipiert, um Ihnen zu helfen, die video Serie und Begleiter der
PBS Amerikaner-Wurzel-Musik Web site in den Sozialstudien der 
mittleren Schule und der High School und in den Geschichte Kategorien 
zu verwenden. Amerikaner-Wurzel-Musik kann auf Band aufgenommene
Wegluft sein und verwendet für bis zu ein Jahr Sendung folgend, oder 
Sie können beschließen, sie durch System PBS für Lehrer zu kaufen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le guide du professeur pour l'usage de 
l'Américain enracine la série documentaire de musique dans la salle 
de classe. Les ressources offertes ici sont conçues pour vous 
aider à utiliser le site visuel de Web de série et de 
compagnon de musique de racines d'Américain de PBS dans des études 
de collège et de lycée et des classes sociales d'histoire. La 
musique de racines d'Américain peut être hors fonction-air 
enregistré sur bande et utilisé pendant jusqu'à une année suivant 
l'émission, ou vous pouvez choisir de l'acheter par le système PBS 
pour des professeurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A guia do professor para usar o americano enraiza 
a série documentary da música na sala de aula. Os recursos 
oferecidos aqui são projetados ajudar-lhe usar o Web site video da 
série e do companheiro da música das raizes do americano de PBS em 
estudos da escola média e da High School e em classes sociais do 
history. A música das raizes do americano pode ser fora-ar 
gravado e usado por até um ano que segue a transmissão, ou você 
pode escolher comprá-la através da loja PBS para professores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La guida dell'insegnante per usando l'americano 
sradica la serie documentaria di musica nell'aula. Le risorse 
offerte qui sono destinate per aiutarle ad usare Web site di serie e 
del compagno di musica delle radici dell'americano di PBS il video 
negli studi della High School e della scuola centrale e nei codici 
categoria sociali di storia. La musica delle radici 
dell'americano può essere fuori-aria registrata ed usato per fino ad 
un anno che segue la radiodiffusione, o potete scegliere comprarla 
attraverso il negozio PBS per gli insegnanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οδηγός δασκάλου για τη χρησιμοποίηση της αμερικανικής 
αποδεικτικής σειράς μουσικής ριζών στην τάξη. Τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς προσφερθέντα εδώ σχεδιάζονται για να σας βοηθήσουν 
να χρησιμοποιήσετε τον αμερικανικό ριζών PBS ιστοχώρο σειράς 
και συντρόφων μουσικής τηλεοπτικό στις μέσες κοινωνικές μελέτες 
σχολείων και γυμνασίου και τις τάξεις ιστορίας. Η 
αμερικανική μουσική ριζών μπορεί να είναι δεμένος με ταινία 
από-αέρας και χρησιμοποιημένος μέχρι και ένα έτος μετά από τη 
ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση, ή μπορείτε να επιλέξετε να την αγοράσετε 
μέσω του καταστήματος PBS για τους δασκάλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La guía del profesor para usar al americano 
arraiga serie documental de la música en la sala de clase. Los 
recursos ofrecidos aquí se diseñan para ayudarle a utilizar el sitio
video del Web de la serie y del compañero de la música de las
raíces del americano de PBS en estudios de la escuela media y de la 
High School secundaria y clases sociales de la historia. La 
música de las raíces del americano puede ser apagado-aire grabado y 
utilizado por hasta un año que sigue la difusión, o usted puede 
elegir comprarla a través del departamento PBS para los profesores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>2083464674</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107918</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tapping-the-roots-of-american-music</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
