<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106232</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106232</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087212</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Wedding.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hochzeit.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mariage.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Casamento.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nozze.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γάμος.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Boda.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This 1866 news engraving showed a chaplain marrying an African-American couple in the offices of the Vicksburg Freedmen's Bureau. Because marriages between slaves before emancipation had no legal standing, many couples rushed to have their marriages officially registered and made solemn during Reconstruction. Marriage was only one way of exercising the new freedom. For many former slaves, freedom meant choosing a new name for themselves, dressing as they pleased, learning to read, or refusing to be deferential towards their former owner.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser 1866 Nachrichten Stich zeigte ein Geistliches, das 
ein Afrikanisch-Amerikanisches Paar in den Büros des Büros der 
Vicksburg Freedmens verbindet. Weil Verbindungen zwischen 
Sklaven, bevor Emanzipation keine zugelassene Stellung hatte, viele 
Paare hetzten, um ihre offiziell registrierten Verbindungen zu haben 
und bildete ernst während der Rekonstruktion. Verbindung war 
von der Ausübung der neuen Freiheit nur Einweg. Für viele 
ehemalige Sklaven bedeutete Freiheit das Wählen eines neuen Namens 
für selbst und ankleidete, wie sie gefielen und erlernten zu lesen, 
oder, in Richtung zu ihrem ehemaligen Inhaber deferential zu sein 
ablehnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette gravure de 1866 nouvelles a montré un aumônier 
mariant un couple afro-américain dans les bureaux du bureau des 
freedmen's de Vicksburg. Puisque les mariages entre les esclaves
avant que l'émancipation n'ait eu aucune position légale, beaucoup 
de couples se sont précipités pour avoir leurs mariages 
officiellement enregistrés et a rendu solennel pendant la 
reconstruction. Le mariage était seulement à sens unique 
d'exercer la nouvelle liberté. Pour beaucoup d'anciens 
esclaves, la liberté a signifié choisir un nouveau nom pour 
eux-mêmes, s'habillant comme ils ont satisfait, apprenant à lire, ou
refusant d'être respectueux vers leur ancien propriétaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este engraving de 1866 notícias mostrou um capelão que 
casa um par Africano-Americano nos escritórios do departamento dos 
freedmen de Vicksburg. Porque as uniões entre escravos antes 
que o emancipation não teve nenhuma posição legal, muitos pares se 
apressaram para ter suas uniões registadas oficialmente e fêz solemn
durante o reconstruction. A união era somente de sentido único
de exercitar a liberdade nova. Para muitos escravos anteriores, 
a liberdade significou escolher um nome novo para se, vestindo-se como
satisfizeram, aprendendo ler, ou recusando ser deferential para seu 
proprietário anterior.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa incisione di 1866 notizie ha mostrato un cappellano
che sposa una coppia Africano-Americana negli uffici dell'ufficio dei 
freedmen di Vicksburg. Poiché le unioni fra gli schiavi prima 
che l'emancipazione non abbia condizione legale, molte coppie hanno 
scorso veloce per avere loro unioni registrate ufficialmente ed ha 
reso solenne durante la ricostruzione. L'unione era soltanto 
unidirezionale di esercitare la nuova libertà. Per molti 
schiavi precedenti, la libertà ha significato la scelta del nome 
nuovo per se stesso, vestentesi come soddisfacevano, imparando 
leggere, o rifiutando di essere deferential verso il loro ex 
proprietario.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η χάραξη 1866 ειδήσεων εμφάνισε έναν 
εφημέριο που παντρεύει ένα αφρικανικός-αμερικανικό ζεύγος στα 
γραφεία του γραφείου των απελευθέρων Vicksburg. Επειδή οι
γάμοι μεταξύ των σκλάβων προτού να μην έχε η χειραφέτηση 
καμία νομική επιφάνεια, πολλά ζεύγη όρμηξαν τους γάμους τους να
καταχωρήσουν επίσημα και έκαναν σοβαρός κατά τη διάρκεια της 
αναδημιουργίας. Ο γάμος ήταν μόνο ένας τρόπος τη νέα 
ελευθερία. Για πολλούς προηγούμενους σκλάβους, η ελευθερία 
σήμανε ένα νέο όνομα για τους, που ντύνουν καθώς παρακάλεσαν, 
μαθαίνοντας να διαβάζουν, ή αρμένος να είναι πλήρεις σεβασμού 
προς τον προηγούμενο ιδιοκτήτη τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este grabado de 1866 noticias mostró a capellán que 
casaba un par Africano-Americano en las oficinas de la oficina de los 
freedmen de Vicksburg. Porque las uniones entre los esclavos 
antes de que la emancipación no tuviera ninguna situación legal, 
muchos pares acometieron para tener sus uniones registradas 
oficialmente e hizo solemne durante la reconstrucción. La 
unión era solamente unidireccional de ejercitar la nueva libertad. 
Para muchos esclavos anteriores, la libertad significó elegir 
un nuevo nombre para sí mismos, vistiendo como satisficieron, 
aprendiendo leer, o rechazando ser respetuosos hacia su propietario 
anterior.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087212</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106232</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/wedding</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
