<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104226</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104226</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209791</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Corresponding Angles </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Entsprechende Winkel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Angles Correspondants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ângulos Correspondentes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Angoli Corrispondenti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αντίστοιχες γωνίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ángulos Correspondientes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the corresponding angles that are formed where a transversal crosses two lines. The applets cycles through the four possible pairs of angles when in animation mode. By dragging the three lines, it can be seen that the angle pairs are congruent only when the lines are parallel. When not in animated mode, there is a button that cycles through each the four pairs of angles. The text on the page discusses the properties of the pairs of corresponding angles both in the parallel and non-parallel cases. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die entsprechenden Winkel zeigen, die wo transversale 
Kreuze zwei Zeilen gebildet werden. Die applet macht durch die 
vier möglichen Paare von Winkeln wenn im Animationmodus einen 
Kreislauf durch. Indem man die drei Zeilen schleppt, kann es 
gesehen werden, daß die Winkelpaare übereinstimmend sind, nur wenn 
die Zeilen parallel sind. Wenn nicht in lebhaftem Modus, gibt es
eine diese Taste Schleifen durch jedes die vier Paare von Winkeln. 
Der Text auf der Seite behandelt die Eigenschaften der Paare der
entsprechenden Winkel in den parallelen und nicht parallelen Fällen. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les angles correspondants qui sont formés où les 
croix transversales deux lignes. Les applet fait un cycle par 
les quatre paires possibles d'angles quand en mode d'animation. 
En traînant les trois lignes, il peut voir que les paires 
d'angle sont conformes seulement quand les lignes sont parallèles. 
Quand pas en mode animé, il y a un bouton ce des cycles par le 
chaque les quatre paires d'angles. Le texte à la page discute 
les propriétés des paires d'angles correspondants dans les cas 
parallèles et non-parallèles. L'applet peut être agrandi à 
la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem os ângulos correspondentes que são dados forma onde 
cruzes transversal duas linhas. Os applet derem um ciclo com os 
quatro pares possíveis dos ângulos quando na modalidade do 
animation. Arrastando as três linhas, pode-se ver que os pares 
do ângulo são congruent somente quando as linhas estão paralelas. 
Quando não na modalidade animated, há uma tecla essa ciclos 
com o cada os quatro pares dos ângulos. O texto na página 
discute as propriedades dos pares de ângulos correspondentes  nos 
casos paralelos e non-parallel. O applet pode ser ampliado ao 
tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano gli angoli corrispondenti che sono formati dove traverse 
trasversali due righe. I applet cicla con i quattro 
accoppiamenti possibili degli angoli quando nel modo di animazione. 
Trascinando le tre righe, può essere visto che gli 
accoppiamenti di angolo sono conformi soltanto quando le righe sono 
parallele. Quando non nel modo animato, ci è un tasto quel 
cicli con l'ogni i quattro accoppiamenti degli angoli. Il testo 
alla pagina discute le proprietà degli accoppiamenti degli angoli 
corrispondenti sia nei casi paralleli che non paralleli. Il 
applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con 
un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, 
allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o 
nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa 
risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della 
geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τις αντίστοιχες γωνίες που διαμορφώνονται όπου τους
εγκάρσιους σταυρούς δύο γραμμές. Οι κύκλοι applets μέσω
των τεσσάρων πιθανών ζευγαριών των γωνιών όταν είναι στον τρόπο
ζωτικότητας. Με το σύρσιμο των τριών γραμμών, μπορεί να 
δει ότι τα ζευγάρια γωνίας είναι σύμφωνα μόνο όταν 
οι γραμμές είναι παράλληλες. Όταν όχι στο ζωντανεψοντα 
τρόπο, υπάρχει ένα κουμπί που κύκλοι μέσω κάθε των τεσσάρων 
ζευγαριών των γωνιών. Το κείμενο στη σελίδα συζητά τις 
ιδιότητες των ζευγαριών των αντίστοιχων γωνιών και στις 
παράλληλες και μη παράλληλες περιπτώσεις. Το Applet 
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran los ángulos correspondientes se forman que donde las 
cruces transversales dos líneas. Los applet completan un ciclo 
con los cuatro pares posibles de ángulos cuando en modo de la 
animación. Arrastrando las tres líneas, puede ser visto que 
los pares del ángulo son congruentes solamente cuando las líneas son
paralelas. Cuando no en modo animado, hay un botón ese los 
ciclos con cada los cuatro pares de ángulos. El texto en la 
paginación discute las características de los pares de ángulos 
correspondientes en los casos paralelos y no paralelos. El 
applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el 
uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la
sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier 
web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida.
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209791</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104226</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/corresponding-angles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
