<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107380</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107380</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201386</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Module Two: Interpersonal Relationships</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Modul Zwei: Zwischenpersonal-Verhältnisse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Module Deux : Rapports Interpersonnels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Módulo Dois: Relacionamentos Interpersonal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modulo Due: Rapporti Tra persone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενότητα δύο: Διαπροσωπικές σχέσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Módulo Dos: Lazos Interpersonales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Interpersonal Relationships Module focuses on developing the life skills of the individual within the context of healthy relationships. Relationships can be with people directly in an individual's environment or with others in the broader community. In order to maintain healthy relationships we need to be aware of the impact we each have on the lives, behaviour, attitudes and values of others.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Zwischenpersonal-Verhältnis-Modulfoki auf dem
Entwickeln der Lebenfähigkeiten der Einzelperson innerhalb des 
Kontextes der gesunden Verhältnisse. Verhältnisse können mit 
Leuten direkt in der Umgebung einer Einzelperson oder mit anderen in 
der ausgedehnteren Gemeinschaft sein. Zwecks gesunde 
Verhältnisse, die wir die Auswirkung berücksichtigen müssen wir 
jedes auf den Lebensdauern, haben Verhalten, Haltung und Werte von 
anderen behalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les foyers interpersonnels de module de rapports 
sur développer les qualifications de la vie de l'individu dans le 
contexte des rapports sains. Les rapports peuvent être avec des
personnes directement dans l'environnement d'un individu ou avec 
d'autres dans la communauté plus large. Afin de mettre à jour 
des rapports sains que nous devons nous rendre compte de l'impact nous
chacun a les vies, le comportement, des attitudes et des valeurs de 
d'autres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os focos interpersonal do módulo dos 
relacionamentos em desenvolver as habilidades da vida do indivíduo 
dentro do contexto de relacionamentos saudáveis. Os 
relacionamentos podem ser com povos diretamente no ambiente de um 
indivíduo ou com o outro na comunidade mais larga. A fim manter
relacionamentos que saudáveis nós necessitamos estar cientes do 
impacto nós cada um tem nas vidas, comportamento, atitudes e valores 
de outros.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I fuochi tra persone del modulo di rapporti sullo 
sviluppare le abilità di vita dell'individuo all'interno del contesto
dei rapporti sani. I rapporti possono essere con la gente 
direttamente nell'ambiente dell'individuo o con altri nella più vasta
Comunità. Per per effettuare i rapporti che sani dobbiamo 
essere informati dell'effetto noi ciascuno ha sulle vite, il 
comportamento, gli atteggiamenti ed i valori di altri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαπροσωπική εστίαση ενότητας σχέσεων στην ανάπτυξη
των δεξιοτήτων ζωής του ατόμου μέσα στο πλαίσιο των υγιών 
σχέσεων. Οι σχέσεις μπορούν να είναι με τους ανθρώπους 
άμεσα στο περιβάλλον ενός ατόμου ή με άλλες στην ευρύτερη 
κοινότητα. Προκειμένου να διατηρηθούν οι υγιείς σχέσεις 
πρέπει να γνωρίζουμε τον αντίκτυπο που κάθε ένας έχουμε στις 
ζωές, τη συμπεριφορά, τις τοποθετήσεις και τις τιμές άλλες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los focos interpersonales del módulo de los lazos
en desarrollar las habilidades de la vida del individuo dentro del 
contexto de lazos sanos. Los lazos pueden estar con la gente 
directamente en el ambiente de un individuo o con otros en la 
comunidad más amplia. Para mantener lazos sanos que necesitamos
estar enterados del impacto nosotros cada uno tiene en las vidas, 
comportamiento, actitudes y valores de otros.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201386</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107380</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/module-two-interpersonal-relationships</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
