<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106724</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106724</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086345</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Didn't Pan Out as We Thought It Was Going To"Amos Owen on the Indian Reorganization Act</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sie verschob nicht heraus, wie wir dachten, daß 
es gehendes To"Amos Owen auf der indischen Reorganisierung-Tat war</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il n'a pas filtré dehors comme nous avons pensé
que c'était To"Amos allant Owen sur l'acte indien de réorganisation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não garimpou para fora como nós pensamos que 
era To"Amos indo Owen no ato indian do reorganization</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non ha fatto una panoramica di fuori abbiamo 
pensato che fosse To"Amos andante Owen sulla Legge indiana della 
riorganizzazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν φιλτράρισε έξω όπως σκεφτήκαμε ότι ήταν 
μετάβαση To"Amos Owen στον ινδικό νόμο αναδιοργάνωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no filtró hacia fuera como pensamos que era 
To"Amos que iba Owen en el acto indio de la reorganización</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Indian Reorganization Act of 1934, which became known as the Indian New Deal, dramatically changed the federal government's Indian policy. Although John Collier, the commissioner of Indian affairs who was responsible for the new policy, may have viewed Indians with great sympathy, not all Native Americans viewed the Indian New Deal in equally positive terms. In this 1970 interview with historian Herbert T. Hoover, Amos Owen, Mdewakanton Sioux tribal chairman, gave a mixed verdict on the Indian Reorganization Act.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die indische Reorganisierung-Tat von 1934, die als
das indische neue Abkommen bekannt wurde, indische Politik der 
drastisch geänderten die Bundesregierung. Obgleich John 
Collier, der Beauftragte der indischen Angelegenheiten, der für die 
neue Politik verantwortlich war, Inder mit großer Sympathie angesehen
haben kann, sahen nicht alle gebürtigen Amerikaner das indische neue 
Abkommen in den gleichmäßig positiven Bezeichnungen an. In 
diesem Interview 1970 mit Historiker Herbert T. Hoover, Amos Owen, 
Mdewakanton Sioux Stammes- Vorsitzender, gab einen Mischurteilsspruch 
auf der indischen Reorganisierung-Tat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Loi indienne de réorganisation de 1934, qui 
est devenue notoire comme nouvelle affaire indienne, la politique 
indienne de gouvernement fédéral excessivement changé. Bien 
que John Collier, commissaire des affaires indiennes qui était 
responsable de la nouvelle politique, ait pu avoir visualisé des 
Indiens avec la grande sympathie, non tous les Américains indigènes 
ont visualisé la nouvelle affaire indienne en termes également 
positifs. Dans cette entrevue 1970 avec l'historien Herbert T. 
Hoover, AMOS Owen, Président tribal de Mdewakanton Sioux, a donné un
verdict mélangé sur l'acte indien de réorganisation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato indian do reorganization de 1934, que se 
tornou sabido como o negócio novo indian, a política indian de 
governo federal dramàtica mudado. Embora o collier de John, 
comissário de casos indian que era responsável para a política 
nova, pudesse ter visto indians com sympathy grande, não todos os 
americanos nativos viram o negócio novo indian em termos ingualmente 
positivos. Nesta entrevista 1970 com historian Herbert T. 
Hoover, Amos Owen, presidente tribal de Mdewakanton Sioux, deu um 
verdict misturado no ato indian do reorganization.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge indiana della riorganizzazione di 1934, 
che è stato conosciuta come il nuovo affare indiano, politica indiana
del governo federale drammaticamente cambiato. Anche se il 
collier del John, il commissario degli affari indiani che era 
responsabile di nuova politica, può osservare gli indiani con 
compassione grande, non tutti gli Americani natali hanno osservato il 
nuovo affare indiano nei termini ugualmente positivi. In questa 
intervista 1970 con lo storico Herbert T. Hoover, gli AMO Owen, 
presidente tribale di Mdewakanton Sioux, ha dato un verdetto mixed 
sulla Legge indiana della riorganizzazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ινδικός νόμος αναδιοργάνωσης του 1934, που έγινε 
γνωστός ως ινδική νέα διαπραγμάτευση, άλλαξε εντυπωσιακά την 
ινδική πολιτική της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης. Αν και John
Collier, ο Επίτροπος των ινδικών υποθέσεων που ήταν αρμόδιος 
για τη νέα πολιτική, μπορεί να είχε εμφανίσει Ινδούς με τη 
μεγάλη συμπόνοια, δεν εμφάνισαν όλοι οι εγγενείς Αμερικανοί την 
ινδική νέα διαπραγμάτευση στους εξίσου θετικούς όρους. Σε 
αυτήν την συνέντευξη του 1970 με τον ιστορικό Herbert T. 
Hoover, amos Owen, σιού φυλετικός πρόεδρος Mdewakanton,
έδωσε μια μικτή απόφαση στον ινδικό νόμο αναδιοργάνωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto indio de la reorganización de 1934, que 
se conocía como el nuevo reparto indio, la política india del 
gobierno federal dramáticamente cambiante. Aunque el collier de
Juan, la comisión de asuntos indios que era responsable de la nueva 
política, pudo haber visto a indios con gran condolencia, no todos 
los americanos nativos vieron el nuevo reparto indio en términos 
igualmente positivos. En esta entrevista 1970 con el historiador
Herberto T. Hoover, Amos Owen, presidente tribal de Mdewakanton Sioux,
dio un veredicto mezclado en el acto indio de la reorganización.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086345</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106724</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-didnt-pan-out-as-we-thought-it-was-going-to-amos-owen-on-the-indian-reorganization-act</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
