<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105303</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105303</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087122</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"To Abolish the Monroe Doctrine": Proclamation from Augusto Csar Sandino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Monroe Lehre abschaffen": Proklamation 
von Augusto Csar Sandino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"pour supprimer la doctrine de Monroe" : 
Proclamation d'Augusto Csar Sandino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"para abolish a doutrina de monroe": 
Proclamation de Augusto Csar Sandino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"per abolire la dottrina di Monroe": 
Proclamazione da Augusto Csar Sandino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Για να καταργήσει το δόγμα του Μονρόε": 
Προκήρυξη από τον Augusto Csar Sandino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"para suprimir la doctrina de Monroe": 
Proclamación de Augusto Csar Sandino</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The "Monroe Doctrine" of 1823 warned European powers to stay out of Latin America, including Central America, which had a particular importance to the United States because of its proximity. By the early 20th century, U.S. companies dominated the economies of Central American republics, including Nicaragua, controlling most of the banana production, railroads, port facilities, mines, and banking institutions. The United States intervened in Nicaragua repeatedly to protect U.S. economic interests. In 1912 U.S. marines landed once again to maintain a pro-American government; this occupation lasted until 1925. Augusto Csar Sandino, a nationalist and leader of Nicaraguan peasants and workers, refused to accept the U.S.-sponsored peace treaty that kept U.S. influence and economic power intact. He organized an army of peasants, workers, and Indians to resist thousands of U.S. marines and the U.S.-trained Nicaraguan National Guard. Sandino's 1933 proclamation called upon all the nations of Central America to oppose U.S. imperialism. From 1927 to 1933 Sandino waged a successful guerrilla war against the United States with support from Mexican and other Latin American anti-imperialists.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die "Monroe Lehre" von 1823 warnte europäische 
Energien, aus lateinischem Amerika, einschließlich Mittelamerika 
heraus zu bleiben, das eine besondere Bedeutung in die Vereinigten 
Staaten wegen seiner Nähe hatte. Bis zum dem frühen 20. 
Jahrhundert beherrschten VEREINIGTE STAATEN Firmen die 
Wirtschaftssysteme der zentralen amerikanischen Republiken, 
einschließlich Nicaragua und steuerten die meisten der Banane 
Produktion, den Eisenbahnen, den Portteildiensten, den Gruben und 
Einrichtungen des Bankgewerbes. Die Vereinigten Staaten griffen 
in Nicaragua wiederholt ein, um VEREINIGTE STAATEN ökonomische 
Interessen zu schützen. In 1912 VEREINIGTEN STAATEN landeten 
Marinen noch einmal, um eine Pro-Amerikanische Regierung 
beizubehalten; diese Besetzung dauerte bis 1925. Augusto 
Csar Sandino, ein Nationalist und Führer der Nicaragualandarbeiter 
und der Arbeiter, abgelehnt, um den U.S.-sponsored Friedensvertrag 
anzunehmen, der den VEREINIGTE STAATEN Einfluß und ökonomische 
Energie intakt hielt. Er organisierte eine Armee der 
Landarbeiter, der Arbeiter und der Inder, um Tausenden der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Marinen und des U.S.-trained nationalen Nicaraguaschutzes zu 
widerstehen. Sandinos Proklamation 1933 ersuchte um alle 
Nationen von Mittelamerika, um VEREINIGTE STAATEN Imperialismus 
entgegenzusetzen. Von unternahm Sandino 1927 bis 1933 einen 
erfolgreichen Bandenkämpferkrieg gegen die Vereinigten Staaten mit 
Support vom Mexikaner und von anderen lateinamerikanischen 
Anti-Imperialisten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La "doctrine de Monroe" de 1823 a averti des 
puissances européennes de rester hors de l'Amérique latine, y 
compris l'Amérique Centrale, qui a eu une importance particulière 
pour les Etats-Unis en raison de sa proximité. Par le début du
20ème siècle, les compagnies des ETATS-UNIS ont dominé les 
économies des républiques américaines centrales, y compris le 
Nicaragua, contrôlant la plupart de la production de banane, des 
chemins de fer, des équipements gauches, des mines, et des 
institutions bancaires. Les Etats-Unis sont intervenus au 
Nicaragua à plusieurs reprises pour protéger des intérêts 
économiques des ETATS-UNIS. Aux 1912 ETATS-UNIS les soldats de 
marine ont débarqué de nouveau pour mettre à jour un gouvernement 
pro-Américain ; ce métier a duré jusqu'en 1925. Augusto
Csar Sandino, un nationaliste et amorce des paysans et des ouvriers de
Nicaragua, refusés pour recevoir le traité de paix d'U.S.-sponsored 
qui a maintenu l'influence des ETATS-UNIS et la puissance économique 
intactes. Il a organisé une armée des paysans, des ouvriers, 
et des Indiens pour résister à des milliers des soldats de marine 
des ETATS-UNIS et de la garde nationale de Nicaragua d'U.S.-trained. 
La proclamation 1933 de Sandino a invité toutes les nations de 
l'Amérique Centrale pour s'opposer à l'impérialisme des ETATS-UNIS.
De Sandino 1927 à 1933 a fait une guerre réussie de 
guérillero contre les Etats-Unis avec le support du Mexicain et 
d'autres anti-impérialistes latino-américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">De "a doutrina monroe" de 1823 advertiu potências
européias permanecer fora de América latin, including América 
Central, que teve uma importância particular aos estados unidos por 
causa de sua proximidade. Pelo 20o século adiantado, as 
companhias de ESTADOS UNIDOS dominaram as economias de repúblicas 
americanas centrais, including Nicarágua, controlando a maioria da 
produção da banana, das estradas de ferro, das facilidades 
portuárias, das minas, e das instituições de operação bancária. 
Os estados unidos intervieram em Nicarágua repetidamente para 
proteger interesses econômicos de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Em 1912 
ESTADOS UNIDOS os fuzileiros navais aterraram uma vez outra vez para 
manter um governo pro-Americano; esta ocupação durou até 
1925. Augusto Csar Sandino, um nacionalista e líder de 
camponeses e de trabalhadores nicaraguan, recusados aceitar o tratado 
da paz de U.S.-sponsored que manteve a influência de ESTADOS UNIDOS e
a potência econômica intatas. Organizou um exército dos 
camponeses, dos trabalhadores, e dos indians para resistir milhares de
fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS e do protetor nacional nicaraguan 
de U.S.-trained. O proclamation 1933 de Sandino convidou todas 
as nações de América Central para opôr o imperialism de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. Sandino 1927 a 1933 empreendeu uma guerra bem sucedida 
do guerrilla de encontro aos estados unidos com a sustentação do 
mexicano e de outros anti-anti-imperialists americanos latin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la dottrina di Monroe" di 1823 ha avvertito le 
potenzi europee rimanere dall'america latina, compreso l'America 
Centrale, che ha avuta un'importanza particolare al unito 
Dichiara a causa della relativa prossimità. Entro 
l'inizio del 20esimo secolo, le aziende degli STATI UNITI hanno 
dominato le economie delle repubbliche americane centrali, compreso la
Nicaragua, gestente la maggior parte della produzione della banana, 
delle ferrovie, delle attrezzature port, delle miniere e delle 
istituzioni di operazioni bancarie. Unito Dichiara 
intervenuto ripetutamente in Nicaragua per proteggere gli interessi 
economici degli STATI UNITI. In 1912 STATI UNITI i fanti di 
marina hanno atterrato ancora una volta per effettuare un governo 
pro-Americano; questa occupazione ha durato fino al 1925. 
Augusto Csar Sandino, un nazionalista e capo dei 
contadini e degli operai nicaraguan, rifiutati per accettare il 
trattato di pace di U.S.-sponsored che ha mantenuto l'influenza degli 
STATI UNITI e l'potenza economica intatte. Ha organizzato un 
esercito dei contadini, degli operai e degli indiani per resistere ai 
migliaia dei fanti di marina degli STATI UNITI e della protezione 
nazionale nicaraguan di U.S.-trained. La proclamazione 1933 del 
Sandino ha invitato tutte le nazioni dell'America Centrale per opporre
l'imperialismo degli STATI UNITI. Sandino 1927 - 1933 ha 
intrapreso un guerrigliero che riuscito la guerra contro unito 
Dichiara con supporto da anti-anti-imperialists messicani ed
altri dell'America latina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το "δόγμα του Μονρόε" 1823 προειδοποίησε τις 
ευρωπαϊκές δυνάμεις να μείνει έξω από τη λατινική Αμερική, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της Κεντρικής Αμερικής, η οποία έχω μια 
ιδιαίτερη σημασία στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες λόγω της εγγύτητάς 
της. Μέχρι τον πρόωρο 20ό αιώνα, οι ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΕΣ 
επιχειρήσεις εξουσίασαν τις οικονομίες των Κεντρικής Αμερικής 
δημοκρατιών, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της Νικαράγουας, που ελέγχει την 
μεγαλύτερη μέρος της παραγωγής μπανανών, σιδηρόδρομοι, 
εγκαταστάσεις λιμένων, ορυχεία, και που καταθέτει τα 
όργανα σε τράπεζα. Οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες επεμ:βαίνω
στη Νικαράγουα για να προστατεύσουν επανειλημμένα τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ 
οικονομικά συμφέροντα. Το 1912 τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ ναυτικά 
προσγειώθηκαν άλλη μια φορά για να διατηρήσουν μια 
υπέρ-αμερικανική κυβέρνηση  αυτό το επάγγελμα διάρκεσε 
μέχρι 1925, Augusto Csar Sandino, έναν εθνικιστή και 
έναν ηγέτη των νικαραγουανών αγροτών και οι εργαζόμενοι, 
αρνήθηκαν να αποδεχθούν την ΗΠΑ-Υποστηριγμένη συνθήκη ειρήνης που
κράτησε την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ επιρροή και την οικονομική δύναμη 
άθικτες. Οργάνωσε έναν στρατό των αγροτών, των 
εργαζομένων, και Ινδών για να αντισταθεί σε χιλιάδες ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ 
ναυτικά και ΗΠΑ-Εκπαιδευμένη νικαραγουανή εθνική φρουρά. Η 
προκήρυξη του 1933 του Sandino ζήτησε από όλα τα έθνη της 
Κεντρικής Αμερικής για να αντιτάξει τον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ιμπεριαλισμό. 
Από το 1927 ως το 1933 Sandino ένας επιτυχής 
πόλεμος ανταρτών ενάντια στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες με υποστήριξη 
από μεξικανό και άλλους λατινοαμερικανικούς αντι-ιμπεριαλιστές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La "doctrina de Monroe" de 1823 advirtió 
potencias europeas de permanecer fuera de América latina, incluyendo 
America Central, que tenía una importancia determinada a los Estados 
Unidos debido a su proximidad. Por el vigésimo siglo temprano, 
las compañías de ESTADOS UNIDOS dominaron las economías de 
repúblicas americanas centrales, incluyendo Nicaragua, controlando a 
la mayoría de la producción del plátano, de los ferrocarriles, de 
los recursos portuarios, de las minas, y de las instituciones de 
actividades bancarias. Los Estados Unidos intervinieron en 
Nicaragua en varias ocasiones para proteger los intereses económicos 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS. En 1912 ESTADOS UNIDOS los infantes de marina
aterrizaron de nuevo para mantener un gobierno favorable-Americano; 
esta ocupación duró hasta 1925. Augusto Csar Sandino, 
nacionalista y arranque de cinta de campesinos y de trabajadores 
nicaraguan, rechazados para validar el tratado de la paz de 
U.S.-sponsored que mantuvo la influencia de ESTADOS UNIDOS y el poder 
económico intactos. Él ordenó a ejército de campesinos, de 
trabajadores, y de indios para oponerse a millares de infantes de 
marina de ESTADOS UNIDOS y del protector nacional nicaraguan de 
U.S.-trained. La proclamación 1933 de Sandino invitó todas las
naciones de America Central para oponer el imperialismo de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. A partir Sandino la 1927 a 1933 emprendió una guerra 
acertada del guerrilla contra los Estados Unidos con la ayuda del 
mexicano y de otros contra-imperialistas americanos latinos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087122</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105303</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/to-abolish-the-monroe-doctrine-proclamation-from-augusto-csar-sandino</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
