<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108576</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108576</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087026</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Problem" and "Family Histories": Charles Johnson Analyzes the Causes of the Chicago Race Riot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das Problem" und "Familiengeschichten": 
Charles Johnson analysiert die Ursachen des Chicago 
Rennen-Aufstands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le problème" et "antécédents familiaux" : 
Charles Johnson analyse les causes de l'émeute de course de 
Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o problema" e de "histories família": 
Charles Johnson analisa as causas do motim da raça de Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il problema" e "dati storici di famiglia": 
Charles Johnson analizza le cause del tumulto della corsa del 
Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το πρόβλημα" και "οικογενειακές ιστορίεσ": 
Θ*Θχαρλες Johnson Analyzes οι αιτίες της φυλετικής 
ταραχής του Σικάγου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el problema" y "antecedentes familiares": 
Charles Johnson analiza las causas del alboroto de la raza de 
Chicago</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As U.S. soldiers returned from Europe in the aftermath of World War I, scarce housing and jobs heightened racial and class antagonisms across urban America. African-American soldiers, in particular, came home from the war expecting to enjoy the full rights of citizenship that they had fought to defend overseas. In the spring and summer of 1919, murderous race riots erupted in 22 American cities and towns. Chicago experienced the most severe of these riots. The most detailed and sober reporting of the causes of the 1919 Chicago race riot came retrospectively from the interracial Chicago Commission on Race Relations. The Commission published a seven hundred-page report in 1922,  The Negro in Chicago . Charles Johnson--a Chicago Urban League official, the associate executive secretary of the integrated commission, and the principal author of its report--hoped that by thoroughly describing the sentiments and living conditions of African Americans and the similarities between European immigrants and recent black migrants to Chicago, the report would generate sympathy for the city's black community. Filled with photographs, charts, and maps,  The Negro in Chicago  carefully dissected Chicago's racial problems, including black and white antagonism over housing, jobs, and crime.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während VEREINIGTE STAATEN Soldaten von Europa in
der Nachmahd des Ersten Weltkrieges zurückkamen, erhöhten knappes 
Gehäuse und Jobs die rassische und Kategorie Antagonismen über 
städtischem Amerika. Die Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Soldaten 
kamen insbesondere nach Hause vom Krieg erwartend, die vollen Rechte 
der Staatsbürgerschaft zu genießen, die sie gekämpft hatten, um 
übersee zu verteidigen. Im Frühling und im Sommer von 1919, 
brachen mörderische Rennenaufstände in 22 amerikanischen Städte und
in Städten aus. Chicago erfuhr das strengste dieser Aufstände.
Der ausführlichste und nüchternste Bericht der Ursachen des 
Chicago Rennenaufstands 1919 kam zurückblickend von der interracial 
Chicago Kommission auf Rennen-Relationen. Die Kommission 
veröffentlichte einen sieben Hundertseite Report 1922, den Schwarzen 
in Chicago. Charles Johnson -- ein Chicago städtischer 
Ligabeamter, der Geschäftsführer des Teilnehmers der integrierten 
Kommission und der allgemeine Autor von seinem Report -- gehofft, 
daß, indem er gänzlich die Gefühle und die lebenden Zustände der 
afrikanischen Amerikaner und von den beschrieb, Ähnlichkeiten 
zwischen europäischen Immigranten und neuen schwarzen Wanderern zu 
Chicago, der Report Sympathie für die schwarze Gemeinschaft der Stadt
festlegen würde. Gefüllt mit Fotographien, Diagramme und 
Karten, zergliederte der Schwarze in Chicago sorgfältig Chicagos 
rassische Probleme, einschließlich Übergehäuse des schwarzen und 
weißen Antagonismus, Jobs und Verbrechen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que les soldats des ETATS-UNIS 
retournaient de l'Europe dans le lendemain de la Première Guerre 
Mondiale, le logement rare et les travaux ont intensifié des 
antagonismes raciaux et de classe à travers l'Amérique urbaine. 
Les soldats afro-américains, en particulier, sont venus à la 
maison de la guerre comptant apprécier les pleines droites de la 
citoyenneté qu'ils avaient combattu pour défendre outre-mer. 
Au printemps et l'été de 1919, les émeutes meurtrières de 
course ont éclaté dans 22 villes et villes américaines. 
Chicago a éprouvé le plus grave de ces émeutes. 
L'enregistrement le plus détaillé et le plus sobre des causes 
de l'émeute 1919 de course de Chicago est venu rétrospectivement de 
la Commission interracial de Chicago sur des relations inter-raciales.
La Commission a édité un état de sept cent-pages en 1922, le 
nègre Chicago. Charles Johnson -- fonctionnaire urbain de 
ligue de Chicago de a, le secrétaire de direction d'associé de la 
commission intégrée, et l'auteur principal de son état -- espéré 
qu'en décrivant complètement les sentiments et les conditions 
vivants des Américains africains et des similitudes entre les 
immigrés européens et les migrants noirs récents vers Chicago, 
l'état produirait de la sympathie pour la communauté noire de la 
ville. Rempli de photographies, diagrammes, et cartes, le nègre
Chicago a soigneusement disséqué les problèmes raciaux de Chicago, 
y compris le logement fini d'antagonisme noir et blanc, les travaux, 
et le crime.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto os soldados de ESTADOS UNIDOS retornaram 
de Europa no aftermath do world.war.i, a carcaça escassa e os 
trabalhos heightened antagonisms raciais e da classe através de 
América urbana. Os soldados Africano-Americanos, no detalhe, 
vieram para casa da guerra esperando apreciar as direitas cheias do 
citizenship que tinham lutado para defender no ultramar. Na mola
e no verão de 1919, os motins murderous da raça erupted em 22 
cidades e cidades americanas. Chicago experimentou o mais severo
destes motins. O relatório o mais detalhado e o mais sober das 
causas do motim 1919 da raça de Chicago veio retrospectively do 
commission interracial de Chicago em relações de raça. O 
commission publicou um relatório em 1922, negro de sete cem-páginas 
em Chicago. Charles Johnson -- um oficial urbano da liga de 
Chicago, secretária executiva do associado do commission integrado, e
autor principal de seu relatório -- esperado que completamente 
descrevendo os sentiments e as condições vivas de americanos 
africanos e das similaridades entre immigrants europeus e emigrantes 
pretos recentes a Chicago, o relatório gerasse o sympathy para a 
comunidade preta da cidade. Enchido com as fotografias, cartas, 
e os mapas, o negro em Chicago dissected com cuidado problemas raciais
de Chicago, including a carcaça excedente do antagonism preto e 
branco, os trabalhos, e o crime.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre i soldati degli STATI UNITI hanno ritornato
da Europa nel guaime del world.war.i, l'alloggiamento limitato ed i 
lavori hanno intensificato gli antagonismi del codice categoria e 
razziali attraverso l'America urbana. I soldati 
Africano-Americani, in particolare, sono venuto a casa dalla guerra 
pensanti godere i diritti completi della cittadinanza che avevano 
combattuto per difendere oltremare. Nella molla e nell'estate di
1919, i tumulti murderous della corsa hanno scoppiato in 22 
città e città americane. Chicago ha sperimentato il più 
severo di questi tumulti. La segnalazione più dettagliata e 
più sobria delle cause del tumulto 1919 della corsa del Chicago è 
venuto in modo retrospettivo dalla Commissione interracial del Chicago
sui rapporti di corsa. La Commissione ha pubblicato un rapporto 
in 1922, il negro delle sette cento-pagine in Chicago. Charles 
Johnson -- un funzionario urbano della lega del Chicago, la segretaria
esecutiva del socio della commissione integrata e l'autore principale 
del relativo rapporto -- sperato che completamente descrivendo i 
sentimenti e gli stati di vita degli Americani africani e delle 
somiglianze fra gli immigranti europei ed i migranti neri recenti a 
Chicago, il rapporto generi la compassione per la Comunità nera della
città. Riempito di fotografie, tabelle e programmi, il negro in
Chicago ha dissecato con attenzione i problemi razziali del Chicago, 
compreso l'alloggiamento eccessivo di antagonismo nero e bianco, i 
lavori ed il crimine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι οι ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΙ στρατιώτες επέστρεψαν 
από την Ευρώπη στη συνέπεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, η λιγοστή 
κατοικία και οι εργασίες ύψωσαν τους φυλετικούς και ανταγωνισμούς
κλάσης σε ολόκληρη την αστική Αμερική. 
Αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά οι στρατιώτες, ειδικότερα, προήλθαν
κατ' οίκον από τον πόλεμο αναμένοντας να απολαύσουν των πλήρων 
δικαιωμάτων της υπηκοότητας που είχαν παλεψει για να υπερασπίσουν 
στο εξωτερικό. Την άνοιξη και το καλοκαίρι του 1919, οι 
δολοφονικές φυλετικές ταραχές ξέσπασαν σε 22 αμερικανικές 
πόλεις και κωμοπόλεις. Το Σικάγο δοκίμασε τον αυστηρότερο 
αυτών των ταραχών. Η πιό λεπτομερής και νηφάλια υποβολή 
έκθεσης των αιτιών της φυλετικής ταραχής του Σικάγου του 1919 
προήλθε αναδρομικά από τη διαφυλετική Επιτροπή του Σικάγου στις 
φυλετικές σχέσεις. Η Επιτροπή δημοσίευσε μια έκθεση επτά 
εκατό-σελίδων το 1922, ο νέγρος στο Σικάγο. Θ*Θχαρλες 
Johnson -- ένας αστικός ανώτερος υπάλληλος ένωσης του 
Σικάγου, ο συνδυαζόμενος εκτελεστικός γραμματέας της 
ενσωματωμένης επιτροπής, και ο κύριος συντάκτης της έκθεσής του 
-- ήλπισε ότι με λεπτομερώς να περιγράψει τα συναισθήματα και τις
συνθήκες διαβίωσης αφρικανικών Αμερικανών και τις ομοιότητες 
μεταξύ των ευρωπαϊκών μεταναστών και των πρόσφατων μαύρων 
μεταναστών στο Σικάγο, η έκθεση θα παρήγε τη συμπόνοια για τη 
μαύρη κοινότητα της πόλης. Γεμισμένος με τις φωτογραφίες, 
διαγράμματα, και χάρτες, ο νέγρος στο Σικάγο τεμάχισε προσεκτικά
τα φυλετικά προβλήματα του Σικάγου, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του 
μαύρου και άσπρου ανταγωνισμού πέρα από την κατοικία, τις 
εργασίες, και το έγκλημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que los soldados de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
volvieron de Europa en las consecuencias de la Primera Guerra Mundial,
la cubierta escasa y los trabajos aumentaron antagonismos raciales y 
de la clase a través de América urbana. Los soldados 
Africano-Americanos, en detalle, vinieron a casa de la guerra 
esperando gozar de las derechas completas de la ciudadanía que 
habían luchado para defender en ultramar. En el resorte y el 
verano de 1919, los alborotos murderous de la raza entraron en 
erupción en 22 ciudades y ciudades americanas. Chicago 
experimentó el más severo de estos alborotos. El señalar más
detallado y más sobrio de las causas del alboroto 1919 de la raza de 
Chicago vino retrospectivo de la Comisión interracial de Chicago en 
relaciones de raza. La Comisión publicó un informe en 1922, el
negro de siete ciento-paginaciones en Chicago. Charles Johnson 
-- funcionario urbano de la liga de Chicago, la secretaria ejecutiva 
del asociado de la comisión integrada, y el autor principal de su 
informe -- esperado que a conciencia describiendo los sentimientos y 
las condiciones vivas de americanos africanos y de las semejanzas 
entre los inmigrantes europeos y los nómadas negros recientes a 
Chicago, el informe generara la condolencia para la comunidad negra de
la ciudad. Llenado de las fotografías, cartas, y las 
correspondencias, el negro en Chicago disecó cuidadosamente los 
problemas raciales de Chicago, incluyendo la cubierta excesiva del 
antagonismo negro y blanco, trabajos, y crimen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087026</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108576</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-problem-and-family-histories-charles-johnson-analyzes-the-causes-of-the-chicago-race-riot</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
