<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104884</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104884</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087183</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Can Control Our Affairs Pretty Well": Southern Senators Protest Proposed Antilynching Legislation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Können Unsere Angelegenheiten Recht Gut 
Steuern": Südsenatoren Protest Proposed Antilynching 
Legislation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Pouvons Contrôler Nos Affaires Assez Bien" 
: Antilynching Legislation Méridional des Sénateurs Protest 
Proposed</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Podemos Controlar Nossos Casos 
Consideravelmente Bem": Antilynching Legislação Dos Senators 
Protesto Propôr Do sul</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Possiamo Gestire Abbastanza Bene I Nostri 
Affari": Antilynching Legislation Del sud Dei Senatori Protest 
Proposed</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μπορούμε να ελέγξουμε τις υποθέσεις μας αρκετά 
καλά": Οι νότιοι γερουσιαστές διαμαρτύρονται την 
προτεινόμενη νομοθεσία Antilynching</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Podemos Controlar Nuestros Asuntos Bastante 
Bien": Antilynching Legislation De Senadores Protest Proposed 
Meridional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Between 1882 and 1964, nearly five thousand people died from lynching, the majority African-American. The 1890s witnessed the worst period of lynching in U.S. history. Lynchings, often witnessed by large crowds of white onlookers, were the most extreme form of Southern white control over the African-American population, regularly meted out against African Americans who had been falsely charged with crimes but in fact were achieving a level of political or economic autonomy that whites found unacceptable. The history of failed attempts to pass federal antilyching legislation goes back to 1894, when a House bill to set up a committee to investigate lynchings failed. In 1922, the House passed a bill to make lynching a Federal crime, but despite President Warren G. Harding's support, Southern senators filibustered and defeated it. In 1933, President Franklin D. Roosevelt failed to support an antilynching bill proposed by the NAACP, fearing that key Southerners lawmakers would retaliate and interfere with his New Deal agenda. In February 1948, President Harry S. Truman asked Congress for federal antilynching legislation. In the following testimony to a House subcommittee, four Southern Congressmen discussed their reasons for opposing what they deemed federal interference in state judicial responsibilities and defend segregation and the "peaceful relations now existing between white man and Negro" in the South. Congressman Charles E. Bennett (Florida) also offered his historical explanation for lynching. None of the bills under consideration by the subcommittee passed.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zwischen 1882 und 1964 fast fünf tausend Leute 
gestorben am Lynchen, die Majorität Afrikanisch-Amerikanisch. 
Das 1890s zeugte die falschste Periode des Lynchens in der 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte. Lynchings, häufig gezeugt von 
den großen Massen der weißen Zuschauer, waren das extremste Formular
der südlichen weißen Steuerung über der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen 
Bevölkerung, regelmäßig ausgeteilt heraus gegen afrikanische 
Amerikaner, die falsch mit Verbrechen aufgeladen worden waren, aber 
tatsächlich erzielten eine Stufe der politischen oder ökonomischen 
Autonomie, daß Weiß nicht annehmbar fand. Die Geschichte der 
verlassenen Versuche, antilyching Bundesgesetzgebung zu führen geht 
zurück zu 1894, als eine Hausrechnung zu aufstellen ein Ausschuß, 
zum von von lynchings nachzuforschen ausfiel. 1922 
verabschiedete das Haus einen Gesetz, um das Lynchen eines 
Bundesverbrechens, aber trotz Präsident Warren G. Hardings des 
Supports, die südlichen obstruierten Senatoren zu bilden und besiegte
ihn. 1933 konnte Präsident Franklin D. Roosevelt eine 
antilynching Rechnung unterstützen, die durch das NAACP vorgeschlagen
wurde nicht und fürchtete, daß Schlüsselsoutherners Gesetzgeber 
seine Tagesordnung des neuen Abkommens sich revanchieren und 
behinderen würden. Im Februar 1948, bat Präsident Harry S. 
Truman Kongreß um antilynching Bundesgesetzgebung. Im folgenden
Zeugnis zu einer Hausunterausschuß, behandelten vier südliche 
Kongreßabgeordnete ihre Gründe für das Entgegensetzen, was sie 
Bundesstörung in den Zustandgerichtsverantwortlichkeiten meinten und 
Abtrennung und die "ruhigen Relationen, die jetzt zwischen weißem 
Mann und Schwarzen" im Süden existieren verteidigen. 
Kongreßabgeordnetes Charles E. Bennett (Florida) gab auch seine
historische Erklärung für das Lynchen. Keine der Rechnungen in
Erwägung durch die Unterausschuß überschritten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entre 1882 et 1964, presque cinq mille personnes 
mortes de lyncher, l'Afro-Américain de majorité. Le 1890s était 
témoin de la plus mauvaise période de lyncher dans l'histoire des 
ETATS-UNIS. Lynchings, souvent été témoin par de grandes 
foules des spectateurs blancs, étaient la forme la plus extrême du 
contrôle blanc méridional de la population afro-américaine, 
régulièrement distribuée dehors contre les Américains africains 
qui avaient été faussement chargés des crimes mais en fait 
réalisaient un niveau d'autonomie politique ou économique que les 
blancs ont trouvé inacceptable. L'histoire des tentatives 
échouées de passer la législation antilyching fédérale va de 
nouveau à 1894, quand une facture de Chambre pour installer un 
comité pour étudier des lynchings a échoué. En 1922, la 
Chambre a passé une facture pour faire lyncher un crime fédéral, 
mais en dépit de support du Président Warren G. Harding's, 
sénateurs méridionaux flibustés et l'a défaite. En 1933, le 
Président Franklin D. Roosevelt n'a pas supporté une facture 
antilynching proposée par le NAACP, craignant que les législateurs 
principaux de Habitants du sud exercent des représailles et gêneraient 
son ordre du jour de nouvelle affaire. En février 1948, le 
Président Harry S. Truman a demandé au congrès la législation 
antilynching fédérale. Dans le témoignage suivant à un 
sous-comité de Chambre, quatre membres du Congrès méridionaux ont 
discuté leurs raisons de s'opposer à ce qu'ils ont considéré 
l'interférence fédérale dans des responsabilités juridiques 
d'état et défendent la ségrégation et "les relations paisibles 
existant maintenant entre l'homme et le nègre blancs" dans les 
Sud. Le membre du Congrès Charles E. Bennett (la 
Floride) a également offert son explication historique pour lyncher. 
Aucune des factures à l'étude par le sous-comité n'a passé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entre 1882 e 1964, quase cinco mil povos morridos 
de lynching, maioria Africano-Americana. O 1890s testemunhou o 
período o mais mau de lynching no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Lynchings, testemunhado frequentemente por multidões grandes 
dos espectadores brancos, era o formulário o mais extremo do controle
branco do sul sobre a população Africano-Americana, meted 
regularmente para fora de encontro aos americanos africanos que tinham
sido carregados falsa com os crimes mas no fato conseguiam um nível 
da autonomia política ou econômica que os brancos encontraram 
inaceitável. O history de tentativas falhadas de passar a 
legislação antilyching federal vai para trás a 1894, quando uma 
conta da casa ao jogo acima um comitê para investigar lynchings 
falhou. Em 1922, a casa passou uma conta para fazer lynching um 
crime federal, mas apesar da sustentação do presidente Warren G. 
Harding, senators do sul filibustered e derrotou-a. Em 1933, o 
presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt não suportou uma conta antilynching 
proposta pelo NAACP, temendo que os lawmakers chaves de Southerners 
retaliate e interfeririam com sua agenda do negócio novo. Em 
fevereiro 1948, o presidente Harry S. Truman pediu a congress 
legislação antilynching federal. No seguinte testimony a uma 
subcomissão da casa, quatro congressistas do sul discutiram suas 
razões para opôr-se o que julgaram a interferência federal em 
responsabilidades judiciais do estado e defendem o segregation e "as 
relações calmas que existem agora entre o homem e o negro brancos" 
no sul. O congressista Charles E. Bennett (Florida) ofereceu 
também sua explanação histórica para lynching. Nenhumas das 
contas sob a consideração pela subcomissão passaram.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fra 1882 e 1964, quasi cinque mila genti morte dal
lynching, la maggioranza Africano-Americana. Il 1890s ha 
testimoniato il periodo più difettoso di lynching nella storia degli 
STATI UNITI. Lynchings, testimoniato spesso dalle grandi folle 
dei onlookers bianchi, era la forma più estrema di controllo bianco 
del sud sopra la popolazione Africano-Americana, meted regolarmente 
fuori contro gli Americani africani che erano stati caricati 
erroneamente dei crimini ma in effetti stava realizzando un livello di
autonomia politica o economica che i bianchi hanno trovato 
inaccettabile. La storia dei tentativi guastati di passare la 
legislazione antilyching federale va di nuovo a 1894, quando una 
fattura della Camera per installare un comitato per studiare i 
lynchings è venuto a mancare. In 1922, la Camera ha passato una
fattura per fare lynching un crimine federale, ma malgrado il supporto
del presidente Warren G. Harding, senatori del sud filibustered e la 
ha sconfitta. In 1933, il presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt non 
è riuscito a sostenere una fattura antilynching proposta dal NAACP, 
temente che i legislatori chiave di Southerners retaliate ed 
interferissero con il suo ordine del giorno di nuovo affare. Nel
mese di febbraio del 1948, il presidente Harry S. Truman ha chiesto al
congresso legislazione antilynching federale. Nella seguente 
testimonianza ad un sottocomitato della Camera, quattro membri del 
Congresso del sud hanno discusso i loro motivi per opporre che cosa 
hanno ritenuto l'interferenza federale dentro dichiarano le 
responsabilità giudiziarie e difendono la segregazione e "i rapporti 
pacifici ora che esistono fra l'uomo ed il negro bianchi" nel sud. 
Il membro del Congresso Charles E. Bennett (Florida) egualmente 
ha offerto la sua spiegazione storica per lynching. Nessun delle
fatture allo studio dal sottocomitato hanno passato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταξύ 1882 και 1964, σχεδόν πέντε χιλιάες 
άνθρωποι πέθαναν από το λυντσάρισμα, η πλειοψηφία 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός. Το 1890s βεβαίωσε τη χειρότερη 
περίοδο λυντσαρίσματος στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉ ιστορία. Τα 
λυντσαρίσματα, που βεβαιώθηκαν συχνά από τα μεγάλα πλήθη των 
λευκών θεατών, ήταν η πιό ακραία μορφή του νότιου άσπρου 
ελέγχου του αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού πληθυσμού, τακτικά έξω 
ενάντια σε αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς που ήταν χρεωμένων ψευδώς με
τα εγκλήματα αλλά στην πραγματικότητα επετύγχαναν ένα επίπεδο 
πολιτικής ή οικονομικής αυτονομίας ότι λευκά που βρέθηκαν 
απαράδεκτα. Η ιστορία των αποτυχημένων προσπαθειών να 
περαστεί η ομοσπονδιακή antilyching νομοθεσία επιστρέφει σε 
1894, όταν απέτυχε ένας λογαριασμός σπιτιών για να 
συνιστήχτει μια επιτροπή για να ερευνήσει τα λυντσαρίσματα. 
Το 1922, η Βουλή ψήφισε ένα νομοσχέδιο για να κάνει το 
λυντσάρισμα ενός ομοσπονδιακού εγκλήματος, αλλά παρά την 
υποστήριξη Προέδρου Warren G. Harding's, οι νότιοι 
γερουσιαστές και αυτό νίκησαν. Το 1933, ο Πρόεδρος 
Franklin D. Roosevelt απέτυχε να υποστηρίξει έναν 
antilynching λογαριασμό που προτάθηκε από το NAACP, φοσμένος
ότι οι βασικοί νομοθέτες νοτίων θα εκδικούνταν και θα 
παρεμπόδιζαν τη νέα ημερήσια διάταξη διαπραγμάτευσής του. 
Τον Φεβρουάριο του 1948, ο Πρόεδρος Harry S. 
Truman ρώτησε το συνέδριο για την ομοσπονδιακή antilynching 
νομοθεσία. Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση σε μια υποεπιτροπή 
σπιτιών, τέσσερα νότια μέλη του Κογκρέσσου συζήτησαν τους 
λόγους τους για τι έκριναν την ομοσπονδιακή παρέμβαση στις 
κρατικές δικαστικές ευθύνες και υπερασπίζουν το διαχωρισμό και 
τις "ειρηνικές σχέσεις που υπάρχουν τώρα μεταξύ του λευκών 
ατόμου και του νέγρου" στο νότο. Congressman Charles 
Ε. Bennett (Φλώριδα) επίσης πρόσφερε την ιστορική εξήγησή του
για το λυντσάρισμα. Κανένας από τους λογαριασμούς υπό 
εξέταση από την υποεπιτροπή δεν πέρασε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entre 1882 y 1964, casi cinco mil personas muertas
de lynching, la mayoría Africano-Americana. El 1890s atestiguó
el período peor de lynching en la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Lynchings, atestiguado a menudo por las muchedumbres grandes de 
los onlookers blancos, era la forma más extrema de control blanco 
meridional sobre la población Africano-Americana, meted regularmente 
hacia fuera contra los americanos africanos que habían sido cargados 
falso con crímenes pero en hecho alcanzaban un nivel de la autonomía
política o económica que los blancos encontraron inaceptable. 
La historia de tentativas falladas de aprobar la legislación 
antilyching federal va de nuevo a 1894, cuando una cuenta de la casa 
al instalar un comité para investigar lynchings falló. En 
1922, la casa aprobó una cuenta para hacer lynching un crimen 
federal, pero a pesar de la ayuda de presidente Warren G. Harding, 
senadores meridionales filibustered y la derrotó. En 1933, 
presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt no pudo utilizar una cuenta 
antilynching propuesta por el NAACP, temiendo que los legisladores 
dominantes de Southerners tomarían represalias e interferirían con 
su agenda del nuevo reparto. En febrero de 1948, presidente 
Harry S. Truman pidió a congreso legislación antilynching federal. 
En el testimonio siguiente a un subcomité de la casa, cuatro 
miembros del Congreso meridionales discutieron sus razones de oponer 
lo que juzgaban interferencia federal en responsabilidades judiciales 
del estado y defienden la segregación y las "relaciones pacíficas 
ahora que existían entre el hombre y el negro blancos" en el sur. 
El miembro del Congreso Charles E. Bennett (la Florida) también
ofreció su explicación histórica para lynching. Ningunas de 
las cuentas bajo consideración del subcomité pasaron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087183</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104884</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-can-control-our-affairs-pretty-well-southern-senators-protest-proposed-antilynching-legislation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
