<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108051</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108051</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212378</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Survival of the Fittest Microbes: Examining the Conditions of One River and the Microbes that Thrive There</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überleben der passendsten Mikroben: Die 
Zustände von einem Fluß und von Mikroben überprüfen, die dort 
vorwärtskommen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Survie des microbes les plus convenables : 
Examinant les conditions d'un fleuve et des microbes qui 
prospèrent là</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sobrevivência dos micróbios os mais aptos: 
Examinando as condições de um rio e dos micróbios que 
prosperam lá</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sopravvivenza dei microbi più adatti: 
Esaminando gli stati di un fiume e dei microbi che prosperano 
là</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιβίωση των καταλληλότερων μικροβίων: 
Εξετάζοντας τους όρους ενός ποταμού και των μικροβίων που 
αναπτύσσονται εκεί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Supervivencia de los microbios más aptos: 
Examinando las condiciones de un río y de los microbios que 
prosperan allí</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson, created for grades 6 - 12, students learn about the harsh conditions of Spain's Rio Tinto River and research the microbes that nonetheless manage to thrive there. They then synthesize their knowledge by creating a reality television program set in the Rio Tinto in which the microbes are the "contestants." The lesson includes an article about the Rio Tinto with accompanying questions, a detailed classroom activity, vocabulary list, discussion questions, extension activities, interdisciplinary connections, and related academic content standards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion erstellt für Grade 6 - 12, 
erlernen Kursteilnehmer über die rauhen Zustände von Rio Tinto 
Spaniens Fluß und erforschen die Mikroben, die nichtsdestoweniger 
handhaben, dort vorwärtszukommen. Sie synthetisieren dann ihr 
Wissen, indem sie ein Wirklichkeit Fernsehenprogramm erstellen, das in
das Rio Tinto eingestellt wird, in dem die Mikroben sind die 
"Kandidaten." Die Lektion schließt einen Artikel über das Rio 
Tinto mit dem Begleiten von von Fragen, von von ausführlicher 
Klassenzimmeraktivität, von von Wortschatzliste, von von Diskussion 
Fragen, von von Extension Aktivitäten, von von interdisziplinären 
Anschlüssen und von von in Verbindung stehenden akademischen 
zufriedenen Standards ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon, créée pour les catégories 6 
- 12, les étudiants se renseignent sur les conditions durs du fleuve 
de Rio Tinto de l'Espagne et recherchent les microbes qui néanmoins 
parviennent à prospérer là. Ils synthétisent alors leur 
connaissance en créant une émission télévisée de réalité 
réglée à Rio Tinto dans lequel les microbes sont les "contestants."
La leçon inclut un article concernant Rio Tinto avec 
accompagner des questions, une activité détaillée de salle de 
classe, une liste de vocabulaire, des questions de discussion, des 
activités d'extension, les connexions interdisciplinaires, et les 
normes relatives de contenu d'universitaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição, criada para as classes 6 - 12, os 
estudantes aprendem sobre as condições ásperas do rio de Rio Tinto 
de Spain e pesquisam os micróbios que nonetheless controlam prosperar
lá. Synthesize então seu conhecimento criando um programa da 
televisão da realidade ajustado no Rio Tinto em que os micróbios 
são os "contestants." A lição inclui um artigo sobre o Rio 
Tinto com acompanhar perguntas, uma atividade detalhada da sala de 
aula, uma lista do vocabulário, umas perguntas da discussão, umas 
atividades da extensão, conexões interdisciplinary, e padrões 
satisfeitos academic relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione, creata per i gradi 6 - 12, gli 
allievi imparano circa gli stati duri del fiume de Rio Tinto della 
Spagna e ricercano i microbi che ciò nonostante riescono a prosperare
là. Allora sintetizzano la loro conoscenza creando un programma
televisivo di realtà regolato a Rio Tinto in cui i microbi sono "i 
contestants." La lezione include un articolo su Rio Tinto con 
accompagnare le domande, un'attività dettagliata dell'aula, una lista
di vocabolario, lle domande di discussione, lle attività di 
estensione, i collegamenti interdisciplinari e gli standard 
soddisfatti accademici relativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα, που δημιουργείται για τους βαθμούς 
6 - 12, οι σπουδαστές μαθαίνουν για τους σκληρούς όρους του 
ποταμού του Ρίο Tinto της Ισπανίας και ερευνούν τα μικρόβια 
που εν τούτοις κατορθώνουν να αναπτυχτούν εκεί. Συνθέτουν 
έπειτα τη γνώση τους με τη δημιουργία ενός τηλεοπτικού 
προγράμματος πραγματικότητας που τίθεται στο Ρίο Tinto στο 
οποίο τα μικρόβια είναι οι "αγωνιζόμενοι." Το μάθημα 
περιλαμβάνει ένα άρθρο για το Ρίο Tinto με τη συνοδεία των 
ερωτήσεων, μιας λεπτομερούς δραστηριότητας τάξεων, ενός 
καταλόγου λεξιλογίου, των ερωτήσεων συζήτησης, των δραστηριοτήτων
επέκτασης, των διεπιστημονικών συνδέσεων, και των σχετικών 
ακαδημαϊκών ικανοποιημένων προτύπων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección, creada para los grados 6 - 12, 
los estudiantes aprenden sobre las condiciones ásperas del río de 
Río Tinto de España e investigan los microbios que no obstante 
manejan prosperar allí. Entonces sintetizan su conocimiento 
creando un programa de la televisión de la realidad fijado en la Río
Tinto en la cual los microbios son los "contestants." La 
lección incluye un artículo acerca de la Río Tinto con el 
acompañamiento de preguntas, de una actividad detallada de la sala de
clase, de una lista del vocabulario, de preguntas de la discusión, de
actividades de la extensión, de conexiones interdisciplinarias, y de 
estándares contentos académicos relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GEORGIA SCURLETIS
FN:GEORGIA SCURLETIS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JAVAID KHAN
FN:JAVAID KHAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NEW YORK TIMES LEARNING NETWORK
FN:NEW YORK TIMES LEARNING NETWORK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212378</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108051</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/survival-of-the-fittest-microbes-examining-the-conditions-of-one-river-and-the-microbes-that-thrive-there</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
