<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/295310384</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>295310384</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200558</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Atmospheric Pressure and Wind Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Druck-und Wind-Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animations de pression atmosphérique et de vent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animations da pressão atmosférica e do vento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazioni del vento e di pressione atmosferica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ατμοσφαιρικές ζωτικότητες πίεσης και αέρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animaciones de la presión atmosférica y del 
viento</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Flash and QuickTime animations that illustrate diurnal changes in wind patterns along coasts due to unequal heating of the land and water, the Coriolis Effect on the Earth's surface and in the context of everyday weather patterns, and global circulation, temperature, and wind patterns. The animations can be paused and rewound to stress important points. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Situationsmerkmale Blitz- und 
QuickTimeanimationen, die tägliche Änderungen in den Windmustern 
entlang den Küsten wegen der ungleichen Heizung des Landes 
veranschaulichen und wässern, der Coriolis Effekt auf die Oberfläche
der Masse und im Kontext der täglichen Wettermuster und globale 
Zirkulation, Temperatur und Windmuster. Die Animationen können 
pausiert werden und gerückspult werden, um wichtige Punkte zu 
betonen. Diese Betriebsmittel sind für Gebrauch in den 
Vorträgen, in den Labors oder in anderen unterrichtenden Aktivitäten
verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces animations d'instantané et de QuickTime de 
dispositifs de site qui illustrent les changements journaliers des 
configurations de vent le long des côtes dues au chauffage inégal de
la terre et arrosent, l'effet de Coriolis sur la surface de la terre 
et dans le contexte de journalier survivent à à des 
configurations, et circulation, température, et des configurations 
globales de vent. Les animations peuvent être faites une pause 
et rebobinées pour soumettre à une contrainte les points importants.
Ces ressources conviennent pour l'usage dans les conférences, 
les laboratoires, ou d'autres activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estes animations do flash e do QuickTime das 
características de local que ilustram mudanças diurnal em testes 
padrões do vento ao longo das costas  devido ao heating desigual da 
terra e as molham, o efeito de Coriolis na superfície da terra e no 
contexto de testes padrões diários do tempo, e circulação, 
temperatura, e testes padrões globais do vento. Os animations 
podem ser pausados e rebobinado para forçar pontos importantes. 
Estes recursos são apropriados para o uso nos lectures, nos 
laboratórios, ou em outras atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Queste animazioni dell'istantaneo e del QuickTime 
delle caratteristiche di luogo che illustrano i cambiamenti 
giornalieri nei modelli del vento lungo i litorali dovuto il heating 
disuguale della terra ed innaffiano, l'effetto di Coriolis sulla 
superficie della terra e nel contesto dei modelli giornalieri del 
tempo e circolazione, temperatura e modelli globali del vento. 
Le animazioni possono essere fatte una pausa e riavvolte per 
sollecitare i punti importanti. Queste risorse sono adatte ad 
uso nelle conferenze, in laboratori, o in altre attività 
d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τη λάμψη και τις 
ζωτικότητες QuickTime που επεξηγούν τις ημερήσιες αλλαγές στα 
πρότυπα αέρα κατά μήκος των ακτών λόγω στο άνισο ζέσταμα του 
εδάφους και του ύδατος, την επίδραση Coriolis στη γήινη 
επιφάνεια και στα πλαίσια των καθημερινών καιρικών προτύπων, και 
τη σφαιρική κυκλοφορία, τη θερμοκρασία, και τα πρότυπα αέρα. 
Οι ζωτικότητες μπορούν να σταματηθούν και rewound για να 
τονίζουν τα σημαντικά σημεία. Αυτά τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για τη χρήση στις διαλέξεις, τα 
εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estas animaciones del flash y de QuickTime de las 
características de sitio que ilustran cambios diurnales en modelos 
del viento a lo largo de las costas  debido a la calefacción desigual
de la pista y riegan, el efecto de Coriolis sobre la superficie de la 
tierra y en el contexto de los modelos diarios del tiempo, y 
circulación, temperatura, y modelos globales del viento. Las 
animaciones se pueden detener brevemente y rebobinar para tensionar 
puntas importantes. Estos recursos son convenientes para el uso 
en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200558</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>295310384</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/atmospheric-pressure-and-wind-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
