<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106690</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106690</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087215</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Welcoming Home a Hero: Calvin Coolidge and Charles Lindbergh Speak</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Haus begrüßen ein Held: Calvin Coolidge und
Charles Lindbergh sprechen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faisant bon accueil à la maison un héros : 
Calvin Coolidge et Charles Lindbergh parlent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dando boas-vindas à HOME um herói: Calvin 
Coolidge e Charles Lindbergh falam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Accogliendo favorevolmente sede un hero: 
Calvin Coolidge e Charles Lindbergh parlano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οικία" υποδοχής ένας ήρωας: Calvin 
Coolidge και Charles Lindbergh Speak</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dando la bienvenida al hogar un héroe: 
Calvin Coolidge y Charles Lindbergh hablan</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When 25-year-old Charles A. Lindbergh set down his monoplane,  The Spirit of St. Louis , at Le Bourget Aerodrome in Paris on May 21, 1927, he instantly became the leading hero of a decade of American heroes and celebrities. Lindbergh had not expected any welcome in France, but word of his arrival spread through Paris, and twenty-five thousand people surrounded the plane even before he stopped taxiing. The frenzy continued when Lindbergh returned to the United States on June 11, 1927, where President Calvin Coolidge and his wife welcomed him at a Washington Monument stand specially built for the occasion. Coolidge's welcome and Lindbergh's brief response were broadcast nationwide. Coolidge lavished praise on the aviator in a very serious voice, and Lindbergh responded humorously. Beneath the joking about a battleship being sent for him, however, was perhaps a serious concern about becoming a prisoner of his sudden fame.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als 25-year-old Charles A. Lindbergh seinen 
Eindecker aufzeichnete, der Geist von St. Louis, bei Le Bourget 
Aerodrome in Paris an Mai 21, 1927, wurde er sofort der führende Held
einer Dekade der amerikanischen Helder und der Berühmtheiten. 
Lindbergh hatte kein Willkommen in Frankreich, aber Wort seiner 
Ankunft erwartet, die durch Paris verbritten wurde, und 
fünfundzwanzig tausend Leute umgaben die Fläche, sogar bevor er 
stoppte mit einem Taxi zu fahren. Die Raserei fuhr fort, als 
Lindbergh in die Vereinigten Staaten an Juni 11, 1927 zurückging, wo 
Präsident Calvin Coolidge und seine Frau ihn auf einem Washington 
Denkmalstand begrüßte, der besonders für die Gelegenheit aufgebaut 
wurde. Willkommen Coolidges und Lindberghs kurze Antwort waren 
Sendung im ganzen Land. Coolidge reagierte lavished Lob auf dem 
Flieger in einer sehr ernsten Stimme und Lindbergh humorvoll. 
Unter dem Scherzen über ein Linienschiff, das für ihn jedoch 
möglicherweise war ein gesendet wurde, ernstes Interesse über das 
Stehen eines Gefangenen seines plötzlichen Ruhmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand 25-year-old Charles A. Lindbergh a établi 
son monoplan, l'esprit de St Louis, chez Le Bourget Aerodrome à Paris
21 mai 1927, il est immédiatement devenu le principal héros d'une 
décennie des héros américains et des célébrités. Lindbergh
ne s'était attendu aucune bienvenue en France, mais à mot de son 
arrivée écartée par Paris, et vingt-cinq mille personnes ont 
entouré l'avion même avant qu'il a cessé de rouler au sol. La
frénésie a continué quand Lindbergh est revenu aux Etats-Unis juin 
11, 1927, où le Président Calvin Coolidge et son épouse lui a 
souhaité la bienvenue à un stand de monument de Washington 
particulièrement établi pour l'occasion. La bienvenue de 
Coolidge et réponse de Lindbergh la brève étaient émission dans 
tout le pays. Par Coolidge l'éloge somptueuse Lindbergh sur 
l'aviateur dans une voix très sérieuse, et a répondu plein 
d'humour. Sous la plaisanterie au sujet d'un cuirassé étant 
envoyé pour lui, cependant, était peut-être une préoccupation 
profonde concernant aller bien à un prisonnier de sa renommée 
soudaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando 25-year-old Charles A. Lindbergh 
estabeleceu seu monoplane, o espírito de St. Louis, em Le Bourget 
Aeródromo em Paris maio em 21, 1927, transformou-se imediatamente o 
herói principal de uma década de heróis americanos e de 
celebridades. Lindbergh não tinha esperado nenhuma boa vinda em
France, mas palavra de sua chegada espalhada através de Paris, e 
twenty-five mil povos cercaram o plano mesmo antes que parou de 
taxiing. O frenzy continuou quando Lindbergh retornou aos 
estados unidos junho em 11, 1927, onde o presidente Calvin Coolidge e 
sua esposa lhe deu boas-vindas em um carrinho do monumento de 
Washington construído especialmente para a ocasião. A boa 
vinda de Coolidge e a resposta breve de Lindbergh eram transmissão 
por todo o país. Coolidge o elogio dado Lindbergh no aviador em
uma voz muito séria, e respondeu humorously. Abaixo de gracejar
sobre um cruzador de batalha que está sendo emitido para ele, 
entretanto, era talvez um interesse sério sobre assentar bem em um 
prisioneiro de sua fama repentina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando 25-year-old Charles A. Lindbergh ha 
stabilito il suo monoplane, lo spirito di St. Louis, a Le Bourget 
Aerodrome a Parigi maggio su 21, 1927, immediatamente è diventato il 
hero principale di una decade degli eroi e dei celebrities 
americani. Lindbergh non aveva previsto alcun benvenuto in 
Francia, ma la parola del suo arrivo sparso attraverso Parigi e 
venticinque mila genti hanno circondato l'aereo persino prima che 
smettesse di rullare. Il frenzy è continuato quando Lindbergh 
restituito al unito Dichiara il 11 giugno 1927, dove il 
presidente Calvin Coolidge e la sua moglie lo ha accolto 
favorevolmente ad un basamento del monumento de Washington sviluppato 
specialmente per l'occasione. Il benvenuto del Coolidge e 
risposta del Lindbergh la breve erano radiodiffusione in tutta la 
nazione. Coolidge ha prodigato nell'elogio sul aviator in una 
voce molto seria e Lindbergh ha risposto divertente. Sotto 
scherzare circa un battleship che è trasmesso per lui, tuttavia, era 
forse una preoccupazione seria circa stare bene ad un prigioniero 
della sua fama improvvisa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν 25-χρονών Charles A. Lindbergh 
καθόρισε το μονοπλάνο του, το πνεύμα του ST Louis, στο 
αεροδρόμιο Le Bourget στο Παρίσι σε Μάιος 21 
..1927, έγινε αμέσως ο κύριος ήρωας μιας δεκαετίας 
αμερικανικών ηρώων και προσωπικοτήτων. Το Lindbergh δεν 
είχε αναμείνει οποιαδήποτε υποδοχή στη Γαλλία, αλλά η λέξη της 
άφιξής του διέδωσε μέσω του Παρισιού, και εικοσι πέντε χιλιάες 
άνθρωποι περιέβαλαν το αεροπλάνο ακόμη και προτού να σταματήσει.
Ο παροξυσμός συνεχίστηκε όταν επέστρεψε Lindbergh στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες στις 11 Ιουνίου ..1927, όπου ο Πρόεδρος 
Calvin Coolidge και η σύζυγός του τον καλωσόρισαν σε μια 
στάση μνημείων της Ουάσιγκτον ειδικά χτίζω για την περίπτωση. 
Η υποδοχή του Coolidge και η συνοπτική απάντηση 
Lindbergh ήταν ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση σε εθνικό επίπεδο. 
Το Coolidge κατασπατάλησε τον έπαινο στον αεροπόρο σε μια 
πολύ σοβαρή φωνή, και Lindbergh αποκρίθηκε χιουμοριστικά. 
Κάτω από να αστειευτεί για ένα θωρηκτό που στέλνεται για 
τον, εντούτοις, ήταν ίσως μια σοβαρή ανησυχία για να γίνει 
φυλακισμένος της ξαφνικής φήμης του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando 25-year-old Charles A. Lindbergh 
estableció su monoplano, el alcohol de St. Louis, en Le Bourget 
Aerodrome en París 21 de mayo de 1927, él hizo inmediatamente el 
héroe principal de una década de héroes americanos y de 
celebridades. Lindbergh no contaba con ninguna recepción en 
Francia, sino palabra de su llegada separada a través de París, y 
veinticinco mil personas rodearon el plano incluso antes de que él 
paró el carretear. El frenesí continuó cuando Lindbergh 
volvió a los Estados Unidos 11 de junio de 1927, donde presidente 
Calvin Coolidge y su esposa le dio la bienvenida en un soporte del 
monumento de Washington construido especialmente para la ocasión. 
La recepción de Coolidge y la respuesta abreviada de Lindbergh 
eran difusión por toda la nación. Coolidge la alabanza 
prodigada Lindbergh en el aviador en una voz muy seria, y respondió 
chistoso. Debajo de bromear sobre un acorazado que era enviado 
para él, sin embargo, estaba quizás una preocupación seria por 
sentir bien a un preso de su fama repentina.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087215</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106690</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/welcoming-home-a-hero-calvin-coolidge-and-charles-lindbergh-speak</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
