<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108213</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108213</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086364</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Jefferson Davis as an unprotected female!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Jefferson Davis als ungeschützte Frau!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Jefferson Davis en tant que femelle non 
protégée!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Jefferson Davis como uma fêmea desprotegida!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Jefferson Davis come femmina non protetta!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Jefferson Νταίηβις ως μη προστατευμένο θηλυκό!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Jefferson Davis como hembra desprotegida!"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Union troops captured the former president of the Confederacy, Jefferson Davis, in May 1865. Whether Davis, who had eluded arrest for over a month, was actually wearing his wife's dress when he was caught is open to question. Nonetheless, the depiction of the captured Davis in woman's clothes was featured in many illustrations and cartoons in the northern press. These images&amp;#8212like earlier pictures of southern women sending their men to war and rioting&amp;#8212questioned the South's claims of courage and chivalry by showing its men and women reversing traditional sex roles.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anschlußtruppen erfaßten den ehemaligen Präsidenten der
Konföderation, Jefferson Davis, im Mai 1865. Ob Davis, das 
Anhalten für über einen Monat ausgewichen hatte, wirklich Kleid 
seiner Frau trug, als er abgefangen wurde, ist fraglich. 
Nichtsdestoweniger wurde die Beschreibung des erfaßten Davis in
der Kleidung der Frau in vielen Abbildungen und in Karikaturen in der 
Nordpresse gekennzeichnet. Diese images&amp;#8212like früh 
Abbildungen der südlichen Frauen, die ihre Männer zum Krieg und zu 
rioting&amp;#8212questioned die Südansprüche des Mutes und Chivalry 
durch das Zeigen seiner Männer und Frauen aufheben traditionelle 
Geschlechtrollen schicken.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les troupes des syndicats ont capturé l'ancien président
de la confédération, Jefferson Davis, en mai 1865. Si Davis, 
qui avait éludé l'arrestation pendant plus d'un mois, portait 
réellement la robe de son épouse quand il a été attrapé est 
discutable. Néanmoins, la description du Davis capturé chez 
les vêtements de la femme a été décrite dans beaucoup 
d'illustrations et dessins animés dans la presse nordique. Ces 
d'images&amp;#8212like images plus tôt des femmes méridionales envoyant 
leurs hommes à la guerre et au rioting&amp;#8212questioned les 
réclamations des Sud du courage et de la chevalerie en 
montrant ses hommes et femmes renversant des rôles traditionnels de 
sexe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As tropas da união capturaram o presidente anterior do 
confederacy, Jefferson Davis, em maio 1865. Se Davis, que tinha 
iludido a apreensão por sobre um mês, desgastava realmente o vestido
da sua esposa quando foi travado está aberto à pergunta. 
Nonetheless, o depiction do Davis capturado na roupa da mulher 
foi caracterizado em muitos ilustrações e cartoons na imprensa do 
norte. Estes de images&amp;#8212like retratos mais cedo das mulheres
do sul que emitem seus homens à guerra e ao rioting&amp;#8212questioned 
as reivindicações sul da coragem e chivalry mostrando seus homens e 
mulheres que invertem papéis tradicionais do sexo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le truppe del sindacato hanno bloccato l'ex presidente del
confederacy, Jefferson Davis, nel mese di maggio 1865. Se Davis,
che aveva eluso l'arresto per sopra un mese, realmente stava portando 
il vestito della sua moglie quando è stato interferito è 
discutibile. Ciò nonostante, il depiction del Davis bloccato in
vestiti della donna è stato descritto in molti illustrazioni e 
fumetti nella pressa nordica. Queste di images&amp;#8212like 
immagini più presto delle donne del sud che trasmettono i loro uomini
alla guerra ed a rioting&amp;#8212questioned i reclami del sud di coraggio
e chivalry mostrando i relativi uomini e donne che invertono i ruoli 
tradizionali del sesso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα στρατεύματα ένωσης συνέλαβαν τον προηγούμενο 
Πρόεδρο της συνομοσπονδίας, Jefferson Νταίηβις, σε Μάιος 
1865, Εάν ο Νταίηβις, που είχε αποφύγει τη σύλληψη για 
κατά τη διάρκεια ενός μήνα, φορούσε πραγματικά το φόρεμα της 
συζύγου του όταν πιάστηκε είναι συζητήσιμος. Εν τούτοις, η
απεικόνιση του συλλήφθείτυ Νταίηβις στα ενδύματα της γυναίκας 
χαρακτηρίστηκε σε πολλά απεικονίσεις και κινούμενα σχέδια στο 
βόρειο Τύπο. Αυτές οι προηγούμενες εικόνες 
images&amp;#8212like των νότιων γυναικών που στέλνουν τους άνδρες 
τους στον πόλεμο και rioting&amp;#8212questioned οι νότιες αξιώσεις 
του θάρρους και της ιπποσύνης με την εμφάνιση ανδρών του και των 
γυναικών που αντιστρέφουν τους παραδοσιακούς ρόλους φύλων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las tropas de la unión capturaron a presidente anterior 
del confederacy, Jefferson Davis, en mayo de 1865. Si Davis, que
había eludido la detención por sobre un mes, desgastaba realmente la
alineada de su esposa cuando lo cogieron es discutible. No 
obstante, la pintura del Davis capturado en las ropas de la mujer fue 
ofrecida en muchas ilustraciones e historietas en la prensa norteña. 
Estos de images&amp;#8212like cuadros anterior de las mujeres 
meridionales que envían sus hombres a la guerra y a 
rioting&amp;#8212questioned las demandas del sur del valor y a código de 
caballería mostrando a sus hombres y mujeres que invierten papeles 
tradicionales del sexo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086364</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108213</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/jefferson-davis-as-an-unprotected-female</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
