<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087150</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Un Colombian con Sandino": U.S. Intervention in Central America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Un Kolumbianerbetrüger Sandino": 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Intervention in Mittelamerika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"escroc Sandino de Colombien d'un" : 
Intervention des ETATS-UNIS en Amérique Centrale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">do "con Sandino do colombian Un": 
Intervenção de ESTADOS UNIDOS em América Central</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"con Sandino del colombian di ONU": 
Intervento degli STATI UNITI in America Centrale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κολομβιανό con Sandino των Η.Ε": ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ
Επέμβαση στην Κεντρική Αμερική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"con Sandino del colombian del Un": 
Intervención de ESTADOS UNIDOS en America Central</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By the early 20th century, U.S. companies dominated the economies of the Central American republics, including Nicaragua, and controlled most of the banana production, railroads, port facilities, mines, and banking institutions. The United States intervened in Nicaragua repeatedly to protect U.S. economic interests. In 1912 U.S. marines landed once again to maintain a pro-American government; this occupation lasted until 1925. Augusto Csar Sandino, a nationalist and leader of Nicaraguan peasants and workers, refused to accept the U.S.-sponsored peace treaty that kept U.S. influence and economic power intact. He organized an army of peasants, workers, and Indians to resist thousands of U.S. marines and the U.S.-trained Nicaraguan National Guard. From 1927 to 1933 Sandino waged a successful guerrilla war against the United States with support from Mexican and other Latin American anti-imperialists. Inter-American solidarity was critical to Sandino's success and a major fear of the United States. One non-Nicaraguan supporter of Sandino was Colombian journalist Alfonso Alexander Moncayo. This memoir by Moncayo described how Sandino deeply admired the Latin American independence leader Simn Bolvar. (An English translation follows the original text in Spanish.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum dem frühen 20. Jahrhundert beherrschten 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Firmen die Wirtschaftssysteme der zentralen 
amerikanischen Republiken, einschließlich Nicaragua und steuerten die
meisten der Banane Produktion, den Eisenbahnen, den Portteildiensten, 
den Gruben und Einrichtungen des Bankgewerbes. Die Vereinigten 
Staaten griffen in Nicaragua wiederholt ein, um VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
ökonomische Interessen zu schützen. In 1912 VEREINIGTEN 
STAATEN landeten Marinen noch einmal, um eine Pro-Amerikanische 
Regierung beizubehalten; diese Besetzung dauerte bis 1925. 
Augusto Csar Sandino, ein Nationalist und Führer der 
Nicaragualandarbeiter und der Arbeiter, abgelehnt, um den 
U.S.-sponsored Friedensvertrag anzunehmen, der den VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Einfluß und ökonomische Energie intakt hielt. Er 
organisierte eine Armee der Landarbeiter, der Arbeiter und der Inder, 
um Tausenden der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinen und des U.S.-trained 
nationalen Nicaraguaschutzes zu widerstehen. Von unternahm 
Sandino 1927 bis 1933 einen erfolgreichen Bandenkämpferkrieg gegen 
die Vereinigten Staaten mit Support vom Mexikaner und von anderen 
lateinamerikanischen Anti-Imperialisten. Zwischen-Amerikanische 
solidarität war zum Erfolg und zu einer Hauptfurcht Sandinos vor den 
Vereinigten Staaten kritisch. Ein NichtNicaraguaner Verfechter 
Sandino war kolumbianischer Journalist Alfonso Alexander Moncayo. 
Diese Abhandlung durch Moncayo beschrieb, wie Sandino tief den 
lateinamerikanischen Unabhängigkeitführer Simn Bolvar bewunderte. 
(eine englische Übersetzung folgt dem ursprünglichen Text auf 
spanisch.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par le début du 20ème siècle, les compagnies 
des ETATS-UNIS ont dominé les économies des républiques 
américaines centrales, y compris le Nicaragua, et ont contrôlé la 
plupart de la production de banane, des chemins de fer, des 
équipements gauches, des mines, et des institutions bancaires. 
Les Etats-Unis sont intervenus au Nicaragua à plusieurs 
reprises pour protéger des intérêts économiques des ETATS-UNIS. 
Aux 1912 ETATS-UNIS les soldats de marine ont débarqué de 
nouveau pour mettre à jour un gouvernement pro-Américain ; ce 
métier a duré jusqu'en 1925. Augusto Csar Sandino, un 
nationaliste et amorce des paysans et des ouvriers de Nicaragua, 
refusés pour recevoir le traité de paix d'U.S.-sponsored qui a 
maintenu l'influence des ETATS-UNIS et la puissance économique 
intactes. Il a organisé une armée des paysans, des ouvriers, 
et des Indiens pour résister à des milliers des soldats de marine 
des ETATS-UNIS et de la garde nationale de Nicaragua d'U.S.-trained. 
De Sandino 1927 à 1933 a fait une guerre réussie de 
guérillero contre les Etats-Unis avec le support du Mexicain et 
d'autres anti-impérialistes latino-américains. La solidarité 
Inter-Américaine était critique au succès et à une crainte 
importante de Sandino des Etats-Unis. Un défenseur de 
non-Nicaraguayen de Sandino était journaliste colombien Alfonso 
Alexandre Moncayo. Ce mémoire par Moncayo a décrit comment 
Sandino a profondément admiré le Chef latino-américain Simn Bolvar 
de l'indépendance. (une traduction en anglais suit le texte 
initial dans l'Espagnol.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pelo 20o século adiantado, as companhias de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS dominaram as economias das repúblicas americanas 
centrais, including Nicarágua, e controlaram a maioria da produção 
da banana, das estradas de ferro, das facilidades portuárias, das 
minas, e das instituições de operação bancária. Os estados 
unidos intervieram em Nicarágua repetidamente para proteger 
interesses econômicos de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Em 1912 ESTADOS UNIDOS
os fuzileiros navais aterraram uma vez outra vez para manter um 
governo pro-Americano; esta ocupação durou até 1925. 
Augusto Csar Sandino, um nacionalista e líder de camponeses e 
de trabalhadores nicaraguan, recusados aceitar o tratado da paz de 
U.S.-sponsored que manteve a influência de ESTADOS UNIDOS e a 
potência econômica intatas. Organizou um exército dos 
camponeses, dos trabalhadores, e dos indians para resistir milhares de
fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS e do protetor nacional nicaraguan 
de U.S.-trained. Sandino 1927 a 1933 empreendeu uma guerra bem 
sucedida do guerrilla de encontro aos estados unidos com a 
sustentação do mexicano e de outros anti-anti-imperialists 
americanos latin. O solidarity Inter-Americano era crítico ao 
sucesso e a um medo principal de Sandino dos estados unidos. Um 
supporter do non-non-Nicaraguan de Sandino era journalist colombian 
Alfonso Alexander Moncayo. Este memoir por Moncayo descreveu 
como Sandino admirou profundamente o líder americano latin Simn 
Bolvar da independência. (uma tradução inglesa segue o texto 
original no espanhol.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro l'inizio del 20esimo secolo, le aziende 
degli STATI UNITI hanno dominato le economie delle repubbliche 
americane centrali, compreso la Nicaragua ed hanno gestito la maggior 
parte della produzione della banana, delle ferrovie, delle 
attrezzature port, delle miniere e delle istituzioni di operazioni 
bancarie. Unito Dichiara intervenuto ripetutamente in 
Nicaragua per proteggere gli interessi economici degli STATI UNITI. 
In 1912 STATI UNITI i fanti di marina hanno atterrato ancora una
volta per effettuare un governo pro-Americano; questa 
occupazione ha durato fino al 1925. Augusto Csar Sandino, un 
nazionalista e capo dei contadini e degli operai nicaraguan, 
rifiutati per accettare il trattato di pace di U.S.-sponsored che ha 
mantenuto l'influenza degli STATI UNITI e l'potenza economica intatte.
Ha organizzato un esercito dei contadini, degli operai e degli 
indiani per resistere ai migliaia dei fanti di marina degli STATI 
UNITI e della protezione nazionale nicaraguan di U.S.-trained. Sandino 1927 - 1933 ha intrapreso un guerrigliero che riuscito la 
guerra contro unito Dichiara con supporto da 
anti-anti-imperialists messicani ed altri dell'America latina. 
La solidarietà Inter-Americana era critica a successo del 
Sandino e un timore importante del unito Dichiara. Un 
sostenitore del non-non-Nicaraguan di Sandino era giornalista 
colombiano Alfonso Alexander Moncayo. Questa memoria da Moncayo 
ha descritto come Sandino profondamente ha ammirato il capo 
dell'America latina Simn Bolvar di indipendenza. (una traduzione
in inglese segue il testo originale nello Spagnolo.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέχρι τον πρόωρο 20ό αιώνα, οι ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΕΣ 
επιχειρήσεις εξουσίασαν τις οικονομίες των Κεντρικής Αμερικής 
δημοκρατιών, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της Νικαράγουας, και έλεγξαν την 
μεγαλύτερη μέρος της παραγωγής μπανανών, των σιδηροδρόμων, των 
εγκαταστάσεων λιμένων, των ορυχείων, και των τραπεζικών 
οργάνων. Οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες επεμ:βαίνω στη 
Νικαράγουα για να προστατεύσουν επανειλημμένα τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ 
οικονομικά συμφέροντα. Το 1912 τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ ναυτικά 
προσγειώθηκαν άλλη μια φορά για να διατηρήσουν μια 
υπέρ-αμερικανική κυβέρνηση  αυτό το επάγγελμα διάρκεσε 
μέχρι 1925, Augusto Csar Sandino, έναν εθνικιστή και 
έναν ηγέτη των νικαραγουανών αγροτών και οι εργαζόμενοι, 
αρνήθηκαν να αποδεχθούν την ΗΠΑ-Υποστηριγμένη συνθήκη ειρήνης που
κράτησε την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ επιρροή και την οικονομική δύναμη 
άθικτες. Οργάνωσε έναν στρατό των αγροτών, των 
εργαζομένων, και Ινδών για να αντισταθεί σε χιλιάδες ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ 
ναυτικά και ΗΠΑ-Εκπαιδευμένη νικαραγουανή εθνική φρουρά. 
Από το 1927 ως το 1933 Sandino ένας επιτυχής 
πόλεμος ανταρτών ενάντια στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες με υποστήριξη 
από μεξικανό και άλλους λατινοαμερικανικούς αντι-ιμπεριαλιστές. 
Η διαμερικανική αλληλεγγύη ήταν κρίσιμη για την επιτυχία 
Sandino και σημαντικός φόβος των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών. 
Ένας μη-νικαραγουανός υποστηρικτής Sandino ήταν 
κολομβιανός δημοσιογράφος Alfonso Alexander moncayo. 
Αυτά τα απομνημονεύματα από moncayo περιέγραψαν πώς 
Sandino θαύμασε βαθειά το λατινοαμερικανικό ηγέτη Simn 
Bolvar ανεξαρτησίας. (Μια αγγλική μετάφραση ακολουθεί το 
αρχικό κείμενο στα ισπανικά.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por el vigésimo siglo temprano, las compañías 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS dominaron las economías de las repúblicas 
americanas centrales, incluyendo Nicaragua, y controlaron a la 
mayoría de la producción del plátano, de los ferrocarriles, de los 
recursos portuarios, de las minas, y de las instituciones de 
actividades bancarias. Los Estados Unidos intervinieron en 
Nicaragua en varias ocasiones para proteger los intereses económicos 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS. En 1912 ESTADOS UNIDOS los infantes de marina
aterrizaron de nuevo para mantener un gobierno favorable-Americano; 
esta ocupación duró hasta 1925. Augusto Csar Sandino, 
nacionalista y arranque de cinta de campesinos y de trabajadores 
nicaraguan, rechazados para validar el tratado de la paz de 
U.S.-sponsored que mantuvo la influencia de ESTADOS UNIDOS y el poder 
económico intactos. Él ordenó a ejército de campesinos, de 
trabajadores, y de indios para oponerse a millares de infantes de 
marina de ESTADOS UNIDOS y del protector nacional nicaraguan de 
U.S.-trained. A partir Sandino la 1927 a 1933 emprendió una 
guerra acertada del guerrilla contra los Estados Unidos con la ayuda 
del mexicano y de otros contra-imperialistas americanos latinos. 
La solidaridad Inter-Americana era crítica al éxito y a un 
miedo importante de Sandino de los Estados Unidos. Un partidario
del no-non-Nicaraguan de Sandino era periodista colombiano Alfonso 
Alexander Moncayo. Esta memoria de Moncayo describió cómo 
Sandino admiró profundamente a arranque de cinta americano latino 
Simn Bolvar de la independencia. (una traducción inglesa sigue 
el texto original en español.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087150</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103890</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/un-colombian-con-sandino-u-s-intervention-in-central-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
