<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108773</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108773</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1879158220</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Guitar Building</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Guitarre Gebäude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bâtiment de Guitare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Edifício Da Guitarra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Costruzione Del Guitar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κτήριο κιθάρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Edificio De la Guitarra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this class, students learn about physics principles by examining the physics responsible for producing music with electronic stringed instruments, while building, testing, and playing their own electric guitar. Students will design their own Guitar bodies, construct their own pick-ups, assemble their own guitars, tune them using a chromatic tuner, and use them to play a simple song. While the instructions here give enough detail that an independent learner could construct their own guitar, please note that this activity should only be attempted with proper adult supervision, whether at home or at school.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Kategorie erlernen Kursteilnehmer über 
Physikgrundregeln, indem sie die Physik überprüfen, die für das 
Produzieren von von Musik mit elektronischem verantwortlich ist, 
stringed Instrumente, beim Aufbauen, Prüfung und Spielen ihrer 
eigenen elektrischen Guitarre. Kursteilnehmer konzipieren ihre 
eigenen Guitarre Körper, konstruieren ihre eigenen Aufnahmen, bauen 
ihre eigenen Guitarren zusammen, justieren sie einen chromatischen 
Tuner verwendend und benutzen sie, um ein einfaches Lied zu spielen. 
Während die Anweisungen hier genügend spezifizieren, daß ein 
unabhängiger Anfänger ihre eigene Guitarre konstruieren könnte, 
beachten Sie bitte, daß diese Aktivität mit korrekter 
Erwachsenüberwachung nur versucht werden sollte, ob zu Hause oder an 
der Schule.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette classe, les étudiants se renseignent 
sur des principes de physique en examinant la physique responsable de 
produire la musique avec électronique stringed des instruments, tout 
en construisant, testant, et jouant leur propre guitare électrique. 
Les étudiants concevront leurs propres corps de guitare, 
construiront leurs propres collectes, assembleront leurs propres 
guitares, les accorderont à l'aide d'un tuner chromatique, et les 
emploieront pour jouer une chanson simple. Tandis que les 
instructions ici donnent assez de détail qu'un étudiant indépendant
pourrait construire leur propre guitare, notez s'il vous plaît que 
cette activité devrait seulement être essayée avec la surveillance 
appropriée d'adulte, si à la maison ou à l'école.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta classe, os estudantes aprendem sobre 
princípios da física examinando a física responsável para produzir
a música com eletrônico stringed instrumentos, ao construir, ao 
testar, e ao jogar sua própria guitarra elétrica. Os 
estudantes projetarão seus próprios corpos da guitarra, construirão
seus próprios coletores, montarão suas próprias guitarras, 
ajustá-las-ão que usam um tuner chromatic, e usá-las-ão jogar uma 
canção simples. Quando as instruções aqui derem bastante 
detalhe que um learner independente poderia construir sua própria 
guitarra, anote por favor que esta atividade deve somente ser tentada 
com supervisão apropriada do adulto, se na HOME ou na escola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo codice categoria, gli allievi imparano 
circa i principii di fisica esaminando la fisica responsabile del 
produrre la musica con elettronico stringed gli strumenti, mentre 
costruiscono, esaminando e giocando il loro proprio guitar elettrico. 
Gli allievi progetteranno i loro propri corpi del guitar, 
costruiranno le loro proprie raccolte, monteranno i loro propri 
guitars, li sintonizzeranno che per mezzo di un sintonizzatore 
cromatico e li useranno per giocare una canzone semplice. Mentre
le istruzioni qui forniscono abbastanza particolare che un 
principiante indipendente potrebbe costruire il loro proprio guitar, 
noti prego che questa attività dovrebbe essere tentata soltanto con 
controllo adeguato dell'adulto, se nel paese o alla scuola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την κλάση, οι σπουδαστές μαθαίνουν για τις 
αρχές φυσικής με την εξέταση της φυσικής αρμόδιας για την 
παραγωγή της μουσικής με ηλεκτρονικό τα όργανα, χτίζοντας, 
εξεταστικός, και παίζοντας την ηλεκτρική κιθάρα τους. Οι 
σπουδαστές θα σχεδιάσουν τους οργανισμούς κιθάρων τους, θα 
κατασκευάσουν τις επαναλείψεις τους, θα συγκεντρώσουν τις κιθάρες 
τους, θα τις συντονίσουν χρησιμοποιώντας έναν χρωματικό δέκτη, 
και θα τις χρησιμοποιήσουν για να παίξουν ένα απλό τραγούδι. 
Ενώ οι οδηγίες δίνουν εδώ αρκετή λεπτομέρεια ότι ένας 
ανεξάρτητος αρχάριος θα μπορούσε να κατασκευάσει την κιθάρα τους,
παρακαλώ να σημειώσει ότι αυτή η δραστηριότητα πρέπει μόνο να 
προσπαθηθεί με την κατάλληλη ενήλικη επίβλεψη, είτε στο σπίτι 
είτε στο σχολείο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta clase, los estudiantes aprenden sobre 
principios de la física examinando la física responsable de producir
música con electrónico los instrumentos de cuerda, mientras que 
construyen, prueban, y tocando su propia guitarra eléctrica. 
Los estudiantes diseñarán sus propios cuerpos de la guitarra, 
construirán sus propias recolecciones, ensamblarán sus propias 
guitarras, las templarán que usan un sintonizador cromático, y las 
utilizarán para jugar una canción simple. Mientras que las 
instrucciones aquí dan bastante detalle que un principiante 
independiente podría construir su propia guitarra, observe por favor que
esta actividad se debe procurar solamente con la supervisión 
apropiada del adulto, si en el país o en la escuela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SEERING, ADAM
FN:SEERING, ADAM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1879158220</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108773</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/guitar-building</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
