<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103020</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103020</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201387</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Module One: Interpersonal Relationships</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Modul Eins: Zwischenpersonal-Verhältnisse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Module Un : Rapports Interpersonnels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Módulo Um: Relacionamentos Interpersonal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modulo Uno: Rapporti Tra persone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενότητα μια: Διαπροσωπικές σχέσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Módulo Uno: Lazos Interpersonales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The present module entitled "Intra-Personal Relationship Skills" will address several components such as self esteem and self improvement, values education, goal setting and time management, substance use and abuse, heritage and finally, wellness and care which will focus on nutrition, fitness and stress management. This will provide learners the opportunity to use basic self development concepts and strategies that promote self respect and high self-esteem. They will develop an understanding of the Universal values that enable them to better live in this rapidly changing world. They will be able to incorporate values clarification strategies in their decision making processes and apply the management principles of goal setting and time management to their personal development.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das anwesende Modul, das "Intra-Persönliche 
Verhältnis-Fähigkeiten" erlaubt wird, adressiert einige Bestandteile
wie Selbstachtung und Selbstverbesserung, bewertet Ausbildung, 
Zieleinstellung und Zeitmanagement, Substanzgebrauch und -mißbrauch, 
Erbe und schließlich, Wellness und Obacht, die auf Nahrung-, Eignung-
und Druckmanagement konzentrieren. Dieses liefert Anfänger die 
Gelegenheit, grundlegende Selbstentwicklung Konzepte zu verwenden und 
Strategien, die Selbstrespekt und hohen Self-esteem fördern. 
Sie entwickeln ein Verständnis der Universalwerte, die sie 
aktivieren, Phasen in dieser schnell ändernden Welt zu verbessern. 
Sie können, Werterklärung Strategien in ihren 
Entscheidungsprozessen zu enthalten und die Verwaltungsprinzipien der 
Zieleinstellung und des Zeitmanagements an ihrer persönlichen 
Entwicklung anzuwenden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le module actuel intitulé "des qualifications 
Intra-Personnelles de rapport" adressera plusieurs composants tels que
l'estime d'art de l'auto-portrait et l'amélioration d'art de l'auto-portrait, évalue 
l'éducation, la configuration de but et la gestion du temps, 
l'utilisation et l'abus de substance, l'héritage et en conclusion, la
santé et le soin qui se concentreront sur la maîtrise du stress 
de nutrition, de forme physique et . Ceci fournira les 
étudiants l'occasion d'utiliser des concepts de base de 
développement d'art de l'auto-portrait et les stratégies qui favorisent le 
respect d'art de l'auto-portrait et le haut art de l'auto-portrait-esteem. Ils 
développeront un arrangement des valeurs universelles qui leur 
permettent d'améliorer de phase en ce monde changeant rapidement. 
Ils pourront incorporer des stratégies de clarification de 
valeurs dans leurs processus décisionnels et s'appliquer les 
principes de gestion de la configuration de but et de la gestion du 
temps à leur développement personnel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O módulo atual intitulado "habilidades 
Intra-Pessoais do relacionamento" dirigir-se-á a diversos componentes
tais como o esteem do self e a melhoria do self, avalia a instrução,
o ajuste do objetivo e a gerência de tempo, o uso e o abuso da 
substância, o heritage e finalmente, o wellness e o cuidado que 
focalizarão na gerência do nutrition, da aptidão e do stress. 
Isto fornecerá os learners a oportunidade de usar conceitos 
básicos do desenvolvimento do self e as estratégias que promovem o 
respeito do self e o self-esteem elevado. Desenvolverão uma 
compreensão dos valores universais que os permitem de melhorar vivo 
neste mundo ràpidamente em mudança. Poderão  incorporar 
estratégias do esclarecimento dos valores em seus processos fazendo 
de decisão e aplicar os princípios de gerência do ajuste do 
objetivo e da gerência de tempo a seu desenvolvimento pessoal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il modulo attuale intitolato "abilità 
Intra-Personali di rapporto" richiamerà parecchi componenti quali la 
stima di auto e miglioramento di auto, stima la formazione, la 
regolazione di obiettivo e gestione di tempo, uso ed abuso della 
sostanza, eredità e per concludere, wellness e cura che metteranno a 
fuoco sulla gestione di nutrizione, di idoneità e di sforzo. 
Ciò fornirà ai principianti l'occasione usare i concetti di 
base di sviluppo di auto e strategie che promuovono il rispetto di 
auto e l'alto self-esteem. Svilupperanno una comprensione dei 
valori universali che permettono loro di migliorare in tensione in 
questo mondo velocemente cambiante. Potranno comprendere le 
strategie di chiarificazione di valori nei loro processi decisionali 
ed applicare i principii di gestione della regolazione di obiettivo e 
della gestione di tempo al loro sviluppo personale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η παρούσα ενότητα που τιτλοφορείται "ενδοατομικές 
δεξιότητες σχέσησ" θα εξετάσει διάφορα συστατικά όπως η μόνη 
εκτίμηση και η μόνη βελτίωση, εκτιμεί την εκπαίδευση, την τιμή 
τών παραμέτρων στόχου και τη χρονική διαχείριση, τη χρήση και 
την κατάχρηση ουσιών, την κληρονομιά και τελικά, το wellness 
και την προσοχή που θα εστιάσουν στη διαχείριση διατροφής, 
ικανότητας και πίεσης. Αυτό θα παράσχει τους αρχαρίους η 
ευκαιρία να χρησιμοποιηθούν οι βασικές μόνες έννοιες και οι 
στρατηγικές ανάπτυξης που προωθούν το μόνο σεβασμό και τον υψηλό
αυτοσεβασμό. Θα αναπτύξουν μια κατανόηση των καθολικών 
τιμών που επιτρέπουν σε τους για να ζήσουν καλύτερα σε αυτόν τον 
γρήγορα μεταβαλλόμενο κόσμο. Θα είναι σε θέση να 
ενσωματώσουν τις στρατηγικές διευκρίνισης τιμών στις διαδικασίες 
λήψης απόφασής τους και να εφαρμόσουν τις διοικητικές αρχές της 
τιμής τών παραμέτρων στόχου και της χρονικής διαχείρισης στην 
προσωπική ανάπτυξή τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El actual módulo titulado las "habilidades 
Intra-Personales del lazo" tratará varios componentes tales como 
estima del uno mismo y mejora del uno mismo, valora la educación, 
configuración de la meta y gerencia de tiempo, el uso y el abuso de 
la sustancia, la herencia y finalmente, la salud y el cuidado que se 
centrarán en la gerencia de la nutrición, de la aptitud y de la 
tensión. Esto proporcionará a los principiantes la oportunidad
de utilizar conceptos básicos del desarrollo del uno mismo y las 
estrategias que promueven respecto del uno mismo y alta autoestima. 
Desarrollarán una comprensión de los valores universales que 
les permiten mejorar vivo en este mundo rápidamente que cambia. 
Podrán incorporar estrategias de la clarificación de los 
valores en sus procesos de toma de decisión y aplicar los principios 
de gerencia de la configuración de la meta y de la gerencia de tiempo
a su desarrollo personal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201387</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103020</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/module-one-interpersonal-relationships</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
