<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107446</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107446</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205933</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Historic American Sheet Arts, 1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Historische Amerikanische Blatt-Künste, 1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts Américains Historiques de Feuille, 
1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes Americanas Historic Da Folha, 1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti Americane Storiche Del Foglio, 1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορικές αμερικανικές τέχνες φύλλων, 1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes Americanos Históricos De la Hoja, 
1850-1920</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents 3,000 pieces of sheet music drawn from a collection at Duke University. The selection covers a variety of music types including bel canto, minstrel, protest, plantation, and sentimental songs, as well as songs from vaudeville and tin pan alley. The collection is particularly strong in antebellum Southern music, confederate imprints, and Civil War songs and music.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschenke 3.000 Stücke Blattmusik gezeichnet von 
einer Ansammlung an Duke University. Die Auswahl umfaßt eine 
Vielzahl der Musiktypen einschließlich Belgesang, Minnesänger, 
Protest, Plantage und sentimental Liede, sowie Liede vom vaudeville 
und Tin Pan Alley von. Die Ansammlung ist in der antebellum 
südlicher Musik, in den Verbündetabdrücken und in den 
Bürgerkrieglieden und -musik besonders stark.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présents 3.000 morceaux de musique de feuille 
tirés d'une collection à Duke University. La sélection couvre
une variété de types de musique comprenant le chant de caractère 
d'appel, le troubadour, la protestation, la plantation, et les 
chansons sentimentales, aussi bien que des chansons de ruelle de 
casserole de vaudeville et de bidon. La collection est 
particulièrement forte dans la musique, les impressions de 
confédéré, et les chansons et la musique méridionales 
d'avant-guerre de guerre civile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">presentes 3.000 partes de música da folha 
desenhadas de uma coleção no duque Universidade. A seleção 
cobre uma variedade de tipos da música including o canto de bel, o 
minstrel, o protesto, a plantação, e canções sentimental, 
as.well.as canções da aléia de bandeja do vaudeville e de lata. 
A coleção é particularmente forte na música, em imprints do 
confederado, e em canções e na música do sul antebellum da guerra 
civil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenti 3.000 parti di musica del foglio 
dissipate da una collezione alla Duke University. La selezione 
riguarda una varietà di tipi di musica compreso canto di bel, il 
minstrel, la protesta, la piantagione e le canzoni sentimental, così 
come le canzoni dal vicolo di vaschetta di latta e del vaudeville. 
L'accumulazione è particolarmente forte nella musica, nelle 
stampe del confederato e nelle canzoni e nella musica del sud 
antebellum di guerra civile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει 3.000 κομμάτια της μουσικής φύλλων που 
προέρχονται από μια συλλογή σε Πανεπιστήμιο του Ντιούκ. Η 
επιλογή καλύπτει ποικίλους τύπους μουσικής συμπεριλαμβανομένου 
του canto μπελ, του τροβαδούρου, της διαμαρτυρίας, της φυτείας, 
και των συναισθηματικών τραγουδιών, καθώς επίσης και των 
τραγουδιών από την παν αλέα επιθεώρησης και κασσίτερου. Η 
συλλογή είναι ιδιαίτερα ισχυρή στην προπολεμική νότια μουσική, 
τις ομόσπονδες σφραγίδες, και τα τραγούδια και τη μουσική 
εμφύλιου πολέμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presentes 3.000 pedazos de música de la hoja 
trazados de una colección en duque University. La selección 
cubre una variedad de tipos de la música incluyendo canto de belio, 
minstrel, protesta, la plantación, y canciones sentimental, así como
canciones del callejón de cacerola del vaudeville y de lata. La
colección es determinado fuerte en música, impresiones del 
confederato, y canciones y música meridionales antebellum de la 
guerra civil.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205933</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107446</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/historic-american-sheet-arts-1850-1920</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
