<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102978</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102978</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207095</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Brown v. Board of Education National Historic Site</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Braunes v. Brett Ausbildung der nationalen 
historischen Sites</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Panneau brun de v. de site historique national 
d'éducation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Placa marrom do v. do local historic nacional da 
instrução</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bordo marrone del v. del luogo storico 
nazionale di formazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Brown V. Board της εθνικής ιστορικής περιοχής
εκπαίδευσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tarjeta marrón del v. del sitio histórico 
nacional de la educación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features Monroe Elementary, the school attended in 1950 by third grader Linda Brown. Because she was black, Brown was barred from attending a white school much closer to her home. The cases brought by father and others led to the Supreme Court's unanimous decision in 1954 that racial segregation in public schools was unconstitutional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale grundlegendes Monroe, die Schule 
beachteten 1950 durch drittes Sortierer Linda Braun. Weil sie 
schwarz war, wurde Braun von eine weiße Schule näeher an ihrem Haus 
viel bedienen abgehalten. Die Fälle, die vom Vater und von 
anderen geholt wurden, führten zu die einmütige Entscheidung des 
Höchsten Gerichts 1954, daß rassische Abtrennung in den allgemeinen 
Schulen verfassungswidrig war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les dispositifs Monroe élémentaire, l'école se 
sont occupés en 1950 par le troisième brun de Linda de niveleuse. 
Puisqu'elle était noire, le brun a été empêché de aller à 
une école blanche beaucoup plus près de sa maison. Les caisses
apportées par le père et d'autres ont mené à la décision unanime 
de cour suprême en 1954 que la ségrégation raciale dans des écoles
d'Etat était inconstitutionnelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as características Monroe elementar, a escola 
atenderam em 1950 pelo terceiro marrom de Linda do graduador. 
Porque era preta, o marrom foi barrado de atender a uma escola 
branca muito mais perto de sua HOME. Os casos trazidos pelo pai 
e por outro conduziram à decisão unânime de corte suprema em 1954 
que o segregation racial em escolas públicas era unconstitutional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le caratteristiche Monroe elementare, la scuola 
hanno assistito in 1950 da terzo colore marrone di Linda del 
selezionatore. Poiché era nera, il colore marrone è stato 
escluso dall'assistere ad una scuola bianca molto più vicino alla sua
sede. I casi portati dal padre e da altri hanno condotto alla 
decisione unanime della Corte suprema in 1954 che la segregazione 
razziale in "public school" era inconstituzionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει το Μονρόε στοιχειώδες, το σχολείο που 
παρακολουθείται το 1950 από το τρίτο γκρέιντερ Linda 
Brown. Επειδή ήταν μαύρη, καφετής φράχτηκε από να 
ανταποκριθεί σε ένα άσπρο σχολείο πολύ πιό κοντά στο σπίτι 
της. Οι υποθέσεις που παρουσιάστηκαν από τον πατέρα και 
άλλους οδήγησαν στην ομόφωνη απόφαση του ανώτατου δικαστηρίου το
1954 ότι ο φυλετικός διαχωρισμός στα δημόσια σχολεία ήταν 
αντισυνταγματικός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las características Monroe elemental, la escuela 
atendieron en 1950 por el tercer marrón de Linda del graduador. 
Porque ella era negra, el marrón fue barrado de atender a una 
escuela blanca mucho más cercano a su hogar. Los casos traídos
por el padre y otros condujeron a la decisión unánime del Tribunal 
Supremo en 1954 que la segregación racial en escuelas públicas era 
inconstitucional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207095</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102978</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/brown-v-board-of-education-national-historic-site</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
