<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108712</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108712</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206958</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Junior Solar Sprint and Hydrogen Fuel Cell Car Competitions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Juniorsolar- Sprinten und 
Wasserstoff-Kraftstoff-Zelle Auto-Konkurrenzen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Concours solaires juniors de voiture de cellules 
de carburant de Sprint et d'hydrogène</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Competições solares júniors do carro da célula
combustível do Sprint e do hidrogênio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Concorsi solari minori dell'automobile delle 
cellule di combustibile dell'idrogeno e di Sprint</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατώτεροι ηλιακοί ανταγωνισμοί αυτοκινήτων κυττάρων 
καυσίμων ορμής και υδρογόνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Competiciones solares menores del coche de la 
célula de combustible del Sprint y del hidrógeno</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">focuses on designing and building solar and hydrogen fuel cell cars. Explore components of solar cars. Conduct experiments to improve car performance. Find activities for measuring solar cell output, tips on vehicle construction and transmission design, and formulas for calculating vehicle performance. See a list of regional competitions sites. Find out how to integrate solar vehicle activities into the curriculum.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Foki auf dem Konzipieren und dem Aufbauen Solar 
und den Wasserstoffkraftstoffzelle Autos. Erforschen Sie 
Bestandteile der Solarautos. Leiten Sie Experimente, um 
Autoleistung zu verbessern. Finden Sie Aktivitäten für das 
Messen der Solarzelle Ausgabe, der Spitzen auf Trägeraufbau und 
Übertragung Design und der Formeln für Rechenträgerleistung. 
Sehen Sie eine Liste der regionalen Konkurrenzsites. 
Finden Sie heraus, wie man Solarträgeraktivitäten in den 
Lehrplan integriert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">foyers sur concevoir et construire solaire et des 
voitures de cellules de carburant d'hydrogène. Explorez les 
composants des voitures solaires. Entreprenez les expériences 
pour améliorer l'exécution de voiture. Trouvez les activités 
pour mesurer la sortie de pile solaire, les extrémités sur la 
construction de véhicule et la conception de transmission, et les 
formules pour l'exécution calculatrice de véhicule. Voir la 
liste de sites régionaux de concours. Découvrez comment 
intégrer des activités solaires de véhicule dans le programme 
d'études.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">focos no projeto e em construir solar e em carros 
da célula combustível do hidrogênio. Explore componentes de 
carros solares. Conduza experiências para melhorar o desempenho
do carro. Encontre atividades para medir a saída da pilha 
solar, as pontas na construção do veículo e no projeto da 
transmissão, e as fórmulas para desempenho calculador do veículo. 
Veja uma lista de locais regionais das competições. 
Encontre para fora como integrar atividades solares do veículo 
no curriculum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fuochi sulla progettazione e sulla costruzione 
solare e sugli automobili delle cellule di combustibile dell'idrogeno.
Esplori i componenti degli automobili solari. Esegua gli 
esperimenti per migliorare le prestazioni dell'automobile. Trovi
le attività per la misurazione l'uscita della pila solare, le punte 
sulla costruzione del veicolo e sulla progettazione della trasmissione
e delle formule per le prestazioni calcolarici del veicolo. Si 
veda una lista dei luoghi regionali dei concorsi. Scopra come 
integrare le attività solari del veicolo nel programma di studi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εστίαση στο σχεδιασμό και την οικοδόμηση ηλιακή και τα
αυτοκίνητα κυττάρων καυσίμων υδρογόνου. Εξερευνήστε τα 
συστατικά των ηλιακών αυτοκινήτων. Πραγματοποιήστε τα 
πειράματα για να βελτιώσετε την απόδοση αυτοκινήτων. Βρείτε
τις δραστηριότητες για τη μέτρηση της εξόδου ηλιακών κυττάρων, 
των ακρών στο σχέδιο κατασκευής οχημάτων και μετάδοσης, και των 
τύπων για τον υπολογισμό της απόδοσης οχημάτων. 
Δείτε έναν κατάλογο περιφερειακών περιοχών 
ανταγωνισμών. Ανακαλύψτε πώς να ενσωματώσει τις ηλιακές 
δραστηριότητες οχημάτων στο πρόγραμμα σπουδών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">focos en diseñar y la construcción solar y 
coches de la célula de combustible del hidrógeno. Explore los 
componentes de coches solares. Conduzca los experimentos para 
mejorar funcionamiento del coche. Encuentre las actividades para
medir salida de la célula solar, extremidades en la construcción del
vehículo y el diseño de la transmisión, y los fórmulas para el 
funcionamiento calculador del vehículo. Vea una lista de los 
sitios regionales de las competiciones. Descubra cómo integrar 
actividades solares del vehículo en el plan de estudios.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206958</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108712</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/junior-solar-sprint-and-hydrogen-fuel-cell-car-competitions</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
