<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104833</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104833</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205231</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exam Skills</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Prüfung-Fähigkeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Qualifications d'Examen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Habilidades Do Exam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Abilità Del Exam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεξιότητες διαγωνισμών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Habilidades Del Examen</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The aim of this lesson is to help students acquire skills that help them prepare for examinations in a focused and organized way. Students devise strategies for reviewing material and developing a revision timeline, and learn to identify the areas of study on which they should concentrate to prepare for tests. They review helpful tips and learn to use past examinations as a guide for future ones. It is the seventh lesson in the study skills series and is intended to support adult learners who are embarking on a course of study and need to acquire skills which will help them to be successful. The lessons are designed as a package with key skills reinforced in each subsequent lesson so that a study culture is developed over time. They can be delivered sequentially or used individually, as a whole or in part, to support other programs of study.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel dieser Lektion ist, Kursteilnehmern zu 
helfen, Fähigkeiten zu erwerben, die ihnen helfen, für Prüfungen in
einer fokussierten und organisierten Methode sich vorzubereiten. 
Kursteilnehmervermächtnisstrategien für das Wiederholen 
materiell und das Entwickeln eines Änderung timeline und erlernen, 
die Untersuchungsbereiche zu kennzeichnen, auf die sie sich 
konzentrieren sollten, um sich für Tests vorzubereiten. Sie 
wiederholen nützliche Spitzen und erlernen, hinter Prüfungen als 
Anleitung für Zukunft eine zu verwenden. Es ist die 7. Lektion 
in den Studie Fähigkeiten Serie und soll Erwachsenanfänger 
unterstützen, die auf einem Bildungsweg sich einschiffen und 
Fähigkeiten erwerben müssen, die ihnen helfen, erfolgreich zu sein. 
Die Lektionen sind während ein Paket mit den 
Schlüsselfähigkeiten konzipiert, die in jeder folgenden Lektion 
verstärkt werden, damit eine Studie Kultur über Zeit entwickelt 
wird. Sie können sequentiell geliefert werden oder, als Ganzes 
oder im Teil einzeln benutzt werden, um andere Programme der Studie zu
unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cette leçon est d'aider des étudiants 
à saisir les qualifications qui les aident à se préparer aux 
examens d'une voie focalisée et organisée. Les stratégies de 
legs d'étudiants pour passer en revue matériel et développer une 
chronologie de révision, et apprennent à identifier les domaines 
d'étude sur lesquels elles devraient se concentrer pour se préparer 
aux essais. Ils passent en revue des extrémités utiles et 
apprennent à utiliser après des examens comme guide pour le futur 
ceux. C'est la septième leçon dans les qualifications série 
d'étude et est destiné pour supporter les étudiants d'adulte qui 
s'embarquent sur un cours d'étude et doivent saisir les 
qualifications qui les aideront à être réussies. Les leçons 
sont conçues pendant qu'un module avec les qualifications principales
renforcées dans chaque leçon ultérieure de sorte qu'une culture 
d'étude soit développée avec le temps. Elles peuvent être 
livrées séquentiellement ou employées individuellement, dans 
l'ensemble ou en partie, pour supporter d'autres programmes d'étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O alvo desta lição é ajudar a estudantes 
adquirir as habilidades que lhes ajudam se preparar para examinações
em uma maneira focalizada e organizada. As estratégias do 
legado dos estudantes para rever material e desenvolver um timeline da
revisão, e aprendem identificar as áreas de estudo em que devem 
concentrar para se preparar para testes. Revêem pontas úteis e
aprendem-nas usar após examinações como uma guia para o futuro . 
É a sétima lição nas habilidades série do estudo e é 
pretendido suportar os learners do adulto que embarking em um curso de
estudo e necessitam adquirir as habilidades que lhes ajudarão ser bem
sucedidas. As lições são projetadas enquanto um pacote com as
habilidades chaves reforçadas em cada lição subseqüente de modo 
que uma cultura do estudo esteja desenvolvida sobre o tempo. 
Podem ser entregados sequencialmente ou usado individualmente, 
ao todo ou na parte, suportar outros programas do estudo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo di questa lezione è aiutare gli allievi 
ad acquistare le abilità che le aiutano a prepararsi per gli esami di
un modo messo a fuoco ed organizzato. Le strategie della 
disposizione testamentaria degli allievi per la riesaminazione 
materiale e sviluppare un timeline di revisione ed imparano 
identificare i settori su cui dovrebbero concentrarsi per prepararsi 
per le prove. Rivedono le punte utili ed imparano usare oltre 
gli esami come guida per futuro ones. È la settima lezione 
nelle abilità serie di studio ed è inteso sostenere i principianti 
dell'adulto che stanno intraprendendo un corso dello studio e devono 
acquistare le abilità che le aiuteranno a riuscire. Le lezioni 
sono progettate mentre un pacchetto con le abilità chiave di rinforzo
in ogni lezione successiva in moda da sviluppare una coltura di studio
col tempo. Possono essere trasportate in sequenza o essere usate
individualmente, nell'insieme o in parte, per sostenere altri 
programmi dello studio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του μαθήματος είναι να ενισχυθούν οι 
σπουδαστές να αποκτήσουν τις δεξιότητες που τους βοηθούν να 
προετοιμαστούν για τις εξετάσεις με έναν και οργανωμένο τρόπο. 
Οι σπουδαστές επινοούν τις στρατηγικές για την αναθεώρηση 
υλική και την ανάπτυξη μιας υπόδειξης ως προς το χρόνο 
αναθεώρησης, και μαθαίνουν να προσδιορίζουν τους τομείς της 
μελέτης στους οποίους πρέπει να επικεντρωθούν για να 
προετοιμαστούν για τις δοκιμές. Αναθεωρούν τις χρήσιμες 
άκρες και μαθαίνουν να χρησιμοποιούν τις προηγούμενες εξετάσεις 
ως οδηγό για μελλοντικούς. Είναι το έβδομο μάθημα στη 
σειρά δεξιοτήτων μελέτης και προορίζεται να υποστηρίξει τους 
ενήλικους αρχαρίους που αρχίζουν σπουδές και πρέπει να 
αποκτήσουν τις δεξιότητες που θα τους βοηθήσουν για να είναι 
επιτυχείς. Τα μαθήματα σχεδιάζονται ως συσκευασία με τις 
βασικές δεξιότητες που ενισχύονται σε κάθε επόμενο μάθημα έτσι 
ώστε ένας πολιτισμός μελέτης αναπτύσσεται κατά τη διάρκεια του 
χρόνου. Μπορούν να παραδοθούν διαδοχικά ή να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν χωριστά, συνολικά ή εν μέρει, για να 
υποστηρίξουν άλλα προγράμματα της μελέτης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La puntería de esta lección es ayudar a 
estudiantes a adquirir las habilidades que les ayudan a prepararse 
para las examinaciones de una manera enfocada y ordenada. Las 
estrategias del legado de los estudiantes para repasar material y 
desarrollar un timeline de la revisión, y aprenden identificar los 
campos de estudio en los cuales deben concentrarse para prepararse 
para las pruebas. Repasan extremidades provechosas y aprenden 
utilizar más allá de examinaciones como guía para el futuro unos. 
Es la séptima lección en las habilidades serie del estudio y 
se piensa apoyar a los principiantes del adulto que están 
emprendiendo un curso del estudio y necesitan adquirir las habilidades
que les ayudarán a ser acertadas. Se diseñan las lecciones 
mientras que un conjunto con las habilidades dominantes reforzadas en 
cada lección subsecuente para desarrollar una cultura del estudio en 
un cierto plazo. Pueden ser entregadas secuencialmente o ser 
utilizadas individualmente, en su totalidad o en parte, para utilizar 
otros programas del estudio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205231</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104833</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exam-skills</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
