<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106526</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106526</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206258</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Space Place</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Platz-Platz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Endroit de l'Espace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Lugar Do Espaço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Posto Dello Spazio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαστημική θέση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Lugar Del Espacio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a place where kids can learn how to make balloon-powered nano-rovers and pop rockets, discover what it's like to be a space engineer, and conduct experiments to identify the best materials for use in space. The site includes space facts and crossword puzzles, riddles, an Intergalactic Adventures board game that explores a black hole, and other fun activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zu entdecken ist ein Platz, in dem Zicklein 
erlernen können, wie man Ballon-angeschaltetes nano-Vagabund bildet 
und Raketen, knallt was es wie ein Platzingenieur sein soll, und 
Führung experimentiert, um die besten Materialien für Gebrauch im 
Platz zu kennzeichnen. Die Site schließt Platztatsachen und 
Kreuzworträtsel, Rätsel, ein intergalaktisches Abenteuerbrettspiel, 
das eine schwarze Bohrung erforscht, und andere Spaßaktivitäten ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un endroit où les gosses peuvent apprendre 
comment faire nano-rovers ballon-actionné et sauter des fusées, 
découvrir comme ce qu'il doit être un ingénieur de l'espace, et la 
conduite expérimente pour identifier les meilleurs matériaux pour 
l'usage dans l'espace. Le site inclut des faits de l'espace et 
des jeux de mots croisé, des énigmes, un jeu de panneau 
intergalactique d'aventures qui explore un trou noir, et d'autres 
activités d'amusement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um lugar onde os miúdos possam aprender como 
fazer nano-vagabundos balão-balloon-powered e estalar foguetes, para 
descobrir o que deve como ser um coordenador do espaço, e a conduta 
experimenta para identificar os mais melhores materiais para o uso no 
espaço. O local inclui fatos do espaço e enigmas de crossword,
riddles, um jogo de placa intergalactic das aventuras que explore um 
furo preto, e outras atividades do divertimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un posto in cui i capretti possono imparare 
come fare i nano-vagabondi aerostato-alimentati e schioccare i razzi, 
scoprire che cosa deve come essere un assistente tecnico dello spazio 
ed il comportamento sperimenta per identificare i materiali migliori 
per uso nello spazio. Il luogo include i fatti dello spazio e 
cruciverba, riddles, un gioco intergalactic del bordo di 
avventure che esplora un foro nero ed altre attività di divertimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια θέση όπου τα κατσίκια μπορούν να μάθουν 
πώς να κάνουν τους μπαλόνι-τροφοδοτημένους νανο-πλάνες και τους 
λαϊκούς πυραύλους, να ανακαλύψουν τι που πρόκειται όπως να 
είσαι διαστημικός μηχανικός, και να πραγματοποιήσουν τα πειράματα
για να προσδιορίσουν τα καλύτερα υλικά για τη χρήση στο διάστημα.
Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τα διαστημικά γεγονότα και τους 
γρίφους σταυρόλεξων, αινίγματα, ένα intergalactic παιχνίδι 
πινάκων περιπετειών που ερευνά μια μαύρη τρύπα, και άλλες 
δραστηριότητες διασκέδασης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un lugar en donde los cabritos pueden aprender 
cómo hacer nano-nano-rovers globo-accionados y hacer estallar los 
cohetes, descubrir como cuál debe ser ingeniero del espacio, y la 
conducta experimenta para identificar los mejores materiales para el 
uso en espacio. El sitio incluye hechos del espacio y los 
crucigramas, las cribas, un juego de tarjeta intergaláctico de las 
aventuras que explore un calabozo, y otras actividades de la 
diversión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206258</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106526</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-space-place</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
