<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105942</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105942</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087098</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"They Have Largely Destroyed The Pride Of Craft:" Helen Zalph Describes Automation in the Printing Industry</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie Haben Zerstört Groß Den Stolz Der 
Fertigkeit:" Helen Zalph beschreibt Automatisierung in der 
Druck-Industrie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Elles Ont en grande partie détruit La Fierté Du
Métier :" Helen Zalph décrit l'automatisation dans l'industrie
de l'imprimerie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Destruíram Pela maior parte O Orgulho Do 
Ofício:" Helen Zalph descreve a automatização na indústria 
imprimindo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"In gran parte Hanno distrutto L'Orgoglio 
Del Mestiere:" Helen Zalph descrive l'automazione nell'industria
di stampa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έχουν καταστρέψει κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος την 
υπερηφάνεια της τέχνης:" Θ*Χελεν Zalph Describes 
Automation στη βιομηχανία εκτύπωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ella Ha destruido En gran parte El Orgullo Del 
Arte:" Helen Zalph describe la automatización en la industria 
de impresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The introduction of new technologies has always altered the relationship between managers and workers, often by eliminating the need for skilled laborers. Helen Zalph and her colleagues in the printing division of the New York Daily News discovered this fact for themselves when computers revolutionized the way they put together the paper during the 1970s. What management gained in efficiency, workers lost in terms of their control over the production process, a sense of community and teamwork, and the sense of pride that comes with skilled craft work. They also lost many of their co-workers, who were no longer needed, and the power of their union. Now working largely in isolated cubby-offices, Zalph and many of her colleagues miss the older methods.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Einleitung der neuen Technologien hat immer 
das Verhältnis zwischen Managern und Arbeitern, häufig geändert, 
indem sie die Notwendigkeit an erfahrenen Arbeitern beseitigte. 
Helen Zalph und ihre Kollegen in der druckenabteilung der New 
York täglichen Nachrichten entdeckte diese Tatsache für selbst, als 
Computer die Methode revolutionierten, die sie das Papier während der
siebziger Jahre zusammenfügten. Welches Management in der 
Leistungsfähigkeit gewann, verloren Arbeiter in ihrer Steuerung über
dem Produktion Prozeß, einer Richtung der Gemeinschaft und der 
Teamwork und der Richtung des Stolzes ausgedrückt, der mit erfahrener
Fertigkeitarbeit kommt. Sie verloren auch viele ihrer 
Mitarbeiter, die nicht mehr benötigt wurden, und die Energie ihres 
Anschlußes. Jetzt, groß arbeitend in lokalisierten 
Cubbybüros, vermissen Zalph und viele ihrer Kollegen die älteren 
Methoden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'introduction de nouvelles technologies a 
toujours modifié le rapport entre les gestionnaires et les ouvriers, 
souvent en éliminant le besoin de travailleurs habiles. Helen 
Zalph et ses collègues dans la division d'impression des nouvelles 
quotidiennes de New York a découvert ce fait pour elles-mêmes quand 
les ordinateurs ont révolutionné la voie qu'ils ont remonté le 
papier pendant les années 70. Quelle gestion a gagné dans 
l'efficacité, les ouvriers ont détruit en termes de leur contrôle 
du procédé de production, d'un sens de la communauté et de travail 
d'équipe, et du sens de la fierté qui vient avec le travail habile 
de métier. Ils ont également détruit plusieurs de leurs 
collègues, qui n'étaient nécessaires plus, et la puissance de leur 
union. Maintenant travaillant en grande partie dans les 
cubby-bureaux d'isolement, Zalph et plusieurs de ses collègues 
manquent les méthodes plus anciennes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A introdução de tecnologias novas alterou sempre
o relacionamento entre gerentes e trabalhadores, frequentemente 
eliminando a necessidade para laborers hábeis. Helen Zalph e 
seus colegas na divisão imprimindo da notícia diária de New York 
descobriu este fato para se quando os computadores revolutionized a 
maneira que uniram o papel durante os 1970s. Que gerência 
ganhou na eficiência, os trabalhadores perderam nos termos de seu 
controle sobre o processo de produção, um sentido da comunidade e do
teamwork, e o sentido do orgulho que vem com trabalho hábil do 
ofício. Perderam também muitos de seus colegas de trabalho, 
que eram uns needed não mais longo, e a potência de sua união. 
Agora trabalhando pela maior parte em cubby-escritórios 
isolados, Zalph e muitos de seus colegas faltam os métodos mais 
velhos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'introduzione di nuove tecnologie ha alterato 
sempre il rapporto fra i gestori e gli operai, spesso eliminando 
l'esigenza nei dei lavoratori esperti. Helen Zalph ed i suoi 
colleghe nella divisione di stampa delle notizie quotidiane de New 
York ha scoperto loro questo fatto per quando i calcolatori hanno 
rivoluzionato il modo che hanno unito la carta durante gli anni 70. 
Che gestione ha guadagnato nel risparmio di temi, gli operai 
hanno perso in termini di loro controllo sopra il processo di 
produzione, un senso di Comunità e di lavoro di squadra ed il senso 
di orgoglio che viene con nel il lavoro esperto del mestiere. 
Egualmente hanno perso molti dei loro colleghe, che più non 
sono stato necessari e l'potenza della loro unione. Ora 
funzionando in gran parte negli cubby-uffici isolati, Zalph e molti 
dei suoi colleghe mancano i più vecchi metodi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εισαγωγή των νέων τεχνολογιών έχει αλλάξει πάντα 
τη σχέση μεταξύ των διευθυντών και των εργαζομένων, συχνά με την 
εξάλειψη της ανάγκης για τα ειδικευμένα laborers. Η 
Helen Zalph και οι συνάδελφοί της στο τμήμα εκτύπωσης των 
καθημερινών ειδήσεων της Νέας Υόρκης ανακάλυψαν αυτό το γεγονός
για τους όταν ξεσήκωσαν οι υπολογιστές τον τρόπο που έβαλαν μαζί
το έγγραφο κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '70. Ποια 
διαχείριση κέρδισε στην αποδοτικότητα, εργαζόμενοι έχασε από την
άποψη του ελέγχου τους της διαδικασίας παραγωγής, μιας αίσθησης 
της κοινότητας και της ομαδικής εργασίας, και της αίσθησης της 
υπερηφάνειας που έρχεται με την ειδικευμένη εργασία τεχνών. 
Έχασαν επίσης πολλών από τους συναδέλφους τους, οι οποίοι 
δεν απαιτήθηκαν πλέον, και η δύναμη της ένωσής τους. Τώρα 
λειτουργώντας κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος στα απομονωμένα 
θuψψυ-γραφεία, Zalph και πολλοί από τους συναδέλφους της 
χάνουν τις παλαιότερες μεθόδους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La introducción de nuevas tecnologías ha 
alterado siempre el lazo entre los encargados y los trabajadores, a 
menudo eliminando la necesidad de trabajadores expertos. Helen 
Zalph y sus colegas en la división de impresión de las noticias 
diarias de Nueva York descubrió este hecho para sí mismos cuando los
ordenadores revolucionaron la manera que pusieron junto el papel 
durante los años 70. Qué gerencia ganó en eficacia, los 
trabajadores perdieron en términos de su control sobre el proceso de 
producción, un sentido de la comunidad y del trabajo en equipo, y el 
sentido del orgullo que viene con el trabajo experto del arte. 
También perdieron muchos de sus compañeros de trabajo, que 
eran necesarios no más largo, y la potencia de su unión. Ahora
trabajando en gran parte en cubby-oficinas aisladas, Zalph y muchos de
sus colegas faltan los más viejos métodos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087098</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105942</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/they-have-largely-destroyed-the-pride-of-craft-helen-zalph-describes-automation-in-the-printing-industry</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
