<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105220</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105220</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203508</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Investigating the Ocean Algal Blooms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachforschen der Ozean-Algal-Blüte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Investigation des fleurs d'algal d'océan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Investigando as flores do algal do oceano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studio delle fioriture dell'algal dell'oceano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έρευνα των ωκεάνιων φυκωδών ανθίσεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Investigar las floraciones del algal del océano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This NOAA computer-based activity is designed to teach students in grades 9-12 how satellite imagery and remote sensing can be used to monitor harmful algal blooms (HABs). This lesson teaches students how to read and interpret satellite images and how to use GIS maps and satellite images to interpret the relationship of HABs and manatee deaths. The activity features a lesson plan and a step-by-step activity containing hyperlinks that connect the student to the relevant images and maps.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese NOAA rechnergestützte Aktivität ist 
konzipiert, um Kursteilnehmern in den Graden 9-12 beizubringen, wie 
Satellitenbilder und die Fernabfragung verwendet werden können, um 
schädliche Algenblüte (HABs) zu überwachen. Diese Lektion 
bringt Kursteilnehmern bei, wie man Satellitenbilder liest und deutet 
und wie man GIS-Karten und Satellitenbilder verwendet, um das 
Verhältnis von HABs und von Manatistodesfällen zu deuten. Die 
Aktivität kennzeichnet einen Lektionplan und eine schrittweisee 
Aktivität, die Hypertext-Links enthalten, die den Kursteilnehmer an 
die relevanten Bilder und die Karten anschließen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité sur ordinateur de NOAA est conçue
pour enseigner à des étudiants dans les catégories 9-12 comment le 
langage figuré satellite et la télédétection peuvent être 
employés pour surveiller les fleurs d'algues nocives (HABs). 
Cette leçon enseigne à des étudiants comment lire et 
interpréter des images satellites et comment employer des cartes de 
GIs et des images satellites pour interpréter le rapport de 
HABs et de décès de lamantin. L'activité comporte un plan de 
leçon et une activité pas à pas contenant les hyperliens qui 
relient l'étudiant aux images et aux cartes appropriées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade por computador de NOAA é projetada
ensinar a estudantes nas classes 9-12 como o imagery satellite e 
detetar remoto podem ser usados monitorar flores algal prejudiciais 
(HABs). Esta lição ensina a estudantes como ler e interpretar 
imagens satellite e como usar mapas dos SOLDADOS e imagens satellite 
interpretar o relacionamento de HABs e de mortes do manatee. A 
atividade caracteriza uma planta da lição e uma atividade passo a 
passo que contêm os hyperlinks que conectam o estudante às imagens e
aos mapas relevantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività computerizzata di NOAA è 
destinata per insegnare ad allievi nei gradi 9-12 come le immagini 
proveniente dal satellite ed il telerilevamento possono essere usati 
per controllare le fioriture d'alghe nocive (HABs). Questa 
lezione insegna ad allievi come leggere ed interpretare le immagini 
satelliti e come usare i programmi di GIS e le immagini satelliti per 
interpretare il rapporto di HABs e delle morti del manatee. 
L'attività caratterizza un programma di lezione e un'attività 
graduale che contengono i hyperlinks che collegano l'allievo alle 
immagini ed ai programmi relativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η βασισμένη σε υπολογιστή δραστηριότητα NOAA 
έχει ως σκοπό να διδάξει τους σπουδαστές στους βαθμούς 9-12 
πώς τα δορυφορικά καλολογικά στοιχεία και η τηλεπισκόπηση 
μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για να ελέγξουν τις επιβλαβείς 
φυκώδεις ανθίσεις (HABs). Αυτό το μάθημα διδάσκει τους 
σπουδαστές πώς να διαβάσει και να ερμηνεύσει τις δορυφορικές 
εικόνες και πώς να χρησιμοποιήσει τους χάρτες GIS και τις 
δορυφορικές εικόνες για να ερμηνεύσει τη σχέση των θανάτων 
HABs και manatee. Η δραστηριότητα χαρακτηρίζει ένα 
σχέδιο μαθήματος και μια βαθμιαία δραστηριότητα που περιέχουν 
τους συνδέσμους υπερ-κειμένου που συνδέουν το σπουδαστή με τις 
σχετικούς εικόνες και τους χάρτες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad computarizada de NOAA se diseña 
para enseñar a estudiantes en grados 9-12 cómo las imágenes basadas
en los satélites y la detección alejada se pueden utilizar para 
vigilar las floraciones algal dañosas (HABs). Esta lección 
enseña a estudiantes cómo leer e interpretar imágenes basadas en 
los satélites y cómo utilizar correspondencias de los SOLDADOS 
ENROLADOS EN EL EJÉRCITO e imágenes basadas en los satélites para 
interpretar el lazo de HABs y de las muertes del manatee. La 
actividad ofrece un plan de la lección y una actividad paso a paso 
que contienen los hyperlinks que conectan a estudiante con las 
imágenes y las correspondencias relevantes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DATA NATIONAL ENVIRONMENTAL SATELLITE
FN:DATA NATIONAL ENVIRONMENTAL SATELLITE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION
FN:NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203508</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105220</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/investigating-the-ocean-algal-blooms</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
