<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108622</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108622</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087218</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We're Talking About Living Conditions:" Anne and Al Filardo Recall the Struggle for Union Benefits in New York City's Carpenter's Union</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Befassen Uns mit Lebenden Bedingungen:" 
Anne und Al Filardo erinnern an den Kampf für Anschluß-Nutzen 
im Anschluß des Tischlers der New York Stadt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Parlons des Conditions Vivantes :" 
Anne et Al Filardo rappellent la lutte pour des avantages des 
syndicats dans l'union du charpentier de la ville de New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Estamos falando Sobre Circunstâncias 
Vivas:" Anne e o al Filardo recordam o esforço para benefícios
da união na união do carpinteiro da cidade de New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Stiamo parlando Delle Circostanze Di vita:" 
Anne ed Al Filardo ricordano la lotta per i benefici del 
sindacato nell'unione del carpentiere della città de New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μιλάμε για τις συνθήκες διαβίωσης:" Η Anne 
και το Al Filardo υπενθυμίζουν την προσπάθεια για τα οφέλη 
ένωσης στην ένωση του ξυλουργού της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Estamos hablando De Condiciones Vivas:" 
Anne y el al Filardo recuerdan la lucha para las ventajas de la 
unión en la unión del carpintero de la ciudad de Nueva York</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Despite the presence of unions in construction trades, and a postwar construction boom, workers during the 1950s had to struggle and organize to win seemingly small benefits like vacation and paid holidays. Al Filardo, a carpenter who worked in the construction industry in New York, recalled how difficult it was to win any concessions from employers during the union-hostile 1950s, when bosses could initiate FBI investigations of union activity. His wife Anne recalled that workers and their families had a difficult and emotionally draining experience, despite high hourly wages, because of the uncertainty of not knowing when they would find or lose work.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Trotz des Vorhandenseins der Anschlüße im 
Aufbauhandel und einer Nachkriegsaufbauhochkonjunktur mußten Arbeiter
während der fünfziger Jahre kämpfen und organisieren, um scheinbar 
kleinen Nutzen wie Ferien und zahlende Feiertage zu gewinnen. Al
Filardo, ein Tischler, der im Baugewerbe in New York arbeitete, wieder
aufgerufen, wie schwierig es alle mögliche Zugeständnisse von den 
Arbeitgebern während der Anschluß-feindlichen fünfziger Jahre 
gewinnen sollte, als Chefs FBI Untersuchungen der Anschlußaktivität 
initialisieren konnten. Seine Frau Anne rief wieder auf, daß 
Arbeiter und ihre Familien eine schwierige und emotional auslaufende 
Erfahrung, trotz der hohen stündlichen Löhne, wegen der Ungewißheit
des Wissens nicht hatten, als sie Arbeit finden oder verlieren 
würden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En dépit de la présence des syndicats dans les 
commerces de construction, et d'une perche d'après-guerre de 
construction, les ouvriers pendant les années 50 ont dû lutter et 
organiser pour gagner les avantages apparemment petits comme des 
vacances et des vacances payées. Al Filardo, un charpentier qui
a travaillé dans l'industrie du bâtiment à New York, rappelé à 
quel point il difficile était de gagner toutes les concessions des 
employeurs pendant les années 50 union-hostiles, quand les patrons 
pourraient lancer des investigations de FBI sur l'activité des
syndicats. Son épouse Anne s'est rappelée que les ouvriers et 
leurs familles ont eu une expérience difficile et s'écoulante avec 
émotion, en dépit des salaires horaires élevés, en raison de 
l'incertitude de ne pas savoir quand ils trouveraient ou détruiraient
le travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Apesar da presença das uniões em comércios da 
construção, e de um crescimento postwar da construção, os 
trabalhadores durante os 1950s tiveram que esforçar-se e organizar 
para ganhar benefícios seemingly pequenos como férias e feriados 
pagos. Al Filardo, um carpinteiro que trabalhasse na indústria 
de construção em New York, recordado como difícil devia ganhar 
todas as concessões dos empregadores durante os 1950s união-hostis, 
quando as saliências poderiam iniciar investigações de FBI da 
atividade da união. Sua esposa Anne recordou que os 
trabalhadores e suas famílias tiveram uma experiência difícil e 
emocionalmente drenando, apesar dos salários de hora em hora 
elevados, por causa da incerteza de não saber quando encontrariam ou 
perderiam o trabalho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Malgrado la presenza dei sindacati nei commerci 
della costruzione e un'asta dopoguerra della costruzione, gli operai 
durante gli anni 50 hanno dovuto lottare ed organizzare per vincere i 
benefici apparentemente piccoli come la vacanza e le feste paid. 
Al Filardo, un carpentiere che ha lavorato nell'industria 
edilizia a New York, ricordato quanto difficile doveva vincere tutte 
le concessioni dai datori di lavoro durante gli anni 50 unione-ostili,
quando le sporgenze potrebbero iniziare le indagini di FBI su 
attività del sindacato. La sua moglie Anne ha ricordato che gli
operai e le loro famiglie hanno avuti un'esperienza difficile ed 
emozionalmente di scarico, malgrado gli alti stipendi orari, a causa 
dell'incertezza di non sapere quando troverebbero o perderebbero il 
lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρά την παρουσία ενώσεων στα εμπόρια κατασκευής, και
έναν μεταπολεμικό βραχίονα κατασκευής, οι εργαζόμενοι κατά τη 
διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '50 έπρεπε να αγωνιστούν και να 
οργανώσουν να αποκομίσουν φαινομενικά τα μικρά οφέλη όπως τις 
διακοπές και τις πληρωμένες διακοπές. Μπόρεσε να αρχίσει το
Al Filardo, ένας ξυλουργός που εργάστηκε στον κλάδο των 
οικοδομικών και τεχνικών έργων στη Νέα Υόρκη, που υπενθυμίστηκε 
πόσο δύσκολο ήταν να κερδηθούν οποιεσδήποτε παραχωρήσεις από 
τους εργοδότες κατά τη διάρκεια της ένωση-εχθρικής δεκαετίας του
'50, όταν προϊστάμενοι τις έρευνες FBI για τη δραστηριότητα 
ένωσης. Η σύζυγός του Anne υπενθύμισε ότι οι 
εργαζόμενοι και οι οικογένειές τους είχαν μια δύσκολης και 
συναισθηματικά στραγγίγματος εμπειρία, παρά τις υψηλές ωριαίες 
αμοιβές, λόγω της αβεβαιότητας της μη γνώσης όταν θα έβρισκαν ή
θα έχαναν την εργασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A pesar de la presencia de uniones en comercios de
la construcción, y un auge de la posguerra de la construcción, los 
trabajadores durante los años 50 tuvieron que luchar y ordenar para 
ganar ventajas aparentemente pequeñas como vacaciones y días de 
fiesta pagados. Al Filardo, carpintero que trabajó en la 
industria de construcción en Nueva York, recordado cómo es difícil 
debía ganar cualquier concesión de patrones durante los años 50 
unio'n-hostiles, cuando los jefes podrían iniciar investigaciones de 
FBI de la actividad de la unión. Su esposa Anne recordó que 
los trabajadores y sus familias tenían una experiencia difícil y 
emocionalmente de drenaje, a pesar de altos salarios cada hora, debido
a la incertidumbre de no saber cuándo encontrarían o perderían el 
trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087218</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108622</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/were-talking-about-living-conditions-anne-and-al-filardo-recall-the-struggle-for-union-benefits-in-new-york-citys-carpenters-union</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
