<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104711</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104711</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086475</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mind Your Business!: One Woman's Encounter with Reformers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kümmern Sie Sich um Ihr Geschäft!: Ein 
Treffen der Frau mit Reformern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Occupez-vous de Vos Affaires ! : Une 
rencontre de la femme avec des Réformateurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ocupe-se De Seu Negócio!: Um encontro da 
mulher com Reformers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Occupisi Del Vostro Commercio!: Un incontro 
della donna con Reformers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Απασχολήστε την επιχείρησή σας!: Μια σύγκρουση 
της γυναίκας με τους μεταρρυθμιστές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Importe De Su Negocio!: Un encuentro de la 
mujer con los Reformadores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Settlement houses first began appearing in the immigrant and working-class districts of American cities in the 1890s. Over the next four decades, immigrant men and women had a wide range of experiences with settlement house reformers. Some immigrants encountered the settlement houses as places of refuge and caring; at other times, they found reformers to be arrogant and patronizing. Born in Russian Poland around 1885, Anzia Yesierska came to America as a young girl in the 1890s. She rejected the traditional notions of womanhood and marriage dictated by her Jewish immigrant family. She toiled in sweatshops and laundries while she taught herself English and began writing. She married twice but both unions were brief. In her first story, "The Free Vacation House," published in 1915, Yesierska painted the middle-class reformers who tried to help the immigrant heroine as meddling busybodies who disregarded her right to dignity and privacy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Regelung Häuser fingen zuerst an, im Immigranten 
zu erscheinen und Arbeiterklassebezirke der amerikanischen Städte im 
1890s. über den folgenden vier Dekaden, den einwandernden Männern 
und den Frauen hatten eine breite Strecke der Erfahrungen mit Regelung
HausReformern. Einige Immigranten trafen die Regelung 
Häuser als Orte von Schutz und von Interessieren an; zu anderen
Malen fanden sie Reformer, um arrogant und patronizing zu sein. 
Getragen in russischem Polen um 1885, kam Anzia Yesierska nach 
Amerika als junges Mädchen im 1890s. Sie wies die 
traditionellen Begriffe von womanhood und von Verbindung 
vorgeschrieben von ihrer jüdischen einwandernden Familie zurück. 
Sie plagte in den Fabriken mit schlechten 
Arbeitsbedingungen und in den Wäschereien ab, während sie Englisch 
sich beibrachte und anfing zu schreiben. Sie verband zweimal, 
aber beide Anschlüße waren kurz. In ihrer ersten Geschichte 
"das freie Ferien-Haus," veröffentlichte 1915, malte Yesierska die 
MittelklasseReformer, die versuchten, der einwandernden Heldin 
als Einmischung Busybodies zu helfen, die ihr Recht zur Würde und zum
Privatleben mißachteten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les maisons de règlement ont commencé la 
première fois à apparaître dans les zones d'immigré et de classe 
ouvrier des villes américaines dans le 1890s. Pendant les 
quatre décennies suivantes, les hommes et les femmes immigrés ont eu
un éventail d'expériences avec des réformateurs de maison de 
règlement. Quelques immigrés ont rencontré les maisons de 
règlement comme lieux de refuge et de s'inquiéter ; à 
d'autres fois, ils ont trouvé des réformateurs pour être arrogants et
patronnants. Soutenu en Pologne russe autour de 1885, Anzia 
Yesierska est venu en Amérique en tant que jeune fille dans le 1890s.
Elle a rejeté les notions traditionnelles de la condition féminine et 
du mariage dictée par sa famille immigrée juive. Elle 
travaille fort dans les bagnes et les blanchisseries tandis qu'elle 
s'enseignait l'anglais et commençait à écrire. Elle s'est 
mariée deux fois mais les deux syndicats étaient brefs. Dans 
sa première histoire, "la Chambre libre de vacances," a édité en 
1915, Yesierska a peint les réformateurs de classe moyenne qui ont 
essayé d'aider la héroïne immigrée comme mouches du coche 
d'intervention qui ont négligé sa droite à la dignité et à 
l'intimité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As casas do estabelecimento começaram 
primeiramente a aparecer no immigrant e os distritos do working-class 
de cidades americanas no 1890s. sobre as quatro décadas seguintes, os
homens immigrant e as mulheres tiveram uma escala larga das 
experiências com os reformers da casa do estabelecimento. 
Alguns immigrants encontraram as casas do estabelecimento como 
lugares do refúgio e de importar-se; em outras vezes, 
encontraram reformers para ser arrogantes e patronizing. 
Carregado em Poland russian em torno de 1885, Anzia Yesierska 
veio a América como uma menina nova no 1890s. Rejeitou as 
noções tradicionais do womanhood e da união ditada por sua família
immigrant jewish. Labuta nos sweatshops e nas lavanderias quando
se ensinou o inglês e se começou a escrever. Casou-se duas 
vezes mas ambas as uniões eram breves. Em sua primeira 
história, "a casa livre das férias," publicou em 1915, Yesierska 
pintou os reformers do middle-class que tentaram ajudar ao heroine 
immigrant como os busybodies do meddling que negligenciaram sua 
direita à dignidade e à privacidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le case di stabilimento in primo luogo hanno 
cominciato a comparire nell'immigrante ed i distretti della classe 
operaia delle città americane nel 1890s. sopra le quattro decadi 
prossime, gli uomini immigrati e le donne hanno avuti una vasta gamma 
delle esperienze dei reformers della casa di stabilimento. 
Alcuni immigranti hanno incontrato le case di stabilimento come 
posti del rifugio e di preoccuparsi; ad altre volte, hanno 
trovato i reformers per essere arroganti e patronizing. 
Sopportato in Polonia russa verso 1885, Anzia Yesierska è 
venuto in America come ragazza giovane nel 1890s. Ha rifiutato 
le nozioni tradizionali del womanhood e dell'unione dettata dalla sua 
famiglia immigrata ebrea. Lavora duramente in azienda che 
sfrutta la manodopera ed in lavanderie mentre si è insegnato 
l'inglese ed ha cominciato a scrivere. Si è sposata due volte 
ma entrambi i sindacati erano brevi. Nella sua prima storia, "la
Camera libera di vacanza," ha pubblicato in 1915, Yesierska ha 
verniciato i reformers della classe media che hanno provato a aiutare 
il heroine immigrato come busybodies di meddling che hanno ignorato la
sua destra alla dignità ed alla segretezza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα σπίτια τακτοποίησης άρχισαν αρχικά στις περιοχές 
μεταναστών και εργατικών τάξεων των αμερικανικών πόλεων στα 
1890s. Κατά τη διάρκεια των επόμενων τεσσάρων δεκαετιών,
οι που έχουν μεταναστεύσει άνδρες και οι γυναίκες είχαν ένα 
ευρύ φάσμα της εμπειρίας με τους μεταρρυθμιστές σπιτιών 
τακτοποίησης. Μερικοί μετανάστες αντιμετώπισαν τα σπίτια 
τακτοποίησης ως θέσεις του καταφυγίου και της φροντίδας  σε 
άλλους χρόνους, βρήκαν τους μεταρρυθμιστές για να είναι 
αλαζονικούς και πατερναλιστικούς. Γεννημένος στη ρωσική 
Πολωνία περίπου 1885, Anzia Yesierska ήρθε στην Αμερική 
ως νέο κορίτσι στο 1890s. Απέρριψε τις παραδοσιακές 
έννοιες της γυναικείας φύσης και του γάμου που υπαγορεύθηκαν από
την εβραϊκή που έχουν μεταναστεύσει οικογένειά της. 
Κοπίασε στα σκλαβοπάζαρο και τα πλυντήρια ενώ διδάχθηκε 
τα αγγλικά και άρχισε. Πάντρεψε δύο φορές αλλά και οι δύο
ενώσεις ήταν συνοπτικές. Στην πρώτη ιστορία της, "το 
ελεύθερο σπίτι διακοπών," δημοσιευμένος το 1915, Yesierska 
χρωμάτισε τους μεταρρυθμιστές μεσαίων τάξεων που προσπάθησαν να 
βοηθήσουν την που έχουν μεταναστεύσει ηρωϊ'δα ως αναμιγγμένος 
κουτσομπόλες που δεν έλαβαν υπόψη το δικαίωμά της στην 
αξιοπρέπεια και τη μυστικότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las casas del establecimiento primero comenzaron a 
aparecer en el inmigrante y los districtos de la clase obrera de 
ciudades americanas en el 1890s. sobre las cuatro décadas próximas, 
los hombres inmigrantes y las mujeres tenían una amplia gama de 
experiencias con los reformadores de la casa del establecimiento. 
Algunos inmigrantes encontraron las casas del establecimiento 
como lugares del refugio y de cuidar; en otras veces, 
encontraron a reformadores para ser arrogantes y que patronizaban. 
Llevado en Polonia rusa alrededor de 1885, Anzia Yesierska vino 
a América como muchacha joven en el 1890s. Ella rechazó las 
nociones tradicionales del womanhood y de la unión dictada por su 
familia inmigrante judía. Ella trabaja en fábricas de 
explotación y lavaderos mientras que ella se enseñó inglés y 
comenzó a escribir. Ella casó dos veces pero ambas uniones 
eran abreviadas. En su primera historia, "la casa libre de las 
vacaciones," publicó en 1915, Yesierska pintó a reformadores de la 
clase media que intentaron ayudar a la heroína inmigrante como 
busybodies de la intromisión que desatendieron la su derecha a la 
dignidad y a la aislamiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086475</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104711</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/mind-your-business-one-womans-encounter-with-reformers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
