<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106980</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106980</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086978</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The latest model.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das neueste Modell.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le dernier modèle.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O modelo o mais atrasado.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ultimo modello.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πιό πρόσφατο μοντέλο.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El modelo más último.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1820s, operatives in the Lowell cotton mills, mostly women, worked twelve hours a day, six days a week. Holidays were few and short: July Fourth, Thanksgiving, and the first day of spring. In the 1830s, with increased competition, conditions worsened as owners cut wages, raised boarding house rents, or increased workloads. To protest these changes, women went out on strike in 1834 and 1836. This promotional engraving showed a mill woman standing in unlikely repose beside a Fale and Jenks spinning frame. The benign relationship of the figure to the machine may have served to reassure nineteenth-century observers that factory work would not debase virtuous womanhood.""</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im 1820s bearbeiteten Arbeiter in den Lowell 
Baumwollspinnereien, meistens Frauen, zwölf Stunden pro Tag, sechs 
Tage ein Woche. Feiertage waren wenige und kurzes: Juli 
vierter, Thanksgiving und der erste Tag des Frühlinges. des 
1830s mit erhöhter Konkurrenz, schnitten die Bedingungen, die als 
Inhaber verschlechtert wurden, Löhne, warfen verschalendes Mieten auf
oder erhöhten Arbeitsbelastungen. Um diese Änderungen zu 
protestieren, gingen Frauen auf Schlag 1834 und 1836 aus. Dieser
fördernde Stich zeigte eine Tausendstelfrau, die in der 
unwahrscheinlichen Ruhe neben einem Fale und Jenks spinnenden Feld 
steht. Das gutartige Verhältnis der Abbildung zur Maschine kann
gedient haben, 19.-Jahrhundert Beobachtern zu versicheren, daß 
Fabrikarbeit würde nicht verderben rechtschaffenes womanhood.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le 1820s, les employés dans les filatures de coton 
de Lowell, la plupart du temps femmes, ont travaillé douze heures par
jour, six jours par semaine. Les vacances étaient peu et 
courtes : Le quatrième juillet, le Thanksgiving, et le premier 
jour du ressort. Dans le 1830s, avec la concurrence accrue, les 
conditions empirées comme propriétaires ont coupé des salaires, ont
soulevé des loyers de pension, ou ont augmenté des charges de 
travail. Pour protester ces changements, les femmes sont sorties
en grève en 1834 et 1836. Cette gravure promotionnelle a 
montré une femme de moulin se tenant dans le repos peu probable trame
près de Fale et de Jenks de rotation. La relation bénigne de 
la figure à la machine a pu avoir servi à rassurer des observateurs 
de dix-neuvième-siècle que le travail d'usine ne rabaisserait pas la
condition féminine vertueuse.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 1820s, os operatives nos moinhos de algodão de Lowell,
na maior parte mulheres, trabalharam doze horas um o dia, seis dias 
uma semana. Os feriados eram poucos e curtos: Julho 
quarto, Thanksgiving, e o primeiro dia da mola. No 1830s, com 
competição aumentada, as circunstâncias worsened como 
proprietários cortaram salários, levantaram aluguéis de casa 
boarding, ou aumentaram workloads. Para protestar estas 
mudanças, as mulheres saíram na batida em 1834 e em 1836. Este
engraving promotional mostrou uma mulher do moinho que está no repose
improvável ao lado de um frame girando de Fale e de Jenks. O 
relacionamento benigno da figura à máquina pode ter servido 
tranquilizar observadores de décimo-século que o trabalho da 
fábrica não rebaixaria o womanhood virtuous.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel 1820s, gli operatori nei cotonifici de Lowell, 
principalmente donne, hanno lavorato dodici ore al giorno, sei giorni 
un la settimana. Le feste erano poche e corto: Quarto
di luglio, Thanksgiving ed il primo giorno della molla. di 
1830s, con concorrenza aumentata, le circostanze peggiorate come 
proprietari hanno tagliato gli stipendi, hanno sollevato gli affitti 
di casa di imbarco, o hanno aumentato le quote di lavoro. 
Protestare questi cambiamenti, le donne hanno uscito sul colpo 
in 1834 ed in 1836. Questa incisione promozionale ha mostrato 
una donna del laminatoio che si leva in piedi nel riposo improbabile 
al lato di un filatoio di Jenks e di Fale. Il rapporto benigno 
tra la figura e la macchina può servire a riassicurare gli 
osservatori di diciannovesimo-secolo che il lavoro della fabbrica non 
degraderebbe il womanhood virtuoso.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο 1820s, οι χειριστές στους μύλους βαμβακιού του 
Lowell, συνήθως γυναίκες, απασχολήθηκαν σε δώδεκα ώρες 
ημερησίως, έξι ημέρες εβδομαδιαίως. Οι διακοπές ήταν 
λίγες και απότομα: Τέταρτη Ιουλίου, ημέρα των ευχαριστιών,
και η πρώτη ημέρα της άνοιξη. Στο 1830s, με τον 
αυξανόμενο ανταγωνισμό, τους όρους που επιδεινώνονται ως αμοιβές 
αποκοπών ιδιοκτητών, τα αυξημένα μισθώματα ενοικιαζόμενων 
δωματίων, ή τους αυξανόμενους φόρτους εργασίας. Για να 
διαμαρτυρηθούν αυτές τις αλλαγές, οι γυναίκες βγήκαν στην 
απεργία το 1834 και το 1836. Αυτή η προωθητική χάραξη 
εμφάνισε γυναίκα μύλων που στέκεται στην απίθανη ανάπαυση εκτός
από ένα περιστρεφόμενο πλαίσιο Fale και Jenks. Η 
καλοκάγαθη σχέση του αριθμού στη μηχανή μπορεί να είχε 
χρησιμεύσει να καθησυχάσει τους παρατηρητές δέκατος-αιώνα ότι η 
εργασία εργοστασίων δεν θα υποτιμούσε την ενάρετη γυναικεία 
φύση.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el 1820s, los operarios en las fábricas de algodón de
Lowell, sobre todo mujeres, trabajaron doce horas al día, seis días 
una semana. Los días de fiesta eran pocos y cortos: De 
julio el cuarto, Thanksgiving, y el primer día del resorte. Del
1830s, con la competición creciente, las condiciones empeoradas como 
propietarios cortaron salarios, levantaron alquileres de la pensión, 
o aumentaron cargas de trabajo. Protestar estos cambios, las 
mujeres salieron en huelga en 1834 y 1836. Este grabado 
promocional mostró a mujer del molino que estaba parada en descanso 
inverosímil al lado de un marco que hacía girar de Fale y de Jenks. 
El lazo benigno de la figura a la máquina pudo haber servido 
para tranquilizar a observadores del diecinueveavo-siglo que el 
trabajo de la fábrica no rebajaría womanhood virtuoso.""</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086978</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106980</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-latest-model</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
