<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107088</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107088</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086779</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Red Jacket Defends Native American Religion, 1805</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rote Jacke Verteidigt Gebürtige Amerikanische 
Religion, 1805</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Veste Rouge Défend La Religion Américaine 
Indigène, 1805</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Revestimento Vermelho Defende A Religião 
Americana Nativa, 1805</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Rivestimento Rosso Difende La Religione 
Americana Natale, 1805</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κόκκινο σακάκι υπερασπίζει την εγγενή αμερικανική 
θρησκεία, 1805</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Chaqueta Roja Defiende La Religión Americana 
Nativa, 1805</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Senecas, members of the Iroquois Confederacy, fought on the side of the British in the American Revolution. Red Jacket, also known as Sagoyewatha, was a chief and orator born in eastern New York; he derived his English name from his habit of wearing many red coats provided to him by his British allies. After the hostilities, as the British ceded their territories to the Americans, the Senecas and many other Indian peoples faced enormous pressure on their homelands. Red Jacket was a critical mediator in relations between the new U.S. government and the Senecas; he led a delegation that met with George Washington in 1792, when he received a peace medal that appeared in subsequent portraits of the Indian leader. In 1805 a Boston missionary society requested Red Jacket's permission to proselytize among the Iroquois settlements in northern New York State. Red Jacket's forceful defense of native religion, below, caused the representative to refuse the Indian's handshake and announce that no fellowship could exist between the religion of God and the works of the Devil.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Senecas, Bauteile der Irokese-Konföderation, 
kämpften auf der Seite der Briten in der amerikanischen Umdrehung. 
Rote Jacke, alias Sagoyewatha, waren ein Leiter und ein Redner, 
die in Ostnew York geboren waren; er berechnete seinen 
englischen Namen von seiner Gewohnheit des Tragens vieler roter 
Mäntel, die zu ihm von seinen britischen Verbündeten zur Verfügung 
gestellt wurden. Nach den Feindseligkeiten als die Briten, die 
ihren Gegenden zu den Amerikanern überlassen wurden, stellten die 
Senecas und viele andere indische Völker enormen Druck auf ihren 
Heimaten gegenüber. Rote Jacke war ein kritischer Vermittler in
den Relationen zwischen der neuen VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung und den
Senecas; er führte eine Delegation, die George Washington 1792 
traf, als er eine Friedensmedaille empfing, die in den folgenden 
Portraits des indischen Führers erschien. 1805 bat eine Boston 
Missionarsgesellschaft um Erlaubnis der roten Jacke proselytize unter 
den Irokeseregelungen im NordcStaat NEW-YORK. Starke 
Verteidigung der roten Jacke der gebürtigen Religion veranließ unten
den Repräsentanten, den Händedruck des Inders abzulehnen und zu 
verkünden, daß kein Stipendium zwischen der Religion des Gottes und 
den Arbeiten des Teufels existieren könnte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Senecas, membres de la confédération de 
Iroquois, ont combattu du côté des Anglais en révolution 
américaine. La veste rouge, également connue sous le nom de 
Sagoyewatha, était un chef et un orateur nés à New York oriental ; 
il a dérivé son nom anglais de son habitude de porter beaucoup
de manteaux rouges fournis à lui par ses alliés britanniques. 
Après les hostilités, en tant qu'Anglais cédés leurs 
territoires aux Américains, les Senecas et beaucoup d'autres peuples 
indiens ont fait face à l'énorme pression sur leurs patries. 
La veste rouge était un médiateur critique dans les relations 
entre le nouveau gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS et les Senecas ; il
a mené une délégation qui a rencontré George Washington en 
1792, quand il a reçu une médaille de paix qui est apparue en 
verticales ultérieures de l'amorce indienne. En 1805 une 
société de missionnaire de Boston a demandé la permission de la 
veste rouge de convertir parmi les règlements de Iroquois dans 
l'état de New-York nordique. La défense puissante de la veste 
rouge de la religion indigène, ci-dessous, a fait refuser la poignée
de main de l'Indien et annoncer le représentant qu'aucune camaraderie
ne pourrait exister entre la religion de Dieu et les travaux du 
diable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os senecas, membros do confederacy do iroquois, 
lutaram no lado dos Ingleses na volta americana. O revestimento 
vermelho, sabido também como Sagoyewatha, era um chefe e um orator 
carregados em New York oriental; derivou seu nome inglês de seu
hábito de desgastar muitos revestimentos vermelhos fornecidos a ele 
por seus aliados britânicos. Após as hostilidades, como os 
Ingleses ceded seus territórios aos americanos, os senecas e muitos 
outros povos indian enfrentaram a pressão enorme em seus homelands. 
O revestimento vermelho era um mediator crítico nas relações 
entre o governo novo de ESTADOS UNIDOS e os senecas; conduziu a 
um delegation que se encontrasse com com George Washington em 1792, 
quando recebeu uma medalha da paz que aparecesse em retratos 
subseqüentes do líder indian. Em 1805 uma sociedade do 
missionário de Boston pediu a permissão do revestimento vermelho 
proselytize entre os estabelecimentos do iroquois no estado de New 
York do norte. A defesa forceful do revestimento vermelho da 
religião nativa, abaixo, fêz com que o representante recusasse o 
handshake do indian e anunciasse que nenhum fellowship poderia existir
entre a religião do deus e os trabalhos do diabo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I senecas, membri del confederacy del iroquois, 
hanno combattuto dal lato dei Britannici nella rivoluzione americana. 
Il rivestimento rosso, anche conosciuto come Sagoyewatha, era un
capo e un orator sopportati a New York orientale; ha derivato il
suo nome inglese dalla sua abitudine di portare molti cappotti rossi 
forniti lui dai suoi alleati britannici. Dopo le ostilità, come
i Britannici ceduti i loro territori agli Americani, i senecas e molta
altra gente indiana hanno affrontato la pressione enorme sulle loro 
patrie. Il rivestimento rosso era un mediatore critico nei 
rapporti fra il nuovo governo degli STATI UNITI ed i senecas; ha
condotto una delegazione che ha incontrato George Washington in 1792, 
quando ha ricevuto una medaglia di pace che è comparso in ritratti
successivi del capo indiano. In 1805 una società di 
missionario de Boston ha chiesto il permesso del rivestimento rosso 
proselytize fra il iroquois che gli stabilimenti a New York del Nord 
Dichiarano. La difesa valida del rivestimento rosso della 
religione natale, sotto, ha indotto il rappresentante a rifiutare la 
stretta di mano dell'indiano ed ad annunciare che nessun fellowship 
potrebbe esistere fra la religione del dio e gli impianti del diavolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Senecas, μέλη της iroquois συνομοσπονδίας, 
πάλεψε στην πλευρά των Βρετανών στην αμερικανική επανάσταση. 
Το κόκκινο σακάκι, επίσης γνωστό ως Sagoyewatha, ήταν 
προϊστάμενος και ομιλητής γεννημένος στην ανατολική Νέα Υόρκη  
άντλησε το αγγλικό όνομά του από τη συνήθειά του φθοράς 
πολλών κόκκινων παλτών που παρέχηκαν σε τον από τους βρετανικούς
συμμάχους του. Μετά από τις εχθρότητες, δεδομένου ότι οι 
Βρετανοί εξεχώρησαν τα εδάφη τους στους Αμερικανούς, το Senecas
και πολλοί άλλοι ινδικοί λαοί αντιμετώπισαν την τεράστια πίεση 
στις πατρίδες τους. Το κόκκινο σακάκι ήταν ένας κρίσιμος 
μεσολαβητής στις σχέσεις μεταξύ της νέας ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης 
και του Senecas  οδήγησε μια αντιπροσωπεία που συναντήθηκε
με George Ουάσιγκτον το 1792, όταν έλαβε ένα μετάλλιο 
ειρήνης που εμφανίστηκε στα επόμενα πορτρέτα του ινδικού ηγέτη. 
Το 1805 μια ιεραποστολική κοινωνία της Βοστώνης ζήτησε τη
δικαιοδοσία του κόκκινου σακακιού να προσυλητίσει μεταξύ των 
iroquois τακτοποιήσεων στο βόρειο κράτος της Νέας Υόρκης. 
Η ισχυρή υπεράσπιση του κόκκινου σακακιού της εγγενούς 
θρησκείας, κατωτέρω, ανάγκασε τον αντιπρόσωπο για να αρνηθεί τη 
χειραψία του Ινδού και να αναγγείλει ότι καμία υποτροφία δεν θα 
μπορούσε να υπάρξει μεταξύ της θρησκείας του Θεού και των 
εργασιών του διαβόλου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los senecas, miembros del confederacy del 
iroquois, lucharon en la cara de los Británicos en la revolución 
americana. La chaqueta roja, también conocida como Sagoyewatha,
era un jefe y un orador llevados en Nueva York del este; él
derivó su nombre inglés de su hábito de desgastar muchas capas 
rojas proporcionadas a él por sus aliados británicos. Después
de las hostilidades, como los Británicos cedidos sus territorios a 
los americanos, los senecas y mucha otra gente india hicieron frente a
la presión enorme en sus patrias. La chaqueta roja era un 
mediador crítico en relaciones entre el nuevo gobierno de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS y los senecas; él condujo a delegación que satisfizo 
con George Washington en 1792, cuando él recibió una medalla de la 
paz que apareció en retratos subsecuentes del arranque de cinta 
indio. En 1805 una sociedad del misionario de Boston solicitó 
el permiso de la chaqueta roja de ganar prosélitos entre los 
establecimientos del iroquois en el estado de Nueva York norteño. 
La defensa poderosa de la chaqueta roja de la religión nativa, 
abajo, hizo a representante rechazar el apretón de manos del indio y 
anunciar que ninguna beca podría existir entre la religión del dios 
y los trabajos del diablo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086779</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107088</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/red-jacket-defends-native-american-religion-1805</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
