<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105469</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105469</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206261</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">America's Space Program: Exploring a New Frontier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Platz-Programm Amerikas: Erforschen einer 
neuen Grenze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Programme de l'Espace de l'Amérique : 
Explorer une nouvelle frontière</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Programa Do Espaço De América: Explorando 
uma fronteira nova</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programma Dello Spazio Dell'America: 
Esplorazione della frontiera nuova</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαστημικό πρόγραμμα της Αμερικής: Εξερεύνηση 
νέων συνόρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Programa Del Espacio De América: Explorar 
una nueva frontera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of America's journey to the moon. The creation of NASA, the Apollo vehicles, and the January 1967 tragedy are part of the story. On July 20, 1969, as the Eagle lunar module approached the moon, it became clear that the computer had chosen an unacceptable landing site -- a boulder-strewn crater. With 114 seconds of fuel left, astronauts Armstrong and Aldrin overrode the computers and manually landed the Eagle.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte von Reise Amerikas zum 
Mond. Die Kreation der NASAS, die Apollo Träger und die Januar 
1967 Tragödie sind ein Teil der Geschichte. An Juli 20, 1969, 
während das Adlermondmodul dem Mond sich näherte, wurde es frei, 
daß der Computer eine nicht annehmbare Landungsite -- einen 
Flußstein-gestreuten Krater gewählt hatte. Wenn 114 Sekunden 
Kraftstoff gelassen sind, setzten Astronauten Armstrong und Aldrin 
über die Computer ausser Kraft und landeten manuell den Adler.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire du voyage de l'Amérique à la 
lune. La création de la NASA, les véhicules d'Apollo, et la 
tragédie de janvier 1967 font partie de l'histoire. Juillet 20,
1969, pendant que le module lunaire d'aigle approchait la lune, il est
apparu clairement que l'ordinateur avait choisi un site inacceptable 
d'atterrissage -- un cratère rocher-répandu. Les 114 secondes 
de carburant étant laissé, les astronautes Armstrong et l'aldrine 
ont ignoré les ordinateurs et ont manuellement débarqué l'aigle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história da viagem de América à lua. 
A criação da NASA, os veículos de Apollo, e a tragédia de 
janeiro 1967 são parte da história. Julho em 20, 1969, 
enquanto o módulo lunar da águia aproximou a lua, tornou-se 
desobstruído que o computador tinha escolhido um local inaceitável 
da aterragem -- uma cratera pedregulho-boulder-strewn. Com os 
114 segundos do combustível deixados, os astronautas Armstrong e o 
aldrin cancelaram os computadores e aterraram manualmente a águia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia del viaggio dell'America alla 
luna. La creazione della NASA, i veicoli dell'Apollo e la 
tragedia di gennaio del 1967 fanno parte della storia. Il 20 
luglio 1969, mentre il modulo lunare dell'aquila si è avvicinato alla
luna, è essere evidente che il calcolatore aveva scelto un luogo 
inaccettabile di atterraggio -- un cratere masso-sparso. Con 114
secondi di combustibile lasciati, gli atronauti Armstrong e l'aldrina 
escludevano i calcolatori e manualmente hanno atterrato l'aquila.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία του ταξιδιού της Αμερικής στο 
φεγγάρι. Η δημιουργία της NASA, τα οχήματα απόλλωνα, και 
η τραγωδία Ιανουαρίου 1967 είναι μέρος της ιστορίας. 
Στις 20 Ιουλίου ..1969, καθώς η σεληνιακή ενότητα αετών 
πλησίασε το φεγγάρι, έγινε σαφές ότι ο υπολογιστής είχε 
επιλέξει μια απαράδεκτη προσγειωμένος περιοχή -- ένας 
λίθος-σκορπισμένος κρατήρας. 114 Δευτερόλεπτα των 
καυσίμων που αφέθηκαν με, οι αστροναύτες Armstrong και aldrin
υπερίσχυσαν τους υπολογιστές και προσγειώθηκαν χειροκίνιτα τον 
αετό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia del viaje de América a la 
luna. La creación de la NASA, los vehículos de Apolo, y la 
tragedia de enero de 1967 son parte de la historia. De julio el 
20 de 1969, como el módulo lunar del águila acercó a la luna, 
llegó a estar claro que el ordenador había elegido un sitio 
inaceptable del aterrizaje -- un cráter canto-derramado. Con 
114 segundos de combustible dejados, los astronautas Armstrong y el 
aldrin reemplazaron los ordenadores y aterrizaron manualmente el 
águila.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206261</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105469</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/americas-space-program-exploring-a-new-frontier</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
