<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103270</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087201</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Ought to Have the Right to Belong to the Union": Frank Smith Speaks on the 1919 Steel Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir sollen das Recht haben, dem Anschluß zu 
gehören": Aufrichtiger Smith spricht über den Stahlschlag 
1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous devons avoir le droit d'appartenir à 
l'union" : Smith franc parle de la grève 1919 en acier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós ought ter a direita pertencer à união": 
Smith frank fala na batida 1919 de aço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"dobbiamo avere la destra appartenere all'unione":
Smith franco parla sul colpo d'acciaio 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οφείλουμε να έχουμε το δικαίωμα να ανήκουμε στην 
Ένωση": Θ*Φρανκ Smith Speaks στην απεργία χάλυβα του 
1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"ought tener la derecha de pertenecer a la 
unión": Smith franco habla en la huelga de acero 1919</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the dramatic 1919 steel strike, 350,000 workers walked off their jobs and crippled the industry. The U.S. Senate Committee on Education and Labor set out to investigate the strike while it was still in progress. In his testimony before the committee, Hungarian-born Frank Smith, a Clairton worker, used his support for the war effort as evidence of his Americanism. "This is the United States," he argued, "and we ought to have the right to belong to the union."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im drastischen 1919 Stahlschlag gingen 350.000 
Arbeiter weg von ihren Jobs und verkrüppelten die Industrie. 
Der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senat-Ausschuß für Ausbildung und 
Arbeit legte dar, um den Schlag nachzuforschen, während er noch in 
Bewegung war. In seinem Zeugnis vor dem Ausschuß, benutzte 
ungarisch-gebürtiger aufrichtiger Smith, ein Clairton Arbeiter, 
seinen Support für die Kriegbemühung als Beweis seines 
Amerikanismus. "dieses ist die Vereinigten Staaten," 
argumentierte er, "und wir sollen das Recht haben, dem Anschluß zu 
gehören."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les 1919 grèves en acier excessive, 350.000 
ouvriers ont marché outre de leurs travaux et ont estropié 
l'industrie. Le comité de sénat des ETATS-UNIS de l'éducation
et du travail s'est mis à étudier la grève tandis qu'elle était 
encore en marche. Dans son témoignage devant le comité, Smith 
franc d'origine hongroise, un ouvrier de Clairton, a utilisé son 
support pour l'effort de guerre comme évidence de son Américanisme. 
"c'est les Etats-Unis," il a discuté, "et nous devons avoir le 
droit d'appartenir à l'union."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas 1919 batidas de aço dramática, 350.000 
trabalhadores andaram fora de seus trabalhos e aleijaram a indústria.
O comitê do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na instrução e no 
trabalho ajustou-se para fora para investigar a batida quando era 
ainda em andamento. Em seu testimony antes do comitê, Smith 
frank hungarian-born, um trabalhador de Clairton, usou sua 
sustentação para o esforço da guerra como a evidência de seu 
americanism. "este é os estados unidos," discutiu, "e nós 
ought ter a direita pertencer à união."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nei 1919 colpi d'acciaio drammatico, 350.000 
operai hanno camminato fuori dei loro lavori ed hanno paralizzato 
l'industria. Il comitato del senato degli STATI UNITI di 
formazione e del Lavoro ha precisato per studiare il colpo 
mentre era ancora in progresso. Nella sua testimonianza prima 
del comitato, Smith franco hungarian-born, un operaio di Clairton, ha 
usato il suo supporto per lo sforzo di guerra come prova del suo 
americanism. "questo è unito Dichiara," ha discusso, "e
dobbiamo avere la destra appartenere all'unione."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δραματική απεργία χάλυβα του 1919, 350.000 
εργαζόμενοι περπάτησαν από τις εργασίες τους και ακρωτηρίασαν τη 
βιομηχανία. Η Επιτροπή ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου της 
εκπαίδευσης και η εργασία καθόρισαν να ερευνήσουν την απεργία 
ενώ ήταν ακόμα υπό εξέλιξη. Στην κατάθεσή του ενώπιον 
της επιτροπής, ο γεννημένος στην Ουγγαρία Frank Smith, ένας 
εργαζόμενος Clairton, χρησιμοποίησε την υποστήριξή του για την 
πολεμική προσπάθεια ως στοιχεία του Americanism του. 
"Αυτά είναι οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες," υποστήριξε, "και 
οφείλουμε να έχουμε το δικαίωμα ανήκω στην ένωση."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las 1919 huelgas de acero dramática, 350.000 
trabajadores recorrieron de sus trabajos y lisiaron la industria. 
El comité del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre la educación y el
trabajo precisó para investigar la huelga mientras que todavía 
estaba en marcha. En su testimonio ante el comité, Smith franco
húngaro-nacido, trabajador de Clairton, utilizó su ayuda para el 
esfuerzo de la guerra como evidencia de su americanism. "éste 
es los Estados Unidos," él discutió, "y ought tener la derecha de 
pertenecer a la unión."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087201</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103270</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-ought-to-have-the-right-to-belong-to-the-union-frank-smith-speaks-on-the-1919-steel-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
