<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103624</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103624</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204583</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Submarines: Using mass, volume and density to create a working submarine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterseeboote: Verwenden der Masse, des 
Datenträgers und der Dichte, um ein Arbeitsunterseeboot herzustellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sous-marins : Utilisation de la masse, du 
volume et de la densité pour créer un sous-marin fonctionnant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Submarinos: Usando a massa, o volume e a 
densidade criar um submarino trabalhando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sommergibile: Usando massa, volume e 
densità per creare un sommergibile funzionante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποβρύχια: Χρησιμοποίηση της μάζας, της έντασης 
του ήχου και της πυκνότητας για να δημιουργήσει ένα λειτουργώντας
υποβρύχιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Submarinos: Usar la masa, el volumen y la 
densidad para crear un submarino de trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The students will design a submarine that will float, subsurface, sink, and return once again to the water's surface by external manipulation of the submarine outside of an aquarium. In order to accomplish this, the students will use not only the concepts of mass, volume, and density but will also integrate buoyancy and ballast in their submarine design.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kursteilnehmer konzipieren ein Unterseeboot, 
das schwimmt, Boden unter der Oberfläche, Wanne und kommen noch 
einmal zur Oberfläche des Wassers durch externe Handhabung der 
Unterwasseraußenseite eines Aquariums zurück. Um dieses zu 
vollenden, verwenden die Kursteilnehmer nicht nur die Konzepte der 
Masse, des Datenträgers und der Dichte aber integrieren auch 
Tragvermögen und Drossel in ihrem Unterwasserdesign.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants concevront un sous-marin qui 
flottera, la sous-surface, évier, et reviennent de nouveau à la 
surface de l'eau par la manipulation externe de l'extérieur 
submersible d'un aquarium. Afin d'accomplir ceci, les étudiants
emploieront non seulement les concepts de la masse, du volume, et de 
la densité mais intégreront également la flottabilité et le 
ballast dans leur conception submersible.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes projetarão um submarino que flutue,
a subsuperfície, o dissipador, e o retorno uma vez outra vez à 
superfície da água pela manipulação externa da parte externa 
submarina de um aquário. A fim realizar este, os estudantes 
usarão não somente os conceitos da massa, do volume, e da densidade 
mas integrarão também o buoyancy e o reator em seu projeto 
submarino.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi progetteranno un sommergibile che 
galleggerà, la sottosuperficie, dispersore e ritornano ancora una 
volta alla superficie dell'acqua tramite manipolazione esterna della 
parte esterna sottomarina di un acquario. Per compire questo, 
gli allievi useranno non soltanto i concetti di massa, di volume e di 
densità ma egualmente integreranno la galleggiabilità e la reattanza
nel loro disegno sottomarino.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα σχεδιάσουν ένα υποβρύχιο που θα 
επιπλεύσει, υποεπιφάνεια, νεροχύτης, και επιστροφή άλλη μια φορά
στην επιφάνεια του ύδατος από τον εξωτερικό χειρισμό του 
υποβρυχίου έξω από ένα ενυδρείο. Προκειμένου να 
ολοκληρωθεί αυτό, οι σπουδαστές θα χρησιμοποιήσουν όχι μόνο τις 
έννοιες της μάζας, της έντασης του ήχου, και της πυκνότητας αλλά
θα ενσωματώσουν επίσης την πλευστότητα και το έρμα στο υποβρύχιο 
σχέδιό τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes diseñarán un submarino que 
flote, la superficie inferior, fregadero, y vuelven de nuevo a la 
superficie del agua por la manipulación externa del exterior 
submarino de un acuario. Para lograr esto, los estudiantes 
utilizarán no solamente los conceptos de la masa, del volumen, y de 
la densidad pero también integrarán flotabilidad y el lastre en su 
diseño submarino.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AMY KOONCE
FN:AMY KOONCE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204583</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103624</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/submarines-using-mass-volume-and-density-to-create-a-working-submarine</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
