<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103044</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103044</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087168</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Waitin' on Roosevelt": Langston Hughes's "Ballad of Roosevelt"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Waitin ' auf Roosevelt": Langston Hughess 
"Ballade von Roosevelt"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Waitin 'sur Roosevelt" : Ballade de 
Langston Hughes "de Roosevelt"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Waitin ' em Roosevelt": Ballad de Langston 
Hughes "de Roosevelt"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Waitin 'su Roosevelt": Ballad di Langston 
Hughes "di Roosevelt"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Waitin" σε Roosevelt ": Μπαλάντα του 
Hughes Langston "Roosevelt"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Waitin ' en Roosevelt": Balada de Langston 
Hughes "de Roosevelt"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The relationship between African Americans and Franklin D. Roosevelt presents something of a paradox. On the one hand, Roosevelt never endorsed anti-lynching legislation; he accepted segregation and disenfranchisement; and he condoned discrimination against blacks in federally funded relief programs. On the other hand, Roosevelt won the hearts and the votes of African Americans in unprecedented numbers. African Americans who supported left-wing parties, however, were more likely to be critical. Langston Hughes, a playwright, poet, and novelist, became a socialist in the 1930s. Although he did not join the Communist Party, he spent a year in the Soviet Union and published his works in magazines sympathetic to liberal, socialist, and Communist causes. In Hughes's "Ballad of Roosevelt," which appeared in the  New Republic  in 1934, the poet criticized the unfulfilled promises that FDR had made to the poor. Hughes's style in this poem showed his distinctive merging of traditional verse with black artistic forms like blues and jazz.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Verhältnis zwischen afrikanischen Amerikaner-
und Franklind. Roosevelt Geschenken etwas eines Paradoxes. 
Einerseits indossierte Roosevelt nie Anti-lynchende 
Gesetzgebung; er nahm Abtrennung und disenfranchisement an; 
und er verzieh Diskriminierung gegen Schwarze in föderativ 
gefinanzierten Entlastung Programmen. Andererseits gewann 
Roosevelt die Inneren und die Stimmen der afrikanischen Amerikaner in 
beispiellosen Zahlen. Afrikanische Amerikaner, die left-wing 
Parteien jedoch unterstützten waren wahrscheinlicher, kritisch 
zu sein. Langston Hughes, ein Stückeschreiber, Dichter und 
Novelist, stand einem Sozialisten in den dreißiger Jahren. 
Obgleich er nicht die kommunistische Partei verband, 
verbrachte er ein Jahr im Sowjet-Anschluß und veröffentlichte seine 
Arbeiten in den Zeitschriften, die zu den liberalen, sozialistischen 
und Kommunistursachen sympatisch sind. Hughess "in der Ballade 
von Roosevelt,", die in der neuen Republik 1934 erschien, kritisierte 
der Dichter die unausgeführten Versprechungen, die FDR den Armen 
gebildet hatte. Art Hughess in diesem Gedicht zeigte sein 
unterscheidendes Mergen des traditionellen Verses mit 
schwarzen künstlerischen Formularen wie Blau und Jazz.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le rapport entre les présents africains 
d'Américains et de Franklin D. Roosevelt quelque chose d'un paradoxe.
D'une part, Roosevelt n'a jamais approuvé la législation 
anti-lynchante ; il a reçu la ségrégation et le 
disenfranchisement ; et il a pardonné la discrimination contre 
des noirs dans des programmes fédéralement placés de soulagement. 
D'autre part, Roosevelt a gagné les coeurs et les voix des 
Américains africains dans des nombres sans précédent. Les 
Américains africains qui ont supporté les parties de gauche, 
cependant, étaient pour être critiques. Langston Hughes, un 
dramaturge, poèt, et romancier, est allé bien à un socialiste dans 
les années 30. Bien qu'il n'ait pas joint le parti communiste, 
il a passé une année dans Union Soviétique et a édité ses travaux en 
magasins sympathiques aux causes libérales, socialistes, et de 
communiste. En ballade de Hughes "de Roosevelt," qui est parue 
dans la nouvelle République en 1934, le poèt a critiqué les 
promesses non atteintes que le FDR avait faites aux pauvres. Le 
modèle de Hughes en cette poésie a montré son fusionnement 
distinctif du vers traditionnel avec les formes artistiques noires 
comme des bleus et le jazz.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O relacionamento entre presentes africanos dos 
americanos e do Franklin D. Roosevelt algo de um paradox. Na uma
mão, Roosevelt nunca endossou a legislação anti-anti-lynching; 
aceitou o segregation e o disenfranchisement; e desculpou 
a discriminação de encontro aos pretos em programas federal 
financiados do relevo. Na outra mão, Roosevelt ganhou os 
corações e os votos de americanos africanos em números 
unprecedented. Os americanos africanos que suportaram partidos 
left-wing, entretanto, eram mais prováveis ser críticos. 
Langston Hughes, um playwright, poeta, e novelist, assentou bem 
em um socialist nos 1930s. Embora não juntasse o partido 
comunista, gastou um ano na Soviete-união e publicou seus trabalhos 
nos compartimentos sympathetic às causas liberais, socialist, e do 
comunista. Ballad de Hughes no "de Roosevelt," que se publicou 
na república nova em 1934, o poeta criticou as promessas unfulfilled 
que o FDR tinha feito aos pobres. O estilo de Hughes neste poema
mostrou seu fundir distintivo do verso tradicional com os formulários
artísticos pretos como azuis e jazz.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il rapporto fra i presenti africani del Franklin e
degli Americani D. Roosevelt qualcosa di un paradosso. Sull'una 
mano, Roosevelt non ha firmato mai la legislazione anti-anti-lynching;
ha accettato la segregazione ed il disenfranchisement; ed 
ha perdonato la distinzione contro i neri nei programmi federalmente 
costituiti un fondo per di rilievo. D'altra parte, Roosevelt ha 
vinto i cuori ed i voti degli Americani africani nei numeri senza 
precedente. Gli Americani africani che hanno sostenuto i partiti
left-wing, tuttavia, erano più probabili essere critici. 
Langston Hughes, un playwright, poet e romanziere, ha stato 
bene ad un socialista nei 1930s. Anche se non ha unito il 
partito comunista, ha speso un anno nell'Soviet-unione ed 
ha pubblicato i suoi impianti in scomparti simpatici alle cause 
liberali, socialiste e del comunista. In ballad del Hughes "di 
Roosevelt," che è stato publicato nella nuova Repubblica in 1934, il 
poet ha criticato le promesse non realizzate che il FDR aveva fatto al
povero. Lo stile del Hughes in questo poem ha mostrato la 
sua fusione distintiva del verse tradizionale con le forme artistiche 
nere come gli azzurri ed il jazz.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σχέση μεταξύ αφρικανικοί Αμερικανών και Franklin 
Δ. Roosevelt παρουσιάζει κάτι ενός παραδόξου. Αφ' ενός, 
Roosevelt δεν επικύρωσε ποτέ τη νομοθεσία αντι-λυντσαρίσματος  
αποδέχθηκε το διαχωρισμό και το disenfranchisement  
και συγχώρησε τη διάκριση ενάντια στους Μαύρους στα 
ομοσπονδιακά χρηματοδοτημένα προγράμματα ανακούφισης. Αφ' 
ετέρου, Roosevelt κέρδισε τις καρδιές και τις ψηφοφορίες 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών στους πρωτοφανείς αριθμούς. 
Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί που υποστήριξαν τα αριστερά 
συμβαλλόμενα μέρη, εντούτοις, ήταν πιθανότερο να είναι 
κρίσιμοι. Το Langston Hughes, ένας θεατρικός 
συγγραφέας, ένας ποιητής, και ένας μυθιστοριογράφος, έγιναν 
σοσιαλιστής στη δεκαετία του '30. Αν και δεν προσχώρησε στο 
Κομμουνιστικό Κόμμα, πέρασε ένα έτος στη Σοβιετική Ένωση και 
δημοσίευσε τις εργασίες του στα περιοδικά συμπονετικά στις 
φιλελεύθερες, σοσιαλιστικές, και κομμουνιστικές αιτίες. 
Μπαλάντα του Hughes στη "Roosevelt," που εμφανίστηκε στη
νέα Δημοκρατία το 1934, ο ποιητής επέκρινε τις ανεκπλήρωτες 
υποσχέσεις που FDR είχε κάνει στους φτωχούς. Το ύφος του
Hughes σε αυτό το ποίημα εμφάνισε διακριτική συγχώνευση 
παραδοσιακού στίχου του με τις μαύρες καλλιτεχνικές μορφές όπως 
τα μπλε και την τζαζ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El lazo entre los presentes africanos de los 
americanos y de Franklin D. Roosevelt algo de una paradoja. En 
la una mano, Roosevelt nunca endosó la legislación 
contra-anti-lynching; él validó la segregación y el 
disenfranchisement; y él perdonó la discriminación contra 
negros en programas federal financiados de la relevación. Por 
otra parte, Roosevelt ganó los corazones y los votos de americanos 
africanos en números sin precedentes. Los americanos africanos 
que utilizaron partidos izquierdistas, sin embargo, eran más 
probables ser críticos. Langston Hughes, dramaturgo, poeta, y 
novelista, sintió bien a un socialista en los años 30. Aunque 
él no ensambló el partido comunista, él pasó un año en la 
Soviet-unio'n y publicó sus trabajos en los compartimientos 
comprensivos a las causas liberales, socialistas, y del comunista. 
En balada de Hughes la "de Roosevelt," que apareció en la nueva
república en 1934, el poeta criticó las promesas incumplidas que el 
FDR había hecho a los pobres. El estilo de Hughes en este poema
mostró su combinación distintiva del verso tradicional con las 
formas artísticas negras como azul y jazz.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087168</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103044</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/waitin-on-roosevelt-langston-hughess-ballad-of-roosevelt</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
