<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103208</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103208</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206637</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Civil War through a Child's Eye</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Bürgerkrieg durch das Auge eines Kindes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La guerre civile par l'oeil d'un enfant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A guerra civil através do olho de uma criança</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La guerra civile attraverso l'occhio del bambino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο εμφύλιος πόλεμος μέσω του ματιού ενός παιδιού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La guerra civil a través del ojo de un niño</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a lesson plan that uses historical fiction and primary sources to expand students' perceptions of the Civil War era. Photos, non-fiction, and literature (Paul Fleischman's Bull Run) help students see this era from a child's perspective.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Lektionplan, der historische Erfindung und
Primärquellen verwendet, um Vorstellungen der Kursteilnehmer der 
Bürgerkriegära zu erweitern. Fotos, Nichterfindung und 
Kursteilnehmer Hilfe der Literatur (Paul Fleischmans Bull Durchlauf) 
sehen diese Ära von der Perspektive eines Kindes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un plan de leçon qui emploie la fiction 
historique et les sources primaires pour augmenter les perceptions des
étudiants de l'ère de guerre civile. Les photos, la 
non-fiction, et les étudiants d'aide de littérature (passage de Bull
de Paul Fleischman) voient cette ère de la perspective d'un enfant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma planta da lição que use o fiction 
histórico e fontes preliminares expandir percepções dos estudantes 
da era da guerra civil. As fotos, o non-non-fiction, e os 
estudantes da ajuda da literatura (funcionamento de Bull de Paul 
Fleischman) vêem esta era do perspective de uma criança.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un programma di lezione che usa il romanzo 
storico e le sorgenti primarie per espandere le percezioni degli 
allievi dell'era di guerra civile. Le foto, il non-romanzo e gli
allievi di aiuto della letteratura (funzionamento di Bull del Paul 
Fleischman) vedono questa era dalla prospettiva del bambino.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα σχέδιο μαθήματος που χρησιμοποιεί την 
ιστορική μυθιστοριογραφία και τις αρχικές πηγές για να επεκτείνει
τις αντιλήψεις των σπουδαστών για την εποχή εμφύλιου πολέμου. 
Οι φωτογραφίες, non-fiction, και οι σπουδαστές οδηγιών 
λογοτεχνίας (Bull Paul Fleischman's που οργανώνεται) 
βλέπουνε αυτήν την εποχή από την προοπτική ενός παιδιού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un plan de la lección que utiliza la ficción 
histórica y fuentes primarias para ampliar las opiniones de los 
estudiantes de la era de la guerra civil. Las fotos, la 
no-ficcio'n, y los estudiantes de la ayuda de la literatura 
(funcionamiento de Bull de Paul Fleischman) ven esta era de la 
perspectiva de un niño.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206637</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103208</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-civil-war-through-a-childs-eye</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
