<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108117</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108117</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086279</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Didn't Raise My Boy to Be a Soldier": Singing Against the War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich hob nicht meinen Jungen an, um ein Soldat zu 
sein": Singen gegen den Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je n'ai pas élevé mon garçon pour être un 
soldat" : Chant contre la guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu não levantei meu menino para ser um soldado": 
Cantar de encontro à guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non ho alzato il mio ragazzo per essere un 
soldato": Cantando contro la guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"δεν ανέθρεψα το αγόρι μου για να είμαι στρατιώτησ": 
Τραγούδι ενάντια στον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no crié a mi muchacho para ser soldado": El
cantar contra la guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By 1915, Americans began debating the need for military and economic preparations for war. Strong opposition to "preparedness" came from isolationists, socialists, pacifists, many Protestant ministers, German Americans, and Irish Americans (who were hostile to Britain). One of the hit songs of 1915, "I Didn't Raise My Boy to Be a Soldier," by lyricist Alfred Bryan and composer Al Piantadosi, captured widespread American skepticism about joining in the European war. Meanwhile, interventionists and militarists like former president Theodore Roosevelt beat the drums for preparedness. Roosevelt's retort to the popularity of the antiwar song was that it should be accompanied by the tune "I Didn't Raise My Girl to Be a Mother." He suggested that the place for women who opposed war was "in China--or by preference in a harem--and not in the United States."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum 1915 fingen Amerikaner an, die 
Notwendigkeit an den militärischen und ökonomischen Vorbereitungen 
für Krieg zu debattieren. Starke Opposition "zur Bereitschaft" 
kam von den Isolationisten, von den Sozialisten, von den pacifists, 
von vielen protestierenden Ministern, von den deutschen Amerikanern 
und von den irischen Amerikanern (wer nach Großbritannien feindlich 
waren). Eins der Hitliede von 1915, "ich hob nicht meinen Jungen
an, um ein Soldat," durch Lyriker Alfred Bryan und Komponist Al 
Piantadosi, erfaßte weitverbreitete amerikanische Skepsis zu sein 
über das Anschließen den europäischen Krieg. Unterdessen 
schlugen Interventionisten und militarists wie ehemaliger Präsident 
Theodore Roosevelt die Trommeln für Bereitschaft. Retorte 
Roosevelts zur Popularität des Antikriegslieds war, daß sie von der 
Melodie begleitet werden sollte, ", das ich nicht mein Mädchen anhob,
um eine Mutter zu sein." Er schlug vor, daß der Platz für 
Frauen, die Krieg entgegensetzten, war "in China -- oder durch 
Präferenz in einem Harem -- und nicht in den Vereinigten Staaten."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">D'ici 1915, les Américains ont commencé à 
discuter le besoin de préparations militaires et économiques pour la
guerre. L'opposition forte au l'"état de préparation" est 
venue des isolationnistes, des socialistes, des pacifistes, de beaucoup 
de ministres protestants, des Américains allemands, et des 
Américains irlandais (qui étaient hostiles en Grande-Bretagne). 
Une des chansons de coup de 1915, "je n'ai pas élevé mon 
garçon pour être un soldat," par l'auteur lyrique Alfred Bryan et 
l'Al Piantadosi, scepticisme américain répandu capturé de 
compositeur au sujet de s'associer à la guerre européenne. En 
attendant, les interventionnistes et les militarists comme l'ancien 
Président Theodore Roosevelt ont battu les tambours pour l'état de 
préparation. La cornue de Roosevelt à la popularité de la 
chanson pacifiste était qu'elle devrait être accompagnée de l'air 
"que je n'ai pas élevé ma fille pour être une mère." Il a 
proposé que l'endroit pour les femmes qui se sont opposées à la 
guerre ait été "en Chine -- ou par préférence dans un harem -- et 
pas aux Etats-Unis."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Por 1915, os americanos começaram a debater a 
necessidade para preparações militares e econômicas para a guerra. 
A oposição forte ao "preparedness" veio dos isolationists, dos
socialists, dos pacifists, de muitos ministros protestant, dos 
americanos alemães, e dos americanos irish (quem eram hostis a Grâ 
Bretanha). Uma das canções da batida de 1915, "eu não 
levantei meu menino para ser um soldado," pelo lyricist Alfred Bryan e
pelo al Piantadosi do compositor, skepticism americano difundido 
capturado sobre juntar na guerra européia. Entrementes, os 
interventionists e os militarists como o presidente anterior Theodore 
Roosevelt bateram os cilindros para o preparedness. O retort de 
Roosevelt à popularidade da canção antiwar era que deve ser 
acompanhado pelo tune "que eu não levantei minha menina para ser uma 
matriz." Sugeriu que o lugar para as mulheres que opuseram a 
guerra estava "em China -- ou pela preferência em um harem -- e não 
nos estados unidos."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro 1915, gli Americani hanno cominciato a 
dibattere l'esigenza delle preparazioni militari ed economiche per la 
guerra. L'opposizione forte "alla preparazione" è venuto dai 
isolationists, dai socialisti, dai pacifists, da molti ministri 
protestanti, dagli Americani tedeschi e dagli Americani irlandesi (chi
erano ostili in Gran-Bretagna). Una delle canzoni di colpo di 
1915, "non ho alzato il mio ragazzo per essere un soldato," dal 
lyricist Alfred Bryan e da Al Piantadosi, scetticismo americano 
diffuso bloccato del compositore circa associarsi alla guerra europea.
Nel frattempo, gli interventisti ed i militarists come l'ex 
presidente Theodore Roosevelt hanno battuto i tamburi per la 
preparazione. La storta del Roosevelt alla popolarità della 
canzone pacifista era che dovrebbe essere accompagnata dall'aria "che 
non ho alzato la mia ragazza per essere una madre." Ha suggerito
che il posto per le donne che hanno opposto la guerra era "in Cina -- 
o dalla preferenza in un harem -- e non in unito Dichiara."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέχρι το 1915, Αμερικανοί άρχισαν την ανάγκη για 
τις στρατιωτικές και οικονομικές προετοιμασίες για τον πόλεμο. 
Η ισχυρή αντίθεση "στην προπαρασκευή" προήλθε από τους 
απομονωτιστές, τους σοσιαλιστές, τα pacifists, πολλούς 
προτεσταντικούς υπουργούς, γερμανικούς Αμερικανούς, και 
ιρλανδικούς Αμερικανούς (που ήταν εχθρικοί στη Μεγάλη Βρετανία).
Ένα από τα τραγούδια χτυπήματος του 1915, "δεν ανέθρεψα 
το αγόρι μου για να είμαι στρατιώτης," από το lyricist 
Alfred Bryan και το Al Piantadosi, συλλήφθείτε 
διαδεδομένος αμερικανικός σκεπτικισμός συνθετών για την ένωση 
στον ευρωπαϊκό πόλεμο. Εν τω μεταξύ, οι οπαδοί του 
παρεμβατισμού και τα militarists όπως τον προηγούμενο Πρόεδρο 
Theodore Roosevelt κτυπούν τα τύμπανα για την προπαρασκευή. 
Η ανταπάντηση του Roosevelt στη δημοτικότητα του 
αντιπολεμικού τραγουδιού ήταν ότι πρέπει να συνοδευθεί από τον 
τόνο "που δεν ανέθρεψα το κορίτσι μου για να είμαι μητέρα." 
Πρότεινε ότι η θέση για τις γυναίκες που αντέταξαν τον 
πόλεμο είμαι "στην Κίνα -- ή από την προτίμηση σε ένα harem 
-- και όχι στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes de 1915, los americanos comenzaron a discutir
la necesidad de las preparaciones militares y económicas para la 
guerra. La oposición fuerte al "estado de preparación" vino de
isolationists, de socialistas, de pacifists, de muchos ministros 
protestantes, de americanos alemanes, y de americanos irlandeses 
(quiénes eran hostiles a Gran Bretaña). Una de las canciones 
del golpe de 1915, "no crié a mi muchacho para ser soldado," por el 
autor Alfred Bryan y el al Piantadosi, escepticismo americano extenso 
capturado del compositor sobre ensamblar en la guerra europea. 
Mientras tanto, los intervencionistas y los militarists como 
presidente anterior Theodore Roosevelt batieron los tambores para el 
estado de preparación. La réplica de Roosevelt al renombre de 
la canción pacifista era que debe ser acompañada por la consonancia 
"que no crié a mi muchacha para ser una madre." Él sugirió 
que el lugar para las mujeres que opusieron guerra estuviera "en China
-- o por preferencia en un harem -- y no en los Estados Unidos."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086279</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108117</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-didnt-raise-my-boy-to-be-a-soldier-singing-against-the-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
