<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106228</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106228</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086750</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pocahontas Rescuing Captain John Smith .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pocahontas Rettender Kapitän John Smith.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Capitaine de Délivrance John Smith de Pocahontas.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capitão Salvando John Smith De Pocahontas.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitano Di Salvataggio John Smith Di Pocahontas.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Pocahontas που διασώζει τον καπετάνιο John 
Smith.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capitán De Rescate Juan Smith De Pocahontas.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the Great Depression, New Deal programs provided work for a range of unemployed Americans, including visual artists who were commissioned to paint murals in federal buildings around the country. Some of these painters found that their expressions clashed with local tastes, particularly when murals portrayed American society, past and present, in a critical light. In the case of this mural for Richmond's Parcel Post Building by Paul Cadmus, titled Pocahontas Rescuing Captain John Smith</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des großen Tiefstands stellten Programme des 
neuen Abkommens Arbeit für eine Strecke der arbeitslosen Amerikaner, 
einschließlich Sichtkünstler zur Verfügung, die beauftragen wurden,
Wandbilder in den Bundesgebäuden um das Land zu malen. Einige 
dieser Maler fanden, daß ihre Ausdrücke mit lokalem Geschmack 
zusammenstießen, besonders als Wandbilder amerikanische Gesellschaft 
schilderten, hinter und anwesend, in einem kritischen Licht. Im 
Fall dieses Wandbildes für Gepäckpost-Gebäude Richmonds durch Paul 
Cadmus, betitelt Pocahontas rettenden Kapitän John Smith</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la grande dépression, les programmes de nouvelle 
affaire ont fourni le travail pour un intervalle des Américains sans 
emploi, y compris les artistes visuels qui ont été commissionnés 
peindre des muraux dans les bâtiments fédéraux dans le pays. 
Certains de ces peintres ont constaté que leurs expressions se 
sont opposées avec le goût local, en particulier quand les muraux 
ont dépeint la société américaine, après et actuel, dans une 
lumière critique. Dans le cas de ce mural pour le bâtiment de 
service des colis postaux de Richmond par Paul Cadmus, intitulé 
capitaine de délivrance John Smith de Pocahontas</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o depression grande, os programas do negócio novo
forneceram o trabalho para uma escala de americanos unemployed, 
including os artistas visuais que comissão pintar murals em 
edifícios federais em torno do país. Alguns destes pintores 
encontraram que suas expressões clashed com gosto local, 
particularmente quando os murals portrayed a sociedade americana, 
após e atual, em uma luz crítica. No exemplo deste mural para 
o edifício do borne de pacote de Richmond por Paul Cadmus, intitulado
capitão salvando John Smith de Pocahontas</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la depressione grande, i programmi di nuovo affare
hanno fornito il lavoro per una gamma di Americani disoccupati, 
compreso gli artisti visivi che sono stati incaricati di verniciare i 
murals in costruzioni federali intorno al paese. Alcuni di 
questi pittori hanno trovato che le loro espressioni clashed con gusto
locale, specialmente quando i murals hanno ritratto la società 
americana, oltre e presente, ad una luce critica. Nel caso di 
questo mural per la costruzione del servizio pacchi postali de 
Richmond da Paul Cadmus, nominato capitano di salvataggio John Smith 
di Pocahontas</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης, τα 
νέα προγράμματα διαπραγμάτευσης παρείχαν την εργασία για μια 
σειρά άνεργων Αμερικανών, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των εικαστηκών 
καλλιτεχνών που ανατέθηκαν για να χρωματίσουν τις τοιχογραφίες στα
ομοσπονδιακά κτήρια γύρω από τη χώρα. Μερικοί από αυτούς
τους ζωγράφους διαπίστωσαν ότι οι εκφράσεις τους διαφώνησαν με 
τις τοπικές προτιμήσεις, ιδιαίτερα όταν απεικόνισαν οι 
τοιχογραφίες την αμερικανική κοινωνία, προηγούμενος και παρών, σε
ένα κρίσιμο φως. Στην περίπτωση αυτής της τοιχογραφίας για 
το κτήριο υπηρεσιών αποστολής δεμάτων του Ρίτσμοντ από Paul 
Cadmus, με τον τίτλο Pocahontas που διασώζει τον καπετάνιο 
John Smith</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la gran depresión, los programas del nuevo 
reparto proporcionaron al trabajo para un rango de americanos parados,
incluyendo los artistas visuales que fueron comisionados pintar murals
en edificios federales alrededor del país. Algunos de estos 
pintores encontraron que sus expresiones clashed con gusto local, 
determinado cuando los murals retrataron a sociedad americana, más 
allá de y presente, en una luz crítica. En el caso de este 
mural para el edificio del servicio postal de paquetes de Richmond de 
Paul Cadmus, titulado capitán de rescate Juan Smith de Pocahontas</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086750</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106228</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/pocahontas-rescuing-captain-john-smith</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
