<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/12356360</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>12356360</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206905</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sow the Seeds of Victory! Posters from the Food Administration During World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Säen Sie die Startwerte für Zufallsgenerator des 
Sieges! Plakate von der Nahrungsmittelleitung während des 
Ersten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Semez les graines de la victoire ! Affiches 
de la gestion de nourriture pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Semeie as sementes da vitória! Posteres da 
administração do alimento durante o world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Semini i semi della vittoria! Manifesti dalla
gestione dell'alimento durante il world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σπείρετε τους σπόρους της νίκης! Αφίσες από τη 
διοίκηση τροφίμων κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Siembre los gérmenes de la victoria! 
Carteles de la administración del alimento durante Primera 
Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells how Herbert Hoover, head of the new U.S. Food Administration, convinced Americans to conserve food during the Great War. Homeowners were urged to sign pledge cards to conserve food. Many observed wheat less Mondays, meatless Tuesdays, and pork less Saturdays. This website presents posters that helped carry one of the messages of Hoover and the Wilson administration: that Food will win the war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt, wie Herbert Staubsauger, Kopf der neuen 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Nahrungsmittelleitung, die überzeugten Amerikaner,
zum der Nahrung während großen War. Homeowners zu konservieren 
gedrängt wurden zu unterzeichnen versprechen Karten, um Nahrung 
zu konservieren. Viele beobachteten Weizen weniger Montage, 
fleischlose Dienstage und Schweinefleisch weniger Samstage. 
Diese Web site stellt Plakate dar, die halfen, eine der 
Meldungen des Staubsaugers und der Wilson Leitung zu tragen: 
diese Nahrung gewinnt den Krieg.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit que l'aspirateur d'Herbert, tête de la 
nouvelle gestion de nourriture des ETATS-UNIS, les Américains 
convaincus pour économiser la nourriture pendant grand War. 
Homeowners ont été invités à signer des cartes d'engagement pour 
économiser la nourriture. Beaucoup ont observé le blé moins 
de lundi, de mardi sans viande, et de porc moins de samedi. Ce 
site Web présente les affiches qui ont aidé à diffuser un des 
messages de l'aspirateur et de la gestion de Wilson : cette 
nourriture gagnera la guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz como o hoover de Herbert, cabeça da 
administração nova do alimento de ESTADOS UNIDOS, os americanos 
convencidos para conservar o alimento durante a Guerra grande 
Homeowners foi incitado assinar cartões do pledge para conservar o 
alimento. Muitos observaram o trigo menos segundas-feiras, 
terças-feiras meatless, e carne de porco menos sábados. Este 
Web site apresenta os posteres que ajudaram carregar uma das mensagens
do hoover e da administração de Wilson: esse alimento ganhará
a guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a come il hoover del Herbert, testa di nuova 
gestione dell'alimento degli STATI UNITI, Americani convinti per 
conservare l'alimento durante la War. Homeowners grande è stato 
invitato a firmare le schedi di impegno per conservare l'alimento. 
Molti hanno osservato il frumento meno lunedì, martedì 
meatless e porco meno sabati. Questo Web site presenta i 
manifesti che hanno contribuito a trasportare uno dei messaggi del 
hoover e della gestione del Wilson: quell'alimento vincerà la 
guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει πώς Herbert Hoover, προϊστάμενος της νέας 
διοίκησης ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ τροφίμων, έπεισε Αμερικανούς για να 
συντηρήσει τα τρόφιμα κατά τη διάρκεια του μεγάλου πολέμου. 
Οι ιδιοκτήτες σπιτιού ωθήθηκαν για να υπογράψουν τις κάρτες
υποχρέωσης για να συντηρήσουν τα τρόφιμα. Πολλοί 
παρατήρησαν το σίτο λιγότερα Δευτέρες, meatless Τρίτες, και 
χοιρινό κρέας λιγότερα Σάββατα. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος 
παρουσιάζει τις αφίσες που βοήθησαν να φέρουν ενός από τα 
μηνύματα Hoover και της κυβέρνησης Wilson: εκείνα τα 
τρόφιμα θα κερδίσουν τον πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice cómo la aspiradora de Herberto, pista de la 
nueva administración del alimento de ESTADOS UNIDOS, los americanos 
convencidos para conservar el alimento durante la gran War. Homeowners
fue impulsada firmar tarjetas del compromiso para conservar el 
alimento. Muchos observaron trigo menos lunes, martes meatless, 
y cerdo menos sábados. Este Web site presenta los carteles que 
ayudaron a llevar uno de los mensajes de la aspiradora y de la 
administración de Wilson: ese alimento ganará la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206905</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>12356360</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sow-the-seeds-of-victory-posters-from-the-food-administration-during-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
