<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104205</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104205</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205679</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Saint Gaudens' Memorial to Shaw and the Massachusetts 54th Regiment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Heiliger Gaudens' Denkmal zu Shaw und zum 
Massachusetts 54th Regiment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mémorial de Saint Gaudens à Shaw et au régiment
du Massachusetts cinquante-quatrième</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Memorial de Saint Gaudens' a Shaw e ao regiment de
Massachusetts 54th</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Memoriale del San Gaudens a Shaw ed al regiment 
del Massachusetts cinquantaquattresimo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μνημείο Αγίου Gaudens σε Shaw και το σύνταγμα της
Μασαχουσέτης 54$ος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Monumento de Santo Gaudens a Shaw y al regimiento 
de Massachusetts 54.o</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">focuses on the powerful memorial created to honor one of the first African-American units of the Civil War. Six sections of in-depth material explore the artist and his working methods, historical background on Shaw and the regiment, the memorial and its conservation, text from the exhibition, and teaching resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Foki auf dem leistungsfähigen Denkmal, das zu 
Ehre eine der ersten Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Maßeinheiten der 
Kapitel des Bürgerkrieges sechs des eingehenden Materials hergestellt
wird, erforschen den Künstler und seine Arbeitsmethoden, historischer
Hintergrund auf Shaw und das Regiment, das Denkmal und seine 
Erhaltung, Text von der Ausstellung und Unterricht Betriebsmittel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">foyers sur le mémorial puissant créé à 
l'honneur un des premières unités afro-américaines de la guerre 
civile. Six sections de matériel détaillé explorent l'artiste
et ses méthodes de travail, historique sur Shaw et le régiment, le 
mémorial et son économie, texte de l'exposition, et ressources 
d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os focos no memorial poderoso criado à honra uma 
das primeiras unidades Africano-Americanas das seções da guerra 
civil seis do material in-depth exploram o artista e seu métodos de 
funcionamento, fundo histórico em Shaw e o regiment, o memorial e seu
conservation, texto do exhibition, e recursos do ensino.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i fuochi sul memoriale potente creato a honor uno 
delle prime unità Africano-Americane delle sezioni di guerra civile 
sei di materiale approfondito esplorano l'artista ed i suoi metodi di 
lavoro, precedenti su Shaw ed il regiment, il memoriale e la relativa 
conservazione, testo dalla mostra e risorse di insegnamento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">η εστίαση στο ισχυρό μνημείο δημιούργησε για να 
τιμήσει μια από τις πρώτες αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές μονάδες του 
εμφύλιου πολέμου. Έξι τμήματα του σε βάθος υλικού 
ερευνούν τον καλλιτέχνη και τις μεθόδους εργασίας, το ιστορικό 
υπόβαθρό του σε Shaw και το σύνταγμα, το μνημείο και τη 
συντήρησή του, το κείμενο από την έκθεση, και τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los focos en el monumento de gran alcance creado 
al honor uno de las primeras unidades Africano-Americanas de las 
secciones de la guerra civil seises del material profundizado exploran
a artista y sus métodos de funcionamiento, fondo histórico en Shaw y
el regimiento, el monumento y su conservación, texto de la 
exposición, y los recursos de la enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205679</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104205</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/saint-gaudens-memorial-to-shaw-and-the-massachusetts-54th-regiment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
