<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107358</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107358</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204066</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Monsters of the Deep: Deep Sea Bioluminescence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Monster vom tiefen: Tiefes Meer 
Bioluminescence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Monstres du profond : Mer Profonde 
Bioluminescence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Monsters do profundo: Mar Profundo 
Bioluminescence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Monsters del profondo: Mare Profondo 
Bioluminescence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέρατα του βαθιού: Βιολογική ακτινοβολία 
μεγάλων θαλασσίων βαθών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Monstruos del profundo: Mar Profundo 
Bioluminescence</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This award-winning Sea and Sky website uses creative graphics to explore deep sea bioluminescence. It defines the phenomenon of bioluminescence, explains the chemical reactions involved, describes organisms with this adaptation, and investigates possible reasons for this dazzling light show. Links direct users to similar pages about hydrothermal vents, ocean layers, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kreative Graphiken diese award-winning des See- 
und Himmelweb site Gebrauches, zum des tiefen Meerbioluminescence zu 
erforschen. Es definiert das Phänomen von bioluminescence, 
erklärt die chemischen betroffenen Reaktionen, beschreibt organismen 
mit dieser Anpassung und forscht mögliche Gründe für dieses helle 
Erscheinen Blendens nach. Links verweisen Benutzer auf ähnliche
Seiten über hydrothermale Entlüftungsöffnungen, Ozeanschichten und 
mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Graphiques créateurs d'utilisations de ce site 
Web award-winning de mer et de ciel pour explorer le bioluminescence 
profond de mer. Il définit le phénomène du bioluminescence, 
explique les réactions chimiques impliquées, décrit des 
organizations avec cette adaptation, et étudie des raisons possibles 
de cette exposition légère de briller. Les liens dirigent des 
utilisateurs vers les pages semblables au sujet des évents, des 
couches d'océan, et de plus hydrothermiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gráficos creativos dos usos deste Web site 
award-winning do mar e do céu para explorar o bioluminescence 
profundo do mar. Define o fenômeno do bioluminescence, explica 
as reações químicas envolvidas, descreve organismos com esta 
adaptação, e investiga razões possíveis para esta mostra clara 
dazzling. As ligações dirigem usuários às páginas similares
sobre respiradouros, camadas do oceano, e mais hydrothermal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Grafici creativi di usi di questo Web site 
award-winning del cielo e del mare per esplorare bioluminescence 
profondo del mare. Definisce il fenomeno del bioluminescence, 
spiega le reazioni chimiche in questione, descrive gli organismi con 
questo adattamento e studia i motivi possibili per questa esposizione 
chiara di abbagliamento. I collegamenti dirigono gli utenti 
verso le pagine simili circa gli sfiati, gli strati dell'oceano e più
idrotermali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η βραβευμένη δημιουργική γραφική παράσταση 
χρήσεων ιστοχώρου θάλασσας και ουρανού για να ερευνήσει τη 
βιολογική ακτινοβολία μεγάλων θαλασσίων βαθών. Καθορίζει 
το φαινόμενο της βιολογικής ακτινοβολίας, εξηγεί τις χημικές 
αντιδράσεις σχετικές, περιγράφει τους οργανισμούς με αυτήν την 
προσαρμογή, και ερευνά τους πιθανούς λόγους για αυτήν την 
τύφλωση ελαφριά εμφανίζει. Συνδέει τους άμεσους χρήστες με
τις παρόμοιες σελίδες για τις υδροθερμικές διεξόδους, τα ωκεάνια 
στρώματα, και περισσότερους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gráficos creativos de las aplicaciones de este 
Web site premiado del mar y del cielo para explorar bioluminescence
profundo del mar. Define el fenómeno del bioluminescence, 
explica las reacciones químicas implicadas, describe organismos con 
esta adaptación, e investiga las razones posibles de esta 
demostración ligera del deslumbramiento. Las conexiones dirigen
a utilizadores a las paginaciones similares sobre respiraderos, capas 
del océano, y más hidrotérmicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:J.D. KNIGHT
FN:J.D. KNIGHT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SEA AND SKY
FN:SEA AND SKY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204066</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107358</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/monsters-of-the-deep-deep-sea-bioluminescence</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
