<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103957</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103957</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087128</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"To Redeem My Family": Venture Smith Frees Himself and his Family</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Meine Familie Zurückkaufen": Wagnis Smith 
gibt sich und seine Familie frei</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Pour Racheter Ma Famille" : L'entreprise 
Smith se libère et sa famille</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Para redeem Minha Família": O risco Smith 
livra-se e sua família</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Per riacquistare La Mia Famiglia": 
L'impresa Smith si libera e la sua famiglia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Για να εξαγοράσει την οικογένειά μου": Η 
επιχείρηση Smith ελευθερώνεται και την οικογένειά του</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Para redimir A Mi Familia": La empresa 
Smith se libera y a su familia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Free labor provided possibilities for emancipation for some enslaved people. The most industrious and the most skilled of the enslaved could take greater advantage of these opportunities. Venture Smith had been born in the 1720s, the son of a West African prince who named him Broteer Furro. Slave traders captured him at the age of six, spirited him away to the coast, and transported him to a life of enslavement in Long Island and eastern Connecticut. After several changes of ownership, he was able to purchase his freedom by his labors at the age of 31. Those labors, along with his entrepreneurial activities such as fishing, working on a whaler, and agricultural activities, made possible the purchase of his son, daughter, and wife's liberty. Near the end of the 18th century he related his life history to Elisha Niles, a schoolteacher and Revolutionary war veteran. Published in 1798,  A Narrative of the Life and Adventures of Venture, a Native of Africa: But Resident above Sixty Years in the United States of America, Related by Himself  recounted his successful negotiation of the slavery economy and recognition of free labor as the key to a free identity.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freie Arbeit stellte Möglichkeiten für 
Emanzipation für einige versklavte Leute zur Verfügung. 
Industrious und das erfahrenste von versklavt konnten grösseren
Nutzen aus diesen Gelegenheiten ziehen. Wagnis Smith war im 
1720s, der Sohn eines afrikanischen Westprinzen geboren gewesen, der 
ihn Broteer Furro benannte. Sklavenhändler erfaßten ihn am 
Alter von sechs, spirited ihn weg zur Küste und transportierten ihn 
zu einer Lebensdauer von enslavement im Long Island und in 
Ostconnecticut. Nachdem einige Änderungen des Besitzes, er 
konnten, seine Freiheit durch seine Arbeiten am Alter von 31 zu 
kaufen. Jene Arbeiten, zusammen mit seinen unternehmerischen 
Aktivitäten wie Fischen, Funktion auf einem whaler und 
landwirtschaftlichen Aktivitäten, ermöglichten den Erwerb von von 
seinem Sohn, von Tochter und Freiheit der Frau. Nahe dem Ende 
des 18. Jahrhunderts stand er seine Lebengeschichte auf Elisha Niles, 
ein Schullehrer und revolutionärer Kriegveteran in Verbindung. 
Veröffentlicht 1798, eine Darstellung der Lebensdauer und 
Abenteuer des Wagnisses, ein Eingeborener von Afrika: Aber 
Bewohner über sechzig Jahren in den Staaten von Amerika, allein in 
Verbindung gestanden nachgezählt seiner erfolgreichen Vermittlung der
Sklavereiwirtschaft und der Anerkennung der freien Arbeit als die 
Taste auf einer freien Identität.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le travail libre a fourni des possibilités pour 
l'émancipation pour quelques personnes asservies. Le plus 
travailleur et le plus habile du asservi ont pu profiter plus grand de
ces occasions. L'entreprise Smith avait été née dans le 
1720s, le fils d'un prince africain occidental qui l'a nommé Broteer 
Furro. Les commerçants l'ont capturé à l'âge de six, 
vif slaves il loin à la côte, et l'ont transporté à 
une vie d'asservissement dans la longue île et le Connecticut oriental. 
Après que plusieurs changements de propriété, il aient pu 
acheter sa liberté par ses travaux à l'âge de 31. Ces 
travaux, avec ses activités entreprenantes telles que la pêche, 
fonctionnement sur un whaler, et activités agricoles, ont rendu 
l'achat possible de son fils, fille, et liberté de l'épouse. 
Près de la fin du 18ème siècle il a rapporté sa histoire de 
la vie à Elisha Niles, un instituteur et ancien combattant 
révolutionnaire. Édité en 1798, un récit de la vie et des 
aventures d'entreprise, un indigène de l'Afrique : Mais 
résidant au-dessus de soixante ans aux Etats-Unis d'Amérique, liés 
tout seul raconté sa négociation réussie de l'économie d'esclavage
et de l'identification du travail libre comme clé à une identité 
libre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O trabalho livre forneceu possibilidades para o 
emancipation para alguns povos enslaved. O mais industrious e o 
mais hábil do enslaved podiam fazer exame de uma vantagem mais grande
destas oportunidades. O risco Smith tinha sido nascido no 1720s,
filho de um príncipe africano ocidental que o nomeasse Broteer Furro.
Os comerciantes slave capturaram-no na idade de seis, spirited o
afastado à costa, e transportaram-no a uma vida do enslavement no 
console longo e em Connecticut oriental. Depois que diversas 
mudanças da posse, ele podiam  comprar sua liberdade por seus 
trabalhos na idade de 31. Aqueles trabalhos, junto com suas 
atividades entrepreneurial tais como a pesca, funcionamento em um 
whaler, e atividades agriculturais, fizeram possível a compra de seus
filho, filha, e liberdade da esposa. Perto do fim do 18o século
relacionou seu history da vida a Elisha Niles, um schoolteacher e 
veteran de guerra revolucionário. Publicado em 1798, em uma 
narrativa da vida e em aventuras do risco, um nativo de África: 
Mas o residente acima de sessenta anos nos Estados Unidos da 
América, relacionados por himself recounted sua negociação bem 
sucedida da economia do slavery e do recognition do trabalho livre 
como a chave a uma identidade livre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il lavoro libero ha fornito le possibilità 
per emancipazione per qualche gente asservita. Il più 
industrious e l'più esperto del asservito hanno potuto trarre 
vantaggio più grande da queste occasioni. L'impresa Smith era 
stata nata nel 1720s, il figlio di un principe africano ad ovest che 
lo ha chiamato Broteer Furro. I commercianti slave lo hanno 
bloccato all'età di sei, spirited lui via al litorale e lo hanno 
trasportato ad una durata del enslavement in isola lunga ed in 
Connecticut orientale. Dopo che parecchi cambiamenti della 
proprietà, lui possano comprare la sua libertà dai suoi lavori 
all'età di 31. Quei lavori, con le sue attività 
imprenditoriali quale pesca, funzionamento su un whaler ed attività 
agricole, hanno reso possibile l'acquisto del suoi figlio, derivato e 
libertà della moglie. Vicino alla conclusione del diciottesimo 
secolo ha riferito la sua storia di vita a Elisha Niles, uno 
schoolteacher e veterano di guerra rivoluzionario. Pubblicato in
1798, in una descrizione della vita e nelle avventure di impresa, un 
nativo dell'Africa: Ma il residente superiore a sessanta anni in
unito Dichiara dell'America, riferito da sè ha raccontato la 
sua trattativa riuscita dell'economia di slavery e del riconoscimento 
del lavoro libero come il tasto ad un'identità libera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ελεύθερη εργασία παρείχε τις δυνατότητες για την 
χειραφέτηση για μερικούς υποδουλωμένους ανθρώπους. Ο πιό
εργατικός και ο πιό ειδικευμένος υποδουλωμένη θα μπορούσε να 
αξιοποιήσει μεγαλύτερο αυτών των ευκαιριών. Η επιχείρηση 
Smith είχε γεννηθεί στο 1720s, ο γιος ενός δυτικού 
αφρικανικού πρίγκηπα που τον ονόμασε Broteer Furro. Οι 
έμποροι σκλάβων τον συνέλαβαν στην ηλικία έξι, εύψυχη αυτός 
μακριά στην ακτή, και τον μετέφεραν σε μια ζωή της υποδούλωσης 
στο μακρύ νησί και το ανατολικό Κοννέκτικατ. Μετά από 
διάφορες αλλαγές της ιδιοκτησίας, ήταν σε θέση να αγοράσει την 
ελευθερία του από δικούς του εργάζεται στην ηλικία 31. 
Εκείνοι εργάζονται, μαζί με τις επιχειρηματικές 
δραστηριότητές του όπως η αλιεία, εργαζόμενος σε ένα whaler, 
και τις γεωργικές δραστηριότητες, που καθίστανται πιθανές την 
αγορά του γιου του, την κόρη, και την ελευθερία της συζύγου. 
Κοντά στο τέλος του 18$ου αιώνα αφορούσε την ιστορία ζωής 
του Elisha Niles, έναν δάσκαλο και έναν επαναστατικό 
πολεμικό παλαίμαχο. Δημοσιευμένος το 1798, ένα αφήγημα 
της ζωής και τις περιπέτειες της επιχείρησης, ένας ντόπιος της 
Αφρικής: Αλλά κάτοικος επάνω από εξήντα έτη στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες της Αμερικής, σχετικές μόνος του 
εξιστορημένος την επιτυχή διαπραγμάτευσή του της οικονομίας 
σκλαβιάς και την αναγνώριση της ελεύθερης εργασίας ως πλήκτρο με 
μια ελεύθερη ταυτότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El trabajo libre proporcionó a las posibilidades 
para la emancipación para alguna gente esclavizada. El más 
industrious y el más experto del esclavizado podían tomar la mayor 
ventaja de estas oportunidades. La empresa Smith había sido 
nata en el 1720s, el hijo de un príncipe africano del oeste que lo 
nombró Broteer Furro. Los comerciantes auxiliares lo capturaron
en la edad de seises, spirited lo lejos a la costa, y lo transportaron
a una vida del enslavement en la isla larga y Connecticut del este. 
Después de que varios cambios de la propiedad, él pudieran 
comprar su libertad por sus trabajos en la edad de 31. Esos 
trabajos, junto con sus actividades emprendedoras tales como pesca, 
funcionamiento en un whaler, y actividades agrícolas, hicieron 
posible la compra de su hijo, hija, y libertad de la esposa. 
Cerca del final del décimo octavo siglo él relacionó su 
historia de la vida con Elisha Niles, un maestro y veterano de 
guerra revolucionario. Publicado en 1798, una narrativa de la 
vida y aventuras de la empresa, un natural de África: Pero el 
residente sobre sesenta años en los Estados Unidos de América, 
relacionados por se contó de nuevo su negociación acertada de la 
economía de la esclavitud y del reconocimiento del trabajo libre como
el clave a una identidad libre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087128</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103957</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/to-redeem-my-family-venture-smith-frees-himself-and-his-family</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
