<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107592</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107592</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206365</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Words and Deeds in American History</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wörter und Briefe in der amerikanischen 
Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mots et contrats dans l'histoire américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Palavras e ações no history americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parole ed atti nella storia americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λέξεις και πράξεις στην αμερικανική ιστορία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Palabras y hechos en historia americana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents historical documents spanning from the 15th to the mid-20th century. Included are the papers of presidents, cabinet ministers, members of Congress, Supreme Court justices, military officers and diplomats, reformers and political activists, artists and writers, scientists and inventors, and other Americans whose lives reflect our country's evolution. A detailed description accompanies each document.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt die historischen Dokumente dar, die vom 15.
dem mid-20th Jahrhundert überspannen. Sind die Papiere der 
Präsidenten, Kabinettsminister, Bauteile von Gerechtigkeit des 
Kongresses, des Höchsten Gerichts, von militärischen Offizieren und 
von Diplomaten, von Reformern und von politischen Aktivisten, von
Künstlern und von Verfassern, von Wissenschaftlern und von Erfindern 
und von anderen Amerikanern enthalten deren Lebensdauern Entwicklung 
unseres Landes reflektieren. Eine ausführliche Beschreibung 
begleitet jedes Dokument.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente les documents historiques enjambant du 
15ème au siècle de mid-20th. Inclus sont les papiers des 
présidents, les ministres du conseil, membres des juges du congrès, 
de cour suprême, des officiers et des diplomates militaires, des 
réformateurs et des activistes politiques, des artistes et des auteurs,
des scientifiques et des inventeurs, et d'autres Américains dont les 
vies reflètent l'évolution de notre pays. Une description 
détaillée accompagne chaque document.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta os originais históricos que medem do 
1ös ao século de mid-20th. Incluídos são os papéis dos 
presidentes, ministros de armário, membros de justiças do congress, 
da corte suprema, de oficiais e de diplomatas militares, de reformers 
e de activistas políticas, de artistas e de escritores, de cientistas
e de inventores, e de outros americanos cujas as vidas refletem a 
evolução do nosso país. Uma descrição detalhada acompanha 
cada original.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta i documenti storici che misurano dal 
quindicesimi al secolo di mid-20th. Incluse sono le carte dei 
presidenti, i ministri dell'armadietto, membri delle giustizie 
della Corte suprema, del congresso, degli ufficiali e dei diplomatici 
militari, dei reformers e degli attivisti politici, degli artisti e 
dei produttori, degli scienziati e degli inventori e di altri 
Americani di cui le vite riflettono lo sviluppo del nostro paese. 
Una descrizione dettagliata accompagna ogni documento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τα ιστορικά έγγραφα που εκτείνονται από 
το 15$ο στο μέσος-20ό αιώνα. Περιλαμβάνονται τα έγγραφα των
Προέδρων, οι υπουργοί γραφείων, τα μέλη του συνεδρίου, τα 
justices ανώτατου δικαστηρίου, οι στρατιωτικοί ανώτεροι 
υπάλληλοι και οι διπλωμάτες, οι μεταρρυθμιστές και τα πολιτικά 
ενεργά στελέχη, οι καλλιτέχνες και οι συγγραφείς, οι επιστήμονες 
και οι εφευρέτες, και άλλοι Αμερικανοί οι των οποίων ζωές 
απεικονίζουν την εξέλιξη της χώρας μας. Μια λεπτομερής 
περιγραφή συνοδεύει κάθε έγγραφο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta los documentos históricos que atraviesan
del décimo quintos al siglo de mid-20th. Incluidos son los 
papeles de los presidentes, ministros de cabina, miembros de las 
justicias del congreso, del Tribunal Supremo, de los oficiales y de 
los diplomatas militares, de los reformadores y de los activistas 
políticos, de los artistas y de los programas de escritura, de los 
científicos y de los inventores, y de otros americanos que vidas 
reflejen la evolución de nuestro país. Una descripción 
detallada acompaña cada documento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206365</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107592</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/words-and-deeds-in-american-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
