<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104070</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104070</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201310</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dive and Discover: Juan de Fuca Ridge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tauchen Sie und entdecken Sie: Juan de Fuca 
Ridge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plongez et découvrez : Juan de Fuca 
Ridge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mergulhe e descubra: Juan de Fuca Cume</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tuffisi e scopra: Juan de Fuca Ridge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βουτήξτε και ανακαλύψτε: Θ*Ιuαν δε Fuca 
Ridge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Zambúllase y descubra: Juan de Fuca Ridge</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Dive and Discover is an interactive distance learning web site designed to immerse you in the excitement of discovery and exploration of the deep seafloor. On this particular website, Dive and Discover brings you right aboard the expedition to the Juan de Fuca Ridge in the Pacific Ocean, where scientists are exploring hydrothermal vent fields and microbes inhabiting hydrothermal vents. The site gives you access to the latest oceanographic and deep submergence research from a variety of scientists including geologists, geophysicists, chemists, and biologists who are exploring the seafloor and making amazing deep-sea discoveries. The mission and objectives, daily updates, photos, videos, and e-mail correspondence with scientists aboard research vessels allow you to follow the progress of the scientific mission and find out about life on the floating laboratories at sea. Deeper discovery links allow the user to further explore the related topics of mid-ocean ridges, hydrothermal vents, and vent biology. This web page also provides links to other Dive and Discover expeditions, other deeper discovery topics, a teacher's page, and further Dive and Discover information.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Und entdecken ist tauchen eine interaktive Abstand
Lernenweb site, die konzipiert ist, um Sie in der Aufregung der 
Entdeckung und der Erforschung des tiefen seafloor unterzutauchen. 
Auf dieser bestimmten Web site entdeckt Tauchen und holt Ihnen 
Recht an Bord der Expedition zu Juan de Fuca Ridge im pazifischen 
Ozean, in dem Wissenschaftler hydrothermale Entlüftungsöffnung 
auffängt und die Mikroben erforschen, die hydrothermale 
Entlüftungsöffnungen bewohnen. Die Site gibt Ihnen Zugriff zur
neuesten ozeanographischen und tiefen submergence Forschung von einer 
Vielzahl der Wissenschaftler einschließlich Geologen, geophysicists, 
Chemiker und Biologen, die das seafloor erforschen und überraschende 
Tiefseeentdeckungen bilden. Die Mission und die Lernziele, die 
täglichen Aktualisierungsvorgänge, die Fotos, die videos und die 
E-mail Korrespondenz mit Wissenschaftlern an Bord der Forschung 
Behälter erlauben Ihnen, dem Fortschritt der wissenschaftlichen 
Mission zu folgen und über das Leben auf den sich hin- und 
herbewegenden Labors am Meer herauszufinden. Tiefere 
Entdeckunglinks erlauben dem Benutzer, die in Verbindung stehenden 
Themen der Mittlerozean Kanten, der hydrothermalen 
Entlüftungsöffnungen und der Entlüftungsöffnung Biologie weiter zu
erforschen. Diese Web-Seite auch stellt Links zu anderem Tauchen
zur Verfügung und entdeckt Expeditionen, andere tiefere 
Entdeckungthemen, Seite eines Lehrers und weiter taucht und entdeckt 
Informationen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plongent et découvrent est un site Web interactif
d'étude de distance conçu pour vous immerger dans l'excitation de la
découverte et de l'exploration du seafloor profond. Sur ce site
Web particulier, le piqué et découvrent vous apporte la droite à 
bord de l'expédition à Juan de Fuca Ridge dans l'océan 
pacifique, où les scientifiques explorent les zones hydrothermiques 
et les microbes d'évent habitant les évents hydrothermiques. 
Le site vous donne l'accès à la dernière recherche 
océanographique et profonde d'immersion d'une variété de 
scientifiques comprenant des géologues, des géophysiciens, des 
chimistes, et des biologistes qui explorent le seafloor et font des 
découvertes hauturières stupéfiantes. La mission et les 
objectifs, les mises à jour quotidiennes, les photos, les videos, et 
la correspondance de E-mail avec des scientifiques à bord des navires
de recherches vous permettent de suivre le progrès de la mission 
scientifique et de découvrir au sujet de la vie sur les laboratoires 
flottants en mer. Des liens plus profonds de découverte 
permettent à l'utilisateur d'explorer plus plus loin les sujets 
relatifs des arêtes de mi-océan, des évents hydrothermiques, et de 
la biologie d'évent. Cette page Web également fournit des 
liens à l'autre piqué et découvre des expéditions, d'autres sujets
plus profonds de découverte, la page d'un professeur, et plus loin 
plonge et découvre l'information.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mergulha e descobre é um Web site interativo da 
aprendizagem de distância projetado immerse o no excitamento da 
descoberta e da exploração do seafloor profundo. Neste Web 
site particular, o mergulho e descobre traz-lhe a direita a bordo da 
expedição ao Juan de Fuca Cume no oceano pacífico, onde os 
cientistas estão explorando campos hydrothermal e os micróbios do 
respiradouro que habitam respiradouros hydrothermal. O local 
dá-lhe o acesso à pesquisa oceanographic e profunda a mais atrasada 
do submergence de uma variedade dos cientistas including geólogos, 
geophysicists, químicos, e biólogos que estão explorando o seafloor
e estão fazendo descobertas deep-sea se espantando. A missão e
os objetivos, os updates diários, as fotos, os videos, e a 
correspondência do E-mail com os cientistas a bordo das embarcações
da pesquisa permitem que você siga o progresso da missão científica
e encontre-o para fora sobre a vida nos laboratórios flutuando no 
mar. Umas ligações mais profundas da descoberta permitem que o
usuário explore mais mais os tópicos relacionados de cumes do 
mid-oceano, de respiradouros hydrothermal, e de biologia do 
respiradouro. Este Web page também fornece as ligações ao 
outro mergulho e descobre expedições, outros tópicos mais profundos
da descoberta, página de um professor, e mais mais mergulha e 
descobre a informação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Si tuffa e scopre è un Web site interattivo 
imparare di distanza destinato per immergerli nell'eccitamento della 
scoperta e dell'esplorazione del seafloor profondo. Su questo 
Web site particolare, il tuffo e scopre vi porta la destra a bordo 
della spedizione al Juan de Fuca Ridge nell'oceano pacifico, in cui 
gli scienziati stanno esplorando i campi idrotermali ed i microbi 
dello sfiato che abitano gli sfiati idrotermali. Il luogo vi dà
l'accesso all'ultima ricerca oceanografica e profonda di submergence 
da una varietà di scienziati compreso i geologi, i geophysicists, i 
chimici ed i biologhi che stanno esplorando il seafloor e stanno 
facendo le scoperte di alto mare di stupore. La missione e gli 
obiettivi, gli aggiornamenti quotidiani, le foto, i videos e la 
corrispondenza di E-mail con gli scienziati a bordo dei vasi di 
ricerca permettono che seguiate il progresso della missione 
scientifica e scopriate circa vita sui laboratori di galleggiante in 
mare. I collegamenti più profondi di scoperta permettono che 
l'utente più ulteriormente esplori i soggetti relativi delle creste 
dell'metà di-oceano, degli sfiati idrotermali e della biologia dello 
sfiato. Questo Web page egualmente fornisce i collegamenti 
all'altro tuffo e scopre le spedizioni, altri soggetti più profondi 
di scoperta, pagina dell'insegnante e più ulteriormente si tuffa e 
scopre le informazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βουτήξτε και ανακαλύψτε είναι ένας διαλογικός 
ιστοχώρος από απόσταση εκμάθησης με σκοπό να σας βυθίσει στον 
ενθουσιασμό της ανακάλυψης και την εξερεύνηση του βαθιού 
θαλάσσιου πυθμένα. Σε αυτόν τον ιδιαίτερο ιστοχώρο, 
βουτήξτε και ανακαλύψτε σας φέρνει σωστούς στην αποστολή στο 
Juan δε Fuca Ridge στον ειρηνικό ωκεανό, όπου οι 
επιστήμονες ερευνούν τα πεδία και τα μικρόβια υδροθερμικών 
διεξόδων κατοικώντας στις υδροθερμικές διεξόδους. Η περιοχή
σας δίνει την πρόσβαση στην πιό πρόσφατη ωκεανογραφική και βαθιά
έρευνα βύθισης από ποικίλους επιστήμονες συμπεριλαμβανομένων των
γεωλόγων, των γεωφυσικών, των φαρμακοποιών, και των βιολόγων που 
εξερευνούν το θαλάσσιο πυθμένα και κάνουν τις καταπληκτικές 
βαθύβιες ανακαλύψεις. Η αποστολή και οι στόχοι, οι 
καθημερινές αναπροσαρμογές, οι φωτογραφίες, τα βίντεο, και η 
αλληλογραφία ηλεκτρονικού ταχυδρομείου με τους επιστήμονες στα 
ερευνητικά σκάφη επιτρέπουν σε σας για να ακολουθήσουν την πρόοδο
της επιστημονικής αποστολής και να ανακαλύψουν για τη ζωή στα 
επιπλέοντα εργαστήρια εν πλω. Οι βαθύτερες συνδέσεις 
ανακαλύψεων επιτρέπουν στο χρήστη για να ερευνήσουν περαιτέρω τα 
σχετικά θέματα των mid-ocean κορυφογραμμών, των υδροθερμικών 
διεξόδων, και της βιολογίας διεξόδων. Αυτή η ιστοσελίδας 
παρέχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με άλλη κατάδυση και ανακαλύπτει 
τις αποστολές, άλλα βαθύτερα θέματα ανακαλύψεων, η σελίδα ενός 
δασκάλου, και βουτά περαιτέρω και ανακαλύπτει τις πληροφορίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Se zambulle y descubre es un Web site interactivo 
el aprender de distancia diseñado para sumergirle en el entusiasmo 
del descubrimiento y de la exploración del seafloor profundo. 
En este Web site determinado, la zambullida y descubre le trae 
la derecha a bordo de la expedición al Juan de Fuca Ridge en el 
Océano Pacífico, en donde los científicos están explorando campos 
hidrotérmicos y los microbios del respiradero que habitan 
respiraderos hidrotérmicos. El sitio le da el acceso a la 
investigación oceanográfica y profunda más última del submergence 
de una variedad de científicos incluyendo geólogos, geophysicists, 
químicos, y los biólogos que están explorando el seafloor y están 
haciendo descubrimientos de alta mar que sorprenden. La misión 
y los objetivos, las actualizaciones diarias, las fotos, los videos, y
la correspondencia del E-mail con los científicos a bordo de los 
recipientes de la investigación permiten que usted siga el progreso 
de la misión científica y que descubra sobre vida en los 
laboratorios flotantes en el mar. Conexiones más profundas del 
descubrimiento permiten que el utilizador explore más lejos los 
asuntos relacionados de los cantos del mediados de-oce'ano, de los 
respiraderos hidrotérmicos, y de la biología del respiradero. 
Este Web page también proporciona a conexiones a la otra 
zambullida y descubre las expediciones, otros asuntos más profundos 
del descubrimiento, paginación de un profesor, y más lejos se 
zambulle y descubre la información.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WOODS HOLE OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTION
FN:WOODS HOLE OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201310</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104070</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/dive-and-discover-juan-de-fuca-ridge</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
