<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106912</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106912</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086122</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Enemies from Within": Senator Joseph R. McCarthy and President Harry S. Truman Trade Accusations of Disloyalty</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Feinde von innerhalb": Senator Joseph R. 
McCarthy und Präsident Harry S. Truman Trade Anklagen von Disloyalty</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"ennemis de dans" : Le sénateur Joseph R. 
McCarthy et accusations du Président Harry S. Truman Trade de 
Déloyauté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"inimigos de dentro": Senator Joseph R. 
McCarthy e accusations do presidente Harry S. Truman Negociar da 
deslealdade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"nemici da entro": Il senatore Joseph R. 
McCarthy e Accuse del presidente Harry S. Truman Trade di 
disloyalty</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εχθροί από μέσα από": Γερουσιαστής Joseph 
R. McCarthy και Προέδρου Harry S. Truman Trade 
κατηγορίες disloyalty</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"enemigos de dentro": Senador José R. 
McCarthy y acusaciones de presidente Harry S. Truman Trade de la 
deslealtad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Wisconsin Republican Joseph R. McCarthy first won election to the Senate in 1946 during a campaign marked by much anticommunist Red-baiting. Partially in response to Republican Party victories, President Harry S. Truman tried to demonstrate his own concern about the threat of Communism by setting up a loyalty program for federal employees. He also asked the Justice Department to compile an official list of 78 subversive organizations. As the midterm election year got underway, former State Department official Alger Hiss, suspected of espionage, was convicted of perjury. McCarthy, in a speech at Wheeling, West Virginia, mounted an attack on Truman's foreign policy agenda by charging that the State Department and its Secretary, Dean Acheson, harbored "traitorous" Communists. Although McCarthy displayed a list of names, he never made the list public. The President responded the following month in a news conference by charging that McCarthy's attacks were in effect sabotaging the nation's bipartisan foreign policy efforts and thus aiding the Soviet Union. The following texts--McCarthy's speech, a public letter from McCarthy to Truman two days later, and a transcript of the Truman press conference--reveal the paranoid atmosphere that prevailed in the political arena and affected public discourse and policy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wisconsin republikanischer Joseph R. McCarthy 
gewann zuerst Wahl zum Senat in 1946 während einer Kampagne, die 
durch viel anticommunist Rot-Anlocken gekennzeichnet wurde. 
Teilweise in Erwiderung auf Republikanische Parteisiege, versuchte 
Präsident Harry S. Truman, sein eigenes Interesse über die Drohung 
des Kommunismus zu demonstrieren, indem er ein Loyalitätprogramm 
für Bundesangestellte aufstellte. Er bat auch um um die 
Gerechtigkeit-Abteilung, um eine amtliche Börsennotierung von 78 
subversiveen Organisationen zu kompilieren. Während das 
Halbzeitwahljahr unterwegs erhielt, ehemalige Zustand-Abteilung 
wurde das amtliche Alger Zischen, vermutet von der Spionage, des 
Meineids überführt. McCarthy, in einer Rede am Drehen, West 
Virginia, hing einen Angriff auf Trumans Tagesordnung der fremden 
Politik ein, indem er auflud, daß die Zustand-Abteilung und seine 
Sekretärin, Dekan Acheson, "traitorous" Kommunisten beherbargen. 
Obgleich McCarthy eine Liste von Namen anzeigte, bildete er nie 
die Liste Öffentlichkeit. Der Präsident reagierte der folgende
Monat in einer Nachrichten Konferenz, indem er Angriffe dieses 
McCarthys auflud, in Kraft sabotierten die zwei Parteien zugehörigen 
Bemühungen der fremden Politik der Nation und unterstützten folglich
den Sowjet-Anschluß. Die folgenden Texte -- Rede McCarthys, ein
allgemeines Zeichen von McCarthy zu Truman zwei Tage später und eine 
Abschrift von der Truman Pressekonferenz -- decken die paranoide 
Atmosphäre auf, die in der politischen Arena und beeinflußte 
allgemeine die Darlegung und die Politik vorherschte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Wisconsin Joseph républicain R. McCarthy a 
gagné la première fois l'élection au sénat dans 1946 pendant une 
campagne marquée par beaucoup de Rouge-amorce d'anticommunist. 
Partiellement en réponse aux victoires de partie républicaine,
le Président Harry S. Truman a essayé de démontrer son propre souci
concernant la menace du communisme en installant un programme de 
fidélité pour les employés fédéraux. Il a également 
demandé le service de justice pour compiler une liste officielle de 
78 organismes subversifs. Pendant que l'année à moyen terme 
d'élection commençait, le sifflement officiel d'Alger d'ancien 
service d'état, suspecté de l'espionnage, a été condamné du 
parjure. McCarthy, dans un discours au roulement, la Virginie 
Occidentale, a monté une attaque à l'ordre du jour de la politique 
étrangère de Truman par le remplissage que le service d'état et son
secrétaire, doyen Acheson, ont hébergé les communistes "déloyaux".
Bien que McCarthy ait affiché une liste de noms, il n'a jamais 
fait le public de liste. Le président a répondu le mois 
suivant dans une conférence de nouvelles en chargeant les attaques de
ce McCarthy en effet sabotaient les efforts bipartis de la politique 
étrangère de la nation et facilitaient de ce fait Union Soviétique. 
Les textes suivants -- le discours de McCarthy, une lettre 
publique de McCarthy à Truman deux jours plus tard, et une 
transcription de la conférence de presse de Truman -- indiquent 
l'atmosphère paranoïde qui a régné dans l'arène politique et le 
discours et la politique publics affectés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Wisconsin Joseph republicano R. McCarthy ganhou 
primeiramente a eleição ao senate em 1946 durante uma campanha 
marcada muito Vermelho-red-baiting do anticommunist. 
Parcialmente em resposta às vitórias do partido republicano, o
presidente Harry S. Truman tentou demonstrar seu próprio interesse 
sobre a ameaça do communism ajustando acima um programa da lealdade 
para empregados federais. Pediu também o departamento da 
justiça para compilar uma lista oficial de 78 organizações 
subversivas. Enquanto o ano midterm da eleição começou 
underway, o silvo oficial de Alger do departamento anterior do estado,
suspeitado do espionage, convicted do perjúrio. McCarthy, em um
discurso em rodar, Virgínia ocidental, montou um ataque na agenda da 
política extrangeira de Truman carregando que o departamento do 
estado e sua secretária, decano Acheson, abrigaram comunistas 
"traitorous". Embora McCarthy indicasse uma lista dos nomes, 
nunca fêz o público da lista. O presidente respondeu o 
seguinte mês em uma conferência da notícia carregando ataques desse
McCarthy de fato sabotaging os esforços bipartisan da política 
extrangeira da nação e ajudava assim à Soviete-união. Os 
seguintes textos -- discurso de McCarthy, uma letra pública de 
McCarthy a Truman dois dias mais tarde, e um transcript da 
conferência de imprensa de Truman -- revelam a atmosfera paranoid que
prevaleceu na arena política e o discurso e a política públicos 
afetados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Wisconsin Joseph Repubblicano R. McCarthy in primo 
luogo ha vinto l'elezione al senato in 1946 durante la campagna 
contrassegnata dal molto Rosso-adescamento di anticommunist. 
Parzialmente in risposta alle vittorie Repubblicane del partito, 
il presidente Harry S. Truman ha provato a dimostrare la sua propria 
preoccupazione circa la minaccia di comunismo installando un programma
di lealtà per gli impiegati federali. Egualmente ha chiesto al 
reparto della giustizia per compilare una lista ufficiale di 78 
organizzazioni sovversive. Mentre l'anno trimestrale di elezione 
ha iniziato, il sibilo ufficiale precedente di State Department Alger, 
ritenuto sospetto di spionaggio, è stato condannato di perjury. 
McCarthy, in un discorso alla roteazione, la Virginia 
dell'Ovest, ha montato un attacco all'ordine del giorno di politica 
straniera del Truman caricandosi che State Department e la relativa 
segretaria, il decano Acheson, harbored i comunisti "traitorous". 
Anche se McCarthy ha visualizzato una lista dei nomi, non ha 
fatto mai il pubblico della lista. Il presidente ha risposto il 
seguente mese in un congresso di notizie caricando gli attacchi di 
quel McCarthy in effetti stava sabotando gli sforzi bipartisan di 
politica straniera della nazione e così stava aiutando 
l'Soviet-unione. I seguenti testi -- discorso del McCarthy, una 
lettera pubblica da McCarthy a Truman due giorni più successivamente 
e una trascrizione della conferenza stampa di Truman -- rivelano 
l'atmosfera paranoid che è prevalso nell'arena politica ed il 
discorso e la politica pubblici influenzati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Wisconsin Republican Joseph Ρ. McCarthy 
κέρδισε αρχικά την εκλογή στη Σύγκλητο το 1946 κατά τη 
διάρκεια μιας εκστρατείας που χαρακτηρίστηκε με πολύ 
αντικομμουνιστές να κόκκινος-δελεάσει. Μερικώς σε απάντηση 
στις δημοκρατικές νίκες συμβαλλόμενου μέρους, ο Πρόεδρος Harry
S. Truman προσπάθησε να καταδείξει την ανησυχία του για την 
απειλή του κομμουνισμού με την οργάνωση ενός προγράμματος πίστης
για τους ομοσπονδιακούς υπαλλήλους. Επίσης ζήτησε από το 
Υπουργείο Δικαιοσύνης για να μεταγλωττίσει έναν επίσημο κατάλογο
78 ανατρεπτικών οργανώσεων. Δεδομένου ότι το έτος 
ενδιάμεσης εκλογής πήρε εν εξελίξει, ο πρώην επίσημος συριγμός 
Alger υπουργείου εξωτερικών, που υποψιάστηκε της κατασκοπείας, 
καταδικάστηκε της επιορκίας. McCarthy, σε μια ομιλία στην
περιστροφή, η δυτική Βιρτζίνια, επικόλλησε μια επίθεση στην 
ημερήσια διάταξη εξωτερικής πολιτικής Truman με τη χρέωση ότι
το υπουργείο εξωτερικών και ο γραμματέας του, Dean Acheson, 
οι "προδοτικοί" κομμουνιστές. Αν και McCarthy παρουσίασε 
έναν κατάλογο ονομάτων, δεν έκανε ποτέ το κοινό καταλόγων. 
Ο Πρόεδρος αποκρίθηκε ο επόμενος μήνας σε μια διάσκεψη 
ειδήσεων με τη χρέωση ότι οι επιθέσεις McCarthy's υπονόμευαν 
ουσιαστικά τις δικομματικές προσπάθειες εξωτερικής πολιτικής του 
έθνους και βοηθούσαν έτσι τη Σοβιετική Ένωση. Τα ακόλουθα 
κείμενα -- ομιλία McCarthy's, μια δημόσια επιστολή από 
McCarthy σε Truman δύο ημέρες αργότερα, και ένα αντίγραφο 
της συνέντευξης τύπου Truman -- αποκαλύπτουν την παρανοϊκή 
ατμόσφαιρα που επικράτησε στον πολιτικό χώρο και είχε επιπτώσεις
στη δημόσιες ομιλία και την πολιτική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Wisconsin José republicano R. McCarthy primero 
ganó la elección al senado en 1946 durante una campaña marcada por 
mucho Rojo-hostigamiento del anticommunist. Parcialmente en 
respuesta a victorias del partido republicano, presidente Harry S. 
Truman intentó demostrar su propia preocupación por la amenaza del 
comunismo setting-up un programa de la lealtad para los empleados 
federales. Él también pidió el departamento de la justicia 
para compilar una lista oficial de 78 organizaciones subversivas. 
Mientras que el año midterm de la elección consiguió en 
curso, el silbido oficial de Alger del departamento anterior del 
estado, sospechado de espionaje, fue condenado por perjurio. 
McCarthy, en un discurso en rodar, Virginia Occidental, montó 
un ataque contra la agenda de la política no nativa de Truman 
cargando que el departamento y su secretaria, decano Acheson del 
estado, abrigaron comunistas "traidores". Aunque McCarthy 
visualizó una lista de nombres, él nunca hizo el público de la 
lista. El presidente respondió el mes siguiente en una 
conferencia de las noticias cargando los ataques de ese McCarthy en 
efecto saboteaba los esfuerzos de dos partidos políticos de la 
política no nativa de la nación y ayudaba así a la Soviet-unio'n. 
Los textos siguientes -- discurso de McCarthy, una carta 
pública de McCarthy a Truman dos días más adelante, y una 
transcripción de la rueda de prensa de Truman -- revelan la 
atmósfera paranoica que prevaleció en la arena política y el 
discurso y la política públicos afectados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086122</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106912</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/enemies-from-within-senator-joseph-r-mccarthy-and-president-harry-s-truman-trade-accusations-of-disloyalty</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
