<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108800</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108800</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206363</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">FBI Youth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">FBI Jugend</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeunesse de FBI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Juventude de FBI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioventù di FBI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νεολαία FBI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juventud de FBI</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">invites students to take the special agent challenge, spend a day in the life of an FBI employee, follow a case through the FBI lab, learn about investigations throughout the world, see specially trained dogs that locate bombs and drugs, and read about the history of the FBI.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">lädt Kursteilnehmer ein, die spezielle 
Mittelherausforderung zu nehmen, verbringt einen Tag im Leben eines 
FBI Angestellten, folgt einem Fall durch das FBI Labor, erlernt über 
Untersuchungen weltweit, sieht besonders ausgebildete Hunde, die 
Bomben und Drogen lokalisieren, und liest über die Geschichte des 
FBI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">invite des étudiants à prendre le défi spécial
d'agent, passe un jour dans la vie d'un employé de FBI, suit 
un cas par le laboratoire de FBI, se renseigne sur des 
investigations dans le monde entier, voit les chiens particulièrement
qualifiés qui localisent des pannes et des drogues, et a connaissance
de l'histoire du FBI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">convida estudantes fazer exame do desafio especial
do agente, gastam um dia na vida de um empregado de FBI, seguem um 
caso através do laboratório de FBI, aprendem-no sobre 
investigações durante todo o mundo, vêem-nos os cães especialmente
treinados que encontram bombas e drogas, e lêem-nos sobre o history 
do FBI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">invita gli allievi a prendere la sfida speciale 
dell'agente, spendono un giorno nella vita di un impiegato di 
FBI, seguono un caso attraverso il laboratorio di FBI, imparano circa 
le indagini nel mondo intero, vedono i cani specialmente addestrati 
che individuano le bombe e le droghe e leggono sulla storia del FBI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσκαλεί τους σπουδαστές για να πάρει την ειδική 
πρόκληση πρακτόρων, να περάσει μια ημέρα στη ζωή ενός υπαλλήλου
FBI, να παρακολουθήσει μια περίπτωση μέσω του εργαστηρίου 
FBI, να μάθει για τις έρευνες σε όλο τον κόσμο, να 
δει τα ειδικά εκπαιδευμένα σκυλιά που εντοπίζουν τις 
βόμβες και τα φάρμακα, και διαβάζουν για την ιστορία της FBI.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">invita a estudiantes que tomen el desafío 
especial del agente, pasa un día en la vida de un empleado de FBI, 
sigue un caso a través del laboratorio de FBI, aprende sobre 
investigaciones a través del mundo, ve los perros especialmente 
entrenados que localizan bombas y las drogas, y lee sobre la historia 
del FBI.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206363</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108800</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fbi-youth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
