<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108329</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108329</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086935</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Fields family, Hale County, Alabama, Summer 1936.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fängt Familie, Hale Grafschaft, Alabama, 
Sommer 1936 auf.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La famille de zones, comté vigoureux, Alabama, 
été 1936.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A família dos campos, condado hale, Alabama, 
verão 1936.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La famiglia dei campi, contea hale, Alabama, 
estate 1936.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η οικογένεια πεδίων, υγιής νομός, Αλαμπάμα, 
καλοκαίρι 1936.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La familia de los campos, condado sano, Alabama, 
verano 1936.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">To build broad public support for its New Deal relief programs, the administration of President Franklin D. Roosevelt encouraged documentation of the human suffering caused by the Depression. From 1935 to 1943, photographers working for several federal government agencies, principally the Farm Security Administration (FSA), traveled the country and produced the most enduring images of the Great Depression. This Walker Evans picture of a poor rural family was part of that massive documentation effort. Wishing to convey both suffering and dignity, FSA photographers searingly presented conditions to the American public, selecting effective compositions and poses influenced by advertising and mass-market magazine formats. These photographic icons of the era were widely circulated in the popular press, including  Time ,  Look , and  Life  magazines, and they appeared in major museum exhibits and best-selling books.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Um ausgedehnten allgemeinen Support für seine Programme 
Entlastung des neuen Abkommens aufzubauen, regte die Leitung des 
Präsidenten Franklin D. Roosevelt Unterlagen des menschlichen 
Suffering an, der durch den Tiefstand verursacht wurde. Von 
reisten 1935 bis 1943, die Photographen, die für einige 
Bundesregierungagenturen, allgemein die Bauernhof-Sicherheit Leitung 
(FSA) arbeiten, das Land und produzierten das Aushalten von von 
Bildern des großen Tiefstands. Diese Wanderer Evans Abbildung 
einer armen landwirtschaftlichen Familie war ein Teil dieser massiven 
Unterlagen Bemühung. Möchten das Leiden und Würde, 
dargestellte Bedingungen der FSA Photographen übermitteln searingly 
zur amerikanischen Öffentlichkeit, wirkungsvollen Aufbau und die 
Haltungen auswählend beeinflußt durch Bekanntmachen und 
Massenmarktzeitschrift Formate. Diese fotographischen Ikonen der
Ära wurden weit in der populären Presse, einschließlich Zeit-, 
Blick- und Lebenzeitschriften verteilt, und sie erschienen in den 
Hauptmuseum Ausstellungen und gut-Verkaufen Bücher.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour établir le large soutien public de ses programmes de
soulagement de nouvelle affaire, la gestion du Président Franklin D. 
Roosevelt a encouragé la documentation de la douleur humaine 
provoquée par la dépression. De 1935 à 1943, photographes 
travaillant pour plusieurs organismes gouvernementaux fédéraux, 
principalement la gestion de sécurité de ferme (FSA), ont voyagé le
pays et ont produit la résistance des images de la grande 
dépression. Cette image d'Evans de marcheur d'une pauvre 
famille rurale faisait partie de cet effort massif de documentation. 
Souhaitant donner la souffrance et la dignité, conditions 
searingly présentées de photographes de FSA au public américain, 
choisissant les compositions pertinentes et les poses influencées par
des formats de magasin de la publicité et de marché grand-public. 
Ces graphismes photographiques de l'ère ont été largement 
distribués dans la presse populaire, y compris des magazines de 
temps, de regard, et de vie, et ils sont apparus dans les objets 
exposés principaux de musée et des livres de meilleur-vente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para construir a sustentação pública larga para seus 
programas do relevo do negócio novo, a administração do presidente 
Franklin D. Roosevelt incentivou a documentação do sofrimento humano
causado pelo depression. 1935 a 1943, fotógrafos que trabalham
para diversas agências de governo federal, principalmente a 
administração da segurança da fazenda (FSA), viajaram o país e 
produziram resistir imagens do depression grande. Este retrato 
de Evans do walker de uma família rural deficiente era parte desse 
esforço maciço da documentação. Desejando fazer saber  a 
sofrer e a dignidade, condições searingly apresentadas dos 
fotógrafos do FSA ao público americano, selecionando composições 
eficazes e os poses influenciados por formatos do compartimento 
anunciar e de mass-market. Estes ícones fotográficos da era 
foram circulados extensamente na imprensa popular, including 
compartimentos do tempo, do olhar, e da vida, e apareceram em 
exibições principais do museu e livros melhor-vender.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sviluppare il vasto sostegno pubblico i relativi programmi
di rilievo di nuovo affare, la gestione del presidente Franklin D. 
Roosevelt ha consigliato alla documentazione del suffering umano 
causato dalla depressione. 1935 - 1943, photographers che 
lavorano per parecchi enti governativi federali, principalmente la 
gestione di sicurezza dell'azienda agricola (FSA), hanno viaggiato il 
paese ed hanno prodotto resistere alle immagini della depressione 
grande. Questa immagine di Evans del camminatore di povera 
famiglia rurale faceva parte di quello sforzo voluminoso della 
documentazione. Desiderando trasportare sia sofferenza che 
dignità, termini searingly presentati dei photographers di FSA al 
pubblico americano, selezionando le composizioni efficaci e le pose 
influenzate dai formati dello scomparto del mass-market e di 
pubblicità. Queste icone fotografiche dell'era ampiamente sono 
state distribuite nella pressa popolare, compreso gli scomparti di 
tempo, di sguardo e di vita e sono comparso nelle esposizioni 
importanti del museo e libri migliore-vendere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για να χτίσει την ευρεία δημόσια οικονομική ενίσχυση 
για τα νέα προγράμματα ανακούφισης διαπραγμάτευσής της, η 
διοίκηση του Προέδρου Franklin D. Roosevelt ενθάρρυνε την 
τεκμηρίωση του ανθρώπινου βασάνου που προκλήθηκε από την 
κατάθλιψη. Από το 1935 ως το 1943, οι φωτογράφοι που 
εργάζονται για διάφορες αντιπροσωπείες ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης, 
κυρίως η διοίκηση αγροτικής ασφάλειας (FSA), ταξίδεψαν τη 
χώρα και παρήγαγαν να υπομείνουν τις εικόνες της μεγάλης 
οικονομικής κρίσης. Αυτή η εικόνα του Evans περιπατητών 
μιας φτωχής αγροτικής οικογένειας ήταν μέρος εκείνης της 
ογκώδους προσπάθειας τεκμηρίωσης. Η επιθυμία να 
μεταβιβαστεί και το βάσανο και η αξιοπρέπεια, φωτογράφοι FSA 
παρουσίασε searingly τους όρους στο αμερικανικό κοινό, που 
επιλέγει τις αποτελεσματικές συνθέσεις και θέτει επηρεασμένος 
από τις μορφές περιοδικών διαφήμισης και mass-market. 
Αυτά τα φωτογραφικά εικονίδια της εποχής κυκλοφόρησαν 
ευρέως στο δημοφιλή Τύπο, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του χρόνου, 
κοιτάζουν, και περιοδικά ζωής, και εμφανίστηκαν σε σημαντικά 
εκθέματα μουσείων και τα με εμπορική επιτυχία βιβλία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A construir la amplia ayuda pública para sus programas de
la relevación del nuevo reparto, la administración de presidente 
Franklin D. Roosevelt animó la documentación del sufrimiento humano 
causado por la depresión. A partir la 1935 a 1943, fotógrafos 
que trabajaban para varias agencias de estatal federal, principalmente
la administración de la seguridad de la granja (FSA), viajó el país
y produjo aguantar imágenes de la gran depresión. Este cuadro 
de Evans del walker de una familia rural pobre era parte de ese 
esfuerzo masivo de la documentación. Deseando transportar el 
sufrimiento y la dignidad, condiciones de los fotógrafos del FSA 
searingly actuales al público americano, seleccionando las 
composiciones eficaces y las actitudes influenciadas por formatos del 
compartimiento de la publicidad y del mass-market. Estos iconos 
fotográficos de la era fueron circulados extensamente en la prensa 
popular, incluyendo los compartimientos del tiempo, de la mirada, y de
la vida, y aparecieron en objetos expuestos importantes del museo y 
los libros de la mejor-venta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086935</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108329</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-fields-family-hale-county-alabama-summer-1936</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
