<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105001</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105001</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206591</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tending the Commons: Folklife and Landscape in Southern West Virginia, 1992-1999</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neigen der Common: Folklife und Landschaft 
in Südwest Virginia, 1992-1999</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tendre les terrains communaux : Folklife et 
horizontal en Virginie Occidentale méridionale, 1992-1999</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tendendo as terras comuns: Folklife e 
paisagem em Virgínia ocidental do sul, 1992-1999</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tendere i terreni comunali: Folklife e 
paesaggio nella Virginia dell'Ovest del sud, 1992-1999</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τάση των αστικών τάξεων: Folklife και τοπίο 
στη νότια δυτική Βιρτζίνια, 1992-1999</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tender a los campos comunes: Folklife y 
paisaje en Virginia Occidental meridional, 1992-1999</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features original sound recordings and photographs centered around hunting, gathering, and subsistence gardening in the mountains in Southern West Virginia's Big Coal River Valley. Interpretive texts and interviews outline the social, historical, economic, environmental, and cultural contexts of community life, and a series of maps and a diagram depict community activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale ursprüngliche Tonaufnahmen und 
Fotographien zentrierten um die Jagd, Versammlung und das 
Erwerbsmittel, das in den Bergen Südwest Virginia in der grossen 
Kohle River Valley im Garten arbeitet. Interpretierende Texte 
und Interviews umreißen die Sozial-, historischen, ökonomischen, 
Klima- und kulturellen Kontexte des Gemeinschaftslebens, und eine 
Reihe Karten und ein Diagramm stellen Gemeinschaftsaktivitäten 
bildlich dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les enregistrements sonores et les photographies 
initiaux de dispositifs se sont concentrés sur la chasse, le 
rassemblement, et la subsistance jardinage dans les montagnes en grand
charbon River Valley de la Virginie Occidentale méridionale. 
Les textes et les entrevues interprétatifs tracent les grandes 
lignes des contextes sociaux, historiques, économiques, 
environnementaux, et culturels de la vie de la communauté, et une 
série de cartes et un diagramme dépeignent des activités de la 
communauté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as gravações sadias e as fotografias originais 
das características centraram-se em torno da caça, do recolhimento, 
e do subsistence que jardina nas montanhas no carvão grande ocidental
do sul River Valley de Virgínia. Os textos e as entrevistas 
interpretive esboçam os contextos sociais, históricos, econômicos, 
ambientais, e cultural da vida da comunidade, e uma série dos mapas e
um diagrama descrevem atividades da comunidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le registrazioni del suono e le fotografie 
originali delle caratteristiche hanno vertuto cercare, 
riunire e sulla sussistenza che fa il giardinaggio nelle 
montagne in carbone grande River Valley della Virginia dell'Ovest del 
sud. I testi e le interviste interpretativi descrivono i 
contesti sociali, storici, economici, ambientali e culturali di vita 
della Comunità e una serie di programmi e uno schema descrivono le 
attività della Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">καταγραφές και φωτογραφίες χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων
αρχικές υγιείς που κεντροθετούνται γύρω από το κυνήγι, τη 
συλλογή, και την επιβίωση που καλλιεργεί στα βουνά στη μεγάλη 
κοιλάδα ποταμών άνθρακα της νότιας δυτικής Βιρτζίνια. Τα 
ερμηνευτικά κείμενα και οι συνεντεύξεις περιγράφουν τα κοινωνικά,
ιστορικά, οικονομικά, περιβαλλοντικά, και πολιτιστικά πλαίσια της
κοινοτικής ζωής, και μια σειρά χαρτών και ένα διάγραμμα 
απεικονίζουν τις κοινοτικές δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las grabaciones y las fotografías originales de 
los sonidos de las características se centraron alrededor de la caza,
de la reunión, y de la subsistencia que cultivaba un huerto en las 
montañas en el carbón grande River Valley de Virginia Occidental 
meridional. Los textos y las entrevistas interpretativos 
contornean los contextos sociales, históricos, económicos, 
ambientales, y culturales de la vida de la comunidad, y una serie de 
correspondencias y un diagrama representan actividades de la 
comunidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206591</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105001</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tending-the-commons-folklife-and-landscape-in-southern-west-virginia-1992-1999</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
