<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103333</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103333</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087343</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Thorn in the Side: A Socialist Takes Aim at Gompers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Dorn in der Seite: Ein Sozialist nimmt 
anstreben Gompers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une épine dans le côté : Un socialiste 
prend visent Gompers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um espinho no lado: Um socialist faz exame 
visa Gompers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una spina nel lato: Un socialista prende 
punta su Gompers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα αγκάθι στην πλευρά: Ένας σοσιαλιστής 
παίρνει το στόχο σε Gompers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una espina en la cara: Un socialista toma 
tiene como objetivo Gompers</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the 1890s, the American Federation of Labor (AFL) was faced with both the rising popularity of the People's Party in rural areas and attempts by the Populist movement to create a farmer-labor alliance. At the same time, socialist trade unionists lobbied for greater political involvement and adoption of several key socialist positions by the AFL. One of those socialist trade unionists was J. Mahlon Barnes, a Philadelphia cigar maker, member of the Cigarmakers' International Union, and member of the Socialist Labor Party. Barnes was a sharp critic of longtime AFL leader Samuel Gompers. In 1894 he played a key role in the only defeat that Gompers suffered in election to the AFL presidency. In this 1896 speech in Boston, Barnes chided Gompers and like-minded mainstream labor leaders for refusing to endorse socialism and, more generally, any form of direct political action.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des 1890s wurde die amerikanische 
Vereinigung der Arbeit (AFL) mit der steigenden Popularität der 
Partei der Leute in den ländlichen Gebieten 
gegenübergestellt und versucht durch die Volksbewegung, zu erstellen 
Landwirt-bearbeiten Bündnis. Gleichzeitig beeinflußten 
sozialistische Gewerkschaftler für grössere politische 
Miteinbeziehung und Annahme von mehreren sozialistische Positionen der
Taste durch das AFL. Einer jener sozialistischen Gewerkschaftler
war J. Mahlon Barnes, ein Philadelphia Zigarrehersteller, Bauteil vom 
des Cigarmakers' internationalen Anschluß und Bauteil der 
sozialistischen ArbeitsPartei. Barnes war ein scharfer 
Kritiker des langfristigen AFL Führers Samuel Gompers. 1894 
spielte er eine Schlüsselrolle in der einzigen Niederlage, die 
Gompers in der Wahl zum AFL Vorsitz erlitt. In dieser Rede 1896 
in Boston, schalt Barnes Gompers und gleichgesinnte 
Hauptströmungsgewerkschaftsführer, damit das Ablehnen sozialismus 
und, im Allgemeinen, jedes mögliches Formular der direkten 
politischen Tätigkeit indossiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant le 1890s, la fédération américaine du 
travail (AFL) a été confrontée à la popularité de montée de la 
partie des personnes dans des zones rurales et essaye par le mouvement
populiste de créer fermier-travaillent l'alliance. En même 
temps, les syndicalistes socialistes ont incité à une plus grandes 
participation et adoption politiques de plusieurs des positions 
socialistes de clé par l'AFL. Un de ces syndicalistes 
socialistes était J. Mahlon Barnes, un générateur de cigare de 
Philadelphie, membre de l'union internationale du Cigarmakers, et 
membre du parti travailliste socialiste. Barnes était un 
critique pointu du Chef à long terme Samuel Gompers d'AFL. En 
1894 il a joué un rôle principal dans la seule défaite que Gompers 
a soufferte dans l'élection à la présidence d'AFL. Dans ce 
discours 1896 à Boston, Barnes a réprimandé Gompers et dirigeants 
syndicaux traditionnels semblables pour que refuser approuve le 
socialisme et, plus généralement, n'importe quelle forme d'action 
politique direct.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o 1890s, o federation americano do 
trabalho (AFL) foi enfrentado com  a popularidade levantando-se do 
partido do pessoa em áreas rurais e tenta pelo movimento populist 
criar fazendeiro-trabalha o alliance. Ao mesmo tempo, os 
unionists de comércio socialist lobbied para uma participação e um 
adoption políticos mais grandes de diversos posições socialist da 
chave pelo AFL. Um daqueles unionists de comércio socialist era
J. Mahlon Barnes, um fabricante do charuto de Filadélfia, membro da 
união internacional do Cigarmakers', e membro do partido labor 
socialist. Barnes era um crítico afiado do líder longtime 
Samuel Gompers de AFL. Em 1894 jogou um papel chave na única 
derrota que Gompers sofreu na eleição ao presidency de AFL. 
Neste discurso 1896 em Boston, Barnes chided Gompers e líderes 
labor mainstream like-minded para que recusar endosse o socialismo e, 
mais geralmente, o todo o formulário da ação política direta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il 1890s, la federazione americana del 
Lavoro (AFL) è stata affrontata sia alla popolarità aumentante 
del partito della gente nelle zone rurali che tenta tramite il 
movimento populistico di creare un'alleanza di farmer-lavoro. 
Allo stesso tempo, i sindacalisti socialisti hanno incitato per 
la partecipazione e l'approvazione politiche più grandi di vari 
posizioni socialiste di tasto dal AFL. Uno di quei sindacalisti 
socialisti era J. Mahlon Barnes, un creatore del sigaro de Filadelfia,
membro dell'unione internazionale del Cigarmakers e membro del partito
Di lavoro socialista. Barnes era un critico tagliente del 
capo da molto tempo Samuel Gompers di AFL. In 1894 ha svolto 
un ruolo chiave nell'unica sconfitta che Gompers ha sofferto 
nell'elezione alla presidenza di AFL. In questo discorso 1896 a 
Boston, Barnes ha rimproverato Gompers ed i capi di lavoro 
tradizionali simili affinchè rifiutare firmi più generalmente il 
socialism e, tutta la forma di azione politica diretta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του 1890s, η αμερικανική 
ομοσπονδία της εργασίας (AFL) βρέθηκε αντιμέτωπη και με την 
αυξανόμενη δημοτικότητα του συμβαλλόμενου μέρους των ανθρώπων 
στις αγροτικές περιοχές και τις προσπάθειες από τη λαϊκιστική 
μετακίνηση να δημιουργηθεί μια συμμαχία αγρότης-εργασίας. 
Συγχρόνως, οι σοσιαλιστικοί συνδικαλιστές πίεσαν για 
μεγαλύτερες πολιτικές συμμετοχή και έγκριση διάφορων βασικών 
σοσιαλιστικών θέσεων από το AFL. Ένας από εκείνους τους
σοσιαλιστικούς συνδικαλιστές ήταν Θ*ι. Mahlon Barnes, 
κατασκευαστής πούρων της Φιλαδέλφειας, μέλος της διεθνούς ένωσης
του Cigarmakers, και μέλος του σοσιαλιστικού εργατικού 
κόμματος. Το Barnes ήταν αιχμηρός κριτικός του 
μακροπρόθεσμου AFL ηγέτη Samuel Gompers. Το 1894 
διαδραμάτισε έναν βασικό ρόλο στη μόνη ήττα που Gompers 
υπέστη στην εκλογή στην προεδρία AFL. Σε αυτήν την 
ομιλία 1896 στη Βοστώνη, Barnes επίπληξε Gompers και τους 
ομοϊδεάτες ηγέτες επικρατούσας εργασίας για την άρνηση να 
επικυρωθεί ο σοσιαλισμός και, γενικότερα, οποιαδήποτε μορφή της 
άμεσης πολιτικής ενέργειας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante el 1890s, la federación americana del 
trabajo (AFL) fue hecha frente con el renombre de levantamiento del 
partido de la gente en áreas rurales y procura por el movimiento 
populista crear granjero-trabaja alianza. En el mismo tiempo, 
los unionistas comerciales socialistas cabildearon para la mayores 
implicación y adopción políticas de varios las posiciones 
socialistas del clave por el AFL. Uno de esos unionistas 
comerciales socialistas era J. Mahlon Barnes, fabricante del cigarro 
de Philadelphia, miembro de la unión internacional del Cigarmakers, y
miembro del partido laborista socialista. Barnes era crítico 
sostenido del arranque de cinta de largo plazo Samuel Gompers de AFL. 
En 1894 él desempeñó un papel dominante en la única derrota 
que Gompers sufrió en la elección a la presidencia de AFL. En 
este discurso 1896 en Boston, Barnes regañó a Gompers y a arranques 
de cinta de trabajo de corriente semejantes para que el rechazo endose
socialismo y, más generalmente, cualquier forma de acción política 
directa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087343</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103333</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-thorn-in-the-side-a-socialist-takes-aim-at-gompers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
