<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106979</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106979</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Safe at School Art Curricula: High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Safe an den Schule-kunst-Lehrplänen: High 
School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Coffre-fort aux programmes d'études d'art 
d'école : Lycée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cofre em curricula da arte da escola: High 
School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cassaforte ai programmi di studi di arte della 
scuola: High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρηματοκιβώτιο στα προγράμματα σπουδών σχολικής 
τέχνης: Γυμνάσιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caja fuerte en los planes de estudios del arte de 
la escuela: High School Secundaria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Fifteen lesson plans teaching conflict resolution through art. Students will explore the use of abstract shapes and the feelings they evoke; learn about the emotional and physiological affects of color; learn to use visual instead of verbal language to have a conversation; work together to create a mural that models cooperation and conflict resolution and use modern packaging materials to create a safe place.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fünfzehn Lektionpläne, die 
$überschneidungzerlegung durch kunst unterrichten. 
Kursteilnehmer erforschen den Gebrauch von abstrakten Formen und
den Gefühlen, die sie erwähnen; erlernen Sie über das 
emotionale und das physiologisch beeinflußt von der Farbe; 
erlernen Sie, Sichtbarmachung anstelle von der mündlichen 
Sprache zu verwenden, um ein Gespräch zu haben; arbeiten Sie 
zusammen, um ein Wandbild zu erstellen, das Mitarbeit formt und 
widersprechen Sie Zerlegung und benutzen Sie moderne 
Verpackenmaterialien, um einen sicheren Platz zu erstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quinze plans de leçon enseignant la résolution 
de conflit par l'art. Les étudiants exploreront l'utilisation 
des formes abstraites et des sentiments qu'ils évoquent ; 
renseignez-vous sur l'émotif et physiologique affecte de 
couleur ; apprenez à employer le visuel au lieu du langage 
verbal pour avoir une conversation ; travaillez ensemble pour 
créer un mural qui modèle la coopération et soyez en conflit 
résolution et employez les matériaux d'emballage modernes pour 
créer un endroit sûr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quinze plantas da lição que ensinam a 
definição do conflito com a arte. Os estudantes explorarão o 
uso de formas abstratas e dos sentimentos que evoke; aprenda 
sobre o emocional e physiological afeta da cor; aprenda usar o 
visual em vez da língua verbal ter uma conversação; trabalhe 
junto para criar um mural que modele a cooperação e oponha 
definição e use materiais empacotando modernos criar um lugar 
seguro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quindici programmi di lezione che insegnano 
risoluzione di conflitto con l'arte. Gli allievi esploreranno 
l'uso delle figure astratte e delle sensibilità che evocano; 
impari circa l'impressionabile e fisiologico interessa di 
colore; impari usare la rappresentazione anziché il linguaggio 
verbale per avere una conversazione; lavori insieme per creare 
un mural che modella la cooperazione e sia in conflitto risoluzione ed
usi i materiali da imballaggio moderni per creare un posto sicuro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μάθημα δεκαπέντε προγραμματίζει τη διδασκαλία η 
επίλυση ψυχικών συγκρούσεων μέσω των σπουδαστών αρθ. θα 
ερευνήσει τη χρήση των αφηρημένων μορφών και των συναισθημάτων 
προκαλούν  μάθετε για τις συναισθηματικές και φυσιολογικές 
επιρροές του χρώματος  μάθετε να χρησιμοποιείτε οπτικός 
αντί της λεκτικής γλώσσας για να έχει μια συνομιλία  
εργαστείτε μαζί για να δημιουργήσετε μια τοιχογραφία που 
διαμορφώνει τη συνεργασία και την επίλυση ψυχικών συγκρούσεων και
χρησιμοποιήστε τα σύγχρονα υλικά συσκευασίας για να δημιουργήσετε
μια ασφαλή θέση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Quince planes de la lección que enseñan la 
resolución del conflicto con arte. Los estudiantes explorarán 
el uso de dimensiones de una variable abstractas y de las sensaciones 
que evocan; aprenda sobre el el emocional y fisiológico afecta 
de color; aprenda utilizar la representación visual en vez de 
lenguaje verbal para tener una conversación; trabaje junto para
crear un mural que modele la cooperación y esté en conflicto 
resolución y utilice los materiales de empaquetado modernos para 
crear un lugar seguro.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106979</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/safe-at-school-art-curricula-high-school</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
