<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104892</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104892</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204377</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Describing Japanese screens and scrolls through words</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beschreiben der japanischen Bildschirme und der 
Rollen durch Wörter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Décrire les écrans et les défilements japonais 
par des mots</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Descrevendo telas e scrolls japoneses com as 
palavras</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Descrizione gli schermi e dei rotoli giapponesi con
le parole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιγραφή των ιαπωνικών οθονών και των κυλίνδρων μέσω
των λέξεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Describir las pantallas y los desfiles japoneses 
con palabras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The first part of a unit on talking and writing about, as well as creating, Japanese screen and scroll paintings. The purpose of this unit plan is to introduce descriptive aspects of art criticism, while teaching appreciation for the art and culture of Japan. Students use observation and descriptive writing to discover richly detailed Japanese screen and scroll paintings so that another student can illustrate it in the next lesson.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das erste Teil einer Maßeinheit auf, sowie das 
Erstellen, japanischen Bildschirm und Rolleanstriche ungefähr 
sprechen und schreiben. Der Zweck dieses Maßeinheit Planes ist,
beschreibende Aspekte der kunstkritik vorzustellen, beim Unterrichten 
der Anerkennung für die kunst und die Kultur von Japan. 
Kursteilnehmergebrauchbeobachtung und beschreibendes Schreiben, 
zum der reich ausführlichen japanischen Bildschirm- und 
Rolleanstriche zu entdecken, damit ein anderer Kursteilnehmer es in 
der folgenden Lektion veranschaulichen kann.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La première partie d'une unité sur parler et 
écrire environ, aussi bien que créer, écran japonais et peintures 
de défilement. Le but de ce plan d'unité est de présenter des
aspects descriptifs de la critique d'art, tout en enseignant 
l'appréciation pour l'art et la culture du Japon. Observation 
d'utilisation d'étudiants et écriture descriptive pour découvrir 
les peintures japonaises richement détaillées d'écran et de 
défilement de sorte qu'un autre étudiant puisse l'illustrer dans la 
prochaine leçon.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A primeira parte de uma unidade em falar e em 
escrever aproximadamente, as.well.as criar, tela japonesa e pinturas 
do scroll. A finalidade desta planta da unidade é introduzir 
aspectos descritivos do criticism da arte, ao ensinar a apreciação 
para a arte e a cultura de Japão. Observação do uso dos 
estudantes e escrita descritiva para descobrir pinturas japonesas rica
detalhadas da tela e do scroll de modo que um outro estudante possa a 
ilustrar na lição seguinte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La prima parte di un'unità sulla comunicazione e 
sulla scrittura circa, così come la creazione, lo schermo giapponese 
e delle pitture del rotolo. Lo scopo di questo programma 
dell'unità è introdurre le funzioni descrittive della critica di 
arte, mentre insegna l'apprezzamento per l'arte e la coltura del 
Giappone. Osservazione di uso degli allievi e scrittura 
descrittiva per scoprire le pitture giapponesi pienamente dettagliate 
del rotolo e dello schermo in moda da potere illustrarlo un altro 
allievo nella lezione seguente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρώτο μέρος μιας μονάδας να μιλήσει και να γράψει 
περίπου, καθώς επίσης και δημιουργώντας, ιαπωνικά οθόνη και 
έργα ζωγραφικής κυλίνδρων. Ο σκοπός αυτού του σχεδίου 
μονάδων είναι να εισαχθούν οι περιγραφικές πτυχές της κριτικής 
τέχνης, διδασκαλικός την εκτίμηση για την τέχνη και τον πολιτισμό
της Ιαπωνίας. Οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν την παρατήρηση και
το περιγραφικό γράψιμο για να ανακαλύψουν την πλουσιοπάροχα 
λεπτομερή ιαπωνική οθόνη και να τυλίξουν τα έργα ζωγραφικής 
έτσι ώστε ένας άλλος σπουδαστής μπορεί να το επεξηγήσει στο 
επόμενο μάθημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La primera parte de una unidad en hablar y escribir
alrededor, así como crear, la pantalla japonesa y pinturas del 
desfile. El propósito de este plan de la unidad es introducir 
aspectos descriptivos de la crítica del arte, mientras que enseña el
aprecio para el arte y la cultura de Japón. Observación del 
uso de los estudiantes y escritura descriptiva para descubrir pinturas
japonesas rico detalladas de la pantalla y del desfile de modo que 
otro estudiante pueda ilustrarla en la lección siguiente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MICHELLE HARRELL
FN:MICHELLE HARRELL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204377</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104892</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/describing-japanese-screens-and-scrolls-through-words</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
