<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106678</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106678</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085264</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Coffee Coloured Children</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kaffee Farbige Kinder</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enfants Colorés Par Café</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Crianças Coloridas Café</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bambini Colorati Caffè</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έγχρωμα καφές παιδιά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Niños Coloreados Café</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">'Coffee Coloured Children' is a powerful exploration of the impact of cultural pressure on self-image. Based on the daily experience of mixed-race children, the narrator recalls the pain and confusion of her own childhood spent in an all-white neighborhood with a white mother and an absent black father. The work opens with a video essay showing adults and children of many ethnicities interacting harmoniously to an upbeat and soulful song with a chorus about 'coffee-colored people.' Through narration by her and her brother and dramatization, Onwurah relays incidents from her own childhood. She recounts the brutal and racist vandalization of her apartment. In reenactments, she is seen making up her face with white makeup and scrubbing her body in the bathtub with chemical abrasives. At the close of the piece, she and her brother stand in front of a fire, burning symbolic mementos of their pain and confusion over their own physical identities. 'Melting pot,' she asks, 'or incinerator? 'The work is approximately 16 and one-half minutes long and was broadcast as a segment of episode 604 (1990), and episode 102 (1991), of 'New Television.' Produced by Ngozi A. Onwurah and Simon Onwurah. Directed by Ngozi A. Onwurah.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">' Kaffee farbige Kinder ' ist eine 
leistungsfähige Erforschung der Auswirkung des kulturellen Drucks auf
Selbst-Bild. Gegründet auf der täglichen Erfahrung der 
Mischenrennen Kinder, erinnert an der Erzähler die Schmerz und das 
Durcheinander ihrer eigenen Kindheit, die in einer all-weißen 
Nachbarschaft mit einer weißen Mutter und einem abwesenden schwarzen 
Vater aufgewendet wird. Die Arbeit öffnet sich mit einem 
videoversuch, der Erwachsene und Kinder vieler Ethnicities zeigt, die 
harmonisch zusammenwirken zu einem positiven und soulful Lied mit 
einem Chor über ' Kaffee-farbige Leute.' Durch Erzählung durch
ihren und ihren Bruder und dramatization, Onwurah Relaisereignisse von
ihrer eigenen Kindheit. Sie zählt das brutale und rassistische 
vandalization ihrer Wohnung nach. In den reenactments ist sie 
gesehenes Bilden herauf ihr Gesicht mit weißer Verfassung und 
Schrubben ihres Körpers in der Badewanne mit chemischen 
Poliermitteln. Am Abschluß des Stückes, sie und ihres 
Bruderstandplatzes vor einem Feuer, der brennenden symbolischen 
Andenken ihrer Schmerz und des Durcheinanderüberschusses ihre eigenen
körperlichen Identitäten. ' schmelzender Topf, ' bittet sie, '
oder Verbrennungsofen? ' die Arbeit ist ungefähr 16 und Halb 
Minute lang und war Sendung als Segment von Episode 604 (1990) und 
Episode 102 (1991), ' des neuen Fernsehens.' Produziert durch 
Ngozi A. Onwurah und Simon Onwurah. Verwiesen durch Ngozi A. 
Onwurah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">'les enfants colorés par café 'est une 
exploration puissante de l'impact de la pression culturelle sur 
art de l'auto-portrait-image. Basé sur l'expérience quotidienne des enfants
de mélanger-course, le narrateur rappelle la douleur et la 
confusion de son propre enfance dépensé dans un voisinage 
tout-blanc avec une mère blanche et un père noir absent. Le 
travail s'ouvre avec un essai visuel montrant des adultes et des 
enfants de beaucoup d'appartenances ethniques agissant l'un sur 
l'autre harmonieusement à une chanson optimiste et émouvante 
avec un choeur au sujet 'des personnes café-colorées.' Par le 
récit par son et son frère et dramatisation, incidents de relais 
d'Onwurah de son propre enfance. Elle raconte le vandalization 
brutal et raciste de son appartement. Dans les reconstitutions, 
elle est fabrication vue vers le haut de son visage avec le maquillage
blanc et frottement de son corps dans la baignoire avec les abrasifs 
chimiques. À l'issue du morceau, elle et son stand de frère 
devant un feu, souvenirs symboliques de brûlure de leur douleur et 
excédent de confusion leurs propres identités physiques. 
'creuset, 'elle demande, 'ou incinérateur ? 'le travail 
est approximativement 16 et un demi- de minutes long et était 
émission comme segment de l'épisode 604 (1990), et épisode 102 
(1991), 'de la nouvelle télévision.' Produit par Ngozi A. 
Onwurah et Simon Onwurah. Dirigé par Ngozi A. Onwurah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">' as crianças coloridas café ' são uma 
exploração poderosa do impacto da pressão cultural na self-imagem. 
Baseado na experiência diária de crianças da mistur-raça, o 
narrator recorda a dor e a confusão de sua própria infância gastada
em uma vizinhança todo-branca com uma matriz branca e um pai preto 
ausente. O trabalho abre com um essay video que mostra adultos e
crianças de muitas etnicidades que interagem harmoniously a um upbeat
e a uma canção soulful com um chorus sobre ' povos café-coloridos.'
Com o narration por seus e seus irmão e dramatization, 
incidents dos relés de Onwurah de sua própria infância. 
Recounts o vandalization brutal e racist de seu apartamento. 
Nos reenactments, é fazer visto acima de sua cara com 
composição branca e esfregar seu corpo na banheira com abrasivos 
químicos. No fim da parte, ela e seu carrinho do irmão na 
frente de um fogo, mementos simbólicos de queimadura de sua dor e 
excesso da confusão suas próprias identidades físicas. ' 
potenciômetro de derretimento, ' pede, ' ou incinerator? ' o 
trabalho é aproximadamente 16 e um meio dos minutos longos e era 
transmissão como um segmento do episode 604 (1990), e episode 102 
(1991), ' da televisão nova.' Produzido por Ngozi A. Onwurah e 
por Simon Onwurah. Dirigido por Ngozi A. Onwurah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">'i bambini colorati caffè 'è un'esplorazione 
potente dell'effetto di pressione culturale sull'auto-immagine. 
Sulla base dell'esperienza quotidiana nei bambini della 
mescol-corsa, il narrator ricorda il dolore e la confusione della sua 
propria infanzia spesa in una vicinanza tutto-bianca con 
una madre bianca e un padre nero assente. Il lavoro si apre con 
un video saggio che mostra gli adulti ed i bambini di molte origini 
etniche che si interagiscono armoniosamente ad una canzone ottimistica
e soulful con un chorus circa 'la gente caffè-colorata.' Con il
narration dal suoi e suoi fratello e dramatization, avvenimenti dei 
relè di Onwurah dalla sua propria infanzia. Racconta il 
vandalization brutale e razzista del suo appartamento. Nei 
reenactments, è fare visto sulla sua faccia con trucco bianco e 
fregare il suo corpo nella vasca da bagno con gli abrasivi chimici. 
Alla fine della parte, lei ed il suo basamento del fratello 
davanti un fuoco, ricordi simbolici bruciantesi del loro dolore ed 
eccedenza di confusione le loro proprie identità fisiche. 'POT 
di fusione, 'chiede, 'o inceneratore? 'il lavoro è circa 16 ed 
a metà di minuti di lunghezza ed era radiodiffusione come segmento 
dell'episodio 604 (1990) ed episodio 102 (1991), 'di nuova 
televisione.' Prodotto da Ngozi A. Onwurah e da Simon Onwurah. 
Diretto da Ngozi A. Onwurah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα "έγχρωμα καφές παιδιά" είναι μια ισχυρή 
εξερεύνηση του αντίκτυπου της πολιτιστικής πίεσης στην 
μόνος-εικόνα. Με βάση την καθημερινή εμπειρία των παιδιών 
αναμιγνύω-φυλών, ο αφηγητής υπενθυμίζει τον πόνο και τη σύγχυση 
της παιδικής ηλικίας της που ξοδεύεται σε μια όλος-άσπρη 
γειτονιά με μια λευκιά μητέρα και έναν απόντα μαύρο πατέρα. 
Η εργασία ανοίγει με ένα τηλεοπτικό δοκίμιο που εμφανίζει 
τους ενηλίκους και παιδιά πολλών εθνών που αλληλεπιδρούν 
αρμονικά σε ένα οπτιμιστές και εκφραστικό τραγούδι με μια 
χορωδία για τους "καφές-χρωματισμένους ανθρώπους." Μέσω της
αφήγησης από την και τον αδελφό και τη δραματοποίησή της, 
γεγονότα ηλεκτρονόμων Onwurah από την παιδική ηλικία της. 
Εξιστορεί το βάναυσο και ρατσιστικό vandalization του 
διαμερίσματός της. Reenactments, βλέπει το 
πρόσωπό της με το άσπρο makeup και το σώμα της στην μπανιέρα 
με τα χημικά λειαντικά. Στον περίβολο του κομματιού, αυτή 
και η στάση αδελφών της στο μέτωπο μιας πυρκαγιάς, συμβολικά 
mementos καψίματος του πόνου και της σύγχυσής τους πέρα από 
τις φυσικές ταυτότητές τους. "Λειώνοντας δοχείο," ρωτά, 
"ή αποτεφρωτήρας; "Η εργασία είναι περίπου 16 και μισά 
λεπτά μακριά και ήταν ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση ως τμήμα μνήμης του 
επεισοδίου 604.1990), και επεισόδιο 102.1991)," της νέας 
τηλεόρασης." Παραχθείς από Ngozi Α. Onwurah και 
simon Onwurah. Κατευθυνμένος από Ngozi Α. Onwurah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">' los niños coloreados café ' son una 
exploración de gran alcance del impacto de la presión cultural en 
uno mismo-imagen. De acuerdo con la experiencia diaria de los 
niños de la mezclar-raza, el narrador recuerda el dolor y la 
confusión de su propia niñez pasada en una vecindad todo-blanca con 
una madre blanca y un padre negro ausente. El trabajo se abre 
con un ensayo video que muestra adultos y a niños de muchas 
pertenencias étnicas que obran recíprocamente armonioso a un upbeat 
y a una canción soulful con un estribillo sobre la ' gente 
cafe'-coloreada.' Con la narración por su y su hermano y 
dramatization, incidentes de los relais de Onwurah de su propia 
niñez. Ella contó de nuevo el vandalization brutal y racist de
su apartamento. En reenactments, ella es fabricación vista 
encima de su cara con el maquillaje blanco y fregar su cuerpo en la 
bañera con abrasivos químicos. En el cierre del pedazo, ella y
su soporte del hermano delante de un fuego, recuerdos simbólicos que 
se queman de su dolor y excedente de la confusión sus propias 
identidades físicas. ¿' crisol que derrite, ' ella pide, ' o 
incinerador? ' el trabajo es aproximadamente 16 y una mitad de 
los minutos largos y era difusión como segmento del episodio 604 
(1990), y el episodio 102 (1991), ' de la televisión nueva.' 
Producido por Ngozi A. Onwurah y Simon Onwurah. Dirigido 
por Ngozi A. Onwurah.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085264</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106678</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/coffee-coloured-children</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
