<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106339</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106339</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209800</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Intercepted arc</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abgefangener Bogen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arc arrêté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Arco interceptado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arco intercettato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρεμποδισμένο τόξο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Arco interceptado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of the intercepted arc - 'That part of a circle that lies between two lines that intersect it'. The applet shows a circle with part of it's circumference highlighted and the central angle shown. As the user drags either end of the arc it is redrawn and the intercpted arc changes. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept des abgefangenen Bogens - ' dieses Teil 
eines Kreises zeigen, der zwischen zwei Zeilen liegt, die es schneiden
'. Der applet stellt dar, daß ein Kreis mit Teil von ihm der 
Umkreis ist, der markiert werden und der zentrale gezeigte Winkel. 
Da der Benutzer jedes Ende des Bogens schleppt, ist es redrawn 
und intercpted Bogenänderungen. Applet kann zum vollen 
Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert
werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf 
es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek 
ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept de l'arc arrêté - 'cette partie d'un 
cercle qui se trouve entre deux lignes qui l'intersectent '. 
L'applet montre que un cercle avec une partie de lui est 
circonférence mise en valeur et l'angle central montré. Car 
l'utilisateur traîne l'une ou l'autre extrémité de l'arc c'est 
redrawn et intercpted des changements d'arc. L'applet peut être
agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur 
de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de 
classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito do arco interceptado - ' essa parte de um 
círculo que se encontre entre duas linhas que a cruzam '. O 
applet mostra que um círculo com parte dele é circunferência 
destacada e o ângulo central mostrado. Porque o usuário 
arrasta uma ou outra extremidade do arco é redrawn e intercpted 
mudanças do arco. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela
cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de 
uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o 
web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto dell'arco intercettato - 'quella parte di un 
cerchio che si trova fra due righe che la intersecano '. Il 
applet mostra che un cerchio con la parte di esso è circonferenza 
evidenziata e l'angolo centrale indicato. Poichè l'utente 
trascina la una o la altra estremità dell'arco è redrawn ed 
intercpted i cambiamenti dell'arco. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια του παρεμποδισμένου τόξου - "ότι μέρος 
ενός κύκλου που βρίσκεται μεταξύ δύο γραμμών που τον κόβουν". 
Το applet εμφανίζει ότι ένας κύκλος με μέρος από το 
είναι περιφέρεια που τονίζονται και η κεντρική γωνία που 
εμφανίζεται. Δεδομένου ότι ο χρήστης σέρνει καθένα τέλος 
του τόξου αποσύρεται και οι αλλαγές τόξων. Το Applet 
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto del arco interceptado - ' esa parte de un 
círculo que mienta entre dos líneas que la intersequen '. El 
applet muestra que un círculo con la parte de él es circunferencia 
destacada y el ángulo central mostrado. Pues el utilizador 
arrastra cualquier extremo del arco es redrawn e intercpted cambios 
del arco. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla 
completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El 
uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso 
otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin 
la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un componente del 
proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la 
referencia abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209800</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106339</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/intercepted-arc</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
