<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105385</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105385</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203032</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Groundwater Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grundwasser-Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animations d'Eaux souterraines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animations Do Groundwater</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazioni Dell'Acqua freatica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωτικότητες υπόγειων νερών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animaciones De la Agua subterránea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Flash and QuickTime animations related to groundwater. They contrast the permeability of gravel, sand, silt, and clay, as well as the speed of groundwater movement in rivers, lakes, and aquifers. They also outline the hydrologic cycle, discussing infiltration, percolation, and the water table, exhibit groundwater overdraft and the resulting formation of a cone of depression, and show how groundwater entering fractured bedrock can become superheated and pushed to the surface, erupting as a geyser. The animations can be paused and rewound to stress important points. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Situationsmerkmale Blitz- und 
QuickTimeanimationen standen auf Grundwasser in Verbindung. Sie 
kontrastieren die Permeabilität des Kieses, des Sandes, der Feinkohle
und des Lehms, sowie die Geschwindigkeit der Grundwasserbewegung in 
den Flüssen, in den Seen und in den Aquifers. Sie umreißen 
auch die hydrologische Schleife und behandeln Infiltration, Filtration
und die Wassertabelle, Ausstellunggrundwasserkontoüberziehung und die
resultierende Anordnung eines Kegels des Tiefstands und das 
Erscheinen, wie das Grundwasser, das zerbrochenes Grundgestein kommt, 
überhitzt und gedrückt zur Oberfläche werden kann und brechen als 
Geysir aus. Die Animationen können pausiert werden und 
gerückspult werden, um wichtige Punkte zu betonen. Diese 
Betriebsmittel sind für Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, in den Labors 
oder in anderen unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces animations d'instantané et de QuickTime de 
dispositifs de site ont associé aux eaux souterraines. Elles 
contrastent la perméabilité du gravier, du sable, de la vase, et de 
l'argile, aussi bien que la vitesse du mouvement d'eaux souterraines 
en fleuves, lacs, et couches aquifères. Ils tracent les grandes
lignes également du cycle hydrologique, discutant l'infiltration, la 
percolation, et la table de l'eau, découvert d'eaux souterraines 
d'objet exposé et la formation résultante d'un cône de dépression,
et exposition comment les eaux souterraines entrant dans la roche en 
place rompue peuvent devenir surchauffées et poussées sur la 
surface, éclatant comme geyser. Les animations peuvent être 
faites une pause et rebobinées pour soumettre à une contrainte les 
points importants. Ces ressources conviennent pour l'usage dans 
les conférences, les laboratoires, ou d'autres activités 
d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estes animations do flash e do QuickTime das 
características de local relacionaram-se ao groundwater. 
Contrastam a permeabilidade do cascalho, da areia, do silt, e da
argila, as.well.as a velocidade do movimento do groundwater nos rios, 
nos lagos, e nos aquifers. Esboçam também o ciclo hydrologic, 
discutindo o infiltration, o percolation, e a tabela da água, 
overdraft do groundwater da exibição e a formação resultante de um
cone do depression, e mostra como o groundwater que entra no bedrock 
fraturado pode se tornar superheated e empurrado para a superfície, 
erupting como um geyser. Os animations podem ser pausados e 
rebobinado para forçar pontos importantes. Estes recursos são 
apropriados para o uso nos lectures, nos laboratórios, ou em outras 
atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Queste animazioni dell'istantaneo e del QuickTime 
delle caratteristiche di luogo si sono riferite ad acqua freatica. 
Contrappongono la permeabilità di ghiaia, della sabbia, del 
limo e dell'argilla, così come la velocità del movimento dell'acqua 
freatica in fiumi, laghi e strati acquiferi. Egualmente 
descrivono il ciclo idrologico, discutente l'infiltrazione, la 
percolazione e la tabella dell'acqua, scoperto dell'acqua freatica 
dell'esposizione e la formazione risultante di un cono della 
depressione ed esposizione come l'acqua freatica che entra nella 
roccia fresca fratturata può essere superheated e spinta verso la 
superficie, scoppiante come geyser. Le animazioni possono 
essere fatte una pausa e riavvolte per sollecitare i punti importanti.
Queste risorse sono adatte ad uso nelle conferenze, in 
laboratori, o in altre attività d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τη λάμψη και τις 
ζωτικότητες QuickTime σχετικές με τα υπόγεια νερά. 
Αντιπαραβάλλουν τη διαπερατότητα του αμμοχάλικου, της άμμου,
του βούρκου, και του αργίλου, καθώς επίσης και της ταχύτητας της 
μετακίνησης υπόγειων νερών στους ποταμούς, τις λίμνες, και τα 
υδροφόρα στρώματα. Περιγράφουν επίσης τον υδρολογικό 
κύκλο, συζητώντας τη διήθηση, τη διείσδυση, και τη στάθμη νερού,
τη μεγαλύτερη των καταθέσεων ανάληψη υπόγειων νερών εκθεμάτων 
και τον προκύπτοντα σχηματισμό ενός κώνου της κατάθλιψης, και 
επιδεικνύουν πώς τα υπόγεια νερά που εισάγουν σπασμένο στρώμα 
βράχου μπορούν να γίνουν superheated και ωθημένα στην 
επιφάνεια, που εκρήγνυται ως geyser. Οι ζωτικότητες 
μπορούν να σταματηθούν και rewound για να τονίζουν τα σημαντικά
σημεία. Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για 
τη χρήση στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες 
διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estas animaciones del flash y de QuickTime de las 
características de sitio se relacionaron con la agua subterránea. 
Ponen en contraste la permeabilidad de la grava, de la arena, 
del légamo, y de la arcilla, así como la velocidad del movimiento de
la agua subterránea en los ríos, los lagos, y los acuíferos. 
También contornean el ciclo hidrológico, discutiendo la 
infiltración, filtración, y el vector del agua, saldo descubierto de
la agua subterránea del objeto expuesto y la formación que resulta 
de un cono de la depresión, y demostración cómo la agua 
subterránea que entra en roca de fondo fracturada puede 
sobrecalentado y empujarse a la superficie, entrando en erupción como
géiser. Las animaciones se pueden detener brevemente y 
rebobinar para tensionar puntas importantes. Estos recursos son 
convenientes para el uso en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras 
actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203032</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105385</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/groundwater-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
