<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107777</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107777</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201369</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Using GLOBE Data to Study the Earth System</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Verwenden von von KUGEL Daten, um das Masse System zu studieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Utilisation des données de GLOBE pour étudier le système de 
la terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Usando dados do GLOBO estudar o sistema da terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Usando i dati del GLOBO per studiare il sistema della terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: 
Χρησιμοποίηση των στοιχείων ΣΦΑΙΡΩΝ για να μελετήσει το 
γήινο σύστημα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Usar datos del GLOBO para estudiar el sistema de la 
tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Earth Exploration Toolbook chapter guides users through the process of locating and graphing data that has been collected by students who participate in the GLOBE Program. Users access the online GLOBE graphing tool and produce a graph comparing four Earth system variables over two complete years. Data include Maximum Air Temperature, Soil Moisture (at depths of both 10 cm and 90 cm), and Rainfall recorded in Greenville, Pennsylvania. As they investigate this specific case study, users discover patterns in the data that reveal seasonal changes in soil moisture. The patterns provide opportunities to discuss such Earth system concepts as the reservoir, the flux or flow of moisture between different reservoirs, and the role of solar energy in driving Earth system processes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel führen 
Benutzer durch den Prozeß des Lokalisierens und der graphischeen 
Darstellung von von Daten, die von den Kursteilnehmern gesammelt 
worden ist, die am KUGEL Programm teilnehmen. Benutzer greifen 
auf das graphisch darstellenhilfsmittel der Online-KUGEL zu und 
produzieren ein Diagramm, das vier Masse System Variablen über zwei 
kompletten Jahren vergleicht. Daten schließen maximale 
Lufttemperatur, Boden-Feuchtigkeit (an den Tiefen von 10 Zentimeter 
und von 90 Zentimeter) und den Niederschlag, der in Greenville, 
Pennsylvania gespeichert wird ein. Da sie diese spezifische 
Fallstudie nachforschen, entdecken Benutzer Muster in den Daten, die 
Saisonänderungen in der Bodenfeuchtigkeit aufdecken. Die Muster
liefern Gelegenheiten, solche Masse System Konzepte wie der 
Vorratsbehälter, der Fluß oder der Fluß der Feuchtigkeit zwischen 
unterschiedliche Vorratsbehälter zu behandeln und die Rolle von 
Solarenergie, wenn sie Masse System Prozesse antreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce chapitre de Toolbook d'exploration de la terre 
guident des utilisateurs par le processus de localiser et de 
représenter graphiquement les données qui ont été rassemblées par
les étudiants qui participent au programme de GLOBE. Les 
utilisateurs accèdent à l'outil de graphique de GLOBE en ligne et 
produisent un graphique comparant quatre variables de système de la 
terre sur deux années complètes. Les données incluent la 
température de l'air maximum, l'humidité de sol (aux profondeurs de 
10 centimètres et de 90 centimètres), et les précipitations 
enregistrées à Greenville, Pennsylvanie. Car ils étudient 
cette étude de cas spécifique, les utilisateurs découvrent des 
configurations dans les données qui indiquent les changements 
saisonniers de l'humidité de sol. Les configurations 
fournissent des occasions de discuter des concepts de système de la 
terre tels que le réservoir, le flux ou l'écoulement de l'humidité 
entre différents réservoirs, et le rôle de l'énergie solaire en 
pilotant des processus de système de la terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este capítulo de Toolbook da exploração da 
terra guia usuários com o processo de encontrar e de representar 
graficamente os dados que foram coletados pelos estudantes que 
participam no programa do GLOBO. Os usuários alcançam a 
ferramenta representando graficamente do GLOBO em linha e produzem um 
gráfico que compara quatro variáveis do sistema da terra sobre dois 
anos completos. Os dados incluem a temperatura de ar máxima, a 
umidade do solo (em profundidades  de 10 cm e de 90 cm), e o rainfall 
gravado em Greenville, Pensilvânia. Porque investigam este 
estudo de caso específico, os usuários descobrem testes padrões nos
dados que revelam mudanças seasonal na umidade do solo. Os 
testes padrões fornecem oportunidades de discutir conceitos do 
sistema da terra como o reservatório, o fluxo ou o fluxo da umidade 
entre reservatórios diferentes, e o papel da energia solar em dirigir
processos do sistema da terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo capitolo di Toolbook di esplorazione della 
terra guida gli utenti con il processo di individuazione e di 
rappresentare graficamente dei dati che sono stati raccolti dagli 
allievi che partecipano al programma del GLOBO. Gli utenti 
accedono allo strumento rappresentante graficamente del GLOBO in linea
e producono un grafico che confronta quattro variabili del sistema 
della terra in due anni completi. I dati includono la 
temperatura dell'aria massima, l'umidità del terreno (alle 
profondità sia di 10 centimetri che di 90 centimetri) e la pioggia 
registrata a Greenville, Pensilvania. Poichè studiano questa 
inchiesta specifica, gli utenti scoprono i modelli nei dati che 
rivelano i cambiamenti stagionali in umidità del terreno. I 
modelli forniscono le occasioni discutere tali concetti del sistema 
della terra come il serbatoio, il cambiamento continuo o il flusso di 
umidità fra i serbatoi differenti ed il ruolo di energia solare 
nell'azionamento dei processi del sistema della terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης 
καθοδηγεί τους χρήστες μέσω της διαδικασίας και το στοιχείο που 
έχει συλλεχθεί από τους σπουδαστές που συμμετέχουν στο πρόγραμμα
ΣΦΑΙΡΩΝ. Οι χρήστες έχουν πρόσβαση στη σε απευθείας σύνδεση
ΣΦΑΙΡΑ δίνοντας με γραφική παράσταση το εργαλείο και παράγουν μια
γραφική παράσταση συγκρίνοντας τέσσερις μεταβλητές γήινων 
συστημάτων πάνω από δύο πλήρη έτη. Τα στοιχεία 
περιλαμβάνουν τη μέγιστη θερμοκρασία αέρα, την εδαφολογική 
υγρασία (στα βάθη και 10 εκατ. και 90 εκατ.), και τις 
βροχοπτώσεις που καταγράφονται στην Γκρήνβιλ, Πενσυλβανία. 
Δεδομένου ότι ερευνούν αυτήν την συγκεκριμένη 
περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη, οι χρήστες ανακαλύπτουν τα πρότυπα στα 
στοιχεία που αποκαλύπτουν εποχιακές αλλαγές στην εδαφολογική 
υγρασία. Τα πρότυπα παρέχουν τις ευκαιρίες να συζητηθούν 
τέτοιες έννοιες γήινων συστημάτων όπως τη δεξαμενή, τη ροή ή 
τη ροή της υγρασίας μεταξύ των διαφορετικών δεξαμενών, και το 
ρόλο της ηλιακής ενέργειας στην οδήγηση των διαδικασιών γήινων 
συστημάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este capítulo de Toolbook de la exploración de 
la tierra dirige a utilizadores con el proceso de localizar y de 
representar los datos gra'ficamente que han sido recogidos por los 
estudiantes que participan en el programa del GLOBO. Los 
utilizadores tienen acceso a la herramienta de representación 
gráfico gra'ficamente del GLOBO en línea y producen un gráfico que 
compara cuatro variables del sistema de la tierra sobre dos años 
completos. Los datos incluyen temperatura del aire máximo, la 
humedad del suelo (en las profundidades de 10 centímetros y de 90 
centímetros), y la precipitación registrada en Greenville, 
Pennsylvania. Pues investigan este estudio de caso específico, 
los utilizadores descubren modelos en los datos que revelan cambios 
estacionales en humedad del suelo. Los modelos proporcionan a 
oportunidades de discutir los conceptos tales del sistema de la tierra
como el depósito, el flux o el flujo de la humedad entre diversos 
depósitos, y el papel de la energía solar en conducir procesos del 
sistema de la tierra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NICK HADDAD
FN:NICK HADDAD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201369</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107777</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-using-globe-data-to-study-the-earth-system</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
