<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106525</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106525</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087550</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Open Education 2007 Conference</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eröffnen Sie Konferenz Ausbildung 2007</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ouvrez La Conférence de l'Éducation 2007</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Abra A Conferência Da Instrução 2007</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Apra Il Congresso Di Formazione 2007</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανοικτή διάσκεψη εκπαίδευσης 2007</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Abra La Conferencia De la Educación 2007</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Open Education 2007 will focus specifically on localizing open educational resources and learning from open educational resources. If our open education efforts aren't supporting learning, we're failing as a field. Period. And as we are beginning to understand how to produce and license content, we have to turn some of our attention to how this content is used by learners and teachers. How do they change, adapt, and localize it for their specific needs or the needs of their specific students? Do open educational resources support learning in ways different from non-open resources? In what concrete ways do open educational resources support learning?</string>
          </description>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geöffnete Ausbildung 2007 konzentriert spezifisch 
auf das Beschränken der geöffneten pädagogischen Betriebsmittel und
das Lernen von den geöffneten pädagogischen Betriebsmitteln. 
Wenn unsere geöffneten Ausbildung Bemühungen nicht das Lernen 
unterstützen, fallen wir als auffangene aus. Periode. 
Und während wir anfangen, zu verstehen, wie man produziert und 
Lizenzinhalt, müssen wir drehen etwas von unserer Aufmerksamkeit zu, 
wie dieser Inhalt von den Anfängern und von den Lehrern benutzt wird.
Wie ändern sie, passen an und beschränken ihn für ihre 
spezifischen Notwendigkeiten oder die Notwendigkeiten ihrer 
spezifischen Kursteilnehmer? Unterstützen geöffnete 
pädagogische Betriebsmittel das Lernen in den Methoden, die zu 
unterschiedlich sind, nicht-öffnen Betriebsmittel? In welchen 
konkreten Methoden unterstützen geöffnete pädagogische 
Betriebsmittel das Lernen?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'éducation ouverte 2007 se concentrera 
spécifiquement sur localiser les ressources éducatives ouvertes et 
apprendre des ressources éducatives ouvertes. Si nos efforts 
ouverts d'éducation ne supportent pas l'étude, nous échouons comme 
zone. Période. Et pendant que nous commençons à 
comprendre comment produire et contenu de permis, nous devons tourner 
une partie de notre attention à la façon dont ce contenu est 
employé par des étudiants et des professeurs. Comment est-ce 
qu'ils le changent, adaptent, et localisent pour leurs besoins 
spécifiques ou les besoins de leurs étudiants spécifiques ? 
Les ressources éducatives ouvertes supportent-elles l'étude 
des voies différentes de non-ouvrent-elles des ressources ? De 
quelles voies concrètes les ressources éducatives ouvertes 
supportent-elles l'étude ?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A instrução aberta 2007 focalizará 
especificamente em localizar recursos educacionais abertos e na 
aprendizagem dos recursos educacionais abertos. Se nossos 
esforços abertos da instrução não estiverem suportando a 
aprendizagem, nós estamos falhando como um campo. Período. 
E enquanto nós estamos começando a compreender como produzir e
índice da licença, nós temos que girar alguma de nossa atenção a 
como este índice é usado por learners e por professores. Como 
o mudam, adaptam, e localizam para suas necessidades específicas ou 
as necessidades de seus estudantes específicos? Os recursos 
educacionais abertos suportam a aprendizagem nas maneiras diferentes 
de non-abrem recursos? Em que maneiras concretas os recursos 
educacionais abertos suportam a aprendizagem?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La formazione aperta 2007 metterà a fuoco 
specificamente sul localizzare le risorse educative aperte e 
sull'imparare dalle risorse educative aperte. Se i nostri sforzi
aperti di formazione non stanno sostenendo imparare, stiamo venendo a 
mancare come campo. Periodo. E mentre stiamo cominciando a
capire come produrre e soddisfare dell'autorizzazione, dobbiamo 
rivolgere alcuna della nostra attenzione a come questo soddisfare è 
usato dai principianti e dagli insegnanti. Come lo cambiano, 
adattano e localizzano per i loro bisogni specifici o i bisogni dei 
loro allievi specifici? Le risorse educative aperte sostengono 
imparare nei modi differenti da non-aprono le risorse? In che 
modi concreti le risorse educative aperte sostengono imparare?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ανοικτή εκπαίδευση το 2007 θα εστιάσει 
συγκεκριμένα στον εντοπισμό των ανοικτών εκπαιδευτικών στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς και την εκμάθηση από τα ανοικτά εκπαιδευτικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς. Εάν οι ανοικτές προσπάθειες 
εκπαίδευσής μας δεν υποστηρίζουν την εκμάθηση, αποτυγχάνουμε ως 
πεδίο. Περίοδος. Και δεδομένου ότι αρχίζουμε να 
καταλαβαίνουμε πώς να παραγάγουμε και να χορηγήσουμε άδεια το 
περιεχόμενο, πρέπει να στρέψουμε μερικών από την προσοχή μας στο
πώς αυτό το περιεχόμενο χρησιμοποιείται από τους αρχαρίους και 
τους δασκάλους. Πώς το αλλάζουν, προσαρμόζουν, και 
εντοπίζουν για τις συγκεκριμένες ανάγκες τους ή τις ανάγκες των 
συγκεκριμένων σπουδαστών τους; Τα ανοικτά εκπαιδευτικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς υποστηρίζουν την εκμάθηση στους τρόπους 
διαφορετικούς από τα μη-ανοικτά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς; Με 
ποιους συγκεκριμένους τρόπους τα ανοικτά εκπαιδευτικά στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς υποστηρίζουν την εκμάθηση;</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La educación abierta 2007 se centrará 
específicamente en localizar recursos educativos abiertos y aprender 
de recursos educativos abiertos. Si nuestros esfuerzos abiertos 
de la educación no están utilizando aprender, estamos fallando como 
campo. Período. Y como estamos comenzando a entender 
cómo producir y contenido de la licencia, tenemos que dar vuelta a 
algo de nuestra atención a cómo este contenido es utilizado por los 
principiantes y los profesores. ¿Cómo lo cambian, adaptan, y 
localizan para sus necesidades específicas o las necesidades de sus 
estudiantes específicos? ¿Los recursos educativos abiertos 
utilizan aprender de las maneras diferentes de no-abren recursos? 
¿De qué maneras concretas los recursos educativos abiertos 
utilizan aprender?</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087550</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106525</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/opened-2007</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
