<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103798</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103798</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086321</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">In Defense of IQ Testing: Lewis M. Terman Replies to Critics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zum Schutze von der IQ Prüfung: Lewis M. 
Terman Replies auf Kritiker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À la défense du test de Q.I. : Lewis M. 
Terman Replies aux critiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na defesa de testar do IQ: Lewis M. Terman 
Responder aos críticos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In difesa della prova di quoziente d'intelligenza: 
Lewis M. Terman Replies ai critici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην υπεράσπιση του ΔΕΙΚΤΗ ΝΟΗΜΟΣΎΝΗΣ που εξετάζει: 
Lewis Μ. Terman απαντήσεις στους κριτικούς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la defensa de la prueba del índice de 
inteligencia: Lewis M. Terman Replies a los críticos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"There is nothing about an individual as important as his IQ," declared psychologist Lewis M. Terman in 1922. To the extent that this is true, it is in large measure because of Terman himself and the opportunity that World War I afforded for the first widespread use of intelligence testing. The army's use of intelligence tests lent new credibility to the emerging profession of psychology, even as it sparked public debate about the validity of the tests and their implications for American democracy. The idea that experts could confidently assign a man to his proper place in the army--and by extension, his place in life--suggested a kind of determinism that some found profoundly at odds with American democracy and its credo of upward mobility through hard work. In "The Great Conspiracy," Lewis Terman replied with acid commentary to a series of articles by Walter Lippmann criticizing IQ tests. Terman portrayed Lippmann as a sentimental humanist whose democratic dogma prevented him from accepting plain facts. According to Terman, Americans clearly exhibited a range of different intellectual endowments and the new science of psychology made it possible to measure and classify those differences.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es gibt nichts über eine Einzelperson, die," 
erklärter Psychologe Lewis M. Terman 1922 so wichtig ist wie sein IQ.
Soweit daß dieses zutreffend ist, ist es in großem Umfang 
wegen Terman selbst und der Gelegenheit, die der Erste Weltkrieg für 
den ersten weitverbreiteten Gebrauch von Intelligenzprüfung sich 
leistete. Der Gebrauch der Armee von Intelligenz prüft 
verliehene neue Glaubwürdigkeit zum auftauchenden Beruf von 
Psychologie, selbst als er allgemeine Debatte über die Gültigkeit 
der Tests und ihrer Implikationen für amerikanische Demokratie 
funkte. Die Idee, daß Experten einen Mann seinem korrekten 
Platz in der Armee sicher zuweisen konnten -- und durch Extension, 
sein Platz im Leben -- schlug eine Art Determinismus vor, die einige 
profund uneins mit amerikanischer Demokratie und seinem Credo von 
aufwärts Mobilität durch harte Arbeit fanden. "in der großen 
Verschwörung" antwortete Lewis Terman mit saurem Kommentar auf eine 
Reihe Artikel durch Walter Lippmann, der IQ Tests kritisiert. 
Terman schilderte Lippmann als sentimental Humanist dessen 
demokratisches Dogma ihn am Annehmen der normalen Tatsachen hinderte. 
Entsprechend Terman stellten Amerikaner offenbar eine Strecke 
der unterschiedlichen intellektuellen Ausstattungen aus und die neue 
Wissenschaft von Psychologie machte es möglich, jene Unterschiede zu 
messen und einzustufen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il n'y a rien au sujet d'un individu aussi 
important que son Q.I.," psychologue avoué Lewis M. Terman en 1922. 
Dans la mesure où c'est vrai, il est dans une large mesure en 
raison de Terman lui-même et de l'occasion que la Première Guerre 
Mondiale a eus les moyens pour le premier usage répandu du test 
d'intelligence. L'utilisation de l'armée de l'intelligence 
teste la nouvelle crédibilité prêtée à la profession naissante de
la psychologie, même pendant qu'elle étincelait discussion publique 
au sujet de la validité des essais et de leurs implications pour la 
démocratie américaine. L'idée que les experts pourraient avec
confiance affecter un homme à son endroit approprié dans l'armée --
et par l'extension, son endroit dans la vie -- a suggéré un genre de
déterminisme que certains ont trouvé profondément à la chance avec
la démocratie américaine et son credo de mobilité ascendante 
par le travail dur. Dans "la grande conspiration," Lewis Terman 
a répondu avec le commentaire acide à une série d'articles par 
Walter Lippmann critiquant des essais de Q.I.. Terman a dépeint
Lippmann en tant qu'humaniste sentimental dont le dogme démocratique 
l'a empêché de recevoir des faits ordinaires. Selon Terman, 
les Américains ont clairement montré un intervalle de différentes 
dotations intellectuelles et la nouvelle science de la psychologie a 
permis pour mesurer et classifier ces différences.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não há nada sobre um indivíduo tão importante 
quanto seu IQ," psicólogo declarado Lewis M. Terman em 1922. 
Até ao ponto em que isto é verdadeiro, está na medida grande 
por causa de Terman ele mesmo e na oportunidade que o world.war.i teve
recursos para para o primeiro uso difundido de testar da 
inteligência. O uso do exército da inteligência testa o 
credibility novo emprestado à profissão emergente do psychology, 
mesmo como ele acendeu debate público sobre a validez dos testes e de
suas implicações para a democracia americana. A idéia que os 
peritos poderiam confiàvel atribuir um homem a seu lugar apropriado 
no exército -- e pela extensão, seu lugar na vida -- sugeriu um tipo
do determinism que algumas encontrassem profundamente em 
probabilidades com democracia americana e seu credo da mobilidade 
ascendente através do trabalho duro. "no conspiracy grande," 
Lewis Terman respondeu com commentary ácido a uma série dos artigos 
por Walter Lippmann que critica testes do IQ. Terman portrayed 
Lippmann como um humanista sentimental cujo o dogma democrático 
impedisse que aceite fatos lisos. De acordo com Terman, os 
americanos exibiram claramente uma escala de endowments intelectuais 
diferentes e a ciência nova do psychology fêz possível medir e 
classificar aquelas diferenças.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ci è niente circa un individuo importante quanto 
il suo quoziente d'intelligenza," psicologo dichiarato Lewis M. Terman
in 1922. Anche se questo è allineare, è in una larga misura a 
causa di Terman egli stesso e dell'occasione che il world.war.i si è 
permesso per il primo uso molto diffuso di prova di intelligenza. 
L'uso dell'esercito di intelligenza verifica la nuova 
credibilità prestata alla professione d'emersione della psicologia, 
proprio mentre ha scintillato dibattito pubblico circa la validità 
delle prove e delle loro implicazioni per la democrazia americana. 
L'idea che gli esperti potrebbero assegnare con confidenza un 
uomo al suo posto adeguato nell'esercito -- e dall'estensione, il suo 
posto nella vita -- ha suggerito un genere di determinismo che alcune 
hanno trovato profondamente in disaccordo con la democrazia americana 
ed il relativo credo di mobilità ascendente attraverso lavoro duro. 
"nella cospirazione grande," Lewis Terman ha risposto con il 
commento acido ad una serie di articoli da Walter Lippmann che critica
le prove di quoziente d'intelligenza. Terman ha ritratto 
Lippmann come humanist sentimental di cui il dogma democratico gli ha 
impedito di accettare i fatti normali. Secondo Terman, gli 
Americani hanno esibito chiaramente una gamma di dotazioni 
intellettuali differenti e la nuova scienza della psicologia ha 
permesso di misurare e classificare quelle differenze.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν υπάρχει τίποτα για ένα άτομο τόσο σημαντικό 
όπως ο ΔΕΙΚΤΗΣ ΝΟΗΜΟΣΎΝΗΣ του," δηλωμένος ψυχολόγος Lewis Μ. 
Terman σε 1922, μέχρι το σημείο που αυτό ισχύει, αυτό 
είναι σε μεγάλο βαθμό λόγω Terman ο ίδιος και της ευκαιρίας 
που ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος εγώ παρείχε για την πρώτη διαδεδομένη 
χρήση της δοκιμής νοημοσύνης. Η χρήση του στρατού των 
δοκιμών νοημοσύνης δάνεισε τη νέα αξιοπιστία στο αναδυόμενο 
επάγγελμα της ψυχολογίας, ακόμη και δεδομένου ότι προκάλεσε τη 
δημόσια συζήτηση για την ισχύ των δοκιμών και των επιπτώσεών 
τους στην αμερικανική δημοκρατία. Η ιδέα ότι οι 
εμπειρογνώμονες θα μπορούσαν με βεβαιότητα να διορίσουν ένα 
άτομο στην κατάλληλη θέση του στο στρατό -- και κατ' επέκταση, η 
θέση του στη ζωή -- πρότεινε ένα είδος αιτιοκρατίας που μερικοί
βρήκαν βαθιά σε διαφωνία με την αμερικανική δημοκρατία και το 
credo ανοδικής κινητικότητάς του μέσω της σκληρής εργασίας. 
"Στη μεγάλη συνωμοσία," Lewis Terman απάντησε με τα 
όξινα σχόλια σε μια σειρά άρθρων από walter Lippmann που 
επικρίνει τις δοκιμές ΔΕΙΚΤΗ ΝΟΗΜΟΣΎΝΗΣ. Το Terman 
απεικόνισε Lippmann ως συναισθηματικό ανθρωπιστή το ο οποίος 
δημοκρατικό δόγμα τον απέτρεψε από την αποδοχή των σαφών 
γεγονότων. Σύμφωνα με Terman, Αμερικανοί εξέθεσαν σαφώς 
μια σειρά των διαφορετικών διανοητικών χρηματοδοτήσεων και η νέα 
επιστήμη της ψυχολογίας το κατέστησε πιθανό να μετρήσει και να 
ταξινομήσει εκείνες τις διαφορές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no hay nada sobre un individuo tan importante como
su índice de inteligencia," psicólogo declarado Lewis M. Terman en 
1922. Hasta el punto de esto sea verdad, está en la medida 
grande debido a Terman misma y la oportunidad que la Primera Guerra 
Mundial produjo para el primer uso extenso de la prueba de la 
inteligencia. El uso del ejército de la inteligencia prueba 
nueva credibilidad prestada a la profesión que emerge de la 
psicología, incluso como él chispeó discusión público sobre la 
validez de las pruebas y de sus implicaciones para la democracia 
americana. La idea que los expertos podrían asignar con 
confianza a un hombre a su lugar apropiado en el ejército -- y por la
extensión, su lugar en vida -- sugirió una clase de determinismo que
algo encontró profundo en desacuerdo con democracia americana y su 
credo de la movilidad ascendente a través de trabajo duro. En 
"la gran conspiración," Lewis Terman contestó con comentario ácido 
a una serie de artículos de Walter Lippmann que criticaba pruebas del
índice de inteligencia. Terman retrató Lippmann como humanista
sentimental que dogma democrático evitó que él validara hechos 
llanos. Según Terman, los americanos exhibieron claramente un 
rango de diversas dotaciones intelectuales y la nueva ciencia de la 
psicología permitió medir y clasificar esas diferencias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086321</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103798</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/in-defense-of-iq-testing-lewis-m-terman-replies-to-critics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
