<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108730</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108730</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087120</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Times Is Gettin Harder": Blues of the Great Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Zeiten Ist Gettin Stark": Blau der großen 
Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les "Temps Est Gettin Plus dur" : Bleus du 
grand transfert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os "Tempos São Gettin Mais duramente": 
Azuis da migração grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"I Tempi È Più duro Gettin": Azzurri 
dell'espansione grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι χρόνοι είναι Gettin σκληρότερο": Μπλε της 
μεγάλης μετανάστευσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los "Tiempos Son Gettin Más difícilmente": 
Azul de la gran migración</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The movement between 1916 and 1921 of a half million African Americans from the South to cities in the North and West was known as the Great Migration. Black migrants told their stories in many forms from letters to poems to paintings. Music offered one of the most original forms in which the migration narrative was told."Times Is Gettin Harder" (a 1940 recording of an older blues tune by Lucious Curtis) described various incidents from racial injustice to economic hardship that prompted one man's journey away from the land of "cotton and corn."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Bewegung zwischen 1916 und 1921 von halbe 
Million afrikanische Amerikaner vom Süden zu den Städte im Norden 
und im Westen bekannt als die große Migration. Schwarze 
Wanderer erklärten ihre Geschichten in vielen Formen von Zeichen zu 
Gedichte zu den Anstrichen. Musik bot eins der ursprünglichsten
Formulare an, in denen die Migration Darstellung told."Times ist 
Gettin stark" (eine Aufnahme 1940 von älteres Blau justieren durch 
Lucious Curtis) beschriebene verschiedene Ereignisse vom rassischen 
Unrecht zur ökonomischen Härte war, die aufforderte eine Reise des 
Mannes weg vom Land "von Baumwolle und von Mais."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement entre 1916 et 1921 de l'demi de 
million d'Américains africains des Sud aux villes dans le 
nord et l'ouest a été connu comme grand transfert. Les 
migrants noirs ont dit leurs histoires sous beaucoup de formes à 
partir des lettres aux poésies aux peintures. La musique a 
offert une des formes les plus initiales dans lesquelles le récit de 
transfert était told."Times est incidents décrits de Gettin plus 
dur" (un enregistrement 1940 d'des bleus plus anciens accordent par 
Lucious Curtis) de divers de l'injustice raciale aux difficultés 
économiques qui ont incité un voyage de l'homme loin de la terre "du
coton et du maïs."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento entre 1916 e 1921 do meios milhão 
americanos africanos do sul às cidades no norte e no oeste foi sabido
como a migração grande. Os emigrantes pretos disseram suas 
histórias em muitos formulários das letras aos poemas às pinturas. 
A música ofereceu um dos formulários os mais originais em que 
a narrativa da migração era told."Times é incidents descritos de 
Gettin mais duramente" (uma gravação 1940 do uns azuis mais velhos 
ajusta por Lucious Curtis) vários do injustice racial ao hardship 
econômico que alertou uma viagem do homem away da terra "do algodão 
e do milho."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento fra 1916 e 1921 dell'milione 
Americani africani mezzi dal sud alle città nel nord e nell'ovest è 
stato conosciuto come l'espansione grande. I migranti neri hanno
detto alle loro storia in molte forme dalle lettere ai poems alle 
pitture. La musica ha offerto una delle forme più originali in 
cui la descrizione di espansione era told."Times è avvenimenti 
descritti di Gettin più duro" (una registrazione 1940 dell'più 
vecchi azzurri sintonizza da Lucious Curtis) vari da injustice 
razziale alle difficoltà economiche che hanno richiamato un viaggio 
dell'uomo via dalla terra "di cotone e di cereale."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μετακίνηση μεταξύ 1916 και 1921 μισών από 
εκατομμύριο αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς από το νότο στις πόλεις στο
Βορρά και τη δύση ήταν γνωστή ως μεγάλη μετανάστευση. Οι 
μαύροι μετανάστες είπαν τις ιστορίες τους με πολλές μορφές από 
τις επιστολές στα ποιήματα στα έργα ζωγραφικής. Η μουσική 
πρόσφερε μια από τις πιό αρχικές μορφές στις οποίες το αφήγημα 
μετανάστευσης ήταν told."Times είναι Gettin σκληρότερο" (μια
καταγραφή του 1940 παλαιότερα μπλε συντονίζει από Lucious 
Curtis) περιγεγραμμένα διάφορα γεγονότα από τη φυλετική 
αδικία στην οικονομική δυσκολία που προέτρεψε ένα ανθρώπινο 
ταξίδι μακρυά από το έδαφος "του βαμβακιού και του καλαμποκιού."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento entre 1916 y 1921 de medios millón 
de americanos africanos del sur a las ciudades en el norte y el oeste 
era conocido como la gran migración. Los nómadas negros 
contaron sus historias en muchas formas de cartas a los poemas a las 
pinturas. La música ofreció una de las formas más originales 
en las cuales la narrativa de la migración era told."Times es 
incidentes descritos de Gettin más difícilmente" (una grabación 
1940 del azul más viejos templa por Lucious Curtis) varios de la 
injusticia racial a la dificultad económica que incitó un viaje del 
hombre lejos de la pista "del algodón y del maíz."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087120</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108730</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/times-is-gettin-harder-blues-of-the-great-migration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
