<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105633</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105633</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206188</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Accidental Scientist: Science and Technology of Cooking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Versehentlicher Wissenschaftler: 
Wissenschaft und Technologie des Kochens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Scientifique Accidentel : La Science et 
technologie de la cuisine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cientista Acidental: Ciência e tecnologia 
de cozinhar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienziato Accidentale: Scienza e tecnologia
di cottura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τυχαίος επιστήμονας: Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία του
μαγειρέματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Científico Accidental: Ciencia y 
tecnología de cocinar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at the science behind food and cooking. Learn about what happens when you eat sugar, bake bread, cook an egg, or pickle foods. Find out how muscle turns to meat, what makes meat tender, and what gives meat its flavor. Take tours of breads and spices of the world. Explore your sense of taste and smell.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die Wissenschaft hinter Nahrung und dem
Kochen. Erlernen Sie über, was geschieht, wenn Sie Zucker 
essen, Brot backen, ein Ei oder Essiggurkenahrungsmittel kochen. 
Finden Sie, wie Muskel an Fleisch wendet heraus, was 
Fleischtender bildet und was Fleisch sein Aroma gibt. Nehmen Sie
Touren der Brote und der Gewürze der Welt. Erforschen Sie Ihre 
Richtung des Geschmacks und riechen Sie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards à la science derrière la nourriture et 
la cuisine. Renseignez-vous sur ce qui se produit quand vous 
mangez du sucre, faites le pain, faites cuire cuire au four un oeuf, 
ou des nourritures de conserves au vinaigre. Découvrez comment 
le muscle se tourne vers la viande, ce qui fait l'offre de viande, et 
ce qui donne à viande sa saveur. Prenez les excursions des 
pains et des épices du monde. Explorez votre sens de goût et 
sentez.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares na ciência atrás do alimento e de 
cozinhar. Aprenda sobre o que acontece quando você come o 
açúcar, coze o pão, cozinha um ovo, ou alimentos do pickle. 
Encontre para fora como o músculo gira para a carne, o que 
fazem o encarregado da carne, e o que dá a carne seu sabor. 
Faça exame de excursões dos pães e dos spices do mundo. 
Explore seu sentido do gosto e cheire-o.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi a scienza dietro alimento e cucinare. 
Impari circa che cosa accade quando mangiate lo zucchero, cocete
il pane, cucinate un uovo, o gli alimenti del sottaceto. Scopra 
come il muscolo si gira verso carne, che cosa fa l'offerta della carne
e che cosa dà a carne il relativo sapore. Prenda i giri dei 
pani e delle spezie del mondo. Esplori il vostro senso di gusto 
e senta l'odore di.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την επιστήμη πίσω από τα τρόφιμα και το 
μαγείρεμα. Μάθετε για αυτό που συμβαίνει πότε τρώτε τη 
ζάχαρη, ψήνετε το ψωμί, μαγειρεύετε ένα αυγό, ή τα τρόφιμα 
τουρσιών. Ανακαλύψτε πώς ο μυς γυρίζει στο κρέας, τι κάνει
την προσφορά κρέατος, και τι δίνει στο κρέας τη γεύση του. 
Πάρτε τους γύρους των ψωμιών και των καρυκευμάτων του 
κόσμου. Ερευνήστε την αίσθησή σας προτίμησης και μυρωδιάς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en la ciencia detrás del alimento y de 
cocinar. Aprenda sobre qué sucede cuando usted come el azúcar,
cuece al horno el pan, cocina un huevo, o los alimentos de la 
salmuera. Descubra cómo el músculo da vuelta a la carne, qué 
hace la oferta de la carne, y qué da a carne su sabor. Tome los
viajes de panes y de especias del mundo. Explore su sentido del 
gusto y huela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206188</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105633</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/accidental-scientist-science-and-technology-of-cooking</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
