<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105275</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105275</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200631</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Being P-Waves and S-Waves</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sein P-Bewegt wellenartig und S-Bewegt 
wellenartig</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Être P-Ondule et S-Ondule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ser P-Acena e S-Acena</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Essere P-Fluttua e S-Fluttua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όντας π-κύματα και s-ky'mata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ser P-Agita y S-Agita</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this role-playing activity, students physically act out the motions of P-waves and S-waves in class to help them develop an understanding of how these waves work in the Earth. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Rolle spielendes Aktivität fungieren 
Kursteilnehmer physikalisch aus den Bewegungen von P-wellenartig 
bewegt und S-wellenartig bewegt in Kategorie, um ihnen zu helfen, zu 
entwickeln ein Verständnis von, wie diese Wellen in der Masse 
arbeiten. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf 
Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für 
Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité jouante un rôle, les 
étudiants agissent physiquement hors des mouvements de P-ondule et 
S-ondule dans la classe pour les aider à développer un arrangement 
de la façon dont ces vagues fonctionnent dans la terre. À 
cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux 
informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les 
extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade role-playing, os estudantes agem 
fisicamente para fora dos movimentos de P-acenam e S-acenam na classe 
para ajudar-lhes desenvolver uma compreensão de como estas ondas 
trabalham na terra. Nesta página do ponto começar, os 
usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de 
aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as
notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as 
referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività d'atteggiamento, gli allievi 
si comportano fisicamente verso l'esterno i movimenti di P-fluttua e 
S-fluttua nel codice categoria per aiutarlo a sviluppare una 
comprensione di come queste onde funzionano nella terra. A 
questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle 
informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto 
per le punte di istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le 
idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την ρόλος-παίζοντας δραστηριότητα, οι 
σπουδαστές ενεργούν φυσικά έξω οι κινήσεις των π-κυμάτων και των
s-kyma'twn στην κλάση για να τους βοηθήσουν να αναπτύξουν μια 
κατανόηση για το πώς αυτά τα κύματα λειτουργούν στη γη. Σε 
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad de actuación de papeles, los 
estudiantes actúan físicamente fuera de los movimientos de P-agitan 
y S-agitan en clase para ayudarles a desarrollar una comprensión de 
cómo estas ondas trabajan en la tierra. En esta paginación del
punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la 
información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para
las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales
didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos 
cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MICHELLE HALL-WALLACE
FN:MICHELLE HALL-WALLACE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RANDALL RICHARDSON
FN:RANDALL RICHARDSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200631</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105275</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/being-p-waves-and-s-waves</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
