<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104767</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104767</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206581</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission 2009</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abraham Lincoln Zweihundertjährige Kommission 
2009</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Commission Bicentenaire 2009 d'Abraham Lincoln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Commission Bicentennial 2009 De Abraham Lincoln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Commissione Bicentenaria 2009 Di Abraham Lincoln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η δισεκατονταετής Επιτροπή 2009 του Abraham 
Λίνκολν</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comisión Bicentenaria 2009 De Abraham Lincoln</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">celebrates the upcoming 200th birthday of our 16th president. A timeline, key speeches, and links to organizations dedicated to the study of Lincoln are provided. Lesson plans (in the education section) help students examine Lincoln's position on slavery, his performance as commander-in-chief, and how U.S. history might have been different had he not been assassinated.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">feiert den upcoming 200. Geburtstag unseres 16. 
Präsidenten. Ein timeline, Schlüsselreden und Links zu den 
Organisationen, die der Studie von Lincoln eingesetzt werden, werden 
zur Verfügung gestellt. Kursteilnehmer Hilfe der Lektionpläne 
(im Ausbildung Kapitel) überprüfen Position Lincolns auf Sklaverei, 
seine Leistung als Kommandant-in-Leiter und wie VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Geschichte unterschiedlich gewesen sein konnte, waren er nicht 
ermordet worden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">célèbre le 200th anniversaire prochain de notre 
16ème président. Une chronologie, des discours principaux, et 
des liens aux organismes consacrés à l'étude de Lincoln sont 
fournis. Les étudiants d'aide de plans de leçon (dans la 
section d'éducation) examinent la position de Lincoln sur 
l'esclavage, son exécution comme commandant-dans-chef, et comment 
l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS pourrait avoir été différente il 
n'avaient pas été assassinés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">comemora o 200th aniversário upcoming de nosso 
1õ presidente. Um timeline, uns discursos chaves, e umas 
ligações às organizações dedicadas ao estudo de Lincoln são 
fornecidos. Os estudantes da ajuda das plantas da lição (na 
seção da instrução) examinam a posição no slavery, seu 
desempenho de Lincoln como o comandante-em-chefe, e como o history de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS pôde ter sido diferente ele não assassinated.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">celebra il 200th compleanno imminente del nostro 
sedicesimo presidente. Un timeline, i discorsi chiave ed i 
collegamenti alle organizzazioni dedicate allo studio di Lincoln sono 
forniti. Gli allievi di aiuto di programmi di lezione (nella 
sezione di formazione) esaminano la posizione su slavery, le sue 
prestazioni de Lincoln come comandante-in-capo e come la storia degli 
STATI UNITI potrebbe essere differente lui non erano stati 
assassinati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">γιορτάζει τα επερχόμενα 200th γενέθλια του 16$ου 
Προέδρου μας. Μια υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο, βασικές 
ομιλίες, και οι συνδέσεις με τις οργανώσεις που αφιερώνονται στη 
μελέτη του Λίνκολν παρέχονται. Οι σπουδαστές οδηγιών 
σχεδίων μαθήματος (στο τμήμα εκπαίδευσης) εξετάζουν τη θέση του 
Λίνκολν στη σκλαβιά, η απόδοσή του όπως 
διοικητής-$$$-ΠΡΟΪΣΤΆΜΕΝΟς, και πώς η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία να είναι 
διαφορετική δεν ήταν δολοφονημένος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">celebra el 200o cumpleaños próximo de nuestro 
décimosexto presidente. Un timeline, los discursos dominantes, 
y las conexiones a las organizaciones dedicadas al estudio de Lincoln 
se proporcionan. Los estudiantes de la ayuda de los planes de la
lección (en la sección de la educación) examinan la posición 
respecto a esclavitud, su funcionamiento de Lincoln como 
comandante-en-jefe, y cómo la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS pudo haber 
sido diferente él no habían sido asesinados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206581</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104767</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/abraham-lincoln-bicentennial-commission-2009</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
