<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108725</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108725</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085242</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Rise of Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anstieg von Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élévation de technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A ascensão da tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'aumento di tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η άνοδος της τεχνολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La subida de tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Airplanes, electric railways, and automobiles joined railways to fuel Americans' growing sense of mobility. They came to characterize the progressive spirit of the new century. As a result of these new modes of public transportation, people were able to travel faster and more easily within and between cities, changing settlement patterns. One image in this group depicts John J. Montgomery, the first American to fly a heavier-than-air machine, and his glider ?Santa Clara? in 1905. An invitation to an air show in San Jose in 1910 suggests the popularity of this potential new mode of transportation. Several cities had electric streetcars that ran on tracks, and images in this group include streetcars in San Diego, San Jose, and Los Angeles. The hand-tinted image of the Interurban Electric Rail Road running between Saratoga and Los Gatos suggests that in 1908, this was enough of a novelty to rate a postcard.The automobile industry was also growing rapidly. Before the internal combustion engine took the lead in the 1910s, cars ran on a variety of fuels; steam, electricity, and gasoline competed for a number of years. This is clearly evident from the two ads that appeared in the Saturday Evening Post for the steam car, and several images of people enjoying both electric- and gas-powered cars.Some inventions aimed to make life easier at home. The photograph of a storefront in 1925 shows the existence of appliances such as washing machines, ironing machines, and vacuum cleaners. In their new-found leisure time, people listened to the radio, an invention that was fairly new at this time. Two photographs taken in the mid-1920s show Charles Herrold, the ?Father of Radio,? operating radio equipment. The combination of new technologies, more free time, and the ability to get from one place to another relatively easily and quickly allowed people to enjoy new forms of entertainment, as indicated by the photograph of a car in front of a movie theater. Expositions were a popular venue to showcase the latest in technology, and several images here represent expositions that took place in San Francisco and San Diego in 1915 and 1916. One photograph depicts a panel of men at the opening of the phone wire between San Francisco and New York for the first time.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Flugzeuge, elektrische Gleise und Automobile 
verbanden Gleise zu wachsender Richtung der Kraftstoff Amerikaner von 
Mobilität. Sie kamen, den progressiven Geist des neuen 
Jahrhunderts zu kennzeichnen. Resultierend aus diesen neuen Modi
des allgemeinen Transportes, konnten Leute, innerhalb und zwischen der
Städte schneller und leicht zu reisen und änderten Regelung Muster. 
Ein Bild in dieser Gruppe stellt John J. Montgomery, der erste 
Amerikaner bildlich dar, um eine Schwer-alsluft Maschine und sein 
Segelflugzeug?Santa Clara zu fliegen? 1905. Eine Einladung
zu einer Flugschau in San Jose 1910 schlägt die Popularität dieses 
möglichen neuen Modus des Transportes vor. Einige Städte 
hatten elektrische streetcars, die auf Spuren liefen, und Bilder in 
dieser Gruppe schließen streetcars in San Diego, in San Jose und in 
Los Angeles ein. Das Hand-abgetönte Bild der Interurban 
elektrischen Schiene Straße, die zwischen Saratoga und Los Gatos 
läuft, schlägt vor, daß 1908, dieses genug einer Neuheit war, zum 
einer postcard.The Automobilindustrie zu bewerten wuchs auch schnell. 
Bevor der Verbrennungsmotor die Leitung in den 1910s nahm, 
liefen Autos auf eine Vielzahl der Kraftstoffe; Dampf, 
Elektrizität und Benzin konkurrierten für eine Anzahl von Jahren. 
Dieses ist offenbar vom zwei ADS, das im Samstag Abend-Pfosten 
für das Dampfauto erschien, und von einigen Bildern der Leute 
offensichtlich, welche die elektrischen und gasbetriebenen cars.Some 
Erfindungen genießen, die darauf abgezielt werden, um das Leben 
einfacher zu Hause zu bilden. Die Fotographie eines Storefront 
in 1925 Erscheinen das Bestehen der Geräte wie Waschmaschinen, 
Bügelmaschinen und Staubsauger. In ihrer neuentdeckten Freizeit
hörten Leute Radio, eine Erfindung, die diesmal ziemlich neu war. 
Zwei Fotographien, die in den Mid-1920s genommen werden, zeigen 
Charles Herrold, das?Father des Radios? funktionierende 
Radioausrüstung. Die Kombination der neuen Technologien, der 
freieren Zeit und der Fähigkeit, von einem Platz zu anderen 
verhältnismäßig leicht und schnell erlaubte Leute zu erhalten, zum 
der neuen Formulare der Unterhaltung zu genießen, wie durch die 
Fotographie eines Autos vor einem Filmtheater angezeigt. 
Ausstellungen waren ein populärer Schauplatz, zum das späteste
in der Technologie zur Schau zu stellen, und einige Bilder hier 
stellen Ausstellungen dar, die in San Francisco und in San Diego 1915 
und 1916 stattfanden. Eine Fotographie stellt ein Panel der 
Männer an der Öffnung der Telefonleitung zwischen San Francisco und 
New York zum ersten Mal bildlich dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les avions, les chemins de fer électriques, et les
automobiles ont joint des chemins de fer au sens croissant des 
Américains de carburant de la mobilité. Ils sont venus pour 
caractériser l'esprit progressif du nouveau siècle. En raison 
de ces nouveaux modes de transport public, les gens pouvaient voyager 
plus rapidement et plus facilement à l'intérieur et entre des 
villes, changeant des configurations de règlement. Une image 
dans ce groupe dépeint John J. Montgomery, le premier Américain pour
voler une machine de lourd-que-air, et son ?Santa Clara de planeur ? 
en 1905. Une invitation à une fête aérienne dans San 
Jose en 1910 suggère la popularité de ce nouveau mode 
potentiel de transport. Plusieurs villes ont eu les tramways 
électriques qui ont fonctionné sur des pistes, et les images dans ce
groupe incluent des tramways à San Diego, San Jose, et à 
Los Angeles. L'image main-teintée de la route électrique 
interurbaine de rail fonctionnant entre Saratoga et Los Gatos suggère
qu'en 1908, c'ait été assez d'une nouveauté pour évaluer une 
industrie d'automobile de postcard.The se soit également développé 
rapidement. Avant que le moteur à combustion interne ait pris 
la tête dans les années 10, les voitures ont fonctionné sur une 
variété de carburants ; la vapeur, l'électricité, et 
l'essence ont concurrencé pendant un certain nombre d'années. 
C'est clairement évident des deux ADS qui est apparu dans 
samedi le poteau de soirée pour la voiture de vapeur, et de plusieurs
images des personnes appréciant des inventions électrique- et 
alimentées au gaz de cars.Some visant pour faciliter la vie à la 
maison. La photographie d'un devanture de magasin dans 1925 
expositions l'existence des appareils tels que des machines à laver, 
des machines repassantes, et des aspirateurs. Dans leur temps 
libre récemment découvert, les gens ont écouté la radio, une 
invention qui était assez nouvelle à ce moment. Deux 
photographies prises au milieu des années 20 montrent Charles 
Herrold, le ?Father de la radio ? matériel par radio de 
fonctionnement. La combinaison de nouvelles technologies, 
d'heure plus libre, et de la capacité d'obtenir d'un endroit à 
l'autre personnes relativement facilement et rapidement permises pour 
apprécier de nouvelles formes de divertissement, comme indiqué par 
la photographie d'une voiture devant un théâtre de film. Les 
expositions étaient un rendez-vous populaire pour présenter le plus 
en retard en technologie, et plusieurs images ici représentent les 
expositions qui ont eu lieu dans San Francisco et San Diego en 1915 
et 1916. Une photographie dépeint un panneau des hommes à 
l'ouverture du fil de téléphone entre San Francisco et New York 
pour la première fois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os aviões, as estradas de ferro elétricas, e os 
automóveis juntaram estradas de ferro ao sentido crescente dos 
americanos do combustível da mobilidade. Vieram caracterizar o 
espírito progressivo do século novo. Em conseqüência destas 
modalidades novas do transporte público, os povos podiam  viajar mais
rapidamente e mais fàcilmente dentro e entre das cidades, mudando 
testes padrões do estabelecimento. Uma imagem neste grupo 
descreve John J. Montgomery, primeiro americano para voar uma máquina
do pesado-do que-ar, e seu?Santa Clara do planador? em 1905. 
Um invitation a uma mostra de ar em San Jose em 1910 sugere a 
popularidade desta modalidade nova potencial do transporte. 
Diversas cidades tiveram os streetcars elétricos que 
funcionaram em trilhas, e as imagens neste grupo incluem streetcars em
San Diego, em San Jose, e em Los Angeles. A imagem mão-matizada
da estrada elétrica interurban do trilho que funciona entre Saratoga 
e Los Gatos sugere que em 1908, este era bastante de um novelty para 
avaliar uma indústria de automóvel de postcard.The estava crescendo 
também ràpidamente. Antes que o motor de combustão interna 
fêz exame da ligação nos 1910s, os carros funcionaram em uma 
variedade dos combustíveis; o vapor, a eletricidade, e a 
gasolina competiram por um número de anos. Isto é claramente 
evidente dos dois ads que apareceu no borne da noite de sábado para o
carro do vapor, e de diversas imagens dos povos que aprecíam  as 
invenções elétricas e gas-powered de cars.Some apontadas fazer a 
vida mais fácil na HOME. A fotografia de um storefront em 1925 
mostras a existência dos dispositivos tais como máquinas de lavagem,
máquinas ironing, e aspiradores de p30. Em seu tempo de lazer 
new-found, os povos escutaram o rádio, uma invenção que fosse 
razoavelmente nova neste tempo. Duas fotografias feitas exame 
nos mid-1920s mostram Charles Herrold, o?Father do rádio? equipamento
de rádio operando-se. A combinação de tecnologias novas, da 
hora mais livre, e da abilidade começar de um lugar a outro povos 
relativamente fàcilmente e rapidamente permitidos para apreciar 
formulários novos do entertainment, como indicado pela fotografia de 
um carro na frente de um teatro do filme. As exposições eram 
um venue popular para showcase o mais atrasado na tecnologia, e 
diversas imagens aqui representam as exposições que ocorreram em San
Francisco e em San Diego em 1915 e em 1916. Uma fotografia 
descreve um painel dos homens na abertura do fio do telefone entre San
Francisco e New York para a primeira vez.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli aeroplani, le ferrovie elettriche e le 
automobili hanno unito le ferrovie a senso crescente degli Americani 
del combustibile di mobilità. Sono venuto caratterizzare lo 
spirito progressivo di nuovo secolo. Come conseguenza di questi 
nuovi modi di trasporto pubblico, la gente poteva viaggiare più 
velocemente e più facilmente in seno e tra le città, cambianti i 
modelli di stabilimento. Un'immagine in questo gruppo descrive 
John il J. Montgomery, il primo americano per volare una macchina 
dell'pesante-che-aria ed il suo?Santa Clara dell'aliante? in 
1905. Un invito ad un'esposizione di aria in San Jose in 1910 
suggerisce la popolarità di questo nuovo modo potenziale di 
trasporto. Parecchie città hanno avute streetcars elettrici che
hanno funzionato sulle piste e le immagini in questo gruppo includono 
gli streetcars a San Diego, San Jose e Los Angeles. L'immagine 
mano-tinta della strada elettrica interurbano della guida che funziona
fra Saratoga e Los Gatos suggerisce che in 1908, questo era abbastanza
di una novità per valutare un'industria di automobile di postcard.The
egualmente stava sviluppandosi velocemente. Prima che il motore 
a combustione interna prenda il comando negli anni 10, gli automobili 
hanno funzionato su una varietà di combustibili; il vapore, 
l'elettricità e la benzina hanno competuto per un certo numero di 
anni. Ciò è chiaramente evidente dai due ads che è comparso 
nell'alberino di sera di sabato per l'automobile del vapore e da 
parecchie immagini della gente che gode sia le invenzioni elettriche 
che alimentate a gas di cars.Some miranti per rendere la vita più 
facile nel paese. La fotografia di uno storefront in 1925 
esposizioni l'esistenza degli apparecchi quali le lavatrici, le 
macchine per stirare e gli aspirapolveri. Nel loro tempo libero 
new-found, la gente ha ascoltato la radio, un'invenzione che era 
ragionevolmente nuova attualmente. Due fotografie prese nei 
mid-1920s mostrano Charles Herrold, il?Father della radio? 
apparecchiatura radiofonica di funzionamento. La combinazione di
nuove tecnologie, di tempo più libero e della capacità ottenere da 
un posto ad un altro gente relativamente facilmente e rapidamente 
permessa per godere le nuove forme di intrattenimento, come indicato 
dalla fotografia di un automobile davanti un teatro di film. 
Le esposizioni erano una sede della riunione popolare per 
montrare il più ritardato nella tecnologia e parecchie 
immagini qui rappresentano le esposizioni che hanno avvenuto a San 
Francisco e San Diego in 1915 ed in 1916. Una fotografia 
descrive per la prima volta un pannello degli uomini all'apertura del 
legare del telefono fra San Francisco e New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα αεροπλάνα, οι ηλεκτρικοί σιδηρόδρομοι, και τα 
αυτοκίνητα ένωσαν τους σιδηροδρόμους για να τροφοδοτήσουν την 
αυξανόμενη αίσθηση Αμερικανών της κινητικότητας. Ήρθαν να 
χαρακτηρίσουν το προοδευτικό πνεύμα του νέου αιώνα. Ως 
αποτέλεσμα αυτών των νέων τρόπων δημόσιας μεταφοράς, οι 
άνθρωποι ήταν σε θέση να ταξιδεψουν γρηγορότερα και ευκολότερα 
ανάμεσα στις πόλεις, που αλλάζουν τα πρότυπα τακτοποίησης. 
Μια εικόνα σε αυτήν την ομάδα απεικονίζει John J. 
Μοντγκόμερυ, ο πρώτος Αμερικανός για να πετάξει μια μηχανή 
βαρύς-από-αέρα, και το ανεμοπλάνο του ?Santa Κλάρα; το 
1905. Μια πρόσκληση σε έναν αέρα εμφανίζει ότι στο 
SAN ο Jose το 1910 προτείνει τη δημοτικότητα αυτού του 
πιθανού νέου τρόπου μεταφοράς. Διάφορες πόλεις είχαν τα 
ηλεκτρικά τραμ που έτρεξαν στις διαδρομές, και οι εικόνες σε 
αυτήν την ομάδα περιλαμβάνουν τα τραμ στο Σαν Ντιέγκο, το SAN 
Jose, και το Λος Αντζελες. Η χέρι-βαμμένη εικόνα του 
υπεραστικού ηλεκτρικού δρόμου ραγών που τρέχει μεταξύ 
Saratoga και του Los Gatos προτείνει ότι το 1908, αυτό 
ήταν αρκετή μιας καινοτομίας να εκτιμήσει μια κάρτα Η 
αυτοκινητική βιομηχανία αυξανόταν επίσης γρήγορα. Προτού 
να πάρει η μηχανή εσωτερικής καύσεως το προβάδισμα στο 1910s, 
τα αυτοκίνητα έτρεξαν σε ποικίλα καύσιμα  ο ατμός, η 
ηλεκτρική ενέργεια, και η βενζίνη ανταγωνίστηκαν για διάφορα 
έτη. Αυτό είναι σαφώς εμφανές από τις δύο αγγελίες που 
εμφανίστηκαν στο ταχυδρομείο βραδιού Σαββάτου για το αυτοκίνητο 
ατμού, και διάφορες εικόνες της απόλαυσης ανθρώπων και 
ηλεκτρικής - και αέριο των αυτοκινήτων Μερικές 
εφευρέσεις στόχευσαν να καταστήσουν τη ζωή ευκολότερη στο σπίτι.
Η φωτογραφία ενός storefront το 1925 εμφανίζει την 
ύπαρξη των συσκευών όπως τα πλυντήρια ρούχων, οι μηχανές 
σιδερώματος, και οι ηλεκτρικές σκούπες. Στον προσφάτως 
ανευρεθέντα ελεύθερο χρόνο τους, οι άνθρωποι άκουσαν το 
ραδιόφωνο, μια εφεύρεση που ήταν αρκετά νέα αυτή τη στιγμή. 
Δύο φωτογραφίες που λαμβάνονται στα μέσα τησδεκαετίας του 
'20 εμφανίζουν Charles Herrold, το ?Father του ραδιοφώνου,;
λειτουργών ραδιο εξοπλισμός. Ο συνδυασμός νέων τεχνολογιών,
περισσότερου ελεύθερου χρόνου, και της δυνατότητας να φταθούν 
από μια θέση σε άλλη οι σχετικά εύκολα και γρήγορα άνθρωποι για
να απολαύσουν τις νέες μορφές της ψυχαγωγίας, όπως υποδεικνύεται
από τη φωτογραφία ενός αυτοκινήτου μπροστά από έναν 
κινηματογράφο. Οι εκθέσεις ήταν ένας δημοφιλής τόπος 
συναντήσεως για να επιδείξουν τον πιό πρόσφατο στην τεχνολογία, 
και διάφορες εικόνες αντιπροσωπεύουν εδώ τις εκθέσεις που 
πραγματοποιήθηκαν στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο και το Σαν Ντιέγκο το 1915 
και το 1916. Μια φωτογραφία απεικονίζει μια επιτροπή των 
ατόμων στο άνοιγμα του τηλεφωνικού καλωδίου μεταξύ του Σαν 
Φρανσίσκο και της Νέας Υόρκης για πρώτη φορά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los aeroplanos, los ferrocarriles eléctricos, y 
los automóviles ensamblaron ferrocarriles al sentido cada vez mayor 
de los americanos del combustible de la movilidad. Vinieron 
caracterizar el alcohol progresivo del nuevo siglo. Como 
resultado de estos nuevos modos del transporte público, la gente 
podía viajar más rápidamente y más fácilmente en y entre las 
ciudades, cambiando modelos del establecimiento. ¿Una imagen en 
este grupo representa a Juan J. Montgomery, el primer americano para 
volar una máquina del pesado-que-aire, y su?Santa Clara del 
planeador? en 1905. Una invitación a una demostración de
aire en San Jose en 1910 sugiere el renombre de este nuevo modo 
potencial del transporte. Varias ciudades tenían streetcars 
eléctricos que se ejecutaron en pistas, y las imágenes en este grupo
incluyen streetcars en San Diego, San Jose, y Los Ángeles. La 
imagen mano-teñida del camino eléctrico interurbano del carril que 
se ejecuta entre Saratoga y Los Gatos sugiere que en 1908, éste era 
bastante de una novedad para clasificar una industria de automóvil de
postcard.The también crecía rápidamente. Antes de que el 
motor de combustión interna tomara el terminal de componente en los 
años 10, los coches se ejecutaron en una variedad de combustibles; 
el vapor, la electricidad, y la gasolina compitieron por un 
número de años. Esto es claramente evidente de los dos ads que
apareció en el poste de la tarde de sábado para el coche del vapor, 
y de varias imágenes de la gente que goza de las invenciones 
eléctricas y de gas de cars.Some estado dirigidas para hacer vida 
más fácil en el país. La fotografía de un storefront en 1925
demostraciones la existencia de aplicaciones tales como lavadoras, 
máquinas que planchan, y aspiradores. En su tiempo libre 
new-found, la gente escuchó la radio, una invención que era bastante
nueva en este tiempo. Dos fotografías tomadas en los mediados 
de los años veinte muestran a Charles Herrold, el?Father de la radio?
equipo de radio de funcionamiento. La combinación de nuevas 
tecnologías, de una hora más libre, y de la capacidad de conseguir a
partir de un lugar a otro gente relativamente fácilmente y 
rápidamente permitida para gozar de nuevas formas de hospitalidad, 
según lo indicado por la fotografía de un coche delante de un teatro
de la película. Las exposiciones eran un lugar popular para 
showcase el más último de tecnología, y varias imágenes aquí 
representan las exposiciones que ocurrieron en San Francisco y San 
Diego en 1915 y 1916. Una fotografía representa un panel de 
hombres en la apertura del alambre del teléfono entre San Francisco y
Nueva York para la primera vez.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085242</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108725</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-rise-of-technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
