<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107042</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107042</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086663</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"No Gods, No Masters": Margaret Sanger on Birth Control</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Keine Götter, Keine Meister": Margaret 
Sanger auf Geburtenkontrolle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Aucuns Dieux, Aucuns Maîtres" : 
Margaret Sanger sur le contrôle des naissances</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nenhuns Deuses, Nenhuns Mestres": Margaret 
Sanger no controle de nascimento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Nessun Dii, Nessun Supervisori": Margaret 
Sanger su controllo di nascita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κανένας Θεός, κανένας κύριοσ": Θ*Μαργαρετ 
Sanger στον έλεγχο γέννησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ningunos Dioses, Ningunos Amos": Margaret 
Sanger en control de la natalidad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Though people had practiced methods of fertility control for hundreds of years, the 20th century saw the advent of more reliable technologies that allowed a sharper separation between sex and reproduction. Before World War I, birth control advocates confronted numerous and often hostile opponents. By the 1920s, though, changing sexual ideologies made such ideas more widely acceptable. The major figure in the American birth control movement, Margaret Sanger, began her crusade as a militant radical whose birth control agitation grew out of her nursing experience in working-class communities. In her short-lived journal,  The Woman Rebel , Sanger proclaimed, "A woman's body belongs to herself alone" and openly defended unwed motherhood. In these excerpts from  The Woman Rebel , Sanger announced the journal's feminist and radical commitments and reported on "The Post Office Ban," the U.S. Post Office's suppression of the journal under the Comstock laws (which prohibited the use of the U.S. mails to distribute information about contraception).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obwohl Leute Methoden der Ergiebigkeitsteuerung 
für Hunderte Jahre geübt hatten, sah das 20. Jahrhundert das 
Aufkommen der zuverlässigeren Technologien, die eine schärfere 
Trennung zwischen Geschlecht und Wiedergabe erlaubten. Vor dem 
Ersten Weltkrieg konfrontierten Geburtenkontrollefürsprecher die 
zahlreichen und häufig feindlichen Konkurrenten. Bis zum den 
zwanziger Jahren obwohl, ändernde sexuelle Ideologien solche Ideen 
weit annehmbar bildeten. Die Hauptabbildung in der 
amerikanischen Geburtenkontrollebewegung, Margaret Sanger, fing ihren 
Kreuzzug als militantes Radikal an dessen Geburtenkontrollebewegung 
aus ihrer Krankenpflegeerfahrung in den Arbeiterklassegemeinschaften 
heraus wuchs. In ihrem kurzlebigen Journal gehört der 
Frau-Aufrührer, proklamiertes Sanger, "der Körper einer Frau 
alleine" und öffentlich verteidigt unwed Mutterschaft. In 
diesen Excerpts vom Frau-Aufrührer, verkündete Sanger die 
feministischen und radikalen Verpflichtungen des Journals und 
berichtete über "das Postamt-Verbot," der Ausgleich des VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Postamtes des Journals unter den Comstock Gesetzen (die den 
Gebrauch der VEREINIGTEN STAATEN sendet, um Informationen über 
Empfängnisverhütung zu verteilen verboten).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que les gens aient pratiqué des méthodes de
commande de fertilité pour des centaines d'années, le 20ème siècle
a vu l'arrivée des technologies plus fiables qui ont permis une 
séparation plus marquée entre le sexe et la reproduction. 
Avant la Première Guerre Mondiale, les avocats de contrôle des
naissances ont confronté de nombreux et souvent hostiles adversaires.
Par les années 20, bien que, les idéologies sexuelles 
changeantes aient rendu de telles idées plus largement acceptables. 
La figure principale dans le mouvement américain de contrôle 
des naissances, Margaret Sanger, a commencé sa croisade comme 
radical militant dont l'agitation de contrôle des naissances s'est
développée hors de sa expérience de soins des communautés de 
classe ouvrière. En son journal de courte durée, la rebelle de
femme, Sanger proclamé, "le corps d'une femme seul appartient à 
elle-même" et ouvrir défendu unwed la maternité. Dans ces 
extraits de la rebelle de femme, Sanger a annoncé les engagements 
féministes et radicaux du journal et a rendu compte "de 
l'interdiction de poste," la suppression de la poste des ETATS-UNIS du
journal en vertu des lois de Comstock (qui ont interdit l'utilisation 
des ETATS-UNIS expédient pour distribuer des informations sur la 
contraception).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora os povos tinham praticado métodos do 
controle da fertilidade para centenas dos anos, o 20o século viu o 
advent de umas tecnologias mais de confiança que permitissem uma 
separação mais afiada entre o sexo e a reprodução. Antes do 
world.war.i, os advogados do controle de nascimento confrontaram 
oponentes numerosos e frequentemente hostis. Pelos 1920s, 
embora, os ideologies sexual em mudança fizeram tais idéias mais 
extensamente aceitáveis. A figura principal no movimento 
americano do controle de nascimento, Margaret Sanger, começou seu 
crusade como um radical militant cujo o agitation do controle de 
nascimento crescesse fora de sua experiência dos cuidados em 
comunidades do working-class. Em seu jornal short-lived, o rebel
da mulher, Sanger proclamado, "corpo de uma mulher herselfpertence- 
sozinho" e defendido abertamente unwed o motherhood. Nestes 
excerpts do rebel da mulher, Sanger anunciou os compromissos 
feministas e radicais do jornal e relatou-os "na proibição do 
escritório de borne," a supressão de escritório de borne de ESTADOS
UNIDOS do jornal sob as leis de Comstock (que proibiram o uso dos 
ESTADOS UNIDOS enviam para distribuir a informação sobre o 
contraception).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benchè la gente si eserciti nei metodi di 
controllo di fertilità per le centinaia degli anni, il ventesimo 
secolo ha visto l'avvenimento delle tecnologie più certe che hanno 
permesso una separazione più marcata fra il sesso e la riproduzione. 
Prima del world.war.i, i fautori di controllo di nascita hanno 
confrontato gli avversari numerosi e spesso ostili. Entro gli 
anni 20, benchè, le ideologie sessuali cambianti rendano tali idee 
più ampiamente accettabili. La figura principale nel movimento 
americano di controllo di nascita, Margaret Sanger, ha cominciato il 
suo crusade come radicale del militante di cui l'agitazione di 
controllo di nascita si è sviluppata dalla sua esperienza di 
professione d'infermiera di Comunità della classe operaia. In 
suo giornale di breve durata, il Ribelle della donna, Sanger 
affermato, "corpo della donna appartiene a sè da solo" e difeso 
apertamente unwed la maternità. In questi brani dal 
Ribelle della donna, Sanger ha annunciato gli impegni femministi 
e radicali del giornale ed ha segnalato "sul divieto dell'ufficio 
postale," la soppressione dell'ufficio postale degli STATI UNITI del 
giornale secondo le leggi di Comstock (che hanno proibito l'uso degli 
STATI UNITI spediscono per distribuire le informazioni sulla 
contraccezione).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και οι άνθρωποι είχαν εφαρμόσει τις μεθόδους 
ελέγχου γονιμότητας για τις εκατοντάδες των ετών, ο 20ός αιώνας 
εβλέίδε την εμφάνιση των πιό αξιόπιστων τεχνολογιών που 
επέτρεψαν έναν αιχμηρότερο χωρισμό μεταξύ του φύλου και της 
αναπαραγωγής. Πριν από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, οι συνήγοροι
ελέγχου γέννησης αντιμετώπισαν τους πολυάριθμους και συχνά 
εχθρικούς αντιπάλους. Μέχρι τη δεκαετία του '20, εν 
τούτοις, που αλλάζει οι σεξουαλικές ιδεολογίες κατέστησαν 
τέτοιες ιδέες ευρύτερα αποδεκτές. Ο σημαντικότερος αριθμός
στην αμερικανική μετακίνηση ελέγχου γέννησης, Margaret 
Sanger, άρχισε τη σταυροφορία της ως στρατευμένο ριζοσπάστη η ο
οποίος αναταραχή ελέγχου γέννησης αυξήθηκε από την εμπειρία 
περιποίησής της στις κοινότητες εργατικών τάξεων. Στο 
βραχύβιο περιοδικό της, ο επαναστάτης γυναικών, Sanger που 
πιστοποιείται, "το σώμα μιας γυναίκας ανήκει σε την μόνο" και 
ανοιχτά υπερασπισμένος η μητρότητα. Σε αυτά τα αποσπάσματα 
από τον επαναστάτη γυναικών, Sanger ανήγγειλε τις φεμινιστικές
και ριζικές υποχρεώσεις του περιοδικού και υπέβαλε έκθεση 
σχετικά με "την απαγόρευση ταχυδρομείων," η καταστολή του 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ ταχυδρομείου του περιοδικού βάσει των νόμων 
Comstock (που απαγόρευσαν τη χρήση των ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ ταχυδρομείων
για να διανείμουν τις πληροφορίες για την αντισύλληψη).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque la gente había practicado métodos de 
control de la fertilidad para los centenares de años, el vigésimo 
siglo consideró el advenimiento de tecnologías más confiables que 
permitieron una separación más sostenida entre el sexo y la 
reproducción. Antes de Primera Guerra Mundial, los abogados del
control de la natalidad enfrentaron a opositores numerosos y a menudo 
hostiles. Por los años 20, aunque, las ideologías sexuales que
cambiaban hicieron tales ideas más extensamente aceptables. La 
figura principal en el movimiento americano del control de la 
natalidad, Margaret Sanger, comenzó su cruzada como radical 
militante que agitación del control de la natalidad creció fuera de
su experiencia del oficio de enfermera en comunidades de la clase 
obrera. En su diario de breve duración, el rebelde de la mujer,
Sanger proclamado, "el cuerpo de una mujer pertenece a se solamente" y
defendido abiertamente unwed maternidad. En estos extractos del 
rebelde de la mujer, Sanger anunció las consolidaciones feministas y 
radicales del diario y señaló sobre "la interdicción del correos," 
la supresión del correos de ESTADOS UNIDOS del diario bajo leyes de 
Comstock (que prohibieron el uso de los ESTADOS UNIDOS envían para 
distribuir la información sobre la contracepción).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086663</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107042</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/no-gods-no-masters-margaret-sanger-on-birth-control</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
