<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/165875213</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>165875213</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200659</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bioinformatics in the Biology Classroom</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bioinformatics im Biologie-Klassenzimmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bioinformatics dans la salle de classe de 
biologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bioinformatics na sala de aula da biologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bioinformatics nell'aula di biologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βιοπληροφορική στην τάξη της βιολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bioinformatics en la sala de clase de la 
biología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This educational journal article addresses the implementation of bioinformatics in the classroom. The author explains how bioinformatics could play a key role for science students pursuing higher education, foster inquiry learning of content that has often been taught in a dry manner, provide the thread that ties classes together, improve biology teaching, enhance the learning of biotech issues and ethics, expose students to real-world science, and significantly help to reform biology teaching and improve learning. The article includes links to bioinformatics resources, information about how to get involved in bioinformatics, and a glossary of terms.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser pädagogische Journalartikel adressiert die
Implementierung von bioinformatics im Klassenzimmer. Der Autor 
erklärt, wie bioinformatics eine Schlüsselrolle für die 
Wissenschaft Kursteilnehmer spielen könnte, die höhere Ausbildung 
ausüben, fördern das Anfragelernen des Inhalts, der häufig in einer
trockenen Weise unterrichtet worden ist, zur Verfügung stellen das 
Gewinde, das die zusammen Kategorien bindet, verbessern 
Biologieunterricht, erhöhen das Lernen der biotech Ausgaben und der 
Ethik, aussetzen Kursteilnehmer realistischer Wissenschaft und helfen 
erheblich, Biologieunterricht zu verbessern und das Lernen zu 
verbessern. Der Artikel schließt Links zu den bioinformatics 
Betriebsmitteln, Informationen über ein, wie man im bioinformatics 
und ein Glossar von Bezeichnungen beteiligt erhält.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet article de journal éducatif adresse la mise 
en place du bioinformatics dans la salle de classe. L'auteur 
explique comment le bioinformatics pourrait jouer un rôle principal 
pour des étudiants de la science poursuivant une éducation plus 
élevée, stimulent l'étude d'enquête du contenu qui a été souvent
enseigné d'une façon sèche, fournissent l'amorçage qui attache des
classes ensemble, améliorent l'enseignement de biologie, mettent en 
valeur l'étude des issues biotechnologiques et de l'éthique, exposent des
étudiants à la science réelle, et aident de manière significative 
à reformer l'enseignement de biologie et à améliorer l'étude. 
L'article inclut des liens aux ressources de bioinformatics, des
informations sur la façon devenir impliqué dans le bioinformatics, 
et un glossaire des limites.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este artigo de jornal educacional dirige-se à 
execução do bioinformatics na sala de aula. O autor explica 
como o bioinformatics poderia jogar um papel chave para os estudantes 
da ciência que perseguem uma instrução mais elevada, promove a 
aprendizagem do inquérito do índice que foi ensinado frequentemente 
em uma maneira seca, fornece a linha que amarra as classes junto, 
melhora o ensino da biologia, realça a aprendizagem de edições e de
ethics do biotech, expõe estudantes à ciência real-world, e 
ajuda-os significativamente reformar o ensino da biologia e melhorar a
aprendizagem. O artigo inclui as ligações aos recursos do 
bioinformatics, a informação sobre como começar involvido no 
bioinformatics, e um glossário dos termos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo articolo pubblicato educativo richiama 
l'implementazione del bioinformatics nell'aula. L'autore spiega 
come il bioinformatics potrebbe svolgere un ruolo chiave per gli 
allievi di scienza che perseguono l'istruzione superiore, promuove 
imparare di inchiesta del soddisfare che è stato insegnato spesso in 
un modo asciutto, fornisce il filetto che lega insieme i codici 
categoria, migliora l'insegnamento di biologia, aumenta imparare delle
edizioni e dell'etica del biotech, espone gli allievi alla scienza 
nell'ambiente e significativamente contribuisce a riformare 
l'insegnamento di biologia ed a migliorare imparare. L'articolo 
include i collegamenti alle risorse di bioinformatics, le informazioni
su come ottenere implicato in bioinformatics e un glossario dei 
termini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το εκπαιδευτικό άρθρο σε περιοδικά εξετάζει την 
εφαρμογή της βιοπληροφορικής στην τάξη. Ο συντάκτης εξηγεί 
σπώς η βιοπληροφορική θα μπορούσε να διαδραματίσει έναν βασικό 
ρόλο για τους σπουδαστές επιστήμης που ακολουθούν την τριτοβάθμια
εκπαίδευση, να ενθαρρύνει την εκμάθηση έρευνας του περιεχομένου 
που έχει διδαχθεί συχνά κατά τρόπο ξηρό, παρέχει το νήμα ότι 
οι κλάσεις δεσμών μαζί, βελτιώνουν τη διδασκαλία της βιολογίας, 
ενισχύουν την εκμάθηση των ζητημάτων και της ηθικής Biotech, 
εκθέτουν τους σπουδαστές στην πραγματική επιστήμη, και βοηθούν 
σημαντικά να μεταρρυθμίσουν τη διδασκαλία της βιολογίας και να 
βελτιώσουν την εκμάθηση. Το άρθρο περιλαμβάνει τις 
συνδέσεις με τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς βιοπληροφορικής, τις 
πληροφορίες για το πώς να αναμιχθεί στη βιοπληροφορική, και ένα 
γλωσσάρι όρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este artículo de diario educativo trata la puesta
en práctica del bioinformatics en la sala de clase. El autor 
explica cómo el bioinformatics podría desempeñar un papel dominante
de los estudiantes de la ciencia que perseguían una educación más 
alta, fomenta aprender de la pregunta del contenido que se ha 
enseñado a menudo de una manera seca, proporciona a la cuerda de 
rosca que ata clases juntas, mejora la enseñanza de la biología, 
realza aprender de las ediciones y del ética del biotech, expone a 
estudiantes a la ciencia del mundo real, y ayuda perceptiblemente a 
reformar la enseñanza de la biología y a mejorar aprender. El 
artículo incluye conexiones a los recursos del bioinformatics, la 
información sobre cómo conseguir implicado en bioinformatics, y un 
glosario de términos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KATHLEEN M. GABRIC
FN:KATHLEEN M. GABRIC
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ACTIONBIOSCIENCE.ORG
FN:ACTIONBIOSCIENCE.ORG
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200659</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>165875213</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/bioinformatics-in-the-biology-classroom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
