<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107070</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107070</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085258</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Free Speech Movement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Freie Rede-Bewegung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Mouvement Libre de la Parole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Movimento Livre Do Discurso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Movimento Libero Di Discorso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ελεύθερο λεκτικό Κίνημα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Movimiento Libre Del Discurso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Free Speech Movement (FSM) was a college campus phenomenon inspired first by the struggle for civil rights and later fueled by opposition to the Vietnam War. The Free Speech Movement began in 1964, when students at the University of California, Berkeley protested a ban on on-campus political activities. The protest was led by several students, who also demanded their right to free speech and academic freedom. The FSM sparked an unprecedented wave of student activism and involvement. Many images in this group make it clear that the center of the activity on the UC Berkeley campus was in Sproul Plaza. One photograph shows students occupying the balconies of Sproul Hall, a campus administration building, holding FSM banners and an American flag. Another photograph shows student leader Mario Savio leading a group of students through Sather Gate toward a meeting of the UC Regents. In defiance of the ban on on-campus political activities, graduate student Jack Weinberg set up a table with political information and was arrested. But a group of approximately 3,000 students surrounded the police car in which he was held, preventing it from moving for 36 hours. Photographs show Weinberg in the car, both Mario Savio and Jack Weinberg on top of the surrounded car speaking to the crowd, and the car encircled by protesters and police. Other photographs that portray key people and events of the Free Speech Movement include the eight students (including Mario Savio) suspended for operating a table on campus without a permit and raising money for unauthorized purposes; Mario Savio speaking to a crowd; students signing a pledge; and students sleeping on the steps of Sproul Plaza. Photographs of students being arrested, holding a mass sit-in, and picketing in support of the student-faculty strike as they protest demonstrators' arrests reflect other aspects of the Free Speech Movement. Singer Joan Baez supported the FSM, and a photograph shows her singing to the demonstrators. Bettina Aptheker, who later became a professor of Feminist Studies at UC Santa Cruz, also supported the FSM. A photograph shows her speaking in front of Sproul Hall. Other photographs in this topic demonstrate that groups such as Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) and the International Workers of the World (IWW) showed solidarity and supported the FSM. Other images in this group include UC President Clark Kerr speaking at the UC Berkeley Greek Theater, and CORE co-founder James Farmer at a CORE rally.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die freie Rede-Bewegung (FSM) war ein 
Hochschulcampusphänomen, das zuerst durch den Kampf für Zivilrechte 
angespornt wurde und später durch Opposition zum Vietnam Krieg 
getankt war. Die freie Rede-Bewegung fing 1964 an, als 
Kursteilnehmer an der Universität von Kalifornien, Berkeley ein 
Verbot auf on-campus politischen Aktivitäten protestierten. Der
Protest wurde von einigen Kursteilnehmern geführt, die auch ihr Recht
verlangten, Rede und akademische Freiheit freizugeben. Das FSM 
funkte eine beispiellose Welle von Kursteilnehmeraktivismus und 
-miteinbeziehung. Viele Bilder in dieser Gruppe bilden es freien
Raum, daß die Mitte der Aktivität auf dem UC Berkeley Campus in der 
Sproul Piazza war. Eine Fotographie zeigt die Kursteilnehmer, 
welche die Balkone von Sproul Hall, ein Campusleitung Gebäude, 
Holding FSM Fahnen und eine amerikanische Markierungsfahne besetzen. 
Eine andere Fotographie zeigt Kursteilnehmerführer Mario Savio,
das eine Gruppe Kursteilnehmer durch Sather Gatter in Richtung zu 
einer Sitzung des UC Regents führt. Im Trotz des 
Verbots auf on-campus politischen Aktivitäten, stellte Schulabgänger
Jack Weinberg eine Tabelle mit politischen Informationen auf und wurde
festgehalten. Aber eine Gruppe von ungefähr 3.000 
Kursteilnehmern umgab das Polizeiauto, in dem er angehalten wurde und 
verhinderte, daß es 6 Stunden lang bewegt. Fotographien zeigen 
Weinberg im Auto, Mario Savio und Jack Weinberg auf das umgebene Auto,
das mit der Masse sprechen, und das Auto, das von den Protesters und 
von der Polizei umkreist wird. Andere Fotographien, die 
Schlüsselleute und Fälle der freien Rede-Bewegung schildern, 
enthalten die acht Kursteilnehmer (einschließlich Mario Savio) 
verschoben für das Laufen lassen einer Tabelle auf Campus ohne eine 
Erlaubnis und das Anheben des Geldes zu nicht autorisierten Zwecken; 
Mario Savio, das mit einer Masse spricht; Kursteilnehmer, 
die versprochene unterzeichnen; und Kursteilnehmer, die auf den 
Jobsteps der Sproul Piazzas schlafen. Fotographien der 
Kursteilnehmer, die festgehalten werden, anhalten eine Masse sitzen-in
und einpfählend zur Unterstützung des Kursteilnehmer-Lehrkörper 
Schlages, da sie Anhalten der Vorführer protestieren, reflektieren 
andere Aspekte der freien Rede-Bewegung. Sänger Joan Baez 
unterstützte das FSM, und eine Fotographie zeigt sie singend zu den 
Demonstrationsmodellen. Bettina Aptheker, das später einem 
Professor der feministischen Studien bei UC Sankt Cruz stand, 
unterstützte auch das FSM. Eine Fotographie zeigt sie sprechend
vor Sproul Hall. Andere Fotographien in diesem Thema zeigen, 
daß zeigten Gruppen wie Kongreß der rassischen Gleichheit (KERN) und
die internationalen Arbeiter der Welt (IWW) solidarität und 
unterstützten das FSM. Andere Bilder in dieser Gruppe enthalten
UC Präsidenten Clark Kerr, der am UC Berkeley griechischen Theater 
spricht, und KERN Co-Gründer James Landwirt an einer KERN-Sammlung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement libre de la parole (FSM) était un 
phénomène de campus d'université inspiré d'abord par la lutte pour
des droits civiques et plus tard rempli de combustible par 
l'opposition à la guerre de Vietnam. Le mouvement libre de la 
parole a commencé en 1964, quand les étudiants à l'université de 
la Californie, Berkeley ont protesté une interdiction des activités 
politiques localisées. La protestation a été menée par 
plusieurs étudiants, qui ont également exigé leur droite de 
libérer la liberté de la parole et d'universitaire. Le FSM a 
étincelé une vague sans précédent d'activisme et de participation 
d'étudiant. Beaucoup d'images dans ce groupe indiquent 
clairement que le centre de l'activité sur le campus UC de Berkeley 
était dans la plaza de Sproul. Une photographie montre des 
étudiants occupant les balcons de Sproul Hall, un bâtiment de 
gestion de campus, drapeaux de FSM de possession et un indicateur 
américain. Une autre photographie montre le Chef Mario Savio 
d'étudiant menant un groupe d'étudiants par la porte de Sather vers 
une réunion des Régents UC. Dans le défit de 
l'interdiction des activités politiques localisées, l'étudiant 
gradué Jack Weinberg a installé une table avec l'information 
politique et a été arrêté. Mais un groupe 
d'approximativement 3.000 étudiants a entouré la voiture de police 
en laquelle il a été tenu, l'empêchant de se déplacer pendant 36 
heures. Les photographies montrent Weinberg dans la voiture, 
Mario Savio et Jack Weinberg sur la voiture entourée parlant à la 
foule, et la voiture encerclée par les protestataires et la police. 
D'autres photographies qui dépeignent les personnes principales
et les événements du mouvement libre de la parole incluent les huit 
étudiants (Mario y compris Savio) suspendus pour actionner une table 
sur le campus sans laiss et soulever l'argent pour des buts non 
autorisés ; Mario Savio parlant à une foule ; étudiants
signant un engagement ; et étudiants dormant sur les étapes de
la plaza de Sproul. Les photographies des étudiants étant 
arrêtés, tenant une masse reposer-dans, et palissadant à l'appui de
la grève d'étudiant-corps enseignant car elles protestent les 
arrestations des programmes de démonstration reflètent d'autres 
aspects du mouvement libre de la parole. Le chanteur Joan Baez a
supporté le FSM, et une photographie la montre chantant aux 
programmes de démonstration. Bettina Aptheker, qui plus tard 
est allé bien à un professeur des études féministes chez 
Santa Cruz UC, a également supporté le FSM. Une photographie 
la montre parlant devant Sproul Hall. D'autres photographies 
dans ce sujet démontrent que les groupes tels que le congrès de 
l'égalité raciale (NOYAU) et les ouvriers internationaux du monde 
(IWW) ont montré la solidarité et ont supporté le FSM. 
D'autres images dans ce groupe incluent le Président UC Clark 
Kerr parlant au théâtre grec UC de Berkeley, et le fermier de 
James de co-fondateur de NOYAU à un rassemblement de NOYAU.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento livre do discurso (FSM) era um 
fenômeno do campus da faculdade inspirado primeiramente pelo esforço
para direitas civis e abastecido mais tarde pela oposição à guerra 
de Vietnam. O movimento livre do discurso começou em 1964, 
quando os estudantes na universidade de Califórnia, Berkeley 
protestaram uma proibição em atividades políticas no local. O
protesto foi conduzido por diversos estudantes, que exijiram também 
sua direita livrar o discurso e a liberdade academic. O FSM 
acendeu uma onda unprecedented do activism e da participação do 
estudante. Muitas imagens neste grupo fazem-lhe o espaço livre 
que o centro da atividade no campus UC de Berkeley estava na plaza de 
Sproul. Uma fotografia mostra os estudantes que ocupam os 
balcões de Sproul Salão, um edifício da administração do campus, 
bandeiras do FSM da terra arrendada e uma bandeira americana. 
Uma outra fotografia mostra o líder Mario Savio do estudante 
que conduz a um grupo dos estudantes através da porta de Sather para 
uma reunião do Regents UC. No defiance da proibição em 
atividades políticas no local, o estudante graduado Jack Weinberg 
ajustou acima uma tabela com informação política e foi prendido. 
Mas um grupo de aproximadamente 3.000 estudantes cercou o carro 
das polícias em que foi prendido, impedindo que se mova por 36 horas.
As fotografias mostram Weinberg no carro,  Mario Savio e Jack 
Weinberg no alto do carro cercado que falam à multidão, e do carro 
encircled por protesters e por polícias. Outras fotografias que
portray os povos chaves e os eventos do movimento livre do discurso 
incluem os oito estudantes (Mario including Savio) suspendidos 
operando uma tabela no campus sem uma licença e levantando o dinheiro
para finalidades desautorizadas; Mario Savio que fala a uma 
multidão; estudantes que assinam um pledge; e estudantes 
que dormem nas etapas da plaza de Sproul. As fotografias dos 
estudantes que estão sendo prendidos, prendendo uma massa sent-em, e 
picketing na sustentação da batida da estudante-faculdade porque 
protestam apreensões dos demonstradores refletem outros aspectos do 
movimento livre do discurso. O singer Joan Baez suportou o FSM, 
e uma fotografia mostra-a que canta aos demonstradores. Bettina 
Aptheker, que assentou bem mais tarde em um professor de estudos 
feministas em Santa UC Cruz, suportou também o FSM. Uma 
fotografia mostra-a que fala na frente de Sproul Salão. Outras 
fotografias neste tópico demonstram que os grupos tais como o 
congress da igualdade racial (NÚCLEO) e os trabalhadores 
internacionais do mundo (IWW) mostraram o solidarity e suportaram o 
FSM. Outras imagens neste grupo incluem o presidente UC Clark 
Kerr que fala no teatro grego UC de Berkeley, e o fazendeiro de James 
do co-co-founder do NÚCLEO em um rally do NÚCLEO.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento libero di discorso (FSM) era un 
fenomeno della città universitaria dell'università ispirato in primo
luogo tramite la lotta per i diritti civili e più successivamente 
rifornito da opposizione alla guerra di Vietnam. Il movimento 
libero di discorso ha cominciato in 1964, quando gli allievi 
all'università di California, Berkeley hanno protestato un divieto di
attività politiche localizzate. La protesta è stata condotta 
da parecchi allievi, che egualmente hanno richiesto la loro destra 
liberare il discorso e la libertà accademica. Il FSM ha 
scintillato un'onda senza precedente di activism e della 
partecipazione dell'allievo. Molte immagini in questo gruppo 
indicano chiaramente che il centro dell'attività sulla città 
universitaria UC del Berkeley era nel plaza di Sproul. Una 
fotografia mostra gli allievi che occupano i balconi di Sproul 
Corridoio, una costruzione della gestione della città universitaria, 
bandiere del FSM della tenuta e una bandierina americana. 
Un'altra fotografia mostra il capo Mario Savio 
dell'allievo che conduce un gruppo degli allievi tramite il cancello 
di Sather verso una riunione del Regents UC. Nel defiance del 
divieto di attività politiche localizzate, l'allievo laureato Jack 
Weinberg ha installato una tabella con le informazioni politiche ed è
stato arrestato. Ma un gruppo di circa 3.000 allievi ha 
circondato l'automobile della polizia in cui è stato tenuto, 
impedente lei muoversi per 36 ore. Le fotografie mostrano 
Weinberg nell'automobile, sia Mario Savio che Jack Weinberg in cima 
all'automobile circondato che parlano alla folla ed all'automobile 
circondato dai contestatori e dalla polizia. Altre fotografie 
che ritraggono la gente chiave e gli eventi del movimento libero di 
discorso includono gli otto allievi (Mario compreso Savio) sospesi per
il funzionamento della tabella sulla città universitaria senza un 
permesso e l'innalzamento dei soldi per gli scopi non autorizzati; 
Mario Savio che parla ad una folla; allievi che firmano un
impegno; ed allievi che dormono sui punti del plaza di Sproul. 
Le fotografie degli allievi che sono arrestati, della 
tenuta una massa sed-in e steccando a sostegno del colpo della 
allievo-facoltà poichè protestano gli arresti dei dimostranti 
riflettono altre funzioni del movimento libero di discorso. Il 
cantante Joan Baez ha sostenuto il FSM e una fotografia la mostra che 
canta ai dimostranti. Bettina Aptheker, che più successivamente
ha stato bene ad un professore degli studi femministi a Santa UC Cruz,
egualmente ha sostenuto il FSM. Una fotografia la mostra che 
parla davanti Sproul Corridoio. Altre fotografie in questo 
soggetto dimostrano che i gruppi quale il congresso di uguaglianza 
razziale (NUCLEO) e gli operai internazionali del mondo (IWW) hanno 
mostrato la solidarietà ed hanno sostenuto il FSM. Altre 
immagini in questo gruppo includono il presidente UC Clark Kerr che 
parla al teatro greco UC del Berkeley ed il coltivatore di James del 
co-fondatore di NUCLEO ad un raduno di NUCLEO.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ελεύθερο λεκτικό Κίνημα (FSM) ήταν ένα 
φαινόμενο πανεπιστημιουπόλεων κολλεγίων που εμπνεύστηκε πρώτα 
από την προσπάθεια για τα αστικά δικαιώματα και που τροφοδοτήθηκε
αργότερα από την αντίθεση στον πόλεμο του Βιετνάμ. Το 
ελεύθερο λεκτικό Κίνημα άρχισε το 1964, όταν διαμαρτυρήθηκαν 
οι σπουδαστές στο πανεπιστήμιο Καλιφόρνιας, Μπέρκλευ! μια 
απαγόρευση στις πολιτικές δραστηριότητες-ΠΑΝΕΠΙΣΤΗΜΙΟΥΠΌΛΕΩΝ. 
Η διαμαρτυρία οδηγήθηκε από διάφορους σπουδαστές, οι 
οποίοι απαίτησαν επίσης το δικαίωμά τους στην ελεύθερη ομιλία 
και την ακαδημαϊκή ελευθερία. Το FSM προκάλεσε ένα 
πρωτοφανές κύμα του ακτιβισμού και της συμμετοχής σπουδαστών. 
Πολλές εικόνες σε αυτήν την ομάδα το καθιστούν σαφές ότι 
το κέντρο της δραστηριότητας στην πανεπιστημιούπολη UC 
Μπέρκλευ! ήταν σε Sproul Plaza. Μια φωτογραφία 
εμφανίζει σπουδαστές που καταλαμβάνουν τα μπαλκόνια της αίθουσας 
Sproul, ενός κτηρίου διοίκησης πανεπιστημιουπόλεων, των 
εμβλημάτων εκμετάλλευσης FSM και μιας αμερικανικής σημαίας. 
Μια άλλη φωτογραφία εμφανίζει ηγέτη Mario Savio 
σπουδαστών που οδηγεί μια ομάδα σπουδαστών μέσω της πύλης 
Sather προς μια συνεδρίαση των αντιβασιλέων UC. Στην 
περιφρόνηση της απαγόρευσης στις πολιτικές 
δραστηριότητες-ΠΑΝΕΠΙΣΤΗΜΙΟΥΠΌΛΕΩΝ, ο διαβαθμισμένος σπουδαστής 
Jack Weinberg ίδρυσε έναν πίνακα με τις πολιτικές 
πληροφορίες και συλλήφθηκε. Αλλά μια ομάδα περίπου 3.000
σπουδαστών περιέβαλε το αυτοκίνητο αστυνομίας στο οποίο 
κρατήθηκε, αποτρέποντας την από την κίνηση για 36 ώρες. 
Οι φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν Weinberg στο αυτοκίνητο, και 
Mario Savio και Jack Weinberg πάνω από το αυτοκίνητο 
μιλώντας στο πλήθος, και το αυτοκίνητο που περικυκλώνεται από 
τους διαμαρτυρομένους και την αστυνομία. Αλλες φωτογραφίες 
που απεικονίζουν τους βασικούς ανθρώπους και τα γεγονότα του 
ελεύθερου λεκτικού Κινήματος περιλαμβάνουν τους οκτώ σπουδαστές 
(συμπεριλαμβανομένου του Mario Savio) που αναστέλλονται για να
ενεργοποιήσουν έναν πίνακα στην πανεπιστημιούπολη χωρίς μια 
άδεια και τη συγκέντρωση των χρημάτων για αναρμόδιους λόγους  
Θ*Μαρηο Savio που μιλά σε ένα πλήθος  σπουδαστές 
που υπογράφουν μια υποχρέωση  και σπουδαστές που κοιμούνται 
στα βήματα Sproul Plaza. Οι φωτογραφίες του σύλληψης 
των σπουδαστών, κρατώντας μια μάζα κάθομαι-μέσα, και 
περιφράσσοντας υπέρ της απεργίας σπουδαστής-ικανότητας δεδομένου
ότι διαμαρτύρονται τις συλλήψεις των επιδεικνυόντων απεικονίζουν 
άλλες πτυχές του ελεύθερου λεκτικού Κινήματος. Ο 
τραγουδιστής Joan Baez υποστήριξε το FSM, και μια 
φωτογραφία την εμφανίζει που τραγουδά στους επιδεικνύοντες. 
Το Bettina Aptheker, που έγινε αργότερα καθηγητής των 
φεμινιστικών μελετών σε UC Santa Cruz, υποστήριξε επίσης 
το FSM. Μια φωτογραφία την εμφανίζει που μιλά μπροστά 
από την αίθουσα Sproul. Αλλες φωτογραφίες σε αυτό το 
θέμα καταδεικνύουν ότι οι ομάδες όπως το συνέδριο της φυλετικής
ισότητας (ΠΥΡΗΝΑΣ) και οι διεθνείς εργαζόμενοι του κόσμου (IWW)
εμφάνισαν αλληλεγγύη και υποστήριξαν το FSM. Αλλες 
εικόνες σε αυτήν την ομάδα περιλαμβάνουν UC Πρόεδρος clark 
Kerr που μιλά στο ελληνικό θέατρο UC Μπέρκλεϋ, και τον 
ομο-ιδρυτή james Farmer ΠΥΡΉΝΩΝ σε μια συνάθροιση ΠΥΡΉΝΩΝ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento libre del discurso (FSM) era un 
fenómeno del campus de la universidad inspirado primero por la lucha 
para las derechas civiles y aprovisionado de combustible más adelante
por la oposición a la guerra de Vietnam. El movimiento libre 
del discurso comenzó en 1964, cuando los estudiantes en la 
universidad de California, Berkeley protestaron una interdicción en 
actividades políticas localizadas. La protesta fue conducida 
por varios estudiantes, que también exigieron la su derecha de 
liberar discurso y la libertad académica. El FSM chispeó una 
onda sin precedente del activismo y de la implicación del estudiante.
Muchas imágenes en este grupo le hacen el claro que el centro 
de la actividad en el campus UC de Berkeley estaba en la plaza de 
Sproul. Una fotografía muestra a estudiantes que ocupan los 
balcones de Sproul Pasillo, un edificio de la administración del 
campus, banderas del FSM de la tenencia y un indicador americano. 
Otra fotografía muestra a arranque de cinta Mario Savio del 
estudiante que conduce a un grupo de estudiantes a través de la 
puerta de Sather hacia una reunión de los Regentes UC. En el
desafío de la interdicción en actividades políticas localizadas, el
estudiante graduado Gato Weinberg instaló un vector con la 
información política y fue arrestado. Pero un grupo de 
aproximadamente 3.000 estudiantes rodeó el coche del policía en el 
cual lo sostuvieron, evitando que se mueva por 36 horas. Las 
fotografías muestran Weinberg en el coche, Mario Savio y Gato 
Weinberg encima del coche rodeado que habla a la muchedumbre, y del 
coche cercado por los manifestantes y el policía. Otras 
fotografías que retratan la gente dominante y acontecimientos del 
movimiento libre del discurso incluyen a ocho estudiantes (Mario 
incluyendo Savio) suspendidos para funcionar un vector en campus sin 
un permiso y levantar el dinero para los propósitos desautorizados; 
Mario Savio que habla a una muchedumbre; estudiantes que 
firman un compromiso; y estudiantes que duermen en los pasos de 
progresión de la plaza de Sproul. Las fotografías de los 
estudiantes que son arrestados, llevando a cabo una masa sentar-en, y 
cercando con piquete en la ayuda de la huelga de la 
estudiante-facultad como protestan las detenciones de los 
manifestantes reflejan otros aspectos del movimiento libre del 
discurso. El cantante Joan Baez apoyó a FSM, y una fotografía 
la muestra que canta a los manifestantes. Bettina Aptheker, que 
sintió bien más adelante a un profesor de estudios feministas en 
Santa UC Cruz, también apoyó a FSM. Una fotografía la muestra
que habla delante de Sproul Pasillo. Otras fotografías en este 
asunto demuestran que los grupos tales como congreso de la igualdad 
racial (BASE) y los trabajadores internacionales del mundo (IWW) 
mostraron solidaridad y apoyaron a FSM. Otras imágenes en este 
grupo incluyen a presidente UC Clark Kerr que habla en el teatro 
griego UC de Berkeley, y a granjero de James del co-fundador de la 
BASE en una reunión de la BASE.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085258</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107070</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-free-speech-movement</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
