<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105105</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105105</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086281</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I found him to be a very intelligent and feeling man": Enslaved James Riley Encounters an Arab Trader, 1815</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich fand ihn, um ein sehr intelligenter und 
Gefühl Mann zu sein": Versklavtes James Riley trifft einen 
arabischen Händler, 1815 an</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je l'ai trouvé pour être un homme très 
intelligent et de sentiment" : James asservi Riley 
rencontre un commerçant arabe, 1815</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu encontrei-o para ser um homem do muito 
inteligente e sentimento": James enslaved Riley encontra um 
comerciante árabe, 1815</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"lo ho trovato per essere un uomo sensibilità e 
molto intelligente": James asservito Riley incontra un 
commerciante arabo, 1815</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"τον βρήκα για να είμαι πολύ ενός ευφυής και αίσθημα
του ατόμου": Υποδουλωμένος james Riley αντιμετωπίζει 
έναν αραβικό έμπορο, 1815</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"lo encontré para ser un hombre muy inteligente y
sensación": James esclavizado Riley encuentra a comerciante 
árabe, 1815</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For centuries pirates, known as the Barbary pirates, operated out of the North African states of Morocco, Algiers, Tunis, and Tripoli. European states paid tribute to them to ensure their people's safe passage. Without British protection and with few financial or diplomatic resources, the new American nation's ships and citizens were vulnerable on the high seas. Between 1785 and 1820, more than 700 Americans were taken hostage and often enslaved. The American public was fascinated by these captives' stories; their tales of desert cities, caravans, and harems bridged the previously popular Puritan captivity narratives and emerging slave narratives. The most influential of all these American Barbary narratives was James Riley's Loss of the American Brig Commerce. A Connecticut sea captain, Riley ran aground in 1815 and was captured by wandering Arabs. He used his enslavement to call into question the enslavement of Africans and express a common humanity with the desert people he encountered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für Jahrhundertpiraten bekannt als die Barbary 
Piraten, funktionierte aus den afrikanischen Nordzuständen von 
Marokko, von Algiers, von Tunis und von Tripoli heraus. 
Europäer gibt zahlenden Tribut zu ihnen an, um sicheren 
Durchgang ihrer Leute sicherzustellen. Ohne britischen Schutz 
und mit wenigen finanziellen oder diplomatischen Betriebsmitteln, 
waren der neuen amerikanischen die Schiffe und die Bürger Nation auf 
den hohen Meeren verletzbar. Zwischen 1785 und 1820 wurden mehr 
als 700 Amerikanern Geisel genommen und häufig versklavt. Die 
amerikanische Öffentlichkeit wurde durch Geschichten dieser 
Gefangenen fasziniert; ihre Geschichten der Wüste Städte, der 
Wohnwagen und der Hareme überbrückten die vorher populären 
puritanischen Gefangenschaftdarstellungen und die auftauchenden 
Sklavendarstellungen. Das einflußreichste aller dieser 
Amerikanerbarbary Darstellungen war James Rileys Verlust des 
amerikanischen Brig-Handels. Ein Connecticut Seekapitän, Riley 
ließ aground 1815 laufen und wurde von wandering Arabern erfaßt. 
Er verwendete sein enslavement, um in Frage das enslavement der 
Afrikaner stell und eine geläufige Menschlichkeit mit den Wüste 
Leuten auszudrücken, die er antraf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour des pirates de siècles, connu en tant que 
pirates de Barbarie, a fonctionné hors des Etats africains 
du nord du Maroc, d'Alger, de Tunis, et du Tripoli. 
l'Européen énonce l'hommage payé à eux pour assurer le 
passage sûr de leurs personnes. Sans protection britannique et 
avec peu de ressources financières ou diplomatiques, de la nouvelle 
les bateaux et les citoyens nation américaine étaient vulnérables 
sur les hautes mers. Entre 1785 et 1820, plus de 700 Américains
ont été pris l'otage et souvent asservis. Le public américain
a été fasciné par les histoires de ces captifs ; leurs contes
des villes, des caravanes, et des harems de désert ont jeté un pont 
sur les récits puritains précédemment populaires de captivité et 
des récits slaves naissants. Le plus influent de tous ces
récits de Barbarie d'Américain était perte de James Riley du 
commerce américain de Brig. Un capitaine de la marine 
marchande du Connecticut, Riley a échoué en 1815 et a été capturé
par les Arabes errants. Il avait l'habitude son asservissement 
pour mettre en question l'asservissement des Africains et pour exprimer 
une humanité commune avec les personnes de désert qu'il a 
rencontrées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para piratas dos séculos, sabido como os piratas 
de Barbary, operou-se fora dos estados africanos nortes de Marrocos, 
de Argel, de Tunes, e de Tripoli. O europeu indica-lhes tributo 
pago para assegurar a passagem segura do seu pessoa. Sem 
proteção britânica e com poucos recursos financeiros ou diplomatic,
os navios e os cidadãos da nação americana nova eram vulneráveis 
nos mares elevados. Entre 1785 e 1820, mais de 700 americanos 
foram feitos exame do refém e enslaved frequentemente. O 
público americano foi fascinado por histórias destes cativos; 
seus tales de cidades, de caravanas, e de harems do deserto 
construíram uma ponte sobre as narrativas puritan previamente 
populares do captiveiro e narrativas slave emergentes. O mais 
influential de todas estas narrativas de Barbary do americano era 
perda de James Riley do comércio americano do brig. Um capitão
de mar de Connecticut, Riley funcionou aground em 1815 e foi capturado
por árabes vagueando. Usou seu enslavement chamar na pergunta o
enslavement dos africanos e expressar um humanity comum com os povos 
que do deserto encontrou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per i pirati di secoli, conosciuto come i pirati 
di Barbary, funzionati dall'Africano del nord dichiara del 
Marocco, di Algeri, di Tunisi e di Tripoli. L'europeo 
dichiara il tributo paid a loro per accertare il passaggio 
sicuro della loro gente. Senza protezione britannica e con poche
risorse finanziarie o diplomatiche, le navi ed i cittadini della nuova
nazione americana erano vulnerabili sugli alti mari. Fra 1785 e 
1820, più di 700 Americani sono stati presi l'ostaggio e spesso sono 
stati asserviti. Il pubblico americano è stato affascinato 
dalle storia di questi prigionieri; i loro racconti delle 
città, dei caravan e dei harems del deserto hanno gettato un ponte 
sulle descrizioni puritan precedentemente popolari di prigionia e 
sulle descrizioni slave d'emersione. L'più influente di tutte 
queste descrizioni di Barbary dell'americano era perdita di James 
Riley del commercio americano del brig. Un capitano di mare del 
Connecticut, Riley ha fatto funzionare in secca in 1815 ed è stato 
bloccato dagli arabi erranti. Ha usato il suo enslavement 
per mettere in dubbio il enslavement degli Africani e per esprimere 
un'umanità comune con la gente che del deserto ha incontrato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για τους πειρατές αιώνων, γνωστούς ως πειρατές 
Βαρβαρίας, λειτούργησε από τις βόρειες αφρικανικές καταστάσεις 
του Μαρόκου, του Αλγερίου, της Τυνησίας, και της Τρίπολης. 
Τα ευρωπαϊκά κράτη πλήρωσαν το φόρο σε τους για να 
εξασφαλίσουν ασφαλή μετάβαση των ανθρώπων τους. Χωρίς 
βρετανική προστασία και με λίγα οικονομικά ή διπλωματικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, τα σκάφη και οι πολίτες του νέου 
αμερικανικού έθνους ήταν τρωτοί στις υψηλές θάλασσες. 
Μεταξύ 1785 και 1820, περισσότεροι από 700 
Αμερικανοί ήταν ληφθείς όμηρος και συχνά υποδουλωμένος. Το
αμερικανικό κοινό συναρπάστηκε από τις ιστορίες αυτών των 
αιχμαλώτων  οι ιστορίες τους πόλεων ερήμων, τροχόσπιτα, και
harems γεφυρωμένος τα προηγουμένως δημοφιλή πουριτανά 
αφηγήματα αιχμαλωσίας και τα αναδυόμενα αφηγήματα σκλάβων. 
Ο επιδρύτερος όλων αυτών των αμερικανικών αφηγημάτων 
Βαρβαρίας ήταν james Riley απώλεια του αμερικανικού 
εμπορίου Brig. Ένας εμποροπλοίαρχος του Κοννέκτικατ, 
Riley έτρεξε προσαραγμένο το 1815 και συλλήφθηκε από τους 
περιπλαμένος Αραβες. Χρησιμοποίησε την υποδούλωσή του για 
να θέσει υπό αμφισβήτηση την υποδούλωση Αφρικανών και να 
εκφράσει μια κοινή ανθρωπότητα με τους ανθρώπους ερήμων που 
αντιμετώπισε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para los piratas de los siglos, conocido como los 
piratas de Barbary, funcionó fuera de los Estados africanos del norte
de Marruecos, de Argel, de Túnez, y de Trípoli. El europeo 
indica tributo pagado a ellos para asegurar el paso seguro de su 
gente. Sin la protección británica y con pocos recursos 
financieros o diplomáticos, las naves y los ciudadanos de la nueva 
nación americana eran vulnerables en los mares altos. Entre 
1785 y 1820, tomaron a rehén y fueron esclavizados a menudo más de 
700 americanos. Las historias de estos cautivos fascinó al 
público americano; sus cuentos de las ciudades, de las 
caravanas, y de los harems del desierto puentearon las narrativas 
puritan previamente populares del cautiverio y las narrativas 
auxiliares que emergían. El más influyente de todas estas 
narrativas de Barbary del americano era pérdida de James Riley del 
comercio americano del bergantín. Un capitán de mar de 
Connecticut, Riley ejecutó encallado en 1815 y fue capturado por los 
árabes que vagaban. Él utilizó su enslavement para llamar en 
la pregunta el enslavement de africanos y para expresar una humanidad 
común con la gente del desierto que él encontró.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086281</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105105</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-found-him-to-be-a-very-intelligent-and-feeling-man-enslaved-james-riley-encounters-an-arab-trader-1815</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
