<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106785</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106785</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086934</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Failure of German-Americanism": Reinhold Niebuhr Blames German Immigrants for Their Problems During WWI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Ausfall des Deutsch-Amerikanismus": 
Reinhold Niebuhr tadelt deutsche Immigranten für ihre Probleme 
während WWI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la panne du l'Allemand-Américanisme" : 
Reinhold Niebuhr blâme les immigrés allemands de leurs 
problèmes pendant le WWI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a falha do Alemão-german-Americanism": 
Reinhold Niebuhr responsabiliza immigrants alemães por seus 
problemas durante WWI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il guasto del Tedesco-german-Americanism": 
Reinhold Niebuhr incolpa degli immigranti tedeschi i loro 
problemi durante il WWI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η αποτυχία γερμανικός- Americanism": 
Θ*Ρεηνχολδ Niebuhr Blames German Immigrants για τα 
προβλήματά τους κατά τη διάρκεια WWI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el incidente del Alema'n-german-Americanism": 
Reinhold Niebuhr culpa a inmigrantes alemanes por sus problemas 
durante WWI</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century, German Americans remained the largest immigrant group, as well as one of the most highly regarded. Thus the vicious nativist attack on the loyalty of German Americans that emerged before and during World War I was particularly remarkable. Germans had followed a successful assimilation strategy through which they sought to become "American" in politics while remaining "German" in culture. This relative acceptance, however, may have contributed to the problem. Because they saw themselves not as strangers but as full members of the American polity, German Americans responded to the war initially by lobbying strongly to influence American foreign policy in ways favorable to Germany. When the German government began submarine warfare, resulting in American deaths, even German Americans joined in questioning the behavior, if not the loyalty, of their fellow immigrants. In 1916, Reinhold Niebuhr, a German American and young theologian (who later became famous), wrote an article in  Atlantic Monthly  in which he argued that German Americans were themselves responsible for the "lack of esteem" in which they were currently held by other Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 20. Jahrhundert blieben deutsche 
Amerikaner die größte einwandernde Gruppe, sowie eine von in hohem 
Grade betrachtet. So war der schändliche nativist Angriff auf 
der Loyalität der deutschen Amerikaner, denen vor und während des 
Ersten Weltkrieges auftauchte, besonders bemerkenswert. Deutsche
hatten einer erfolgreichen Assimilation Strategie gefolgt, durch die 
sie suchten, "Amerikaner" in der Politik zu werden während restlicher
"Deutscher" in der Kultur. Diese relative Abnahme kann zum 
Problem jedoch beigetragen haben. Weil sie nicht als Fremde aber
als vollwertige Mitglieder der amerikanischen Staatsverwaltung sich 
sahen, reagierten deutsche Amerikaner auf den Krieg zuerst, indem sie 
stark auf fremde Politik des Einfluß Amerikaners in den Methoden 
beeinflußten, die nach Deutschland vorteilhaft sind. Als die 
deutsche Regierung Unterwasserkriegsführung anfing, und das 
resultiert in den amerikanischen Todesfällen, sogar die deutschen 
Amerikaner verbunden, wenn das Verhalten, wenn nicht die Loyalität, 
ihrer Mitimmigranten gefragt wird. 1916 schrieben Reinhold 
Niebuhr, ein deutscher amerikanischer und junger Theologian (wer 
später berühmt wurde), einen Artikel in der atlantischen 
Monatszeitschrift, in der er argumentierte, daß deutsche Amerikaner 
selbst für den "Mangel an Achtung" verantwortlich waren in, welchem 
ihnen aktuell von anderen Amerikanern angehalten wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle, les Américains 
allemands sont restés le plus grand groupe immigré, comme un de le 
plus fortement considéré. Ainsi l'attaque nativiste méchante 
sur la fidélité des Américains allemands avant lesquels a émergé 
et pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale était particulièrement 
remarquable. Les Allemands avaient suivi une stratégie réussie
d'assimilation par laquelle ils ont recherché à devenir "Américain"
dans la politique tandis que "Allemand" restant dans la culture. 
Cette acceptation relative, cependant, a pu avoir contribué au 
problème. Puisqu'ils se sont vus pas comme étrangers mais en 
tant que membres à part entière du régime américain, les 
Américains allemands ont répondu à la guerre au commencement en 
incitant fortement à la politique étrangère d'Américain 
d'influence des voies favorables en Allemagne. Quand le 
gouvernement allemand a commencé la guerre submersible, ayant pour 
résultat les décès américaines, même Américains allemands 
associés à remettre en cause le comportement, si pas la fidélité, 
de leurs immigrés de camarade. En 1916, Reinhold Niebuhr, un 
théologien américain et jeune allemand (qui plus tard est devenu 
célèbre), ont écrit un article en revue mensuelle atlantique en 
laquelle il a argué du fait que les Américains allemands étaient 
eux-mêmes responsables du "manque d'estime" dans ce qu'ils ont été 
actuel tenus par d'autres Américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado, os americanos alemães 
remanesceram o grupo immigrant o maior, assim como um do considerado o
mais altamente. Assim o ataque nativist vicious na lealdade dos 
americanos alemães de que emergiu antes e durante o world.war.i era 
particularmente notável. Os alemães tinham seguido uma 
estratégia bem sucedida do assimilation com que procuraram se 
transformar "americano" na política quando "alemão restante" na 
cultura. Esta aceitação relativa, entretanto, pode ter 
contribuído ao problema. Porque se viram não como desconhecido
mas como membros cheios do polity americano, os americanos alemães 
responderam à guerra inicialmente lobbying fortemente à política 
extrangeira do americano da influência nas maneiras favoráveis a 
Germany. Quando o governo alemão começou a guerra submarina, 
tendo por resultado mortes americanas, mesmo americanos alemães 
juntados em questionar o comportamento, if.not a lealdade, de seus 
immigrants do companheiro. Em 1916, Reinhold Niebuhr, um 
theologian americano e novo alemão (quem se tornou mais tarde 
famoso), escreveram um artigo na revista mensal atlantic em que 
discutiu que os americanos alemães eram eles mesmos responsáveis 
para a "falta do esteem" em qual foram prendidos atualmente por outros
americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, gli Americani 
tedeschi sono rimasto il più grande gruppo immigrato, come pure uno 
del il più altamente considerato. Così l'attacco nativist 
vizioso alla lealtà degli Americani tedeschi di che è emerso prima e
durante il world.war.i era particolarmente notevole. I tedeschi 
avevano seguito una strategia riuscita di assimilazione con cui hanno 
cercato di diventare "americano" nella politica mentre "tedesco" 
restante nella coltura. Questa accettazione relativa, tuttavia, 
può contribuire al problema. Poiché si sono visti non come 
sconosciuti ma come membri titolari del polity americano, gli 
Americani tedeschi hanno risposto inizialmente alla guerra incitando 
fortemente alla politica straniera dell'americano di influenza nei 
modi favorevoli in Germania. Quando il governo tedesco ha 
cominciato la guerra sottomarina, con conseguente morti americane, 
persino Americani tedeschi associati a mettere in discussione il 
comportamento, se non la lealtà, dei loro immigranti del collega. 
In 1916, Reinhold Niebuhr, un theologian americano e giovane 
tedesco (chi più successivamente sono diventato famosi), hanno 
scritto un articolo in mensile atlantico in cui ha sostenuto che gli 
Americani tedeschi erano essi stessi responsabili "della mancanza di 
stima" in quale attualmente sono stati tenuti da altri Americani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, γερμανικοί Αμερικανοί 
παρέμειναν η μεγαλύτερη που έχουν μεταναστεύσει ομάδα, καθώς 
επίσης και μια από ο πιό ιδιαίτερα θεωρημένη. Κατά 
συνέπεια η κακοήθης επίθεση nativist στην πίστη γερμανικών 
Αμερικανών που προέκυψαν πριν από και κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου ήμουν ιδιαίτερα αξιοπρόσεκτος. Γερμανοί
είχαν ακολουθήσει μια επιτυχή στρατηγική αφομοίωσης μέσω της 
οποίας επιδίωξαν να γίνουν "αμερικανικά" στην πολιτική υπόλοιπος
"γερμανικά" στον πολιτισμό. Αυτή η σχετική αποδοχή, 
εντούτοις, μπορεί να είχε συμβάλει στο πρόβλημα. Επειδή 
εβλέίδαν όχι ως ξένους αλλά ως πλήρη μέλη των 
αμερικανικών πολιτικών, γερμανικοί Αμερικανοί αποκρίθηκαν στον 
πόλεμο αρχικά με να πιέσουν για να επηρεάσουν έντονα την 
αμερικανική εξωτερική πολιτική στους τρόπους ευνοϊκούς στη 
Γερμανία. Όταν η γερμανική κυβέρνηση άρχισε την υποβρύχια 
εχθροπραξία, προκύπτων στους αμερικανικούς θανάτους, ακόμη και 
γερμανικοί Αμερικανοί ένωσαν στην επερώτηση της συμπεριφοράς, 
εάν όχι η πίστη, των συντροφικών μεταναστών τους. Το 
1916, ο Reinhold Niebuhr, ένας γερμανικός αμερικανικός και
νέος θεολόγος (που έγιναν αργότερα διάσημοι), έγραψαν ένα 
άρθρο σε ατλαντικό μηνιαία στον οποίο υποστήριξε ότι γερμανικοί
Αμερικανοί ήταν οι ίδιοι αρμόδιοι για τη "έλλειψη εκτίμησησ" 
στην οποία αυτήν την περίοδο άλλοι Αμερικανοί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Del vigésimo siglo temprano, los americanos 
alemanes seguían siendo el grupo inmigrante más grande, tan bien 
como uno de mirado lo más altamente posible. Así el ataque 
nativista vicioso contra la lealtad de los americanos alemanes antes 
de quienes emergió y durante Primera Guerra Mundial era determinado 
notable. Los alemanes habían seguido una estrategia acertada de
la asimilación con la cual intentaron hacer "americano" en política 
mientras que "alemán restante" en cultura. Esta aceptación 
relativa, sin embargo, pudo haber contribuido al problema. 
Porque se vieron no como extranjeros sino como miembros de pleno
derecho del polity americano, los americanos alemanes respondieron a 
la guerra inicialmente cabildeando fuertemente a la política no 
nativa del americano de la influencia de las maneras favorables a 
Alemania. Cuando el gobierno alemán comenzó la guerra 
submarina, dando por resultado las muertes americanas, incluso 
americanos alemanes unidos en preguntar el comportamiento, si no la 
lealtad, de sus inmigrantes del compañero. En 1916, Reinhold 
Niebuhr, un teólogo americano y joven alemán (quién llegó a ser 
más adelante famoso), escribieron un artículo en la publicación 
mensual atlántica en la cual él discutió que los americanos 
alemanes fueran ellos mismos responsables de la "carencia de la 
estima" en cuál otros americanos les sostuvieron actualmente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086934</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106785</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-failure-of-german-americanism-reinhold-niebuhr-blames-german-immigrants-for-their-problems-during-wwi</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
