<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103257</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103257</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086870</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Susie Steno": A Union's View of Clerical Workers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Susie Steno": Ansicht eines Anschlußes der
kanzleimäßigen Arbeiter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Susie Steno" : La vue des syndicats des 
ouvriers de secrétaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Susie Steno": Opinião de uma união 
trabalhadores de escritório</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Susie Steno": Punto di vista del sindacato 
degli operai di segreteria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Susie Steno": Η όψη μιας ένωσης των 
γραφείου εργαζομένων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Susie Steno": Opinión de una unión 
trabajadores administrativos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1939, a federal Women's Bureau survey revealed that only one in fifteen union members was female. But the same observers also noted the truism that women workers, once organized, often became tenacious and militant unionists. Unionists saw women as temporary members of the work force (as indeed most were before 1940, when the average worker was a young single woman). They mistakenly assumed that such workers would not be dedicated union members. Some saw women as unwelcome competitors for "men's jobs" and worked to keep women out of better paid union jobs rather than recruiting them to join the union. Even the United Office and Professional Workers Association (UOPWA), a progressive union that focused its efforts on clerical workers, shared some of these demeaning views of women. A regular column in the UOPWA's publication, the  Ledger,  featured "Susie Steno," a condescending caricature of a clerical worker as a frivolous and naive young woman, albeit one who becomes a good unionist.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1939 deckte eine Büroübersicht der Bundesfrauen 
auf, daß nur eins in fünfzehn Anschlußbauteilen weiblich war. 
Aber die gleichen Beobachter beachteten auch den Truism, den 
Frauarbeiter, sobald organisiert, häufig tenacious und militante 
Unionisten wurden. Unionisten sahen Frauen da temporäre 
Bauteile der Arbeit Kraft (als in der Tat die meisten waren vor 1940, 
als der durchschnittliche Arbeiter eine junge einzelne Frau war). 
Sie nahmen irrtümlich an, daß solche Arbeiter nicht engagierte
Anschlußbauteile sein würden. Einige sahen Frauen als nicht 
willkommene Konkurrenten für "Jobs der Männer" und arbeiteten, um 
Frauen aus besseren zahlenden Anschlußjobs anstatt -einziehen sie 
heraus zu halten, den Anschluß zu verbinden. Sogar die 
vereinigte Büro-und Fachmann-Arbeiter-Verbindung (UOPWA), ein 
progressiver Anschluß, der seine Bemühungen auf kanzleimäßige 
Arbeiter richtete, geteilt einigen dieser demeaning Ansichten der 
Frauen. Eine regelmäßige Spalte in der Publikation des UOPWAs,
im Hauptbuch, in gekennzeichnetem "Susie Steno," in einer 
herablassenden Karikatur eines kanzleimäßigen Arbeiters als 
leichtfertige und naive junge Frau, obwohl in einer, wer einem guten 
Unionisten steht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1939, une enquête du bureau des femmes 
fédérales a indiqué que seulement un dans quinze travailleurs 
syndiqués était femelle. Mais les mêmes observateurs ont 
également noté le truisme que les ouvriers de femmes, une fois 
qu'organisés, sont souvent devenus les syndicalistes tenaces et 
militants. Les syndicalistes ont vu des femmes car les membres
provisoires de la main-d'oeuvre (en tant qu'en effet la plupart 
avaient lieu avant 1940, quand l'ouvrière moyenne était une jeune 
femme célibataire). Ils ont de manière erronée supposé que 
de tels ouvriers ne seraient pas les travailleurs syndiqués dédiés.
Certains ont vu des femmes en tant que concurrents fâcheux pour
les "travaux des hommes" et ont travaillé pour garder des femmes hors
des meilleurs travaux payés plutôt que de de les recruter des 
syndicats de joindre l'union. L'association unie d'ouvriers 
même de bureau et de professionnel (UOPWA), une union progressive qui
a concentré ses efforts sur les ouvriers de secrétaire, partagée 
certaines de ces vues demeaning des femmes. Une colonne 
régulière dans la publication de l'UOPWA, le registre, "Susie 
décrit Steno," une caricature condescendante d'un ouvrier de 
secrétaire en tant que jeune femme frivole et naïve, quoiqu'une qui 
va bien à un bon syndicaliste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1939, um exame do departamento das mulheres 
federais revelou que somente um em quinze membros de união era 
fêmea. Mas os mesmos observadores anotaram também o truism que
os trabalhadores das mulheres, uma vez que organizados, se 
transformaram frequentemente unionists tenacious e militant. Os 
unionists viram mulheres porque membros provisórios da força de 
trabalho (como certamente a maioria se realizavam antes de 1940, 
quando o trabalhador médio era uma única mulher nova). 
Supuseram equivocadamente que tais trabalhadores não seriam 
membros de união dedicados. Alguns viram mulheres como 
concorrentes unwelcome para dos "trabalhos homens" e trabalharam para 
manter mulheres fora dos trabalhos pagos melhores melhor que de 
recrutá-los da união juntar a união. A associação unida dos
trabalhadores mesmo do escritório e do profissional (UOPWA), uma 
união progressiva que focalizasse seus esforços em trabalhadores de 
escritório, compartilhada algumas destas opiniões humilhantes as 
mulheres. Uma coluna regular na publicação do UOPWA, no 
livro-razão, em "Susie caracterizado Steno," em um caricature 
condescending de um trabalhador de escritório como uma mulher nova 
frivolous e ingénua, albeit em um quem assenta bem em um unionist 
bom.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1939, un'indagine dell'ufficio delle donne 
federali ha rivelato che soltanto uno in quindici membri del sindacato
era femminile. Ma gli stessi osservatori egualmente hanno notato
la verità che gli operai delle donne, una volta che organizzati, sono
diventato spesso unionisti del militante e tenacious. Gli 
unionisti hanno visto le donne poichè membri provvisori della forza 
di lavoro (come effettivamente la maggior parte avevano luogo prima di
1940, quando l'operaio medio era una donna non-sposata giovane). 
Hanno supposto erroneamente che tali operai non sarebbero membri
dedicati del sindacato. Alcuni hanno visto le donne come 
competitori unwelcome per "i lavori degli uomini" ed hanno funzionato 
per mantenere le donne dai lavori paid migliori piuttosto che dal 
reclutamento del sindacato loro unire l'unione. L'associazione 
unita degli operai del professionista ed anche dell'ufficio (UOPWA), 
un'unione progressiva che ha concentrato i relativi sforzi sugli 
operai di segreteria, compartecipe alcuni di questi punti di vista 
avvilenti delle donne. Una colonna normale nella pubblicazione 
del UOPWA, nel registro, "in Susie descritto Steno," in un caricature 
condescending di un operaio di segreteria come donna giovane frivolous
ed ingenuo, anche se in uno chi sta bene ad un buon unionista.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1939, μια ομοσπονδιακή έρευνα γραφείων των 
γυναικών αποκάλυψε ότι μόνο το ένα σε δεκαπέντε μέλη ένωσης 
ήταν θηλυκό. Αλλά οι ίδιοι παρατηρητές σημείωσαν επίσης 
την κοινοτοπία ότι εργαζόμενοι γυναικών, μόλις οργανώνω, έγιναν
συχνά σταθεροί και στρατευμένοι ενωτικοί. Οι ενωτικοί 
εβλέίδαν τις γυναίκες ως προσωρινά μέλη του εργατικού 
δυναμικού (όπως πράγματι πιό πολύ ήταν πριν από το 1940, 
όταν ο μέσος εργαζόμενος ήταν νέα ανύπαντρη). Εσφαλμένα 
υπέθεσαν ότι τέτοιοι εργαζόμενοι δεν θα ήταν αφιερωμένα μέλη 
ένωσης. Μερικοί εβλέίδαν τις γυναίκες ως 
ανεπιθύμητους ανταγωνιστές για τις "εργασίες των ανδρών" και 
ελειτούργησαν για να κρατήσουν τις γυναίκες από τις καλύτερες 
πληρωμένες εργασίες ένωσης παρά τη στρατολόγηση τους για να 
ενώσουν την ένωση. Ακόμη και το ενωμένο γραφείο και η 
επαγγελματική ένωση εργαζομένων (UOPWA), μια προοδευτική ένωση
που έστρεψε τις προσπάθειές της στους γραφείου εργαζομένους, 
υποστήριξαν μερικές από αυτές τις εξευτελιστικές όψεις των 
γυναικών. Μια κανονική στήλη στη δημοσίευση του UOPWA, το
καθολικό, χαρακτήρισε "Susie Steno," μια condescending 
καρικατούρα ενός γραφείου εργαζομένου ως επιπόλαια και αφελή 
νέα γυναίκα, αν και μια που γίνεται καλός ενωτικός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1939, una encuesta sobre la oficina de las 
mujeres federales reveló que solamente uno en quince miembros de 
unión era femenino. Pero los mismos observadores también 
observaron el truismo que los trabajadores de las mujeres, una vez que
estuvieron ordenados, hicieron a menudo unionistas tenacious y 
militantes. Los unionistas vieron a mujeres pues los miembros 
temporales de la fuerza de trabajo (como la mayoría eran de hecho 
antes de 1940, cuando el trabajador medio era una sola mujer joven). 
Asumieron equivocadamente que tales trabajadores no serían 
miembros de unión dedicados. Algunos vieron a mujeres como 
competidores incómodos para los "trabajos de los hombres" y 
trabajaron para guardar a mujeres fuera de trabajos pagados mejores 
más bien que de reclutarlos de la unión de ensamblar la unión. 
La asociación unida de los trabajadores incluso de la oficina y
del profesional (UOPWA), una unión progresiva que se centró sus 
esfuerzos en trabajadores administrativos, compartida algunas de estas
opiniones degradantes mujeres. Una columna regular en la 
publicación del UOPWA, el libro mayor, "Susie ofrecido Steno," un 
caricature condescending de un trabajador administrativo como mujer 
joven frívola e ingenua, no obstante uno quién siente bien a un buen
unionista.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086870</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103257</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/susie-steno-a-unions-view-of-clerical-workers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
