<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106930</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106930</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087240</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">William Walker's "Filibusters" relax after the Battle of Granada.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Verzögerungspolitiken" des William Wanderers 
entspannen sich nach der Schlacht von Granada.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Flibustiers "du marcheur de William les" 
détendent après la bataille de Grenade.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Filibusters "do walker de William os" relaxam 
após a batalha de Granada.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I filibusters "del camminatore del William" si 
distendono dopo la battaglia di Granada.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι "κωλυσιεργίεσ" William Walker's χαλαρώνουν 
μετά από τη μάχη της Γρανάδας.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Filibusters "del walker de Guillermo los" relajan 
después de la batalla de Granada.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Slaveholders went to great extremes to expand slavery, turning to Mexico, western territories, and even Central America. Supported by fifty-eight mercenaries, the Tennessee-born William Walker "invaded" Nicaragua in May 1855. Within six months he succeeded in exploiting civil unrest in the country and declared himself president. Walker's government, which opened the country to slavery, was recognized by the United States in 1856. But he was overthrown a year later by forces financed by his former sponsor, the railroad entrepreneur Cornelius Vanderbilt.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Slaveholders ging zu den großen Übermaßen, die 
Sklaverei zu erweitern und wendete an Mexiko, westliche Gegenden und 
sogar Mittelamerika. Unterstützt durch fifty-eight Söldner, 
"drang" der Tennessee-getragene William Wanderer Nicaragua im Mai 1855
ein. Innerhalb sechs Monate folgte er, mit, Zivilruhelosigkeit 
im Land auszunutzen und erklärte sich Präsident. Regierung des
Wanderers, die das Land zur Sklaverei öffnete, wurde durch die 
Vereinigten Staaten 1856 erkannt. Aber er wurde ein Jahr später
durch die Kräfte besiegt, die von seinem ehemaligen Förderer, der 
Eisenbahnunternehmer Cornelius Vanderbilt finanziert wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Slaveholders est allé à de grandes extrémités 
augmenter l'esclavage, se tournant vers le Mexique, les territoires 
occidentaux, et même l'Amérique Centrale. Supporté par des 
mercennaires de fifty-eight, le marcheur Tennessee-soutenu de William 
"a envahi" le Nicaragua en mai 1855. Dans les six mois il a 
réussi à exploiter le malaise civil dans le pays et s'est déclaré 
président. Le gouvernement du marcheur, qui a ouvert le pays à
l'esclavage, a été identifié par les Etats-Unis en 1856. Mais
il a été renversé un an après par des forces financées par son 
ancien commanditaire, l'entrepreneur Cornelius Vanderbilt de chemin de
fer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Slaveholders foi aos extremos grandes expandir o slavery, 
girando para México, territórios ocidentais, e mesmo América 
Central. Suportado por mercenaries do fifty-eight, o walker 
Tennessee-carregado de William "invadiu" Nicarágua em maio 1855. 
Dentro de seis meses sucedeu em explorar o unrest civil no país
e declarou-se presidente. O governo do walker, que abriu o país
ao slavery, foi reconhecido pelos estados unidos em 1856. Mas 
overthrown um ano mais tarde pelas forças financiadas por seu 
patrocinador anterior, empreendedor Cornelius Vanderbilt da estrada de
ferro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Slaveholders è andato agli estremi grandi espandere lo 
slavery, girantesi nel Messico, i territori occidentali e perfino in 
America Centrale. Sostenuto dai mercenaries del fifty-eight, il 
camminatore Tennessee-sopportato del William "ha invaso" la Nicaragua 
nel mese di maggio 1855. Entro sei mesi è riuscito a sfruttare 
l'agitazione civile nel paese e si è dichiarato presidente. Il 
governo del camminatore, che ha aperto il paese a slavery, è stato 
riconosciuto dal unito Dichiara in 1856. Ma overthrown un
anno più successivamente dalle forze finanziate dal suo ex garante, 
l'imprenditore Cornelius Vanderbilt della ferrovia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Slaveholders πήγε στα μεγάλα άκρα να επεκτείνει 
τη σκλαβιά, που γυρίζει στο Μεξικό, τα δυτικά εδάφη, και ακόμη 
και την Κεντρική Αμερική. Υποστηριγμένος από πενήντα οκτώ 
mercenaries, ο Tennessee-gennime'nos William Walker 
"εισέβαλε" στη Νικαράγουα σε Μάιος 1855, Μέσα σε έξι
μήνες πέτυχε στην εκμετάλλευση της αστικής ανησυχίας στη χώρα 
και δηλώθηκε τον Πρόεδρο. Η κυβέρνηση του περιπατητή, που 
άνοιξε τη χώρα στη σκλαβιά, αναγνωρίζω από τις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες το 1856. Αλλά νικήθηκε ένα έτος αργότερα από
τις δυνάμεις που χρηματοδοτήθηκαν από τον προηγούμενο χορηγό του,
ο επιχειρηματίας Cornelius Vanderbilt σιδηροδρόμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Slaveholders fue a los grandes extremos a ampliar la 
esclavitud, dando vuelta a México, a los territorios occidentales, e 
incluso a America Central. Utilizado por los mercenarios del 
fifty-eight, el walker Tennessee-llevado de Guillermo "invadió" 
Nicaragua en mayo de 1855. En el plazo de seis meses él tuvo 
éxito en explotar malestar civil en el país y se declaró 
presidente. El gobierno del walker, que abrió el país en la 
esclavitud, fue reconocido por los Estados Unidos en 1856. Pero 
las fuerzas lo derrocó un año más tarde financiadas por su 
patrocinador anterior, el empresario Cornelius Vanderbilt del 
ferrocarril.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087240</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106930</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/william-walkers-filibusters-relax-after-the-battle-of-granada</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
