<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106502</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106502</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086690</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">One African-American Dreams About Rebuilding the South</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Träume einer über das 
Umbauen des Südens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rêves d'un Afro-Américain au sujet de reconstruire 
les Sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sonhos um Africano-Americanos sobre reconstruir o 
sul</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sogni Africano-Americani uno circa la 
ricostruzione del sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όνειρα ένας αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός για την 
επανοικοδόμηση του νότου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sueños Africano-Americanos uno sobre la 
reconstrucción del sur</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the decades following the Civil War, many white southern landowners, entrepreneurs, and journalists campaigned for the creation of a "New South" economy that would emphasize modern industrial development. With the plantation system no longer dominating the southern economy, the South could build its own factories to turn raw materials into finished products: cotton into cloth, tobacco into cigarettes, coal and iron ore into steel. White southern leaders were not the only ones who argued that industrialization was the key to future Southern progress. A small group of black businessmen and landowners, who had taken advantage of the opportunities open to African Americans during Reconstruction, also supported the ideal of a New South based on industrial growth. In the following 1896 statement, Warren C. Coleman, a black North Carolina businessman, called on his fellow black Southerners to support his plan to build a cotton mill that would be operated by black workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Dekaden, die dem Bürgerkrieg folgen, 
warben viele weiße südliche Grundbesitzer, Unternehmer und 
Journalisten für die Kreation einer "neuen Süd" Wirtschaft, die 
moderne industrielle Entwicklung hervorheben würde. Wenn das 
Plantagesystem nicht mehr die südliche Wirtschaft beherrscht, könnte
der Süden seine eigenen Fabriken aufbauen, um Rohstoffe zu 
Fertigwaren zu machen: Baumwolle in Tuch, Tabak in Zigaretten, 
Kohle und Eisenerz in Stahl. Weiße südliche Führer waren 
nicht die einzigen, die argumentierten, daß Industrialisierung die 
Taste zum zukünftigen südlichen Fortschritt war. Eine kleine 
Gruppe schwarze Geschäftsmänner und Grundbesitzer, die Nutzen aus 
den Gelegenheiten gezogen hatten, die zu den afrikanischen Amerikanern
während der Rekonstruktion geöffnet sind, unterstützte auch das 
ideale eines neuen Südens, der auf industriellem Wachstum basierte. 
In der folgenden Anweisung 1896 ersuchte Warren C. Coleman, ein 
schwarzer Nord-Carolina Geschäftsmann, um sein Mitschwarzes 
Southerners, um seinen Plan zu unterstützen, um eine 
Baumwollspinnerei aufzubauen, die von den schwarzen Arbeitern 
bearbeitet würde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les décennies suivant la guerre civile, 
beaucoup de propriétaires fonciers, entrepreneurs, et journalistes 
méridionaux blancs ont fait campagne pour la création d'une 
"nouvelle" économie du sud qui soulignerait le développement 
industriel moderne. Avec le système de plantation ne dominant 
plus l'économie méridionale, les Sud ont pu construire ses 
propres usines pour transformer les matières premières premières en
produits finis : coton dans le tissu, tabac dans le minerai de 
cigarettes, de charbon et de fer dans l'acier. Les amorces 
méridionales blanches n'étaient pas les seules qui ont argué du 
fait que l'industrialisation était la clé au futur progrès 
méridional. Un petit groupe d'hommes d'affaires et de 
propriétaires fonciers noirs, qui avaient tiré profit des occasions 
ouvertes d'Américains africains pendant la reconstruction, a 
également supporté l'idéal d'un nouveau Sud basé sur la 
croissance industrielle. Dans le rapport 1896 suivant, Warren C.
Coleman, un homme d'affaires du nord noir de la Caroline, a invité
ses Habitants du sud de noir de camarade à supporter son plan pour 
construire une filature de coton qui serait actionnée par les 
ouvriers noirs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas décadas que seguem a guerra civil, muitos 
latifundiários, empreendedores, e journalists do sul brancos fizeram 
campanha para a criação de uma economia "sul" nova que emfatizasse o
desenvolvimento industrial moderno. Com o sistema da plantação
que domina não mais por muito tempo a economia do sul, o sul podia 
construir suas próprias fábricas para girar materiais crus em 
produtos terminados: algodão no pano, tabaco no minério dos 
cigarros, do carvão e de ferro no aço. Os líderes do sul 
brancos não eram únicos que discutiram que o industrialization era a
chave ao progresso do sul futuro. Um grupo pequeno dos homens de
negócios e dos latifundiários pretos, que tinham feito exame da 
vantagem das oportunidades abertas aos americanos africanos durante o 
reconstruction, suportou também o ideal de um sul novo baseado no 
crescimento industrial. Na seguinte indicação 1896, Warren C. 
Coleman, um homem de negócios preto de North.carolina, convidou seu 
preto Southerners do companheiro para suportar sua planta para 
construir um moinho de algodão que fosse operado por trabalhadores 
pretos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nelle decadi che seguono la guerra civile, molti 
latifondisti, imprenditori e giornalisti del sud bianchi hanno fatto 
una campagna per la creazione "di nuova" economia del sud che dare 
risalto allo sviluppo industriale moderno. Con il sistema della 
piantagione più che non domina l'economia del sud, il sud ha potuto 
costruire le relative proprie fabbriche per trasformare nelle materie 
prime i prodotti finiti: cotone nel panno, tabacco nelle 
sigarette, carbone e minerale ferroso in acciaio. I capi 
del sud bianchi non erano quei unici che sostenessero che 
l'industrializzazione era il tasto a progresso del sud futuro. 
Un piccolo gruppo degli uomini d'affari e dei latifondisti neri,
che avevano approfittato delle occasioni aperte agli Americani 
africani durante la ricostruzione, egualmente ha sostenuto il ideale 
di nuovo sud basato su sviluppo industriale. Nella seguente 
istruzione 1896, Warren C. Coleman, un uomo d'affari nero del 
North.carolina, ha invitato il suo nero Southerners del collega per 
sostenere il suo programma per costruire un cotonificio che sarebbe 
funzionato dagli operai neri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις δεκαετίες μετά από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο, πολλοί 
λευκοί νότιοι landowners, επιχειρηματίες, και δημοσιογράφοι 
έκαναν εκστρατεία για τη δημιουργία μιας οικονομίας "νέου νότου"
που θα υπογράμμιζε τη σύγχρονη βιομηχανική ανάπτυξη. Με το 
σύστημα φυτειών που εξουσιάζει όχι άλλο τη νότια οικονομία, ο 
νότος θα μπορούσε να χτίσει τα εργοστάσιά του για να μετατρέψει 
τις πρώτες ύλες σε ολοκληρωμένα προϊόντα: βαμβάκι στο 
ύφασμα, καπνός στα τσιγάρα, μετάλλευμα άνθρακα και σιδήρου στο 
χάλυβα. Οι λευκοί νότιοι ηγέτες δεν ήταν οι μόνοι που 
υποστήριξαν ότι η εκβιομηχάνιση ήταν το πλήκτρο στη μελλοντική 
νότια πρόοδο. Μια μικρή ομάδα μαύρων επιχειρηματιών και 
landowners, που είχαν εκμεταλλευθεί τις ευκαιρίες ανοικτές σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς κατά τη διάρκεια της αναδημιουργίας, 
υποστήριξε επίσης το ιδανικό ενός νέου νότου βασισμένου στη 
βιομηχανική αύξηση. Στην ακόλουθη δήλωση 1896, Warren 
Γ. Coleman, ένας μαύρος επιχειρηματίας της βόρειας Καρολίνας, 
κάλεσε τους συντροφικούς μαύρους νοτίους του για να υποστηρίξει 
το σχέδιό του για να χτίσει έναν μύλο βαμβακιού που θα 
χρησιμοποιούταν από τους μαύρους εργαζομένους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las décadas que seguían la guerra civil, 
muchos terratenientes, empresarios, y periodistas meridionales blancos
hicieron campaña para la creación de una "nueva" economía del sur 
que acentuaría el desarrollo industrial moderno. Con el sistema
de la plantación dominando no más de largo la economía meridional, 
el sur podía construir sus propias fábricas para dar vuelta a las 
materias primas en productos acabados: algodón en el paño, 
tabaco en el mineral de los cigarrillos, del carbón y de hierro en el
acero. Los arranques de cinta meridionales blancos no eran los 
únicos que discutieron que la industrialización fuera el clave al 
progreso meridional futuro. Un grupo pequeño de los hombres de 
negocios y de los terratenientes negros, que se habían aprovechado de
las oportunidades abiertas a los americanos africanos durante la 
reconstrucción, también utilizó el ideal de un nuevo sur basado en 
crecimiento industrial. En la declaración siguiente 1896, 
Warren C. Coleman, hombre de negocios negro de Carolina del Norte, 
invitó su negro Southerners del compañero para utilizar su plan para
construir una fábrica de algodón que sería funcionada por los 
trabajadores negros.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086690</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106502</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/one-african-american-dreams-about-rebuilding-the-south</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
