<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103956</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103956</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203898</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mercenaria Laboratory Exercise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mercenaria Laborübung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Exercice de Laboratoire de Mercenaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exercício Do Laboratório De Mercenaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esercitazione Del Laboratorio Di Mercenaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εργαστηριακή άσκηση Mercenaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ejercicio Del Laboratorio De Mercenaria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Invertebrate Anatomy Online exercise, featuring the hard-shell clam Mercenaria mercenaria (quahog), is part of an Internet laboratory manual for courses in Invertebrate Zoology. This exercise features an introduction to Mollusca and a step-by-step dissection guide, including hand-drawn figures, defined terms, and detailed explanations of form and function. Students will learn about the external anatomy (shell), muscles, mantle skirts, mantle cavity, mantle folds, siphons, gills, labial palps, hemal system, exhalant chamber, excretory system, digestive system, nervous system, and reproductive system.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Onlineübung der wirbellosen Anatomie, das 
Hartshell Muschel Mercenaria mercenaria (quahog) kennzeichnend, ist 
ein Teil eines Internet-Laborhandbuches für Kurse in der wirbellosen 
Zoologie. Diese Übung kennzeichnet eine Einleitung zu den 
Mollusca und eine schrittweisee Zerlegunganleitung, einschließlich 
hand-drawn Abbildungen, definierte Bezeichnungen und genau 
geschilderte Erklärungen des Formulars und der Funktion. 
Kursteilnehmer erlernen über die externe Anatomie (Shell), die 
Muskeln, die Umhangröcke, Umhangraum, Umhangfalten, Druckdosen, 
Kiemen, labial palps, hemal System, exhalant Raum, absonderndes 
System, Verdauungssystem, nervöses System und reproduktives System.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice en ligne d'anatomie invertébrée, 
comportant le mercenaria de Mercenaria de palourde de 
dur-interpréteur de commandes interactif (quahog), fait partie d'un 
manuel de laboratoire d'Internet pour des cours en zoologie 
invertébrée. Cet exercice comporte une introduction aux 
molluscums et un guide pas à pas de dissection, y compris les figures
tirées par la main, des limites définies, et des explications 
détaillées de forme et de fonction. Les étudiants se 
renseigneront sur l'anatomie externe (interpréteur de commandes 
interactif), des muscles, des jupes de manteau, la cavité de manteau,
des plis de manteau, des siphons, des ouïes, des palps labiaux, 
le système hématique, la chambre exhalante, le système excrétoire,
le système digestif, le système nerveux, et le système 
reproducteur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício em linha do anatomy invertebrate, 
caracterizando o mercenaria de Mercenaria dos moluscos do duro-escudo 
(quahog), é parte de um manual de laboratório do Internet para 
cursos no zoology invertebrate. Este exercício caracteriza uma 
introdução aos moluscos e uma guia passo a passo do dissection, 
including figuras hand-drawn, termos definidos, e explanações 
detalhadas do formulário e da função. Os estudantes 
aprenderão sobre o anatomy externo (escudo), os músculos, as saias 
do mantle, a cavidade do mantle, as dobras do mantle, os sifões, as 
brânquias, palps labial, o sistema hemal, a câmara exhalant, o 
sistema excretory, o sistema digestivo, o sistema nervoso, e o sistema
reproductive.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione in linea di anatomia 
invertebrata, caratterizzante il mercenaria di Mercenaria del mollusco
delle duro-coperture (quahog), fa parte di un manuale di laboratorio 
del Internet per i corsi in zoologia invertebrata. Questa 
esercitazione caratterizza un'introduzione ai molluschi e una guida 
graduale di dissezione, compreso le figure disegnate a mano, concetti 
definiti e spiegazioni dettagliate della forma e della funzione. 
Gli allievi impareranno circa l'anatomia esterna (coperture), i 
muscoli, i pannelli esterni del manto, la cavità del manto, i 
popolare del manto, i sifoni, le branchie, i palps labial, il sistema 
hemal, l'alloggiamento exhalant, il sistema escretivo, il sistema 
digestivo, il sistema nervoso ed il sistema riproduttivo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ασπόνδυλη σε απευθείας σύνδεση άσκηση 
ανατομίας, που χαρακτηρίζει το mercenaria Mercenaria μαλακίων
σκληρός-κοχυλιών (quahog), είναι μέρος ενός εργαστηριακού 
εγχειριδίου Διαδικτύου για τις σειρές μαθημάτων στην ασπόνδυλη 
ζωολογία. Αυτή η άσκηση χαρακτηρίζει μια εισαγωγή στα 
μαλάκια και έναν βαθμιαίο οδηγό ανατομής, συμπεριλαμβανομένων 
των hand-drawn αριθμών, τους καθορισμένους όρους, και τις 
λεπτομερείς εξηγήσεις της μορφής και της λειτουργίας. Οι 
σπουδαστές θα μάθουν για την εξωτερική ανατομία (κοχύλι), τους 
μυς, τις φούστες μανδυών, την κοιλότητα μανδυών, τις πτυχές 
μανδυών, τα σιφώνια, τα βράγχια, τα χειλικά palps, το hemal 
σύστημα, την εκπνέουσα αίθουσα, το απεκκριτικό σύστημα, το 
χωνευτικό σύστημα, το νευρικό σύστημα, και το αναπαραγωγικό 
σύστημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio en línea de la anatomía 
invertebrada, ofreciendo el mercenaria de Mercenaria de la almeja del 
duro-shell (quahog), es parte de un manual de laboratorio del Internet
para los cursos en zoología invertebrada. Este ejercicio ofrece
una introducción a moluscos y una guía paso a paso de la disección,
incluyendo figuras hand-drawn, los términos definidos, y las 
explicaciones detalladas de la forma y de la función. Los 
estudiantes aprenderán sobre la anatomía externa (shell), los 
músculos, las faldas de la capa, la cavidad de la capa, dobleces de 
la capa, sifones, papadas, palps labial, sistema hemal, compartimiento
exhalante, sistema excretorio, sistema digestivo, sistema nervioso, y 
sistema reproductivo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RICHARD FOX
FN:RICHARD FOX
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:INVERTEBRATE ANATOMY ONLINE
FN:INVERTEBRATE ANATOMY ONLINE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203898</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103956</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mercenaria-laboratory-exercise</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
