<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201581</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Evaluating How Our Students Think and Learn: Research Results from the Trenches</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auswerten, wie unsere Kursteilnehmer denken und 
erlernen: Forschungsresultate von den Gräben</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Évaluant comment nos étudiants pensent et 
apprennent : Résultats de la recherche des fossés</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Avaliando como nossos estudantes pensam e aprendem:
Resultados de pesquisa das trincheiras</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Valutando come i nostri allievi pensano ed 
imparano: Risultati della ricerca dalle trincee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αξιολογώντας πώς οι σπουδαστές μας σκέφτονται και 
μαθαίνουν: Ερευνητικά αποτελέσματα από τις τάφρους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Evaluando cómo nuestros estudiantes piensan y 
aprenden: Resultados de investigación de los fosos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This PowerPoint presentation addresses research on the thinking and learning processes of students and how increased knowledge of these processes can be used to structure lectures in a manner that will change the way students learn. It covers methods for course redesign, classroom assessment techniques, levels of learning and goals in general education courses. Among other things, it was found that student success is predictable, all students benefit from active learning, and group work is important.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese PowerPoint Darstellung Adressen Forschung auf
den denkenden und Lernprozessen der Kursteilnehmer und wie erhöhtes 
Wissen dieser Prozesse verwendet werden kann, um zu strukturieren, 
Vorträge, in gewissem Sinne, die ändern, welche, die Methode 
Kursteilnehmer erlernen. Sie umfaßt Methoden für 
Kursneukonstruktion, Klassenzimmereinschätzung Techniken, Stufen des 
Lernens und Ziele in den allgemeine Ausbildung Kursen. Unter 
anderem wurde es, daß Kursteilnehmererfolg vorhersagbar ist, alle 
Kursteilnehmer profitiert vom aktiven Lernen gefunden, und Gruppe 
Arbeit ist wichtig.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette recherche d'adresses de présentation de 
PowerPoint sur les apprentissages de pensée et des étudiants et 
comment la plus grande connaissance de ces processus peut être 
employée pour structurer conférences en quelque sorte qui changeront
que les étudiants de voie apprennent. Elle couvre des méthodes
pour la nouvelle conception de cours, les techniques d'évaluation de 
salle de classe, les niveaux de l'étude et les buts en général des 
cours d'éducation. Entre autres, on l'a constaté que le 
succès d'étudiant est prévisible, tous les étudiants tirent 
bénéfice de l'étude active, et le travail de groupe est important.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta pesquisa dos endereços da apresentação de 
PowerPoint sobre os processos pensar e aprender dos estudantes e como 
o conhecimento aumentado destes processos pode ser usado estruturar 
lectures em uma maneira que mude os estudantes da maneira aprende. 
Cobre métodos para o redesign do curso, as técnicas da 
avaliação da sala de aula, os níveis da aprendizagem e os objetivos
em cursos da instrução geral. Entre outras coisas, 
encontrou-se que o sucesso do estudante é predictable, todos os 
estudantes beneficia-se da aprendizagem ativa, e o trabalho do grupo 
é importante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa ricerca di indirizzi di presentazione del 
PowerPoint sugli apprendimento pensanti e degli allievi e come la 
conoscenza aumentata di questi processi può essere usata per 
strutturare conferenze in un modo che cambierà gli allievi di modo 
impara. Riguarda i metodi per la riprogettazione di corso, le 
tecniche di valutazione dell'aula, i livelli di imparare e gli 
obiettivi nei corsi di istruzione generale. Tra l'altro, è 
stato trovato che il successo dell'allievo è prevedibile, tutti gli 
allievi trae beneficio dall'imparare attivo ed il lavoro de gruppo è 
importante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η παρουσίαση PowerPoint εξετάζει την έρευνα 
για τις διαδικασίες σκέψης και εκμάθησης των σπουδαστών και πώς η
αυξανόμενη γνώση αυτών των διαδικασιών μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί 
για να κτίσει τις διαλέξεις με έναν τρόπο που θα αλλάξει τους 
σπουδαστές τρόπων μάθετε. Καλύπτει τις μεθόδους για τον 
επανασχεδιασμό σειράς μαθημάτων, τις τεχνικές αξιολόγησης των 
τάξεων, τα επίπεδα εκμάθησης και τους στόχους στις σειρές 
μαθημάτων γενικής εκπαίδευσης. Μεταξύ άλλων, διαπιστώθηκε 
ότι η επιτυχία σπουδαστών είναι προβλέψιμη, όλοι οι σπουδαστές 
ωφελούνται από την ενεργό εκμάθηση, και η εργασία ομάδας είναι 
σημαντική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta investigación de los direccionamientos de la 
presentación de PowerPoint sobre los procesos del pensamiento y de 
aprendizaje de estudiantes y cómo el conocimiento creciente de estos 
procesos se puede utilizar para estructurar las conferencias de una 
manera que cambie los estudiantes de la manera aprende. Cubre 
los métodos para el reajuste del curso, las técnicas del gravamen de
la sala de clase, los niveles de aprender y las metas en cursos de la 
educación general. Entre otras cosas, fue encontrado que el 
éxito del estudiante es fiable, todos los estudiantes beneficia de 
aprender activo, y el trabajo del grupo es importante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID STEER
FN:DAVID STEER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201581</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106735</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/evaluating-how-our-students-think-and-learn-research-results-from-the-trenches</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
