<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107900</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107900</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202821</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Everyday People Fight for Everyday Rights</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Täglicher Leute-Kampf für tägliche Rechte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lutter journalier de personnes pour des droits 
journaliers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Luta diária dos povos para direitas diárias</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lotta giornaliere della gente per i diritti 
giornalieri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι καθημερινοί άνθρωποι παλεύουν για τα καθημερινά 
δικαιώματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lucha diaria de la gente para las derechas 
diarias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson, students will learn that the Civil Rights Movement, while led by many great individuals, was primarily a movement of everyday people. They will then put that knowledge of the past into practice and participate in their own Civil Rights March. The culminating activity is a multimedia presentation that, depending on which course, can be aimed at non-citizens outlining what civil rights are and how all Americans gained those rights through the actions of these everyday people.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion erfahren Kursteilnehmer, daß 
die Zivilrecht-Bewegung, während durch viele große Einzelpersonen 
führte, hauptsächlich eine Bewegung der täglichen Leute war. 
Sie dann setzen sich daß Wissen der Vergangenheit in Praxis und
nehmen an ihren eigenen Zivilrechten März teil. Die 
kulminierende Aktivität ist eine Multimediadarstellung, die, 
abhängig von dem Kurs, angestrebtes Nichtbürgerumreißen sein kann, 
was Zivilrechte sind und wie alle Amerikaner jene Rechte durch die 
Tätigkeiten dieser täglichen Leute gewannen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon, les étudiants apprendront que 
le mouvement de droits civiques, tandis que menait par beaucoup de 
grands individus, était principalement un mouvement des personnes 
journalières. Ils alors mettront que la connaissance du passé 
en pratique et participent à leurs propres droits civiques mars. 
L'activité culminante est une présentation de multimédia qui,
selon lequel le cours, peut être traçage des grandes lignes visé de
non-citoyens ce qui sont les droits civiques et comment tous les 
Américains ont gagné ces droites par les actions de ces personnes 
journalières.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição, os estudantes aprenderão que o 
movimento das direitas civis, quando conduziu por muitos indivíduos 
grandes, era primeiramente um movimento de povos diários. 
Então porã0 que conhecimento do passado na prática e 
participarão em suas próprias direitas civis março. A 
atividade culminando é uma apresentação dos multimedia que, 
dependendo de que o curso, pode ser esboçar visado dos non-citizens o
que as direitas civis são e como todos os americanos ganharam aquelas
direitas com as ações destes povos diários.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione, gli allievi impareranno che il 
movimento di diritti civili, mentre ha condotto da molti individui 
grandi, era soprattutto un movimento della gente giornaliere. 
Allora metteranno che conoscenza dell'esperienza in pratica e 
partecipano ai loro propri diritti civili marzo. L'attività di 
culminazione è una presentazione di multimedia che, secondo che il 
corso, può essere descrizione puntata su dei non-citizens che cosa i 
diritti civili sono e come tutti gli Americani hanno guadagnato quei 
diritti con le azioni di questa gente giornaliere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν ότι το 
Κίνημα αστικών δικαιωμάτων, ενώ οδηγείται από πολλά μεγάλα 
άτομα, ήταν πρώτιστα μια κυκλοφορία των καθημερινών ατόμων. 
Έπειτα θα βάλουν ότι γνώση του παρελθόντος σε εφαρμογή και
συμμετέχουν στα αστικά δικαιώματά τους Μάρτιος. Η 
καταλήγοντας δραστηριότητα είναι μια παρουσίαση πολυμέσων που, 
ανάλογα με το οποίο τη σειρά μαθημάτων, μπορεί να στοχεύσουν 
στους μη-πολίτες που περιγράφουν ποια αστικά δικαιώματα είναι και
πώς όλοι οι Αμερικανοί κέρδισαν εκείνα τα δικαιώματα μέσω των 
ενεργειών αυτών των καθημερινών ανθρώπων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección, los estudiantes aprenderán que 
el movimiento de las derechas civiles, mientras que condujo por muchos
grandes individuos, era sobre todo un movimiento de la gente diaria. 
Después pondrán que conocimiento del pasado en práctica y 
participan en las sus propias derechas civiles marcha. La 
actividad que culmina es una presentación de las multimedias que, 
dependiendo de que el curso, puede ser el contornear dirigido de los 
non-citizens cuáles las derechas civiles son y cómo todos los 
americanos ganaron las esas derechas con las acciones de esta gente 
diaria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JASON PERKINS
FN:JASON PERKINS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202821</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107900</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/everyday-people-fight-for-everyday-rights</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
