<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201362</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Annotating Change in Satellite Images</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Kommentieren der Änderung in den Satellitenbildern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Annotation du changement des images satellites</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Anotando a mudança em imagens satellite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Annotazione del cambiamento nelle immagini satelliti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: 
Σχολιασμός της αλλαγής στις δορυφορικές εικόνες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Anotación del cambio en imágenes basadas en los 
satélites</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This activity of the Earth Exploration Toolbook walks users through a technique for documenting change in before-and-after sets of satellite images. The technique can be used for any set of time-series images that are spatially registered to show the exact same area at the same scale. In the chapter, users examine three Landsat images of the Pearl River delta in southeastern China. In the images, users observe changes in land use over time, then identify and outline areas of new land that were created by dredging sediments from the river bottom. The final product is an annotated image that highlights new land and indicates when it was created.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Aktivität der Masse Erforschung Toolbook 
Wegbenutzer durch eine Technik für das Dokumentieren der Änderung 
innen vor-und-nach Sets der Satellitenbilder. Die Technik kann 
für irgendwie eingestellt worden von den Zeitfolgebildern verwendet 
werden, die räumlich registriert werden, um den gleichen Bereich an 
der gleichen Skala das genaue zu zeigen. Im Kapitel überprüfen
Benutzer drei Landsat Bilder des Perle Flußdreiecks in südöstlichem
China. In den Bildern beobachten Benutzer Änderungen in der 
Flächennutzung über Zeit, dann kennzeichnen und umreißen Bereiche 
des neuen Landes, die erstellt wurden, indem man Sedimente von der 
Flußunterseite ausbaggerte. Das abschließende Produkt ist ein 
angemerktes Bild, dem neues Land der Höhepunkte und anzeigt, als es 
hergestellt wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité des utilisateurs de promenades de 
Toolbook d'exploration de la terre par une technique pour documenter 
le changement dedans avant-et-après des ensembles d'images 
satellites. La technique peut être utilisée pour  réglé des 
images de série de temps qui sont dans l'espace enregistrées pour 
montrer à l'exact la même zone à la même échelle. Dans le 
chapitre, les utilisateurs examinent trois images de Landsat du delta 
de fleuve de perle en Chine du sud-est. Dans les images, les 
utilisateurs observent des changements d'utilisation de la terre avec 
le temps, puis identifient et tracent les grandes lignes des zones de 
la nouvelle terre qui ont été créées en draguant des sédiments du
bas de fleuve. Le produit final est une image annotée que la 
nouvelle terre de points culminants et indique quand elle a été 
créée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade dos usuários das caminhadas de 
Toolbook da exploração da terra com uma técnica para documentar a 
mudança dentro antes-e-após jogos de imagens satellite. A 
técnica pode ser usada para ajustado  das imagens do time-series que 
são registadas spatially para mostrar ao exato a mesma área na mesma
escala. No capítulo, os usuários examinam três imagens de 
Landsat do delta do rio da pérola em China do sudeste. Nas 
imagens, os usuários observam mudanças no uso de terra sobre o 
tempo, a seguir identificam e esboçam as áreas de terra nova que 
foram criadas dredging sedimentos do fundo do rio. O produto 
final é uma imagem anotada que a terra nova dos destaques e indique 
quando foi criada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività degli utenti delle camminate di 
Toolbook di esplorazione della terra con una tecnica per la 
documentazione del cambiamento dentro prima-e-dopo gli insiemi delle 
immagini satelliti. La tecnica può essere usata per affatto 
regolato delle immagini di serie cronologica che nello spazio sono 
registrate per mostrare l'esatto la stessa zona alla stessa scala. 
Nel capitolo, gli utenti esaminano tre immagini del Landsat del 
delta del fiume della perla in Cina del sud-est. Nelle immagini,
gli utenti osservano i cambiamenti nell'utilizzazione delle terre col 
tempo, quindi identificano e descrivono le zone di nuova terra che 
sono state create dragando i sedimenti dalla parte inferiore del 
fiume. Il prodotto finale è un'immagine annotata che la nuova 
terra di punti culminanti ed indica quando è stata creata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα των χρηστών περιπάτων Toolbook
γήινης εξερεύνησης μέσω μιας τεχνικής για την αλλαγή πριν 
από-και-μετά από τα σύνολα δορυφορικών εικόνων. Η τεχνική
μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για έθεσε καθόλου time-series των 
εικόνων που καταχωρούνται στο χώρο για να εμφανίσουν ακριβή ίδια
περιοχή στην ίδια κλίμακα. Στο κεφάλαιο, οι χρήστες 
εξετάζουν τρεις εικόνες Landsat του δέλτα ποταμών 
μαργαριταριών στη νοτιοανατολική Κίνα. Στις εικόνες, οι 
χρήστες παρατηρούν τις αλλαγές σε χρήση εδάφους κατά τη 
διάρκεια του χρόνου, κατόπιν προσδιορίζουν και περιγράφουν τις 
περιοχές του νέου εδάφους που δημιουργήθηκαν με την εκβάθυνση των
ιζημάτων από το κατώτατο σημείο ποταμών. Το τελικό 
προϊόν είναι μια σχολιασμένη εικόνα που δίνει έμφαση στο νέο 
έδαφος και δείχνει πότε δημιουργήθηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad de los utilizadores de las caminatas
de Toolbook de la exploración de la tierra con una técnica para 
documentar el cambio adentro antes-y-despue's de los conjuntos de 
imágenes basadas en los satélites. La técnica se puede 
utilizar para  fijado de las imágenes del time-series que espacial se
colocan para mostrar al exacto la misma área en la misma escala. 
En el capítulo, los utilizadores examinan tres imágenes de 
Landsat del delta del río de la perla en China del sudeste. En 
las imágenes, los utilizadores observan cambios en utilización del 
suelo en un cierto plazo, después identifican y contornean las áreas
de la pista nueva que fueron creadas dragando los sedimentos del fondo
del río. El producto final es una imagen anotada que la pista 
nueva de los toques de luz e indica cuando fue creada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LUANN DAHLMAN
FN:LUANN DAHLMAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201362</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107423</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-annotating-change-in-satellite-images</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
