<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104773</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104773</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087332</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Religious Flame That Spread All Over Kentucky": Peter Cartwright Brings Evangelical Christianity to the West, 1801-04</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Eine Fromme Flamme, Die Alle Überschuß 
Kentucky" Verbritt: Peter Cartwright holt evangelisches 
Christentum zum Westen, 1801-04</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Une Flamme Religieuse Qui A écarté Partout Le 
Kentucky" : Peter Cartwright apporte le christianisme 
évangélique à l'ouest, 1801-04</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Uma Flama Religiosa Que Espalhasse Tudo Excesso 
Kentucky": Peter Cartwright traz o christianity evangelical ao 
oeste, 1801-04</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Una Fiamma Religiosa Che Ha sparso Dappertutto Il
Kentucky": Peter Cartwright porta il christianity evangelical 
all'ovest, 1801-04</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια θρησκευτική φλόγα που είναι εξαπλωμένη σε όλο το
Κεντάκυ": Θ*Πετερ Cartwright Brings Evangelical 
Christianity στη δύση, 1801-04</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Una Llama Religiosa Que Separó Todos Excedente 
Kentucky": Peter Cartwright trae el cristianismo evangélico al 
oeste, 1801-04</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the decades following the Revolution, a vast variety of choices appeared on the American religious landscape as an antiauthoritarian climate encouraged the formation of new democratic religious sects. The Baptists and Methodists were most adept in preaching to the new populist audience during these years of camp meeting revivalism. Peter Cartwright greatly contributed to the Methodists' success at introducing evangelical Protestantism to the new settlements of the West. Born in Virginia in 1785 and raised in Kentucky, Cartwright served as an itinerant minister bringing his version of enthusiastic religion to Kentucky, Tennessee, Indiana, and Ohio. This account of his conversion in the camp meeting of 1801 and his later career as a circuit rider comes from his autobiography, which was published in 1856.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Dekaden, die der Umdrehung folgen, erschien
eine beträchtliche Vielzahl von Wahlen auf der amerikanischen frommen
Landschaft, während ein antiauthoritarian Klima die Anordnung der 
neuen demokratischen frommen sects anregte. Die Baptisten und 
die Methodisten waren beim Predigen zu den neuen Volkspublikum 
während dieser Jahre von Lagersitzung revivalism am geschicktesten. 
Peter Cartwright trug groß zu den Methodisten den Erfolg am 
Einführen von von evangelischem Protestantism zu den neuen Regelungen
des Westens bei. Getragen in Virginia 1785 und in Kentucky 
angehoben, diente Cartwright als reisender Minister, der seine Version
der enthusiastischen Religion nach Kentucky, Tennessee, Indiana und 
Ohio holt. Dieses Konto seiner Konvertierung in der Lagersitzung
von 1801 und seiner neueren Karriere als Stromkreismitfahrer kommt von
seiner Autobiographie, die 1856 veröffentlicht wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les décennies suivant la révolution, une 
vaste variété de choix est apparue sur l'horizontal religieux 
américain pendant qu'un climat antiauthoritarian encourageait la 
formation de nouveaux sects religieux démocratiques. Les 
baptistes et les méthodistes étaient les plus versés dans la 
prédication aux nouvelles assistances populistes pendant ces années 
de revivalism de réunion de camp. Peter Cartwright a 
considérablement contribué aux méthodistes le succès à présenter
le Protestantisme évangélique aux nouveaux règlements de l'ouest. 
Soutenu en Virginie en 1785 et augmenté au Kentucky, 
Cartwright a servi de ministre ambulant apportant sa version de 
religion enthousiaste au Kentucky, au Tennessee, en Indiana, et en 
Ohio. Ce compte de sa conversion lors de la réunion de camp de 
1801 et de sa carrière postérieure en tant que cavalier de circuit 
vient de son autobiographie, qui a été éditée en 1856.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas décadas que seguem a volta, uma variedade 
vasta das escolhas apareceu na paisagem religiosa americana enquanto 
um clima antiauthoritarian incentivou a formação de sects religiosos
democráticos novos. Os baptists e os methodists eram os mais 
peritos em preaching às audiências populist novas durante estes anos
do revivalism da reunião do acampamento. Peter Cartwright 
contribuiu extremamente aos methodists' o sucesso em introduzir 
Protestantism evangelical aos estabelecimentos novos do oeste. 
Carregado em Virgínia em 1785 e levantado em Kentucky, 
Cartwright serviu como um ministro itinerant que traz sua versão da 
religião entusiástica a Kentucky, a Tennessee, a Indiana, e a Ohio. 
Este cliente de sua conversão na reunião do acampamento de 
1801 e de sua carreira mais atrasada como um cavaleiro do circuito vem
de seu autobiography, que foi publicado em 1856.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nelle decadi che seguono la rivoluzione, una 
varietà ampia di scelte è comparso sul paesaggio religioso americano
mentre un clima antiauthoritarian ha consigliato alla formazione di 
nuovi sects religiosi democratici. I Battisti ed i 
methodists erano più adept nella predica ai pubblici populistici 
nuovi durante questi anni del revivalism di riunione 
dell'accampamento. Peter Cartwright notevolmente ha contribuito 
ai methodists il successo a introdurre Protestantism evangelical ai 
nuovi stabilimenti dell'ovest. Sopportato nella Virginia in 1785
ed alzato nel Kentucky, Cartwright ha servito da ministro 
ambulante che porta la sua versione della religione entusiastica nel 
Kentucky, nel Tennessee, in Indiana e nell'Ohio. Questo cliente 
della sua conversione nella riunione dell'accampamento di 1801 e della
sua carriera successiva come rider del circuito viene dal suo 
autobiography, che è stato pubblicato in 1856.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις δεκαετίες μετά από την επανάσταση, μια απέραντη 
ποικιλία των επιλογών εμφανίστηκε στο αμερικανικό θρησκευτικό 
τοπίο δεδομένου ότι ένα antiauthoritarian κλίμα ενθάρρυνε το 
σχηματισμό των νέων δημοκρατικών θρησκευτικών sects. Το 
Baptists και το Methodists ήταν τα πιό έμπειροτα στο κήρυγμα
στο νέο λαϊκιστικό ακροατήριο κατά τη διάρκεια αυτών των ετών 
revivalism συνεδρίασης των στρατόπεδων. Θ*Πετερ 
Cartwright συνέβαλε πολύ στην επιτυχία του Methodists στην 
εισαγωγή του εβαγγελικού Προτεσταντισμού στις νέες τακτοποιήσεις 
της δύσης. Γεννημένος στη Βιρτζίνια το 1785 και αυξημένος
στο Κεντάκυ, cartwright εχρησίμευσε ως ένας πλανόδιος υπουργός
που φέρνει την έκδοση ενθουσιώδους θρησκείας του στο Κεντάκυ, το 
Tennessee, το Ινδιάνα, και το Οχάιο. Αυτός ο απολογισμός 
της μετατροπής του στη συνεδρίαση των στρατόπεδων 1801 και την 
πιό πρώην σταδιοδρομία του ως αναβάτη κυκλωμάτων προέρχεται από
την αυτοβιογραφία του, η οποία δημοσιεύθηκε το 1856.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las décadas que seguían la revolución, una 
variedad extensa de opciones apareció en el paisaje religioso 
americano mientras que un clima antiauthoritarian animó la formación
de nuevos sects religiosos democráticos. Los Bautista y los 
methodists eran los más peritos de la predicación a las nuevas 
audiencias populistas durante estos años del revivalism de la 
reunión del campo. Peter Cartwright contribuyó grandemente a 
los methodists el éxito en introducir Protestantism evangélico a los
nuevos establecimientos del oeste. Llevado en Virginia en 1785 y
levantado en Kentucky, Cartwright sirvió como ministro ambulante que 
traía su versión de la religión entusiástica a Kentucky, a 
Tennessee, a Indiana, y a Ohio. Esta cuenta de su conversión en
la reunión del campo de 1801 y de su carrera más última como jinete
del circuito viene de su autobiografía, que fue publicada en 1856.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087332</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104773</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-religious-flame-that-spread-all-over-kentucky-peter-cartwright-brings-evangelical-christianity-to-the-west-1801-04</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
