<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103635</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103635</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207133</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Korea: The Unfinished War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Korea: Der Unfertige Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Corée : La Guerre Non finie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Coreia: A Guerra Unfinished</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Corea: La Guerra Non finita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κορέα: Ο ατελής πόλεμος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Corea: La Guerra Inacabada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the forgotten war that almost led to World War III. When communist troops of North Korea crossed the 38th parallel on June 25, 1950, the U.S. and later the U.N. joined forces with South Korea to stop the invasion. The Soviet Union and China supported North Korea in the three-year war, which claimed 54,246 American lives. This website offers a radio documentary, interviews with veterans and historians, and information about integrating the military.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft den vergessenen Krieg, der fast zu 
Weltkrieg III führte. Als kommunistische Truppen von Nordkorea 
die 38th Ähnlichkeit an Juni 25 kreuzten, 1950, die VEREINIGTEN 
STAATEN und später verband das U.N. Kräfte mit Südkorea, um die 
Invasion zu stoppen. Der Sowjet-Anschluß und das Porzellan 
unterstützten Nordkorea im dreijährigen Krieg, der 54.246 
amerikanische Lebensdauern behauptete. Diese Web site bietet 
einen Radiodokumentarfilm, Interviews mit Veteranen und Historiker und
Informationen über die Integrierung des Militärs an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine la guerre oubliée qui a presque mené à 
la guerre mondiale III. Quand les troupes communistes de la 
Corée du nord ont croisé le trente-huitième parallèle juin 25,
1950, ETATS-UNIS et plus tard l'U.N. a joint des forces avec la Corée
Du sud pour arrêter l'invasion. Union Soviétique et la Chine 
ont supporté la Corée du nord dans la guerre de trois ans, qui a
réclamé les 54.246 vies américaines. Ce site Web offre un 
documentaire par radio, des entrevues avec des vétérans et des 
historiens, et des informations sur intégrer les militaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina a guerra esquecida que conduziu quase à 
guerra de mundo III. Quando as tropas comunistas de Coreia norte
cruzaram a 38th paralela junho em 25, 1950, os ESTADOS UNIDOS e mais 
tarde o U.N. juntou forças com Coreia sul para parar a invasão. 
A Soviete-união e a China suportaram Coreia norte na guerra 
three-year, que reivindicou 54.246 vidas americanas. Este Web 
site oferece um documentary de rádio, entrevistas com veterans e 
historians, e informação sobre integrar as forças armadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina la guerra dimenticata che quasi ha 
condotto alla guerra mondiale III. Quando le truppe comuniste 
del Korea di Nord hanno attraversato il trentottesimo parallelo il 25 
giugno, 1950, STATI UNITI e più successivamente il U.N. ha unito le 
forze con la Corea del sud per arrestare l'invasione. 
L'Soviet-unione e la Cina hanno sostenuto il Korea di Nord nella 
guerra triennale, che ha esatto 54.246 vite americane. Questo 
Web site offre un documentary radiofonico, interviste con i veterani e
storici e le informazioni sull'integrata dei militari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τον ξεχασμένο πόλεμο που οδήγησε σχεδόν στον
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙΙ. Όταν τα κομμουνιστικά στρατεύματα της
βόρειας Κορέας διέσχισαν τον 38$ο παράλληλο στις 25 Ιουνίου 
..1950, οι ΗΠΑ και αργότερα τα Η.Ε ένωσαν τις δυνάμεις με τη 
Νότια Κορέα για να σταματήσουν την εισβολή. Η Σοβιετική 
Ένωση και η Κίνα υποστήριξαν τη βόρεια Κορέα στον τρίχρονο 
πόλεμο, ο οποίος απαίτησε 54.246 αμερικανικές ζωές. 
Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος προσφέρει ένα ραδιο ντοκιμαντέρ, τις 
συνεντεύξεις με τους παλαιμάχους και τους ιστορικούς, και τις 
πληροφορίες για την ενσωμάτωση των στρατιωτικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina la guerra olvidada que casi condujo a la 
guerra mundial III. Cuando las tropas comunistas de Corea del 
norte cruzaron el 38.o paralelo 25 de junio 1950, los de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS y el U.N. ensambló más adelante fuerzas con Corea del sur 
para parar la invasión. La Soviet-unio'n y la China utilizaron 
Corea del norte en la guerra de tres años, que demandó 54.246 vidas 
americanas. Este Web site ofrece un documentary de radio, las 
entrevistas con los veteranos y los historiadores, e información 
sobre integrar a los militares.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207133</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103635</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/korea-the-unfinished-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
