<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104504</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104504</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087325</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Nave and Self-Taught Artist": John Frazee Sculpts Daniel Webster, 1833</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Nave und ein Selbst-Unterichtskünstler": 
John Frazee Sculpts Daniel Webster, 1833</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un artiste de Nave et de art de l'auto-portrait-taught" 
: John Frazee Sculpts Daniel Webster, 1833</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um nave e um artista Self-Ensinado": John 
Frazee Sculpts Daniel Webster, 1833</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un nave e un artista Auto-Insegnato": John 
Frazee Sculpts Daniel Webster, 1833</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα Nave και ένας αυτοδίδακτος καλλιτέχνησ": 
Θ*Ιοχν Frazee Sculpts Daniel Webster, 1833</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un cubo y un artista Uno mismo-Enseñado": 
Juan Frazee Sculpts Daniel Webster, 1833</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many artists working in the decades after the American Revolution came from the ranks of artisans and mechanics. In a republic that dispensed with aristocratic patrons and royal academies, art came to be supported by a middling populace more interested in portraits than grand history painting. Sculpture in marble, time consuming and expensive, was even more remote than paints, and the new nation lacked grand palaces or mansions for display. John Frazee, born in Rahway, New Jersey in 1790, lacked the benefit of formal instruction but still progressed from carving lettering on gravestones to fashioning busts of the rich and famous. Without formal knowledge or the constraints of European customs, American-born and trained artist-artisans such as Frazee resorted to indigenous and ingenious solutions to the problems they faced in a commercializing society, such as Frazee's mechanical invention to transfer an image from painting to a marble bust.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Künstler, die in den Dekaden nach der 
amerikanischen Umdrehung arbeiten, kamen von den Rank der Handwerker 
und der Mechaniker. In einer Republik, die von aristokratischen 
Gönnern und königlichen Akademien Abstand nahm, kam kunst, durch 
eine Mittelproduktbevölkerung unterstützt zu werden, die mehr an 
Portraits als großartiger Geschichte Anstrich interessiert wurde. 
Skulptur im Marmor, zeitraubend und kostspielig, war sogar 
entfernt als Farben, und die neue Nation ermangelte großartige 
Paläste oder Villen für Bildschirmanzeige. John Frazee, 
getragen in Rahway, Neu-Jersey 1790, ermangelte, den Nutzen der 
formalen Anweisung aber kam noch vom Schnitzen der Beschriftung auf 
Grabsteinen bis zu umarbeitenbüsten vom reichen und das berühmt 
weiter. Ohne formales Wissen oder die Begrenzungen der 
europäischen Gewohnheiten, die Amerikanisch-getragenen und 
ausgebildeten Künstler-Handwerker wie Frazee griff auf die 
eingeborenen und scharfsinnigen Lösungen zu den Problemen, die sie in
einer in den Handel bringengesellschaft gegenüberstellten, wie 
Frazees mechanischer Erfindung, um ein Bild vom Malen auf eine 
Marmorbüste zu übertragen zurück.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup d'artistes travaillant dans les 
décennies après la révolution américaine sont venus des rangs des 
artisans et de la mécanique. Dans une république qui s'est 
passée des patrons aristocratiques et des académies royales, l'art 
est venu pour être supporté par une foule d'issue de blé 
davantage intéressée aux verticales que la peinture grande 
d'histoire. La sculpture en marbre, long et cher, était bien 
plus à distance que des peintures, et la nouvelle nation a manqué 
des palais ou des manoirs grands pour l'affichage. John Frazee, 
soutenu dans Rahway, New Jersey en 1790, a manqué de l'avantage de 
l'instruction formelle mais a toujours progressé de découper le 
lettrage sur des pierres tombales aux bustes de mode du riche et 
célèbre. Sans connaissance formelle ou artiste-artisans 
Américain-soutenus et qualifiés des contraintes des coutumes 
européennes, tels que Frazee a recouru aux solutions indigènes et 
ingénieuses aux problèmes qu'ils ont fait face dans une société de
commercialisation, telle que l'invention mécanique de Frazee pour 
transférer une image à partir de peindre à un buste de marbre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos artistas que trabalham nas décadas após a
volta americana vieram dos Rank dos artisans e dos mecânicos. 
Em uma república que dispensasse com patrons aristocratic e 
academies reais, a arte veio ser suportada por um populace do middling
interessado mais nos retratos do que a pintura grande do history. 
O sculpture no mármore, tempo que consome e caro, era mesmo 
mais remoto do que pinturas, e a nação nova faltou palácios ou 
mansions grandes para o indicador. John Frazee, carregado em 
Rahway, Novo-Jersey em 1790, faltou o benefício da instrução formal
mas progrediu ainda de carving o lettering em gravestones aos bustos 
formando do rico e famoso. Sem conhecimento formal ou os 
artista-artist-artisans Americano-carregados e treinados dos 
confinamentes de costumes europeus, tais como Frazee recorreu às 
soluções indígenas e ingenious aos problemas que enfrentaram em uma
sociedade commercializing, tal como a invenção mecânica de Frazee 
para transferir uma imagem de pintar a um busto de mármore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti artisti che lavorano nelle decadi dopo la 
rivoluzione americana sono venuto dalla truppa degli artigianale 
e dei meccanici. In una repubblica che ha erogato con i patroni 
aristocratic e le accademie reali, l'arte è venuto essere sostenuta
da un populace della semola di più interessato ai ritratti che la
grande pittura di storia. La scultura in marmo, che richiede 
tempo e costoso, era ancor più a distanza che le vernici e la nuova 
nazione difettava di grandi palazzi o mansions per visualizzazione. 
John Frazee, sopportato in Rahway, Nuovo-Jersey in 1790, 
difettava del beneficio di istruzione convenzionale ma ancora ha 
progredito dalla scultura dell'iscrizione sui gravestones ai busti di 
moda del ricco e famoso. Senza conoscenza convenzionale o 
artista-artigianale Americano-sopportati ed addestrati di vincoli 
delle abitudini europee, quale Frazee ha ricorso alle soluzioni 
indigene ed ingenious ai problemi ch'hanno affrontato in una società 
di commercializzazione, quale l'invenzione meccanica del Frazee per 
trasferire un'immagine dalla verniciatura ad un busto di marmo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί καλλιτέχνες που εργάζονται στις δεκαετίες μετά
από την αμερικανική επανάσταση προήλθαν από τις τάξεις των 
artisans και τους μηχανικούς. Σε μια δημοκρατία που 
διένειμε με τους αριστοκρατικούς προστάτες και τις βασιλικές 
ακαδημίες, η τέχνη ήρθε να υποστηριχθεί από έναν λαό 
εμπορευμάτων πιό ενδιαφερόμενο στα πορτρέτα από τη μεγάλη 
ζωγραφική ιστορίας. Το γλυπτό στο μάρμαρο, χρόνος που 
καταναλώνει και ακριβός, ήταν ακόμα πιό απομακρυσμένο από τα 
χρώματα, και το νέο έθνος στερήθηκε τα μεγάλα παλάτια ή τα 
μέγαρα για την παρουσίαση. Θ*Ιοχν Frazee, γεννημένο σε 
Rahway, Νιου Τζέρσευ! το 1790, στερήθηκε το όφελος της 
επίσημης οδηγίας αλλά ακόμα προχώρησε από την εγγραφή χάραξης 
στις ταφόπετρες στη διαμόρφωση των αποτυχιών πλούσιος και 
διάσημος. Χωρίς την επίσημη γνώση ή τους περιορισμούς του 
ευρωπαϊκού τελωνείου, ο αμερικανικός-γεννημένος και 
εκπαιδευμένος καλλιτέχνης -καλλιτέχνης-αρτησανς όπως Frazee 
προσέφυγε στις γηγενείς και έξυπνες λύσεις στα προβλήματα που 
αντιμετώπισαν σε μια εμπορευματοποιώντας κοινωνία, όπως η 
μηχανική εφεύρεση Frazee για να μεταφέρουν μια εικόνα από τη 
ζωγραφική σε μια μαρμάρινη αποτυχία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos artistas que trabajaban en las décadas 
después de la revolución americana vinieron de las filas de 
artesanos y de mecánicos. En una república que dispensó con 
los patrón aristocráticos y las academias reales, el arte vino ser 
utilizado por un populacho del acemite interesado más en retratos que
la pintura magnífica de la historia. La escultura en mármol, 
desperdiciador de tiempo y costoso, estaba aún más alejada que las 
pinturas, y la nueva nación faltó palacios o las mansiones 
magníficos para la visualización. Juan Frazee, nacido en 
Rahway, Nuevo-Jersey en 1790, faltó la ventaja de la instrucción 
formal pero todavía progresó de tallar el deletreado en los 
gravestones a los bustos que formaban el del rico y famoso. Sin 
conocimiento formal o artista-artesanos Americano-llevados y 
entrenados de los apremios de costumbres europeos, tales como Frazee 
recurrió a las soluciones indígenas e ingeniosas a los problemas que
hicieron frente en una sociedad de comercialización, tal como 
invención mecánica de Frazee para transferir una imagen de pintar a 
un busto de mármol.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087325</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104504</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-nave-and-self-taught-artist-john-frazee-sculpts-daniel-webster-1833</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
