<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105126</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105126</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211259</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Association Homepage: U.S. Climate at a Glance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationales ozeanisches und atmosphärisches 
Verbindung homepage: VEREINIGTE STAATEN Klima auf einen Blick</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Homepage océanique et atmosphérique national 
d'association : Climat des ETATS-UNIS d'un coup d'oeil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Homepage oceanic e atmosférico nacional da 
associação: Clima de ESTADOS UNIDOS duma olhada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Homepage oceanico ed atmosferico nazionale di 
associazione: Clima degli STATI UNITI con un'occhiata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ωκεάνεια και ατμοσφαιρική αρχική σελίδα 
ένωσης: ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ Κλίμα σε μια ματιά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Homepage oceánico y atmosférico nacional de la 
asociación: Clima de ESTADOS UNIDOS de un vistazo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Association (NOAA) provides climate data for the United States. These data are primarily intended for the study of climate variability and change. Whenever possible, observations have been adjusted to account for the artificial effects introduced into the climate record by factors such as instrument changes, station relocations, observer practice changes and urbanization. As a result, some values available on this site differ from the official observations. Users can access national, regional, statewide and city mean temperature and precipitation data. This is a helpful site for anyone looking for temperature of precipitation data.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die nationale ozeanische und atmosphärische 
Verbindung (NOAA) stellt Klimadaten für die Vereinigten Staaten zur 
Verfügung. Diese Daten sind hauptsächlich für die Studie der 
Klimaveränderlichkeit bestimmt und ändern. Wann immer 
möglich, Beobachtungen justiert worden sind, um die künstlichen 
Effekte zu erklären, die in den Klimasatz durch Faktoren wie 
Instrumentänderungen, Stationverschiebungen, 
Beobachterpraxisänderungen und Verfeinerung eingeführt werden. 
Infolgedessen bewertet einiges vorhandenes auf dieser Site sich 
unterscheiden von den amtlichen Beobachtungen. Benutzer können 
nationales, auf regionales zugreifen, national und 
Stadtmitteltemperatur und Niederschlagdaten. Dieses ist eine 
nützliche Site für jedermann, das nach Temperatur von 
Niederschlagdaten sucht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'association océanique et atmosphérique 
nationale (NOAA) fournit des données de climat pour les Etats-Unis. 
Ces données sont principalement destinées pour l'étude de la 
variabilité de climat et changent. Autant que possible, des 
observations ont été ajustées pour expliquer les effets artificiels
présentés dans l'enregistrement de climat par des facteurs tels que 
des changements d'instrument, des réadressages de station, des 
changements de pratique en matière d'observateur et l'urbanisation. 
En conséquence, une partie évalue disponible sur ce site 
diffère des observations officielles. Les utilisateurs peuvent 
accéder à national, à régional, la température par état et de 
ville et des données moyennes de précipitation. C'est un site 
utile pour n'importe qui qui recherche la température des données de
précipitation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A associação oceanic e atmosférica nacional 
(NOAA) fornece dados do clima para os estados unidos. Estes 
dados são pretendidos primeiramente para o estudo do variability do 
clima e mudam. Sempre que possível, as observações foram 
ajustadas para esclarecer os efeitos artificiais introduzidos no 
registro do clima por fatores tais como mudanças do instrumento, 
relocations da estação, mudanças da prática do observador e 
urbanization. Em conseqüência, algum avalia disponível neste 
local difere das observações oficiais. Os usuários podem 
alcançar nacional, regional, temperatura statewide e da cidade e 
dados médios da precipitação. Este é um local útil para 
qualquer um que procura a temperatura de dados da precipitação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'associazione oceanica ed atmosferica nazionale 
(NOAA) fornisce i dati di clima per unito Dichiara. 
Questi dati soprattutto sono intesi per lo studio su 
variabilità di clima e cambiano. Per quanto possibile, le 
osservazioni sono state registrate per rappresentare gli effetti 
artificiali introdotti nel record di clima dai fattori quali i 
cambiamenti dello strumento, le rilocazioni della stazione, i 
cambiamenti di pratica dell'osservatore e l'urbanizzazione. Di 
conseguenza, alcuno stima disponibile su questo luogo differisce da 
dalle osservazioni ufficiali. Gli utenti possono accedere a 
nazionale, a regionale, temperatura della città e per tutto lo stato 
e dati medi della precipitazione. Ciò è un luogo utile per 
chiunque che cerca la temperatura dei dati della precipitazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εθνική ωκεάνεια και ατμοσφαιρική ένωση (NOAA) 
παρ:έχω τα στοιχεία κλίματος για τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. 
Αυτά τα στοιχεία προορίζονται πρώτιστα για τη μελέτη της 
μεταβλητότητας και της αλλαγής κλίματος. Όποτε είναι 
δυνατόν, οι παρατηρήσεις έχουν ρυθμιστεί για να αποτελέσουν τα 
τεχνητά αποτελέσματα που εισάγονται στο αρχείο κλίματος από τους
παράγοντες όπως οι αλλαγές οργάνων, οι επαναμεταθέσεις σταθμών, 
οι αλλαγές πρακτικής παρατηρητών και η αστικοποίηση. Κατά 
συνέπεια, μερικές τιμές διαθέσιμες σε αυτήν την περιοχή 
διαφέρουν από τις επίσημες παρατηρήσεις. Οι χρήστες 
μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση σε εθνικό, περιφερειακός, σε εθνικό 
επίπεδο και η πόλη σημαίνει τα στοιχεία θερμοκρασίας και πτώσης.
Αυτό είναι μια χρήσιμη περιοχή για καθεμία που ψάχνει τη 
θερμοκρασία των στοιχείων πτώσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La asociación oceánica y atmosférica nacional 
(NOAA) proporciona a los datos del clima para los Estados Unidos. 
Estos datos se piensan sobre todo para el estudio de la 
variabilidad del clima y cambian. Siempre que sea posible, las 
observaciones se hayan ajustado para explicar los efectos artificiales
introducidos en el expediente del clima por factores tales como 
cambios del instrumento, realocaciones de la estación, cambios de la 
práctica del observador y urbanización. Consecuentemente, algo
valora disponible en este sitio diferencia de las observaciones 
oficiales. Los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a nacional, a 
regional, temperatura a lo largo y ancho del estado y de la ciudad y 
los datos malos de la precipitación. Esto es un sitio 
provechoso para cualquier persona que busca la temperatura de los 
datos de la precipitación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211259</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105126</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-oceanic-and-atmospheric-association-homepage-u-s-climate-at-a-glance</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
