<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103973</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103973</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211775</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Public beliefs about Evolution and Creation.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Allgemeiner Glaube über Entwicklung und Kreation.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Croyance publique au sujet d'évolution et de 
création.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Opinião pública sobre a evolução e a 
criação.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Credenza pubblica circa sviluppo e la creazione.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημόσιες πεποιθήσεις για την εξέλιξη και τη 
δημιουργία.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Creencia pública sobre la evolución y la 
creación.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This online essay contains detailed statistics contrasting the number of scientists who are Young-Earth Creationists (5% or less) to the members of the American public who are Young Earth Creationists (about 50%). The article also offers other statistics regarding typical American's beliefs, internet surfers' beliefs and conservative Christians' beliefs about evolution.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Onlineversuch enthält die ausführlichen 
Statistiken, welche die Zahl Wissenschaftlern kontrastieren, die 
Jung-Masse Creationists (5% oder kleiner) zu den Bauteilen der 
amerikanischen Öffentlichkeit sind, die junge Masse Creationists sind
(ungefähr 50%). Der Artikel bietet auch andere Statistiken 
betreffend sind Glauben des typischen Amerikaners, Glauben der 
Internet Surfers' und Glauben der konservativen Christen über 
Entwicklung an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet essai en ligne contient des statistiques détaillées 
contrastant le nombre de scientifiques qui sont la Jeune-Terre 
Creationists (5% ou moins) aux membres du public américain qui sont 
la jeune terre Creationists (environ 50%). L'article offre 
également d'autres statistiques concernant la croyance de 
l'Américain typique, la croyance des internautes et la croyance des 
chrétiens conservateurs au sujet de l'évolution.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este essay em linha contem os statistics detalhados que 
contrastam o número dos cientistas que são Novo-Terra Creationists 
(5% ou menos) aos membros do público americano que são terra nova 
Creationists (aproximadamente 50%). O artigo oferece também 
outros statistics a respeito da opinião do americano típico, da 
opinião de surfers' de Internet e da opinião dos cristãos 
conservadores sobre a evolução.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo saggio in linea contiene le statistiche dettagliate
che contrappongono il numero di scienziati che sono Giovane-Terra 
Creationists (5% o di meno) ai membri del pubblico americano che sono 
terra giovane Creationists (circa 50%). L'articolo egualmente 
offre altre statistiche per quanto riguarda credenza dell'americano 
tipico, credenza dei surfers di Internet e credenza dei cristiani del 
conservatore circa sviluppo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σε απευθείας σύνδεση δοκίμιο περιέχει τις 
λεπτομερείς στατιστικές που αντιπαραβάλλουν τον αριθμό 
επιστημόνων που είναι νέος-γη Creationists (5% ή λιγότεροι)
στα μέλη του αμερικανικού κοινού που είναι νέα γη Creationists
(περίπου 50%). Το άρθρο προσφέρει επίσης άλλες 
στατιστικές σχετικά με τις πεποιθήσεις χαρακτηριστικού 
Αμερικανού, τις πεποιθήσεις των surfers Διαδικτύου και τις 
πεποιθήσεις των συντηρητικών Χριστιανών για την εξέλιξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ensayo en línea contiene la estadística detallada 
que pone en contraste el número de los científicos que son 
Joven-Tierra Creationists (el 5% o menos) a los miembros del público 
americano que son tierra joven Creationists (el cerca de 50%). 
El artículo también ofrece la otra estadística con respecto 
la creencia del americano típico, la creencia de las personas que 
practica surf de Internet y a la creencia de los cristianos 
conservadores sobre la evolución.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211775</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103973</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/public-beliefs-about-evolution-and-creation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
