<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104062</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104062</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086831</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Singing for Suffrage: A Yiddish Musical Dialogue</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Singen für Stimmrecht: Ein Yiddish 
Musikal-Dialog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chant pour le suffrage : Un Dialogue de 
Musical de Yiddish</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cantar para o suffrage: Um Diálogo Do 
Musical De Yiddish</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cantando per il suffrage: Un Dialogo Di 
Musical Di Yiddish</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τραγούδι για την ψήφο: Ένα γίντις μουσικό 
διαλογικό παράθυρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El cantar para el sufragio: Un Diálogo Del 
Musical De Yiddish</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1920, after more than seventy years of struggle, the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. While nineteenth-century suffrage campaigns gained partial voting rights for women in twenty states, beginning in 1910 the push for suffrage took on a new urgency under the National American Woman Suffrage Association (NAWSA) and the more radical National Woman's Party (NWP). Their campaigns reached wide audiences, in part because suffragists had learned to spread their messages through imaginative use of various media. Supporters held old-fashioned pageants and street parades as well as statewide tours, thanks to the relatively new technology of automobiles. "Der Sufferegetsky," a Yiddish suffrage song, illustrates yet another medium used in the campaign for women's enfranchisement. In the lyrics, a female suffragist imagined the days when women would be treated like people and men would do the cooking. Her male interlocutor glumly predicted that emancipated women would mistreat men. [English translation follows Yiddish.]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1920 nachdem mehr als siebzig Jahre Kampf, die 
19.änderung zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit Frauen das Recht 
bewilligte zu wählen. Während 19.-Jahrhundert Stimmrecht die 
gewonnenen teilweisen wählenden Rechte für Frauen in Zwanzig 
Zuständen wirbt, anfangend in 1910 nahm der Stoß für Stimmrecht auf
einer neuen Dringlichkeit unter der nationalen amerikanischen 
Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung (NAWSA) und der radikaleren nationalen 
Partei der Frau (NWP). Ihre Kampagnen erreichten breite 
Publikum, im Teil, weil suffragists erlernt hatten, ihre Meldungen 
durch phantasiereichen Gebrauch von verschiedenen Media zu verbreiten.
Verfechter hielten altmodische Pageants und Straße Paraden 
sowie Nationaltouren, dank die verhältnismäßig neue Technologie der
Automobile an. "Der Sufferegetsky," ein Yiddish Stimmrechtlied, 
veranschaulicht dennoch ein anderer Medium, der in der Kampagne für 
enfranchisement der Frauen verwendet wird. In den Lyriken
stellte sich ein weibliches suffragist die Tage vor, als Frauen wie 
Leute behandelt würden und Männer das Kochen tun würden. Ihr 
männlicher Interlocutor sagte glumly voraus, daß emanzipierte Frauen
Männer schlecht behandeln würden. [ englische Übersetzung 
folgt Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1920, après que plus de soixante-dix ans de 
lutte, le dix-neuvième amendement à la constitution des ETATS-UNIS 
ait accordé à des femmes la droite de voter. Tandis que le 
suffrage de dix-neuvième-siècle fait campagne droit de vote partiel 
gagné pour des femmes dans vingt états, commençant dans 1910 la 
poussée pour le suffrage a pris une nouvelle urgence sous 
l'association américaine nationale de suffrage de femme (NAWSA) et la
partie de la femme nationale plus radicale (NWP). Leurs 
campagnes ont atteint les assistances larges, en partie parce que les 
suffragettes avaient appris à écarter leurs messages par 
l'utilisation imaginative de divers medias. Les défenseurs ont 
tenu des reconstitutions historiques et des défilés démodés de rue
aussi bien que les excursions par état, grâce à la technologie 
relativement nouvelle des automobiles. "Der Sufferegetsky," une 
chanson de suffrage de Yiddish, illustre encore un autre support 
utilisé dans la campagne pour l'enfranchisement des femmes. 
Dans le lyrique, une suffragette féminine a imaginé les jours 
où des femmes seraient traitées comme des personnes et les hommes 
feraient la cuisine. Son interlocuteur mâle a d'un air triste 
prévu que les femmes émancipées maltraiteraient des hommes. [
la traduction en anglais suit Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1920, depois que mais de setenta anos do 
esforço, a décima nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
concedeu a mulheres a direita votar. Quando um suffrage de 
décimo-século fizer campanha as direitas votando parciais ganhas 
para mulheres em vinte estados, começando em 1910 o impulso para o 
suffrage fêz exame em um urgency novo sob a associação americana 
nacional do suffrage da mulher (NAWSA) e o partido da mulher nacional 
mais radical (NWP). Suas campanhas alcançaram audiências 
largas, na parte porque os suffragists tinham aprendido espalhar suas 
mensagens com o uso imaginative de vários media. Os supporters 
prenderam pageants e paradas old-fashioned da rua as.well.as as 
excursões statewide, agradecimentos à tecnologia relativamente nova 
dos automóveis. "Der Sufferegetsky," uma canção do suffrage 
de Yiddish, ilustra contudo um outro media usado na campanha para o 
enfranchisement das mulheres. Nos lyrics, um suffragist fêmea 
imaginou os dias em que as mulheres seriam tratadas como povos e os 
homens fariam cozinhar. Seu interlocutor masculino predisse 
glumly que as mulheres emancipated mistreat homens. [ a 
tradução inglesa segue Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1920, dopo che più di settanta anni di lotta, 
la diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI UNITI 
assegni a donne la destra votare. Mentre il suffrage di 
diciannovesimo-secolo fa una campagna diritti di voto parziali 
guadagnati per le donne in venti dichiara, cominciando in 1910 
la spinta per suffrage ha intrapreso una nuova urgenza sotto 
l'associazione americana nazionale di suffrage della donna (NAWSA) ed 
il partito della donna nazionale più radicale (NWP). Le loro 
campagne hanno raggiunto i pubblici larghi, in parte perché i 
suffragists avevano imparato spargere i loro messaggi con uso 
immaginativo di vari media. I sostenitori hanno tenuto gli 
spettacoli e le parate antiquati della via così come i giri in 
tutto lo stato, grazie alla tecnologia relativamente nuova delle 
automobili. "Der Sufferegetsky," una canzone di suffrage di 
Yiddish, illustra ancora un altro media usato nella campagna per il 
enfranchisement delle donne. Nei lyrics, un suffragist femminile
ha immaginato i giorni in cui le donne sarebbero curate come la gente 
e gli uomini farebbero la cottura. Il suo interlocutor maschio 
ha predetto glumly che le donne emancipated mistreat gli uomini. 
[ la traduzione in inglese segue Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1920, μετά από περισσότερο από εβδομήντα έτη 
προσπάθειας, τη δέκατη έννατη τροποποίηση στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
σύνταγμα που χορηγείται τις γυναίκες το δικαίωμα να ψηφίσει. 
Ενώ οι εκστρατείες ψήφου δέκατος-αιώνα κέρδισαν τα μερικά
δικαιώματα ψήφου για τις γυναίκες σε είκοσι κράτη, αρχίζοντας το
1910 η ώθηση για την ψήφο πήρε μια νέα επείγουσα ανάγκη κάτω
από την εθνική αμερικανική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών (NAWSA) και 
το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος περισσότερης ριζικής εθνικής γυναίκας 
(NWP). Οι εκστρατείες τους έφθασαν στα ευρέα ακροατήρια, 
εν μέρει επειδή suffragists είχαν μάθει να διαδίδουν τα 
μηνύματά τους μέσω της επινοητικής χρήσης των διάφορων μέσων. 
Οι υποστηρικτές κράτησαν τις ντεμοντέ παρελάσεις θεαμάτων 
και οδών καθώς επίσης και τους εθνικούς γύρους, χάρι στη 
σχετικά νέα τεχνολογία των αυτοκινήτων. "Der 
Sufferegetsky," ένα γίντις τραγούδι ψήφου, επεξηγεί ακόμα 
ένα μέσο που χρησιμοποιείται στην εκστρατεία για το 
enfranchisement των γυναικών. Στα λυρικά ποιήματα, 
θηλυκός suffragist φαντάστηκε τις ημέρες όταν θα θεραπεύονταν 
οι γυναίκες όπως τους ανθρώπους και οι άνδρες θα έκαναν το 
μαγείρεμα. Ο αρσενικός συνομιλητής της glumly πρόβλεψε 
ότι οι χειραφετημένες γυναίκες θα κακομεταχειρίζονταν τους 
άνδρες. [ Η αγγλική μετάφραση ακολουθεί γίντις. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1920, después de que más de setenta años de 
lucha, la diecinueveavo enmienda a la constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
concediera a mujeres la derecha de votar. Mientras que el 
sufragio del diecinueveavo-siglo hace campaña los derechos al voto 
parciales ganados para las mujeres en veinte estados, comenzando en 
1910 el empuje para el sufragio adquirió una nueva urgencia bajo la 
asociación americana nacional del sufragio de la mujer (NAWSA) y 
partido de la mujer nacional más radical (NWP). Sus campañas 
alcanzaron a audiencias anchas, en parte porque los suffragists 
habían aprendido separar sus mensajes con el uso imaginativo de 
varios media. Los partidarios llevaron a cabo desfiles y 
desfiles pasados de moda de la calle así como los viajes estatales, 
gracias relativamente a la nueva tecnología de automóviles. 
"Der Sufferegetsky," una canción del sufragio de Yiddish, 
ilustra otro media usado en la campaña para el enfranchisement de las
mujeres. En las líricas, un suffragist femenino imaginaba los 
días en que tratarían a las mujeres como la gente y los hombres 
harían cocinar. Su interlocutor masculino predijo sombrío que 
las mujeres emancipated mistreat a hombres. [ la traducción 
inglesa sigue Yiddish. ]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086831</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104062</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/singing-for-suffrage-a-yiddish-musical-dialogue</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
