<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103350</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103350</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086217</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Have You No Sense of Decency": The Army-McCarthy Hearings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"haben Sie Sie keine Richtung des Anstands": 
Die Armee-McCarthy Hörfähigkeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"ayez-vous aucun sens de décence" : Les 
Auditions d'Armée-McCarthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"tenha-o nenhum sentido do decency": Os 
Hearings Do Exército-McCarthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"abbiali nessun senso di decency": Le Udienze
Dell'Esercito-McCarthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν σας έχει καμία αίσθηση της ευπρέπειασ": Οι 
ακροάσεις στρατός- McCarthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"téngale ningún sentido de la decencia": 
Las Audiencias Del Eje'rcito-McCarthy</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Anticommunist crusader Senator Joseph R. McCarthy stepped into national prominence on February 9, 1950, when he mounted an attack on President Truman's foreign policy agenda. McCarthy charged that the State Department and its Secretary, Dean Acheson, harbored "traitorous" Communists. McCarthy's apocalyptic rhetoric made critics hesitate before challenging him. Those accused by McCarthy faced loss of employment, damaged careers, and in many cases, broken lives. After the 1952 election, in which the Republican Party won control of Congress, McCarthy became chairman of the Senate Committee on Government Operations and its Subcommittee on Investigations. McCarthy then extended his targets to include numerous government agencies, in addition to the broadcasting and defense industries, universities, and the United Nations. After Secretary of the Army, Robert T. Stevens, refused to intercede to halt an overseas assignment for McCarthy's chief consultant, G. David Schine, who had been drafted, McCarthy's committee began a two-month investigation of the Army. Viewers saw the following dramatic encounters televised live as they occurred between McCarthy, Special Counsel for the Army Joseph N. Welch, Counselor for the Army John G. Adams, and the subcommittee's chief counsel, Roy Cohn. Although McCarthy's power declined sharply following the hearings and the Senate voted to condemn him a few months later, scholars disagree on whether McCarthy's appearance before a mass television audience caused his fall. Historians do, however, credit ABC-TV's decision to broadcast the hearings live, the only one to do so, with the network's rise to prominence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anticommunist Kreuzfahrer Senator Joseph R. 
McCarthy trat in nationalen Vorsprung an Februar 9, 1950, als er einen
Angriff auf Präsident Trumans Tagesordnung der fremden Politik 
einhing. McCarthy lud auf, daß die Zustand-Abteilung und seine 
Sekretärin, Dekan Acheson, "traitorous" Kommunisten beherbargen. 
McCarthys apokalyptische Rhetorik ließ Kritiker vor schwierigem
zögern er. Die, die von McCarthy beschuldigt wurden, stellten 
Verlust der Beschäftigung gegenüber, beschädigten die Karrieren und
in vielen Fällen, gebrochen Leben. Nach der Wahl 1952 in der 
die Republikanische Partei Steuerung des Kongresses gewann, stand McCarthy 
Vorsitzendem des Senat-Ausschusses für Regierung Operationen und 
seiner Unterausschusses auf Untersuchungen. McCarthy dehnte dann
seine Ziele aus, um zahlreiche Regierungsagenturen, zusätzlich zu den
Sendung und Verteidigungindustrien, Universitäten und die Nationen zu
enthalten. Nach Minister fuer der Armee, lehnte Robert T. 
Stevens ab, zu intervenieren, um eine Überseeanweisung für McCarthys
Hauptberater, G. David Schine, das anzuhalten gezeichnet worden war, 
Ausschuß McCarthys anfing eine zweimonatige Untersuchung der Armee. 
Projektoren sahen das folgendes drastisches Treffen im Fernsehen
übertragene Phasen, während sie zwischen McCarthy, spezieller 
Ratschlag für die Armee Joseph N. Welch, Ratgeber für die Armee John
G. Adams und der Hauptberater der Unterausschusses auftraten, Roy 
Cohn. Obgleich die Energie McCarthys, die scharf nach den 
Hörfähigkeiten und dem Senat gesunken wurde, wählte, um ihn einige 
Monate später zu verurteilen,SIND Gelehrte an anderer Meinung, ob 
Aussehen McCarthys vor einem Massenfernsehenpublikum seinen Fall 
verursachte. Historiker schreiben jedoch Entscheidung 
ABC-Fernsehapparates gut, um die Hörfähigkeiten zu übertragen 
leben, das einzige, um, mit dem Anstieg des Netzes zum Vorsprung so zu
tun.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le sénateur Joseph R. McCarthy de croisé 
d'Anticommunist a fait un pas dans la proéminence nationale février 
9, 1950, quand il a monté une attaque à l'ordre du jour de politique
étrangère du Président Truman's. McCarthy a chargé que le 
service d'état et son secrétaire, doyen Acheson, ont hébergé les 
communistes "déloyaux". La rhétorique apocalyptique de 
McCarthy a incité des critiques à hésiter avant provocant il. 
Ceux accusés par McCarthy ont fait face à la perte d'emploi, 
ont endommagé des carrières, et dans beaucoup de cas, cassées les 
vies. Après l'élection 1952, dans laquelle la partie 
républicaine a gagné la commande du congrès, McCarthy est allé 
bien au Président du comité de sénat des exécutions de 
gouvernement et de son sous-comité sur des investigations. 
McCarthy a alors étendu ses cibles pour inclure de nombreux 
organismes gouvernementaux, en plus des industries de radiodiffusion 
et de défense, universités, et les Nations Unies. Après le 
secrétaire de l'armée, Robert T. Stevens, a refusé d'intervenir 
pour stopper une affectation d'outre-mer pour le consultant en 
matière en chef de McCarthy, G. David Schine, qui avait été 
dessiné, le comité de McCarthy a commencé une recherche de deux 
mois sur l'armée. Les visualisateurs ont vu le de phase 
télévisé par rencontre excessive suivante pendant qu'ils se 
produisaient entre McCarthy, avocat-conseil spécial pour l'armée 
Joseph N. Welch, conseiller pour l'armée John G. Adams, et 
l'avocat-conseil en chef du sous-comité, Roy Cohn. Bien que la 
puissance de McCarthy diminuée brusquement après les auditions et le
sénat ait voté pour le condamner quelques mois plus tard, les 
disciples sont en désaccord en fonction si l'aspect de McCarthy 
devant une assistance de masse de télévision a causé sa chute. 
Les historiens , cependant, la décision du degré de solvabilité ABC- pour
annoncer les auditions vivent, les seules pour faire ainsi, avec 
l'élévation du réseau à la proéminence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O senator Joseph R. McCarthy do cruzado de 
Anticommunist pisou no prominence nacional fevereiro em 9, 1950, 
quando montou um ataque na agenda da política extrangeira do 
presidente Truman. McCarthy carregou que o departamento do 
estado e sua secretária, decano Acheson, abrigaram comunistas 
"traitorous". O rhetoric apocalyptic de McCarthy fêz críticos 
hesitate antes de challenging ele. Aqueles acusados por McCarthy
enfrentaram a perda do emprego, carreiras danificadas, e em muitas 
caixas, quebradas vidas. Após a eleição 1952, em que o 
partido republicano ganhou o controle do congress, McCarthy assentou 
bem no presidente do comitê do senate em operações do governo e de 
sua subcomissão em investigações. McCarthy estendeu então 
seus alvos para incluir agências de governo numerosas, além às 
indústrias da transmissão e da defesa, às universidades, e às 
nações unidas. Após a secretária do exército, Robert T. 
Stevens, recusou interceder para parar uma atribuição ultramarina 
para o consultante principal de McCarthy, G. David Schine, que tinha 
sido esboçado, comitê de McCarthy começou uma investigação 
two-month do exército. Os visores viram dramático o vivo 
televised seguinte encontro enquanto ocorreram entre McCarthy, 
conselho especial para o exército Joseph N. Welch, counselor para o 
exército John G. Adams, e conselho principal da subcomissão, Roy 
Cohn. Embora a potência de McCarthy declinada agudamente depois
dos hearings e do senate vote para condemn o alguns meses mais tarde, 
os scholars discordam sobre se a aparência de McCarthy antes de uma 
audiência maciça da televisão causou sua queda. Os 
historians, entretanto, creditam a decisão de ABC-Tevê para 
transmitir os hearings vivem, único para fazer assim, com a ascensão
da rede ao prominence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il senatore Joseph R. McCarthy del crociato di 
Anticommunist ha fatto un passo nella protuberanza nazionale il 9 
febbraio 1950, quando ha montato un attacco all'ordine del giorno di 
politica straniera del presidente Truman. McCarthy si è 
caricato che State Department e la relativa segretaria, il decano Acheson, 
harbored i comunisti "traitorous". La retorica apocalyptic del 
McCarthy ha incitato i critici ad esitare prima di challenging lui. 
Quelli accusati da McCarthy hanno affrontato la perdita di 
occupazione, hanno danneggiato le carriere ed in molti casi, rotte 
vite. Dopo l'elezione 1952, in cui il partito Repubblicano ha 
vinto il controllo del congresso, McCarthy ha stato bene al presidente
del comitato del senato dei funzionamenti di governo e del relativo 
sottocomitato sulle indagini. McCarthy allora ha esteso i suoi 
obiettivi per includere gli enti governativi numerosi, oltre che le 
industrie della difesa e di broadcasting, le università e le Nazioni 
Unite. Dopo la segretaria dell'esercito, Robert T. Stevens, ha 
rifiutato di intervenire per fermare un'assegnazione d'oltremare per 
il consulente in materia principale del McCarthy, G. David Schine, che
era stato disegnato, comitato del McCarthy ha cominciato un'indagine 
di due mesi sull'esercito. I visori hanno visto drammatico il in
tensione teletrasmesso seguente incontro mentre si sono presentati fra
McCarthy, consulente legale speciale per l'esercito Joseph N. Welch, 
counselor per l'esercito John G. Adams ed il consulente legale 
principale del sottocomitato, Roy Cohn. Anche se l'potenza del 
McCarthy ribassante acutamente dopo le udienze ed il senato ha votato 
per condannarla alcuni mesi più successivamente, gli eruditi non sono
d'accordo sopra se l'apparenza del McCarthy prima di un pubblico 
totale della televisione ha causato la sua caduta. Gli storici, 
tuttavia, accreditano la decisione della ABC-TV per trasmettere per 
radio le udienze vivono, quella unica per fare così, con l'aumento 
della rete alla protuberanza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αντικομμουνιστής σταυροφόρος γερουσιαστής Joseph 
R. McCarthy περπάτησε στην εθνική προεξοχή στις 9 
Φεβρουαρίου ..1950, όταν επικόλλησε μια επίθεση στην ημερήσια 
διάταξη εξωτερικής πολιτικής Προέδρου Truman's. McCarthy χρέωσε ότι το υπουργείο εξωτερικών και ο γραμματέας 
του, Dean Acheson, οι "προδοτικοί" κομμουνιστές. McCarthy's η αποκαλυπτική ρητορική που γίνεται τους κριτικούς 
διστάζει πρίν προκαλεί τον. Εκείνοι που κατηγορήθηκαν από 
McCarthy αντιμετώπισαν την απώλεια απασχόλησης, έβλαψαν τις 
σταδιοδρομίες, και σε πολλές περιπτώσεις, που έσπασαν ζωές. 
Μετά από την εκλογή του 1952, στην οποία το δημοκρατικό 
κόμμα κέρδισε τον έλεγχο του συνεδρίου, McCarthy έγινε 
πρόεδρος της Επιτροπής Συγκλήτου των κυβερνητικών διαδικασιών και
της υποεπιτροπής του στις έρευνες. McCarthy επέκτεινε 
έπειτα τους στόχους του για να περιλάβει τις πολυάριθμες 
κυβερνητικές αντιπροσωπείες, εκτός από τις βιομηχανίες 
ραδιοφωνικής αναμετάδοσης και υπεράσπισης, τα πανεπιστήμια, και τα
Ηνωμένα Έθνη. Μετά από το γραμματέα του στρατού, Robert
T. Stevens, αρνήθηκε να παρεμβει για να σταματήσει μια 
υπερπόντια ανάθεση για McCarthy's προϊστάμενος το σύμβουλο, Γ. 
Δαβίδ Schine, που είχε συνταχθεί, επιτροπή McCarthy's 
άρχισε μια δίμηνη έρευνα για το στρατό. Οι εμφανίσεις 
εβλέίδαν τις ακόλουθες δραματικές συγκρούσεις που 
μεταδόθηκαν ζωντανές όπως εμφανίστηκαν μεταξύ McCarthy, 
ειδική συμβουλή για το στρατό Joseph N. Welch, σύμβουλος 
για το στρατό John G. Adams, και η υποεπιτροπή συμβουλεύει
προϊστάμενος, Roy Cohn. Αν και η δύναμη McCarthy's 
σημείωσε απότομη κάμψη μετά από τις ακροάσεις και τη Σύγκλητο 
που ψηφίστηκαν για να τον καταδικάσει λίγους μήνες αργότερα, οι 
μελετητές διαφωνούν εάν η εμφάνιση McCarthy's πριν από ένα 
ακροατήριο μαζικής τηλεόρασης προκάλεσε την πτώση του. Οι 
ιστορικοί, εντούτοις, πιστώνουν την απόφαση της αψθ-TV να 
μεταδώσουν ραδιοφωνικά τις ακροάσεις ζωντανές, μοναδική για να 
κάνουν έτσι, με την άνοδο του δικτύου στην προεξοχή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Senador José R. McCarthy del cruzado de 
Anticommunist caminó en prominencia nacional 9 de febrero de 1950,
cuando él montó un ataque contra agenda de la política no nativa de
presidente Truman. McCarthy cargó que el departamento y su 
secretaria, decano Acheson del estado, abrigaran comunistas 
"traidores". El retórico apocalíptico de McCarthy hizo que los
críticos vacilan antes de desafiador él. Ésos acusados por 
McCarthy hicieron frente a la pérdida de empleo, dañaron las 
carreras, y en muchos casos, rotas las vidas. Después de la 
elección 1952, en la cual el partido republicano ganó el control del
congreso, McCarthy sintió bien al presidente del comité del senado 
sobre operaciones del gobierno y de su subcomité en investigaciones. 
McCarthy entonces extendió sus blancos para incluir las 
agencias de estatal numerosas, además de las industrias de la 
difusión y de la defensa, las universidades, y los Naciones Unidas. 
Después de la secretaria del ejército, Roberto T. Stevens, 
rechazó interceder para parar una asignación de ultramar para el 
principal consultor de McCarthy, G. David Schine, que había sido 
bosquejado, el comité de McCarthy comenzó una investigación de dos 
meses del ejército. Los espectadores vieron el vivo televisada 
encuentro dramático siguiente como ocurrieron entre McCarthy, consejo
especial para el ejército José N. Welch, consejero para el ejército
Juan G. Adams, y consejo del subcomité el principal, Roy Cohn. 
Aunque la potencia de McCarthy declinada sostenidamente después
de las audiencias y del senado votó para condenarlo algunos meses 
más adelante, los eruditos discrepan encendido si el aspecto de 
McCarthy ante una audiencia total de la televisión causó su caída. 
Los historiadores, sin embargo, acreditan la decisión de ABC-TV
para difundir las audiencias viven, la única para hacer así pues, 
con la subida de la red a la prominencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086217</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103350</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/have-you-no-sense-of-decency-the-army-mccarthy-hearings</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
