<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105965</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105965</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206090</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Climate Discovery Teacher's Guide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anleitung Des Klima-Entdeckung-Lehrers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Guide du Professeur de Découverte de Climat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Guia Do Professor Da Descoberta Do Clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Guida Dell'Insegnante Di Scoperta Di Clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οδηγός του δασκάλου ανακαλύψεων κλίματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guía Del Profesor Del Descubrimiento Del Clima</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">includes lessons on how the sun's magnetism interacts with the earth's magnetic field, how scientists study ancient climates, how the earth system works and how climate changes over time, and how climate models are used to predict the future of earth's climate.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schließt Lektionen auf ein, wie der Magnetismus 
des Sonnen auf die magnetische Masse auffängt einwirkt, wie 
Wissenschaftler alte Klimata studieren, wie das Masse System arbeitet 
und wie Klima Überzeit ändert und wie Klimamodelle benutzt werden, 
um die Zukunft des Klimas der Masse vorauszusagen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">inclut des leçons sur la façon dont le 
magnétisme du soleil agit l'un sur l'autre avec le champ magnétique 
de la terre, la façon dont les scientifiques étudient des climats 
antiques, comment le système de la terre fonctionne et comment le 
climat change le temps fini, et comment des modèles de climat sont 
employés pour prévoir le futur du climat de la terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">inclui lições em como o magnetismo do sun 
interage com o campo magnético da terra, em como os cientistas 
estudam climas antigos, como o sistema da terra trabalha e como o 
clima muda o tempo excedente, e como os modelos do clima são usados 
predizer o futuro do clima da terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">include le lezioni su come il magnetismo del sun 
si interagisce con il campo magnetico della terra, su come gli 
scienziati studiano i climi antichi, come il sistema della terra 
funziona e come il clima cambia col tempo e come i modelli di clima 
sono usati per predire il futuro del clima della terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει τα μαθήματα τον τρόπο με τον οποίο ο 
μαγνητισμός του ήλιου αλληλεπιδρά με το γήινο μαγνητικό πεδίο, 
στον τρόπο με τον οποίο οι επιστήμονες μελετούν τα αρχαία 
κλίματα, πώς οι εργασίες γήινων συστημάτων και πώς αλλαγές 
κλίματος κατά τη διάρκεια του χρόνου, και πώς μοντέλα κλίματος 
χρησιμοποιούνται για να προβλέψουν το μέλλον του γήινου κλίματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incluye lecciones en cómo el magnetismo del sun 
obra recíprocamente con el campo magnético de la tierra, cómo los 
científicos estudian climas antiguos, cómo el sistema de la tierra 
trabaja y cómo el clima cambia en un cierto plazo, y cómo los 
modelos del clima se utilizan para predecir el futuro del clima de la 
tierra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206090</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105965</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/climate-discovery-teachers-guide</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
