<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105853</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105853</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206947</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Court Documents Related to Martin Luther King, Jr., and Memphis Sanitation Workers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gericht-Dokumente in Verbindung gestanden auf 
Martin Luther König, jr. und Memphis Hygiene-Arbeitern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Documents de cour liés au roi de Martin Luther, 
au Jr., et aux ouvriers d'hygiène de Memphis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Originais da corte relacionados ao rei de Martin 
Luther, ao Jr., e aos trabalhadores do sanitation de Memphis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Documenti della corte relativi al re del Martin 
Luther, al Jr. ed agli operai di risanamento de Memphis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έγγραφα δικαστηρίου σχετικά με Martin Luther 
King, νεώτερος, και εργαζόμενοι υγιεινής της Μέμφιδας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Documentos de la corte relacionados con el rey de 
Martin Luther, el Jr., y los trabajadores del saneamiento de Memphis</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides fliers and other documents related to the demonstration in Memphis on March 28, 1968. On that day, students near the end of the march broke windows of businesses. Looting ensued. The march was halted. King was deeply distressed by the violence. He and fellow leaders negotiated a commitment to nonviolence among disagreeing factions in Memphis, and another march was planned for April 8. On April 4, as he stepped out of his motel room to go to dinner, he was assassinated.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Flieger zur Verfügung und anderes 
dokumentiert in Verbindung stehendes mit der Demonstration in Memphis 
an März 28, 1968. An diesem Tag brachen Kursteilnehmer nahe dem
Ende des Märzes Fenster von Geschäften. Das Plündern folgte. 
Der März wurde angehalten. König wurde tief durch die 
Gewalttätigkeit beunruhigt. Er und Mitführer verhandelten 
über eine Verpflichtung zu den Gewaltlosigkeiten unter anderer 
MeinungSEIENDEN Parteien in Memphis, und ein anderer März wurde für 
April 8 geplant. An April 4, während er aus seinem Motelraum 
heraus, zum Abendessen zu gehen trat, wurde er ermordet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des insectes et autre documente connexe à
la démonstration à Memphis 28 mars 1968. Ce jour, les 
étudiants près de l'extrémité de la marche ont cassé des 
fenêtres des entreprises. Le pillage s'est ensuivi. La 
marche a été stoppée. Le roi a été profondément affligé 
par la violence. Des amorces lui et de camarade ont négocié un
engagement au nonviolence parmi les factions étant en désaccord à 
Memphis, et une autre marche a été projetée pour avril 8. 
Avril 4, pendant qu'il faisait un pas hors de sa chambre de 
motel d'aller au dîner, il a été assassiné.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece insectos e outro documenta relacionado à 
demonstração em Memphis março em 28, 1968. Nesse dia, os 
estudantes perto da extremidade do março quebraram janelas dos 
negócios. Looting seguiu. O março foi parado. O 
rei foi afligido profundamente pela violência. Líderes e do 
companheiro negociaram um compromisso ao nonviolence entre factions 
discordando em Memphis, e um outro março foi planeado para abril 8. 
Abril em 4, enquanto pisou fora de seu quarto de motel ir ao 
jantar, assassinated.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le alette di filatoio ed altro documenta 
relativo alla dimostrazione a Memphis il 28 marzo 1968. Quel 
giorno, gli allievi vicino all'estremità del procedere hanno rotto le
finestre dei commerci. Saccheggio seguito. Il procedere è
stato fermato. Il re profondamente è stato afflitto dalla 
violenza. Capi del collega e lui hanno negoziato un 
impegno al nonviolence fra le fazioni non stanti d'accordo a Memphis e
un altro procedere è stato progettato per il 8 aprile. Il 4 
aprile, mentre ha fatto un passo dalla sua stanza di motel andare al 
pranzo, è stato assassinato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα ιπτάμενα και άλλα έγγραφα σχετικά με την 
επίδειξη στη Μέμφιδα στις 28 Μαρτίου, το 1968. εκείνη
την ημέρα, οι σπουδαστές κοντά στο τέλος του Μαρτίου έσπασαν τα 
Windows των επιχειρήσεων. Η λεηλασία ακολούθησε. Ο 
Μάρτιος σταματήθηκε. Ο βασιλιάς στενοχωρήθηκε βαθειά από 
τη βία. Αυτός και οι συντροφικοί ηγέτες διαπραγματεύτηκαν 
μια δέσμευση για την πολιτική της μη βίας μεταξύ των διαφωνώντας 
φατριών στη Μέμφιδα, και ένας άλλος Μάρτιος προγραμματίστηκε για
τις 8 Απριλίου. Στις 4 Απριλίου, καθώς περπάτησε από το 
δωμάτιο μοτέλ του για να πάει στο γεύμα, δολοφονήθηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a los aviadores y otro documenta 
relacionado a la demostración en Memphis de marcha la 28 de 1968. 
En ese día, los estudiantes cerca del extremo del marzo 
rompieron ventanas de negocios. El saqueo sobrevino. El 
marzo fue parado. La violencia apenó al rey profundamente. 
Los arranques de cinta él y del compañero negociaron una 
consolidación al nonviolence entre las facciones que discrepaban en 
Memphis, y otro marzo fue planeado para de abril el 8. De abril 
el 4, como él caminó de su cuarto de motel de ir a la cena, lo 
asesinaron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206947</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105853</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/court-documents-related-to-martin-luther-king-jr-and-memphis-sanitation-workers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
