<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107684</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107684</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206019</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Learning Landscapes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erlernenlandschaften</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Horizontaux D'Étude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Paisagens De Aprendizagem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Paesaggi Imparanti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τοπία εκμάθησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paisajes Que aprenden</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers lessons on deserts, ecosystems, riparian zones, invasive plants, wild horses, groundwater, soil composition, hydroelectric power, renewable energy, water conservation techniques of desert animals, sound conductors, volcanoes, waterwheels, watersheds, weeds, gold mining, habitat depletion, and more. Students may design a home for an animal or create a seismograph, anemometer, steam engine, greenhouse, or solar collectors.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet Lektionen auf Wüsten, Oekosystemen, 
riparian Zonen, Angriffsbetrieben, wilden Pferden, Grundwasser, 
Bodenaufbau, hydroelektrischer Energie, auswechselbarer Energie, 
Wassererhaltung Techniken der Wüste Tiere, stichhaltigen Leitern, 
Vulkanen, waterwheels, Wasserscheiden, Unkräutern, Goldbergbau, 
Lebensraumentleerung und mehr an. Kursteilnehmer können ein 
Haus für ein Tier konzipieren oder einen Seismographen, ein 
Anemometer, eine Dampfmaschine, ein Gewächshaus oder 
Sonnenkollektoren herstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre des leçons sur des déserts, des 
écosystèmes, des zones ripicoles, des usines invahissantes, des 
chevaux sauvages, des eaux souterraines, la composition de sol, 
l'énergie hydroélectrique, l'énergie renouvelable, des techniques 
d'économie de l'eau des animaux de désert, des conducteurs sains, 
des volcans, des waterwheels, des lignes de partage, des mauvaises 
herbes, l'exploitation d'or, l'épuisement d'habitat, et plus. 
Les étudiants peuvent concevoir une maison pour un animal ou 
créer un sismographe, un anémomètre, un moteur de vapeur, une serre
chaude, ou des capteurs solaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece lições em desertos, em ecosystems, em 
zonas riparian, em plantas invasive, em cavalos selvagens, em 
groundwater, em composição do solo, na potência hydroelectric, na 
energia renewable, nas técnicas do conservation da água de animais 
do deserto, em condutores sadios, em vulcões, em waterwheels, em 
watersheds, em ervas daninhas, em mineração do ouro, em depletion do
habitat, e em mais. Os estudantes podem projetar uma HOME para 
um animal ou criar um seismograph, um anemómetro, um motor de vapor, 
uma estufa, ou uns coletores solares.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre le lezioni sui deserti, sugli ecosistemi, 
sulle zone riparian, sulle piante invasive, sui cavalli selvaggi, 
sull'acqua freatica, sulla composizione del terreno, sulla forza 
idroelettrica, sull'energia rinnovabile, sulle tecniche di 
conservazione dell'acqua degli animali del deserto, sui conduttori 
sani, sui vulcani, sui waterwheels, sugli spartiacque, sulle erbacce, 
sull'estrazione mineraria dell'oro, sullo svuotamento dell'habitat e 
su più. Gli allievi possono progettare una sede per un animale 
o creare un sismografo, un anemometro, un motore a vapore, una serra, 
o i collettori solari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τα μαθήματα στις ερήμους, τα οικοσυστήματα, 
τις παρόχθιες ζώνες, τις της εισβολής εγκαταστάσεις, τα άγρια 
άλογα, τα υπόγεια νερά, την εδαφολογική σύνθεση, την 
υδροηλεκτρική δύναμη, την ανανεώσιμη ενέργεια, τις τεχνικές 
συντήρησης ύδατος ζώων ερήμων, τους υγιείς αγωγούς, τα 
ηφαίστεια, waterwheels, τους υδροκρίτες, τα ζιζάνια, τη χρυσή 
μεταλλεία, τη μείωση βιότοπων, και περισσότεροι. Οι 
σπουδαστές μπορούν να σχεδιάσουν ένα σπίτι για ένα ζώο ή να 
δημιουργήσουν seismograph, ένα ανεμόμετρο, μια μηχανή ατμού, 
ένα θερμοκήπιο, ή ηλιακούς συσσωρευτές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece lecciones en desiertos, ecosistemas, zonas 
riparian, plantas invasoras, caballos salvajes, agua subterránea, la 
composición del suelo, la potencia hidroeléctrica, la energía 
reanudable, técnicas de la conservación del agua de los animales del
desierto, conductores sanos, volcanes, waterwheels, líneas divisoria 
de las aguas, malas hierbas, la explotación minera del oro, el 
agotamiento del habitat, y más. Los estudiantes pueden diseñar
un hogar para un animal o crear un sismógrafo, un anemómetro, un 
motor de vapor, un invernadero, o colectores solares.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206019</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107684</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/learning-landscapes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
