<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108748</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108748</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Welcome to Planet Oit!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zum Planeten Oit!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue à la planète Oit !</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda ao planeta Oit!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto al pianeta Oit!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στον πλανήτη Oit!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Recepción al planeta Oit!</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Planet Oit is an online computer game developed by a team from North Dakota State University in which the students play interplanetary explorers as a means to teach the concepts and principles of physical geology. Planet Oit has been designed as a coherent geophysical space where geological regions contain plausible phenomenon which are populated with plausible objects, of plausible types. Planet Oit currently contains over 50 locations, nearly 100 rock and mineral types, 200 outcrops, veins, boulders and so forth, and over 40 instrument and tool types. The students' task is to obtain the appropriate equipment and perform tests on the samples they find before they can report their findings back to Earth. User registration is required but at no cost. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Planet Oit ist ein Onlinecomputerspiel, das von einem Team
von der North Dakota Landesuniversität entwickelt wird, in der die 
Kursteilnehmer interplanetarische Forscher als Mittel, die Konzepte 
und die Grundregeln der physikalischer Geologie zu unterrichten 
spielen. Planet Oit ist als zusammenhängender geophysikalischer
Platz konzipiert worden, in dem geologische Regionen plausibles 
Phänomen, die mit plausiblen Nachrichten bevölkert werden, der 
plausiblen Typen enthalten. Planet Oit enthält aktuell über 50
Standorten, fast 100 Felsen- und Mineraltypen, 200 Zutageliegen, 
Adern, Flußsteine und so weiter und über 40 Instrument- und 
Hilfsmitteltypen. Die Aufgabe der Kursteilnehmer ist, die 
passende Ausrüstung zu erhalten und Tests auf den Proben 
durchzuführen, die sie finden, bevor sie über ihre Entdeckungen 
zurück zu Masse berichten können. Benutzerregistrierung wird 
aber an keinen Kosten benoetigt. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite 
können Benutzer auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung,
Kontext für Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und 
Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen 
zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La planète Oit est un jeu d'ordinateur en ligne 
développé par une équipe de l'université de l'Etat du nord du 
Dakota à laquelle les étudiants jouent les explorateurs 
interplanétaires en tant que des moyens d'enseigner les concepts et 
les principes de la géologie physique. La planète Oit a été 
conçue comme espace géophysique logique où les régions 
géologiques contiennent le phénomène plausible qui sont peuplées 
avec les objets plausibles, des types plausibles. La planète 
Oit contient actuel plus de 50 emplacements, presque 100 types de 
roche et de minerai, 200 affleurements, veines, rochers et ainsi de 
suite, et plus de 40 types d'instrument et d'outil. Les 
étudiants chargent doit obtenir le matériel approprié et 
réaliser des essais sur les échantillons qu'ils trouvent avant 
qu'ils puissent enregistrer leurs résultats de nouveau à la terre. 
L'enregistrement d'utilisateur est exigé mais à aucun coût. 
À cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent 
accéder aux informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, 
contexte pour les extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes
et, le matériel didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les 
références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O planeta Oit é um jogo de computador em linha 
desenvolvido por uma equipe da universidade de estado de dakota norte 
em que os estudantes jogam exploradores interplanetários como meios 
ensinar os conceitos e os princípios da geologia física. O 
planeta Oit foi projetado como um espaço geofísico coherent onde as 
regiões geological contivessem o fenômeno plausible que são 
povoadas com objetos plausible, de tipos plausible. O planeta 
Oit contem atualmente sobre 50 posições, quase 100 tipos da rocha e 
do mineral, 200 outcrops, veias, pedregulhos e assim por diante, e 
sobre 40 tipos do instrumento e da ferramenta. A tarefa dos 
estudantes é obter o equipamento apropriado e executar testes nas 
amostras que encontram antes que possam relatar seus findings para 
trás à terra. O registo do usuário é requerido mas em nenhum
custo. Nesta página do ponto começar, os usuários podem 
alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do 
exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os 
materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as referências e os 
tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il pianeta Oit è un gioco di calcolatore in linea 
sviluppato da una squadra dal Dakota del Nord Dichiara 
l'università in cui gli allievi giocano gli esploratori 
interplanetari come mezzi per insegnare i concetti ed i principii 
della geologia fisica. Il pianeta Oit è stato progettato come 
spazio geofisico coerente in cui le regioni geologiche contengono il 
fenomeno plausibile che sono popolate con gli oggetti plausibili, dei 
tipi plausibili. Il pianeta Oit attualmente contiene oltre 50 
posizioni, quasi 100 tipi del minerale e della roccia, 200 
affioramenti, vene, massi e così via ed oltre 40 tipi dello strumento
e dello strumento. L'operazione degli allievi è di ottenere 
l'apparecchiatura adatta e di effettuare le prove sui campioni che 
trovano prima che possano segnalare i loro risultati di nuovo a terra.
Il registro dell'utente è richiesto ma a nessun costo. A 
questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle 
informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto 
per le punte di istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le 
idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πλανήτης Oit είναι ένα σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
παιχνίδι υπολογιστών που αναπτύσσεται από μια ομάδα από το 
κρατικό πανεπιστήμιο της βόρειας Ντακότας στο οποίο οι 
σπουδαστές παίζουν τους διαπλανητικούς εξερευνητές ως μέσα να 
διδάξουν οι έννοιες και οι αρχές της φυσικής γεωλογίας. Ο 
πλανήτης Oit έχει σχεδιαστεί ως συνεπές γεωφυσικό διάστημα 
όπου οι γεωλογικές περιοχές περιέχουν το εύλογο φαινόμενο που 
είναι εποικημένες με τα εύλογα αντικείμενα, των εύλογων τύπων. 
Ο πλανήτης Oit περιέχει αυτήν την περίοδο πάνω από 50 
θέσεις, βράχος σχεδόν 100 και ορυκτοί τύποι, 200 
επανθίσεις, φλέβες, λίθοι και ούτω καθ'εξής, και πάνω από 40
τύποι οργάνων και εργαλείων. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία των 
σπουδαστών είναι να λάβουν τον κατάλληλο εξοπλισμό και να 
εκτελέσουν τις δοκιμές στα δείγματα που βρίσκουν προτού να 
μπορέσουν να εκθέσουν τα συμπεράσματά τους πίσω στη γη. Η 
εγγραφή χρηστών απαιτείται αλλά με κανένα κόστος. Σε 
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El planeta Oit es un juego de ordenador en línea 
desarrollado por un equipo de la universidad de estado de Dakota del 
Norte en la cual los estudiantes juegan a exploradores 
interplanetarios como los medios de enseñar los conceptos y los 
principios de la geología física. El planeta Oit se ha 
diseñado como espacio geofísico coherente donde las regiones 
geológicas contienen fenómeno plausible que se pueblan con los 
objetos plausibles, de tipos plausibles. El planeta Oit contiene
actualmente sobre 50 localizaciones, casi 100 tipos de la roca y del 
mineral, 200 afloramientos, venas, cantos rodados y así 
sucesivamente, y sobre 40 tipos del instrumento y de la herramienta. 
La tarea de los estudiantes es obtener el equipo apropiado y 
realizar pruebas en las muestras que encuentran antes de que puedan 
señalar sus resultados de nuevo a la tierra. El registro del 
utilizador se requiere pero en ningún coste. En esta 
paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso
a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto
para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los 
materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los 
asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NORTH DAKOTA STATE UNIVERSITY
FN:NORTH DAKOTA STATE UNIVERSITY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108748</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/welcome-to-planet-oit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
