<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/8963519</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>8963519</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087149</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">U.S. Intervention in Central America: Kellogg's Charges of a Bolshevist Threat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">VEREINIGTE STAATEN Intervention in Mittelamerika: 
Ladungen Kelloggs einer Bolshevist Drohung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Intervention des ETATS-UNIS en Amérique Centrale :
Les frais de Kellogg d'une menace de Bolshevist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Intervenção de ESTADOS UNIDOS em América 
Central: Cargas de Kellogg de uma ameaça de Bolshevist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Intervento degli STATI UNITI in America Centrale: 
Spese del Kellogg di una minaccia di Bolshevist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ Επέμβαση στην Κεντρική Αμερική: 
Δαπάνες της Kellogg μιας απειλής Bolshevist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Intervención de ESTADOS UNIDOS en America 
Central: Cargas de Kellogg de una amenaza de Bolshevist</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By the early 20th century, U.S. companies dominated the economies of the five Central American republics, controlling most of the banana production, railroads, port facilities, mines, and banking institutions. This export-based economy also maintained a social hierarchy of a small number of large landowners and millions of landless peasants. Nicaragua offers a case study of both American domination of the region and local and international resistance to that domination. During the 19th century Nicaragua was among the main contenders for an interoceanic canal and thus drew major railroad and steamship investors from both Britain and the United States. The United States intervened in Nicaragua four times during the 1890s to protect U.S. economic interests during periods of political unrest. In 1912 U.S. marines landed once again to maintain a pro-American government; this occupation lasted until 1925. As this January 1927 memorandum submitted to the U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee indicated, Secretary of State Frank Kellogg justified U.S. occupation of Nicaragua on the basis of communist threats from Mexico and the Soviet Union. The United States brokered a peace treaty between Nicaraguan liberals and conservatives that allowed the two parties to share political power, but U.S. influence and economic power remained intact.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum dem frühen 20. Jahrhundert beherrschten 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Firmen die Wirtschaftssysteme der fünf zentralen 
amerikanischen Republiken und steuerten die meisten der Banane 
Produktion, Eisenbahnen, Portteildienste, Gruben und Einrichtungen des
Bankgewerbes. Dieses exportieren-gegründete Wirtschaft behielt 
auch eine Sozialhierarchie einer kleinen Anzahl von großen 
Grundbesitzern und der Millionen der anschlußlosen Landarbeiter bei. 
Nicaragua bietet eine Fallstudie der amerikanischen Herrschaft 
der Region und des lokalen und internationalen Widerstandes zu dieser 
Herrschaft an. Während des 19. Jahrhunderts gehörte Nicaragua 
zu den Hauptkämpfern für einen interoceanic Kanal und zeichnete 
folglich Haupteisenbahn- und Steamshipinvestoren von Großbritannien 
und von den Vereinigten Staaten. Die Vereinigten Staaten griffen
in Nicaragua viermal während des 1890s, VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
ökonomische Interessen während der Perioden der politischen 
Ruhelosigkeit zu schützen ein. In 1912 VEREINIGTEN STAATEN 
landeten Marinen noch einmal, um eine Pro-Amerikanische Regierung 
beizubehalten; diese Besetzung dauerte bis 1925. Als 
dieser Januar 1927 gab Protokoll beim angezeigten VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Senat-fremden Relationen Ausschuß, beim Staatssekretär Freivermerk 
Kellogg ausgeschlossene VEREINIGTE STAATEN Besetzung von Nicaragua 
aufgrund von kommunistischen Drohungen von Mexiko und beim 
Sowjet-Anschluß ein. Die Vereinigten Staaten brokered einen 
Friedensvertrag zwischen Nicaragualiberalen und Konservativen, die den
zwei Parteien erlaubten, politische Energie zu teilen, aber 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN beeinflussen und ökonomische Energie blieb 
intakt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par le début du 20ème siècle, les compagnies 
des ETATS-UNIS ont dominé les économies des cinq républiques 
américaines centrales, contrôlant la majeure partie de la production
de banane, des chemins de fer, des équipements gauches, des mines, et
des institutions bancaires. Ceci économie exporter-basée a 
également mis à jour une hiérarchie sociale de un nombre restreint 
de grands propriétaires fonciers et des millions de paysans 
sans terre. Le Nicaragua offre une étude de cas de la 
domination américaine de la région et de la résistance locale et 
internationale à cette domination. Pendant le 19ème siècle le
Nicaragua était parmi les compétiteurs principaux pour un canal 
interoceanic et a ainsi tiré les investisseurs principaux de chemin 
de fer et de navire à vapeur de Grande-Bretagne et des Etats-Unis. 
Les Etats-Unis sont intervenus au Nicaragua quatre fois pendant 
le 1890s de protéger des intérêts économiques des ETATS-UNIS 
pendant des périodes du malaise politique. Aux 1912 ETATS-UNIS 
les soldats de marine ont débarqué de nouveau pour mettre à jour un
gouvernement pro-Américain ; ce métier a duré jusqu'en 1925. 
En tant que ce janvier 1927 le mémorandum a soumis au Comité 
étranger de relations de sénat des ETATS-UNIS indiqué, au 
secrétaire d'état le métier des ETATS-UNIS justifié par Kellogg
de contreseing du Nicaragua sur la base des menaces communistes du 
Mexique et à Union Soviétique. Les Etats-Unis ont sponsorisé 
un traité de paix entre les libéraux et les conservateurs de 
Nicaragua qui ont permis aux deux parties de partager la puissance 
politique, mais les ETATS-UNIS influencent et la puissance économique
est demeurée intact.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pelo 20o século adiantado, as companhias de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS dominaram as economias das cinco repúblicas americanas
centrais, controlando a maioria da produção da banana, estradas de 
ferro, as facilidades portuárias, as minas, e as instituições de 
operação bancária. Isto economia export-baseada manteve 
também uma hierarquia social de um número pequeno de latifundiários
grandes e de milhões de camponeses landless. Nicarágua oferece
um estudo de caso  do domination americano da região e da 
resistência local e internacional a esse domination. Durante o 
1ø século Nicarágua era entre os contendores principais para um 
canal interoceanic e desenhava assim investors principais da estrada 
de ferro e do steamship  de Grâ Bretanha e dos estados unidos. 
Os estados unidos intervieram em Nicarágua quatro vezes durante
o 1890s proteger interesses econômicos de ESTADOS UNIDOS durante 
períodos do unrest político. Em 1912 ESTADOS UNIDOS os 
fuzileiros navais aterraram uma vez outra vez para manter um governo 
pro-Americano; esta ocupação durou até 1925. Como este 
janeiro 1927 o memorando submeteu-se ao comitê extrangeiro das 
relações do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS indicado, à secretária da 
ocupação justificada Kellogg de ESTADOS UNIDOS do franquia do estado
de Nicarágua na base de ameaças comunistas de México e à 
Soviete-união. Os estados unidos brokered um tratado da paz 
entre os liberais e os conservadores nicaraguan que permitiram que os 
dois partidos compartilhassem da potência política, mas ESTADOS 
UNIDOS influenciam e a potência econômica remanesceu intact.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro l'inizio del 20esimo secolo, le aziende 
degli STATI UNITI hanno dominato le economie delle cinque repubbliche 
americane centrali, gestenti la maggior parte della produzione della 
banana, le ferrovie, le attrezzature port, le miniere e le istituzioni
di operazioni bancarie. Ciò economia esport-basata egualmente 
ha effettuato una gerarchia sociale di piccolo numero di grandi 
latifondisti e di milioni di contadini landless. La Nicaragua 
offre un'inchiesta sia della dominazione americana della regione che 
della resistenza locale ed internazionale a quella dominazione. 
Durante il diciannovesimo secolo la Nicaragua era fra i 
concorrenti principali per un canale interoceanic e così ha estratto 
la ferrovia principale e gli investitori della nave a vapore sia dalla
Gran-Bretagna che dal uniti Dichiara. Unito 
Dichiara intervenuto in Nicaragua quattro volte durante il 
1890s proteggere gli interessi economici degli STATI UNITI durante i 
periodi di agitazione politica. In 1912 STATI UNITI i fanti di 
marina hanno atterrato ancora una volta per effettuare un governo 
pro-Americano; questa occupazione ha durato fino al 1925. 
Come questo gennaio del 1927 il memorandum ha presentato al 
comitato straniero di rapporti del senato degli STATI UNITI indicato, 
la segretaria di Dichiara l'occupazione franca degli STATI 
UNITI giustificata Kellogg della Nicaragua in base alle minacce 
comuniste dal Messico e dall'Soviet-unione. Unito 
Dichiara brokered un trattato di pace fra i liberali ed i 
conservatori nicaraguan che hanno permesso che i due partiti 
ripartissero l'potenza politica, ma gli STATI UNITI influenzano e 
l'potenza economica è rimasto intact.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέχρι τον πρόωρο 20ό αιώνα, οι ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΕΣ 
επιχειρήσεις εξουσίασαν τις οικονομίες των πέντε Κεντρικής 
Αμερικής δημοκρατιών, που ελέγχουν την μεγαλύτερη μέρος της 
παραγωγής μπανανών, σιδηρόδρομοι, εγκαταστάσεις λιμένων, 
ορυχεία, και που καταθέτουν τα όργανα σε τράπεζα. 
Αυτή η εξαγωγή-βασισμένη οικονομία διατήρησε επίσης μια 
κοινωνική ιεραρχία ενός μικρού αριθμού μεγάλων landowners και
εκατομμυρίων των landless αγροτών. Η Νικαράγουα προσφέρει
μια περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη και της αμερικανικής κυριαρχίας της 
περιοχής και της τοπικής και διεθνούς αντίστασης σε εκείνη την 
κυριαρχία. Κατά τη διάρκεια του 19$ου αιώνα η Νικαράγουα 
ήταν μεταξύ των βασικών υποψηφίων για ένα διωκεανικό κανάλι και
έτσι σύρω σημαντικούς επενδυτές σιδηροδρόμου και ατμοπλοίων και 
από τη Μεγάλη Βρετανία και από τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Οι 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες επενέβησαν στη Νικαράγουα τέσσερις φορές 
κατά τη διάρκεια του 1890s για να προστατεύσουν τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ 
οικονομικά συμφέροντα κατά τη διάρκεια περίοδος πολιτικής 
ανησυχίας. Το 1912 τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ ναυτικά προσγειώθηκαν 
άλλη μια φορά για να διατηρήσουν μια υπέρ-αμερικανική κυβέρνηση 
αυτό το επάγγελμα διάρκεσε έως το 1925. Όπως αυτό
το υπόμνημα Ιανουαρίου 1927 που υποβλήθηκε στην ξένη Επιτροπή 
σχέσεων ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου έδειξε, ο γραμματέας του κράτους 
Frank Kellogg δικαιολόγησε το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ επάγγελμα της 
Νικαράγουας βάσει των κομμουνιστικών απειλών από το Μεξικό και 
τη Σοβιετική Ένωση. Οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες μια συνθήκη 
ειρήνης μεταξύ των νικαραγουανών φιλελευθέρων και των 
συντηρητικών που επέτρεψαν στα δύο συμβαλλόμενα μέρη για να 
μοιραστούν την πολιτική δύναμη, αλλά η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ επιρροή και η 
οικονομική δύναμη παρέμειναν άθικτες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por el vigésimo siglo temprano, las compañías 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS dominaron las economías de las cinco repúblicas 
americanas centrales, controlando la mayoría de la producción del 
plátano, los ferrocarriles, los recursos portuarios, las minas, y a 
instituciones de actividades bancarias. Esto economía 
exportar-basada también mantuvo una jerarquía social de un número 
pequeño de terratenientes grandes y de millones de campesinos sin 
tierras. Nicaragua ofrece un estudio de caso de la dominación 
americana de la región y de la resistencia local e internacional a 
esa dominación. Durante el diecinueveavo siglo Nicaragua estaba
entre los competidores principales para un canal interoceanic y trazó
así a inversionistas importantes del ferrocarril y del buque de vapor
de Gran Bretaña y de los Estados Unidos. Los Estados Unidos 
intervinieron en Nicaragua cuatro veces durante el 1890s de proteger 
los intereses económicos de ESTADOS UNIDOS durante períodos del 
malestar político. En 1912 ESTADOS UNIDOS los infantes de 
marina aterrizaron de nuevo para mantener un gobierno 
favorable-Americano; esta ocupación duró hasta 1925. 
Como este enero de 1927 el memorándum sometió al comité no 
nativo de las relaciones del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS indicado, a la 
secretaria de la ocupación alineada Kellogg de ESTADOS UNIDOS de la 
carta franca del estado de Nicaragua en base de amenazas comunistas de
México y a la Soviet-unio'n. Los Estados Unidos brokered un 
tratado de la paz entre los liberales y los conservadores nicaraguan 
que permitieron que los dos partidos compartieran potencia política, 
pero ESTADOS UNIDOS influencian y seguía habiendo el poder económico
intacto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087149</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>8963519</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/u-s-intervention-in-central-america-kelloggs-charges-of-a-bolshevist-threat</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
