<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104110</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104110</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206308</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">SEGway</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">SEGway</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">SEGway</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">SEGway</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">SEGway</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">SEGway</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">SEGway</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a gateway to astronomy and space science resources. Find lessons on auroras, comets, satellites, satellite images of earth, properties of light, Venus, weather on Mars, solar cycle, tracking orbiting spacecraft, classifying galaxies, calculating rotation rates of planets, sunspots, interstellar medium, and electromagnetic radiation. Learn about basic astrophysics research techniques and how satellites see the universe at different wavelengths.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Gateway zu den Astronomie- und 
Platzwissenschaftsbetriebsmitteln. Finden Sie Lektionen auf 
auroras, Kometen, Satelliten, Satellitenbilder von Masse, 
Eigenschaften des Lichtes, Venus, Wetter auf Mars, Solarschleife und 
das umkreisende Raumfahrzeug aufspüren und Galaxien, Rechenumdrehung 
Kinetik der Planeten, Sunspots, interstellar Medium und 
elektromagnetische Strahlung einstufen. Erlernen Sie über 
grundlegende Astrophysikforschung Techniken und wie Satelliten das 
Universum an den unterschiedlichen Wellenlängen sehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un Gateway aux ressources d'astronomie et de 
science de l'espace. Trouvez les leçons sur des auroras, 
comètes, les satellites, les images satellites de la terre, 
propriétés de lumière, Venus, survivez à sur Mars, cycle 
solaire, en dépistant le vaisseau spatial orbital, classifiant des 
galaxies, des cadences calculatrices de rotation des planètes, des 
taches solaires, le support interstellaire, et le rayonnement 
électromagnétique. Renseignez-vous sur des techniques de base 
de recherche en matière d'astrophysique et comment les satellites 
voient l'univers à différentes longueurs d'onde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um Gateway aos recursos da astronomia e da 
ciência do espaço. Encontre lições em auroras, cometas, 
satélites, imagens satellite da terra, propriedades da luz, Venus, 
tempo em Marte, ciclo solar, seguindo nave espacial orbiting, 
classificando galáxias, taxas calculadoras da rotação dos planetas,
sunspots, o media interstellar, e a radiação eletromagnética. 
Aprenda sobre técnicas básicas da pesquisa da astrofísica e 
como os satélites vêem o universo em wavelengths diferentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un Gateway alle risorse di scienza dello spazio
e di astronomia. Trovi le lezioni sui auroras, le comete, i 
satelliti, le immagini satelliti di terra, proprietà di luce, Venus, 
tempo su Marte, ciclo solare, rintracciando la nave spaziale orbiting,
classificante le galassie, i tassi calcolatori di rotazione dei 
pianeti, i sunspots, il media interstellar e la radiazione 
elettromagnetica. Impari circa le tecniche di base di ricerca in
astrofisica e come i satelliti vedono l'universo alle lunghezze d'onda
differenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια πύλη στην αστρονομία και τα διαστημικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς επιστήμης. Βρείτε τα μαθήματα στις 
αυγές, κομήτες, δορυφόροι, δορυφορικές εικόνες της γης, 
ιδιότητες του φωτός, Αφροδίτη, καιρός στον Αρη, ηλιακός κύκλος,
ακολουθώντας βάζοντας σε τροχιά διαστημικό σκάφος, που ταξινομεί
τους γαλαξίες, υπολογίζοντας τα ποσοστά περιστροφής πλανητών, τις
ηλιακές κηλίδες, το interstellar μέσο, και την ηλεκτρομαγνητική
ακτινοβολία. Μάθετε για τις βασικές ερευνητικές τεχνικές 
αστροφυσικής και πώς οι δορυφόροι βλέπουνε τον κόσμο στα 
διαφορετικά μήκη κύματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">está un Gateway a los recursos de la astronomía 
y de la ciencia del espacio. Encuentre las lecciones en los 
auroras, cometas, satélites, imágenes basadas en los satélites de 
la tierra, características de la luz, Venus, tiempo en Marte, ciclo 
solar, siguiendo la nave espacial orbiting, clasificando galaxias, 
índices calculadores de la rotación de planetas, manchas solares, 
media interestelar, y la radiación electromágnetica. Aprenda 
sobre técnicas básicas de la investigación de la astrofísica y 
cómo los satélites ven el universo en diversas longitudes de onda.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206308</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104110</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/segway</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
