<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102998</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102998</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087100</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"They Must Work Harder Than Ever": "A Working Man" Remembers Life in New York City, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie Müssen Stark Als Überhaupt Arbeiten": 
"ein Funktion Mann" erinnert sich das an Leben in New York City,
1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ils Doivent Fonctionner Plus dur Que Jamais" : 
"un ouvrier" se rappelle la vie à New York City, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Devem Trabalhar Mais duramente Do que Sempre": 
"um homem de funcionamento" recorda a vida em New York City, 
1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Devono Funzionare Più duro Che mai": "un 
uomo di funzionamento" si ricorda della vita a New York City, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πρέπει να εργαστούν σκληρότερα από πάντα": 
"Ένα εργαζόμενο άτομο" θυμάται τη ζωή στην πόλη της Νέας 
Υόρκης, 1830s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Deben Trabajar Más difícilmente Que Siempre": 
"un hombre de funcionamiento" recuerda la vida en New York City,
1830s</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Early nineteenth-century cities experienced enormous growth. New York's population tripled after 1810, numbering over 312,000 by 1840. As the population exploded, the gap between rich and poor also deepened. Writing in a British periodical in 1845, "A Working Man" described changes in the urban workplace and also in residential and leisure patterns. Recounting his family's emigration to America in 1825-35, he emphasized emigrants' enormously high expectations and frequently ensuing disappointments. While work was plentiful, the pace was brutal and hours long. With its congested thoroughfares and colorful vistas, the city made a vivid impression upon residents and visitors alike. While residents could boast of an abundance of fruit and other items in the markets, the city's unstructured growth also resulted in rampant disease and filthy streets. "A Working Man" was struck by the city's youthful population, but also by the low esteem reserved for old age.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frühe 19.-Jahrhundert Städte erfuhren enormes 
Wachstum. Bevölkerung New York verdreifachte nach 1810 und 
numerierte über 312.000 bis zum 1840. Während die Bevölkerung
explodierte, vertiefte sich der Abstand zwischen reichem und Armen 
auch. Schreibend in eine britische Zeitschrift 1845, ", ein 
Funktion Mann" beschrieb Änderungen an dem städtischen Arbeitsplatz 
und auch in den Wohn- und Freizeitmustern. Auswanderung seiner
Familie nach Amerika 1825-35 nachzählend, hob er hohe Erwartungen und
häufig folgende Enttäuschungen der Emigranten enorm hervor. 
Während Arbeit reichlich war, war der Schritt brutal und die 
Stunden lang. Mit seinen verstopften Durchgangsstraßen und 
bunten vistas bildete die Stadt einen klaren Eindruck nach den 
gleichBewohnern und Besuchern. Während Bewohner eines 
Überflußes an der Frucht und an anderen Einzelteilen in den Märkten
sich rühmen konnten, ergab das unstrukturierte Wachstum der Stadt 
auch zügellose Krankheit und schmutzige Straßen. "ein Funktion
Mann" wurde durch die jugendliche Bevölkerung der Stadt, aber auch 
durch die niedrige Achtung angeschlagen, die für altes Alter 
aufgehoben wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les villes tôt de dix-neuvième-siècle ont 
éprouvé l'énorme croissance. La population de New York a 
triplé après 1810, numérotant plus de 312.000 d'ici 1840. 
Pendant que la population éclatait, l'intervalle entre riche et
les pauvres a également approfondi. Écrivant dans un 
périodique britannique en 1845, "un ouvrier" a décrit des 
changements dans le lieu de travail urbain et également des 
configurations résidentielles et de loisirs. Racontant 
l'émigration de sa famille en Amérique en 1825-35, il a souligné 
les espérances énormément élevées et les déceptions fréquemment
suivantes des émigrants. Tandis que le travail était abondant,
le pas était brutal et des heures long. Avec ses voies de 
communication encombrées et vistas colorés, la ville a fait une 
impression vive sur des résidants et des visiteurs semblables. 
Tandis que les résidants pourraient se vanter d'une abondance 
de fruit et d'autres éléments sur les marchés, la croissance non 
structurée de la ville a également eu comme conséquence la maladie 
effrénée et les rues dégoûtantes. "un ouvrier" a été 
frappé par la population jeune de la ville, mais également par la 
basse estime réservée pour le vieil âge.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As cidades adiantadas de décimo-século 
experimentaram o crescimento enorme. A população de New York 
triplicou após 1810, numerando sobre 312.000 por 1840. Enquanto
a população explodiu, a abertura entre rico e pobres aprofundou-se 
também. Escrevendo em um periodical britânico em 1845, "um 
homem de funcionamento" descreveu mudanças no workplace urbano e 
também em testes padrões residential e do lazer. Recounting o 
emigration da sua família a América em 1825-35, emfatizou 
expectativas enormemente elevadas e desapontamentos freqüentemente 
seguindo dos emigrants'. Quando o trabalho era abundante, o 
ritmo era brutal e horas longo. Com seus passagens 
congestionadas e vistas coloridos, a cidade fêz uma impressão 
vívida em cima dos residentes e dos visitantes semelhantes. 
Quando os residentes poderiam boast de uma abundância de fruta 
e de outros artigos nos mercados, o crescimento unstructured da cidade
resultou também na doença rampant e em ruas filthy. "um homem 
de funcionamento" foi golpeado pela população jovem da cidade, mas 
também pelo esteem baixo reservado para a idade velha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le città in anticipo di diciannovesimo-secolo 
hanno avvertito lo sviluppo enorme. La popolazione de New York 
si è triplicata dopo 1810, numerando oltre 312.000 entro 1840. 
Mentre la popolazione ha esploso, lo spacco fra ricco e 
povero egualmente ha approfondito. Scrivendo in un 
periodico britannico in 1845, "un uomo di funzionamento" ha descritto 
i cambiamenti nel posto di lavoro urbano ed anche nei modelli di svago
e residenziali. Raccontando l'emigrazione della sua famiglia in 
America in 1825-35, ha dato risalto alle aspettative enormemente alte 
ed ai disappunti frequentemente seguenti degli emigranti. Mentre
il lavoro era abbondante, il passo era brutale ed ore di lunghezza. 
Con le relativi vie pubbliche congestionate e vistas colorful, 
la città ha fatto un'impressione chiara sui residenti e sugli ospiti 
simili. Mentre i residenti potrebbero vantarsi di un'abbondanza 
di frutta e di altri articoli nei mercati, lo sviluppo non strutturato
della città egualmente ha provocato la malattia sfrenata e vie 
ripugnanti. "un uomo di funzionamento" è stato colpito dalla 
popolazione youthful della città, ma anche dalla stima bassa 
riservata alla vecchia età.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι πρόωρες πόλεις δέκατος-αιώνα δοκίμασαν την 
τεράστια αύξηση. Πληθυσμός της Νέας Υόρκης που 
τριπλασιάζεται μετά από 1810, αριθμώντας πάνω από 312.000 
από 1840. Δεδομένου ότι ο πληθυσμός εξερράγη, το χάσμα 
μεταξύ πλούσιου και των φτωχών που εμβαθύνεται επίσης. 
Γράφοντας σε ένα βρετανικό περιοδικό το 1845, "ένα 
εργαζόμενο άτομο" περιέγραψε τις αλλαγές στον αστικό εργασιακό 
χώρο και επίσης στα κατοικημένα και πρότυπα ελεύθερου χρόνου. 
Εξιστορώντας την αποδημία της οικογένειάς του στην Αμερική 
το 1825-35, υπογράμμισε τις επόμενες απογοητεύσεις των 
μεταναστών πάρα πολύ τις υψηλές προσδοκίες και συχνά. Ενώ
η εργασία ήταν άφθονη, ο ρυθμός ήταν βάναυσος και ώρες πολλές.
Με τις κορεσμένες οδούς και ζωηρόχρωμα vistas της, η πόλη
έκανε μια ζωηρή εντύπωση επάνω στους κατοίκους και τους 
επισκέπτες όμοιους. Ενώ οι κάτοικοι μπόρεσαν να καυχηθούν 
μιας αφθονίας φρούτων και άλλων αντικειμένων στις αγορές, η μη 
δομημένη αύξηση της πόλης οδήγησε επίσης στην ασυγκράτητη 
ασθένεια και τις ακάθαρτες οδούς. "Ένα εργαζόμενο άτομο" 
χτυπήθηκε από το νεανικό πληθυσμό της πόλης, αλλά και από τη 
χαμηλή εκτίμηση διατήρησε για τα γηρατειά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las ciudades tempranas del diecinueveavo-siglo 
experimentaron crecimiento enorme. La población de Nueva York 
triplicó después de 1810, numerando sobre 312.000 antes de 1840. 
Mientras que la población estalló, el boquete entre rico y los
pobres también profundizó. Escribiendo en un periódico 
británico en 1845, "un hombre de funcionamiento" describió cambios 
en el lugar de trabajo urbano y también en modelos residenciales y 
del ocio. Contando de nuevo la emigración de su familia a 
América en 1825-35, él acentuó las expectativas enormemente altas y
las decepciones con frecuencia que sobrevenían de los emigrantes. 
Mientras que el trabajo era abundante, el paso era brutal y 
horas largo. Con sus carreteras congestionadas y vistas 
coloridos, la ciudad hizo una impresión viva sobre los residentes y 
los visitantes semejantes. Mientras que los residentes podrían 
jactarse de una abundancia de fruta y de otros items en los mercados, 
el crecimiento no estructurado de la ciudad también dio lugar a 
enfermedad desenfrenada y a calles asquerosas. "un hombre de 
funcionamiento" pulso por la población joven de la ciudad, pero 
también por la estima baja reservada para la vieja edad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087100</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102998</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/they-must-work-harder-than-ever-a-working-man-remembers-life-in-new-york-city-1830s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
