<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086205</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Gompers Calls for Action Over Cripple Creek</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gompers Aufrufe für Tätigkeit 
Überschuss-Krüppel-Nebenfluß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Appels de Gompers pour la crique d'estropié 
d'excédent d'action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atendimentos de Gompers para o creek do aleijado 
do excesso da ação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Richieste di Gompers per l'insenatura del cripple 
dell'eccedenza di azione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι προσκλήσεις Gompers για την ενέργεια 
ακρωτηριάζουν τον κολπίσκο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Llamadas de Gompers para el cala del lisiado del 
excedente de la acción</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The American West's history of radical unionism at the turn of the century reflects the breadth of nineteenth-century class struggle. In Cripple Creek, Colorado, for example, violent conflict broke out in 1903 between members of the Western Federation of Miners (WFM) and corporate mining interests determined to crush the union. Before it was over, thirty men were dead and the union was defeated. Though hostile to the Socialist-leaning WFM, American Federal of Labor leader Samuel Gompers issued the following June 20, 1904, statement in support of the striking miners at Cripple Creek.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die amerikanische Westgeschichte des radikalen 
unionism an der Jahrhundertwende reflektiert die Breite des 
19.-Jahrhundert Kategorie Kampfes. Im Krüppel-Nebenfluß lief 
Kolorado, für Beispiel, heftige $überschneidung heraus 1903 zwischen
Bauteile der westlichen Vereinigung der Bergmänner (WFM) und die 
korporativen gewinneninteressen, die festgestellt wurden, um den 
Anschluß zu zerquetschen ein. Bevor es rüber sein, waren 
dreißig Männer tot und der Anschluß wurde besiegt. Zwar 
feindlich zum Sozialistisch-lehnenden WFM, gab amerikanisches Bundes 
des Gewerkschaftsführers Samuel Gompers den folgenden Juni 20, 1904, 
Anweisung zur Unterstützung der auffallenden Bergmänner am 
Krüppel-Nebenfluß heraus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'histoire occidentale américaine du syndicalisme 
radical à la fin du siècle reflète la largeur de la lutte de classe
de dix-neuvième-siècle. Dans la crique d'estropié, le 
Colorado, par exemple, conflit violent a éclaté en 1903 entre les 
membres de la fédération occidentale des mineurs (WFM) et les 
intérêts d'extraction de corporation déterminés pour écraser 
l'union. Avant qu'il plus de, trente hommes étaient morts et 
l'union a été défaite. Cependant hostile au WFM depenchement,
fédéral américain du dirigeant syndical Samuel Gompers a émis juin
suivant 20, 1904, rapport à l'appui des mineurs saisissants à la 
crique d'estropié.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O history ocidental americano do unionism radical 
na volta do século reflete a largura da luta de classes de 
décimo-século. No creek do aleijado, Colorado, para o exemplo,
conflito violento quebrou para fora em 1903 entre membros do 
federation ocidental dos mineiros (WFM) e os interesses minando 
incorporados determinados esmagar a união. Antes que sobre, 
trinta homens estiveram inoperantes e a união foi derrotada. 
Though hostil ao WFM Socialist-inclinando-se, federal americano 
do líder labor Samuel Gompers emitiu seguinte junho o 20, 1904, 
indicação na sustentação dos mineiros impressionantes no creek do 
aleijado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La storia ad ovest americana del unionism radicale
alla fine del secolo riflette la larghezza di lotta di codice 
categoria di diciannovesimo-secolo. Nell'insenatura del cripple,
Colorado, per esempio, conflitto violento ha scoppiato in 1903 fra i 
membri della federazione occidentale dei minatori (WFM) e gli 
interessi estraenti corporativi determinati per schiacciare l'unione. 
Prima che finito, trenta uomini erano guasti e l'unione è stata
sconfitta. Comunque ostile al WFM Socialista-pendente, federale 
americano del capo Di lavoro Samuel Gompers ha pubblicato 
seguente 20 giugno 1904, istruzione a sostegno dei minatori notevoli 
all'insenatura del cripple.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιστορία της αμερικανικής δύσης του ριζικού 
συνδικαλισμού στο γύρισμα του αιώνα απεικονίζει το εύρος της 
προσπάθειας κλάσης δέκατος-αιώνα. Cripple στον 
κολπίσκο, Κολοράντο, παραδείγματος χάριν, η βίαια σύγκρουση 
ξέσπησε το 1903 μεταξύ των μελών της δυτικής ομοσπονδίας των 
ανθρακωρύχων (WFM) και τα εταιρικά ενδιαφέροντα μεταλλείας 
αποφάσισαν να συντρίψουν την ένωση. Προτού να τελειώσει, 
τριάντα άτομα ήταν νεκρά και η ένωση νικήθηκε. Εν τούτοις
εχθρικός στη σοσιαλιστικός-κλίση WFM, αμερικανικός 
ομοσπονδιακός του ηγέτη Samuel Gompers εργασίας εξέδωσε 
ακόλουθου τις 20 Ιουνίου ..1904, δήλωση υπέρ των εντυπωσιακών 
ανθρακωρύχων Cripple στον κολπίσκο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La historia del oeste americana del unionism 
radical al final del siglo refleja la anchura de la lucha de clase del
diecinueveavo-siglo. En el cala del lisiado, Colorado, por 
ejemplo, conflicto violento explotó en 1903 entre los miembros de la 
federación occidental de los mineros (WFM) y los intereses que 
minaban corporativos determinados para machacar la unión. Antes
de que encima, treinta hombres eran muertos y la unión fue derrotada.
Sin embargo hostil al WFM Socialista-que se inclinaba, federal 
americano del arranque de cinta de trabajo Samuel Gompers publicó de 
junio siguiente el 20 de 1904, declaración en la ayuda de los mineros
llamativos en el cala del lisiado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086205</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103240</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/gompers-calls-for-action-over-cripple-creek</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
