<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106233</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106233</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086149</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Family amalgamation among the man-stealers."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Familie Legierung unter dem Mann-stealers."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"fusion de famille parmi l'homme-stealers."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">da "amalgamation família entre o homem-stealers."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"amalgamazione della famiglia fra 
l'uomo-stealers."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οικογενειακή συγχώνευση μεταξύ των άτομο- 
stealers."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"amalgamación de la familia entre el 
hombre-stealers."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although they vehemently opposed slavery, few antislavery advocates believed blacks and whites could or should live together as equals. Some abolitionists viewed the potential for intimacy between whites and blacks as one of the demoralizing effects of the "peculiar institution." This unlikely domestic scene in a plantation household, with slave children joining their owners at the dinner table, was published in an 1834 antislavery tract as one indication of the scandalous relations fostered by slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich sie vehement Sklaverei entgegensetzten, 
befürwortet wenig antislavery glaubte, daß Schwarze und Weiß oder 
als Gleichgestellte zusammen leben sollten konnten. Einige 
abolitionists sahen das Potential für Intimacy zwischen Weiß und 
Schwarzen als einer der Demoralisiereneffekte der "eigenartigen 
Anstalt." an Diese unwahrscheinliche inländische Szene in einem
Plantagehaushalt, wenn die Sklavenkinder ihre Inhaber am Abendtische 
verbinden, wurde in einer antislavery Fläche 1834 als eine Anzeige 
über die scandalous Relationen veröffentlicht, die durch Sklaverei 
gefördert wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien qu'elles se soient énergiquement opposées à 
l'esclavage, peu d'antiesclavagiste préconise a cru que les noirs et les 
blancs pourraient ou devraient vivre ensemble en tant qu'égales. 
Quelques abolitionnistes ont visualisé le potentiel pour 
l'intimité entre les blancs et les noirs en tant qu'un des effets de 
démoralisation "de l'établissement particulier." Cette scène 
domestique peu probable dans un ménage de plantation, avec les 
enfants slaves joignant leurs propriétaires à la table de 
dîner, a été éditée dans une région 1834 d'antiesclavagiste en tant 
qu'une indication des relations scandaleuses stimulées par 
esclavage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora oponham vehemently o slavery, pouco antislavery 
advoga acreditou que os pretos e os brancos poderiam ou devem viver 
junto como iguais. Alguns abolitionists viram o potencial para o
intimacy entre brancos e pretos como um dos efeitos demoralizing "da 
instituição peculiar." Esta cena doméstica improvável em uma
casa da plantação, com as crianças slave que juntam seus 
proprietários na tabela de jantar, foi publicada em um intervalo 1834
do antislavery como uma indicação das relações scandalous 
promovidas pelo slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se con veemenza hanno opposto lo slavery, poco 
antislavery sostiene ha creduto che i neri ed i bianchi potrebbero o 
dovrebbero vivere insieme come uguali. Alcuni abolitionists 
hanno osservato il potenziale per intimacy fra i bianchi ed i neri 
come uno degli effetti di demoralizzazione "dell'istituzione 
particolare." Questa scena domestica improbabile in una famiglia
della piantagione, con i bambini slave che uniscono i loro proprietari
alla tabella di pranzo, è stata pubblicata in un tratto 1834 di 
antislavery come un'indicazione dei rapporti scandalous promossi da 
slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και αντέταξαν βίαια τη σκλαβιά, λίγοι ενάντιοι στη
δουλεία συνήγοροι εθεώρησαν τους Μαύρους και τα λευκά θα 
μπορούσαν ή πρέπει να ζήσουν μαζί όπως είναι ίσος με. 
Μερικοί ρεφορμιστές εμφάνισαν τη δυνατότητα για την 
οικειότητα μεταξύ των λευκών και των Μαύρων ως ένα από τα 
διαφθείροντας αποτελέσματα του "ιδιαίτερου οργάνου." 
Αυτή η απίθανη εσωτερική σκηνή σε μια οικογένεια φυτειών, 
με τα παιδιά σκλάβων που ενώνουν τους ιδιοκτήτες τους στον πίνακα
γευμάτων, δημοσιεύθηκε σε ένα ενάντιο στη δουλεία κομμάτι 
1834 ως μια ένδειξη των σκανδαλωδών σχέσεων που ενθαρρύνθηκαν 
από τη σκλαβιά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque vehemente opusieron esclavitud, poco antislavery 
aboga creyó que los negros y los blancos podrían o que deben vivir 
juntos como iguales. Algunos abolitionists vieron el potencial 
para la intimidad entre los blancos y los negros como uno de los 
efectos de la desmoralización de la "institución peculiar." 
Esta escena doméstica inverosímil en una casa de la 
plantación, con los niños auxiliares ensamblando a sus propietarios 
en el vector de cena, fue publicada en una zona 1834 del antislavery 
como una indicación de las relaciones scandalous fomentadas por la 
esclavitud.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086149</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106233</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/family-amalgamation-among-the-man-stealers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
