<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107818</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107818</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206592</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Iron Hill School: An African-American One-Room School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eisen-Hügel-Schule: Eine 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Ein-Raum Schule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">École de Colline de Fer : Une École 
Afro-américaine d'Un-Pièce</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escola Do Monte Do Ferro: Uma Escola 
Africano-Americana Do Um-Quarto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scuola Della Collina Del Ferro: Una Scuola 
Africano-Americana Della Un-Stanza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχολείο Hill σιδήρου: Ένα 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικό σχολείο ένας-δωματίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escuela De la Colina Del Hierro: Una Escuela
Africano-Americana Del Uno-Cuarto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a curriculum-oriented guide focusing on a school constructed in 1923 in a rural area of northern Delaware, one of more than 80 schools for African-American children built between 1919 and 1928 as part of philanthropist Pierre Samuel du Pont's Delaware experiment. The site shows photos, maps, and diagrams about the school itself and suggests student activities ranging from philanthropy to school architecture.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Lehrplan-orientierte Anleitung, die auf 
eine Schule konzentriert, die 1923 in einem ländlichen Gebiet von 
Norddelaware, eine von mehr als 80 Schulen für die 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Kinder konstruiert wird, die zwischen 1919 
und 1928 als Teil des Philanthrop Pierre Samuel Du Pont Delaware 
Experimentes aufgebaut werden. Die Site zeigt Fotos, Karten und 
Diagramme über die Schule selbst und schlägt die 
Kursteilnehmeraktivitäten vor, die von Philanthropie zu 
Schulearchitektur reichen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un guide programme d'études-orienté se 
concentrant sur une école construite en 1923 dans une région rurale 
du Delaware nordique, une de plus de 80 écoles pour les enfants 
afro-américains construits entre 1919 et 1928 en tant qu'élément de 
l'expérience du Delaware de Pierre Samuel dupont de 
philanthrope. Le site montre des photos, des cartes, et des 
diagrammes au sujet de l'école lui-même et suggère des activités 
d'étudiant s'étendant de la philanthropie à l'architecture 
d'école.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma guia curriculum-orientada que focaliza em 
uma escola construída em 1923 em uma área rural de Delaware do 
norte, uma de mais de 80 escolas para as crianças Africano-Americanas
construídas entre 1919 e 1928 como a parte da experiência de 
Delaware de Pierre Samuel du Pont do philanthropist. O local 
mostra fotos, mapas, e diagramas sobre a escola próprios e sugere as 
atividades do estudante que variam do philanthropy à arquitetura da 
escola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una guida programma di studi-orientata che 
mette a fuoco su una scuola costruita in 1923 in una zona rurale del 
Delaware del Nord, una di più di 80 scuole per i bambini 
Africano-Americani costruiti fra 1919 e 1928 come componente 
dell'esperimento del Delaware del Pierre Samuel du Pont del 
filantropo. Il luogo mostra le foto, i programmi e gli schemi 
circa la scuola in se e suggerisce le attività dell'allievo che 
variano dalla filantropia all'architettura della scuola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένας πρόγραμμα σπουδών-προσανατολισμένος στο 
οδηγός εστιάζοντας σε ένα σχολείο που κατασκευάζεται το 1923 
σε μια αγροτική περιοχή του βόρειου Delaware, ένα από 
περισσότερα από 80 σχολεία για τα αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά παιδιά
που χτίζονται μεταξύ 1919 και 1928 ως τμήμα του πειράματος 
του Pierre Samuel Du Pont Delaware φιλανθρώπων. 
Η περιοχή εμφανίζει τις φωτογραφίες, τους χάρτες, και 
διαγράμματα για το ίδιο το σχολείο και προτείνει τις 
δραστηριότητες σπουδαστών που κυμαίνονται από τη φιλανθρωπία ως 
τη σχολική αρχιτεκτονική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una guía plan de estudios-orientada que se 
centra en una escuela construida en 1923 en un área rural de Delaware
norteño, una de más de 80 escuelas para los niños 
Africano-Americanos construidos entre 1919 y 1928 como parte del 
experimento de Delaware de Pierre Samuel du Pont del philanthropist. 
El sitio muestra las fotos, las correspondencias, y los 
diagramas sobre la escuela sí mismo y sugiere las actividades del 
estudiante que se extienden de la filantropía a la configuración de 
la escuela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206592</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107818</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/iron-hill-school-an-african-american-one-room-school</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
