<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102975</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102975</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086500</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"My Master Has Sold Albert to a Trader": Maria Perkins Writes to Her Husband, 1852</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"mein Meister hat Albert an einen Händler" 
verkauft: Maria Perkins schreibt ihrem Ehemann, 1852</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"mon maître a vendu Albert à un commerçant" : 
Maria Perkins écrit à son mari, 1852</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"meu mestre vendeu Albert a um comerciante": 
Maria Perkins escreve a seu marido, 1852</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il mio supervisore ha venduto Albert ad un 
commerciante": Maria Perkins scrive al suo marito, 1852</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο κύριός μου έχει πωλήσει Αλβέρτο σε έναν έμπορο":
Μαρία Perkins Writes στο σύζυγό της, 1852</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"mi amo ha vendido a Albert a un comerciante": 
Maria Perkins escribe a su marido, 1852</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One of the principal tragedies of slavery was family separation. In this letter, written in Charlottesville, Virginia in 1852, a woman writes to her husband about the sale of their son, Albert, to a slaver trader. Maria and Richard Perkins, who were owned by different masters, were already separated, but now Maria Perkins was witnessing the complete dissolution of her household, both people and possessions. She attempts to salvage at least her marriage by asking her husband to convince his owner buy her. Most slaves did not know how to read and write and this letter, in Mrs. Perkins' own handwriting, is unusual. This letter first came to light in 1929 when Yale historian Ulrich Bonnell Phillips published it in his  Life and Labor in the Old South , and it remains in his papers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine der allgemeinen Tragödien der Sklaverei war 
Familie Trennung. In diesem Brief geschrieben in 
Charlottesville, schreibt Virginia 1852, eine Frau ihrem Ehemann über
den Verkauf ihres Sohns, Albert, zu einem slaver Händler. Maria
und Richard Perkins, der durch unterschiedliche Meister besessen 
wurden, wurden bereits, aber jetzt Maria, die Perkins die komplette 
Auflösung ihres Haushalts zeugte, Leute und Besitz getrennt. 
Sie versucht, mindestens ihre Verbindung, indem sie ihren 
Ehemann zu retten bittet, seinen Inhaber zu überzeugen, kauft sie. 
Die meisten Sklaven konnten nicht lesen und und dieses Zeichen, 
in eigene Handschrift der Mrs Perkins' zu schreiben, ist 
ungewöhnlich. Dieses Zeichen kam zuerst, 1929 zu beleuchten, 
als Yale Historiker Ulrich Bonnell Kreuzkopf- veröffentlicht ihm in 
seiner Lebensdauer und in Arbeit im alten Süden und es in seinen 
Papieren bleiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une des principales tragédies de l'esclavage 
était séparation de famille. Dans cette lettre, écrite dans 
Charlottesville, le Virginie en 1852, une femme écrit à son mari au 
sujet de la vente de leur fils, Albert, à un commerçant de slaver. 
Maria et Richard Perkins, qui ont été possédés par 
différents maîtres, ont été déjà séparés, mais maintenant 
Maria que Perkins était témoin de la dissolution complète de son 
ménage, les gens et les possessions. Elle essaye de récupérer
au moins son mariage en demandant à son mari de convaincre son 
propriétaire l'achètent. La plupart des esclaves n'ont pas su 
lire et écrire et cette lettre, dans propre écriture de Mme 
Perkins', est peu commune. Cette lettre a émergé la première 
fois en 1929 où Phillips d'Ulrich Bonnell d'historien de Yale édité
lui dans la sa vie et travail dans les vieux Sud, et elle 
reste en son journal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma das tragédias principais do slavery era 
separação da família. Nesta letra, escrita em 
Charlottesville, Virgínia em 1852, uma mulher escreve a seu marido 
sobre a venda de seu filho, Albert, a um comerciante do slaver. 
Maria e Richard Perkins, que foi possuído por mestres 
diferentes, foram separados já, mas agora Maria que Perkins 
testemunhava a dissolução completa de sua casa,  povos e 
possessões. Tenta salvar ao menos sua união pedindo que seu 
marido convença seu proprietário compra-a. A maioria de 
escravos não souberam ler e para escrever e esta letra, em próprio 
handwriting da Sra. Perkins', é incomun. Esta letra veio 
primeiramente iluminar-se em 1929 em que Phillips de Ulrich Bonnell do
historian de Yale publicado lhe em seus vida e trabalho no sul velho, 
e remanescem em seus papéis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una delle tragedie principali di slavery era 
separazione della famiglia. In questa lettera, scritta in 
Charlottesville, la Virginia in 1852, una donna scrive al suo marito 
circa la vendita del loro figlio, Albert, ad un commerciante dello 
slaver. Maria e Richard Perkins, che è stato posseduto dai 
supervisori differenti, già sono stati separati, ma ora Maria che 
Perkins stava testimoniando la dissoluzione completa della sua 
famiglia, sia la gente che possessi. Tenta di salvare almeno la 
sua unione chiedendo al suo marito di convincere il suo proprietario 
la compra. La maggior parte dei schiavi non hanno saputo leggere
e scrivere e questa lettera, nella propria scrittura a mano della 
sig.ra Perkins, è insolita. Questa lettera in primo luogo è 
emerso in 1929 in cui "phillips" di Ulrich Bonnell dello storico di 
Yale pubblicato esso nella suoi vita e Lavoro nel vecchio sud ed 
esso rimangono in sue carte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια από τις κύριες τραγωδίες της σκλαβιάς ήταν 
οικογενειακός χωρισμός. Σε αυτήν την επιστολή, που γράφεται
σε Charlottesville, Βιρτζίνια το 1852, μια γυναίκα γράφει στο
σύζυγό της για την πώληση του γιου τους, Αλβέρτος, σε έναν 
έμπορο slaver. Η Μαρία και Richard Perkins, που ήταν
κύριες από τους διαφορετικούς κυρίους, ήταν ήδη χωρισμένες, 
αλλά τώρα η Μαρία Perkins βεβαίωνε την πλήρη διάλυση της 
οικογένειάς της, και άνθρωποι και κατοχές. Προσπαθεί να 
σώσει τουλάχιστον το γάμο της με την ερώτηση ο σύζυγός ότι της 
για να πείσει τον ιδιοκτήτη του την αγοράζει. Οι 
περισσότεροι σκλάβοι δεν ήξεραν πώς να διαβάσουν και να γράψουν 
και αυτή η επιστολή, στη γραφή κας Perkins', είναι ασυνήθιστη.
Αυτή η επιστολή ήρθε αρχικά στο φως ελαφρύς το 1929 
όταν Yale δημοσίευσε ο ιστορικός Ulrich Bonnell 
Phillips το στη ζωή του και την εργασία στον παλαιό νότο, και 
παραμένει στα έγγραφά του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una de las tragedias principales de la esclavitud 
era separación de la familia. En esta letra, escrita en 
Charlottesville, Virginia en 1852, una mujer escribe a su marido sobre
la venta de su hijo, Albert, a un comerciante del slaver. 
Separaron a Maria y a Richard Perkins, que fue poseído por 
diversos amos, ya, pero ahora Maria que Perkins atestiguaba la 
disolución completa de su casa, gente y las posesiones. Ella 
procura salvar por lo menos su unión pidiendo que su marido convenza 
a su propietario la compra. La mayoría de los esclavos no 
sabían leer y escribir y esta carta, en propio cursivo de señora 
Perkins, es inusual. Esta carta primero vino encenderse en 1929 
en que Phillips de Ulrich Bonnell del historiador de Yale publicada le
en su vida y trabajo en el viejo sur, y ella permanece en sus papeles.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086500</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102975</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/my-master-has-sold-albert-to-a-trader-maria-perkins-writes-to-her-husband-1852</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
