<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108595</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108595</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206869</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hispano Arts and Culture of the Northern Rio Grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hispano künste und Kultur des Nordrios Grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts de Hispano et culture de Rio nordique Grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes de Hispano e cultura do Rio do norte Grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti di Hispano e coltura di Rio del Nord Grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες Hispano και πολιτισμός του βόρειου Ρίο 
Grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes de Hispano y cultura de la Río norteña 
Grande</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is an online presentation of a multi-format ethnographic field collection documenting religious and secular music of Spanish-speaking residents of rural Northern New Mexico and Southern Colorado. The collection consists of approximately 8 hours of audio recordings (146 titles on 36 recording discs), 1 graphic image, and 218 pages of print material including administrative correspondence, recording logs, song text transcriptions, and publications.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Onlinedarstellung eines Multiformats, das
ethnographisch ist, auffangen die Ansammlung, die fromme und 
weltliche Musik der spanischsprechenden Bewohner von 
landwirtschaftlichem Nordnew-Mexico und von Südkolorado dokumentiert.
Die Ansammlung besteht aus ungefähr 8 Stunden Audioaufnahmen 
(146 Namen auf 6 speichernden Platten), 1 graphischem Bild und 218 
Druckseiten Material einschließlich administrative Korrespondenz, 
speichernde Protokolle, Liedtextübertragungen und Publikationen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une présentation en ligne d'une collection 
ethnographique de zone de multi-format documentant la musique 
religieuse et séculaire des résidants de langue espagnole du 
Nouveau-Mexique nordique rural et du Colorado méridional. La 
collection se compose d'approximativement 8 heures d'enregistrements 
sonores (146 titres sur 36 disques d'enregistrement), de 1 image 
graphique, et de 218 pages de matériel d'impression comprenant la 
correspondance administrative, les logarithmes naturels 
d'enregistrement, les transcriptions des textes de chanson, et les 
publications.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma apresentação em linha de uma coleção 
ethnographic do campo do multi-formato que documenta a música 
religiosa e secular de residentes spanish-speaking de Novo México do 
norte rural e de Colorado do sul. A coleção consiste em 
aproximadamente 8 horas das gravações audio (146 títulos em 36 
discos de gravação), de 1 imagem gráfica, e de 218 páginas do 
material da cópia including a correspondência administrativa, 
registros de gravação, transcrições do texto da canção, e 
publicações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una presentazione in linea di una collezione 
ethnographic del campo di multi-formato che documenta la musica 
religiosa e secolare dei residenti di lingua spagnola del Nuovo 
Messico del Nord rurale e di Colorado del sud. L'accumulazione 
consiste di circa 8 ore delle registrazioni audio (146 titoli su 36 
dischi di registrazione), di 1 immagine grafica e di 218 pagine del 
materiale della stampa compreso corrispondenza amministrativa, i libri
macchina di registrazione, le trascrizioni del testo di canzone e le 
pubblicazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση παρουσίαση μιας 
εθνογραφικής συλλογής πεδίων πολυ-μορφής τεκμηριώνοντας τη 
θρησκευτική και κοσμική μουσική των ισπανόφωνων κατοίκων του 
αγροτικού βόρειου New Mexico και του νότιου Κολοράντο. 
Η συλλογή αποτελείται από περίπου 8 ώρες ηχητικών 
καταγραφών (146 τίτλοι σε 36 καταγράφοντας δίσκους), 1 
γραφικής εικόνας, και 218 σελίδων του υλικού τυπωμένων υλών 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της διοικητικής αλληλογραφίας, των 
καταγράφοντας κούτσουρων, των μεταγραφών κειμένων τραγουδιού, και
των δημοσιεύσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una presentación en línea de una colección 
etnográfica del campo del multi-formato que documenta la música 
religiosa y secular de residentes de habla hispana de New México 
norteño rural y de Colorado meridional. La colección consiste 
en aproximadamente 8 horas de las grabaciones audio (146 títulos en 
36 discos de registración), de 1 imagen gráfica, y de 218 
paginaciones de material de la impresión incluyendo correspondencia 
administrativa, registros de registración, transcripciones del texto 
de la canción, y publicaciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206869</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108595</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hispano-arts-and-culture-of-the-northern-rio-grande</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
