<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213083</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Water What-ifs: Water Quality and Dissolved Oxygen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wasser Was-What-ifs: Wasserqualität und 
aufgelöster Sauerstoff</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce qui-Statistiques financière internationale de 
l'Eau : Qualité de l'eau et oxygène dissous</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Que-What-ifs Da Água: Qualidade de água e 
oxigênio dissolvido</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Che cosa-SFI (statistiche finanziarie 
internazionali) Dell'Acqua: Qualità dell'acqua ed ossigeno 
disciolto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τι-ηφς ύδατος: Ποιότητα νερού και διαλυμένο 
οξυγόνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Que'-What-ifs Del Agua: Calidad del agua y 
oxígeno disuelto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Science Junction website features general information and three lesson plans about dissolved oxygen geared toward middle and high school students. Lessons cover topics such as what dissolved oxygen is, why it is important, and how decomposition of organic material affects dissolved oxygen. The third lesson includes an activity in which students are instructed to design an experiment to test effects of changes in dissolved oxygen concentration. The lessons meet several National Science Education Standards, Delaware science standards, and North Carolina competency goals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Wissenschaft Verzweigung Web site Merkmale 
allgemeinen Informationen und drei Lektionpläne über aufgelösten 
Sauerstoff übersetzten in Richtung zu den mittlere und High School 
Kursteilnehmern. Lektionabdeckungthemen wie was sich auflösten,
Sauerstoff ist, warum es wichtig ist und wie Aufspaltung des 
organischen Materials aufgelösten Sauerstoff beeinflußt. Die 
dritte Lektion schließt eine Aktivität ein, in der Kursteilnehmer 
angewiesen werden, ein Experiment zu konzipieren, um Effekte der 
Änderungen in aufgelöster Sauerstoffkonzentration zu prüfen. 
Die Lektionen Standards treffen einiger nationaler Wissenschaft 
Ausbildung Standards, Delawares Wissenschaft und Nord-Carolina 
Kompetenzziele.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces informations générales de dispositifs de 
site Web de jonction de la Science et trois plans de leçon sur 
l'oxygène dissous ont embrayé vers des étudiants de lycée moyen 
et. Les sujets de couverture de leçons tels que ce qui se sont 
dissous l'oxygène est, pourquoi il est important, et comment 
décomposition de matériel organique affecte l'oxygène dissous. 
La troisième leçon inclut une activité dans laquelle des 
étudiants sont chargés de concevoir une expérience pour tester des 
effets des changements de la concentration dissous en oxygène. 
Les leçons des normes rencontrent de plusieurs de la Science 
d'éducation normes nationales, du Delaware science, et des buts 
du nord de compétence de la Caroline.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta informação geral das características do 
Web site da junção da ciência e três plantas da lição sobre o 
oxigênio dissolvido engrenaram para estudantes da High School média 
e. Os tópicos da tampa das lições tais como o que se 
dissolveram o oxigênio são, porque ele são importante, e como 
decomposition do material orgânico afeta o oxigênio dissolvido. 
A terceira lição inclui uma atividade em que os estudantes 
são instruídos projetar uma experiência testar efeitos das 
mudanças na concentração de oxigênio dissolvida. As lições
encontram-se com padrões da ciência de diversos da ciência da 
instrução padrões nacionais, de Delaware, e de competency de 
North.carolina objetivos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Queste generalità delle caratteristiche di Web 
site della giunzione di scienza e tre programmi di lezione circa 
ossigeno disciolto hanno innestato verso gli allievi della High School
centrale e. I soggetti della copertura di lezioni quale che cosa
si sono dissolti ossigeno è, perchè esso sono importante e come la 
decomposizione di materiale organico interessa l'ossigeno disciolto. 
La terza lezione include un'attività in cui gli allievi sono 
incaricati di progettare un esperimento per verificare gli effetti dei
cambiamenti nel tenore in ossigeno dissolto. Le lezioni vengono 
a contatto standard di scienza di parecchi di scienza di formazione 
standard nazionali, del Delaware ed obiettivi di competenza del 
North.carolina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος συνδέσεων επιστήμης χαρακτηρίζει 
γενικές πληροφορίες και τρία σχέδια μαθήματος για το διαλυμένο 
οξυγόνο που συνδέεται προς τους σπουδαστές μεσών και γυμνασίου. 
Τα θέματα κάλυψης μαθημάτων όπως αυτό που διάλυσε το 
οξυγόνο είναι, γιατί είναι σημαντικό, και πώς η αποσύνθεση του 
οργανικού υλικού έχει επιπτώσεις στο διαλυμένο οξυγόνο. Το
τρίτο μάθημα περιλαμβάνει μια δραστηριότητα στην οποία οι 
σπουδαστές καθοδηγούνται για να σχεδιάσουν ένα πείραμα για να 
εξετάσουν τα αποτελέσματα των αλλαγών στη διαλυμένη συγκέντρωση 
οξυγόνου. Τα μαθήματα ανταποκρίνονται σε διάφορα εθνικά 
πρότυπα εκπαίδευσης επιστήμης, τα πρότυπα επιστήμης του 
Delaware, και τους στόχους ικανότητας της βόρειας Καρολίνας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta información de carácter general de las 
características del Web site de la ensambladura de la ciencia y tres 
planes de la lección sobre el oxígeno disuelto engranaron hacia 
estudiantes de la High School media y secundaria. Los asuntos de
la cubierta de las lecciones tales como qué disolvieron oxígeno es, 
porqué él es importante, y cómo descomposición del material 
orgánico afecta el oxígeno disuelto. La tercera lección 
incluye una actividad en la cual manden a los estudiantes diseñar un 
experimento para probar efectos de cambios en la concentración de 
oxígeno disuelta. Las lecciones resuelven los estándares de la
ciencia de varios de la ciencia de la educación estándares 
nacionales, de Delaware, y las metas de la capacidad de Carolina del 
Norte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:APRIL J. CLEVELAND
FN:APRIL J. CLEVELAND
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SCIENCE JUNCTION, NC STATE UNIVERSITY
FN:SCIENCE JUNCTION, NC STATE UNIVERSITY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213083</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107160</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/water-what-ifs-water-quality-and-dissolved-oxygen</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
