<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106947</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106947</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203996</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Miller Museum Online Exhibit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Miller Museum Onlineausstellung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Objet exposé En ligne de Musée de Miller</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exibição Em linha Do Museu De Moleiro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esposizione In linea Del Museo Del Mugnaio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε απευθείας σύνδεση έκθεμα μουσείων μυλωνάδων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Objeto expuesto En línea Del Museo De Molinero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website is part of the online version of the Miller Museum of Geology (Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario). The website includes exhibits on the origin of the Earth, of cells, the Ediacaran fauna, and other assemblages of Proterozoic animals. This is a useful site for images and information regarding the dawn of animal life on Earth.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site ist ein Teil der Onlineversion des 
Miller Museums von Geologie (Universität der Königin, Kingston, 
Ontario). Die Web site schließt Ausstellungen auf dem Ursprung 
der Masse, der Zellen, der Ediacaran Fauna und anderer Assemblierungen
der Proterozoic Tiere ein. Dieses ist eine nützliche Site zu 
Bildern und der Information betreffend ist die Dämmerung der 
Tierlebensdauer auf Masse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web fait partie de la version en ligne du 
musée de Miller de la géologie (l'université de la Reine, Kingston,
Ontario). Le site Web inclut des objets exposés sur l'origine 
de la terre, des cellules, de la faune d'Ediacaran, et d'autres 
assemblages des animaux protérozoïques. C'est un site utile 
pour des images et l'information concernant l'aube de la vie animale 
sur terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site é parte da versão em linha do 
museu de Moleiro da geologia (universidade da rainha, Kingston, 
Ontário). O Web site inclui exibições na origem da terra, das
pilhas, do fauna de Ediacaran, e de outros assemblages de animais 
proterozoic. Este é um local útil para imagens e informação 
a respeito do alvorecer da vida animal na terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site fa parte della versione in linea 
del museo del Mugnaio della geologia (università della regina, 
Kingston, Ontario). Il Web site include le esposizioni 
sull'origine della terra, delle cellule, della fauna di Ediacaran e di
altri raduni degli animali proterozoic. Ciò è un luogo utile 
per le immagini e le informazioni per quanto riguarda l'alba di vita 
animale su terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος είναι μέρος της σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση έκδοσης του μουσείου μυλωνάδων της γεωλογίας 
(πανεπιστήμιο της βασίλισσας, Κίνγκστον, Οντάριο). Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει τα εκθέματα στην προέλευση της γης, των 
κυττάρων, της πανίδας Ediacaran, και άλλων συναθροίσεων των 
proterozoic ζώων. Αυτό είναι μια χρήσιμη περιοχή για τις
εικόνες και τις πληροφορίες σχετικά με την αυγή της ζωικής ζωής 
στη γη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site es parte de la versión en línea 
del museo de Molinero de la geología (universidad de la reina, 
Kingston, Ontario). El Web site incluye objetos expuestos en el 
origen de la tierra, de células, de la fauna de Ediacaran, y de otras
ensambladuras de animales proterozoic. Esto es un sitio útil 
para las imágenes y la información con respecto al amanecer de la 
vida animal en la tierra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203996</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106947</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/miller-museum-online-exhibit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
