<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105717</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105717</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206460</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Siege and Battle of Corinth: A New Kind of War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Belagerung und die Schlacht von Korinth: 
Eine neue Art Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le siège et la bataille de Corinthe : Un 
nouveau genre de guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O siege e a batalha de Corinth: Um tipo novo
da guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il siege e la battaglia di Corinth: Un nuovo
genere di guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πολιορκία και η μάχη Corinth: Ένα νέο 
είδος πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El sitio y la batalla de Corinth: Una nueva 
clase de guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of two Civil War engagements near Corinth, a small Mississippi town established in the 1850s where two railroads crossed. On October 2, 1862, Confederates attacked Union forces that occupied the town and that had built extensive entrenchments and earthworks (which are featured at this website). By nightfall the next day, 2,360 Union and 4,848 Confederate men were dead or wounded.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte von zwei 
Bürgerkriegverpflichtungen nahe Korinth, eine kleine Mississippi 
Stadt, die im 1850s hergestellt wird, in dem zwei Eisenbahnen 
kreuzten. An Oktober 2, 1862, Verbündete nahm Anschlußkräfte 
in Angriff, die die Stadt besetzten und die umfangreiche Entrenchments
und Bodenbewegungen aufgebaut hatten (die an dieser Web site 
gekennzeichnet werden). Durch das Dunkelwerden, das am nächsten
Tag ist, waren 2.360 Anschluß- und 4.848 verbündetemänner tot oder 
verletzt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire de deux engagements de guerre 
civile ville près de Corinthe, une petite Mississippi établie dans 
le 1850s où deux chemins de fer ont croisé. 2 octobre 1862, 
confédérés a attaqué les forces des syndicats qui ont occupé la 
ville et qui avaient construit les retranchements étendus et les 
terrassements (qui sont décrits à ce site Web). Par la tombée
de la nuit le jour suivant, 2.360 4.848 confédérés hommes des 
syndicats et étaient morts ou blessés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história de dois acoplamentos da guerra 
civil perto uma cidade pequena de Corinth, Mississippi estabelecida no
1850s onde duas estradas de ferro se cruzaram. Outubro em 2, 
1862, confederados atacou as forças da união que ocuparam a cidade e
que tinham construído os entrenchments e os earthworks extensivos 
(que são caracterizados neste Web site). Pelo anoitecer no dia 
seguinte, 2.360 4.848 os confederate homens da união e eram 
inoperantes ou feridos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia di due impegni di guerra civile 
vicino città a Corinth, una piccola Mississippi stabilita nel 1850s 
dove due ferrovie hanno attraversato. Il 2 ottobre 1862, 
confederati ha attacato le forze del sindacato che hanno occupato la 
città e che avevano costruito i vasti entrenchments e sterri (che 
sono descritti a questo Web site). Dal tramonto il giorno 
seguente, 2.360 4.848 e del sindacato uomini confederati erano guasti 
o ferriti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία δύο δεσμεύσεων εμφύλιου πολέμου 
κοντά σε Corinth, μια μικρή πόλη του Μισισιπή που καθιερώνεται
στο 1850s όπου δύο σιδηρόδρομοι που διασχίζονται. Στις 2 
Οκτωβρίου ..1862, οι σύμμαχοι επιτέθηκαν στις δυνάμεις ένωσης 
που κατέλαβαν την πόλη και που είχαν χτίσει τις εκτενείς 
περιχαρακώσεις και τα χωματουργικά έργα (που χαρακτηρίζονται σε 
αυτόν τον ιστοχώρο). Από το σούρουπο επόμενη ημέρα, 
2.360 4.848 ομόσπονδων άτομα ένωσης και ήταν νεκρές ή 
πληγωμένος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia de dos contratos de la guerra 
civil cerca Mississippi una ciudad pequeña de Corinth, establecida en
el 1850s donde dos ferrocarriles se cruzaron. 2 de octubre de
1862, confederatos atacó las fuerzas de la unión que ocuparon la 
ciudad y que habían construido los atrincheramientos y los 
terraplenes extensos (que se ofrecen en este Web site). Por el 
anochecer el día siguiente, 2.360 4.848 confederados hombres de la 
unión y eran muertos o heridos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206460</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105717</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-siege-and-battle-of-corinth-a-new-kind-of-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
