<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107844</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107844</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086905</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Bostonians paying the excise-man, or tarring and feathering."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das den Steuereinnehmer zahlende tarring und mit 
Federn versehende Bostonians oder."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le Bostonians payant l'excise-man, ou tarring et 
faisant varier le pas."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o Bostonians que paga o excise-man, ou tarring e 
feathering."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il Bostonians che paga il excise-man, o tarring e
mettente le piume."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το Bostonians που πληρώνουν το φόρος-άτομο, ή και 
επένδυση με φτερά."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el Bostonians que paga al excise-man, o tarring y
emplumando."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A 1774 British print depicted the tarring and feathering of Boston Commissioner of Customs John Malcolm. Tarring and feathering was a ritual of humiliation and public warning that stopped just short of serious injury. Victims included British officials such as Malcolm and American merchants who violated non-importation by importing British goods. Other forms of public humiliation included daubing victims' homes with the contents of cesspits, or actual violence against property, such as the burning of stately homes and carriages. This anti-Patriot print showed Customs Commissioner Malcolm being attacked under the Liberty Tree by several Patriots, including a leather-aproned artisan, while the Boston Tea Party occurred in the background. In fact, the Tea Party had taken place four weeks earlier.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Drucken 1774 Briten bildlich darstellten das Tarring und 
das Mit Federn versehen des Boston Beauftragten der Gewohnheiten John 
Malcolm. Tarring und Gefieder waren ein Ritual von Erniedrigung-
und Öffentlichkeits-WARNING, das gerechten Kurzschluß der ernsten 
Verletzung stoppte. Opfer enthielten britische Beamte wie 
Malcolm und amerikanische Kaufleute, die Nichtimport verletzten, indem
sie britische Waren importierten. Andere Formulare der 
allgemeinen Erniedrigung schlossen Häuser der feuerbeständige 
Beschichtung Opfer mit dem Inhalt von cesspits oder tatsächliche 
Gewalttätigkeit gegen Eigenschaft, wie das Brennen der prächtigen 
Häuser und der Wagen ein. Dieser Anti-Patriot Druck zeigte 
Gewohnheiten Beauftragten Malcolm, der unter dem Freiheit-Baum von 
einigen Patrioten, einschließlich einen Leder-aproned Handwerker 
angegriffen wurde, während die Boston Tee-Partei im 
Hintergrund auftrat. Tatsächlich hatte die Tee-Partei 
vier Wochen früh stattgefunden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les 1774 Anglais impriment ont dépeint tarring et faire 
varier le pas du commissaire de Boston des coutumes John Malcolm. 
Tarring et changement de pas étaient un rituel de 
l'avertissement d'humiliation et de public qui a arrêté le short 
juste des dommages sérieux. Les victimes ont inclus les 
fonctionnaires britanniques tels que Malcolm et les négociants 
américains qui ont violé la non-importation en important les 
marchandises britanniques. D'autres formes d'humiliation 
publique ont inclus enduire les maisons des victimes avec 
les teneurs des cesspits, ou la violence réelle contre la 
propriété, telle que la brûlure des maisons majestueuses et des 
chariots. Cette copie d'anti-Patriote a montré commissaire 
Malcolm de douane étant attaqué sous l'arbre de liberté par 
plusieurs patriotes, y compris un artisan de cuir-aproned, alors que 
la partie de thé de Boston se produisait dans le fond. En fait,
la partie de thé avait eu lieu pendant quatre semaines plus tôt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">1774 Ingleses imprimem descreveram tarring e feathering do
comissário de Boston dos costumes John Malcolm. Tarring e o 
feathering eram um ritual do aviso do humiliation e do público que 
parasse o short justo de ferimento sério. As vítimas 
incluíram os oficiais britânicos tais como Malcolm e os comerciantes
americanos que violated o non-non-importation importando bens 
britânicos. Outros formulários do humiliation público 
incluíram HOME das vítimas do daubing com os índices dos cesspits, 
ou a violência real de encontro à propriedade, tal como a queimadura
de HOME e de carros stately. Esta cópia do anti-anti-Patriot 
mostrou o comissário Malcolm dos costumes que está sendo atacado sob
a árvore da liberdade por diversos patriots, including um artisan do 
couro-aproned, quando o partido do chá de Boston ocorreu no fundo. 
No fato, o partido do chá tinha ocorrido quatro semanas mais 
cedo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">1774 Britannici stampano hanno descritto tarring e mettere
le piume del commissario de Boston delle abitudini John Malcolm. 
Tarring ed il piumaggio erano un rituale di avvertimento del 
pubblico e di humiliation che ha arrestato lo short giusto della 
ferita seria. Le vittime hanno incluso i funzionari britannici 
quale Malcolm ed i commercianti americani che hanno violato 
l'non-importazione importando le merci britanniche. Altre forme 
di humiliation pubblico hanno incluso le sedi delle vittime del 
daubing con il contenuto dei cesspits, o la violenza reale contro la 
proprietà, come bruciarsi delle sedi e dei carrelli stately. 
Questa stampa del anti-anti-Patriot ha mostrato il commissario 
Malcolm di dogana che è attacato sotto l'albero di libertà da 
parecchi patriots, compreso un artigianale del cuoio-aproned, mentre 
il partito del tè de Boston si è presentato nei precedenti. 
Infatti, il partito del tè aveva avvenuto più presto quattro 
settimane.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια βρετανική τυπωμένη ύλη 1774 απεικόνισε και την 
επένδυση με φτερά του Επιτρόπου της Βοστώνης του τελωνείου 
John Malcolm. Το Tarring και feathering ήταν ένα 
τελετουργικό της ταπείνωσης και της δημόσιας προειδοποίησης που 
σταμάτησε ακριβώς λίγο πριν από το σοβαρό τραυματισμό. Τα 
θύματα περιέλαβαν τους βρετανικούς ανώτερους υπαλλήλους όπως ο 
Malcolm και οι αμερικανικοί έμποροι που παραβίασαν την 
μη-εισαγωγή με την εισαγωγή των βρετανικών αγαθών. Αλλες 
μορφές της δημόσιας ταπείνωσης περιέλαβαν τα σπίτια των θυμάτων 
σοβά με το περιεχόμενο των cesspits, ή την πραγματική βία 
ενάντια στην ιδιοκτησία, όπως το κάψιμο των εντυπωσιακών σπιτιών
και των μεταφορών. Αυτή η τυπωμένη ύλη αντι-πατριωτών 
εμφάνισε στο τελωνείο Επίτροπο Malcolm που επιτίθεται κάτω 
από το δέντρο ελευθερίας από διάφορους πατριώτες, η συμπερίληψη
του α δερμάτινος- χειροτεχνικός, ενώ το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος 
τσαγιού της Βοστώνης εμφανίστηκε στο υπόβαθρο. Στην 
πραγματικότητα, το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος τσαγιού είχε 
πραγματοποιηθεί τέσσερις εβδομάδες νωρίτερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">1774 Británicos imprimen representaron tarring y emplumar
de la comisión de Boston de los costumbres Juan Malcolm. 
Tarring y el cambio de paso eran un ritual de la humillación y de
la alerta del público que paró cortocircuito justo de lesión seria.
Las víctimas incluyeron a los funcionarios británicos tales 
como Malcolm y a comerciantes americanos que violaron la 
no-importacio'n importando mercancías británicas. Otras formas
de humillación pública incluyeron los hogares de las víctimas del 
daubing con el contenido de cesspits, o violencia real contra 
característica, tal como quemarse de hogares majestuosos y de 
carros. Esta impresión del contra-Patriota mostró a comisión 
Malcolm de los costumbres que era atacado bajo el árbol de la 
libertad por varios patriotas, incluyendo un artesano del 
cuero-aproned, mientras que el partido del té de Boston ocurrió en 
el fondo. En hecho, el partido del té había ocurrido cuatro 
semanas anterior.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086905</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107844</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-bostonians-paying-the-excise-man-or-tarring-and-feathering</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
