<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106284</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106284</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205396</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Young and the Restless: The Oxbow School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Junge und das rastlose: Die Oxbow 
Schule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les jeunes et l'agité : L'École d'Oxbow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os jovens e o agitado: A Escola De Oxbow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I giovani e l'agitato: La Scuola Di Oxbow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι νεολαίες και ο ανήσυχος: Το σχολείο Oxbow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los jóvenes y el agitado: La Escuela De 
Oxbow</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">SPARK follows a class of young visual artists as they progress through a semester at The Oxbow School in Napa Valley, an intensive arts program for high school students. This Educator Guide is about Oxbow and its sister programs - intensives that involve high-level studio work and critique for students in an atelier environment.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">FUNKEN folgt einer Kategorie junge Sichtkünstler,
während sie durch ein Semester an der Oxbow Schule in der Napa Senke 
weiterkommen, einem intensiven kunstprogramm für High School 
Kursteilnehmer. Diese Erzieher-Anleitung ist über Oxbow und 
seine Schwesterprogramme - intensives, die hochqualifizierte 
Studioarbeit und -kritik für Kursteilnehmer in eine 
Atelierumgebung miteinbeziehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'ÉTINCELLE suit une classe de jeunes artistes 
visuels pendant qu'ils progressent par un semestre à l'école d'Oxbow
en vallée de Napa, un programme intensif d'arts pour des étudiants 
de lycée. Ce guide d'éducateur est au sujet d'Oxbow et de ses 
programmes de soeur - les intensives qui impliquent le travail et la 
critique à niveau élevé de studio pour des étudiants dans un 
environnement d'atelier.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A FAÍSCA segue uma classe de artistas visuais 
novos enquanto progridem com um semester na escola de Oxbow no vale de
Napa, um programa intensive das artes para estudantes da High School. 
Esta guia do educador é sobre Oxbow e seus programas da irmã -
os intensives que envolvem o trabalho e a crítica high-level do 
estúdio para estudantes em um ambiente do atelier.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La SCINTILLA segue un codice categoria degli 
artisti visivi giovani mentre progrediscono con un semestre alla 
scuola di Oxbow in valle di Napa, un programma intenso di arti per gli
allievi della High School. Questa guida dell'educatore è circa 
Oxbow ed i relativi programmi della sorella - intensives che 
coinvolgono il lavoro e la valutazione ad alto livello dell'studio per
gli allievi in un ambiente dell'atelier.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ΣΠΙΝΘΗΡΑΣ ακολουθεί μια κλάση των νέων εικαστηκών 
καλλιτεχνών καθώς προχωρούν μέσω ενός εξαμήνου στο σχολείο 
Oxbow Napa στην κοιλάδα, ένα εντατικό πρόγραμμα τεχνών για 
τους σπουδαστές γυμνασίου. Αυτός ο οδηγός εκπαιδευτικών 
είναι για Oxbow και τα προγράμματα αδελφών του - intensives 
που περιλαμβάνουν την υψηλού επιπέδου εργασία και την κριτική 
στούντιο για τους σπουδαστές σε ένα περιβάλλον ατελιέ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La CHISPA sigue a clase de artistas visuales 
jóvenes como progresan en un semestre en la escuela de Oxbow en el 
valle de Napa, un programa intensivo de los artes para los estudiantes
de la High School secundaria. Esta guía del educador está 
sobre Oxbow y sus programas de la hermana - los intensives que 
implican el trabajo y la crítica de alto nivel del estudio para los 
estudiantes en un ambiente del taller.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205396</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106284</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-young-and-the-restless-the-oxbow-school</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
