<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103804</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103804</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206598</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tonto National Monument: Saving a National Treasure</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tonto Nationales Denkmal: Sichern eines 
nationalen Schatzes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Monument National de Tonto : Sauvegarder un 
trésor national</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Monumento Nacional De Tonto: Conservando um 
tesouro nacional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Monumento Nazionale Di Tonto: Salvare un 
tesoro nazionale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικό μνημείο Tonto: Διάσωση ενός εθνικού 
θησαυρού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Monumento Nacional De Tonto: Salvar un 
tesoro nacional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of the Salado people, who thrived in the Arizona valley where Tonto Creek joins the Salt River (1050-1450 AD). The Salado culture combined customs of several American Indian groups. They channeled the river to create farmland in the desert. They built Pueblo-style buildings. They left no written records. This monument, established in December 1907, was among the first sites protected under the Antiquities Act of 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte der Salado Leute, die in 
der Arizonasenke vorwärtskamen, in der Tonto Nebenfluß den 
Salz-Fluß (ANZEIGE 1050-1450) verbindet. Die Salado Kultur 
kombinierte Gewohnheiten einiger indianischer Gruppen. Sie 
lenkten den Fluß, um Ackerland in der Wüste herzustellen. Sie 
bauten Pueblo-Art Gebäude auf. Sie ließen keine schriftlichen 
Sätze. Dieses Denkmal, hergestellt im Dezember 1907, gehörte 
zu den ersten Sites, die unter der Antiquitäten Tat von 1906 
geschützt wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire des personnes de Salado, qui ont 
prospéré dans la vallée de l'Arizona où la crique de Tonto joint 
le fleuve de sel (ANNONCE 1050-1450). La culture de Salado a 
combiné des coutumes de plusieurs groupes indiens. Ils ont 
creusé des rigoles le fleuve pour créer des champs dans le désert. 
Ils ont construit des bâtiments de Pueblo-modèle. Ils 
n'ont laissé aucun enregistrement écrit. Ce monument, établi 
en décembre 1907, était parmi les premiers sites protégés sous la 
Loi d'antiquités de 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história dos povos de Salado, que 
prosperaram no vale do arizona onde o creek de Tonto junta o rio de 
sal (ANÚNCIO 1050-1450). A cultura de Salado combinou costumes 
de diversos grupos indian americanos. Canalizaram o rio para 
criar a terra no deserto. Construíram edifícios do 
Povoado-estilo. Não deixaram nenhum registro escrito. 
Este monumento, estabelecido em dezembro 1907, era entre os 
primeiros locais protegidos sob o ato dos antiquities de 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia della gente di Salado, che ha 
prosperato nella valle dell'Arizona in cui l'insenatura di Tonto 
unisce il fiume del sale (ANNUNCIO 1050-1450). La coltura di 
Salado ha unito le abitudini di parecchi gruppi indiani americani. 
Hanno scavato canali il fiume per creare il terreno coltivabile 
nel deserto. Hanno costruito le costruzioni di Pueblo-stile. 
Non hanno lasciato record scritti. Questo monumento, 
stabilito nel mese di dicembre del 1907, era fra i primi luoghi 
protetti a norma della legge di antichità di 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία των ανθρώπων Salado, οι οποίοι 
αναπτύχτηκαν στην κοιλάδα της Αριζόνα όπου ο κολπίσκος Tonto 
ενώνει τον αλατισμένο ποταμό (ΑΓΓΕΛΙΑ 1050-1450). Ο 
πολιτισμός Salado συνδύασε το τελωνείο διάφορων αμερικανικών 
ινδικών ομάδων. Διοχέτευσαν τον ποταμό για να δημιουργήσουν
το καλλιεργήσιμο έδαφος στην έρημο. Έχτισαν τα κτήρια 
πuεψλο-ύφους. Δεν άφησαν κανένα γραπτό αρχείο. Αυτό 
το μνημείο, που καθιερώθηκε τον Δεκέμβριο του 1907, ήταν 
μεταξύ των πρώτων περιοχών που προστατεύθηκαν στο πλαίσιο του 
νόμου αρχαιοτήτων του 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia de la gente de Salado, que 
prosperó en el valle del Arizona donde el cala de Tonto ensambla el 
río de la sal (ANUNCIO 1050-1450). La cultura de Salado 
combinó costumbres de varios grupos indios americanos. 
Acanalaron el río para crear tierras de labrantío en el 
desierto. Construyeron edificios del Pueblo-estilo. No 
dejaron ningún expediente escrito. Este monumento, establecido 
en diciembre de 1907, estaba entre los primeros sitios protegidos bajo
acto de las antigüedades de 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206598</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103804</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tonto-national-monument-saving-a-national-treasure</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
