<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108587</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108587</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206961</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Votes for Women: Selections from NAWSA Collection, 1848-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stimmen für Frauen: Anwählungen von NAWSA 
Ansammlung, 1848-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voix pour des femmes : Sélections à partir
de la collection de NAWSA, 1848-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Votos para mulheres: Seleções da coleção
de NAWSA, 1848-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Voti per le donne: Selezioni 
dall'accumulazione di NAWSA, 1848-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψηφοφορίες για τις γυναίκες: Επιλογές από 
NAWSA τη συλλογή, 1848-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Votos para las mujeres: Selecciones de la 
colección de NAWSA, 1848-1921</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">consists of 167 books, pamphlets, and other artifacts documenting the suffrage campaign. They are a subset of the Library's collection donated by Carrie Chapman Catt, longtime president of the National American Woman Suffrage Association. The collection includes works from the libraries of other members and officers of the organization, including, Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Susan B. Anthony, Lucy Stone, Alice Stone Blackwell, Julia Ward Howe, Elizabeth Smith Miller, and Mary A. Livermore.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">aus 167 Büchern, Flugschriften und anderen 
Kunstprodukten besteht das Dokumentieren der Stimmrechtkampagne. 
Sie sind eine Teilmenge der Ansammlung der Bibliothek, die von 
Carrie Chapman Catt, langfristiger Präsident der nationalen 
amerikanischen Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung gespendet wird. Die 
Ansammlung schließt Arbeiten von den Bibliotheken anderer Bauteile 
und Offiziere der Organisation, einschließlich, von Elizabeth Cady 
Stanton, Susan B. Anthony, Lucy Stein, Alice Steinblackwell, Julia 
Bezirk Howe, Elizabeth Smith Miller und Mary A. Livermore ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">se compose de 167 livres, de brochures, et 
d'autres objets façonnés documentant la campagne de suffrage. 
Ils sont un sous-ensemble de la collection de la bibliothèque 
donnée par Carrie Chapman Catt, président à long terme de 
l'association américaine nationale de suffrage de femme. La 
collection inclut des travaux des bibliothèques d'autres membres et 
officiers de l'organisation, y compris, d'Elizabeth Cady Stanton, 
Susan B. Anthony, pierre de Lucy, Alice Blackwell en pierre, salle de 
Julia Howe, Elizabeth Smith Miller, et Mary A. Livermore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">consiste em 167 livros, em panfletos, e em outros 
artifacts que documentam a campanha do suffrage. São um 
subconjunto da coleção da biblioteca doada por Carrie Chapman Catt, 
presidente longtime da associação americana nacional do suffrage da 
mulher. A coleção inclui trabalhos das bibliotecas de outros 
membros e oficiais da organização, including, de Elizabeth Cady 
Stanton, Susan B. Anthony, pedra de Lucy, Alice Blackwell de pedra, 
divisão Howe, Elizabeth Smith Moleiro, e Mary A. Livermore de Julia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiste di 167 libri, degli opuscoli e di altri 
manufatti che documentano la campagna di suffrage. Sono un 
sottoinsieme dell'accumulazione delle biblioteche donata da Carrie 
Chapman Catt, presidente da molto tempo dell'associazione americana 
nazionale di suffrage della donna. L'accumulazione include gli 
impianti dalle librerie di altri membri ed ufficiali 
dell'organizzazione, compreso, da Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Susan B. 
Anthony, la pietra di Lucy, Alice Blackwell di pietra, il quartiere 
Howe, Elizabeth Smith Mugnaio e Mary A. Livermore di Julia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποτελείται από 167 βιβλία, τα τεύχη, και άλλα 
χειροποίητα αντικείμενα τεκμηριώνοντας την εκστρατεία ψήφου. 
Είναι ένα υποσύνολο της συλλογής της βιβλιοθήκης που 
δίνεται από Carrie γυρολόγος Catt, μακροπρόθεσμος Πρόεδρος 
της εθνικής αμερικανικής ένωσης ψήφου γυναικών. Η συλλογή 
περιλαμβάνει τις εργασίες από τις βιβλιοθήκες άλλων μελών και 
ανώτερων υπαλλήλων της οργάνωσης, συμπεριλαμβανομένου, 
Elizabeth Cady Stanton, της Susan B. Anthony, πέτρα
Lucy, της Alice Stone Blackwell, της Julia Ward 
Howe, Elizabeth Smith Miller, και Mary A. 
Livermore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">consiste en 167 libros, los folletos, y otros 
artefactos que documentan la campaña del sufragio. Son un 
subconjunto de la colección de la biblioteca donada por Carrie 
Chapman Catt, presidente de largo plazo de la asociación americana 
nacional del sufragio de la mujer. La colección incluye 
trabajos de las bibliotecas de otros miembros y oficiales de la 
organización, incluyendo, de Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Susan B. 
Anthony, piedra de Lucy, Alicia Blackwell de piedra, sala Howe, 
Elizabeth Smith Molinero, y Maria A. Livermore de Julia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206961</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108587</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/votes-for-women-selections-from-nawsa-collection-1848-1921</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
