<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107080</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107080</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206666</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Helping Children Prepare for Disasters</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Helfende Kinder bereiten sich für Unfälle vor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les enfants aidants se préparent aux désastres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As crianças de ajuda preparam-se para disastres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I bambini d'assistenza si preparano per i 
disastri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βοηθώντας τα παιδιά να προετοιμαστούν για τις 
καταστροφές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los niños que ayudan se preparan para los 
desastres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps kids put together a disaster supply kit, set up a family disaster plan, read about what they might feel in a disaster, learn about pet protection, read a series of stories about kids who are always prepared for a natural disaster, and join Project IMPACT, a community damage mitigation program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Zicklein fügten einen 
Unfallversorgungsmaterialsatz zusammen, aufgestellt einem Familie 
Unfalplan, gelesen über, was sie in einen Unfall glauben konnten, 
über Haustierschutz zu erlernen, lasen eine Reihe Geschichten über 
Zicklein, die immer für eine Naturkatastrophe vorbereitet werden, und
Projekt AUSWIRKUNG, ein Gemeinschaftsbeschädigung Mitigationprogramm 
zu verbinden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les gosses d'aides ont remonté un lot des 
consommables de désastre, ont installé un plan de désastre de 
famille, eu connaissance de ce que se sentir ils pourraient dans un 
désastre, se renseigner sur la protection d'animal de compagnie, ont 
lu une série d'histoires au sujet des gosses qui sont toujours 
disposés pour un désastre normal, et joindre l'IMPACT de projet, un 
programme de réduction de dommages de la communauté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os miúdos das ajudas uniram um kit de suprimento 
do disastre, ajustado acima uma planta do disastre da família, lida 
sobre o que puderam sentir em um disastre, para aprender sobre a 
proteção do animal de estimação, leram uma série das histórias 
sobre os miúdos que são preparados sempre para um disastre natural, 
e para juntar o IMPACTO do projeto, um programa do mitigation dos 
danos da comunidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i capretti di aiuti hanno unito un corredo 
iniziale di disastro, hanno installato un piano d'emergenza della 
famiglia, letto su che cosa potrebbero ritenere in un disastro, 
imparare circa protezione dell'animale domestico, hanno letto una 
serie di storia circa i capretti che sono preparati sempre per un 
disastro naturale ed unire l'EFFETTO di progetto, un programma di 
mitigation di danni della Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τα κατσίκια οδηγιών να βάλει μαζί μια εξάρτηση 
ανεφοδιασμού καταστροφής, οργάνωσαν ένα σχέδιο οικογενειακού σε 
περίπτωση καταστροφής, που διαβάστηκε για αυτό που που να 
αισθανθούν σε μια καταστροφή, να μάθει για την προστασία 
κατοικίδιων ζώων, διαβάζουν μια σειρά ιστοριών για τα κατσίκια 
που είναι πάντα έτοιμα για μια φυσική καταστροφή, και ενώνουν 
τον ΑΝΤΙΚΤΥΠΟ έργου, ένα κοινοτικό πρόγραμμα μετριασμού ζημίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los cabritos de las ayudas juntaron un kit de 
materiales consumibles del desastre, instalado un plan del desastre de
la familia, leído sobre lo que puede ser que se sientan en un 
desastre, aprender sobre la protección del animal doméstico, leyeron
una serie de historias sobre los cabritos que están preparados 
siempre para un desastre natural, y ensamblar el IMPACTO del proyecto,
un programa de la mitigación del daños de la comunidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206666</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107080</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/helping-children-prepare-for-disasters</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
