<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107948</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107948</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086192</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Gertie Refuses a Suitor: Edna Ferber's "The Frog and the Puddle"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gertie lehnt einen Bewerber ab: Edna Ferbers
"der Frosch und die Pfütze"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gertie refuse un prétendant : La grenouille
d'Edna Ferber "et le magma"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gertie recusa um suitor: A râ de Edna 
Ferber "e a poça"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gertie rifiuta un suitor: La rana di Edna 
Ferber "e la pozza"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Gertie αρνείται ένα Suitor: Edna 
βάτραχος Ferber "ο και η λακκούβα"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gertie rechaza a pretendiente: La rana de 
Edna Ferber "y el charco"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Department stores became a major source of employment for young, urban white women beginning in the late 19th century. They also offered a new focus for stories and novels about life in America's burgeoning cities. Writers as diverse as Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, and O. Henry often used the world of department stores and the shop girls who worked there to create a modern fiction (including a brand new form--the short story) that allowed readers to feel the texture of urban life. Ferber's shop-girl heroines were strong-willed, and though they expressed vulnerability and desire for male companionship, they valued their careers. In this 1912 short story, titled "The Frog and the Puddle," Ferber described the lonely life of a young sales girl in a Chicago department store and the attentions of a male neighbor, whom she meets unexpectedly one night in the boarding house in which both reside.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abteilung Speicher wurden eine Hauptquelle der 
Beschäftigung für Junge, die städtischen weißen Frauen, die im des
späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert anfangen. Sie boten auch 
einen neuen Fokus für Geschichten und Romane über das Leben in 
Amerikas sprießenden Städte an. Verfasser so verschieden, wie 
Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber und O. Henry häufig die Welt der 
Abteilung Speicher und der Systemmädchen benutzten, die dort 
arbeiteten, um eine moderne Erfindung zu erstellen (einschließlich 
nagelneues Formular -- die kurze Geschichte) die Lesern erlaubte, der 
Beschaffenheit der städtischen Lebensdauer zu glauben. 
Heldinnen Kaufenmädchen Ferbers wurden stark-gewillt, und 
obwohl sie Verwundbarkeit und Wunsch nach männlicher Begleitung 
ausdrückten, bewerteten sie ihre Karrieren. In dieser 
Geschichte mit 1912 Kurzschlüssen betitelt "den Frosch und die 
Pfütze," beschrieb Ferber das einsame Leben eines jungen Verkäufe 
Mädchens in einem Chicago Abteilung Speicher und die Aufmerksamkeit 
eines männlichen Nachbars, dem sie unerwartet eine Nacht im 
verschalenden Haus trifft, in dem beide sich befinden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les grands magasins sont devenus une source 
importante d'emploi pour des jeunes, femmes blanches urbaines 
commençant vers la fin du 19ème siècle. Ils ont également 
offert un nouveau foyer pour des histoires et des romans au sujet de 
la vie dans les villes bourgeonnantes de l'Amérique. Auteurs 
aussi divers que Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, et O. Henry ont 
souvent utilisé le monde des grands magasins et des filles de 
système qui ont travaillé là pour créer une fiction moderne (forme
nouvelle y compris -- l'histoire courte) qui a permis à des lecteurs 
de sentir la texture de la vie urbaine. Des héroïnes de la 
faire des emplettes-fille de Ferber fort-ont été voulues, et bien 
qu'ils aient exprimé la vulnérabilité et le désir pour la 
compagnie mâle, elles ont évalué leurs carrières. Dans cette
histoire de 1912 shorts, intitulée "la grenouille et le magma," 
Ferber a décrit la vie isolée d'une jeune fille de ventes dans un 
grand magasin de Chicago et les attentions d'un voisin mâle, qu'elle 
rencontre inopinément une nuit dans la pension dans laquelle toutes 
les deux résident.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As lojas de departamento transformaram-se uma 
fonte principal do emprego para jovens, mulheres brancas urbanas que 
começam no 1ø século atrasado. Ofereceram também um foco 
novo para histórias e novelas sobre a vida em cidades burgeoning de 
América. Escritores tão diversos como Theodore Dreiser, Edna 
Ferber, e O. Henry usaram frequentemente o mundo das lojas de 
departamento e das meninas da loja que trabalharam lá para criar um 
fiction moderno (formulário brandnew including -- a história curta) 
que permitisse que os leitores sentissem a textura da vida urbana. 
Os heroines da compr-menina de Ferber forte-foram queridos, e 
embora expressaram o vulnerability e o desejo para o companionship 
masculino, avaliaram suas carreiras. Nesta história de 1912 
short, intitulada "a râ e a poça," Ferber descreveu a vida só de 
uma menina nova das vendas em uma loja de departamento de Chicago e as
atenções de um vizinho masculino, quem se encontrasse com inesperada
uma noite na casa boarding em que ambos residem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I grandi magazzini si sono transformati in in una 
sorgente importante di occupazione per i giovani, donne bianche urbane
che cominciano verso la fine del diciannovesimo secolo. 
Egualmente hanno offerto un nuovo fuoco per le storia ed i 
romanzi circa vita nelle città burgeoning dell'America. 
Produttori vari come Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber ed O. Henry 
hanno usato spesso il mondo dei grandi magazzini e delle ragazze del 
negozio che hanno lavorato là per creare un romanzo moderno (forma 
brandnew compresa -- la storia corta) che ha permesso che i lettori 
ritenessero la struttura di vita urbana. I heroines della 
acquist-ragazza del Ferber forte-sono stati voluti e benchè 
esprimessero la vulnerabilità ed il desiderio per companionship 
maschio, hanno stimato le loro carriere. In questa storia di 
1912 short, nominata "la rana e la pozza," Ferber ha descritto la vita
sola di una ragazza giovane di vendite in un grande magazzino del 
Chicago e le attenzioni di un vicinot maschio, quale viene a contatto 
inatteso di una notte nella casa di imbarco in cui entrambe risiedono.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα καταστήματα τμήματος έγιναν μια σημαντική πηγή 
απασχόλησης για τις νέες, αστικές λευκές γυναίκες που αρχίζουν 
προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα. Πρόσφεραν επίσης μια νέα 
εστίαση για τις ιστορίες και τα μυθιστορήματα για τη ζωή να 
φυτρώσουν της Αμερικής στις πόλεις. Οι συγγραφείς τόσο 
διαφορετικοί όσο Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, και Ο. 
Henry χρησιμοποίησαν συχνά τον κόσμο των καταστημάτων τμημάτων
και των κοριτσιών καταστημάτων που ελειτούργησε εκεί για να 
δημιουργήσει μια σύγχρονη μυθιστοριογραφία (συμπεριλαμβανομένης 
μιας ολοκαίνουργιας μορφής -- η σύντομη ιστορία) που επέτρεψε 
στους αναγνώστες για να αισθανθεί τη σύσταση της αστικής ζωής. 
Οι ηρωϊ'δες κατάστημα-κοριτσιών του Ferber ήταν 
ισχυρογνώμουσες, και αν και εξέφρασαν την ευπάθεια και την 
επιθυμία για την αρσενική συντροφικότητα, εκτίμησαν τις 
σταδιοδρομίες τους. Σε αυτήν την σύντομη ιστορία του 
1912, με τον τίτλο "ο βάτραχος και η λακκούβα," Ferber 
περιέγραψαν τη μόνη ζωή ενός νέου κοριτσιού πωλήσεων σε ένα 
κατάστημα τμημάτων του Σικάγου και τις προσοχές ενός αρσενικού 
γείτονα, ο οποίος συναντά απροσδόκητα μια νύχτα στο 
ενοικιαζόμενο δωμάτιο στο οποίο και τα δύο κατοικούν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los almacenes grandes se convirtieron en una 
fuente importante del empleo para los jóvenes, mujeres blancas 
urbanas que comenzaban en la a fines del siglo XIX. También 
ofrecieron un nuevo foco para las historias y las novelas sobre vida 
en las ciudades burgeoning de América. Programas de escritura 
tan diversos como Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, y O. Henry utilizaron
a menudo el mundo de los almacenes grandes y de las muchachas del 
departamento que trabajaron allí para crear una ficción moderna 
(forma brandnew incluyendo -- la historia corta) que permitió que los
programas de lectura sintieran la textura de la vida urbana. 
Fuerte-queri'an a las heroínas de la hacer compras-muchacha 
de Ferber, y aunque expresaron vulnerabilidad y el deseo para el 
compañerismo masculino, valoraron sus carreras. En esta 
historia de 1912 cortocircuitos, titulada "la rana y el charco," 
Ferber describió la vida sola de una muchacha joven de las ventas en 
un almacén grande de Chicago y las atenciones de un vecino masculino,
que ella resuelve inesperado una noche en la pensión en la cual ambas
residen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086192</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107948</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/gertie-refuses-a-suitor-edna-ferbers-the-frog-and-the-puddle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
