<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105534</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105534</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Median of a triangle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mittelpunkt eines Dreiecks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Médiane d'une triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Número médio de um triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mediana di un triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διάμεσος ενός τριγώνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Punto medio de un triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet illustrating the medians of a triangle. The applet shows a triangle where the user can drag the vertices to reshape it. As the triangle is being reshaped, the user can see the three median lines tracking the changes, and observe that that all three always intersect at a point inside the triangle. The page text explains that this point of intersection is also the centroid of the triangle, and explains how to determine the location of the medians. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, welche 
die Mittelpunkte eines Dreiecks veranschaulichen. Der applet 
zeigt einem Dreieck, wo der Benutzer die Gipfel schleppen kann, um ihn
umzugestalten. Während das Dreieck umgestaltet wird, kann der 
Benutzer die drei mittleren Zeilen sehen, die Änderungen aufzuspüren
und beobachtet den, den alle drei immer an einem Punkt innerhalb des 
Dreiecks schneiden. Der Seite Text beschreibt, daß dieser 
Koinzidenzpunkt auch der Schwerpunkt des Dreiecks ist, und beschreibt,
wie man den Standort der Mittelpunkte feststellt. Applet kann 
zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif illustrant 
les médianes d'une triangle. L'applet montre à une triangle 
où l'utilisateur peut traîner les sommets pour le restructurer. 
Pendant que la triangle est restructurée, l'utilisateur peut 
voir les trois lignes médianes dépister les changements, et observe 
cela que chacun des trois intersecte toujours à un point à 
l'intérieur de la triangle. Le texte de page explique que ce 
point d'intersection est également le centre de surface de la 
triangle, et explique comment déterminer l'emplacement des médianes.
L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que ilustram os
números médios de um triângulo. O applet mostra a um 
triângulo onde o usuário pode arrastar os vertices para reshape o. 
Enquanto o triângulo reshaped, o usuário pode ver as três 
linhas medianas seguir as mudanças, e observa aquele que todos os 
três cruzam sempre em um ponto dentro do triângulo. O texto da
página explica que este ponto de interseção é também o centróide
do triângulo, e explica como determinar a posição dos números 
médios. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che illustrano
le mediane di un triangolo. Il applet mostra ad un triangolo 
dove l'utente può trascinare i vertici per rimodellarlo. Mentre
il triangolo sta rimodellando, l'utente può vedere le tre righe 
mediane rintracciare i cambiamenti ed osserva quello che tutti e tre 
le intersecano sempre ad un punto all'interno del triangolo. Il 
testo della pagina spiega che questo punto dell'intersezione è 
egualmente il centro di massa del triangolo e spiega come determinare 
la posizione delle mediane. Il applet può essere ingrandito al 
formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που επεξηγούν 
τις διαμέσους ενός τριγώνου. Το applet εμφανίζει ένα 
τρίγωνο όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει vertices για να το 
αναδιαμορφώσει. Δεδομένου ότι το τρίγωνο αναδιαμορφώνεται, 
ο χρήστης μπορεί να δει τις τρεις μεσαίες γραμμές τις 
αλλαγές, και να παρατηρήσει ότι εκείνες οι και οι τρεις πάντα 
κόβουν σε ένα σημείο μέσα στο τρίγωνο. Το κείμενο σελίδων
εξηγεί ότι αυτό το σημείο της διατομής είναι επίσης centroid
του τριγώνου, και εξηγεί πώς να καθορίσει τη θέση των διαμέσων. 
Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης
για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση 
στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que ilustran 
los puntos medios de un triángulo. El applet muestra a 
triángulo donde el utilizador puede arrastrar las cimas para 
restructurarlo. Mientras que se está restructurando el 
triángulo, el utilizador puede ver las tres líneas medianas el 
seguir de los cambios, y observa el que los tres intersequen siempre 
en una punta dentro del triángulo. El texto de la paginación 
explica que esta punta de la intersección es también el centro de 
figura del triángulo, y explica cómo determinar la localización de 
los puntos medios. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105534</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/median-of-a-triangle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
