<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108697</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108697</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206023</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploratorium Online</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Exploratorium Online</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Exploratorium En ligne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exploratorium Em linha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Exploratorium In linea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Exploratorium on-line</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Exploratorium En línea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features dozens of online learning activities and exhibits. Make a mold terrarium, pinhole projector, telescope, or hair hygrometer. Explore the brain, biodiversity, Antarctica, DNA, frogs, structures, or illusions. Learn about magnetism, electricity, motors, eyeballs, perception, Mars, chocolate, seasonings, or the science of cooking, sports, and music. Search over 3,000 photos and movies. Watch webcasts of science demonstrations by teachers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet Dutzende der Onlinelernenaktivitäten
und -ausstellungen. Bilden Sie einen Form Terrarium, einen 
Splintlochprojektor, ein Teleskop oder ein Haarhygrometer. 
Erforschen Sie das Gehirn, den Biodiversity, die Antarktik, die 
DNA, die Frösche, die Strukturen oder die Illusionen. Erlernen 
Sie über Magnetismus, Elektrizität, Motoren, Augäpfel, Vorstellung,
Mars, Schokolade, Seasonings oder die Wissenschaft des Kochens, des 
Sports und der Musik. Suchen Sie über 3.000 Fotos und Filmen. 
Überwachen Sie webcasts der Wissenschaft Demonstrationen durch 
Lehrer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte des douzaines d'étude et d'objets 
exposés en ligne. Faites un terrarium de moule, un projecteur 
de trou d'épingle, un télescope, ou un hygromètre de cheveux. 
Explorez le cerveau, la biodiversité, l'Antarctique, l'ADN, les
grenouilles, les structures, ou les illusions. Renseignez-vous 
sur le magnétisme, l'électricité, les moteurs, les globes 
oculaires, la perception, le Mars, le chocolat, les assaisonnements, 
ou la science de la cuisine, des sports, et de la musique. 
Recherchez plus de 3.000 photos et films. Observez les 
webcasts des démonstrations de la science par des professeurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza dúzias de atividades e de exibições
em linha de aprendizagem. Faça um terrarium do molde, um 
projetor do pinhole, um telescópio, ou um hygrometer do cabelo. 
Explore o cérebro, o biodiversity, o antarctica, o DNA, as 
râs, as estruturas, ou os illusions. Aprenda sobre o 
magnetismo, a eletricidade, os motores, os eyeballs, a percepção, o 
Marte, o chocolate, os seasonings, ou a ciência de cozinhar, de 
esportes, e de música. Procurare sobre 3.000 fotos e filmes. 
Preste atenção a webcasts de demonstrações da ciência por 
professores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza le dozzine delle attività imparanti 
e delle esposizioni in linea. Faccia un terrarium della muffa, 
un proiettore di foro di spillo, un telescopio, o un igrometro dei 
capelli. Esplori il cervello, il biodiversity, l'Antartide, il 
DNA, le rane, le strutture, o le illusioni. Impari circa 
magnetismo, elettricità, i motori, i eyeballs, la percezione, Marte, 
cioccolato, condimenti, o la scienza di cottura, degli sport e della 
musica. Cerchi oltre 3.000 foto e film. Guardi i 
webcasts delle dimostrazioni di scienza dagli insegnanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δωδεκάδες χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων των σε απευθείας
σύνδεση δραστηριοτήτων και των εκθεμάτων εκμάθησης. Κάνετε 
ένα terrarium φορμών, έναν προβολέα οπών καρφίτσας, ένα 
τηλεσκόπιο, ή το υγρόμετρο τρίχας. Ερευνήστε τον εγκέφαλο,
τη βιοποικιλότητα, την Ανταρκτική, το DNA, τους βατράχους, τις 
δομές, ή τις παραισθήσεις. Μάθετε για το μαγνητισμό, την 
ηλεκτρική ενέργεια, τις μηχανές, τους βολβούς του ματιού, την 
αντίληψη, τον Αρη, τη σοκολάτα, τα καρυκεύματα, ή την επιστήμη 
του μαγειρέματος, του αθλητισμού, και της μουσικής. 
Αναζήτηση άνω των 3.000 φωτογραφιών και κινηματογράφων. 
Ρολόι webcasts των επιδείξεων επιστήμης από τους 
δασκάλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece docenas de actividades que aprenden y de 
objetos expuestos en línea. Haga un terrario del molde, un 
proyector del agujero de alfiler, un telescopio, o un higrómetro del 
pelo. Explore el cerebro, la biodiversidad, el antártida, la DNA, 
las ranas, las estructuras, o las ilusiones. Aprenda sobre 
magnetismo, electricidad, motores, globos oculares, la opinión, 
Marte, el chocolate, los condimentos, o la ciencia de cocinar, de 
deportes, y de la música. Busque sobre 3.000 fotos y 
películas. Mire los webcasts de las demostraciones de la 
ciencia de los profesores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206023</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108697</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exploratorium-online</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
