<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107618</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107618</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087236</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Whose Library Is It Anyway?: A Visit to the Lenox</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wer Bibliothek Es Irgendwie? Ist: Ein Besuch
zum Lenox</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À qui Bibliothèque Est Lui de toute façon ? : 
Une visite au Lenox</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">De quem Biblioteca É Ele De qualquer maneira?: 
Uma visita ao Lenox</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Di chi Libreria È Comunque Esso?: Una 
chiamata al Lenox</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποιά βιβλιοθήκη είναι αυτός οπωσδήποτε;: Μια 
επίσκεψη στο Lenox</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De quién Biblioteca Es Él De todos modos?: 
Una visita al Lenox</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The founders of the great libraries of the 19th century were often ambivalent about whether their goal was to disseminate or conserve knowledge. They were also uncertain about the intended audience. John Cotton Dana of the Newark Public Library was atypical in his populist stance that "it is a proper function of a library to amuse." He argued that a "shallow mind" was better than an "empty one." Other librarians preferred to see themselves as cultivators of public taste and their buildings as uplifting houses of culture. The stuffiness and remoteness of late nineteenth-century libraries provoked this humorous sketch, published in  Life  magazine in 1884, which satirized the closed-door practices of the theoretically "public" library donated by wealthy James Lenox to New York City.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Gründer der großen Bibliotheken des 19. 
Jahrhunderts waren häufig ungefähr ambivalent, ob ihr Ziel, Wissen 
zu verbreiten oder zu konservieren war. Sie waren auch über die
beabsichtigten Publikum unsicher. John Baumwolle Dana der Newark
allgemeinen Bibliothek war in seiner Volksposition atypisch, die "es 
eine korrekte Funktion einer zu unterhalten ist Bibliothek." Er 
argumentierte, daß ein "flacher Verstand" besser war, als "leert 
ein." Andere Librarian zogen es vor, sich wie Landwirte des 
allgemeinen Geschmacks und ihrer Gebäude als emporhebende Häuser der
Kultur zu sehen. Der Stuffiness und die Entferntheit der späten
19.-Jahrhundert Bibliotheken erregten diese humorvolle Skizze, 
veröffentlicht in der Lebenzeitschrift 1884, das die Geschlossentür 
Praxis der theoretisch "allgemeinen" Bibliothek satirized, die durch 
wohlhabendes James Lenox nach New York City gespendet wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les fondateurs des grandes bibliothèques du 
19ème siècle étaient souvent ambivalents environ si leur but était
de diffuser ou économiser la connaissance. Ils étaient 
également incertains au sujet des assistances destinées. Le 
coton Dana de John de la bibliothèque publique de Newark était
atypique dans sa position populiste que "c'est une fonction 
appropriée d'une bibliothèque à amuser." Il a argué du fait 
que "un esprit peu profond" était meilleur que "vident un." 
D'autres bibliothécaires ont préféré se voir comme des 
cultivateurs de goût public et de leurs bâtiments en tant que 
maisons élevantes de culture. Le manque d'air et l'éloignement
des bibliothèques en retard de dix-neuvième-siècle ont provoqué ce
croquis plein d'humour, édité en magasin de la vie en 1884, qui a 
satirisé les pratiques à huis clos de la bibliothèque 
théoriquement "publique" donnée par James riche Lenox à New 
York City.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os founders das bibliotecas grandes do 1ø século
eram frequentemente ambivalent aproximadamente se seu objetivo era 
disseminate ou conservar o conhecimento. Eram também incertos 
sobre as audiências pretendidas. O algodão Dana de John da 
biblioteca pública de Newark era atypical em seu stance populist que 
"é uma função apropriada de uma biblioteca a divertir." 
Discutiu que "uma mente rasa" era melhor do que "esvazía um." 
Outros bibliotecários preferiram ver-se como cultivadores do 
gosto público e dos seus edifícios como casas uplifting da cultura. 
O stuffiness e o remoteness de bibliotecas atrasadas de 
décimo-século provocaram este esboço humorous, publicado no 
compartimento da vida em 1884, que satirized as práticas da 
closed-porta da biblioteca teòrica "pública" doada por James rico 
Lenox a New York City.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I fondatori delle librerie grandi del 
diciannovesimo secolo erano spesso ambivalent circa se il loro 
obiettivo era di diffondere o conservare la conoscenza. Erano 
egualmente incerte circa i pubblici progettati. Il cotone Dana 
del John della biblioteca pubblica de Newark era atipico nella sua 
posizione populistica che "è una funzione adeguata di una libreria da
divertire." Ha sostenuto che "una mente poco profonda" era 
migliore di "svuota uno." Altri bibliotecari hanno preferito 
vedersi come coltivatori di gusto pubblico e delle loro costruzioni 
come case uplifting di coltura. Lo stuffiness e la distanza 
delle librerie ritardate di diciannovesimo-secolo hanno provocato 
questo abbozzo divertente, pubblicato in scomparto di vita in 1884, 
che satirized le pratiche di chiuso-door della libreria teoricamente
"pubblica" donata da James ricco Lenox a New York City.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ιδρυτές των μεγάλων βιβλιοθηκών του 19$ου αιώνα 
ήταν συχνά αμφίθυμοι για εάν ο στόχος τους ήταν να διαδώσουν ή
να συντηρήσουν τη γνώση. Ήταν επίσης αβέβαιοι για το 
προοριζόμενο ακροατήριο. Θ*Ιοχν Cotton Dana της 
δημόσιας βιβλιοθήκης του Newark ήταν άτυπος στη λαϊκιστική 
θέση του ότι "είναι μια κατάλληλη λειτουργία μιας βιβλιοθήκης 
για να διασκεδάσει." Υποστήριξε ότι ένα "ρηχό μυαλό" ήταν
καλύτερο από "κενό ένα." Αλλοι βιβλιοθηκάριοι προτίμησαν 
να δουν ως καλλιεργητές της δημόσιας προτίμησης και τα 
κτήριά τους ως τα σπίτια του πολιτισμού. Το stuffiness 
και η απόσταση των πρόσφατων βιβλιοθηκών δέκατος-αιώνα 
προκάλεσαν αυτό το χιουμοριστικό σκίτσο, που δημοσιεύθηκε στο 
περιοδικό ζωής το 1884, το οποίο σατίρισε τις κεκλεισμένων των
θυρών πρακτικές της θεωρητικά "δημόσιασ" βιβλιοθήκης που δόθηκε 
από πλούσιος james Lenox στην πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los fundadores de las grandes bibliotecas del 
diecinueveavo siglo eran a menudo ambivalentes alrededor si su meta 
era diseminar o conservar conocimiento. Eran también incierta 
sobre las audiencias previstas. El algodón Dana de Juan de la 
biblioteca pública de Newark era anormal en su postura populista que 
"es una función apropiada de una biblioteca a divertirse." Él 
discutió que una "mente baja" fuera mejor que "vacia uno." 
Otros bibliotecarios prefirieron verse como los cultivadores del
gusto público y de sus edificios como casas que elevaban de la 
cultura. La congestión y el alejamiento de las últimas 
bibliotecas del diecinueveavo-siglo provocaron este bosquejo chistoso,
publicado en compartimiento de la vida en 1884, que satirized las 
prácticas de la cerrado-puerta de la biblioteca teóricamente 
"pública" donada por James rico Lenox a New York City.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087236</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107618</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/whose-library-is-it-anyway-a-visit-to-the-lenox</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
