<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106490</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106490</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087311</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Jubilee of Freedom": Freed Slaves March in Charleston, South Carolina, March, 1865</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Jubiläum der Freiheit": Freigegebene 
Sklaven März in Charleston, Südcarolina, März, 1865</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un jubilé de la liberté" : Esclaves 
libérés mars à Charleston, Caroline du sud, mars, 1865</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um jubilee da liberdade": Escravos livrados
março em Charleston, carolina sul, março, 1865</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un giubileo di libertà": Schiavi liberati 
marzo a Charleston, Carolina del Sud, marzo, del 1865</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα ιωβηλαίο της ελευθερίασ": Ελευθερωμένοι 
σκλάβοι Μάρτιος στο Τσάρλεστον, νότια Καρολίνα, τον Μάρτιος, του
1865</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un jubileo de la libertad": Esclavos 
liberados marcha en Charleston, Carolina del Sur, marcha de 1865</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">At the Civil War's end, enslaved people responded in a variety of ways to take their freedom. One meaning of freedom can be glimpsed in the following report from Charleston, South Carolina, published in the  New York Daily Tribune  on April 4, 1865, just a few days before General Robert E. Lee's surrender in Virginia. Charleston boasted one of the largest and most important African-American communities in the antebellum South. Two months after the Confederate Army fled, the city's black men and women organized a parade to celebrate their emancipation. The parade numbered thousands of marchers and included dramatic tableaux, banners, and songs. African Americans used such public celebrations to symbolize their deeply held beliefs and feelings, in a manner that paralleled the public displays of their white working-class counterparts in the decades before the war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Am Ende des Bürgerkrieges reagierten versklavte 
Leute in einer Vielzahl von Methoden, ihre Freiheit zu nehmen. 
Eine Bedeutung der Freiheit kann im folgenden Report von 
Charleston, Südcarolina flüchtig gesehen werden, veröffentlicht 
worden in der New York täglichen Tribüne an April 4, 1865, 
gerade einige Tage bevor Auslieferung des Generals Robert E. Lees in 
Virginia. Charleston rühmte sich eine der größten und 
wichtigsten Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Gemeinschaften im antebellum 
Süden. Zwei Monate nachdem die verbündete Armee floh, 
organisierten der schwarzen die Männer und die Frauen Stadt eine 
Parade, um ihre Emanzipation zu feiern. Die Parade numerierte 
Tausenden marchers und schloß drastische Verzeichnisse, Fahnen und 
Liede ein. Afrikanische Amerikaner verwendeten solche allgemeine
Feiern, um ihren tief angehaltenen Glauben zu symbolisieren und 
Gefühle, in gewissem Sinne das entsprachen die allgemeinen 
Bildschirmanzeigen ihrer weißen Arbeiterklassegegenstücke in den 
Dekaden vor dem Krieg.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À l'extrémité de guerre civile, les personnes 
asservies ont répondu par une multitude de moyens de prendre leur 
liberté. Une signification de la liberté peut être aperçue 
dans l'état suivant de Charleston, Caroline du sud, éditée à
New York Tribune quotidien 4 avril 1865, juste quelques jours 
avant que reddition du Général Robert E. Lee's en Virginie. 
Charleston a revendiqué une des plus grandes et les plus 
importantes communautés afro-américaines dans les Sud 
d'avant-guerre. Pendant deux mois après que l'armée 
confédérée s'est sauvée, les hommes noirs et les femmes de la 
ville ont organisé un défilé pour célébrer leur émancipation. 
Le défilé a numéroté des milliers de marchers et a inclus 
des tableaux excessifs, des drapeaux, et des chansons. Les 
Américains africains avaient l'habitude de telles célébrations 
publiques pour symboliser leur croyance profondément tenue et les 
sentiments, en quelque sorte celui ont mis en parallèle les 
affichages publics de leurs contre-parties blanches de classe ouvrier 
dans les décennies avant la guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na extremidade de guerra civil, os povos enslaved 
responderam em uma variedade das maneiras fazer exame de sua 
liberdade. Um meaning da liberdade pode glimpsed no seguinte 
relatório de Charleston, carolina sul, publicado na New York Tribune 
diário abril em 4, 1865, apenas alguns dias antes que rendição do 
general Robert E. Lee em Virgínia. Charleston boasted uma das 
comunidades Africano-Americanas as maiores e as mais importantes no 
sul antebellum. Dois meses depois que o exército confederate 
fujiu, os homens pretos e as mulheres da cidade organizaram uma parada
para comemorar seu emancipation. A parada numerou milhares dos 
marchers e incluiu quadros, bandeiras, e canções dramáticos. 
Os americanos africanos usaram tais celebrations públicos 
symbolize seus opinião e sentimentos profundamente prendidos, em uma 
maneira que paralelizasse os indicadores públicos de suas 
contrapartes brancas do working-class nas décadas antes da guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">All'estremità della guerra civile, la gente 
asservita ha risposto in una varietà di modi prendere la loro 
libertà. Un significato della libertà può glimpsed nel 
seguente rapporto da Charleston, Carolina del Sud, pubblicata a New 
York Tribune quotidiano il 4 aprile 1865, appena alcuni giorni prima 
che resa del General Robert E. Lee nella Virginia. Charleston si
è vantato una di più grandi e Comunità Africano-Americane più 
importanti nel sud antebellum. Due mesi dopo che l'esercito 
confederato fuggisca, gli uomini neri e le donne della città hanno 
organizzato una parata per celebrare la loro emancipazione. La 
parata ha numerato le migliaia dei marchers ed ha incluso i tableaux, 
le bandiere e le canzoni drammatici. Gli Americani africani 
hanno usato tali celebrazioni pubbliche per simbolizzare la loro 
credenza e sensibilità profondamente tenute, in un modo che ha messo 
le visualizzazioni in parallelo pubbliche delle loro controparti 
bianche della classe operaia nelle decadi prima della guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο τέλος του εμφύλιου πολέμου, οι υποδουλωμένοι 
άνθρωποι αποκρίθηκαν με ποικίλους τρόπους να ληφθεί η ελευθερία 
τους. Μια έννοια της ελευθερίας μπορεί να είναι στην 
ακόλουθη έκθεση από το Τσάρλεστον, νότια Καρολίνα, που 
δημοσιεύεται στο καθημερινό βήμα της Νέας Υόρκης στις 4 Απριλίου
..1865, ακριβώς μερικές ημέρες πριν από την General 
Robert Ε. Lee's παράδοση στη Βιρτζίνια. Το Τσάρλεστον 
καυχήθηκε μια από τις μεγαλύτερες και σημαντικότερες 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές κοινότητες στον προπολεμικό νότο. 
Δύο μήνες μετά από τον ομόσπονδο στρατό τρεπόμενο σε 
φυγή, οι μαύροι άνδρες της πόλης και οι γυναίκες οργάνωσαν μια 
παρέλαση για να γιορτάσουν την χειραφέτηση τους. Η 
παρέλαση που αριθμείται χιλιάδες marchers και 
συμπεριλαμβανόμενες δραματικές εικόνες, εμβλήματα, και τραγούδια.
Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί χρησιμοποίησαν τέτοιους δημόσιους 
εορτασμούς για να συμβολίσουν τις βαθειά κρατημένα πίστεις και τα
συναισθήματά τους, με έναν τρόπο που παραλλήλισε τις δημόσιες 
παρουσιάσεις των λευκών αντίστοιχων εργατικών τάξεών τους στις 
δεκαετίες πριν από τον πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el extremo de la guerra civil, la gente 
esclavizada respondió en una variedad de maneras de tomar su 
libertad. Un significado de la libertad se puede glimpsed en el 
informe siguiente de Charleston, Carolina del Sur, publicado en la 
Nueva York Tribune diario 4 de abril de 1865, apenas algunos días 
antes de que entrega de general Roberto E. Leés en Virginia. 
Charleston se jactó a una de las comunidades 
Africano-Americanas más grandes y más importantes del sur 
antebellum. Dos meses después de que el ejército confederado 
huyó, los hombres negros y las mujeres de la ciudad ordenaron un 
desfile para celebrar su emancipación. El desfile numeró 
millares de marchers e incluyó cuadros, banderas, y canciones 
dramáticos. Los americanos africanos utilizaron tales 
celebraciones públicas para simbolizar su creencia y sensaciones 
profundamente llevadas a cabo, de una manera que fue paralelo a las 
visualizaciones públicas de sus contrapartes blancas de la clase 
obrera en las décadas antes de la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087311</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106490</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-jubilee-of-freedom-freed-slaves-march-in-charleston-south-carolina-march-1865</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
