<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103912</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103912</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Fight Begins at Home: Jewett Defends Asian Immigrants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kampf fängt zu Hause an: Jewett 
Verteidigt Asiatische Immigranten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le combat commence à la maison : Jewett 
Défend Les Immigrés Asiatiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A luta começa na HOME: Jewett Defende 
Immigrants Asian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lotta comincia nel paese: Jewett Difende 
Gli Immigranti Asiatici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πάλη αρχίζει στο σπίτι: Το Jewett 
υπερασπίζει τους ασιατικούς μετανάστες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La lucha comienza en el país: Jewett 
Defiende A Inmigrantes Asiáticos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Labor leaders like Denis Kearney and H. L. Knight of California's Workingmen's Party often resorted to popular racist arguments to justify the exclusion of Chinese immigrants. In an 1878 address, Kearney and Knight described the Chinese as a race of "cheap working slaves" who undercut American living standards and thus should be banished from America's shores. A few American labor leaders, mostly in the radical and socialist wing of the movement, were more sympathetic. In a letter to the Detroit  Socialist  in May 1878, B.E.G. Jewett argued that the slogan should not be that "the Chinese must go," but that "the oppressors, money-mongers, . . . must go." Though voices like Jewett were exceptional, they serve as reminders that some late nineteenth-century white Americans were able to pierce the veil of prejudice that men like Kearney and Knight erected against Asian immigrants.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gewerkschaftsführer wie Denis Kearney und H. L. 
Knight der Partei der Workingmens Kaliforniens griffen häufig
auf populäre rassistische Argumente zurück, um den Ausschluß der 
chinesischen Immigranten auszuschließen. In einer Adresse 1878 
beschrieben Kearney und Ritter die Chinesen, wie ein Rennen "des 
preiswerten Arbeitens" schuftet, wer amerikanische lebende Standards 
unterschneiden und von den Ufern Amerikas folglich verbannt werden 
sollten. Einige amerikanische Gewerkschaftsführer, meistens im 
radikalen und sozialistischen Flügel der Bewegung, waren 
sympatischer. In einem Zeichen zum Detroit Sozialisten im Mai 
1878, B.E.G. Jewett argumentierte, daß der Slogan nicht sein 
sollte, den "der Chinese,", aber der "gehen muß die Unterdrücker, 
Geld-Händler. . . muß gehen." Obwohl Stimmen
wie Jewett aussergewöhnlich waren, dienen sie als Anzeigen, daß 
einige spätes 19.-Jahrhundert weiße Amerikaner konnten, den Schleier
des Vorurteils zu durchbohren, den Männer wie Kearney und Ritter 
gegen asiatische Immigranten aufrichteten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dirigeants syndicaux comme Denis Kearney et H. 
L. Knight de la partie des ouvriers de la Californie ont souvent 
recouru aux arguments racistes populaires pour justifier l'exclusion 
des immigrés chinois. Dans une adresse 1878, Kearney et 
chevalier ont décrit les Chinois comme une course "de travailler bon 
marché asservit" qui dégagent des normes vivantes américaines et 
devraient être banis ainsi des rivages de l'Amérique. Quelques
dirigeants syndicaux américains, la plupart du temps dans l'aile 
radicale et socialiste du mouvement, étaient plus bien disposés. 
Dans une lettre au socialiste de Detroit en mai 1878, B.E.G. 
Jewett a argué du fait que le slogan ne devrait pas être que 
"le Chinois doit aller," mais qui "les oppresseurs, argent-vendeurs. 
. . doit aller." Bien que les voix comme 
Jewett aient été exceptionnelles, elles servent de rappels que 
quelques Américains blancs de dix-neuvième-siècle en retard 
pouvaient percer le voile du préjudice que les hommes comme Kearney 
et le chevalier ont érigé contre les immigrés asiatiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os líderes labor como Denis Kearney e H. L. Knight
do partido dos workingmen de Califórnia recorreram frequentemente aos
argumentos racist populares para justificar a exclusão de immigrants 
chineses. Em um endereço 1878, Kearney e o knight descreveram 
os chineses como uma raça "de trabalhar barato slaves" quem undercut 
padrões vivos americanos e assim devem banished das costas de 
América. Alguns líderes labor americanos, na maior parte na 
asa radical e socialist do movimento, eram mais sympathetic. Em 
uma letra ao socialist de Detroit em maio 1878, B.E.G. Jewett 
discutiu que o slogan não deve ser a que "o chinês deve ir," mas que
"os oppressors, dinheiro-money-mongers. . . deve 
ir." Embora as vozes como Jewett eram excepcionais, servem como 
lembretes que alguns americanos brancos de décimo-século atrasado 
podiam  perfurar o véu do preconceito que os homens como Kearney e o 
knight erigiram de encontro aos immigrants asian.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I capi di lavoro come Denis Kearney e H. L.
Knight del partito dei workingmen della California hanno ricorso 
spesso agli argomenti razzisti popolari per giustificare l'esclusione 
degli immigranti cinesi. In un indirizzo 1878, Kearney ed il
cavaliere hanno descritto il cinese come una corsa "di 
funzionamento poco costoso assoggetta" chi tagliano gli standard 
viventi americani e dovrebbero banished così dai puntelli 
dell'America. Alcuni capi di lavoro americani, 
principalmente nell'ala radicale e socialista del movimento, erano 
più simpatici. In una lettera al socialista de Detroit nel mese
di maggio 1878, B.E.G. Jewett ha sostenuto che lo slogan non 
dovrebbe essere che "il cinese deve andare," ma che "i 
oppressors, soldo-money-mongers. . . deve andare." 
Benchè le voci come Jewett siano eccezionali, servono da 
ricordi che alcuni Americani bianchi del diciannovesimo-secolo tardo 
potevano perforare il velare del pregiudizio che gli uomini come 
Kearney ed il cavaliere hanno eretto contro gli immigranti asiatici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ηγέτες εργασίας όπως Denis Kearney και Χ. Λ. 
Knight του συμβαλλόμενου μέρους Workingmen Καλιφόρνιας 
προσέφυγαν συχνά στα δημοφιλή ρατσιστικά ορίσματα να 
δικαιολογηθεί ο αποκλεισμός των κινεζικών μεταναστών. Σε μια
διεύθυνση 1878, Kearney και ο ιππότης περιέγραψαν τους 
Κινέζους ως φυλή των "φτηνών εργαζόμενων σκλάβων" ποιοι 
περικόπτουν το αμερικανικό βιοτικό επίπεδο και πρέπει έτσι να 
είναι από τις ακτές της Αμερικής. Μερικοί Αμερικανικοί 
ηγέτες εργασίας, συνήθως στο ριζικό και σοσιαλιστικό φτερό της 
μετακίνησης, ήταν πιό συμπονετικοί. Σε μια επιστολή στο 
σοσιαλιστή του Ντητρόιτ σε Μάιος 1878, B.E.G. Jewett 
υποστήριξε ότι το σύνθημα δεν πρέπει να είναι ότι "οι Κινέζοι 
πρέπει να πάνε," αλλά ότι "οι καταπιεστές, χρήμα-έμποροι. 
.. πρέπει να πάτε." Αν και οι φωνές όπως 
Jewett ήταν εξαιρετικές, χρησιμεύουν ως οι υπενθυμίσεις ότι 
κάποιος πρόσφατος δέκατος-αιώνας λευκοί Αμερικανοί ήταν σε 
θέση να διαπερνήσει το πέπλο της προκατάληψης που τα άτομα όπως 
Kearney και ο ιππότης δημιούργησαν ενάντια στους ασιατικούς 
μετανάστες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los arranques de cinta de trabajo como Denis 
Kearney y H. L. Knight del partido de los workingmen de California 
recurrieron a menudo a los argumentos racist populares para alinear la
exclusión de inmigrantes chinos. En un direccionamiento 1878, 
Kearney y el caballero describieron a chinos como esclaviza una raza 
del "trabajo barato" quiénes socavan estándares vivos americanos y 
se deben banished así de las orillas de América. Algunos 
arranques de cinta de trabajo americanos, sobre todo en el ala radical
y socialista del movimiento, eran más comprensivos. En una 
carta al socialista de Detroit en mayo de 1878, B.E.G. Jewett 
discutió que fuera el lema a que "el chino debe ir," pero que "los 
opresores, dinero-money-mongers. . . debe ir." 
Aunque las voces como Jewett eran excepcionales, sirven como 
recordatorios que algunos americanos blancos del último 
diecinueveavo-siglo podían perforar el velo del prejudicar que los 
hombres como Kearney y el caballero erigieron contra inmigrantes 
asiáticos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103912</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-fight-begins-at-home-jewett-defends-asian-immigrants</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
