<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108605</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108605</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087475</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Caught in the Shafting."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"abgefangen im Shafting."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"attrapé dans le Shafting."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"travado no Shafting."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"interferito nello Shafting."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πιαμένος στο Shafting."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cogido en el Shafting."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The  National Police Gazette  portrays, in a characteristically lurid fashion, an industrial accident in a North Grosvenor, Connecticut, cotton mill. Many late-nineteenth century businessmen ignored hazardous working conditions, since they had little financial incentive to make the workplace safer. In 1881 alone, 30,000 railway workers were killed or injured on the job, and industrial hazards existed in other industries, including textiles. A national weekly magazine, the  National Police Gazette  enthusiastically violated the mores of genteel culture, focusing on legal and illegal sports, violent crimes and accidents, and sex. Women were often depicted as perpetrators or victims of violence, providing titillation to the weekly magazine's male readership.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die nationale Polizei-Zeitung schildert, auf eine 
charakteristisch lurid Art und Weise, einen Betriebsunfall in einem 
Nordgrosvenor, Connecticut, Baumwollspinnerei. Viele 
spät-19.jahrhundertgeschäftsmänner ignorierten gefährliche 
Arbeitsbedingungen, da sie wenig finanziellen Anreiz hatten, zum des 
Arbeitsplatzes sicherer zu bilden. In 1881 allein wurden 30.000 
Bahnarbeiter auf dem Job beendet oder verletzt, und industrielle 
Gefahren existierten in anderen Industrien, einschließlich Gewebe. 
Eine nationale wöchentliche Zeitschrift, die nationale 
Polizei-Zeitung verletzte enthusiastisch die mores der genteel Kultur 
und konzentrierte auf zugelassenen und ungültigen Sport, heftige 
Verbrechen und Unfälle und Geschlecht. Frauen wurden häufig 
als Täter oder Opfer der Gewalttätigkeit bildlich dargestellt und 
stellten titillation zur wöchentlichen männlichen Leserschaft der 
Zeitschrift zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La gazette nationale de police dépeint, d'une mode 
caractéristiquement sinistre, un accident industriel de travail dans 
un Grosvenor du nord, le Connecticut, filature de coton. 
Beaucoup de tard-dix-neuvième hommes d'affaires de siècle ont 
ignoré des conditions de travail dangereuses, puisqu'ils ont eu peu 
d'incitation financière pour rendre le lieu de travail plus sûr. 
Dans 1881 seuls, 30.000 ouvriers ferroviaires ont été 
détruits ou blessés sur le travail, et les risques industriels ont 
existé dans d'autres industries, y compris des textiles. Un 
magasin hebdomadaire national, la gazette nationale de police a avec 
enthousiasme violé les mores de la culture distinguée, se 
concentrant sur des sports légaux et illégaux, des crimes et des 
accidents violents, et le sexe. Des femmes ont été souvent 
dépeintes comme malfaiteurs ou victimes de violence, fournissant le 
titillation au lectorat mâle du magasin hebdomadaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O gazette nacional das polícias portrays, em uma forma 
caracterìstica lurid, um acidente industrial em um Grosvenor norte, 
Connecticut, moinho de algodão. Muitos tarde-décimos nonos 
homens de negócios do século ignoraram condições de funcionamento 
perigosas, desde que tiveram pouco incentive financeiro para fazer o 
workplace mais seguro. Em 1881 sozinhos, 30.000 trabalhadores 
railway foram matados ou feridos no trabalho, e os perigos industriais
existiram em outras indústrias, including textiles. Um 
compartimento semanal nacional, o gazette nacional das polícias 
violated entusiàstica os mores da cultura genteel, focalizando em 
esportes legais e ilegais, em crimes e em acidentes violentos, e em 
sexo. As mulheres foram descritas frequentemente como os 
perpetrators ou as vítimas da violência, fornecendo o titillation ao
readership masculino do compartimento semanal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il gazette nazionale della polizia ritrae, ad un modo 
tipicamente lurid, un infortunio sul lavoro in un Grosvenor del nord, 
Connecticut, cotonificio. Molti in ritardo-diciannovesimi uomini
d'affari di secolo hanno ignorato le condizioni di lavoro pericolose, 
poiché hanno avuti poco motivo finanziario per rendere il posto di 
lavoro più sicuro. In 1881 solo, 30.000 operai ferroviari sono 
stati uccisi o ferito stati sul lavoro ed i rischi industriali hanno 
esistito in altre industrie, compreso le tessile. Uno scomparto 
settimanale nazionale, il gazette nazionale della polizia ha violato 
entusiastico i mores di coltura genteel, mettendo a fuoco sugli sport 
legali ed illegali, sui crimini e sugli incidenti violenti e sul 
sesso. Le donne sono state descritte spesso come i perpetrators 
o vittime della violenza, fornenti il titillation al readership 
maschio dello scomparto settimanale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εφημερίδα εθνικής αστυνομίας απεικονίζει, σε μια 
χαρακτηριστικά εντυπωσιακή μόδα, ένα βιομηχανικό ατύχημα στο 
Βορρά Grosvenor, Κοννέκτικατ, εκατομμύρια βαμβακιού 
Πολλοί επιχειρηματίες του πρόσφατος-δέκατου έννατου αιώνα 
αγνόησαν τις επικίνδυνες συνθήκες εργασίας, δεδομένου ότι είχαν
λίγα οικονομικά κίνητρα για να καταστήσουν τον εργασιακό χώρο 
ασφαλέστερο. Το 1881 μόνος, 30.000 εργαζόμενοι 
σιδηροδρόμων σκοτώθηκαν ή τραυματίστηκαν στην εργασία, και οι 
βιομηχανικοί κίνδυνοι υπήρξαν σε άλλες βιομηχανίες, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των κλωστοϋφαντουργικών προϊόντων. Ένα
εθνικό εβδομαδιαίο περιοδικό, η εφημερίδα εθνικής αστυνομίας 
παραβίασε ενθουσιωδώς τα mores του καλοαναθρεμένου πολιτισμού, 
που εστιάζει στο νομικό και παράνομο αθλητισμό, τα βίαια 
εγκλήματα και τα ατυχήματα, και το φύλο. Οι γυναίκες 
απεικονίστηκαν συχνά ως δράστες ή θύματα της βίας, που παρέχει 
το titillation στο αρσενικό αναγνωστικό κοινό του εβδομαδιαίου 
περιοδικού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La gaceta nacional del policía retrata, en una manera 
característico espeluznante, un accidente de trabajo en un Grosvenor 
del norte, Connecticut, fábrica de algodón. Muchos 
tarde-diecinueveavo hombres de negocios del siglo no hicieron caso de 
condiciones de trabajo peligrosas, puesto que tenían poco incentivo 
financiero para hacer el lugar de trabajo más seguro. En 1881 
solos, mataron o fueron dañados a 30.000 trabajadores ferroviarios en
el trabajo, y los peligros industriales existieron en otras 
industrias, incluyendo los textiles. Un compartimiento semanal 
nacional, la gaceta nacional del policía violó entusiástico los 
mores de la cultura genteel, centrándose en deportes legales e 
ilegales, crímenes y accidentes violentos, y sexo. 
Representaron a las mujeres a menudo como los autores o 
víctimas de la violencia, proporcionando al titillation al número 
total de lectores masculino del compartimiento semanal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087475</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108605</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/caught-in-the-shafting</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
