<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105183</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105183</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Thales theorem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Thales Theorem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Théorème de Thales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Theorem de Thales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Teorema di Thales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θεώρημα Thales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Teorema de Thales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet illustrating Thales Theorem (the diameter of a circle always subtends a right angle to any point on the circumference). The applet shows a circle where the user can rotate the diameter and a move a point on the circumference. The applet continuously shows the resulting right triangle, demonstrating that the theorem holds no matter how the points are moved around. Text on the page defines the theorem and relates it to other geometric entities. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, die 
Thales Theorem veranschaulichen (den Durchmesser von ein Kreis immer 
subtends ein rechter Winkel zu irgendeinem Punkt auf dem Umkreis). 
Der applet zeigt einem Kreis, wo der Benutzer den Durchmesser 
und eine Bewegung ein Punkt auf dem Umkreis drehen kann. Der 
applet zeigt ununterbrochen das resultierende rechte Dreieck und 
zeigt, daß das Theorem anhält, egal wie die Punkte herum verschoben 
werden. Text auf der Seite definiert das Theorem und steht es 
auf anderen geometrischen Instanzen in Verbindung. Applet kann 
zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif illustrant 
le théorème de Thales (le diamètre d'un cercle des subtends 
toujours un angle droit avec tout point sur la circonférence). 
L'applet montre à un cercle où l'utilisateur peut tourner le 
diamètre et un mouvement par point sur la circonférence. 
L'applet montre sans interruption la bonne triangle résultante,
démontrant que le théorème tient n'importe comment les points sont 
déplacés autour. Le texte à la page définit le théorème et
l'associe à d'autres entités géométriques. L'applet peut 
être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un 
projecteur de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la 
salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que ilustram o 
theorem de Thales (o diâmetro de subtends de um círculo sempre um 
ângulo direito a algum ponto na circunferência). O applet 
mostra a um círculo onde o usuário pode girar o diâmetro e um 
movimento um o ponto na circunferência. O applet mostra 
continuamente o triângulo direito resultante, demonstrando que o 
theorem prende não importa como os pontos são movidos ao redor. 
O texto na página define o theorem e relaciona-o a outras 
entidades geométricas. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de
tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois 
de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo 
o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma 
sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che illustrano
teorema di Thales (il diametro dei subtends del cerchio sempre un 
angolo retto a qualsiasi punto sulla circonferenza). Il applet 
mostra ad un cerchio dove l'utente può ruotare il diametro e un 
movimento un punto sulla circonferenza. Il applet mostra 
continuamente il giusto triangolo risultante, dimostrante che il 
teorema tiene non importa come i punti sono spostati intorno. Il
testo alla pagina definisce il teorema e lo collega ad altre entità 
geometriche. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di 
schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που επεξηγούν 
το θεώρημα Thales (η διάμετρος ενός κύκλου υποτείνει πάντα 
μια σωστή γωνία σε οποιοδήποτε σημείο στην περιφέρεια). Το 
applet εμφανίζει έναν κύκλο όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να 
περιστραφεί τη διάμετρο και μια κίνηση ένα σημείο στην 
περιφέρεια. Το applet εμφανίζει συνεχώς προκύπτον σωστό 
τρίγωνο, καταδεικνύοντας ότι το θεώρημα δεν κρατά ανεξάρτητα 
από το πόσο τα σημεία κινούνται γύρω. Το κείμενο στη 
σελίδα καθορίζει το θεώρημα και το αφορά άλλες γεωμετρικές 
οντότητες. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que ilustran 
el teorema de Thales (el diámetro de los subtends de un círculo 
siempre un angulo recto de cualquier punta en la circunferencia). 
El applet muestra a círculo donde el utilizador puede rotar el 
diámetro y un movimiento a la punta en la circunferencia. El 
applet muestra continuamente el triángulo derecho que resulta, 
demostrando que el teorema sostiene no importa cómo las puntas se 
mueven alrededor. El texto en la paginación define el teorema y
lo relaciona con otras entidades geométricas. El applet se 
puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105183</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/thales-theorem</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
