<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104244</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104244</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086736</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Playing with the Possible</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen mit dem möglichen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeu avec le possible</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogar com o possível</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giocando con il possibile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδι με τον πιθανό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El jugar con el posible</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website documents a high school drama class in which students wrote and performed their own autobiographical monologues. The site is centered around video clips that illustrate how students used drama to develop, express, and debate understandings around contested issues in their lives. Pincus also reflects on the nature of teacher inquiry and its role in her personal and professional development.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site dokumentiert eine High School 
Dramakategorie, in der Kursteilnehmer ihre eigenen autobiographischen 
Monologe schrieben und durchführten. Die Site wird um 
videoclips zentriert, die veranschaulichen, wie Kursteilnehmer Drama 
verwendeten, um sich zu entwickeln, ausdrückliche und Bedingung 
um gewetteiferte Ausgaben in ihren Lebensdauern Debatte. Pincus 
reflektiert auch sich auf der Natur der Lehreranfrage und seiner Rolle
in ihrer persönlichen und professionellen Entwicklung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web documente une classe de drame de 
lycée dans laquelle les étudiants ont écrit et ont exécuté leurs 
propres monologues autobiographiques. Le site est concentré 
sur les clips visuels qui des vues illustrent comment les 
étudiants avaient l'habitude le drame pour se développer, exprès, 
et de discussion autour des issues contestées en leurs vies. 
Pincus réfléchit également sur la nature de l'enquête de 
professeur et de son rôle dans son développement personnel et 
professionnel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site documenta uma classe do drama da 
High School em que os estudantes escreveram e executaram seus 
próprios monologues autobiographical. O local é centrado em 
torno dos grampos video que understandings ilustram como os estudantes
usaram o drama se tornar, expressos, e do debate em torno das 
edições contestadas em suas vidas. Pincus reflete também na 
natureza do inquérito do professor e do seu papel em seu 
desenvolvimento pessoal e profissional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site documenta un codice categoria di 
dramma della High School in cui gli allievi hanno scritto ed 
effettuato i loro propri monologues autobiografici. Il luogo è 
concentrato intorno alle video clip che understandings espressi e e di
dibattito illustrano come gli allievi hanno usato il dramma per 
svilupparsi, intorno alle edizioni contestate nelle loro vite. 
Pincus egualmente riflette sulla natura dell'inchiesta 
dell'insegnante e del relativo ruolo nel suo sviluppo personale e 
professionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος τεκμηριώνει μια κλάση δράματος 
γυμνασίου στην οποία οι σπουδαστές έγραψαν και εκτέλεσαν τους 
αυτοβιογραφικούς μονολόγους τους. Η περιοχή είναι 
κεντροθετημένη γύρω από τους τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες που 
επεξηγούν πώς οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποίησαν το δράμα που 
αναπτύσσονται, που εκφράζουν, και τους όρους συζήτησης γύρω από 
τα αμφισβητημένα ζητήματα στις ζωές τους. Το Pincus 
απεικονίζει επίσης στη φύση της έρευνας δασκάλων και του ρόλου 
του στην προσωπική και επαγγελματική ανάπτυξή της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site documenta una clase del drama de la 
High School secundaria en la cual los estudiantes escribieron y 
realizaron sus propios monólogos autobiográficos. El sitio se 
centra alrededor de los clips video que entendimiento ilustran cómo los 
estudiantes utilizaron drama para convertirse, expreso, y del 
discusión alrededor de ediciones disputadas en sus vidas. 
Pincus también refleja en la naturaleza de la pregunta del 
profesor y de su papel en su desarrollo personal y profesional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARSHA PINCUS
FN:MARSHA PINCUS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086736</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104244</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/playing-with-the-possible-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
