<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103906</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103906</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086313</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"If It Were Not For My Trust in Christ I Do Not Know How I Could Have Endured It": Testimony from Victims of New York's Draft Riots, July, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wenn es nicht für mein Vertrauen in Christ ich 
war, können Sie nicht, ich es ausgehalten haben könnte": 
Zeugnis von den Opfern der Entwurf-Aufstände New York, Juli, 
1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"si ce n'étaient pas pour ma confiance en Christ 
moi ne savez pas je pourrais l'avoir supportée" : Témoignage 
des victimes des émeutes de l'ébauche de New York, juillet, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"se não era para minha confiança em Christ mim 
não saiba eu poderia a ter resistido": Testimony das vítimas 
de motins do esboço de New York, julho, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"se non fosse per la mia fiducia in Christ io non 
sappia potrei resisterle": Testimonianza dalle vittime dei 
tumulti della brutta copia de New York, luglio, del 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εάν δεν ήταν για την εμπιστοσύνη μου σε Χριστό ι 
Do Not Know πώς θα μπορούσα να την έχω υπομείνει": 
Κατάθεση από τα θύματα των ταραχών σχεδίων της Νέας 
Υόρκης, τον Ιούλιος, του 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"si no era para mi confianza en Cristo yo no sepa 
habría podido aguantarla": Testimonio de víctimas de los 
alborotos del bosquejo de Nueva York, julio de 1863</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Between July 13 and 16, 1863, the largest riots the United States had yet seen shook New York City. In the so-called Civil War draft riots, the city's poor white working people, many of them Irish immigrants, bloodily protested the federally-imposed draft requiring all men to enlist in the Union Army. The rioters took out their rage on their perceived enemies: the Republicans whose wealth allowed them to purchase substitutes for military service, and the poor African Americans--their rivals in the city's labor market--for whom the war was being fought. On July 20, four days after federal troops put down the uprising, a group of Wall Street businessmen formed a committee to aid New York's devastated black community. The Committee of Merchants for the Relief of Colored People Suffering from the Late Riots gathered and distributed funds, and collected the following testimony.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zwischen Juli 13 und 16, 1863, rüttelten die 
größten Aufstände, welche die Vereinigten Staaten schon gesehen 
hatten, New York City. In den sogenannten 
Bürgerkriegentwurfaufständen protestierten die armen weißen 
Arbeitsleute der Stadt, viele von ihnen irische Immigranten, bloodily 
den Bundes-auferlegten Entwurf, der alle Männer benötigt, in der 
Anschluß-Armee einzutragen. Die rioters nahmen ihre Raserei auf
ihren wahrgenommenen Feinden heraus: die Republikaner deren 
Fülle sie Ersatz für militärischen Service kaufen ließ und die 
armen afrikanischen Amerikaner -- ihre Rivalen im Arbeitsmarkt der 
Stadt -- für, wem wurde der Krieg gekämpft. An Juli 20, vier 
sich Tage nachdem Bundestruppen hinunter den Aufstieg setzten, bildete
eine Gruppe Wall Street Geschäftsmänner einen Ausschuß, um New York
verwüsteter schwarzer Gemeinschaft zu helfen. Das 
Handelsgremium für die Entlastung der Farbigen, die unter den späten
Aufständen leiden, erfaßte und verteilte Kapital und sammelte das 
folgende Zeugnis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entre juillet 13 et 16, 1863, les plus grandes 
émeutes que les Etats-Unis avaient encore vu ont secoué New York 
City. Dans les prétendues émeutes d'ébauche de guerre civile,
les pauvres personnes travaillantes blanches de la ville, bon nombre 
d'entre elles les immigrés irlandais, ont bloodily protesté 
l'ébauche fédéral-imposée exigeant de tous les hommes de enrôler 
dans l'armée des syndicats. Les rioters ont sorti leur fureur 
sur leurs ennemis perçus : les républicains dont la richesse 
leur a permise d'acheter des produits de remplacement pour le service 
militaire, et les pauvres Américains africains -- leurs rivaux sur le
marché du travail de la ville -- pour qui la guerre était combattue.
Juillet 20, pendant quatre jours après que les troupes 
fédérales ont déposé le soulèvement, un groupe d'hommes 
d'affaires de Wall Street a formé un comité pour aider la 
communauté noire dévastée de New York. Le Comité des 
négociants pour le soulagement des personnes de couleur souffrant des
défuntes émeutes a recueilli et a distribué des fonds, et a 
rassemblé le témoignage suivant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entre julho 13 e 16, 1863, os motins que os 
maiores os estados unidos tinham visto ainda agitaram New York City. 
Nos motins so-called do esboço da guerra civil, os povos 
trabalhando brancos deficientes da cidade, muitos deles immigrants 
irish, protestaram bloodily o esboço federal-imposto que requer todos
os homens alistar-se no exército de união. Os rioters 
removeram sua raiva em seus inimigos percebidos: os republicanos
cuja a riqueza permitiu que comprassem substitutos para o serviço 
militar, e os americanos africanos deficientes -- seus rivais no 
mercado labor da cidade -- para quem a guerra era lutada. Julho 
em 20, quatro dias depois que as tropas federais colocaram o uprising,
um grupo de homens de negócios de Wall Street deu forma a um comitê 
para ajudar à comunidade preta devastated de New York. O 
comitê de comerciantes para o relevo dos povos coloridos que sofrem 
dos motins atrasados recolheu e distribuiu fundos, e coletou o 
seguinte testimony.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fra 16 luglio 13 e 1863, i più grandi tumulti che
unito Dichiarasse ancora avevano visto hanno agitato New York 
City. Nei cosiddetti tumulti della brutta copia di guerra 
civile, la povera gente lavorante bianca della città, molte di 
loro immigranti irlandesi, bloodily ha protestato la brutta copia 
federale-imposta che richiede a tutti gli uomini di arruolare 
nell'esercito del sindacato. I rioters hanno eliminato la loro 
collera sui loro nemici percepiti: i Repubblicani di cui la 
ricchezza li ha permessi di comprare i sostituti per servizio militare
ed i poveri Americani africani -- i loro rivale nel mercato 
di lavoro della città -- per chi la guerra stava combattenda. 
Il 20 luglio, quattro giorni dopo che le truppe federali 
posassero la rivolta, un gruppo degli uomini d'affari del Wall 
Street ha formato un comitato per aiutare la Comunità nera devastante
de New York. Il comitato dei commercianti per il rilievo della 
gente colorata che soffre dai tumulti ritardati ha riunito e
distribuito i fondi monetari ed ha raccolto la seguente testimonianza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταξύ 16 Ιουλίου 13 και ..1863, οι 
μεγαλύτερες ταραχές που οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες είχαν 
δει ακόμα τίναξαν την πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης. 
Στις αποκαλούμενες ταραχές σχεδίων εμφύλιου πολέμου, οι 
φτωχοί λευκοί εργαζόμενοι άνθρωποι της πόλης, πολλοί από τους 
ιρλανδικοί μετανάστες, διαμαρτυρήθηκαν bloodily το 
ομοσπονδιακά- σχέδιο που απαιτεί όλα τα άτομα για να 
στρατολογήσουν στο στρατό ένωσης. Οι στασιαστές πήραν έξω 
την οργή τους στους αντιληπτούς εχθρούς τους: τους 
Δημοκρατικούς ο των οποίων πλούτος επέτρεψε σε τους για να 
αγοράσει τα υποκατάστατα της στρατιωτικής θητείας, και οι φτωχοί 
αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί -- οι ανταγωνιστές τους στην αγορά 
εργασίας της πόλης -- για ποιους ο πόλεμος πάλευαν. Στις 20 
Ιουλίου, τέσσερις ημέρες αφότου κατέγραψαν τα ομοσπονδιακά 
στρατεύματα την έγερση, μια ομάδα επιχειρηματιών Γουώλ Στρητ 
διαμόρφωσε μια επιτροπή στην κατεστραμμένη μαύρη κοινότητα της 
Νέας Υόρκης ενίσχυσης. Η Επιτροπή των εμπόρων για την 
ανακούφιση των έγχρωμων ανθρώπων που πάσχουν από τις πρόσφατες 
ταραχές σύλλεξε και διένειμε τα κεφάλαια, και συνέλεξε την 
ακόλουθη κατάθεση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entre 13 de julio y 16 de 1863, los alborotos 
más grandes que los Estados Unidos todavía habían visto 
sacudarieron New York City. En los alborotos supuestos del 
bosquejo de la guerra civil, la gente de trabajo blanca pobre de la 
ciudad, muchas de ellos los inmigrantes irlandeses, bloodily protestó
el bosquejo federal-impuesto que requería a todos los hombres alistar
en el ejército de unión. Los rioters tomaron hacia fuera su 
rabia en sus enemigos percibidos: los republicanos que 
abundancia permitió que compraran los substitutos para el servicio 
militar, y los americanos africanos pobres -- sus rivales en el 
mercado de trabajo de la ciudad -- para quién la guerra era luchada. 
De julio el 20, cuatro días después de que las tropas 
federales colocaron la sublevación, un grupo de los hombres de 
negocios de Wall Street formó a comité para ayudar a la comunidad 
negra devastada de Nueva York. El comité de los comerciantes 
para la relevación de la gente coloreada que sufría de los últimos 
alborotos recolectó y distribuyó fondos, y recogió el testimonio 
siguiente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086313</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103906</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/if-it-were-not-for-my-trust-in-christ-i-do-not-know-how-i-could-have-endured-it-testimony-from-victims-of-new-yorks-draft-riots-july-1863</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
