<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974120</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">WolfQuest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">WolfQuest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">WolfQuest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">WolfQuest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">WolfQuest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">WolfQuest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">WolfQuest</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Learn about wolf ecology by living the life of a wild wolf in Yellowstone National Park. Play alone or with friends in on-line multiplayer missions, explore the wilderness, hunt elk, and encounter stranger wolves in your quest to find a mate. Ultimately, your success will depend on forming a family pack, raising pups, and ensuring the survival of your pack. The WolfQuest experience goes beyond the game with an active online community where you can discuss the game with other players, chat with wolf biologists, and share artwork and stories about wolves.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erlernen Sie über Wolfökologie, indem Sie das 
Leben eines wilden Wolfs in Yellowstone Nationalpark leben. 
Spielen Sie alleine oder mit Freunden in den 
Onlinemultispielermissionen, erforschen die Wildnis, jagen Elche und 
antreffen merkwürdigere Wölfe in Ihrer Suche, um einen Gehilfen zu 
finden. Schließlich hängt Ihr Erfolg von der Formung eines 
Familie Satzes, vom Anheben der Welpen und vom Sicherstellen des 
Überlebens Ihres Satzes ab. Die WolfQuest Erfahrung geht über 
dem Spiel mit einer aktiven Onlinegemeinschaft hinaus, in der Sie das 
Spiel mit anderen Spielern behandeln können, mit Wolfbiologen und 
Anteilgestaltungsarbeit und -geschichten über Wölfe zu plaudern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Renseignez-vous sur l'écologie de loup en vivant 
la vie d'un loup sauvage en parc national de Yellowstone. Jouez 
seul ou avec des amis dans des missions multijoueuses en ligne, 
explorent le désert, chassent des élans, et rencontrent des loups 
plus étranges à votre recherche pour trouver un compagnon. 
Finalement, votre succès dépendra de former un paquet de 
famille, d'élever des chiots, et d'assurer la survie de votre paquet.
L'expérience de WolfQuest dépasse le jeu avec une communauté 
en ligne active où vous pouvez discuter le jeu avec d'autres joueurs,
pour causer avec les biologistes de loup, et le dessin-modèle et les 
histoires de part au sujet des loups.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprenda sobre o ecology do lobo vivendo a vida de 
um lobo selvagem no parque nacional de Yellowstone. Jogue 
sozinho ou com os amigos em missões multiplayer em linha, exploram a 
região selvagem, caçam alces, e encontram uns lobos mais estranhos 
em seu quest para encontrar um mate. Finalmente, seu sucesso 
dependerá de dar forma a um bloco da família, de levantar filhotes 
de cachorro, e de assegurar a sobrevivência de seu bloco. A 
experiência de WolfQuest vai além do jogo com uma comunidade em 
linha ativa onde você possa discutir o jogo com outros jogadores, 
chat com biólogos do lobo, e arte -final e histórias da parte sobre 
lobos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Impari circa l'ecologia del lupo vivendo la vita 
di un lupo selvaggio nel parco nazionale di Yellowstone. Gioc da
solo o con gli amici nelle missioni multiplayer in linea, esplorano la
selva, cercano gli alci ed incontrano i lupi più sconosciuti 
nella vostra ricerca per trovare un compagno. Infine, il vostro 
successo dipenderà dal formare un pacchetto della famiglia, 
dall'innalzamento dei pups e dall'accertare la sopravvivenza del 
vostro pacchetto. L'esperienza di WolfQuest va oltre il gioco 
con una Comunità in linea attiva in cui potete discutere il gioco con
altri giocatori, chiacchierare con i biologhi del lupo ed 
illustrazione e storia della parte circa i lupi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μάθετε για την οικολογία λύκων μέχρι ζωή διαβίωσης 
την ενός άγριου λύκου στο εθνικό πάρκο Yellowstone. 
Παίξτε μόνο ή με τους φίλους στις σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
αποστολές multiplayer, εξερευνήστε την αγριότητα, κυνηγήστε τις
άλκες, και αντιμετωπίστε τους πιό παράξενους λύκους στην 
αναζήτησή σας για να βρείτε έναν σύντροφο. Τελικά, η 
επιτυχία σας θα εξαρτηθεί από τη διαμόρφωση ενός οικογενειακού 
πακέτου, την ανατροφή των κουταβιών, και την εξασφάλιση της 
επιβίωσης του πακέτου σας. Η εμπειρία WolfQuest 
υπερβαίνει το παιχνίδι με μια ενεργό σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
κοινότητα όπου μπορείτε να συζητήσετε το παιχνίδι με άλλους 
παίκτες, συνομιλία με τους βιολόγους λύκων, και το έργο τέχνης 
και τις ιστορίες μεριδίου για τους λύκους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aprenda sobre la ecología del lobo viviendo la 
vida de un lobo salvaje en el parque nacional de Yellowstone. 
Juegue solamente o con los amigos en misiones multiplayer en 
línea, exploran el yermo, buscan alces, y encuentran lobos más 
extraños en su búsqueda para encontrar a un compañero. En 
última instancia, su éxito dependerá de formar un paquete de la 
familia, de criar perritos, y de asegurar la supervivencia de su 
paquete. La experiencia de WolfQuest va más allá del juego con
una comunidad en línea activa donde usted puede discutir el juego con
otros jugadores, a charlar con los biólogos del lobo, y las 
ilustraciones y las historias de la parte sobre lobos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974120</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102861</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/wolfquest</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
