<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105021</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105021</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206899</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">When Work is Done</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn Arbeit erledigt wird</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand le travail est effectué</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando o trabalho for feito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando il lavoro è fatto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν η εργασία γίνεται</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando se hace el trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a lesson plan that uses photographs as primary sources and that can help students develop historical analysis skills. After completing the introductory lesson using photographs as primary sources, students compile their own albums based on a thesis statement about life in the 20th century.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Lektionplan, der Fotographien als 
Primärquellen benutzt und die können, Kursteilnehmern helfen, 
historische Analyse Fähigkeiten zu entwickeln. Nachdem sie die 
einleitende Lektion mit Fotographien als Primärquellen durchgeführt 
haben, kompilieren Kursteilnehmer ihre eigenen Alben, die auf einer 
Theseanweisung über das Leben im 20. Jahrhundert basieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un plan de leçon qui utilise des 
photographies en tant que sources primaires et qui peuvent aider des 
étudiants à développer des qualifications historiques d'analyse. 
Après avoir terminé la leçon préliminaire en utilisant des 
photographies en tant que sources primaires, les étudiants compilent 
leurs propres albums basés sur un rapport de thèse au sujet de la 
vie au 20ème siècle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma planta da lição que use fotografias como 
as fontes preliminares e que podem para ajudar a estudantes 
desenvolver habilidades históricas da análise. Após ter 
terminado a lição introdutória usando fotografias como fontes 
preliminares, os estudantes compilam seus próprios albums baseados em
uma indicação do thesis sobre a vida no 20o século.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un programma di lezione che usa le fotografie 
come sorgenti primarie e che possono aiutare gli allievi a sviluppare 
le abilità storiche di analisi. Dopo avere completato la 
lezione introduttiva usando le fotografie come sorgenti primarie, gli 
allievi compilano i loro propri album basati su un'istruzione di tesi 
circa vita nel ventesimo secolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα σχέδιο μαθήματος που χρησιμοποιεί τις 
φωτογραφίες ως αρχικές πηγές και που μπορεί να βοηθήσει τους 
σπουδαστές να αναπτύξουν τις ιστορικές δεξιότητες ανάλυσης. 
Μετά από να ολοκληρώσουν το εισαγωγικό μάθημα που 
χρησιμοποιεί τις φωτογραφίες ως αρχικές πηγές, οι σπουδαστές 
μεταγλωττίζουν τα λευκώματά τους βασισμένα σε μια δήλωση 
διατριβής για τη ζωή στο 20ό αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un plan de la lección que utiliza las 
fotografías como fuentes primarias y que puedan ayudar a estudiantes 
a desarrollar habilidades históricas del análisis. Después de
terminar la lección introductoria usando las fotografías como 
fuentes primarias, los estudiantes compilan sus propios álbumes 
basados en una declaración de la tesis sobre vida en el vigésimo 
siglo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206899</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105021</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/when-work-is-done</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
