<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203022</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Great Moments in Science: Light of Life 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Große Momente in der Wissenschaft: Licht 
von Leben 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Grands moments en la Science : Lumière de 
la vie 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Momentos grandes na ciência: Luz da vida 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Momenti grandi nella scienza: Luce di vita 
3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεγάλες στιγμές στην επιστήμη: Φως της ζωής 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Grandes momentos en ciencia: Luz de la vida 
3</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Great Moments in Science radio transcript describes photons of light (not to be confused with bioluminescence) that can be seen only with the most sensitive photodetectors. Scientists believe that this light might be used by cells to communicate with each other. The audio version of this program can be downloaded and requires RealPlayer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses beschreibt große Momente in der 
Wissenschaft Radioabschrift Photonen des Lichtes (nicht mit 
bioluminescence verwirrt werden) die nur mit den empfindlichsten 
Photodetektoren gesehen werden können. Wissenschaftler glauben,
daß dieses Licht durch Zellen benutzt werden konnte, um mit einander 
zu verständigen. Die Audioversion dieses Programms kann 
downloadet werden und benötigt RealPlayer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce les grands moments dans la transcription de 
radio de la Science décrit les photons de la lumière (ne pas être 
confondu avec le bioluminescence) qui peuvent être vus seulement avec
les détecteurs photoélectriques les plus sensibles. Les 
scientifiques croient que cette lumière pourrait être employée par 
des cellules pour communiquer avec l'un l'autre. La version 
sonore de ce programme peut être téléchargée et exige RealPlayer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este os momentos grandes no transcript do rádio 
da ciência descrevem os photons da luz (para não ser confundido com 
o bioluminescence) que podem ser vistos somente com os photodetectors 
os mais sensíveis. Os cientistas acreditam que esta luz pôde 
ser usada por pilhas se comunicar com se. A versão audio deste 
programa pode downloaded e requer RealPlayer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo momenti grandi nella trascrizione della 
radio di scienza descrive i fotoni di luce (non essere confuso con il 
bioluminescence) che possono essere visti soltanto con i rivelatori 
fotoelettrici più sensibili. Gli scienziati ritengono che 
questa luce potrebbe essere usata dalle cellule per comunicare con a 
vicenda. La versione audio di questo programma può essere 
trasferita e richiede RealPlayer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό μεγάλες στιγμές στο ραδιο αντίγραφο επιστήμης 
περιγράφει τα φωτόνια του φωτός (για να μην συγχεθούν με τη 
βιολογική ακτινοβολία) που μπορούν να δουν μόνο με 
τους πιό ευαίσθητους φωτοανιχνευτές. Οι επιστήμονες θεωρούν
ότι αυτό το φως να χρησιμοποιηθεί από τα κύτταρα για να 
επικοινωνήσει το ένα με το άλλο. Η ηχητική έκδοση αυτού 
του προγράμματος μπορεί να μεταφορτωθεί και απαιτεί RealPlayer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este los grandes momentos en la transcripción de 
la radio de la ciencia describen los fotones de la luz (no ser 
confundido con bioluminescence) que se pueden ver solamente con los 
fotodetectores más sensibles. Los científicos creen que esta 
luz se pudo utilizar por las células para comunicarse con uno a. 
La versión audio de este programa se puede descargar y requiere
RealPlayer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KARL S. KRUSZELNICKI
FN:KARL S. KRUSZELNICKI
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AUSTRALIAN BROADCASTING CORPORATION
FN:AUSTRALIAN BROADCASTING CORPORATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203022</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107679</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/great-moments-in-science-light-of-life-3</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
