<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104024</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104024</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206775</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Coffeyville, Kansas: The Town That Stopped the Dalton Gang</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Coffeyville, Kansas: Die Stadt, die die 
Dalton Gruppe stoppte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Coffeyville, Le Kansas : La ville qui a 
arrêté la troupe de Dalton</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Coffeyville, Kansas: A cidade que parou o 
grupo de Dalton</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Coffeyville, Kansas: La città che ha 
arrestato il gruppo del Dalton</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Coffeyville, Κάνσας: Η πόλη που σταμάτησε τη 
dalton συμμορία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Coffeyville, Kansas: La ciudad que paró a 
cuadrilla de Dalton</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts the bank robbery attempt that made Coffeyville famous in 1892. Bob Dalton's gang had been robbing trains, stealing horses, and looting gambling houses in the Midwest. But Dalton wanted more. He claimed he would beat anything Jesse James ever did?rob two banks at once, in broad daylight. This is the story of his attempt to do so and the response he met from the citizens of this small southeastern Kansas town.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt den Bankraubversuch nach, der Coffeyville 
berühmt 1892 bildete. Bob Daltons Gruppe hatte Serien beraubt, 
Pferde gestohlen und geplündert spielende Häuser im Mittelwesten. 
Aber Dalton wünschte mehr. Er behauptete ihn würde 
schlagen alles Jesse James überhaupt did?rob zwei Bänke sofort, im 
ausgedehnten Tageslicht. Dieses ist die Geschichte seines 
Versuchs, so zu tun und der Antwort, die er von den Bürgern dieser 
kleinen südöstlichen Kansas Stadt traf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte la tentative de vol de banque qui a rendu 
Coffeyville célèbre en 1892. La troupe de Bob Dalton avait 
volé des trains, avait volé des chevaux, et avait pillé les maisons
de jeu dans le Midwest. Mais Dalton a voulu plus. Il l'a 
réclamé battrait n'importe quoi des banques du did?rob deux de Jesse
James jamais immédiatement, en large jour. C'est 
l'histoire de sa tentative de faire ainsi et de la réponse qu'il a 
rencontrée des citoyens de cette petite ville du sud-est du Kansas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts a tentativa do robbery do banco que fêz 
Coffeyville famoso em 1892. O grupo de Bob Dalton tem roubado 
trens, tem roubado cavalos, e looting casas gambling no Midwest. 
Mas Dalton quis mais. Reivindicou-o bateria qualquer coisa
bancos do did?rob dois de Jesse James sempre em uma vez, na luz do dia
larga. Esta é a história de sua tentativa de fazer assim e da 
resposta que se encontrou com dos cidadãos desta cidade do sudeste 
pequena de Kansas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta il tentativo di robbery della banca
che ha reso Coffeyville famoso in 1892. Il gruppo del Bob Dalton
stava rubando i treni, stava rubando i cavalli e stava saccheggiando 
le case di gioco nel Midwest. Ma Dalton ha desiderato più. 
Lo ha esatto batterebbe qualche cosa banca del did?rob due
di Jesse James mai immediatamente, nella vasta luce del giorno. 
Ciò è la storia del suo tentativo di fare così e della 
risposta che ha venuto a contatto di dai cittadini di questa piccola 
città del sud-est del Kansas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί την προσπάθεια ληστείας τραπεζών ότι 
γίνοντα Coffeyville διάσημο σε 1892, dalton βαριδιών 
συμμορία λήστευε τα τραίνα, τα stealing άλογα, και τα σπίτια 
παιχνιδιού λεηλασίας midwest. Αλλά dalton θέλησε 
περισσότερων. Απαίτησε ότι θα κτυπούσε τίποτα Jesse 
james did?rob πάντα δύο τράπεζες αμέσως, στο ευρύ φως της 
ημέρας. Αυτό είναι η ιστορία της προσπάθειάς του να κάνει
έτσι και της απάντησης που συναντήθηκε από τους πολίτες αυτής 
της μικρής νοτιοανατολικής πόλης του Κάνσας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo la tentativa del robo de la 
batería que hizo Coffeyville famoso en 1892. La cuadrilla de 
Bob Dalton había estado robando los trenes, había estado robando 
caballos, y había estado saqueando casas de juego en el Cercano 
oeste. Pero Dalton deseó más. Él lo demandó batiría 
cualquier cosa las baterías del did?rob dos de Jesse James siempre 
inmediatamente, en amplia hora solar. Ésta es la historia de su
tentativa de hacer tan y de la respuesta que él resolvió de los 
ciudadanos de esta ciudad del sudeste pequeña de Kansas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206775</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104024</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/coffeyville-kansas-the-town-that-stopped-the-dalton-gang</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
