<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106411</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106411</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211981</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rock/Mineral Scavenger Hunt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rock/Mineral Reiniger-Jagd</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chasse À Scavenger de Rock/Mineral</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Caça Do SCAVENGER De Rock/Mineral</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Pulitore Di Rock/Mineral Cerca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βράχος/ορυκτό κυνήγι οδοκαθαριστών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caza Del Limpiador De Rock/Mineral</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this game activity, teams of students compete to find a specimen of each rock or mineral on a list in a field area. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Spielaktivität konkurrieren Teams der 
Kursteilnehmer, um ein Probenmaterial jedes Felsens oder Mineral auf 
einer Liste in einem auffangenbereich zu finden. Auf dieser 
Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen über die 
erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité de jeu, les équipes 
d'étudiants concurrencent pour trouver un spécimen de chaque roche 
ou le minerai sur une liste dans une zone de zone. À cette page
de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux 
informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les 
extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade do jogo, as equipes dos estudantes
competem para encontrar um espécime de cada rocha ou o mineral em uma
lista em uma área do campo. Nesta página do ponto começar, os
usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de 
aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as
notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as 
referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività del gioco, le squadre di 
allievi competono per trovare un esemplare di ogni roccia o il 
minerale su una lista in una zona del campo. A questa pagina del
punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sugli
obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di 
istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le idee di 
valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα παιχνιδιών, οι ομάδες των 
σπουδαστών ανταγωνίζονται για να βρούν ένα δείγμα κάθε βράχου 
ή μεταλλεύματος σε έναν κατάλογο σε μια περιοχή πεδίων. Σε
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad del juego, los equipos de 
estudiantes compiten para encontrar un espécimen de cada roca o el 
mineral en una lista en un área del campo. En esta paginación 
del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la 
información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para
las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales
didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos 
cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REBECCA TEED
FN:REBECCA TEED
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211981</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106411</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rock-mineral-scavenger-hunt</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
