<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106884</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106884</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086996</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Musical Saga of Homestead</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die musikalische Saga des Gehöfts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Saga musicale de la ferme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Saga musical do homestead</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Saga musicale della fattoria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μουσικό μακρύ περιπετειώδες μυθιστόρημα του 
αγροτικού σπιτιού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Saga musical de la granja</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Workers sang during strikes not only to state their beliefs and goals, but because singing helped bind workers together. The Homestead strike of 1892 even had its own  Homestead Strike Songster , and the story of the strike can be traced in the lyrics of the following four songs. "The Homestead Strike" explained that Carnegie's efforts to "lower our wages" was the basic cause of the strike. "The Fort That Frick Built" described Homestead manager Henry Frick's transformation of the mill on the eve of the strike into a fortress with barbed-wire fences. The death of nine strikers was chronicled in "Father Was Killed by the Pinkerton Men." And "Song of a Strike," written by George Swetnam, retrospectively commemorated the Homestead strikers' courage in defending their homes and their jobs against the overwhelming might of the Carnegie Steel Company and their hired "bum detectives."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeiter sangen während der Schläge nicht nur, 
um ihren Glauben und Ziele anzugeben, aber weil, der geholfenen 
zusammen singend Bindung, Arbeiter. Der Gehöftschlag von 1892 
hatte sogar seinen eigenen Gehöft-Schlag Songster, und die Geschichte
des Schlages kann in den Lyriken der folgenden vier Liede 
verfolgt werden. "der Gehöft-Schlag" erklärte, daß die 
Bemühungen Carnegies "niedriger unsere Löhne" die grundlegende 
Ursache des Schlages waren. "das Fort, das Frick" aufbaute, 
beschrieb Transformation Gehöftmanager Henry Fricks des Tausendstels 
auf dem Vorabend des Schlages in eine Festung mit Stacheldrahtzäunen.
Der Tod von neun Schlaggeräten wurde aufgezeichnet "im Vater 
wurde beendet von den Pinkerton Männern." Und "Lied eines 
Schlages," geschrieben durch George Swetnam, gedachte zurückblickend 
den Mut der Gehöftschlaggeräte, wenn es ihre Häuser verteidigte und
ihre Jobs gegen das Überwältigen konnten von Carnegie Steel Company 
und ihre angestellten "wertlosdetektive."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les ouvriers ont chanté pendant des grèves non 
seulement pour énoncer leur croyance et buts, mais pendant parce que 
chantant des ouvriers aidés de grippage ensemble. La grève de 
ferme de 1892 a même eu son propre Chanteur de grève de ferme, et
l'histoire de la grève peut être tracée dans le lyrique des quatre 
chansons suivantes. "la grève de ferme" a expliqué que les 
efforts de Carnegie's "inférieurs nos salaires" étaient la cause de 
base de la grève. "le fort que Frick a construit" a décrit la 
transformation de Frick d'Henry de gestionnaire de ferme du moulin la 
veille de la grève dans une forteresse avec des barrières de 
barbelé. La mort de neuf butées a été faite la chronique 
dans le "père a été détruite par les hommes de Pinkerton." 
Et la "chanson d'une grève," écrit par George Swetnam, a 
rétrospectivement commémoré le courage des butées de ferme en 
défendant leurs maisons et leurs travaux contre accabler pourraient 
de Carnegie Steel Company et leurs "détectives sans valeur loués."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os trabalhadores cantaram durante batidas para 
indicar não somente seus opinião e objetivos, mas porque cantando os
trabalhadores ajudados do ligamento junto. A batida do homestead
de 1892 teve mesmo sua própria batida Songster do homestead, e a 
história da batida pode ser seguida nos lyrics das seguintes quatro 
canções. "a batida do homestead" explicou que os esforços de 
Carnegie "mais baixos nossos salários" eram a causa básica da 
batida. "o fort que Frick construiu" descreveu a transformação
de Frick do Henry do gerente do homestead do moinho no eve da batida 
em um fortress com cercas do arame farpado. A morte de nove 
grevistas chronicled no "pai foi matada pelos homens de Pinkerton." 
E a "canção de uma batida," escrito por George Swetnam, 
comemorou retrospectively a coragem dos grevistas do homestead em 
defender suas HOME e seus trabalhos de encontro a oprimir puderam do 
Carnegie Aço Companhia e seus "detetives bum empregados."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli operai hanno cantato durante i colpi per 
dichiarare non soltanto la loro credenza ed obiettivi, ma 
perché cantando gli operai aiutati di legatura insieme. Il 
colpo della fattoria di 1892 persino ha avuto relativo proprio colpo 
Songster della fattoria e la storia del colpo può essere seguita nei 
lyrics di seguenti quattro canzoni. "il colpo della fattoria" ha
spiegato che gli sforzi del Carnegie "più bassi i nostri stipendi" 
erano la causa di base del colpo. "il Forte che Frick ha 
costruito" ha descritto la trasformazione del Frick di henry del 
gestore della fattoria del laminatoio la vigilia del colpo in un 
fortress con le recinzioni del filo spinato. La morte di nove 
percussori chronicled "in padre è stata uccisa dall'uomo di 
Pinkerton." E "la canzone di un colpo," scritto da George 
Swetnam, ha commemorato in modo retrospettivo il coraggio dei 
percussori della fattoria nel difendere le loro sedi ed i loro lavori 
contro sopraffare potrebbero del Carnegie Steel Company ed i loro 
"detectivi bum assunti."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εργαζόμενοι τραγούδησαν κατά τη διάρκεια των 
απεργιών όχι μόνο για να δηλώσουν τις πεποιθήσεις και τους 
στόχους τους, αλλά επειδή τραγούδι που ενισχύθηκε να δεσμεύσει 
τους εργαζομένους από κοινού. Η απεργία αγροτικών σπιτιών 
1892 ακόμη και είχε τον τραγουδιστή απεργίας αγροτικών 
σπιτιών της, και η ιστορία της απεργίας μπορεί να επισημανθεί στα
λυρικά ποιήματα των ακόλουθων τεσσάρων τραγουδιών. "Η 
απεργία αγροτικών σπιτιών" εξήγησε ότι οι προσπάθειες 
Carnegie "χαμηλότερες οι αμοιβές μασ" ήταν η βασική αιτία της 
απεργίας. "Το οχυρό που Frick έχτισε" περιέγραψε το 
μετασχηματισμό Henry Frick's διευθυντών αγροτικών σπιτιών 
του μύλου την παραμονή της απεργίας σε ένα φρούριο με 
barbed-wire τις φραγές. Ο θάνατος εννέα απεργών 
εξιστορήθηκε κατά γράμμα "στον πατέρα σκοτώθηκε από τα άτομα 
Pinkerton." Και "το τραγούδι μιας απεργίας," γραπτός από 
George Swetnam, τίμησε την μνήμη αναδρομικά του θάρρους των 
απεργών αγροτικών σπιτιών στην υπεράσπιση των σπιτιών τους και οι
εργασίες τους ενάντια να συντρίψουν της επιχείρησης χάλυβα 
Carnegie και των μισθωμένων "ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών αχρήστων 
τους."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los trabajadores cantaron durante huelgas para 
indicar no solamente su creencia y metas, pero porque cantaron a 
trabajadores ayudados del lazo juntos. La huelga de la granja de
1892 incluso tenía su propia huelga Songster de la granja, y la 
historia de la huelga se puede rastrear en las líricas de las cuatro 
canciones siguientes. "la huelga de la granja" explicó que los 
esfuerzos de Carnegie "más bajos nuestros salarios" eran la causa 
básica de la huelga. "la fortaleza que Frick construyó" 
describió la transformación de Frick del Henrio del encargado de la 
granja del molino en la víspera de la huelga en una fortaleza con las
cercas del alambre de púas. La muerte de nueve huelguistas 
chronicled en "padre fue matada por los hombres de Pinkerton." Y
la "canción de una huelga," escrito por George Swetnam, conmemoró 
retrospectivo el valor de los huelguistas de la granja en defender sus
hogares y sus trabajos contra abrumar pudieron del Carnegie Steel 
Company y sus "detectives empleados del vago."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086996</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106884</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-musical-saga-of-homestead</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
