<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087390</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"An Ignorant Back-woods Bear Hunter": Davy Crockett Runs for Office on the Tennessee Frontier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ein Unwissender Hinterwälder-Bär Jäger": 
Davy Crockett Durchläufe für Büro auf der Tennessee Grenze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Un Chasseur Ignorant d'Ours de Forêts" : 
Passages de Davy Crockett pour le bureau sur la frontière du 
Tennessee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Um Caçador Ignorant Do Urso Dos Back-woods": 
Funcionamentos de Davy Crockett para o escritório na fronteira 
de Tennessee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Un Cacciatore Ignaro Dell'Orso Dei Back-woods": 
Funzionamenti di Davy Crockett per l'ufficio sulla frontiera del
Tennessee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ανίδεο back-woods αντέχει τον κυνηγό": 
Τρεξίματα Crockett Davy για το γραφείο στα σύνορα του 
Tennessee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Un Cazador Ignorante Del Oso De los Back-woods": 
Funcionamientos de Davy Crockett para la oficina en la frontera 
de Tennessee</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Davy Crockett was a frontiersmen, soldier, and politician who used his autobiography to help create an image of himself as a larger-than-life American hero. The description of frontier politics presented here is based on his campaign for a seat in the Tennessee legislature in 1821. In the early decades of the 19th century, property qualifications for voting were lifted and more white men gained access to the vote. With this greater access came new and more democratic styles of political activity. To recruit support at elections, office seekers made public meetings and popular entertainments part of political life. Crockett's account reflected these changes, suggesting that humor, hunting skills, and male camaraderie were as important to electoral success as a clear stance on the issues of the day.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Davy Crockett war Frontiersmen, Soldat und 
Politiker, der seine Autobiographie benutzte, um zu helfen, ein Bild 
von als Groß-alslebensdauer Amerikanerheld zu erstellen. Die 
Beschreibung der Grenzpolitik, die hier dargestellt wird, basiert auf 
seiner Kampagne für einen Sitz in der Tennessee Gesetzgebung 1821. 
In den frühen Dekaden des 19. Jahrhunderts, wurden Eigenschaft 
Qualifikationen für das Wählen angehoben und weißere Männer 
erhielten zur Stimme Zutritt. Mit diesem grösseren Zugriff 
kamen neue und demokratischere Arten der politischen Aktivität. 
Support an den Wahlen einziehen, ließen Bürosucher allgemeine 
Sitzungen und populäre Unterhaltungen zerteilen von der politischen 
Lebensdauer. Konto Crocketts reflektierte diese Änderungen und 
schlug diese Stimmung, Jagdfähigkeiten vor, und männlicher 
Kameradschaftsgeist waren zum Wahlerfolg wie eine freie Position auf 
den Ausgaben des Tages so wichtig.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Davy Crockett était les frontaliers, le soldat, 
et le politicien qui avait l'habitude son autobiographie pour aider à
créer une image de se en tant que héros d'Américain de la 
grand-que-vie. La description de la politique de frontière 
présentée ici est basée sur sa campagne pour un siège dans la 
législature du Tennessee en 1821. Dans les décennies tôt du 
19ème siècle, des qualifications de propriété pour voter ont été
soulevées et des hommes plus blancs ont accédé à la voix. 
Avec ce plus grand accès sont venus les nouveaux et plus 
démocratiques modèles de l'activité politique. Pour recruter 
le support aux élections, les chercheurs de bureau ont fait des 
réunions publiques et les divertissements populaires partie de la vie
politique. Le compte de Crockett a reflété ces changements, 
suggérant cette humeur, qualifications de chasse, et la camaraderie 
mâle étaient aussi importante pour le succès électoral qu'une 
position claire sur les questions du jour.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Davy Crockett era frontiersmen, soldado, e 
político que usou seu autobiography ajudar criar uma imagem dhimself 
como um herói do americano da grande-do que-vida. A descrição
da política da fronteira apresentada aqui é baseada em sua campanha 
para um assento na legislatura de Tennessee em 1821. Nas 
décadas adiantadas do 1ø século, as qualificações da propriedade 
para votar foram levantadas e uns homens mais brancos ganharam o 
acesso ao voto. Com este acesso mais grande vieram os estilos 
novos e mais democráticos da atividade política. Para recrutar
a sustentação em eleições, os seekers do escritório fizeram 
reuniões públicas e os entertainments populares parte da vida 
política. O cliente de Crockett refletiu estas mudanças, 
sugerindo esse humor, habilidades da caça, e o camaraderie masculino 
era tão importante para o sucesso electoral quanto um stance 
desobstruído nas introduções do dia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Davy Crockett era frontiersmen, soldato e politico
che ha usato il suo autobiography per contribuire a creare un'immagine
di sè come hero dell'americano di gran-che-vita. La descrizione
della politica di frontiera presentata qui è basata sulla sua 
campagna per una sede nella legislatura del Tennessee in 1821. 
Nelle decadi in anticipo del diciannovesimo secolo, le 
qualificazioni della proprietà per il voto sono state alzate e gli 
uomini più bianchi hanno accesso al voto. Con questo accesso 
più grande sono venuto i nuovi e stili più democratici di attività 
politica. Per reclutare il supporto alle elezioni, i cercatori 
dell'ufficio hanno fatto le riunioni pubbliche e gli intrattenimenti 
popolari parte di vita politica. Il cliente del Crockett ha 
riflesso questi cambiamenti, suggerendo quell'umore, cercando 
le abilità ed il camaraderie maschio era importante a successo 
elettorale come posizione libera sulle emissioni del giorno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Davy Crockett ήταν frontiersmen, στρατιώτης,
και πολιτικός που χρησιμοποίησαν την αυτοβιογραφία του για να 
βοηθήσουν να δημιουργήσουν μια εικόνα του ως αμερικανικό ήρωα 
μεγάλος-από-ζωής. Η περιγραφή της συνοριακής πολιτικής που
παρουσιάζεται εδώ είναι βασισμένη στην εκστρατεία του για ένα 
κάθισμα στο νομοθετικό σώμα του Tennessee το 1821. Στις
αρχές των δεκαετιών του 19$ου αιώνα, τα προσόντα ιδιοκτησίας για 
την ψηφοφορία ανυψώθηκαν και περισσότερα λευκά άτομα απόκτησαν 
πρόσβαση στην ψηφοφορία. Με αυτήν την μεγαλύτερη πρόσβαση 
ήρθε νέες και δημοκρατικότερες μορφές της πολιτικής 
δραστηριότητας. Για να στρατολογήσουν την υποστήριξη στις 
εκλογές, οι αναζητητές γραφείων έκαναν τις δημόσιες συνεδριάσεις
και το δημοφιλές μέρος ψυχαγωγιών της πολιτικής ζωής. Ο 
απολογισμός του Crockett απεικόνισε αυτές τις αλλαγές, που 
προτείνουν ότι το χιούμορ, οι δεξιότητες κυνηγιού, και η 
αρσενική συναδελφικότητα ήταν τόσο σημαντικά στην εκλογική 
επιτυχία όσο μια σαφής θέση στα ζητήματα της ημέρας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Davy Crockett era los frontiersmen, soldado, y el 
político que utilizó su autobiografía para ayudar a crear una 
imagen de se como héroe del americano de la grande-que-vida. La
descripción de la política de la frontera presentada aquí se basa 
en su campaña para un asiento en la legislatura de Tennessee en 1821.
En las décadas tempranas del diecinueveavo siglo, las 
calificaciones de la característica para votar fueron levantadas y 
hombres más blancos accedieron al voto. Con este mayor acceso 
vinieron los nuevos y más democráticos estilos de la actividad 
política. Para reclutar la ayuda en las elecciones, los 
buscadores de la oficina hicieron reuniones públicas y las 
hospitalidades populares parte de vida política. La cuenta de 
Crockett reflejó estos cambios, sugiriendo ese humor, habilidades de 
la caza, y el camaraderie masculino era tan importante para el éxito 
electoral como una postura clara en las aplicaciones el día.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087390</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103915</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-ignorant-back-woods-bear-hunter-davy-crockett-runs-for-office-on-the-tennessee-frontier</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
