<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103848</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103848</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086354</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Was Like A Weed:" Carl Oglesby on The 1960s Student Movement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Es War Wie Ein Unkraut:" Karl Oglesby auf 
der sechziger Jahre Kursteilnehmer-Bewegung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Il Était Comme Une Mauvaise herbe :" Karl 
Oglesby sur le mouvement d'étudiant des années 60</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Era Como Uma Erva daninha:" Carl Oglesby no
movimento do estudante dos 1960s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Era Come Un'Erbaccia:" Carl Oglesby sul 
movimento dell'allievo degli anni 60</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ήταν όπως ένα ζιζάνιο:" Θ*Θαρλ Oglesby στο 
Κίνημα σπουδαστών της δεκαετίας του '60</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Era Como Una Mala hierba:" Carl Oglesby en 
el movimiento del estudiante de los años 60</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Inspired by the Civil Rights movement, Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) was formed in 1962 to address issues of poverty, as well as feelings of helplessness, alienation, and indifference in African-American and working class communities. The group, which focused initially on community organizing, quickly became a leader of the anti-war movement when President Johnson escalated the war in Vietnam in 1965. A graduate student in 1965 at the University of Michigan, Carl Oglesby worked as a writer for a defense contractor. He was horrified at what he began to learn about Vietnam, and when SDS members found him he quickly joined the group. Oglesby quit his job, spoke at the first teach-in against the Vietnam War at Michigan, and was elected president of SDS in 1965. He then spent years traveling around the country speaking against the war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angespornt durch die Zivilrechte Bewegung, wurden 
Kursteilnehmer für eine demokratische Gesellschaft (SDS) 1962 
gebildet, um Punkte der Armut, sowie Gefühle von Hilflosigkeit, von 
Entfremdung und von Gleichgültigkeit in den Afrikanisch-Amerikanische
und Funktion Kategorie Gemeinschaften anzusprechen. Die Gruppe, 
die zuerst auf die organisierende Gemeinschaft konzentrierte, wurde 
schnell ein Führer der Antikriegsbewegung, als Präsident Johnson den
Krieg in Vietnam 1965 sich entwickelte. Ein Schulabgänger 1965 
an der Universität von Michigan, Karl Oglesby arbeitete als Verfasser
für eine Verteidigungfremdfirma. Er wurde erschrocken an, was 
er anfing, über Vietnam zu erlernen, und als SDS Bauteile ihn fanden,
verband er schnell die Gruppe. Oglesby beendete seinen Job, 
Speiche an ersten teach-in gegen den Vietnam Krieg bei Michigan und 
wurde Präsidenten von SDS 1965 gewählt. Er verbrachte dann die
Jahre, die um das Land reisen, das gegen den Krieg spricht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Inspiré par les droits civiques mouvement, des 
étudiants pour une société démocratique (SDS) ont été formés en
1962 pour aborder des questions de la pauvreté, aussi bien que des 
sentiments d'abandon, d'aliénation, et d'indifférence dans 
l'Afro-Américain et les communautés de classe ouvrière. Le 
groupe, qui s'est concentré au commencement sur la communauté 
organisant, est rapidement devenu une amorce du mouvement pacifiste 
quand président Johnson a escaladé la guerre au Vietnam en 1965.
Un étudiant gradué en 1965 à l'université du Michigan, Karl 
Oglesby a travaillé en tant qu'auteur pour un entrepreneur de 
défense. Il a été horrifié à ce qu'il a commencé à se 
renseigner sur le Vietnam, et quand les membres de SDS l'ont trouvé 
il a rapidement joint le groupe. Oglesby a quitté son travail, 
rai au premier programmable par apprentissage contre la guerre de 
Vietnam chez le Michigan, et a été élu président de SDS en 1965. 
Il a alors passé des années voyageant dans le pays parlant 
contre la guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Inspirado pelas direitas civis movimento, os 
estudantes para uma sociedade democrática (SDS) foram dados forma em 
1962 para dirigir-se a introduções da pobreza, as.well.as 
sentimentos do helplessness, do alienation, e do indifference em 
comunidades Africano-Americana e de funcionamento da classe. O 
grupo, que focalizou inicialmente na comunidade que organiza, 
transformou-se rapidamente um líder do movimento anti-war quando o 
presidente Johnson escalou a guerra em Vietnam em 1965. Um 
estudante graduado em 1965 na universidade de Michigan, Carl Oglesby 
trabalhou como um escritor para um contratante de defesa. Foi 
horrorizado em o que começou a aprender sobre Vietnam, e quando os 
membros do SDS o encontraram juntou rapidamente o grupo. Oglesby
parou seu trabalho, raio no primeiro teach-in de encontro à guerra de
Vietnam em Michigan, e foi elegido presidente do SDS em 1965. 
Gastou então os anos que viajam em torno do país que fala de 
encontro à guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ispirato dai diritti civili movimento, gli allievi
per una società democratica (SDS) sono stati formati in 1962 per 
richiamare le emissioni di povertà, così come le sensibilità di 
helplessness, dell'alienazione e dell'indifferenza nelle Comunità di 
funzionamento ed Africano-Americano del codice categoria. Il 
gruppo, che ha messo a fuoco inizialmente su Comunità che organizza, 
è diventato rapidamente un capo del movimento pacifista quando
il presidente Johnson ha intensificato la guerra nel Vietnam in 1965. 
Un allievo laureato in 1965 all'università de Michigan, Carl 
Oglesby ha lavorato come produttore per un appaltatore di difesa. 
È stato sconvolto a che cosa ha cominciato ad imparare circa il
Vietnam e quando i membri di SDS lo hanno trovato ha unito rapidamente
il gruppo. Oglesby ha rinunciato il suo lavoro, spoke al primo 
teach-in contro la guerra di Vietnam al Michigan ed è stato scelto 
presidente di SDS in 1965. Allora ha speso gli anni 
che viaggiano intorno al paese che parla contro la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εμπνευσμένοι από τη μετακίνηση αστικών δικαιωμάτων, 
οι σπουδαστές για μια δημοκρατική κοινωνία (SDS) διαμορφώθηκαν 
το 1962 για να αντιμετωπίσουν τα ζητήματα της ένδειας, καθώς 
επίσης και των συναισθημάτων της ανικανότητας, της αλλοτρίωσης, 
και της αδιαφορίας σε αφρικανικός-Αμερικανό και τις κοινότητες 
εργατικής τάξης. Η ομάδα, που εστίασε αρχικά στην 
κοινοτική οργάνωση, έγινε γρήγορα ηγέτης της αντιπολεμικής 
μετακίνησης όταν κλιμάκωσε ο Πρόεδρος Johnson τον πόλεμο στο 
Βιετνάμ το 1965. Ένας διαβαθμισμένος σπουδαστής το 
1965 στο πανεπιστήμιο του Μίτσιγκαν, Carl Oglesby 
εργάστηκε ως συγγραφέας για έναν αμυντικό ανάδοχο. 
Τρομάχτηκε σε αυτό που άρχισε να μαθαίνει για το Βιετνάμ, 
και όταν τον βρήκαν τα μέλη SDS προσχώρησε γρήγορα στην 
ομάδα. Το Oglesby εγκατέλειψε την εργασία του, μίλησε 
πρώτο teach-in ενάντια στον πόλεμο του Βιετνάμ στο Μίτσιγκαν, 
και εκλέχτηκε τον Πρόεδρο SDS το 1965. Πέρασε έπειτα 
τα έτη που ταξιδεύουν γύρω από τη χώρα που μιλά ενάντια στον 
πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Inspirado por las derechas civiles movimiento, 
formaron a los estudiantes para una sociedad democrática (SDS) en 
1962 para tratar aplicaciones la pobreza, así como sensaciones del 
desamparo, de la enajenación, y de la indiferencia en comunidades de 
la clase Africano-Americana y obrera. El grupo, que se centró 
inicialmente en la comunidad que ordenaba, hizo rápidamente un 
arranque de cinta del movimiento pacifista cuando presidente Johnson 
extendió la guerra en Vietnam en 1965. Un estudiante graduado 
en 1965 en la universidad de Michigan, Carl Oglesby trabajó como 
programa de escritura para un contratista de defensa. Lo 
horrorizaron en lo que él comenzó a aprender sobre Vietnam, y cuando
los miembros del SDS lo encontraron él ensambló rápidamente a 
grupo. Oglesby salió su trabajo, rayo en el primer teach-in 
contra la guerra de Vietnam en Michigan, y fue elegido presidente del 
SDS en 1965. Él entonces pasó los años que viajaban alrededor
del país que hablaba contra la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086354</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103848</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-was-like-a-weed-carl-oglesby-on-the-1960s-student-movement</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
