<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104502</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104502</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087084</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The World Will Note": President Truman Announces the Atom Bomb</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Welt Beachtet": Präsident Truman 
Announces die Atombombe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Monde Notera" : Le Président Truman 
Announces la bombe atomique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Mundo Anotará": Presidente Truman 
Anunciar a bomba de átomo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Mondo Noterà": Presidente Truman 
Announces la bomba atomica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο κόσμος θα σημειώσει": Πρόεδρος Truman 
Announces η βόμβα ατόμων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Mundo Observará": Presidente Truman 
Announces la bomba atómica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The bombs dropped on Hiroshima and Nagasaki in August, 1945 stand out not just for the number of people killed--as many, or more, died in "firebombings" in Germany during the war--but for the strange, alien quality of the atom bomb's effects. The atomic bomb's immense destructive capacity staggered observers, and its effects have haunted the world's imagination ever since. By the time the United States had a usable atomic bomb, the war in Europe was over, but thousands of American soldiers remained in the Pacific fighting the Japanese. Although some historians argue that the war could have been ended without the dropping of the bomb, in the summer of 1945 President Harry Truman made the fateful decision to proceed. In this dramatic radio address, Truman told the nation that a bomb had been dropped on the city of Hiroshima on August 6. Truman inaccurately described Hiroshima as a "military base." It was the base of the Second General Headquarters of the Imperial Army, but civilians outnumbered army personnel by about six to one.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Bomben fielen auf Hiroschima und Nagasaki im 
August, 1945 stehen heraus für die Zahl den Leuten nicht gerecht, die
beendet werden -- bis zu oder mehr, gestorben "in den firebombings" in
Deutschland während des Krieges -- aber für die merkwürdige, 
ausländische Qualität der Effekte der Atombombe. Die 
Atomgeschwankten Beobachter der bombe unermeßliche zerstörende 
Kapazität und seine Effekte haben die Phantasie der Welt seitdem 
frequentiert. Bis die Vereinigten Staaten eine verwendbare 
Atombombe hatten, sein der Krieg in Europa rüber, aber Tausenden der 
amerikanischen Soldaten blieben im Pazifik die Japaner kämpfend. 
Obgleich einige Historiker argumentieren, daß der Krieg ohne 
der Bombe zu fallen beendet worden sein könnte, am Sommer von 
Präsidenten 1945 Harry Truman traf die verhängnisvolle Entscheidung,
um fortzufahren. In dieser drastischen Rundfunkansprache 
erklärte Truman der Nation, daß eine Bombe auf die Stadt von 
Hiroschima an August 6 fallengelassen worden war. Truman 
beschrieb ungenau Hiroschima als "militärische Unterseite." Es 
war die Unterseite des zweiten Generals Hauptsitz der imperialen Armee,
aber ZivilistenWAREN Armepersonal durch ungefähr sechs bis eins 
zahlenmäßig überlegen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les pannes ont relâché sur Hiroshima et Nagasaki
en août, 1945 se tiennent dehors non simplement pour le nombre de 
personnes détruites -- autant de, ou plus, mort dans des 
"firebombings" en Allemagne pendant la guerre -- mais pour la qualité
étrange et étrangère des effets de la bombe atomique. Les 
observateurs chancelés immense par capacité de la panne atomique 
destructive, et ses effets ont hanté l'imagination du monde depuis. 
Avant que les Etats-Unis aient eu une panne atomique utilisable,
la guerre en Europe plus de, mais les milliers de soldats américains 
sont demeurés dans le Pacifique combattant les Japonais. Bien 
que quelques historiens arguent du fait que la guerre pourrait avoir 
été terminée sans baisse de la panne, en été du Président 1945 
Harry Truman a pris la décision fatidique pour procéder. Dans 
cette adresse par radio excessive, Truman a indiqué à la nation 
qu'une panne avait été lâchée sur la ville d'Hiroshima août 6. 
Truman a inexactement décrit Hiroshima comme "base militaire." 
C'était la base des deuxièmes sièges sociaux généraux de 
l'armée impériale, mais les civils ont dépassé le personnel en 
nombre d'armée par environ six à un.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As bombas deixaram cair em Hiroshima e Nagasaki em
agosto, 1945 está para fora nao justo para o número dos povos 
matados -- tanto como, ou mais, morrido em "firebombings" em Germany 
durante a guerra -- mas para a qualidade estranha, estrangeira dos 
efeitos de bomba de átomo. Os observadores desconcertados da 
bomba atômica capacidade destrutiva immense, e seus efeitos têm 
assombrado a imaginação do mundo sempre desde. Pelo tempo os 
estados unidos tiveram uma bomba atômica usable, a guerra em Europa 
sobre, mas os milhares dos soldados americanos remanesceram no 
Pacífico que lutam os japoneses. Embora alguns historians 
discutissem que a guerra poderia ter sido terminada sem deixar cair da
bomba, no verão do presidente 1945 Harry Truman fêz a decisão 
fateful para proseguir. Neste endereço de rádio dramático, 
Truman disse à nação que uma bomba tinha sido deixada cair na 
cidade de Hiroshima agosto em 6. Truman descreveu inaccurately 
Hiroshima como "uma base militar." Era a base das segundas 
matrizes gerais do exército imperial, mas os civis outnumbered o 
pessoal do exército por aproximadamente seis a um.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le bombe sono caduto su Hiroshima e Nagasaki in 
agosto, 1945 si leva in piedi fuori non giusta per il numero di gente 
uccisa -- altretanto, o più, morto "in firebombings" in Germania 
durante la guerra -- ma per la qualità sconosciuta e straniera degli 
effetti della bomba atomica. Gli osservatori vacillati capienza 
distruttiva immensa della bomba atomica ed i relativi effetti hanno 
frequentato l'immaginazione del mondo da allora. Per il momento 
in cui unito Dichiari abbia una bomba atomica utilizzabile, la
guerra in Europa finito, ma i migliaia dei soldati americani sono 
rimasto nel combattimento pacifico i giapponesi. Anche se alcuni 
storici sostengono che la guerra potrebbe essere conclusa senza cadere
della bomba, di estate del presidente 1945 Harry Truman ha preso la 
decisione fateful per continuare. In questo indirizzo 
radiofonico drammatico, Truman ha detto alla nazione a che una bomba 
fosse stata caduta sulla città di Hiroshima il 6 agosto. Truman
ha descritto inesatto Hiroshima come "base militare." Era la 
base delle seconde sedi generali dell'esercito imperiale, ma i civili 
hanno oltrepassato i personali dell'esercito da circa sei - uno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τις βόμβες που έπεσαν στη Χιροσίμα και το Ναγκασάκι 
τον Αύγουστο, στάση του 1945 έξω όχι μόνο για τον αριθμό 
ανθρώπων σκότωσαν -- όπως πολλοί, ή περισσότεροι, πέθανε "στα 
firebombings" στη Γερμανία κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου -- 
αλλά για την παράξενη, αλλοδαπή ποιότητα των αποτελεσμάτων της 
βόμβας ατόμων. Η απέραντη καταστρεπτική ικανότητα της 
ατομικής βόμβας τρίκλισε τους παρατηρητές, και τα αποτελέσματά 
του έχουν συχνάσει την παγκόσμια φαντασία από τότε. Ώσπου
να είχαν οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες μια χρησιμοποιήσιμη ατομική 
βόμβα, ο πόλεμος στην Ευρώπη τελείωσε, αλλά χιλιάδες 
αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες παρα:μένω στον Ειρηνικό παλεύοντας τους 
Ιάπωνες. Αν και μερικοί ιστορικοί υποστηρίζουν ότι τον 
πόλεμο θα μπορούσε να έχουν τελειώσει χωρίς να πέσει της 
βόμβας, το καλοκαίρι του 1945 ο Πρόεδρος Harry Truman 
έλαβε τη μοιραία απόφαση να προχωρήσει. Σε αυτήν την 
δραματική ραδιο διεύθυνση, Truman είπε στο έθνος ότι μια 
βόμβα είχαν πέσει στην πόλη της Χιροσίμα στις 6. Αυγούστου 
Truman ανακριβώς περιγραμμένη Χιροσίμα ως "στρατιωτική βάση." 
Ήταν η βάση της δεύτερης γενικής έδρας του αυτοκρατορικού 
στρατού, αλλά οι πολίτες ξεπέρασαν αριθμητικώς το προσωπικό 
στρατού από περίπου έξι σε ένα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las bombas cayeron en Hiroshima y Nagasaki en 
agosto, 1945 está parada hacia fuera no justa para el número de la 
gente matada -- tanto, o más, muerto en "firebombings" en Alemania 
durante la guerra -- pero para la calidad extraña, extranjera de los 
efectos de la bomba atómica. Los observadores escalonados 
capacidad destructiva inmensa de la bomba atómica, y sus efectos han 
frecuentado la imaginación del mundo desde que. Para el momento
en que los Estados Unidos tuvieran una bomba atómica usable, la 
guerra en Europa encima, pero seguía habiendo los millares de 
soldados americanos en el Pacífico que luchaban a los japoneses. 
Aunque algunos historiadores discuten que la guerra se habría 
podido terminar sin caer de la bomba, en el verano del presidente 1945
Harry Truman tomó la decisión profética para proceder. En 
este direccionamiento de radio dramático, Truman dijo a nación que 
una bomba hubiera sido caída en la ciudad de Hiroshima de agosto el 
6. Truman describió inexacto Hiroshima como "base militar." 
Era la base de las segundas jefaturas generales del ejército 
imperial, pero los civiles excedieron en número a personal del 
ejército por cerca de seises a uno.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087084</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104502</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-world-will-note-president-truman-announces-the-atom-bomb</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
