<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108203</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108203</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1562380903</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Klondike Gold Rush</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Klondike Goldanstürme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Précipitations d'Or de Klondike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As Arremetidas Do Ouro De Klondike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli Sbalzi Dell'Oro Di Klondike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η χρυσή βιασύνη Klondike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las Acometidas Del Oro De Klondike</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The enclosed curriculum materials consist of a variety of original documents related to the Klondike gold rush and Seattle and a set of maps of the Pacific Northwest and Alaska. These materials are intended to provide students with an opportunity to learn about and investigate a specific topic in Washington history: How the Klondike/Alaska gold rush played a role in Seattle's economic growth and its rise to a position of economic dominance among Northwest cities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die beiliegenden Lehrplanmaterialien bestehen aus 
einer Vielzahl der Originalurkunden, die nach die Klondike 
Goldanstürme und das Seattle in Verbindung gestanden werden und des 
Sets Karten des pazifischen Nordwestens und des Alaskas. Diese 
Materialien sollen Kursteilnehmer mit einer Gelegenheit versehen, 
ungefähr zu erlernen und ein spezifisches Thema in der Washington 
Geschichte nachzuforschen: Wie die Klondike/Alaska Goldanstürme
eine Rolle Seattles im Wirtschaftswachstum und seinen Anstieg in eine 
Position der ökonomischen Herrschaft unter Nordweststädte spielten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les matériaux inclus de programme d'études se 
composent d'une variété de documents initiaux liés aux 
précipitations et à Seattle d'or de Klondike et d'un ensemble de 
cartes du nord-ouest et de l'Alaska Pacifiques. Ces matériaux 
sont destinés pour fournir à des étudiants une occasion d'apprendre
environ et d'étudier un sujet spécifique dans l'histoire de 
Washington : Comment les précipitations d'or de Klondike/Alaska
ont joué un rôle dans la croissance économique de Seattle et son 
élévation dans une position de dominance économique parmi les 
villes du nord-ouest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os materiais incluidos do curriculum consistem em 
uma variedade dos originais originais relacionados às arremetidas e 
ao Seattle do ouro de Klondike e de um jogo dos mapas do noroeste e do
Alaska pacíficos. Estes materiais são pretendidos fornecer 
estudantes com uma oportunidade de aprender aproximadamente e 
investigar um tópico específico no history de Washington: Como
as arremetidas do ouro de Klondike/Alaska jogaram um papel no 
crescimento econômico de Seattle e sua ascensão a uma posição do 
dominance econômico entre cidades noroestes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I materiali inclusi di programma di studi 
consistono di una varietà di documenti originali relativi agli sbalzi
ed a Seattle dell'oro di Klondike e di insieme dei programmi del 
nord-ovest e dell'Alaska pacifici. Questi materiali sono intesi 
per fornire agli allievi un'occasione imparare circa e studiare un 
soggetto specifico nella storia de Washington: Come gli sbalzi
dell'oro di Klondike/Alaska hanno giocato un ruolo nello sviluppo 
economico de Seattle ed il relativo aumento ad una posizione di 
dominanza economica fra le città di nord-ovest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα εσωκλειόμενα υλικά προγράμματος σπουδών 
αποτελούνται από ποικίλα αρχικά έγγραφα σχετικά με τη χρυσά 
βιασύνη Klondike και το Σιάτλ και ένα σύνολο χαρτών των 
ειρηνικών βορειοδυτικών και της Αλάσκας. Αυτά τα υλικά 
προορίζονται να παρέχουν στους σπουδαστές μια ευκαιρία να 
μαθευτεί περίπου και να ερευνηθεί ένα συγκεκριμένο θέμα στην 
ιστορία της Ουάσιγκτον: Πώς η χρυσή βιασύνη Klondike/tis
Αλάσκας διαδραμάτισε έναν ρόλο στην οικονομική ανάπτυξη του 
Σιάτλ και την άνοδό της σε μια θέση της οικονομικής κυριαρχίας 
μεταξύ των βορειοδυτικών πόλεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los materiales incluidos del plan de estudios 
consisten en una variedad de documentos originales relacionados con 
las acometidas y la Seattle del oro de Klondike y de un conjunto de 
correspondencias del noroeste y de la Alaska pacíficos. Estos 
materiales se piensan para proveer de estudiantes una oportunidad de 
aprender alrededor y de investigar un asunto específico en la 
historia de Washington: Cómo las acometidas del oro de 
Klondike/Alaska jugaron un papel en el desarrollo económico de 
Seattle y su subida a una posición de la dominación económica entre
ciudades del noroeste.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1562380903</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108203</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-klondike-gold-rush</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
