<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107795</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107795</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086891</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The  Amistad  Rebellion.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Amistad Aufstand.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Rébellion d'Amistad.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Rebelião De Amistad.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Ribellione Di Amistad.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εξέγερση Amistad.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Rebelión De Amistad.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In July 1839, captive West Africans rebelled and took over the Spanish slaveship  Amistad . They ordered the owners to Africa but, instead, the  Amistad  was taken on a meandering course, finally waylaid by a U.S. Navy brig. The Africans were charged with the murder of the captain and jailed in New Haven, Connecticut. Abolitionists came to their support; ex-President John Quincy Adams represented them in court. After a long legal battle, the Supreme Court freed the "mutineers" in 1841. The following year they returned to Africa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Juli 1839, lehnten sich sichernde Westafrikaner auf und
übernahmen das spanische slaveship Amistad. Sie bestellten die 
Inhaber nach Afrika, aber stattdessen wurde das Amistad auf einem 
schlängelnden Kurs genommen, schließlich waylaid durch einen 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marine Brig. Die Afrikaner wurden mit dem 
Mord am Kapitän aufgeladen und gefangengesetzt in New-Haven, 
Connecticut. Abolitionists kam zu ihrem Support; 
ExPräsident John Quincy Adams stellte sie bei Gericht dar. 
Nach einer langen zugelassenen Schlacht gab das Höchste Gericht
die "mutineers" 1841 frei. Das folgende Jahr gingen sie nach 
Afrika zurück.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En juillet 1839, les Africains occidentaux captifs se sont
rebellés et ont succédé le slaveship espagnol Amistad. Ils 
ont commandé les propriétaires en Afrique mais, au lieu de cela, 
l'Amistad a été pris sur un cours de méandre, finalement waylaid 
par une prison de marine des ETATS-UNIS. Les Africains ont 
été chargés du meurtre du capitaine et emprisonnés à New Haven, 
le Connecticut. Les abolitionnistes sont venus à leur support ; 
Ex-Président John Quincy Adams les a représentés devant le 
tribunal. Après une longue bataille légale, la cour suprême a
libéré les "mutins" en 1841. L'année suivante ils sont 
revenus à l'Afrique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em julho 1839, os africanos ocidentais prisioneiros 
rebelled e fizeram exame sobre do slaveship espanhol Amistad. 
Requisitaram os proprietários a África mas, instead, o Amistad
foi feito exame em um curso meandering, waylaid finalmente por um brig
da marinha de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Os africanos foram carregados com 
o assassinato do capitão e jailed em New Haven, Connecticut. 
Abolitionists veio a sua sustentação; O ex-Presidente 
John Quincy Adams representou-os na corte. Após uma batalha 
legal longa, a corte suprema livrou os "mutineers" em 1841. O 
seguinte ano retornaram a África.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mese di luglio del 1839, gli Africani ad ovest 
prigionieri si sono ribellati ed assunto la direzione dello slaveship 
spagnolo Amistad. Hanno ordinato i proprietari in Africa ma, 
invece, il Amistad è stato preso su un corso serpeggiante, infine 
waylaid da un brig del blu marino degli STATI UNITI. Gli 
Africani sono stati caricati dell'omicidio del capitano e sono stati 
imprigionati a New Haven, Connecticut. Abolitionists è venuto 
al loro supporto; Il ex-Presidente John Quincy Adams li ha 
rappresentati in tribunale. Dopo una battaglia legale lunga, la 
Corte suprema ha liberato "i mutineers" in 1841. Il seguente 
anno hanno ritornato in Africa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Ιούλιο του 1839, η αιχμάλωτη δύση Αφρικανοί 
επαναστάτησε και ανέλαβε το ισπανικό slaveship Amistad. 
Διέταξαν τους ιδιοκτήτες στην Αφρική αλλά, αντ' αυτού, το 
Amistad λήφθηκε σε μια σειρά μαθημάτων ελιγμού, waylaid 
τελικά από ένα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ναυτικό brig. Οι Αφρικανοί 
χρεώθηκαν με τη δολοφονία του καπετάνιου και φυλακίστηκαν στο 
Νιού Χάβεν, Κοννέκτικατ. Οι ρεφορμιστές ήρθαν στην 
υποστήριξή τους  πρώην-Πρόεδρος John Quincy Adams 
τους αντιπροσώπευσε στο δικαστήριο. Μετά από μια 
μακροχρόνια νομική μάχη, το ανώτατο δικαστήριο ελευθέρωσε τους 
"στασιαστέσ" το 1841. Το επόμενο έτος επέστρεψαν στην 
Αφρική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En julio de 1839, los africanos del oeste prisioneros 
rebelaron y asumieron el control el slaveship español Amistad. 
Pidieron a propietarios a África pero, en lugar, el Amistad fue
adquirido un curso de serpenteo, finalmente waylaid por un bergantín 
de la Marina de guerra de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Cargaron con el asesinato 
del capitán y fueron encarcelados a los africanos en New Haven, 
Connecticut. Abolitionists vino a su ayuda; Ex-Presidente 
Juan Quincy Adams los representó en corte. Después de una 
batalla legal larga, el Tribunal Supremo liberó los "mutineers" en 
1841. El año siguiente volvieron a África.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086891</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107795</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-amistad-rebellion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
