<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206449</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Liberty Ships and Victory Ships, America's Lifeline in War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freiheit-Schiffe und Sieg-Schiffe, Rettungsleine 
Amerikas im Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bateaux de liberté et bateaux de victoire, la 
ligne de sauvetage de l'Amérique dans la guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Navios de liberdade e navios da vitória, 
lifeline de América na guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Navi di libertà e navi di vittoria, cavo di 
sicurezza dell'America nella guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκάφη ελευθερίας και σκάφη νίκης, σανίδα σωτηρίας 
της Αμερικής στον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Naves de libertad y naves de la victoria, cuerda 
de salvamento de América en guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of two World War II ship-building efforts. In 1941, with war raging in Europe, President Roosevelt authorized the production of 441-foot cargo ships. These Liberty ships proved too slow and small, so in 1943, a new effort began building Victory ships, which cruised at 18.5 mph, compared to the Liberty's 12.5 mph. By the war's end, the Maritime Commission had built 2,751 Liberty and 531 Victory ships.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte von zwei 
Weltkriegschiffsbautechnikbemühungen. 1941 wenn der Krieg in 
Europa rast, autorisierte Präsident Roosevelt die Produktion der 
441-foot Frachtschiffe. Diese Freiheitschiffe prüften zu 
langsames und klein, also 1943, fing eine neue Bemühung die Gebäude 
Siegschiffe, die bei 18.5 MPH kreuzten, verglichen mit den 12.5 MPH 
der Freiheit an. Durch das Ende des Krieges hatte die 
Seekommission 2.751 531 des Sieges Schiffe der Freiheit und aufgebaut.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire de deux efforts de construction 
navale de la deuxième guerre mondiale. En 1941, avec la guerre 
faisant rage en Europe, le Président Roosevelt a autorisé la 
production des cargos 441-foot. Ces bateaux de liberté ont 
prouvé trop lent et petit, ainsi en 1943, un nouvel effort a 
commencé les bateaux de victoire de bâtiment, qui ont conduit à 
vitesse normale à 18.5 M/H, comparés à 12.5 M/H de la liberté. 
Par l'extrémité de la guerre, la Commission maritime avait 
construit 2.751 531 de victoire bateaux de liberté et.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história de dois esforços do 
ship-building da segunda guerra mundial. Em 1941, com a guerra 
que raging em Europa, o presidente Roosevelt autorizou a produção de
navios de carga 441-foot. Estes navios de liberdade provaram 
demasiado lento e pequeno, assim que em 1943, um esforço novo 
começou os navios da vitória do edifício, que cruzaram em 18.5 mph,
comparados aos 12.5 mph da liberdade. Pela extremidade da 
guerra, o commission marítimo tinha construído 2.751 531 da vitória
navios da liberdade e.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia di due sforzi di costruzione 
navale della seconda guerra mondiale. In 1941, con la guerra che
si infuria in Europa, il presidente Roosevelt ha autorizzato la 
produzione delle navi da carico 441-foot. Queste navi di 
libertà hanno dimostrato troppo lento e piccolo, in modo da in 1943, 
un nuovo sforzo ha cominciato le navi di vittoria della costruzione, 
che cruised a 18.5 mph, confrontate ai 12.5 mph della libertà. 
Dall'estremità della guerra, la Commissione marittima aveva 
costruito 2.751 di vittoria 531 e di libertà nave.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει στην ιστορία του παγκόσμιου δύο πολέμου ΙΙ τις 
προσπάθειες ναυπηγικής. Το 1941, με τον πόλεμο που 
οργίζεται στην Ευρώπη, ο Πρόεδρος Roosevelt ενέκρινε την 
παραγωγή των σκαφών φορτίου 441-ποδιών. Αυτά τα σκάφη 
ελευθερίας αποδείχθηκαν πάρα πολύ αργά και μικρά, έτσι το 
1943, μια νέα προσπάθεια άρχισε τα σκάφη νίκης, που ταξίδεψαν
18,5 mph, έναντι 12,5 mph της ελευθερίας. Από το 
πολεμικό τέλος, η θαλάσσια Επιτροπή είχε ναυπηγήσει 2.751 
531 νίκης σκάφη ελευθερίας και.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia de dos esfuerzos de la 
construcción naval de la Segunda Guerra Mundial. En 1941, con 
la guerra rabiando en Europa, presidente Roosevelt autorizó la 
producción de los buques de carga 441-foot. Estas naves de 
libertad probaron demasiado lento y pequeño, así que en 1943, un 
nuevo esfuerzo comenzó las naves de la victoria del edificio, que 
cruzaron en 18.5 mph, comparadas a los 12.5 mph de la libertad. 
Por el extremo de la guerra, la Comisión marítimo había 
construido 2.751 531 de la victoria naves de la libertad y.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206449</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105890</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/liberty-ships-and-victory-ships-americas-lifeline-in-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
