<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104714</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104714</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086693</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"One Should Not Look to Research as a Kind of a Panacea": Social Scientists in the 1950s Discuss Studies of Television Viewing by Children</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"man sollte nicht schauen, um als Art Panazee zu 
erforschen": Sozialwissenschaftler in den fünfziger Jahren 
behandeln Studien der Fernsehen-Betrachtung durch Children</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"on ne devrait pas regarder pour rechercher comme 
genre de panacée" : Les sociologues dans les années 50 
discutent des études du visionnement de télévision par Children</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um não deve olhar para pesquisar como um tipo de
um panacea": Os cientistas sociais nos 1950s discutem estudos da
visão da televisão por Criança</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"uno non dovrebbe osservare per ricercare come 
genere di panacea": I sociologi negli anni 50 discutono gli 
studi sull'osservazione della televisione da Children</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κάποιος δεν πρέπει να κοιτάξει στην έρευνα ως είδος 
μιας πανάκειασ": Οι κοινωνικοί επιστήμονες στη δεκαετία του 
'50 συζητούν τις μελέτες της τηλεοπτικής όψης από τα παιδιά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"uno no debe mirar para investigar como clase de 
una panacea": Los científicos sociales en los años 50 discuten
estudios de la visión de la televisión de Children</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While experimental television broadcasts were first transmitted in the 1920s, mass production of television sets did not occur until after World War II. By 1960 the number of sets in the U.S. had surpassed the number of homes. With this relatively swift introduction of television into domestic American life, concern was voiced over the harmful influence that watching television might have on the nation's children. Although Congress held its first hearing on the subject in 1952, they chose not to take any action to interfere with the industry, in part because that year the National Association of Radio and Television Broadcasters adopted a code to regulate broadcast content. In 1954 and 1955, Congress conducted additional hearings to investigate whether television--along with other mass media products that appealed to children, such as comic books and motion pictures--had anything to do with the documented rise in incidents of juvenile crime. As the renowned media researcher Paul Lazarsfeld testified, studies showed that the hearings, which themselves were televised, only led to worry among viewers rather than to practical measures to correct any perceived problem. In the following testimony from the 1955 hearings, child psychologist Eleanor E. Maccoby discussed her research findings, while Lazarsfeld advocated the funding of long-term projects. Both stressed the limitations of research for providing reliable evidence that would definitively link juvenile delinquency to television viewing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während experimentelle Fernsehensendungen zuerst 
in die zwanziger Jahre übertragen wurden, trat Großserienfertigung 
der Fernseher nicht bis nach den Zweiten Weltkrieg auf. Durch 
1960 hatte die Zahl Sets in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN die Zahl Häusern 
übertroffen. Mit dieser verhältnismäßig schnellen Einleitung
des Fernsehens in inländische amerikanische Lebensdauer, wurde 
Interesse über dem schädlichen Einfluß geäußert, den 
überwachendes Fernsehen auf den Kindern der Nation haben konnte. 
Obgleich Kongreß seine erste Hörfähigkeit auf dem Thema 1952 
anhielt, beschlossen sie, keine Maßnahmen zu ergreifen, um die 
Industrie, im Teil zu behinderen, weil dieses Jahr die nationale 
Verbindung der Radio-und Fernsehen-Rundfunkstationen einen Code 
annahm, um Sendung Inhalt zu regeln. 1954 und 1955 leitete 
Kongreß zusätzliche Hörfähigkeiten, um nachzuforschen, ob 
Fernsehen -- zusammen mit anderen Massenmediaprodukten, die Kindern, 
wie komischen Büchern und Bewegung Abbildungen gefielen -- alles 
hatte, mit dem dokumentierten Anstieg in den Ereignissen des 
jugendlichen Verbrechens zu tun. Wie der berühmte Mediaforscher
Paul Lazarsfeld bezeugte, zeigten Studien daß die Hörfähigkeiten, 
die selbst im Fernsehen übertragen wurden, nur geführt, um sich 
unter Projektoren anstatt zu den praktischen Massen zu sorgen, 
irgendein wahrgenommenes Problem zu beheben. Im folgenden 
Zeugnis von den 1955 Hörfähigkeiten, behandelte Kindpsychologe 
Eleanor E. Maccoby ihre Forschung Entdeckungen, während Lazarsfeld 
die Finanzierung der langfristigen Projekte befürwortete. Beide
betonten die Beschränkungen der Forschung für das Zur Verfügung 
stellen des zuverlässigen Beweises, der endgültig jugendliche 
Gesetzesverletzung mit Fernsehenbetrachtung binden würde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que des émissions expérimentales de 
télévision étaient transmises la première fois dans les années 
20, la production en série des téléviseurs ne s'est pas produite 
jusque 2'après la deuxième guerre mondiale. Par 1960 le nombre
de positionnements aux ETATS-UNIS avait surpassé le nombre de 
maisons. Avec cette introduction relativement rapide de 
télévision dans la vie américaine domestique, le souci a été 
exprimé au-dessus de l'influence nocive que la télévision 
d'observation pourrait avoir sur les enfants de la nation. Bien 
que le congrès ait tenu sa première audition sur le sujet en 1952, 
ils ont choisi de ne pas prendre n'importe quelle mesure pour gêner 
l'industrie, en partie parce que cette année l'association nationale 
des radiodiffuseurs de radio et de télévision a adopté un code pour
régler le contenu d'émission. En 1954 et 1955, le congrès a 
conduit des auditions supplémentaires pour étudier si la 
télévision -- le long avec d'autres produits de mass media qui ont 
fait appel aux enfants, tels en tant que livres comiques et films 
cinématographiques -- a eu n'importe quoi faire avec l'élévation 
documentée des incidents du crime juvénile. Comme le chercheur
renommé Paul Lazarsfeld de medias a témoigné, les études ont 
prouvé que les auditions, qu'elles-mêmes ont été télévisées, 
seulement mené à s'inquiéter parmi des visualisateurs plutôt 
qu'aux mesures pratiques de corriger tout problème perçu. Dans
le témoignage suivant des 1955 auditions, le psychologue Eleanor E. 
Maccoby d'enfant a discuté ses résultats de recherches, alors que 
Lazarsfeld préconisait le placement des projets à long terme. 
Tous les deux ont souligné les limitations de la recherche pour
fournir l'évidence fiable qui joindrait définitivement la 
délinquance juvénile au visionnement de télévision.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando as transmissões experimentais da 
televisão foram transmitidas primeiramente nos 1920s, a produção 
maciça de jogos de televisão não ocorreu até após a segunda 
guerra mundial. Por 1960 o número dos jogos nos ESTADOS UNIDOS 
surpassed o número das HOME. Com esta introdução 
relativamente rápida da televisão na vida americana doméstica, o 
interesse foi exprimido sobre a influência prejudicial que a 
televisão prestando atenção pôde ter nas crianças da nação. 
Embora o congress prendesse seu primeiro hearing no assunto em 
1952, escolheram não fazer exame de nenhuma ação para interferir 
com a indústria, na parte porque esse ano a associação nacional de 
radiodifusores do rádio e da televisão adotou um código para 
regular o índice da transmissão. Em 1954 e em 1955, o congress
conduziu hearings adicionais para investigar se a televisão -- junto 
com outros produtos dos media maciços que apelaram às crianças, 
tais como livros e retratos de movimento comic -- teve qualquer coisa 
fazer com a ascensão documentada nos incidents do crime juvenile. 
Como o investigador renowned Paul Lazarsfeld dos media 
testified, os estudos mostraram que os hearings, que eles mesmos 
televised, only conduzido para se preocupar entre visores melhor que 
às medidas práticas corrigir algum problema percebido. No 
seguinte testimony dos 1955 hearings, o psicólogo Eleanor E. Maccoby 
da criança discutiu seus findings da pesquisa, quando Lazarsfeld 
advogou financiar de projetos a longo prazo. Ambos forçaram as 
limitações da pesquisa para fornecer a evidência de confiança que 
ligaria definitively o delinquency juvenile à visão da televisão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre le radiodiffusioni sperimentali della 
televisione in primo luogo sono state trasmesse negli anni 20, la 
fabbricazione in serie dei televisori non si è presentata fino dopo 
alla seconda guerra mondiale. Da 1960 il numero di insiemi negli
STATI UNITI aveva sorpassato il numero di sedi. Con questa 
introduzione relativamente rapida della televisione in vita americana 
domestica, la preoccupazione è stata espressa sopra l'influenza 
nociva che la televisione guardante potrebbe avere sui bambini della 
nazione. Anche se il congresso ha tenuto la relativa prima 
udienza sull'oggetto in 1952, hanno scelto non intraprendere 
alcun'azione per interferire con l'industria, in parte perché 
quell'anno l'associazione nazionale dei distributori a spaglio della 
televisione e della radio ha adottato un codice per regolare il 
soddisfare di radiodiffusione. In 1954 ed in 1955, il congresso 
ha condotto le udienze supplementari per studiare se la televisione --
con altri prodotti di mass-media che hanno fatto appello ai bambini, 
quali i libri ed il cinema comic -- ha avuta qualche cosa fare con 
l'aumento documentato negli avvenimenti del crimine giovanile. 
Il ricercatore renowned Paul Lazarsfeld di media ha 
testimoniato, gli studi hanno indicato che le udienze, che essi stessi
sono stati teletrasmessi, solo condotto per preoccuparsi fra i visori 
piuttosto che alle misure pratiche correggere qualsiasi problema 
percepito. Nella seguente testimonianza dalle 1955 udienze, lo 
psicologo Eleanor E. Maccoby del bambino ha discusso i suoi risultati 
di ricerca, mentre Lazarsfeld ha sostenuto costituire un fondo per dei
progetti di lunga durata. Entrambi hanno sollecitato le 
limitazioni di ricerca per fornire la prova certa che definitivo 
collegherebbe la delinquenza giovanile all'osservazione della 
televisione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ οι πειραματικές τηλεοπτικές ραδιοφωνικές 
μεταδόσεις μεταδόθηκαν αρχικά στη δεκαετία του '20, η μαζική 
παραγωγή των τηλεοπτικών συνόλων δεν εμφανίστηκε μέχρι τον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Μέχρι το 1960 ο αριθμός συνόλων 
στις ΗΠΑ είχε ξεπεράσει τον αριθμό σπιτιών. Με αυτήν την 
σχετικά γρήγορη εισαγωγή της τηλεόρασης στην εσωτερική 
αμερικανική ζωή, η ανησυχία εκφράστηκε πέρα από την επιβλαβή 
επιρροή που η τηλεόραση προσοχής να έχει στα παιδιά του έθνους. 
Αν και το συνέδριο πραγματοποίησε την πρώτη ακρόασή του για
το θέμα το 1952, επέλεξαν να μην λάβουν οποιαδήποτε μέτρα να 
παρεμποδίσουν τη βιομηχανία, εν μέρει επειδή εκείνο το έτος η 
εθνική ένωση των εκφωνητών ραδιοφώνων και τηλεόρασης υιοθέτησε 
έναν κώδικα για να ρυθμίσει το περιεχόμενο ραδιοφωνικής 
μετάδοσης. Το 1954 και το 1955, το συνέδριο διεύθυνε 
τις πρόσθετες ακροάσεις που ερευνούν εάν η τηλεόραση -- μαζί με 
άλλα προϊόντα μαζικής επικοινωνίας μέσων που απευθύνθηκαν στα 
παιδιά, όπως τα κωμικές βιβλία και οι ταινίες -- είχε τίποτα 
που κάνει με την τεκμηριωμένη άνοδο στα γεγονότα του νεανικού 
εγκλήματος. Όπως ο διάσημος ερευνητής Paul Lazarsfeld 
μέσων πιστοποίησε, οι μελέτες έδειξαν ότι οι ακροάσεις, που οι 
ίδιοι μεταδόθηκαν, οδήγησαν μόνο στην ανησυχία μεταξύ των 
εμφανίσεων παρά στα πρακτικά μέτρα για να διορθωθεί οποιοδήποτε 
αντιληπτό πρόβλημα. Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση από τις 
ακροάσεις του 1955, ο ψυχολόγος Eleanor Ε. Maccoby παιδιών
συζήτησε τα ερευνητικά συμπεράσματά της, ενώ Lazarsfeld 
υποστήριξε τη χρηματοδότηση των μακροπρόθεσμων προγραμμάτων. 
Και οι δύο τόνισαν τους περιορισμούς της έρευνας για την 
παροχή των αξιόπιστων στοιχείων που θα σύνδεαν οριστικά τη 
νεανική εγκληματικότητα με την τηλεοπτική όψη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que las difusiones experimentales de la 
televisión primero fueron transmitidas en los años 20, la 
producción en masa de las televisiones no ocurrió hasta después de 
la Segunda Guerra Mundial. Por 1960 el número de conjuntos en 
los ESTADOS UNIDOS había sobrepasado el número de hogares. Con
esta introducción relativamente rápida de la televisión en vida 
americana doméstica, la preocupación fue expresada sobre la 
influencia dañosa que la televisión que miraba pudo tener en los 
niños de la nación. Aunque el congreso llevó a cabo su 
primera audiencia en el tema en 1952, eligieron no tomar ninguna 
acción para interferir con la industria, en parte porque ese año la 
asociación nacional de los locutores de la radio y de la televisión 
adoptó un código para regular el contenido de la difusión. En
1954 y 1955, el congreso condujo audiencias adicionales para 
investigar si la televisión -- junto con otros productos de los 
medioses de comunicación que abrogaron a los niños, tales como 
libros y películas cómicos -- tenía cualquier cosa hacer con la 
subida documentada de incidentes del crimen juvenil. Como el 
investigador renombrado Paul Lazarsfeld de los media atestiguó, los 
estudios mostraron que las audiencias, que ellos mismos fueron 
televisados, sólo está conducido para preocuparse entre espectadores
más bien que a las medidas prácticas de corregir cualquier problema 
percibido. En el testimonio siguiente de las 1955 audiencias, el
psicólogo Eleanor E. Maccoby del niño discutió sus resultados de la
investigación, mientras que Lazarsfeld abogó el financiamiento de 
proyectos a largo plazo. Ambos tensionaron las limitaciones de 
la investigación para proporcionar a la evidencia confiable que 
conectaría definitivo delincuencia juvenil a la visión de la 
televisión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086693</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104714</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/one-should-not-look-to-research-as-a-kind-of-a-panacea-social-scientists-in-the-1950s-discuss-studies-of-television-viewing-by-children</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
