<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104434</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104434</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086844</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Speak, Garvey, Speak!"A Follower Recalls a Garvey Rally</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sprechen Sie, Garvey, Speak!"A 
Nachfolger-Rückrufe eine Garvey Sammlung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"parlez, Garvey, rappels de palpeur de Speak!"A un
rassemblement de Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"fale, Garvey, recordações do seguidor de 
Speak!"A um rally de Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"parli, Garvey, richiami del seguicamma di 
Speak!"A un raduno di Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μιλήστε, Garvey, ανακλήσεις οπαδών Speak!"A μια 
συνάθροιση Garvey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"hable, Garvey, memorias del seguidor de Speak!"A 
una reunión de Garvey</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Jamaican-born Marcus Garvey, a brilliant orator and black nationalist leader, turned his Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA) into the most important black organization in the United States in the early 1920s. Garvey's speeches often drew huge audiences, and stories of Garvey's stubborn resistance in the face of white hostility proliferated among his supporters. In an oral history interview, devotee Audley Moore remembered the Jamaican's defiant behavior at a rally in New Orleans caused "the [white] police [to] file out . . . like little puppy dogs with their tails behind them." She proudly recalled the crowd intimidating the police by raising their guns and chanting "speak, Garvey, speak."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Jamaikanisch-getragene Marcus Garvey, ein 
leuchtender Redner und schwarzer nationalistischer Führer, machte 
seine Universalschwarze-Verbesserung Verbindung (UNIA) zu die 
wichtigste schwarze Organisation in den Vereinigten Staaten in den 
frühen zwanziger Jahren Reden, die Garveys häufig sehr große 
Publikum zeichnete und Geschichten von Garveys störrischem Widerstand
angesichts der weißen Feindseligkeit, die unter seinen Verfechtern 
stark vermehrt wurde. In einem Mundgeschichte Interview 
erinnerte sich eifriger Anhänger Audley Moore an das defiant 
Verhalten des Jamaikaners an einer Sammlung in New-Orleans, welches 
"die verursacht wurde [ Datei der Weiß] Polizei [ ] heraus. . 
. wie kleine Welpe Hunde mit ihren Endstücken hinter 
ihnen." Sie rief stolz die Masse wieder auf, die Polizei 
einzuschüchtern, indem sie ihre Gewehren anhob und singend "zu 
sprechen, sprechen Garvey."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Marcus Jamaïquain-soutenu Garvey, un orateur 
brillant et amorce nationaliste noire, a transformé son association 
universelle d'amélioration de nègre (UNIA) en organisation noire la 
plus importante aux Etats-Unis dans le début des années 20 les 
discours que de Garvey a souvent dessiné les assistances énormes, et
histoires de la résistance têtue de Garvey face à l'hostilité 
blanche proliférée parmi ses défenseurs. Dans une entrevue 
orale d'histoire, le passionné Audley Moore s'est rappelé le 
comportement provoquant du Jamaïquain à un rassemblement à la 
Nouvelle-Orléans causée "[ le fichier de police de blanc ] [ ] 
dehors. . . comme de petits chiens de chiot avec 
leurs queues derrière elles." Elle a fièrement rappelé la 
foule intimider la police en soulevant leurs pistolets et chantant 
"pour parler, Garvey, parlent."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Marcus Jamaican-carregado Garvey, um orator 
brilhante e líder nacionalista preto, girou sua associação 
universal da melhoria do negro (UNIA) na organização preta a mais 
importante nos estados unidos nos 1920s. onde adiantados discursos de 
Garvey desenhou frequentemente audiências enormes, e histórias da 
resistência stubborn de Garvey na cara da hostilidade branca 
proliferated entre seus supporters. Em uma entrevista oral do 
history, o devoto Audley Moore recordou o comportamento defiant do 
jamaican em um rally em Nova Orleães causada "a lima das polícias [ 
do branco ] [ ] para fora. . . como cães pequenos 
do filhote de cachorro com suas caudas atrás delas." Recordou 
orgulhosamente a multidão intimidating as polícias levantando seus 
injetores e chanting "para falar, Garvey, fala."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Marcus Giamaicano-sopportato Garvey, un orator 
brillante e capo nazionalista nero, ha girato il suo negro 
universale l'associazione di miglioramento che (UNIA) 
nell'organizzazione nera più importante in unito Dichiara 
nell'inizio degli anni 20 discorsi del Garvey ha dissipato spesso i 
pubblici enormi e le storia di resistenza testarda del Garvey di 
fronte ad ostilità bianca proliferata fra i suoi sostenitori. 
In un'intervista orale di storia, il devoto Audley Moore si è 
ricordato del comportamento del jamaican ribelle ad un raduno a New
Orleans causata "l'archivio della polizia [ di bianco ] [ ] fuori. 
. . come i cani piccoli dal puppy con le loro code 
dietro loro." Ha ricordato fiero la folla intimidire la polizia 
alzando le loro pistole e chanting "per parlare, Garvey, parla."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο τζαμαϊκανός-γεννημένος Marcus Garvey, ένας 
λαμπρός ομιλητής και ένας μαύρος εθνικιστικός ηγέτης, 
μετέτρεψαν την καθολική ένωση βελτίωσης νέγρων του (UNIA) σε 
σημαντικότερη μαύρη οργάνωση στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες στις 
ομιλίες του πρόωρου Garvey της δεκαετίας του '20 έσυραν συχνά 
τα τεράστια ακροατήρια, και ιστορία της επίμονης αντίστασης 
Garvey παρά την άσπρη εχθρότητα πολλαπλασιάστηκαν μεταξύ των 
υποστηρικτών του. Σε μια προφορική συνέντευξη ιστορίας, ο 
θιασώτης Audley Moore θυμήθηκε ότι η προκλητική συμπεριφορά
του τζαμαϊκανού σε μια συνάθροιση στη Νέα Ορλεάνη προκάλεσε "το 
[ άσπρο ] αρχείο αστυνομίας [ ] έξω. .. 
όπως τα σκυλιά λίγων κουταβιών με τις ουρές τους πίσω από
τους." Υπενθύμισε υπερήφανα το πλήθος εκφοβιστικός την 
αστυνομία με την αύξηση των πυροβόλων όπλων τους και chanting 
"μιλήστε, Garvey, μιλά."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Marcus Jamaicano-llevado Garvey, un orador 
brillante y arranque de cinta nacionalista negro, dio vuelta a su 
asociación universal de la mejora del negro (UNIA) en la 
organización negra más importante de los Estados Unidos en los años
20 tempranos que los discursos de Garvey trazó a menudo a audiencias 
enormes, y a historias de la resistencia obstinada de Garvey en la 
cara de la hostilidad blanca proliferada entre sus partidarios. 
En una entrevista oral de la historia, el devoto Audley Moore 
recordó el comportamiento desafiante del jamaican en una reunión en 
New Orleans causada "el fichero del policía [ del blanco ] [ ] hacia 
fuera. . . como pequeños perros del perrito con sus
colas detrás de ellas." Ella recordó orgulloso a muchedumbre 
el intimidar del policía levantando sus armas y cantando "para 
hablar, Garvey, habla."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086844</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104434</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/speak-garvey-speak-a-follower-recalls-a-garvey-rally</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
