<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105769</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105769</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204304</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Formulating Questions to Meet Information Needs of ESL Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Formulierung von von Fragen, um Informationsbedarf
der ESL Kursteilnehmer zu erfüllen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Formulation des questions pour satisfaire les 
besoins de l'information des étudiants d'ESL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Formulando perguntas para encontrar-se com 
necessidades de informação de estudantes de ESL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Formulare le domande per soddisfare le esigenze 
delle informazioni degli allievi di ESL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διατύπωση των ερωτήσεων για να ικανοποιήσει τις 
ανάγκες πληροφοριών των σπουδαστών του ESL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Formular preguntas para satisfacer necesidades de 
información de los estudiantes de ESL</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A multi-activity lesson plan to teach the concept of asking engaging, researchable questions prior to reading which leads to effective inquiries during project work. Using engaging questions creates a sense of connectedness by linking academic contents with students' personal concerns. The lesson is primarily designed for English Language Learners although it can be adapted for mainstream students. This lesson can also be modified for use with grades 4-8.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Multiaktivität Lektionplan zum Unterrichten 
das Konzept des Bittens engagierend, researchable Fragen vor Messwert,
welches zu wirkungsvolle Anfragen während der Projektarbeit führt. 
Das Verwenden der engagierenden Fragen erstellt eine Richtung 
von connectedness, indem es akademischen Inhalt mit persönlichen 
Interessen der Kursteilnehmer bindet. Die Lektion ist 
hauptsächlich für englische Sprachenanfänger konzipiert, obgleich 
sie für Hauptströmungskursteilnehmer angepaßt werden kann. 
Diese Lektion kann für Gebrauch mit Graden auch geändert 
werden 4-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un plan de leçon de multi-activité pour 
enseigner le concept de demander s'engageant, questions researchable 
avant la lecture ce qui mène aux enquêtes pertinentes pendant le 
travail de projet. L'utilisation des questions s'engageantes 
crée un sens de connexité en joignant le contenu d'universitaire avec 
les soucis personnels des étudiants. La leçon est 
principalement conçue pour des étudiants d'anglais bien qu'elle 
puisse être adaptée pour les étudiants traditionnels. Cette 
leçon peut également être modifiée pour l'usage avec des 
catégories 4-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma planta da lição da multi-atividade para 
ensinar o conceito de pedir que acopla, perguntas researchable antes 
da leitura qual conduz aos inquéritos eficazes durante o trabalho de 
projeto. Usar perguntas acoplando cría um sentido do 
connectedness ligando índices academic com os interesses pessoais dos
estudantes. A lição é projetada primeiramente para learners 
de língua inglesa embora possa ser adaptada para os estudantes 
mainstream. Esta lição pode também ser modificada para o uso 
com classes 4-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un programma di lezione di multi-attività per 
insegnare il concetto di chiedere che si aggancia, domande 
researchable prima di lettura quale conduce alle inchieste efficaci 
durante di progetto di lavoro. Usando le domande d'aggancio crea
un senso del connectedness collegando il soddisfare accademico con le
preoccupazioni personali degli allievi. La lezione soprattutto 
è progettata per gli studenti di lingue inglesi anche se può essere 
adattata per gli allievi tradizionali. Questa lezione può anche
essere modificata per uso con i gradi 4-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα σχέδιο μαθήματος πολυ-δραστηριότητας για να 
διδάξει την έννοια της ερώτησης της δέσμευσης, researchable 
ερωτήσεις πριν από την ανάγνωση που οδηγεί στις αποτελεσματικές 
έρευνες κατά τη διάρκεια της εργασίας προγράμματος. Η 
χρησιμοποίηση των ερωτήσεων δέσμευσης δημιουργεί μια αίσθηση της 
συνεκτικότητας με τη σύνδεση του ακαδημαϊκού περιεχομένου με τις 
προσωπικές ανησυχίες των σπουδαστών. Το μάθημα σχεδιάζεται 
πρώτιστα για αρχάριος αγγλικής γλώσσας αν και μπορεί να 
προσαρμοστεί για τους επικρατόντες σπουδαστές. Αυτό το 
μάθημα μπορεί επίσης να τροποποιηθεί για τη χρήση με τους 
βαθμούς 4-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un plan de la lección de la multi-actividad para 
enseñar el concepto de pedir que engancha, preguntas researchable 
antes de la lectura cuál conduce a las preguntas eficaces durante 
trabajo de proyecto. Usar preguntas de acoplamiento crea un 
sentido del connectedness conectando contenido académico a las 
preocupaciones personales de los estudiantes. La lección se 
diseña sobre todo para los principiantes de lenguaje inglés aunque 
puede ser adaptada para los estudiantes de corriente. Esta 
lección se puede también modificar para el uso con los grados 4-8.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DEBORAH WILKES
FN:DEBORAH WILKES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KRISTI TRIPLETT
FN:KRISTI TRIPLETT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KAREN WALLER
FN:KAREN WALLER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204304</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105769</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/formulating-questions-to-meet-information-needs-of-esl-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
