<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108273</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108273</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206406</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lincoln Home National Historic Site: A Place of Growth and Memory</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lincoln Nach Hause Nationale Historische Site: 
Ein Ort des Wachstums und des Speichers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Site Historique À la maison National de Lincoln :
Un endroit de croissance et de mémoire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Local Historic Para casa Nacional De Lincoln: 
Um lugar do crescimento e da memória</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luogo Storico A casa Nazionale De Lincoln: 
Un posto di sviluppo e della memoria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ιστορική περιοχή "Οικιαών του Λίνκολν: 
Μια θέση της αύξησης και της μνήμης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sitio Histórico A casa Nacional De Lincoln: 
Un lugar del crecimiento y de la memoria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts the life of our 16th president. See photos of the house in Springfield, Illinois, that Abraham Lincoln, his wife, and family occupied for 17 years. Read news accounts of his departure for Washington, D.C., from Springfield and of his funeral. Learn about the series of events that led to his election as the first president born west of the Appalachians.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt das Leben unseres 16. Präsidenten nach. 
Sehen Sie Fotos des Hauses in Springfield, Illinois, das Abraham
Lincoln, seine Frau und Familie für 17 Jahre besetzte. Lesen 
Sie Nachrichten Konten seiner Abfahrt für Washington, Gleichstrom, 
von Springfield und seines Begräbnisses. Erlernen Sie über die
Reihe von Fällen, die das zu seine Wahl als der erste Präsident 
führte, der westlich von den Appalachians getragen wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte la vie de notre 16ème président. 
Voir les photos de la maison à Springfield, l'Illinois, 
qu'abraham Lincoln, son épouse, et famille a occupé pendant 17 
années. Lisez les comptes de nouvelles de son départ pour 
Washington, C.C, à Springfield et de son enterrement. 
Renseignez-vous sur la série d'événements que cela a menés 
à son élection en tant que premier président soutenu à l'ouest des
Appalaches.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts a vida de nosso 1õ presidente. 
Veja fotos da casa em Springfield, Illinois, que Abraham 
Lincoln, sua esposa, e família ocupou por 17 anos. Leia 
clientes da notícia de sua partida para Washington, C.C., de 
Springfield e de seu funeral. Aprenda sobre a série dos eventos
que isso conduziu a sua eleição como o primeiro presidente carregado
ao oeste dos appalachians.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta la vita del nostro sedicesimo presidente.
Veda le foto della casa a Springfield, l'Illinois, che Abraham 
Lincoln, la sua moglie e famiglia ha occupato per 17 anni. Legga
i clienti di notizie della sua partenza per Washington, DC, da 
Springfield e del suo funerale. Impari circa la serie di eventi 
che quello ha condotto alla sua elezione come il primo presidente 
sopportato ad ovest dei appalachians.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί τη ζωή του 16$ου Προέδρου μας. 
Δείτε τις φωτογραφίες του σπιτιού στο 
Σπρίνγκφιλντ, Ιλλινόις, το οποίο ο Abraham Λίνκολν, η σύζυγός
του, και η οικογένεια κατέλαβαν για 17 έτη. Διαβάστε τους
απολογισμούς ειδήσεων της αναχώρησης για την Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ 
ΡΕΎΜΑ, από το Σπρίνγκφιλντ και κηδείας του του. Μάθετε για 
τη σειρά γεγονότων που οδήγησε στην εκλογή του ως πρώτος 
Πρόεδρος γεννημένος δυτικά του Appalachians.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo la vida de nuestro décimosexto 
presidente. Vea las fotos de la casa en Springfield, Illinois, 
que Abraham Lincoln, su esposa, y familia ocupó por 17 años. 
Lea las cuentas de las noticias de su salida para Washington, 
C.C., de Springfield y de su entierro. Aprenda sobre la serie de
acontecimientos que eso condujo a su elección como el primer 
presidente llevado al oeste de los apalaches.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206406</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108273</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lincoln-home-national-historic-site-a-place-of-growth-and-memory</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
