<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106172</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106172</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087297</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Foreigner in My Own Land": Juan Nepomuceno Seguin Flees Texas, 1842</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Ausländer in meinem eigenen Land": 
Juan Nepomuceno Seguin Flieht Texas, 1842</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un Étranger dans ma propre terre" : 
Juan Nepomuceno Seguin Se sauve Le Texas, 1842</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um estrangeiro em minha própria terra": 
Juan Nepomuceno Seguin Foge Texas, 1842</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"uno straniero nella mia propria terra": 
Juan Nepomuceno Seguin Fuggisce Il Texas, 1842</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας αλλοδαπός στο έδαφός μου": Θ*Ιuαν 
Nepomuceno Seguin Flees Τέξας, 1842</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un extranjero en mi propia pista": Juan 
Nepomuceno Seguin Huye Tejas, 1842</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Few Anglos lived in San Antonio after the Texas Revolution of 1835-36 and Tejanos (Texas-Mexicans) continued their rule. Juan Nepomuceno Seguin was born into a prominent tejano family and had close ties with Stephen Austin, leader of the first American settlers in Texas. He became mayor or alcade at an early age and fought on the Anglo side with the coming of Texas' revolt against Mexico. However, his political situation increasingly became fragile because of the changing balance of power and Anglos' efforts to wrest control. When the Mexican General Vasquez captured San Antonio in 1842, he announced that Seguin held loyalties to Mexico and Seguin's enemies denounced him as a spy. Seguin fled to Mexico. Those Tejanos who remained in Texas often found their livestock and corn stolen; others had their land taken in disputes. After the Mexican War of 1846-48, Seguin returned north. The writing and publication of the  Personal Memoirs of John N. Seguin  was part of his effort to set the story straight and appeal to Americans while also lashing out about the conflicted position of Mexican Texans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenig Anglos lebte in San Antonio nach der Texas 
Umdrehung von 1835-36 und Tejanos (Texas-Mexikaner) setzte ihre 
Richtlinie fort. Juan Nepomuceno Seguin wurde in eine 
vorstehende tejano Familie getragen und nahe Gleichheit mit Stephen 
Austin, Führer der ersten amerikanischen Siedleren in Texas hatte. 
Er wurde Bürgermeister oder alcade an einem frühen Alter und 
kämpfte auf der Angloseite mit dem Kommen von Aufruhr Texas gegen 
Mexiko. Jedoch wurde seine politische Situation in zunehmendem 
Maße wegen der ändernden Balance der Energie und der Bemühungen 
Anglos' zur wrest Steuerung zerbrechlich. Als der mexikanische 
General Vasquez San Antonio 1842 erfaßte, verkündete er, daß Seguin
Loyalitäten nach Mexiko anhielt und Feinde Seguins ihn denunzierte, 
während ein Spion Seguin nach Mexiko floh. Jenes fand Tejanos, 
das in Texas blieb, häufig ihr Vieh und Mais gestohlen; andere 
hatten ihr Land, das in den Debatten genommen wurde. Nach dem 
mexikanischen Krieg von 1846-48, ging Seguin nördlich zurück. 
Das Schreiben und die Publikation der persönlichen Abhandlungen
von John N. Seguin waren ein Teil seiner Bemühung, die Geschichte 
gerade einzustellen und Amerikanern beim aus über der widersprochenen
Position von mexikanischem Texans auch peitschen zu gefallen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Peu d'anglos a vécu dans San Antonio après 
la révolution du Texas de 1835-36 et Tejanos (Texas-Mexicain) a 
continué leur règle. Juan Nepomuceno Seguin a été 
soutenu dans une famille en avant de tejano et a eu les cravates 
étroites avec Stephen Austin, amorce des premiers colons 
américains dans le Texas. Il est devenu maire ou alcade à un 
âge jeune et a combattu du côté anglo avec venir de la révolte du 
Texas contre le Mexique. Cependant, sa situation politique est 
de plus en plus devenue fragile en raison de l'equilibre changeant des
forces et des efforts d'Anglos à la commande wrest. Quand le 
Général mexicain Vasquez a capturé San Antonio en 1842, il a 
annoncé que Seguin a tenu des fidélités sur le Mexique et les 
ennemis de Seguin l'a dénoncé pendant qu'un espion Seguin se sauvait
au Mexique. Ces Tejanos qui est resté dans le Texas a souvent 
trouvé leur bétail et maïs volés ; d'autres ont eu leur 
terre prise dans les conflits. Après la guerre mexicaine de 
1846-48, Seguin est retourné au nord. L'écriture et la 
publication des mémoires personnels de John N. Seguin faisaient 
partie de son effort de placer l'histoire droite et de faire appel aux
Américains tout en également fouettant hors de environ la position 
étée en conflit des Texans mexicains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pouco Anglos viveu em San Antonio após a volta de
Texas de 1835-36 e Tejanos (Texas-Mexicano) continuou sua régua. 
Juan Nepomuceno Seguin foi carregado em uma família proeminente
do tejano e teve laços próximos com Stephen Austin, líder dos 
primeiros settlers americanos em Texas. Transformou-se mayor ou 
alcade em uma idade adiantada e lutou-se no lado anglo com a vinda da 
revolta de Texas' de encontro a México. Entretanto, sua 
situação política tornou-se cada vez mais frágil por causa do 
contrapeso de potência em mudança e de esforços de Anglos' ao 
controle o mais wrest. Quando o general mexicano Vasquez 
capturou San Antonio em 1842, anunciou que Seguin prendeu lealdades a 
México e inimigos de Seguin denounced o enquanto um espião Seguin 
fujiu a México. Aquele Tejanos que remanesceu em Texas 
encontrou frequentemente seus animais domésticos e milho roubados; 
outros tiveram sua terra feita exame nas disputas. Após a
guerra mexicana de 1846-48, Seguin retornou para o norte. A 
escrita e a publicação dos memoirs pessoais de John N. Seguin eram 
parte de seu esforço ajustar a história reta e apelar aos americanos
ao também chicotear para fora sobre da posição oposta de Texans 
mexicano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poco Anglos ha vissuto in San Antonio dopo la 
rivoluzione del Texas di 1835-36 e Tejanos (Texas-texas-Mexicans) ha 
continuato la loro regola. Juan Nepomuceno Seguin è stato 
sopportato in una famiglia prominente di tejano ed ha avuto legami 
vicini con Stephen Austin, capo dei primi settlers americani 
nel Texas. Si è transformato in in sindaco o in alcade ad 
un'età giovane ed ha combattuto dal lato anglo con venire della 
sommossa del Texas contro il Messico. Tuttavia, la sua 
situazione politica sempre più è diventato fragile a causa 
dell'equilibrio cambiante di forze e di sforzi del Anglos 
strappare il controllo. Quando il General messicano 
Vasquez ha bloccato il San Antonio in 1842, ha annunciato che Seguin 
ha tenuto le lealtà nel Messico e nemici del Seguin lo ha denunciato 
mentre una spia Seguin è fuggito nel Messico. Quel Tejanos che 
è rimasto nel Texas spesso ha trovato il loro bestiame e cereale 
rubati; altri hanno avuti loro terra presa nelle dispute. 
Dopo la guerra messicana di 1846-48, Seguin ha ritornato a 
nord. La scrittura e la pubblicazione delle memorie personali di
John N. Seguin facevano parte del suo sforzo regolare la storia 
diritta e fare appello agli Americani mentre però frustando verso 
l'esterno circa la posizione contrastante di Texans messicano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λίγο Anglos έζησε στο SAN Antonio μετά από 
την επανάσταση του Τέξας 1835-36 και Tejanos 
(Τέξας-μεξικανοί) συνέχισε τον κανόνα τους. Θ*Ιuαν 
Nepomuceno Seguin γεννήθηκε σε μια προεξέχουσα οικογένεια 
tejano και είχε τους στενούς δεσμούς με stephen Ώστιν, 
ηγέτης των πρώτων αμερικανικών αποίκων στο Τέξας. Έγινε 
δήμαρχος ή alcade σε μια νεαρή ηλικία και πάλεψε στην πλευρά 
Anglo με τον ερχομό της επανάστασης του Τέξας ενάντια στο 
Μεξικό. Εντούτοις, η πολιτική κατάστασή του έγινε όλο και
περισσότερο εύθραυστη λόγω της μεταβαλλόμενης ισορροπίας των 
προσπαθειών δύναμης και Anglos να αποσπαστεί ο έλεγχος. 
Όταν ο μεξικάνικος στρατηγός Vasquez συνέλαβε το SAN 
Antonio το 1842, ανήγγειλε ότι Seguin κράτησε τις πίστεις
στο Μεξικό και οι εχθροί Seguin τον κατήγγειλαν ως κατάσκοπο 
Seguin που στο Μεξικό. Εκείνο το Tejanos που παρέμεινε 
στο Τέξας βρήκε συχνά το ζωικό κεφάλαιο και το καλαμπόκι τους 
κλεμμένα  άλλοι πήραν το έδαφός τους στις διαφωνίες. 
Μετά από το μεξικάνικο πόλεμο 1846-48, Seguin 
επέστρεψε το Βορρά. Το γράψιμο και η δημοσίευση των 
προσωπικών απομνημονευμάτων John N. Seguin ήταν μέρος της
προσπάθειάς του να θέσει την ιστορία ευθεία και να απευθυνθεί σε
Αμερικανούς επίσης μαστιγώνοντας έξω για τη συγκρουσμένη θέση 
μεξικάνικου Texans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Poco Anglos vivió en San Antonio después de la 
revolución de Tejas de 1835-36 y Tejanos (Tejas-Mexicano) continuó 
su regla. Juan Nepomuceno Seguin fue llevado en una familia 
prominente del tejano y tenía lazos cercanos con Stephen Austin, 
arranque de cinta de los primeros colonos americanos en Tejas. 
Él hizo alcalde o alcade en una edad temprana y luchó en la 
cara anglo con venir de la rebelión de Tejas contra México. 
Sin embargo, su situación política llegó a ser cada vez más 
frágil debido a el equilibrio que cambiaba de la potencia y de los 
esfuerzos de Anglos al control ma's wrest. Cuando el general 
mexicano Vasquez capturó San Antonio en 1842, él anunció que Seguin
llevó a cabo lealtades a México y los enemigos de Seguin denunci lo 
mientras que un espía Seguin huyó a México. Eso Tejanos que 
permanecía en Tejas a menudo encontró su ganado y maíz robados; 
otros tenían su pista tomada en conflictos. Después de 
la guerra mexicana de 1846-48, Seguin volvió al norte. La 
escritura y la publicación de las memorias personales de Juan N. 
Seguin eran parte de su esfuerzo de fijar la historia recta y de 
abrogar a los americanos mientras que también azotaba fuera sobre de 
la posición estada en conflicto de Texans mexicano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087297</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106172</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-foreigner-in-my-own-land-juan-nepomuceno-seguin-flees-texas-1842</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
