<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209895</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Interior / exterior angles of a polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Innen-/Außenwinkel eines Polygons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Angles intérieurs/extérieurs d'un polygone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ângulos interior/exteriores de um polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Angoli interni/esterni di un poligono</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εσωτερικές/εξωτερικές γωνίες ενός πολυγώνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ángulos interiores/exteriores de un polígono</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the relationship of the interior and exterior angles of a polygon. The applet shows an irregular polygon where one vertex is draggable. As it is dragged the interior and exterior angles at that vertex are displayed, and a formula is continuously updated showing that they are supplementary. The tricky part is when the vertex is dragged inside the polygon making it concave. The applet shows how the relationship still holds provided you get the signs of the angles right. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Verhältnis der Innen- und Außenwinkel eines 
Polygons zeigen. Der applet zeigt einem unregelmäßigen 
Polygon, wo ein Gipfel draggable ist. Während er geschleppt 
wird, werden die Innen- und Außenwinkel an diesem Gipfel angezeigt, 
und eine Formel ist ununterbrochen aktualisierte Vertretung, daß sie 
Ergänzungs sind. Das tricky Teil ist, wenn der Gipfel innerhalb
des Polygons geschleppt wird, das es konkav bildet. Der applet 
zeigt, wie die Einflüsse des Verhältnisses noch Sie erhalten die 
Zeichen der Winkel recht lieferten. Applet kann zum vollen 
Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert
werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf 
es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek 
ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le rapport des angles intérieurs et extérieurs d'un 
polygone. L'applet montre à un polygone irrégulier où un 
sommet est draggable. Pendant qu'il est traîné les angles 
intérieurs et extérieurs à ce sommet sont affichés, et une formule
est sans interruption apparence mise à jour qu'ils complètent. 
La partie rusée est quand le sommet est traîné à 
l'intérieur du polygone la rendant concave. L'applet montre 
comment les prises de rapport vous fournissaient toujours obtiennent 
les signes des angles droits. L'applet peut être agrandi à la 
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o relacionamento dos ângulos interior e exteriores de um 
polygon. O applet mostra a um polygon irregular onde um vertex 
é draggable. Enquanto é arrastado os ângulos interior e 
exteriores nesse vertex estão indicados, e uma fórmula é 
continuamente exibição updated que são suplementares. A parte
complicada é quando o vertex é arrastado dentro do polygon que faz a
côncava. O applet mostra como as preensões do relacionamento 
ainda o forneceram começam os sinais dos ângulos direitos. O 
applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um 
projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, 
estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou
na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este 
recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook da 
geometria da referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il rapporto degli angoli interni ed esterni di un poligono.
Il applet mostra ad un poligono irregolare dove un vertice è 
draggable. Mentre è trascinato gli angoli interni ed esterni a 
quel vertice sono visualizzati e una formula è continuamente 
rappresentazione aggiornata che sono supplementari. La parte 
ingannevole è quando il vertice è trascinato all'interno del 
poligono che la rende concava. Il applet mostra come le strette 
di rapporto ancora li hanno forniti ottengono i segni degli angoli di 
destra. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo 
pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione
nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel 
paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. 
Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del 
manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τη σχέση των εσωτερικών και εξωτερικών γωνιών ενός
πολυγώνου. Το applet εμφανίζει ανώμαλο πολύγωνο όπου 
ένα vertex είναι draggable. Δεδομένου ότι σέρνεται οι
εσωτερικές και εξωτερικές γωνίες σε εκείνο το vertex 
παρουσιάζονται, και ένας τύπος ενημερώνεται συνεχώς δείχνοντας 
ότι είναι συμπληρωματικές. Το δυσνόητο μέρος είναι πότε 
vertex σέρνεται μέσα στο πολύγωνο καθιστώντας το κοίλο. 
Το applet επιδεικνύει πώς η σχέση κρατά ακόμα υπό τον 
όρο ότι παίρνετε τα σημάδια των γωνιών σωστών. Το 
Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη 
χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην 
τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από 
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el lazo de los ángulos interiores y exteriores de un 
polígono. El applet muestra a polígono irregular donde está 
draggable una cima. Mientras que se arrastra los ángulos 
interiores y exteriores en esa cima se visualizan, y un fórmula es 
continuamente demostración actualizada que son suplementarios. 
La parte difícil es cuando la cima se arrastra dentro del 
polígono que la hace cóncava. El applet muestra cómo los 
asimientos del lazo todavía le proporcionaron consiguen las muestras 
de los ángulos derechas. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla
de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de 
clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede 
tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209895</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105240</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/interior-exterior-angles-of-a-polygon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
