<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104734</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104734</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087065</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The uncommon increase of Settlements in the back Country": Sir William Johnson Watches the Settlers Invade Indian Lands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die seltene Zunahme von Regelungen des 
rückseitigen Landes": Sir William Johnson Watches die Siedleren
dringen indische Länder ein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'augmentation rare des règlements du pays 
arrière" : Monsieur William Johnson observe les colons 
envahir les terres indiennes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o aumento uncommon dos estabelecimentos no país 
traseiro": O senhor William Johnson Prestar atenção os 
settlers invade terras indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'aumento raro degli stabilimenti nel paese 
posteriore": Il sir William Johnson Watches i settlers invade le
terre indiane</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η ασυνήθιστη αύξηση των τακτοποιήσεων στην πίσω 
χώρα": Ο Sir William Johnson Watches οι άποικοι 
εισβάλλει στα ινδικά εδάφη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el aumento infrecuente de establecimientos en el 
país posterior": Sir Guillermo Johnson Watches los colonos 
invade pistas indias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As North American colonists, eager for land, spilled over the Appalachian Mountains in the 1750s, British concern and Indian anger over the expansion rose. Sir William Johnson, a migrant from Ireland who had settled in central New York, was a British official with ties to the Iroquois; in 1756 he was appointed superintendent of Indian Affairs for the northern colonies. In 1772, after British victory in the Seven Year's War, he wrote to the Earl of Dartmouth, the Secretary of State for the Colonies, describing the abuses of the traders and the Indians' complaints about the settlers. Johnson feared the loss of authority by the established government, and judging of the settlers that "they are in general a lawless sett of People. "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als nordamerikanische Kolonisten, die für Land, 
verschüttet über den Appalachian Bergen im 1750s eifrig sind, 
betreffen Briten und indischer Zorn über der Expansion stieg. 
Sir William Johnson, ein Wanderer aus Irland, das in zentralem 
New York vereinbart hatte, war ein britischer Beamter mit Gleichheit 
zum Irokesen; 1756 wurde er Betriebsleiter der indischen 
Angelegenheiten für die Nordkolonien ernannt. 1772 nach 
britischem Sieg im sieben Krieg des Jahres, schrieb er dem Grafen von 
Dartmouth, der Staatssekretär für die Kolonien und beschrieb die 
Mißbräuche der Händler und die Beanstandungen der Inder über die 
Siedleren. Johnson fürchtete den Verlust der Berechtigung durch
die hergestellte Regierung und das Beurteilen der Siedleren, die "sie 
im allgemeinen ein gesetzloser Pflasterstein der Leute sind"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En tant que colons américains du nord, 
désireux pour la terre, renversés au-dessus des montagnes 
appalachiennes dans le 1750s, les Anglais concernent et la colère 
indienne au-dessus de l'expansion a monté. Monsieur William 
Johnson, un migrant d'Irlande qui s'était établie à New York 
central, était un fonctionnaire britannique avec des cravates au 
Iroquois ; en 1756 il a été nommé surveillant des affaires 
indiennes pour les colonies nordiques. En 1772, après victoire 
britannique dans des sept la guerre ans, il a écrit au comte de 
Dartmouth, le secrétaire d'état pour les colonies, décrivant les 
abus des commerçants et les plaintes des Indiens au sujet des colons.
Johnson a craint la perte d'autorité par le gouvernement 
établi, et juger des colons que "elles sont en général un pavé 
anarchique des personnes"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como os colonos norte-americanos, ansiosos para a 
terra, derramados sobre as montanhas appalachian no 1750s, Ingleses 
concernem e a raiva indian sobre a expansão levantou-se. O 
senhor William Johnson, um emigrante de Ireland que se tinha 
estabelecido em New York central, era um oficial britânico com os 
laços ao iroquois; em 1756 foi apontado superintendente de 
casos indian para as colônias do norte. Em 1772, após a 
vitória britânica na guerra dos sete anos, escreveu ao earl de 
Dartmouth, secretária de estado para as colônias, descrevendo os 
abusos dos comerciantes e as queixas dos indians' sobre os settlers. 
Johnson temeu a perda da autoridade pelo governo estabelecido, e
julgar dos settlers que "são no general um sett lawless dos povos"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come colonizzatori nordamericani, desiderosi per 
terra, rovesciati sopra le montagne appalachian nel 1750s, Britannici 
si interessano e la rabbia indiana sopra l'espansione è aumentato. 
Il sir William Johnson, un migrante dall'Irlanda che si era 
depositata a New York centrale, era un funzionario britannico con i 
legami al iroquois; in 1756 è stato nominato soprintendente 
degli affari indiani per le colonie nordiche. In 1772, dopo la 
vittoria britannica nella guerra dei sette anni, ha scritto al earl di
Dartmouth, la segretaria di Dichiara per le colonie, 
descrivendo gli abusi dei commercianti ed i reclami degli indiani 
circa i settlers. Johnson ha temuto la perdita di autorità dal 
governo stabilito e giudicare dei settlers che "sono in generale un 
pavè lawless della gente"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαν βορειοαμερικανικούς αποίκους, πρόθυμους για το 
έδαφος, που ανατράπηκε πέρα από τα της όξινης απορροής βουνά 
στο 1750s, η βρετανική ανησυχία και ο ινδικός θυμός πέρα από 
την επέκταση αυξήθηκαν. Ο Sir William Johnson, ένας 
μετανάστης από την Ιρλανδία που είχε εγκαταστήσει στην κεντρική 
Νέα Υόρκη, ήταν βρετανικός ανώτερος υπάλληλος με τους δεσμούς 
iroquois  το 1756 διορίστηκε τον επιθεωρητή των ινδικών
υποθέσεων για τις βόρειες αποικίες. Το 1772, μετά από τη
βρετανική νίκη στον επτά πόλεμο του έτους, έγραψε στον κόμη 
Dartmouth, ο γραμματέας του κράτους για τις αποικίες, που 
περιγράφει τις κακοποιήσεις των εμπόρων και τις καταγγελίες των 
Ινδών για τους αποίκους. Johnson φοβισμένο η 
απώλεια αρχής από την καθιερωμένη κυβέρνηση, και κρίση των 
αποίκων ότι "είναι γενικά ένα άναρχο λιθόστρωτο των ανθρώπων. 
"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Como colonos norteamericanos, impacientes para la 
pista, derramados sobre las montañas apalaches en el 1750s, 
Británicos tratan y la cólera india sobre la extensión se levantó.
Sir Guillermo Johnson, nómada de Irlanda que había colocado en
Nueva York central, era un funcionario británico con los lazos al 
iroquois; en 1756 lo designaron superintendente de los asuntos 
indios para las colonias norteñas. En 1772, después de la 
victoria británica en la guerra de los siete años, él escribió al 
earl de Dartmouth, la secretaria del estado para las colonias, 
describiendo los abusos de los comerciantes y las quejas de los indios
sobre los colonos. Johnson temió la pérdida de autoridad por 
el gobierno establecido, y la sentencia de los colonos que "son en 
general un sett sin ley de la gente"</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087065</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104734</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-uncommon-increase-of-settlements-in-the-back-country-sir-william-johnson-watches-the-settlers-invade-indian-lands</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
