<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106591</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106591</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770210039</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploring Amistad: Race and the Boundaries of Freedom in Antebellum Maritime America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschendes Amistad: Rennen und die 
Grenzen der Freiheit in Antebellum Seeamerika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Amistad L'explorant : Course et les bornes 
de la liberté en Amérique maritime d'avant-guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Amistad Explorando: Raça e os limites da 
liberdade em América marítima antebellum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Amistad D'Esplorazione: Corsa ed i contorni 
di libertà in America marittima antebellum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξερεύνηση Amistad: Φυλή και τα όρια της 
ελευθερίας στην προπολεμική θαλάσσια Αμερική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Amistad Que explora: Raza y los límites de 
la libertad en América marítimo antebellum</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Exploring Amistad examines the Amistad revolt, a shipboard uprising of slaves off the coast of Cuba. It uses timelines, a library of historical documents, a discovery section and bibliography to teach about this watershed historical event, which set off a legal, political, and popular debate over the slave trade, slavery, race, Africa, and ultimately America itself.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschendes Amistad überprüft den Amistad 
Aufruhr, einen Bordaufstieg der Sklaven weg von der Küste von 
Kuba. Es benutzt timelines, eine Bibliothek der historischen 
Dokumente, ein Entdeckungkapitel und Bibliographie, um über diesen 
historischen Fall der Wasserscheide zu unterrichten, der weg von 
einer zugelassenen, politischen und populären Debatte über dem 
Sklave Handel, der Sklaverei, dem Rennen, dem Afrika und schließlich 
dem Amerika selbst einstellte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Amistad l'explorant examine la révolte d'Amistad,
un soulèvement de bord du navire des esclaves outre de la côte du 
Cuba. Il emploie des chronologies, une bibliothèque des 
documents historiques, une section de découverte et la bibliographie 
pour enseigner au sujet de cet événement historique de ligne de 
partage, qui a placé outre d'une discussion légale, politique, et 
populaire au-dessus du commerce, de l'esclavage, de la course, de 
l'Afrique, et finalement de l'Amérique slaves elle-même.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Amistad explorando examina a revolta de Amistad, 
um uprising do shipboard dos escravos fora da costa de Cuba. Usa
timelines, uma biblioteca de originais históricos, uma seção da 
descoberta e a bibliografia ensinar sobre este evento histórico do 
watershed, que se ajustou fora de um debate legal, político, e 
popular sobre o comércio, o slavery, a raça, a África, e finalmente
a América própria do escravo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Amistad d'esplorazione esamina la sommossa di 
Amistad, una rivolta di fiancata della nave degli schiavi fuori 
del litorale della Cuba. Usa i timelines, una libreria dei 
documenti storici, una sezione di scoperta e la bibliografia per 
insegnare circa questo evento storico di spartiacque, che si è 
regolato fuori di un dibattito legale, politico e popolare sopra il 
commercio, lo slavery, la corsa, l'Africa ed infine l'America in se 
dello schiavo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Amistad que explora examina la rebelión de 
Amistad, una sublevación del shipboard de esclavos de la costa de 
Cuba. Utiliza timelines, una biblioteca de documentos 
históricos, una sección del descubrimiento y la bibliografía para 
enseñar sobre este acontecimiento histórico de la línea divisoria 
de las aguas, que fijó de un discusión legal, político, y popular 
sobre el comercio, la esclavitud, la raza, la África, y en última 
instancia la América sí mismo del esclavo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770210039</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106591</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exploring-amistad</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
