<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103659</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103659</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206105</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The New Millenium Observatory (NeMO)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Neue Millenium Sternwarte (NeMO)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Nouvel Observatoire de Millénaire (NeMO)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Obervatório Novo De Millenium (NeMO)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Nuovo Osservatorio Di Millenium (NeMO)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το νέο παρατηρητήριο χιλιετίας (NeMO)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Observatorio Nuevo De Millenium (NeMO)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Studies interactions between submarine volcanic activity and seafloor hotsprings, offers a unit called The Case of the Missing Rumbleometer. High school and middle school students learn about locating the epicenter of an earthquake, calculating the distance to the epicenter from hydrophones (underwater microphones), identifying evidence of a lava eruption, detecting a hydrothermal vent, estimating the age of lava based on animal species in the area, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Studien Interaktionen zwischen vulkanischer 
Unterwasseraktivität und seafloor hotsprings, Angebote eine 
Maßeinheit benannten den Fall vom fehlenden Rumbleometer. High 
School und der mittleren Schule Kursteilnehmer erlernen über das 
Lokalisieren des Epizentrums eines Erdbebens und errechnen den Abstand
zum Epizentrum von den Hydrophonen (Unterwassermikrophone) und 
kennzeichnen Beweis einer Lavaeruption und entdecken eine 
hydrothermale Entlüftungsöffnung und schätzen das Alter von Lava 
basiert auf Tiersorte im Bereich und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les interactions d'études entre l'activité et 
les hotsprings volcaniques submersibles de seafloor, offres une unité
ont appelé le cas du Rumbleometer manquant. Les étudiants de 
lycée et de collège se renseignent sur localiser l'épicentre d'un
tremblement de terre, calculant la distance à l'épicentre des 
hydrophones (microphones sous-marins), identifiant l'évidence d'une 
éruption de lave, détectant un évent hydrothermique, estimant 
l'âge de la lave basé sur les espèces animales dans la zone, 
et davantage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As interações dos estudos entre a atividade e os
hotsprings vulcânicos submarinos do seafloor, ofertas uma unidade 
chamaram o exemplo do Rumbleometer faltante. Os estudantes da 
High School e da escola média aprendem sobre encontrar o epicenter de
um terremoto, calculando a distância ao epicenter dos hidrofones 
(microfones subaquáticos), identificando a evidência de um eruption 
da lava, detectando um respiradouro hydrothermal, estimando a idade da
lava baseada na espécie animal na área, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le interazioni di studi fra attività ed i 
hotsprings vulcanici sottomarini di seafloor, offerte un'unità hanno 
chiamato il caso del Rumbleometer mancante. Gli allievi della 
scuola centrale e della High School imparano circa l'individuazione 
del epicenter di un terremoto, calcolatore la distanza al epicenter 
dagli idrofoni (microfoni subacquei), identificanti la prova di un 
eruption della lava, rilevando uno sfiato idrotermale, valutante 
l'età di lava basata sulla specie animale nella zona e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αλληλεπιδράσεις μελετών μεταξύ υποβρύχια 
ηφαιστειακά hotsprings δραστηριότητας και θαλάσσιου πυθμένα, 
προσφέρουν μια μονάδα αποκαλούμενη περίπτωση να λείψουν 
Rumbleometer. Το γυμνάσιο και οι μέσοι σχολικοί 
σπουδαστές μαθαίνουν για την εντόπιση του επίκεντρου ενός 
σεισμού, υπολογίζοντας την απόσταση στο επίκεντρο από 
hydrophones (υποβρύχια μικρόφωνα), προσδιορίζοντας τα στοιχεία 
μιας έκρηξης λάβας, ανιχνεύοντας μια υδροθερμική διέξοδο, 
υπολογίζοντας την ηλικία της λάβας βασισμένη στα ζωικά είδη στην
περιοχή, και περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las interacciones de los estudios entre la 
actividad y los hotsprings volcánicos submarinos del seafloor, 
ofertas una unidad llamaron el caso del Rumbleometer que falta. 
Los estudiantes de la High School secundaria y de la escuela 
media aprenden sobre el localización del epicenter de un terremoto, 
calculando la distancia al epicenter de los hidrófonos (micrófonos 
subacuáticos), identificando evidencia de una erupción de la lava, 
detectando un respiradero hidrotérmico, estimando la edad de la lava 
basada en la especie animal en el área, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206105</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103659</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-new-millenium-observatory-nemo</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
