<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086280</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Entered into Business, with Hope, Confidence, and Activity": Ann Carson Becomes an Independent Entrepreneur, ca. 1810</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich nahm am Geschäft, mit Hoffnung, Vertrauen und
Aktivität" teil: Ann Carson wird ein unabhängiger Unternehmer,
Ca. 1810</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai entamé des affaires, avec l'espoir, la 
confiance, et l'activité" : Ann Carson devient un entrepreneur 
indépendant, ca. 1810</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu participei no negócio, com esperança, 
confiança, e atividade": Ann Carson transforma-se um 
empreendedor independente, ca. 1810</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho preso parte al commercio, con speranza, 
riservatezza ed attività": Ann Carson diventa un imprenditore 
indipendente, ca. 1810</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"εισήγαγα στην επιχείρηση, με την ελπίδα, την 
εμπιστοσύνη, και τη δραστηριότητα": ANN Carson 
Becomes ένας ανεξάρτητος επιχειρηματίας, περίπου 1810</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"entré en negocio, con esperanza, confianza, y 
actividad": Ana Carson hace empresario Independiente, ca. 
1810</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early nineteenth century a woman in the emerging middle class was often dependent on her father or husband's position. Many women, however, chose or were forced to seek independence and autonomy in their work and family lives. Anne Carson was one such person. With an alcoholic father and a timid mother, her middle status in port city Philadelphia was always shaky. She attended one of the first coeducational academies in the new nation but her unemployed father forced the 15-year-old to marry a 41-year-old ship captain. Her husband's frequent abuse and absences left her without financial support, and Anne worked as a seamstress and opened a china shop to support her parents, siblings, and four children. She achieved modest success, but economic distress after the War of 1812 and her involvement in a murder case sent her spiraling into Philadelphia's underclass. In an effort to earn money she published her autobiography, where she recorded the variety of work available to women in the commercial cities of the early Republic.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 19.jahrhundert war eine Frau in der 
auftauchenden mittleren Kategorie häufig von ihrer Vater- oder 
Ehemannposition abhängig. Viele Frauen jedoch wählten oder 
wurden erzwungen, um Unabhängigkeit und Autonomie in ihren Arbeit und
Familie Lebensdauern zu suchen. Anne Carson war eine solche 
Person. Mit einem alkoholischen Vater und einer schüchternen 
Mutter war ihr mittlerer Status in der Portstadt Philadelphia immer 
wackelig. Sie bediente eine der ersten coeducational Akademien
in der neuen Nation, aber ihr arbeitsloser Vater erzwang das 
15-year-old, um einen Schiff 41-year-old Kapitän zu heiraten. 
Häufiger Mißbrauch und Abwesenheiten ihres Ehemanns ließen 
sie ohne finanziellen Support, und Anne arbeitete als Näherin und 
öffnete ein Porzellansystem, um ihre Eltern, Geschwister und vier 
Kinder zu unterstützen. Sie erzielte bescheidenen Erfolg, aber 
ökonomische Bedrängnis nach dem Krieg von 1812 und ihre 
Miteinbeziehung in einem Mordfall sendeten sie windend in underclass 
Philadelphias. In einer Bemühung, Geld veröffentlichte sie zu 
erwerben ihre Autobiographie, in der sie die Vielzahl der Arbeit 
vorhanden für Frauen in den kommerziellen Städte der frühen 
Republik speicherte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Au dix-neuvième siècle tôt une femme dans la 
bourgeoisie naissante dépendait souvent de sa position de père ou de
mari. Beaucoup de femmes, cependant, ont choisi ou ont été 
forcées de rechercher l'indépendance et l'autonomie en quelques 
leurs vies de travail et de famille. Anne Carson était une 
telle personne. Avec un père alcoolique et une mère timide, 
son mode moyen dans la ville gauche Philadelphie était toujours 
précaire. Elle a servi une des premières académies 
coéducationnelles dans la nouvelle nation mais son père sans emploi 
a forcé le 15-year-old pour épouser un capitaine du bateau 
41-year-old. L'abus fréquent et les absences de son mari l'ont 
laissée sans aide financière, et Anne a travaillé en tant 
qu'ouvrière couturier et a ouvert une boutique de porcelaine pour 
supporter ses parents, enfants de mêmes parents, et quatre enfants. 
Elle a réalisé le succès modeste, mais la détresse 
économique après la guerre de 1812 et sa participation dans un cas 
de meurtre l'ont envoyée se développant en spirales dans la 
population défavorisée de Philadelphie. Dans un effort de la gagner à 
argent a édité son autobiographie, où elle a enregistré la 
variété de travail disponible aux femmes dans les villes 
commerciales de la République tôt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No décimo nono século adiantado uma mulher na 
classe média emergente era frequentemente dependente de sua posição
do pai ou do marido. Muitas mulheres, entretanto, escolheram ou 
foram forçadas para procurar a independência e a autonomia em suas 
vidas do trabalho e da família. Anne Carson era uma tal pessoa.
Com um pai alcoólico e uma matriz tímida, seu status médio na
cidade portuária Filadélfia era sempre shaky. Atendeu a um dos
primeiros academies coeducational na nação nova mas seu pai 
unemployed forçou o 15-year-old para casar um capitão do navio 
41-year-old. O abuso freqüente e as ausências do seu marido 
deixaram-na sem sustentação financeira, e Anne trabalhou como um 
seamstress e abriu uma loja do china para suportar seus pais, 
siblings, e quatro crianças. Conseguiu o sucesso modesto, mas a
aflição econômica após a guerra de 1812 e sua participação em um
exemplo do assassinato emitiram-na que espirala em underclass de 
Filadélfia. Em um esforço ganhar a dinheiro publicou seu 
autobiography, onde gravou a variedade do trabalho disponível às 
mulheres nas cidades comerciais da república adiantada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel diciannovesimo secolo in anticipo una donna nel
codice categoria centrale d'emersione dipendeva spesso dalla sua 
posizione del marito o del padre. Molte donne, tuttavia, hanno 
scelto o sono state costrette a cercare l'indipendenza e l'autonomia 
nelle loro vite della famiglia e del lavoro. Anne Carson era una
tale persona. Con un padre alcolico e una madre timida, la sua 
condizione centrale in città port Filadelfia era sempre shaky. 
Ha assistito ad una delle prime accademie coeducational nella 
nuova nazione ma il suo padre disoccupato ha forzato il 15-year-old 
per sposare un capitano della nave 41-year-old. Il frequente 
abuso e le assenze del suo marito la hanno lasciata senza contributo 
finanziario ed Anne ha lavorato come seamstress ed ha aperto un 
negozio del china per sostenere i suoi genitori, i fratelli germani e 
quattro bambini. Ha realizzato il successo modesto, ma 
l'afflizione economica dopo la guerra di 1812 e la sua partecipazione 
ad un caso di omicidio la hanno trasmessa che si sviluppa a spirale 
nei underclass de Filadelfia. In uno sforzo guadagnare a soldi 
ha pubblicato il suo autobiography, in cui ha registrato la varietà 
di lavoro disponibile alle donne nelle città commerciali della 
Repubblica in anticipo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του δέκατου έννατου αιώνα μια γυναίκα στην
αναδυόμενη μέση κλάση εξαρτήθηκε συχνά από τη θέση της πατέρων
ή του συζύγου. Πολλές γυναίκες, εντούτοις, επέλεξαν ή 
αναγκάστηκαν να επιδιώξουν την ανεξαρτησία και την αυτονομία στις 
ζωές τους εργασίας και οικογενειών. Η Anne Carson ήταν
ένα τέτοιο άτομο. Με έναν οινοπνευματώδη πατέρα και μια 
συνεσταλμένη μητέρα, η μέση θέση της στην πόλη Φιλαδέλφεια 
λιμένων ήταν πάντα τρεμάμενη. Παρευρέθηκε σε μια από τις 
πρώτες μικτής εκπαίδευσης ακαδημίες στο νέο έθνος αλλά ο 
άνεργος πατέρας της ανάγκασε τον 15-χρονών για να 
παντρεψει έναν 41-χρονών καπετάνιο σκαφών. Η συχνές
κατάχρηση και οι απουσίες του συζύγου της την άφησαν χωρίς 
οικονομική ενίσχυση, και η Anne εργάστηκε ως seamstress και 
άνοιξε ένα κατάστημα της Κίνας για να υποστηρίξει τους γονείς 
της, αμφιθαλείς, και τέσσερα παιδιά. Επέτυχε τη μέτρια 
επιτυχία, αλλά ο οικονομικός κίνδυνος μετά από τον πόλεμο 
1812 και η συμμετοχή της σε μια περίπτωση δολοφονίας την 
έστειλαν που κινείται σπειροειδώς στον αδικημένο πληθυσμό της 
Φιλαδέλφειας. Σε μια προσπάθεια να κερδηθούν τα χρήματα 
δημοσίευσε την αυτοβιογραφία της, όπου κατέγραψε την ποικιλία της
εργασίας διαθέσιμη στις γυναίκες στις εμπορικές πόλεις της 
πρώτης Δημοκρατίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el diecinueveavo siglo temprano una mujer en la 
clase media que emergía era a menudo dependiente en su posición del 
padre o del marido. Muchas mujeres, sin embargo, eligieron o 
fueron forzadas para buscar independencia y la autonomía en sus vidas
del trabajo y de la familia. Anne Carson era una tal persona. 
Con un padre alcohólico y una madre tímida, su estatus medio 
en la ciudad portuaria Philadelphia era siempre inestable. Ella 
atendió a una de las primeras academias coeducacionales en la nueva 
nación pero su padre parado forzó el 15-year-old para casar a un 
capitán de la nave 41-year-old. El abuso frecuente y las 
ausencias de su marido la dejaron sin ayuda financiera, y Anne 
trabajó como costurera y abrió un departamento de China para apoyar 
a sus padres, a hermanos, y a cuatro niños. Ella alcanzó 
éxito modesto, pero la señal de socorro económica después de la 
guerra de 1812 y su implicación en un caso del asesinato la enviaron 
que torcía en espiral en los underclass de Philadelphia. En un 
esfuerzo de ganar a dinero la publicó su autobiografía, donde ella 
registró la variedad de trabajo disponible para las mujeres en las 
ciudades comerciales de la república temprana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086280</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104302</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-entered-into-business-with-hope-confidence-and-activity-ann-carson-becomes-an-independent-entrepreneur-ca-1810</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
