<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105008</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105008</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086952</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Happiest Laboring Class in the World": Two Virginia Slaveholders Debate Methods of Slave Management, 1837.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die glücklichste bearbeitenkategorie in der 
Welt": Zwei Virginia Slaveholders Debatte-Methoden 
Sklavenmanagements, 1837.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la classe travaillante la plus heureuse dans le 
monde" : Deux méthodes de discussion de la Virginie 
Slaveholders de gestion Slave, 1837.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a classe trabalhando a mais feliz no mundo": 
Dois métodos do debate de Virgínia Slaveholders da gerência 
slave, 1837.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il codice categoria lavorante più felice nel 
mondo": Due metodi di dibattito della Virginia Slaveholders 
della gestione slave, 1837.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η ευτυχέστερη κλάση εργασίας στον κόσμο": Δύο 
μέθοδοι συζήτησης της Βιρτζίνια Slaveholders διαχείρισης 
σκλάβων, 1837.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la clase que trabaja más feliz del mundo": 
Dos métodos del discusión de Virginia Slaveholders de la 
gerencia auxiliar, 1837.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">These two pieces appeared in the  Farmer's Register , a periodical of practical information for farmers, in 1837. Yet they go far beyond the simply practical to convey a great deal about the culture of slavery in the antebellum south--perhaps more than the authors intended. Two unnamed Virginia slaveholders debated the advantages and disadvantages of employing overseers; opined about the best types of food, housing, and clothing for slaves; and weighed the relative benefits of kindness and severity in their treatment of slaves. They also speculated about the characters of the enslaved African Americans they compelled to work for them. While these slaveholders confidently related their methods of control over their enslaved work force, their own words told quite another story about slaves' resistance through trickery and theft. And their insistence that slavery was a humane and necessary system was belied by their own descriptions of slaves who were ill, exhausted, and undernourished. Such innate contradictions weakened and ultimately damaged the institution of southern slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese zwei Stücke erschienen im Register des Landwirts, 
eine Zeitschrift der praktischen Informationen für Landwirte, 1837. 
Dennoch gehen sie über dem einfach praktischen hinaus weit, 
über die Kultur der Sklaverei im antebellum Süden -- möglicherweise
mehr als die beabsichtigten Autoren sehr viel zu übermitteln. 
Zwei namenlose Virginia slaveholders debattierten die Vorteile 
und die Nachteile der Beschäftigung der Aufseher; gemeint über
die besten Typen der Nahrung, des Gehäuses und der Kleidung für 
Sklaven; und gewogen dem relativen Nutzen der Freundlichkeit und
der Schwierigkeit in ihrer Behandlung der Sklaven. Sie 
spekulierten auch über die Zeichen der versklavten afrikanischen 
Amerikaner, die sie zwangen, um für sie zu bearbeiten. Während
diese slaveholders sicher ihre Methoden der Steuerung über ihrer 
versklavten Arbeit Kraft in Verbindung standen, erklärten ihre 
eigenen Wörter durchaus eine andere Geschichte über Widerstand der 
Sklaven durch Trickery und Diebstahl. Und ihre Beharrlichkeit, 
daß Sklaverei ein menschliches und notwendiges System war, wurde 
durch ihre eigenen Beschreibungen der Sklaven widerlegt, die krank 
waren, erschöpften und undernourished. Solche angeborene 
Widersprüche schwächten und beschädigten schließlich die Anstalt 
der südlichen Sklaverei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces deux morceaux sont apparus dans le registre du 
fermier, un périodique d'information pratique pour des fermiers, en 
1837. Pourtant ils vont lointains au delà simplement du 
pratique transporter beaucoup au sujet de la culture de l'esclavage 
dans les sud d'avant-guerre -- perhaps plus que les auteurs 
destinés. Deux slaveholders anonymes de la Virginie ont 
discuté les avantages et les inconvénients d'employer des 
contrôleurs ; été d'avis au sujet des meilleurs types de la 
nourriture, du logement, et d'habillement pour des esclaves ; et
pesé les avantages relatifs de la bonté et de la sévérité dans 
leur traitement des esclaves. Ils ont également speculé au 
sujet des caractères des Américains africains asservis qu'ils ont 
contraint pour travailler pour eux. Tandis que ces slaveholders 
associaient avec confiance leurs méthodes de contrôle de leur 
main-d'oeuvre asservie, leurs propres mots ont indiqué une tout à 
fait autre histoire au sujet de la résistance des esclaves par la 
supercherie et le vol. Et leur insistance que l'esclavage était 
un système humanitaire et nécessaire a été démontée par leurs 
propres descriptions des esclaves qui étaient malades, ont épuisé, 
et undernourished. De telles contradictions innées ont affaibli
et ont finalement endommagé l'établissement de l'esclavage 
méridional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estas duas partes apareceram no registo do fazendeiro, um 
periodical da informação prática para fazendeiros, em 1837. 
Contudo vão distante além do simplesmente prático fazer saber
bastante sobre a cultura do slavery no sul antebellum -- talvez mais 
do que os autores pretendidos. Dois slaveholders unnamed de 
Virgínia debateram as vantagens e as desvantagens de empregar 
overseers; opined sobre os mais melhores tipos de alimento, de 
carcaça, e de roupa para escravos; e pesado os benefícios 
relativos da bondade e da severidade em seu tratamento dos escravos. 
Speculated também sobre os caráteres dos americanos que 
africanos enslaved compeliram para trabalhar para eles. Quando 
estes slaveholders relacionaram confiàvel seus métodos do controle 
sobre sua força de trabalho enslaved, suas próprias palavras 
disseram uma completamente outra história sobre a resistência dos 
escravos com o trickery e o roubo. E seu insistence que o 
slavery era um sistema humano e necessário belied por suas próprias 
descrições dos escravos que eram doentes, esgotavam, e 
undernourished. Tais contradictions innate enfraqueceram e 
danificaram finalmente a instituição do slavery do sul.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Queste due parti sono comparso nel registro del 
coltivatore, un periodico delle informazioni pratiche per i 
coltivatori, in 1837. Tuttavia vanno lontane oltre semplicemente
il pratico trasportare molto circa la coltura di slavery nel sud 
antebellum -- forse più degli autori progettati. Due 
slaveholders non specificati della Virginia hanno dibattuto i vantaggi
e gli svantaggi di impiegare i overseers; opined circa i tipi 
migliori di alimento, di alloggiamento e di vestiti per gli schiavi; 
e pesato i benefici relativi di bontà e di severità nel loro 
trattamento degli schiavi. Egualmente hanno speculato circa i 
caratteri degli Americani che africani asserviti hanno costretto per 
lavorare per loro. Mentre questi slaveholders hanno collegato 
con confidenza i loro metodi di controllo sopra la loro forza di 
lavoro asservita, le loro proprie parole hanno detto ad un'abbastanza 
altra storia circa resistenza degli schiavi con trickery ed il furto. 
E la loro insistenza che lo slavery era un sistema umanitario e 
necessario belied dalle loro proprie descrizioni degli schiavi che 
erano malati, hanno esaurito ed undernourished. Tali 
contraddizioni innate hanno indebolito ed infine hanno danneggiato 
l'istituzione di slavery del sud.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτά τα δύο κομμάτια εμφανίστηκαν στον κατάλογο του 
αγρότη, ένα περιοδικό των πρακτικών πληροφοριών για τους 
αγρότες, σε 1837, Ακόμα πηγαίνουν αρκετά πέρα από απλά
τον πρακτικό να μεταβιβάσουν πολύ για τον πολιτισμό της σκλαβιάς 
στον προπολεμικό νότο -- ίσως περισσότερο από τους συντάκτες 
προορισμένους. Δύο απροσδιόριστος slaveholders της 
Βιρτζίνια συζήτησαν τα πλεονεκτήματα και τα μειονεκτήματα της 
υιοθέτησης των overseers  θεωρημένος για τους καλύτερους 
τύπους τροφίμων, κατοικιών, και ιματισμών για τους σκλάβους  
και σταθμισμένος τα σχετικά οφέλη της ευγένειας και της 
δριμύτητας στη μεταχείριση σκλάβων τους. Σκέφτηκαν επίσης 
για τους χαρακτήρες των υποδουλωμένων αφρικανικών Αμερικανών που 
ανάγκασαν για να λειτουργήσουν για τους. Ενώ αυτά τα 
slaveholders αφορούσαν με βεβαιότητα τις μεθόδους ελέγχου τους 
του υποδουλωμένου εργατικού δυναμικού τους, οι λέξεις τους είπαν 
αρκετά μια άλλη ιστορία για την αντίσταση των σκλάβων μέσω της 
πονηριάς και της κλοπής. Και η επιμονή τους ότι η σκλαβιά 
ήταν ένα ανθρωπιστικό και απαραίτητο σύστημα διαψεύδθηκε από 
τις περιγραφές σκλάβων τους που ήταν άρρωστοι, εξάντλησαν, και. 
Τέτοιες έμφυτες αντιφάσεις αποδυνάμωσαν και έβλαψαν τελικά
το όργανο της νότιας σκλαβιάς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estos dos pedazos aparecieron en el registro del granjero,
un periódico de la información práctica para los granjeros, en 
1837. Con todo van lejanos más allá del simplemente práctico 
a transportar mucho sobre la cultura de la esclavitud en el sur 
antebellum -- quizás más que los autores previstos. Dos 
slaveholders innomados de Virginia discutieron las ventajas y las 
desventajas de emplear a overseers; opined sobre los mejores 
tipos de alimento, de cubierta, y de ropa para los esclavos; y 
pesado las ventajas relativas de la amabilidad y de la severidad en su
tratamiento de esclavos. También especularon sobre los 
caracteres de los americanos africanos esclavizados que obligaron para
trabajar para ellos. Mientras que estos slaveholders 
relacionaron con confianza sus métodos de control sobre su fuerza de 
trabajo esclavizada, sus propias palabras contaron absolutamente otra 
historia sobre la resistencia de los esclavos con mañosidad y hurto. 
Y su insistencia que la esclavitud era un sistema humano y 
necesario belied por sus propias descripciones de los esclavos que 
eran enfermos, agotaron, y undernourished. Tales contradicciones
naturales debilitaron y dañaron en última instancia a institución 
de la esclavitud meridional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086952</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105008</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-happiest-laboring-class-in-the-world-two-virginia-slaveholders-debate-methods-of-slave-management-1837</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
