<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106264</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106264</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974115</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ayiti: The Cost of Life</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ayiti: Die Kosten des Lebens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ayiti : Le coût de la vie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ayiti: O custo da vida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ayiti: Il costo di vita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ayiti: Το κόστος της ζωής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayiti: El coste de vida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Help the Guinard family struggle to make ends meet and get ahead in their poverty-stricken homeland, Haiti. In this sometimes tragic and always challenging simulation game, you help the parents, Jean and Marie, and their children, Patrick, Jacqueline, and Yves, make decisions about work, education, community building, personal purchases, and health care that might brighten their future. Includes lesson plans for teachers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Helfen Sie der Guinard Familie zu kämpfen, um 
Enden Treffen zu bilden und voran in ihrer Armut-getroffenen Heimaten,
Haiti zu erhalten. In diesem manchmal tragischen und immer 
schwierigen Simulation Spiel helfen Sie den Eltern, Jean und Marie und
ihre Kinder, Patrick, Jacqueline und Yves, treffen Entscheidungen 
über Arbeit, Ausbildung, Gemeinschaftsgebäude, persönliche Erwerbe 
und Gesundheitspflege, die ihre Zukunft erhellen konnte. 
Schließt Lektionpläne für Lehrer ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aidez la famille de Guinard à lutter pour faire 
le rassemblement de fins et pour obtenir en avant dans leur patrie 
pauvreté-frappée, Haïti. Dans ce jeu parfois tragique et 
toujours provocant de simulation, vous aidez les parents, Jean et 
Marie, et leurs enfants, Patrick, Jacqueline, et Yves, prenez des 
décisions au sujet de travail, d'éducation, de bâtiment de la 
communauté, d'achats personnels, et de santé qui pourrait éclairer 
leur futur. Inclut des plans de leçon pour des professeurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ajude à família de Guinard esforçar-se para 
fazer a reunião dos fins e para começá-la adiante em seu homeland 
pobreza-golpeado, Haiti. Neste jogo às vezes trágico e sempre 
challenging da simulação, você ajuda aos pais, Jean e Marie, e seus
crianças, Patrick, Jacqueline, e Yves, faz decisões sobre o 
trabalho, a instrução, o edifício da comunidade, compras pessoais, 
e cuidado de saúde que pôde brighten seu futuro. Inclui 
plantas da lição para professores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Aiuti la famiglia di Guinard a lottare per fare il
raduno di conclusioni e per ottenere avanti nella loro patria 
povertà-impressionante, Haiti. In questo gioco a volte tragico 
e sempre challenging di simulazione, aiutate i genitori, Jean e Marie 
ed i loro bambini, Patrick, Jacqueline e Yves, prendete le decisioni 
circa lavoro, formazione, la costruzione della Comunità, gli acquisti
personali e la sanità che potrebbe illuminare il loro futuro. 
Include i programmi di lezione per gli insegnanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βοηθήστε την οικογενειακή Guinard προσπάθεια να 
γίνουν οι άκρες να συναντηθούν και να πάρουν μπροστά στην 
poverty-stricken πατρίδα τους, Αϊτή. Σε αυτό το μερικές 
φορές τραγικό και πάντα προκλητικό παιχνίδι προσομοίωσης, 
βοηθάτε τους γονείς, Jean και Marie, και τα παιδιά τους, 
Πάτρικ, Jacqueline, και Yves, λαμβάνει τις αποφάσεις για την 
εργασία, την εκπαίδευση, το κοινοτικό κτήριο, τις προσωπικές 
αγορές, και την υγειονομική περίθαλψη που να λαμπρύνουν το μέλλον
τους. Περιλαμβάνει τα σχέδια μαθήματος για τους δασκάλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayude a la familia de Guinard a luchar para hacer 
la reunión de los finales y para conseguir a continuación en su 
patria pobreza-pulso, Haití. En este juego a veces trágico y 
siempre desafiador de la simulación, usted ayuda a los padres, Jean y
Marie, y sus niños, Patrick, Jacqueline, y Yves, toma decisiones 
sobre trabajo, la educación, el edificio de la comunidad, compras 
personales, y el cuidado médico que pudo aclarar su futuro. 
Incluye los planes de la lección para los profesores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974115</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106264</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ayiti-the-cost-of-life</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
