<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104000</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104000</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086719</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Panic, as a health officer, sweeping the garbage out of Wall Street."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Panik, wie Gesundheit Offizier, den Abfall aus 
Wall Street heraus fegend."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"panique, comme un officier de santé, balayant 
les ordures hors de Wall Street."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"pânico, como um oficial da saúde, varrendo o 
lixo fora de Wall Street."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"panico, come ufficiale di salute, scopante 
l'immondizia da Wall Street."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πανικός, ως ανώτερο υπάλληλο υγείας, που σκουπίζει 
τα απορρίματα από Γουώλ Στρητ."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"pánico, como oficial de la salud, barriendo la 
basura fuera de Wall Street."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On September 19, 1873 the nation plunged into the longest and most severe economic depression up to that time. Thousands of businesses, large and small, went bankrupt, and the human toll was immense: fully a million workers were unemployed by 1874, and in some cities, unemployment levels reached 25 percent. The depression delivered a fatal blow to Reconstruction, as northern businessmen shifted their attention away from the rights of African Americans. It also nearly destroyed the labor movement, as pre-depression wage gains were erased and union membership plummeted. Despite the ghastly appearance of the figure representing financial panic, this  New York Daily Graphic  cover cartoon of September 29, 1873, subscribed to the belief that such financial busts" cleansed the economy</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An September 19, 1873 die Nation getaucht in die längste 
und meiste strenge Wirtschaftskrise bis zu dieser Zeit. 
Tausenden Geschäfte, groß und klein, machten Bankrott, und die
menschliche Abgabe war unermeßlich: völlig waren Million 
Arbeiter bis zum 1874 arbeitslos, und in einigen Städte, erreichten 
Arbeitslosigkeit Stufen 25 Prozent. Der Tiefstand lieferte einen
tödlichen Schlag an Rekonstruktion, da Nordgeschäftsmänner ihre 
Aufmerksamkeit weg von den Rechten der afrikanischen Amerikaner 
verschoben. Er auch zerstörte fast die Arbeiterbewegung, da 
Vortiefstand Lohngewinne gelöscht wurden und Anschlußmitgliedschaft 
absank. Trotz des gräßlichen Aussehens der Abbildung, die 
finanzielle Panik, diese New York tägliche graphische 
Abdeckungkarikatur von September 29, 1873, unterzeichnet zum Glauben 
darstellt, daß solche finanzielle Büsten "die Wirtschaft reinigten</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">19 septembre 1873 la nation plongée dans plus longue et 
la plupart grave de dépression économique jusqu'à ce temps. 
Les milliers d'entreprises, grand et petit, ont fait faillite, 
et le péage humain était immense : entièrement million 
d'ouvriers étaient sans emploi d'ici 1874, et dans quelques villes, 
les niveaux du chômage ont atteint 25 pour cent. La dépression
a livré un coup mortel à la reconstruction, car les hommes 
d'affaires nordiques ont décalé leur attention loin des droites des 
Américains africains. Elle également a presque détruit le 
mouvement de travail, car des gains salariaux de pré-dépression ont 
été effacés et adhésion des syndicats descendaient. En 
dépit de l'aspect horrible de la figure représentant la panique 
financière, ce nouveau dessin animé graphique quotidien de 
couverture d'York septembre de 29, 1873, souscrit à la croyance que 
de tels bustes financiers "ont nettoyé l'économie</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em setembro 19, 1873 a nação mergulhada em de depression
econômico o mais longo e a maioria severo até esse tempo. Os 
milhares dos negócios, grande e pequeno, foram falidos, e o pedágio 
humano era immense: inteiramente milhão trabalhadores eram 
unemployed por 1874, e em algumas cidades, os níveis do desemprego 
alcançaram 25 por cento. O depression entregou um sopro fatal 
ao reconstruction, porque os homens de negócios do norte deslocaram 
sua atenção away das direitas de americanos africanos. Também
destruiu quase o movimento labor, porque os ganhos de salário do 
pre-pre-depression foram apagados e sociedade da união plummeted. 
Apesar da aparência ghastly da figura que representa o pânico 
financeiro, este cartoon gráfico diário da tampa de New York 
setembro de 29, 1873, subscrito à opinião que tais bustos 
financeiros "cleansed a economia</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Su settembri 19, 1873 la nazione immersa della nella 
depressione economica più lunga e maggior parte severa fino a quel 
tempo. Le migliaia dei commerci, grande e piccolo, hanno fallito
ed il tributo umano era immenso: completamente milione operai 
erano disoccupati entro 1874 ed in alcune città, i livelli di 
disoccupazione hanno raggiunto 25 per cento. La depressione ha 
trasportato un colpo mortale a ricostruzione, poichè gli uomini 
d'affari nordici hanno spostato la loro attenzione via dai diritti 
degli Americani africani. Egualmente quasi ha distrutto 
il movimento di lavoro, poichè i guadagni di stipendio di 
pre-depressione sono stati cancellati ed insieme dei membri del 
sindacato è disceso. Malgrado l'apparenza ghastly della figura 
che rappresenta panico finanziario, questo fumetto grafico quotidiano 
della copertura de New York de 29 settembre 1873, abbonato alla 
credenza che tali busti finanziari "hanno pulito l'economia</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 19 Σεπτεμβρίου ..1873 το έθνος που βυθίζεται
στην πιό μακροχρόνια και πιό βαριά οικονομική ύφεση μέχρι 
εκείνο τον χρόνο. Χιλιάδες επιχειρήσεις, μεγάλος και 
μικρός, χρεωκόπησαν, και ο ανθρώπινος φόρος ήταν απέραντος: 
πλήρως εκατομμύριο εργαζόμενοι ήταν άνεργοι από 1874, 
και σε μερικές πόλεις, τα επίπεδα ανεργίας έφθασαν σε 25 τοις 
εκατό. Η κατάθλιψη παρέδωσε ένα μοιραίο χτύπημα στην 
αναδημιουργία, καθώς οι βόρειοι επιχειρηματίες μετατόπισαν την 
προσοχή τους μακρυά από τα δικαιώματα αφρικανικών Αμερικανών. 
Επίσης σχεδόν κατέστρεψε τη μετακίνηση εργασίας, καθώς τα 
κέρδη αμοιβών προ-κατάθλιψης σβήθηκαν και η ιδιότητα μέλους 
ένωσης έπεσε κατακόρυφα. Παρά την τρομακτική εμφάνιση του 
αριθμού που αντιπροσωπεύει τον οικονομικό πανικό, αυτά τα 
κινούμενα σχέδια κάλυψης της Νέας Υόρκης καθημερινά γραφικά της
29ης Σεπτεμβρίου ..1873, που προσυπογράφονται στην πεποίθηση 
ότι τέτοιες οικονομικές αποτυχίες "καθάρισαν την οικονομία</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De septiembre el 19, 1873 la nación hundida en de la 
depresión económica más larga y la mayoría severa hasta ese 
tiempo. Los millares de negocios, grande y pequeño, arruinaban,
y el peaje humano era inmenso: millón de trabajadores estaban 
completamente parados antes de 1874, y en algunas ciudades, los 
niveles del desempleo alcanzaron 25 por ciento. La depresión 
entregó un soplo fatal a la reconstrucción, pues los hombres de 
negocios norteños cambiaron de puesto su atención lejos de las 
derechas de americanos africanos. También destruyó casi el 
movimiento de trabajo, pues los aumentos de salario de la 
pre-depresio'n fueron borrados y calidad de miembro cayó a plomo de 
la unión. A pesar de el aspecto horroroso de la figura que 
representa pánico financiero, esta historieta gráfica diaria de la 
cubierta de Nueva York del de septiembre 29 de 1873, suscrita a la 
creencia que tales bustos financieros "limpiaron la economía</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086719</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104000</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/panic-as-a-health-officer-sweeping-the-garbage-out-of-wall-street</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
