<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105179</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105179</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086098</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Don't Smoke--Unless You Like It": A 1950 Case Against Antismoking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Rauchen Sie Nicht -- Es sei denn Sie Es" Mögen: 
Ein Argument 1950 Gegen Antismoking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ne fumez pas -- À moins que Vous Les aimez" : 
Un Point de droit 1950 Contre Antismoking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Não fume -- A menos que Você Gosta D": Um
Argumento 1950 De encontro A Antismoking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non fumi -- A meno che Lo gradiate": Un 
Argomento 1950 Contro Antismoking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μην καπνίστε -- εκτός αν τον συμπαθείτε": Μια 
περίπτωση του 1950 ενάντια σε αντικαπνιστικό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No fume -- A menos que Usted Tiene gusto De Él":
Un Caso 1950 En contra De Antismoking</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Tobacco was promoted in Europe in the 17th century as a cure for a number of ailments, including toothache, fatigue, and joint pains, as well as a calming agent. Smoking for enjoyment, however, was mainly responsible for the growth of the tobacco industry. By the time the following  Collier's  article was published in 1950, a campaign to warn smokers--who by then made up more than half of the American population--of potential dangerous effects of smoking was underway. Opposed to these efforts, the author argued that scientific attempts to link tobacco products to lung cancer and heart disease had failed and that the antismoking crusade interfered with needed research into more likely cancer causes. In 1951, an important medical study in London concluded that smoking was "an important factor" contributing to lung cancer. Despite a growing antismoking movement, aided by a 1979 Surgeon-General's report linking smoking to heart disease and the classification of nicotine as an addictive drug by the Food and Drug Administration in 1995, over five trillion cigarettes were sold that year. Threatened with state and local class-action lawsuits, the U.S. tobacco industry agreed in 1998 to a consent decree that settled 37 pending cases, quieted future claims, and ended certain types of tobacco advertising.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tabak wurde in Europa im 17. Jahrhundert wie eine 
Heilung für eine Anzahl von Unpäßlichkeiten, einschließlich 
toothache, Ermüdung und die gemeinsamen Schmerz, sowie ein 
beruhigendes Mittel gefördert. Das Rauchen für Genuß war 
jedoch für das Wachstum der Tabakindustrie hauptsächlich 
verantwortlich. Bis der folgenden Artikel des Colliers 1950 
veröffentlicht wurde, war eine Kampagne, zum der Raucher -- wer mehr 
bis dahin als Hälfte der amerikanischen Bevölkerung bildeten -- der 
möglichen gefährlichen Effekte des Rauchens zu warnen unterwegs. 
Entgegengesetzt diesen Bemühungen, argumentierte der Autor, 
daß wissenschaftliche Versuche, Tabakprodukte mit Lungenkrebs und 
Innerer Krankheit zu binden ausgefallen waren und daß der antismoking
Kreuzzug erforderliche Forschung in wahrscheinlichere Krebsursachen 
behinderte. 1951 stellte eine wichtige medizinische Studie in 
London fest, daß das Rauchen "ein wichtiger Faktor war", der zum 
Lungenkrebs beiträgt. Trotz einer wachsenden antismoking 
Bewegung geholfen durch einen Chirurg-Allgemeinen Report 1979 wurden 
die Bindung des Rauchens zur Inneren Krankheit und der Klassifikation 
des Nikotins als süchtig machende Droge durch die Nahrungsmittel-und 
Droge-Leitung 1995, über fünf Zigaretten Trillion verkauft, die 
Jahr. Bedroht mit Zustand und lokalen Kategorie-Tätigkeit 
Prozessen, stimmte die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Tabakindustrie 1998 einem 
Anerkenntnisurteil daß vereinbarte 37 während Fälle, beruhigte 
Zukunftansprüche und beendete bestimmte Typen des Tabakbekanntmachens
zu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Du tabac a été favorisé en Europe au 17ème 
siècle comme un traitement pour un certain nombre de maux, y compris 
le mal de dents, la fatigue, et les douleurs communes, aussi bien qu'un 
agent calmant. Le tabagisme pour le plaisir, cependant, était 
principalement responsable de la croissance de l'industrie de tabac. 
Avant que l'article suivant de Collier ait été édité en 
1950, une campagne pour avertir les fumeurs -- qui ont d'ici là 
composé plus que la moitié de la population américaine -- des 
effets dangereux potentiels du tabagisme était en cours. 
Opposé à ces efforts, l'auteur a argué du fait que les 
tentatives scientifiques de joindre des produits de tabac au cancer de
poumon et à la maladie de coeur avaient échoué et que la croisade 
antismoking a gêné la recherche nécessaire dans des causes plus 
probables de cancer. En 1951, une étude médicale importante à
Londres a conclu que le tabagisme était "un facteur important" 
contribuant au cancer de poumon. En dépit d'un mouvement 
antismoking croissant, facilité par un état 1979 
Chirurgien-Général on a vendu joindre le tabagisme à la maladie de 
coeur et la classification de la nicotine comme drogue provoquant une 
dépendance par la gestion de nourriture et de drogue en 1995, plus de
cinq cigarettes trillion qui année. Menacé par l'état et les 
procès locaux de classe-action, l'industrie de tabac des ETATS-UNIS a
convenu en 1998 un décret de consentement que 37 arrangés en 
attendant des cas, des réclamations apaisées de futur, et certains 
types terminés de publicité de tabac.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O tabaco foi promovido em Europa no 17o século 
como uma cura para um número de ailments, including o toothache, a 
fatiga, e dores comuns, as.well.as um agente se acalmando. Fumar
para a apreciação, entretanto, era principalmente responsável para 
o crescimento da indústria do tabaco. O artigo pelo tempo do 
seguinte collier foi publicado em 1950, uma campanha para advertir que
os smokers -- quem perto compuseram então mais do que a metade da 
população americana -- de efeitos perigosos potenciais de fumar eram
underway. Oposto a estes esforços, o autor discutiu que as 
tentativas científicas de ligar produtos do tabaco ao cancer de 
pulmão e à doença de coração tinham falhado e que o crusade 
antismoking interferiu com a pesquisa needed em umas causas mais 
prováveis do cancer. Em 1951, um estudo médico importante em 
Londres concliu que fumar era "um fator importante" que contribui ao 
cancer de pulmão. Apesar de um movimento antismoking crescente,
ajudado por um relatório 1979 Cirurgião-Geral ligar fumar à doença
de coração e a classificação do nicotine como uma droga addictive 
pela administração do alimento e da droga em 1995, sobre cinco 
cigarros trillion foi vendido que ano. Ameaçado com o estado e 
os lawsuits locais da classe-ação, a indústria do tabaco de ESTADOS
UNIDOS concordou em 1998 a um decree de consentimento que 37 
estabelecidos durante casos, reivindicações quieted do futuro, e 
determinados tipos terminados de anunciar do tabaco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il tabacco è stato promosso in Europa nel 
diciassettesimo secolo come una cura per un certo numero di ailments, 
compreso toothache, affaticamento e dolori uniti, così come un agente
calmantesi. Fumando per il godimento, tuttavia, era 
pricipalmente responsabile dello sviluppo dell'industria del tabacco. 
Per il momento in cui l'articolo del seguente collier sia 
pubblicato in 1950, una campagna per avvertire i fumatori -- chi per 
allora hanno composto più della metà della popolazione americana -- 
degli effetti pericolosi potenziali di fumare era in corso. 
Opposto a questi sforzi, l'autore ha sostenuto che scientifici 
collegare i prodotti del tabacco al cancro polmonare ed alla malattia 
di cuore avevano fallito e che il crusade antismoking ha interferito 
con ricerca necessaria sulle cause più probabili del cancro. In
1951, uno studio medico importante a Londra ha concluso che fumare era
"un fattore importante" che contribuisce al cancro polmonare. 
Malgrado un movimento antismoking crescente, aiutato da un 
rapporto Chirurgo-Generale 1979 collegare fumare alla malattia di 
cuore e la classificazione di nicotina come droga addictive tramite la
gestione della droga e dell'alimento in 1995, oltre cinque sigarette 
trilione è stato venduto che anno. Minacciato per 
dichiari e le cause locali di codice categoria-azione, 
l'industria del tabacco degli STATI UNITI accosentita in 1998 ad 
un decreto di consenso che ha depositato 37 pending i casi, hanno 
acquietato i reclami futuri e determinati tipi conclusi di pubblicità
del tabacco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο καπνός προήχθη στην Ευρώπη στο 17$ο αιώνα ως 
θεραπεία για διάφορες ασθένειες, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του 
πονόδοντου, της κούρασης, και των κοινών πόνων, καθώς επίσης και
ενός ηρεμώντας πράκτορα. Καπνίζοντας για την απόλαυση, 
εντούτοις, ήταν κυρίως αρμόδιος για την αύξηση της βιομηχανίας 
καπνών. Ώσπου να δημοσιεύθηκε το άρθρο του ακόλουθου 
ανθρακωρύχου το 1950, μια εκστρατεία για να προειδοποιήσει τους 
καπνιστές -- ποιοι αποτέλεσαν έως τότε περισσότερο από το μισό 
από τον αμερικανικό πληθυσμό -- για τα πιθανά επικίνδυνα 
αποτελέσματα του καπνίσματος ήταν εν εξελίξει. Αντιταγμένος
σε αυτές τις προσπάθειες, ο συντάκτης υποστήριξε ότι οι 
επιστημονικές προσπάθειες να συνδεθούν τα προϊόντα καπνού με τον
καρκίνο πνευμόνων και τις καρδιακές παθήσεις είχαν αποτύχει και 
ότι η αντικαπνιστική σταυροφορία παρεμπόδισε την αναγκαία έρευνα
στις πιθανότερες αιτίες καρκίνου. Το 1951, μια σημαντική 
ιατρική μελέτη στο Λονδίνο κατέληξε στο συμπέρασμα ότι το 
κάπνισμα ήταν "ένας σημαντικός παράγοντασ" συμβάλλοντας στον 
καρκίνο πνευμόνων. Παρά μια αυξανόμενη αντικαπνιστική 
μετακίνηση, που βοηθήθηκε από τη σύνδεση εκθέσεων ενός του 
1979 χειρούργος-στρατηγού που καπνίζουν στις καρδιακές 
παθήσεις και την ταξινόμηση της νικοτίνης ως εθιστικό φάρμακο 
από τη διοίκηση τροφίμων και φαρμάκων το 1995, πάνω από τα 
τσιγάρα πέντε τρισεκατομμύρια πωλήθηκαν που έτος. 
Απειλητική με το κράτος και τις τοπικές class-action 
δίκες, η βιομηχανία ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ καπνών συμφώνησε το 1998 με 
ένα διάταγμα συγκατάθεσης ότι εγκατεστημένος 37 εκκρεμείς 
περιπτώσεις, οι μελλοντικές αξιώσεις, και τελείωσε ορισμένους 
τύπους διαφημίσεων καπνών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El tabaco fue promovido en Europa en el 17mo siglo
como una curación para un número de dolencias, incluyendo toothache,
fatiga, y dolores comunes, así como un agente que calmaba. El 
fumar para el disfrute, sin embargo, era principalmente responsable 
del crecimiento de la industria del tabaco. Para el momento en 
que el artículo del collier siguiente fuera publicado en 1950, una 
campaña para advertir a los fumadores -- quiénes para entonces 
compusieron más que la mitad de la población americana -- de efectos
peligrosos potenciales de fumar estaba en curso. Opuesto a estos
esfuerzos, el autor discutió que las tentativas científicas de 
conectar productos del tabaco al cáncer de pulmón y a la enfermedad 
cardíaca hubieran fallado y que la cruzada antismoking interfirió
con la investigación necesaria en causas más probables del cáncer. 
En 1951, un estudio médico importante en Londres concluyó que 
el fumar era "un factor importante" que contribuía al cáncer de 
pulmón. A pesar de un movimiento antismoking cada vez mayor, 
ayudado por un informe Cirujano-General 1979 la conexión de fumar a 
la enfermedad cardíaca y de la clasificación de la nicotina como 
droga adictiva por la administración del alimento y de la droga en 
1995, sobre cinco cigarrillos trillón fue vendida que año. 
Amenazado con el estado y pleitos locales de la clase-accio'n, 
la industria del tabaco de ESTADOS UNIDOS convino en 1998 un decreto 
de consentimiento que 37 colocados hasta que finalicen casos, demandas
calladas del futuro, y ciertos tipos terminados de publicidad del 
tabaco.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086098</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105179</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dont-smoke-unless-you-like-it-a-1950-case-against-antismoking</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
