<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104529</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104529</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207089</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Courts to Classes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerichte zu den Kategorien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cours aux classes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cortes às classes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Corti ai codici categoria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δικαστήρια στις κλάσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cortes a las clases</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students learn about the federal court system. Teachers can use the site to connect court-related issues to students' everyday lives. Visitors can learn about the Open Doors of Justice Program, use a lesson plan on the differences between civil and criminal cases, participate in a mini-moot court, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer erlernen über das 
Bundesgerichtshofsystem. Lehrer können die Site benutzen, um 
Gericht-in Verbindung stehende Ausgaben an tägliche Lebensdauern der 
Kursteilnehmer anzuschließen. Besucher können über die 
geöffneten Türen des Gerechtigkeit-Programms erlernen, verwenden 
einen Lektionplan auf den Unterschieden zwischen Zivil- und 
kriminellen Fällen, nehmen Sie an einem Mini-strittigen Gericht und 
mehr teil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les étudiants d'aides se renseignent sur le 
système de cour fédérale. Les professeurs peuvent employer le
site pour relier les issues cour-connexes aux vies journalières des 
étudiants. Les visiteurs peuvent se renseigner sur les portes 
ouvertes du programme de justice, utilisent un plan de leçon sur les 
différences entre civil et les cas criminels, participez à une cour 
mini-discutable, et davantage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os estudantes das ajudas aprendem sobre o sistema 
de corte federal. Os professores podem usar o local conectar 
edições corte-relacionadas às vidas diárias dos estudantes. 
Os visitantes podem aprender sobre as portas abertas do programa
da justiça, usam uma planta da lição nas diferenças entre civil e 
casos criminal, participe em uma corte mini-mini-moot, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli allievi di aiuti imparano circa il sistema di 
corte federale. Gli insegnanti possono usare il luogo per 
collegare le edizioni corte-relative alle vite giornalieri degli 
allievi. Gli ospiti possono imparare circa i portelli aperti del
programma della giustizia, usano un programma di lezione sulle 
differenze fra civile ed i casi criminali, partecipi ad una corte 
mini-discutibile e di più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να μάθουν για το ομοσπονδιακό 
σύστημα δικαστηρίων. Οι δάσκαλοι μπορούν να χρησιμοποιήσουν
την περιοχή για να συνδέσουν τα δικαστήριο-σχετικά με το ζητήματα
με τις καθημερινές ζωές των σπουδαστών. Οι επισκέπτες 
μπορούν να μάθουν για τις ανοικτές πόρτες του προγράμματος 
δικαιοσύνης, να χρησιμοποιήσουν ένα σχέδιο μαθήματος για τις 
διαφορές μεταξύ των αστικών και εγκληματικών υποθέσεων, να 
συμμετέχει σε ένα μίνι-αμφισψητήσιμο δικαστήριο, και 
περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los estudiantes de las ayudas aprenden sobre el 
sistema judicial federal. Los profesores pueden utilizar el 
sitio para conectar ediciones corte-relacionadas con las vidas diarias
de los estudiantes. Los visitantes pueden aprender sobre las 
puertas abiertas del programa de la justicia, utilizan un plan de la 
lección en las diferencias entre civil y los casos criminales, 
participe en una corte mini-discutible, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207089</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104529</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/courts-to-classes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
