<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106305</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106305</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206043</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Water Cycle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Wasser-Schleife</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Cycle de l'Eau</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Ciclo Da Água</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Ciclo Dell'Acqua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο κύκλος ύδατος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Ciclo Del Agua</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the movement of water across (and below and above) earth's surface. Among the topics: condensation, evaporation, freshwater storage, ground-water storage and discharge, infiltration, precipitation, snowmelt runoff to streams, springs, streamflow, surface runoff, transpiration, water in the atmosphere, ice and snow, and oceans. A diagram and text summarizing the water cycle are available in more than 30 languages.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft die Bewegung des Wassers über (und 
unten und oben) Oberfläche der Masse. Unter den Themen: 
Kondensation, Verdampfung, Frischwasserspeicherung, 
Grundwasserspeicher und -entladung, Infiltration, Niederschlag, 
snowmelt Abfluß zu den Strömen, Frühlinge, streamflow, 
Oberflächenabfluß, Transpiration, Wasser in der Atmosphäre, Eis und
Schnee und Ozeane. Ein Diagramm und ein Text, welche die 
Wasserschleife zusammenfaßt, sind in mehr als 30 Sprachen vorhanden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine le mouvement de l'eau à travers (et 
ci-dessous et ci-dessus) la surface de la terre. Parmi les 
sujets : condensation, évaporation, mémoire d'eau douce, 
mémoire et décharge de ground-water, infiltration, précipitation, 
écoulement de snowmelt aux jets, ressorts, streamflow, eaux de 
surface , transpiration, eau dans l'atmosphère, glace et neige, et 
océans. Un diagramme et un texte récapitulant le cycle de 
l'eau sont disponibles dans plus de 30 langages.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina o movimento da água através (e abaixo e 
acima) da superfície da terra. Entre os tópicos: 
condensação, evaporação, armazenamento freshwater, 
armazenamento e descarga do ground-water, infiltration, 
precipitação, runoff do snowmelt aos córregos, molas, streamflow, 
runoff de superfície, transpiration, água na atmosfera, gelo e neve,
e oceanos. Um diagrama e um texto que sumariam o ciclo da água 
estão disponíveis em mais de 30 línguas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina il movimento di acqua attraverso (e sotto 
e sopra) la superficie della terra. Fra i soggetti: 
condensazione, evaporazione, memoria d'acqua dolce, memoria e 
scarico del ground-water, infiltrazione, precipitazione, scolo dello 
snowmelt ai flussi, molle, streamflow, acque di superficie, 
traspirazione, acqua nell'atmosfera, ghiaccio e neve ed oceani. 
Uno schema e un testo che ricapitolano il ciclo dell'acqua sono 
disponibili in più di 30 linguaggi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τη μετακίνηση του ύδατος πέρα από (και 
κατωτέρω και ανωτέρω) τη γήινη επιφάνεια. Μεταξύ των 
θεμάτων: συμπύκνωση, εξάτμιση, του γλυκού νερού 
αποθήκευση, αποθήκευση και απαλλαγή υπόγειων νερών, διήθηση, 
πτώση, snowmelt απορροή στα ρεύματα, τα ελατήρια, 
streamflow, την απορροή επιφάνειας, την εφίδρωση, το ύδωρ στην 
ατμόσφαιρα, τον πάγο και το χιόνι, και τους ωκεανούς. Ένα 
διάγραμμα και ένα κείμενο που συνοψίζουν τον κύκλο ύδατος είναι
διαθέσιμα σε περισσότερες από 30 γλώσσες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina el movimiento del agua a través (y abajo 
y arriba) de la superficie de la tierra. Entre los asuntos: 
condensación, evaporación, almacenaje de agua dulce, 
almacenaje y descarga del ground-water, infiltración, precipitación,
salida del snowmelt a las secuencias, resortes, streamflow, salida 
superficial, transpiración, agua en la atmósfera, hielo y nieve, y 
océanos. Un diagrama y un texto que resumen el ciclo del agua 
están disponibles en más de 30 lenguajes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206043</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106305</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-water-cycle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
