<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086748</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Plugging the Leaks: A Specialist Spies on Union Activities</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einstecken der Leckstellen: Ein Fachmann 
spioniert auf Anschluß-Aktivitäten aus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Branchement des fuites : Un spécialiste 
remarque sur des activités des syndicats</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Plugging os escapes: Um specialist espía em
atividades da união</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tappo delle perdite: Un esperto spia sulle 
attività del sindacato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύνδεση των διαρροών: Ένας ειδικός κατασκοπεύει
στις δραστηριότητες ένωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tapar los escapes: Un especialista espía en
actividades de la unión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the earliest years of the 20th century, employers mounted organized campaigns to break the power of labor unions. The employers had a broad array of tactics, including blacklists, strikebreakers, and court injunctions against strikers' use of boycotts and sympathy strikes. From 1900 to 1920, 775 injunctions were issued against labor activities. Between 1880 and 1900, there had been only 150. Although early twentieth-century employers had reliable allies in state police forces and tightly controlled local police, they continued to hire their own private police--detective agencies that used secret operatives to disrupt unions and supplied thugs to protect strikebreakers during strikes. F. J. Heine, general manager of the Employers' Information Service in Cleveland, Ohio, explained his strike-breaking services to prospective clients in this 1911 letter.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die frühen Jahre des 20. Jahrhunderts, hingen 
Arbeitgeber organisierte Kampagnen ein, um die Energie der 
Arbeiterverbände einzulaufen. Die Arbeitgeber hatten eine 
ausgedehnte Reihe Taktiken, einschließlich schwarze Listen, 
Streikbrecher und Gerichtinjunktionen gegen Gebrauch der Schlaggeräte
von Boykotts und Sympathieschlägen. Von 1900 bis 1920, wurden 
775 Injunktionen gegen Arbeitsaktivitäten herausgegeben. 
Zwischen 1880 und 1900 hatte es nur 150 gegeben. Obgleich 
frühe Zwanzigstjahrhundert Arbeitgeber zuverlässige Verbündete im 
Zustand polizeilich überwachen Kräfte hatten und fest gesteuerte 
lokale Polizei, fuhren sie fort, ihre eigene private Polizei 
anzustellen -- Detektivbüros, die geheime Arbeiter verwendeten, um 
Anschlüße zu stören und Schurkeen angaben, um Streikbrecher 
während der Schläge zu schützen. F. J. Heine, Generaldirektor
des Informationsdienstes der Arbeitgeber in Cleveland, Ohio, erklärte
seine Strike-breakingdienstleistungen zukünftigen Klienten in diesem 
Zeichen 1911.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En premières années du 20ème siècle, les 
employeurs ont organisé des campagnes organisées pour casser la 
puissance des syndicats. Les employeurs ont eu un large choix de
la tactique, y compris des listes noires, de briseurs de grève, et 
d'injonctions de cour contre l'utilisation des butées des boycotts et
des grèves de sympathie de solidarité. De 1900 à 1920, 775 
injonctions ont été émises contre des activités de travail. 
Entre 1880 et 1900, il y avait eu seulement de 150. Bien 
que les premiers employeurs de vingtième-siècle aient eu les alliés
dignes de confiance dans l'état maintiennent l'ordre des forces et 
police locale étroitement commandée, ils ont continué à louer leur
propre police privée -- les agences de détectives qui ont utilisé 
les employés secrets pour perturber des syndicats et ont fourni des 
gangsters pour protéger des briseurs de grève pendant les grèves. 
F. J. Heine, directeur général du service d'information des 
employeurs à Cleveland, Ohio, a expliqué ses services de refus de 
faire grève aux clients éventuels dans cette lettre 1911.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos anos os mais adiantados do 20o século, os 
empregadores montaram campanhas organizadas para quebrar a potência 
de uniões labor. Os empregadores tiveram uma disposição larga
das táticas, including listas negras, dos strikebreakers, e dos 
injunctions da corte de encontro ao uso dos grevistas dos boycotts e 
das batidas de sympathy. 1900 a 1920, 775 injunctions foram 
emitidos de encontro às atividades labor. Entre 1880 e 1900, 
tinha havido somente 150. Embora os empregadores adiantados de 
vigésimo-século tivessem aliados de confiança no estado policiassem
forças e polícias locais firmemente controladas, continuaram a 
empregar suas próprias polícias confidenciais -- as agências 
detective que usaram operatives secretos disrupt uniões e forneceram 
thugs para proteger strikebreakers durante batidas. F. J. Heine,
gerente geral do serviço de informação dos empregadores em 
Cleveland, Ohio, explicou seus serviços do strike-breaking aos 
clientes em perspectiva nesta letra 1911.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante i primi anni del ventesimo secolo, i 
datori di lavoro hanno organizzato le campagne organizzate per rompere
l'potenza dei sindacati di lavoro. I datori di lavoro hanno 
avuti un vasto allineamento delle tattiche, compreso le liste nere, 
dei crumiri e delle ingiunzioni della corte contro uso dei percussori 
dei boicottaggi e dei colpi di compassione. 1900 - 1920, 775 
ingiunzioni si sono pubblicate contro le attività di lavoro. 
Fra 1880 e 1900, ci erano stati soltanto 150. Anche se i 
datori di lavoro in anticipo di ventesimo-secolo hanno fatti 
dichiarare agli alleati certi dentro le forze della polizia e la
polizia locale strettamente gestita, hanno continuato ad assumere la 
loro propria polizia riservata -- agenzie detective che hanno usato 
gli operatori segreti per interrompere i sindacati ed hanno fornito i 
thugs per proteggere i crumiri durante i colpi. F. J. Heine, 
direttore generale del servizio d'informazione dei datori di lavoro a 
Cleveland, Ohio, ha spiegato i suoi servizi di strike-breaking ai 
futuri clienti in questa lettera 1911.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα πιό πρώτα έτη του 20ού αιώνα, οι εργοδότες 
επικόλλησαν τις οργανωμένες εκστρατείες για να σπάσουν τη δύναμη 
των εργατικών συνδικάτων. Οι εργοδότες είχαν μια ευρεία 
σειρά τακτικής, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των μαύρων λιστών, 
strikebreakers, και των εντολών δικαστηρίων ενάντια στη χρήση 
των απεργών των μποϊκοταρισμάτων και των απεργιών συμπόνοιας. 
Από το 1900 ως το 1920 ..775 εντολές εκδόθηκαν 
ενάντια στις δραστηριότητες εργασίας. Μεταξύ 1880 και 
1900, είχαν υπάρξει μόνο 150. Αν και οι πρώτοι 
εργοδότες εικοστός-αιώνα είχαν τους αξιόπιστους συμμάχους στις 
δυνάμεις κρατικής αστυνομίας και τη στενά ελεγχόμενη τοπική 
αστυνομία, συνέχισαν να μισθώνουν την ιδιωτική αστυνομία τους -- 
αντιπροσωπείες ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών που χρησιμοποίησαν τους 
μυστικούς χειριστές για να αναστατώσουν τις ενώσεις και παρείχαν 
τους κακοποιούς για να προστατεύσουν strikebreakers κατά τη 
διάρκεια των απεργιών. Φ. Θ*ι. Heine, γενικός διευθυντής 
της υπηρεσίας πληροφοριών των εργοδοτών στο Κλήβελαντ, Οχάιο, 
εξήγησε στις απεργία-σπάζοντας υπηρεσίες του στους ενδεχόμενους 
χρήστες σε αυτήν την επιστολή του 1911.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años del vigésimo siglo, los patrones 
montaron campañas ordenadas para romper la potencia de sindicatos. 
Los patrones tenían un amplio arsenal de táctica, incluyendo 
listas negras, de rompehuelgas, y de prescripciones de la corte contra
el uso de los huelguistas de boicoteos y de huelgas de condolencia. 
A partir la 1900 a 1920, 775 prescripciones fueron publicadas 
contra actividades de trabajo. Entre 1880 y 1900, había habido 
solamente 150. Aunque los patrones tempranos del vige'simo-siglo
tenían aliados confiables en estado limpian fuerzas y policía local 
firmemente controlado, continuaron empleando a su propio policía 
privado -- las agencias detectives que utilizaron a operarios secretos
para interrumpir uniones y proveieron a gamberros para proteger a 
rompehuelgas durante huelgas. F. J. Heine, director general del 
servicio informativo de los patrones en Cleveland, Ohio, explicó sus 
servicios del strike-breaking a los clientes anticipados en esta carta
1911.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086748</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106864</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/plugging-the-leaks-a-specialist-spies-on-union-activities</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
