<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106133</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106133</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086832</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Sir I Will Thank You with All My Heart":  Seven Letters from the Great Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sir I Will Thank You mit meinem ganzem Inneren": 
Sieben Zeichen von der großen Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"monsieur I Will Thank You avec tout mon coeur" : 
Sept lettres du grand transfert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"senhor Eu  Agradecer Você com todo meu 
coração": Sete letras da migração grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sir I Will Thank You con tutto il mio cuore": 
Sette lettere dall'espansione grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο Sir I Will Thank You με όλη την καρδιά
μου": Επτά επιστολές από τη μεγάλη μετανάστευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"sir I Will Thank You con todo mi corazón": 
Siete cartas de la gran migración</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Between 1916 and 1921 a half million African Americans left the South and journeyed to cities in the North and West in what was then the largest internal movement of a people in such a concentrated period of time in the history of the nation. Migrants' letters to northern newspapers were among the best and most voluminous sources for understanding the migration process and interpreting the migrants' motivations for leaving. Seven letters to the Chicago  Defender -- a black newspaper published in Chicago that strongly urged southern blacks to migrate North--attest to migrants' strong desire to "better their condition," often risking their lives and possessions to make the trip north.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zwischen 1916 und 1921 ließen halbe Million 
afrikanische Amerikaner den Süden und reisten nach Städte im Norden 
und im Westen in, was dann die größte interne Bewegung Leute in 
solch einem starkem Zeitabschnitt in der Geschichte der Nation war. 
Zeichen der Wanderer zu den Nordzeitungen gehörten zu den 
besten und umfangreichsten Quellen für das Verstehen der Prozeß 
Migration und die Deutung der Beweggründe der Wanderer für das 
Verlassen. Sieben Zeichen zum Chicago Verteidiger -- eine 
schwarze Zeitung veröffentlichte in Chicago, das stark auf südliche 
Schwarze drängte, nördlich fortzuziehen -- bezeugen zum starken 
Wunsch der Wanderer "besser ihren Zustand," ihre Lebensdauern und 
Besitz häufig, riskierend, um die Reise Nord zu bilden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entre 1916 et 1921 demi de million d'Américains 
africains ont laissé les Sud et ont voyagé aux villes dans 
le nord et l'ouest dans ce qui était alors le plus grand 
mouvement interne d'un peuple dans une période si concentrée dans 
l'histoire de la nation. Les lettres des migrants aux journaux 
nordiques étaient parmi les meilleures et les plus volumineuses 
sources pour l'arrangement le transfert de processus et interprétant 
les motivations des migrants pour partir. Sept lettres au 
défenseur de Chicago -- un journal noir a édité Chicago qui a 
fortement invité des noirs méridionaux à passer nord -- 
attest au désir fort des migrants "meilleur leur état," souvent 
risquant les leurs vies et possessions pour rendre le voyage du nord.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entre 1916 e 1921 os meios milhão americanos 
africanos deixaram o sul e viajaram às cidades no norte e no oeste em
o que era então o movimento interno o maior de um pessoa em um 
período de tempo tão concentrado no history da nação. As 
letras dos emigrantes aos jornais do norte eram entre as mais melhores
e fontes as mais voluminous para compreender a migração process e 
interpretar os motivations dos emigrantes para sair. Sete letras
ao defender de Chicago -- um jornal preto publicou em Chicago que 
incitou fortemente pretos do sul migrar para o norte -- atestam ao 
desejo forte dos emigrantes "melhor sua condição," frequentemente 
arriscando suas vidas e possessões para fazer o desengate norte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fra 1916 e 1921 i milione Americani africani mezzi
hanno lasciato il sud ed hanno viaggiato alle città nel nord e 
nell'ovest in che cosa era allora il più grande movimento interno di 
una gente in un periodo di tempo concentrato nella storia della 
nazione. Le lettere dei migranti ai giornali nordici erano fra 
le sorgenti migliori e più voluminose per capire l'espansione 
trattata e l'interpretazione delle motivazioni dei migranti per 
andare. Sette lettere alla protezione del Chicago -- un giornale
nero ha pubblicato in Chicago che ha invitato fortemente i neri del 
sud a migrare a nord -- attestano a desiderio forte dei migranti 
"migliore il loro stato," spesso rischiando le loro vite e possessi 
per rendere il viaggio del nord.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταξύ 1916 και 1921 μισός εκατομμύριο Αφρικανός
Αμερικανοί άφησε το νότο και ταξίδεψε στις πόλεις στο Βορρά και 
τη δύση σε αυτό που ήταν έπειτα η μεγαλύτερη εσωτερική 
μετακίνηση άνθρωποι σε μια τέτοια συγκεντρωμένη χρονική περίοδο 
στην ιστορία του έθνους. Οι επιστολές των μεταναστών στις 
βόρειες εφημερίδες ήταν μεταξύ του καλύτερου και των 
περισσότερων ογκωδών πηγών για την κατανόηση της διαδικασίας 
μετανάστευσης και την ερμηνεία των κινήτρων των μεταναστών για την
αναχώρηση. Επτά επιστολές στον υπερασπιστή του Σικάγου -- 
μια μαύρη εφημερίδα που δημοσιεύεται στο Σικάγο που ώθησε έντονα
τους νότιους Μαύρους για να μεταναστεύσει ο Βορράς -- βεβαιώνουν 
στην ισχυρή επιθυμία των μεταναστών "καλύτερη τον όρο τους," 
συχνά διακινδυνεύοντας τις ζωές και τις κατοχές τους για να 
κάνουν το Βορρά ταξιδιού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entre 1916 y 1921 medios millón de americanos 
africanos dejaron el sur y viajaron a las ciudades en el norte y el 
oeste en cuál era entonces el movimiento interno más grande de una 
gente en un período del tiempo tan concentrado en la historia de la 
nación. Las cartas de los nómadas a los periódicos norteños 
estaban entre las fuentes mejores y más voluminosas para entender la 
migración de proceso e interpretar las motivaciones de los nómadas 
para irse. Siete cartas al defensor de Chicago -- un periódico 
negro publicó en Chicago que impulsó fuertemente negros meridionales
emigrar al norte -- atestiguan al deseo fuerte de los nómadas "mejor 
su condición," a menudo arriesgando sus vidas y posesiones para hacer
el viaje del norte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086832</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106133</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sir-i-will-thank-you-with-all-my-heart-seven-letters-from-the-great-migration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
