<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103170</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103170</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086689</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">On the Road Again: Pinkerton on the Tramp</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf der Straße wieder: Pinkerton auf dem 
Tramp</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sur la route encore : Pinkerton sur le bruit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na estrada outra vez: Pinkerton na caminhada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sulla strada ancora: Pinkerton sul vagabondo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο δρόμο πάλι: Pinkerton στον αγύρτη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el camino otra vez: Pinkerton en el 
vagabundo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The word "tramp" came into common usage in the 1870s as a disparaging description of homeless men thrown out of work by the economic depression and forced to take to the road in search of a job or food. Fears of the "tramp menace" were revived during the even more devastating depression that began in 1893. Many Americans viewed tramps with a combination of fear and disgust. The 1878 work  Strikers, Communists, Tramps, and Detectives , written by the famous detective Allan Pinkerton, presented a somewhat more mixed portrait of the tramp. In this chapter on "Tramp Printers and Tramp Encampments," Pinkerton expressed some sympathy for the plight of people thrown out of work by the depression, grudgingly admired the audacity of the tramping printers, and argued against treating all tramps as criminals. Still, like other middle-class observers before and since, Pinkerton wanted to separate those he saw as the "deserving" poor from poor people he viewed as undeserving and possibly dangerous.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Wort "Tramp" kam in geläufigen Verbrauch im 
1870s als herabsetzende Beschreibung der heimatlosen Männer, die aus 
Arbeit heraus durch die Wirtschaftskrise geworfen wurden und erzwungen
waren, zur Straße auf der Suche nach einem Job oder einer Nahrung zu 
nehmen. Furcht vor der "Trampdrohung" wurde während des sogar 
verheerenderen Tiefstands wieder belebt, der 1893 anfing. Viele 
angesehene Amerikaner tramps mit einer Kombination von Furcht und von 
Ekel. Die 1878 Arbeit Schlaggeräte, Kommunisten, Tramps und die
Detektive, geschrieben vom berühmten detective Allan Pinkerton, 
stellten ein ein wenig gemischtportrait des Tramp dar. In diesem
Kapitel auf "Tramp-Druckern und in den Tramp-Lagern" drückte 
Pinkerton etwas Sympathie für die Lage der Leute aus, die aus Arbeit 
heraus durch den Tiefstand geworfen wurden, widerwillig bewundert der 
Dreistigkeit der tramping Drucker, und argumentiert gegen das 
Behandeln alle tramps als Verbrecher. Noch, wie andere 
Mittelklassebeobachter vor und da, Pinkerton die trennen wollte, sah 
er, wie das "Verdienen" der Armen von den armen Leuten, die er ansah, 
wie undeserving und vielleicht gefährlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mot "bruit" a hérité l'utilisation commune 
dans le 1870s comme description de dépréciation des hommes sans 
foyer jetés sans emploi par la dépression économique et forcés de 
prendre à la route à la recherche d'un travail ou d'un aliment. 
Des craintes de la "menace de bruit" ont été rétablies 
pendant la dépression bien plus dévastatrice qui a commencé en 
1893. Beaucoup d'Américains visualisés marche à pas marqués 
avec une combinaison de la crainte et du dégoût. Les 1878 
butées de travail, communistes, vagabonds, et détectives, écrits 
par le Allan révélateur célèbre Pinkerton, ont présenté une 
verticale en quelque sorte plus mélangée du bruit. En ce 
chapitre sur des "imprimantes de bruit et campements de bruit," 
Pinkerton a exprimé de la sympathie pour la situation difficile des 
personnes jetées sans emploi par la dépression, à contrecoeur 
admirée la témérité des imprimantes de vagabondage, et discuté 
contre traiter tous marche à pas marqués comme criminels. 
Toujours, comme d'autres observateurs de classe moyen avant et 
puisque, Pinkerton a voulu séparer ceux il a vu comme "mériter" des 
pauvres de pauvres personnes qu'il a visualisées comme undeserving et
probablement dangereux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A palavra "caminhada" veio no uso comum no 1870s 
como uma descrição despreciando dos homens desabrigados jogados fora
do trabalho pelo depression econômico e forçados a fazer exame à 
estrada na busca de um trabalho ou de um alimento. Os medos da 
"da ameaça caminhada" revived durante o depression mesmo mais 
devastating que começou em 1893. Muitos americanos vistos vagam
com uma combinação do medo e da aversão. Os 1878 grevistas do
trabalho, comunistas, caminhadas, e detetives, escritos pelo Allan 
detective famoso Pinkerton, apresentaram um retrato um tanto mais 
misturado da caminhada. Neste capítulo da "em impressoras 
caminhada e em encampments da caminhada," Pinkerton expressou algum 
sympathy para o plight dos povos jogados fora do trabalho pelo 
depression, admirado grudgingly o audacity das impressoras vagando, e 
discutido de encontro a tratar tudo vaga como criminosos. Ainda,
como outros observadores do middle-class antes e desde que, Pinkerton 
quis separar aqueles viu como "merecer" pobres dos povos que 
deficientes viu como undeserving e possivelmente perigoso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La parola "vagabondo" ha entrato nell'uso comune 
nel 1870s come descrizione di sottovalutazione degli uomini senza casa
gettati senza lavoro dalla depressione economica e costretti a 
prendere alla strada alla ricerca di un lavoro o di un alimento. 
I timori "della minaccia del vagabondo" sono stati fatti 
rivivere durante la depressione ancor più devastating che ha 
cominciato in 1893. Molti Americani osservati preme il piede con
una combinazione di timore e di repulsione. I 1878 percussori 
del lavoro, comunisti, vagabondi e detectivi, scritti dal Allan 
detective famoso Pinkerton, hanno presentato un ritratto piuttosto 
più mixed del vagabondo. In questo capitolo "sulle stampanti 
del vagabondo e nei encampments del vagabondo," Pinkerton ha espresso 
una certa compassione per la situazione difficile della gente gettata 
senza lavoro dalla depressione, con riluttanza ammirata il audacity 
delle stampanti prementi il piede e parlato contro trattare tutti 
preme il piede come criminali. Eppure, come altri osservatori 
della classe media prima e poiché, Pinkerton ha desiderato separare 
quelli ha visto come "meritare" povero dalla povera gente che
ha osservato come undeserving e possibilmente pericoloso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η λέξη "αγύρτησ" μπήκε στην κοινή χρήση 1870s ως 
περιγραφή δυσφήμησης των άστεγων ατόμων που ρίχτηκαν άνεργων 
από την οικονομική ύφεση και που αναγκάστηκαν να πάρουν στο 
δρόμο σε αναζήτηση μιας εργασίας ή τροφίμων. Οι φόβοι της 
"απειλής αγυρτών" αναβιώθηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια της ακόμα πιό 
καταστρεπτικής κατάθλιψης που άρχισε σε 1893, Πολλοί 
Αμερικανοί εμφάνισαν τους αγύρτες με έναν συνδυασμό φόβου και 
αποστροφής. Οι 1878 απεργοί εργασίας, κομμουνιστές, οι 
αγύρτες, και οι ιδιωτικοί αστυνομικοί, που γράφτηκαν από το 
διάσημο ιδιωτικό αστυνομικό Allan Pinkerton, παρουσίασαν 
ένα κάπως πιό μικτό πορτρέτο του αγύρτη. Σε αυτό το 
κεφάλαιο σχετικά με τους "εκτυπωτές αγυρτών και τις 
στρατοπεδεύσεις αγυρτών," Pinkerton εξέφρασε κάποια συμπόνοια 
για τη δύσκολη θέση των ανθρώπων που ρίχτηκαν άνεργων από την 
κατάθλιψη, θαύμασε απρόθυμα το θράσο των εκτυπωτών αγυρτείας, 
και μίλησε ενάντια στη θεραπεία όλων των αγυρτών ως εγκληματίες.
Ακόμα, όπως άλλους παρατηρητές μεσαίων τάξεων πριν από 
και από, Pinkerton που θέλησαν για να χωρίσει εκείνοι 
εβλέίδε ως "να αξίζει" φτωχοί από τους φτωχούς ανθρώπους
που εμφάνισε όπως undeserving και ενδεχομένως επικίνδυνος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La palabra "vagabundo" vino en uso común en el 
1870s como descripción que desacreditaba de los hombres sin hogar 
lanzados sin trabajo por la depresión económica y forzados llevar el
camino en búsqueda de un trabajo o de un alimento. Los miedos 
de la "amenaza del vagabundo" fueron restablecidos durante la 
depresión aún más devastadora que comenzó en 1893. Muchos 
americanos vistos andan por con una combinación del miedo y de la 
repugnancia. Los 1878 huelguistas del trabajo, comunistas, 
vagabundos, y detectives, escritos por el Allan detective famoso 
Pinkerton, presentaron un retrato algo más mezclado del vagabundo. 
En este capítulo en las "impresoras del vagabundo y campamentos
del vagabundo," Pinkerton expresó una cierta condolencia para el 
apuro de la gente lanzada sin trabajo por la depresión, a 
regañadientes admirada el audacity de las impresoras que andaban por,
y discutido contra tratar todos anda por como criminales. No 
obstante, como otros observadores de la clase media antes y puesto 
que, Pinkerton deseó separar ésos él vio como "merecer" a pobres de
la gente pobre que él vio como undeserving y posiblemente peligroso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086689</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103170</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/on-the-road-again-pinkerton-on-the-tramp</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
