<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103075</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103075</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086301</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Was More of a Citizen": A Puerto Rican Garment Worker Describes Discrimination in the 1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich war mehr eines Bürgers": Ein Puerto 
Rican Kleid-Arbeiter beschreibt Unterscheidung in den zwanziger 
Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'étais plus d'un citoyen" : Un ouvrier de
vêtement de Puerto Rican décrit la discrimination dans les années 
20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu era mais de um cidadão": Um trabalhador
do garment de Puerto Rican descreve a discriminação nos 1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ero più di un cittadino": Un operaio 
dell'indumento di Puerto Rican descrive la distinzione negli anni 20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"ήμουν περισσότερος ενός πολίτη": Ένας 
εργαζόμενος ενδυμάτων Puerto Rican περιγράφει τη διάκριση 
στη δεκαετία του '20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"era más de un ciudadano": Un trabajador de
la ropa de Puerto Rican describe la discriminación en los años 20</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">We generally think of Puerto Rican migration to the U.S. mainland as largely a post-World War II phenomenon, since more than 800,000 Puerto Ricans came to the United States between 1940 and 1969. But immigration actually started much earlier in the century; between 1915 and 1930 more than 50,000 Puerto Rican migrants headed for the United States--especially New York City. The new immigrants faced a mixed reception, particularly from immigrants from other countries. In this interview for the radio program "Nosotros Trabajamos en la Costura"(We Work in the Garment Industry), garment worker Luisa Lopez told how she faced discrimination from European immigrant workers when she went to work in garment factories in the 1920s. Yet sometimes alliances crossed ethnic lines: Lopez found an ally in an Italian-American socialist.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wir denken im Allgemeinen an Puerto Rican 
Migration zum VEREINIGTE STAATEN Festland als groß Phänomen des 
Pfosten-Weltkrieges II, da mehr als 800.000 Puerto Ricans in die 
Vereinigten Staaten zwischen 1940 und 1969 kamen. Aber 
Immigration begann wirklich viel früh im Jahrhundert; zwischen 
1915 und 1930 mehr als 50.000 Puerto Rican gehen Wanderer für die 
Vereinigten Staaten -- besonders New York City voran. Die neuen 
Immigranten stellten eine Mischaufnahme, besonders von den Immigranten
aus anderen Ländern gegenüber. In diesem Interview für 
erklärte das Radioprogramm "Nosotros Trabajamos en La Costura"(We 
Arbeit in der Kleid-Industrie), Kleidarbeiter Luisa Lopez, wie sie 
Unterscheidung von den europäischen einwandernden Arbeitern 
gegenüberstellte, als sie ging, in den Kleidfabriken in den zwanziger
Jahren zu arbeiten, dennoch manchmal Bündnisse ethnische Zeilen 
kreuzten: Lopez fand einen Verbündeten in einem 
Italienisch-Amerikanischen Sozialisten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nous pensons généralement au transfert de Puerto
Rican au continent des ETATS-UNIS comme en grande partie phénomène 
de la guerre II de poteau-Monde, puisque plus de 800.000 Puerto Ricans
sont venus aux Etats-Unis entre 1940 et 1969. Mais l'immigration
a commencé réellement beaucoup plus tôt en siècle ; entre 
1915 et 1930 plus de 50.000 Puerto Rican les migrants se dirigent pour
les Etats-Unis -- particulièrement New York City. Les nouveaux 
immigrés ont fait face à une réception mélangée, en particulier 
des immigrés d'autres pays. Dans cette entrevue le travail de 
Costura"(We de La d'en de Nosotros Trabajamos pour programme par 
radio" dans l'industrie de vêtement), ouvrier Luisa Lopez de 
vêtement a indiqué qu'elle a fait face à la discrimination des 
ouvriers immigrés européens quand elle est allée travailler dans 
des usines de vêtement dans les années 20. Pourtant parfois 
les alliances ont croisé les lignes ethniques : Lopez a trouvé
un allié dans un socialiste Italien-Américain.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nós pensamos geralmente da migração de Puerto 
Rican ao mainland de ESTADOS UNIDOS como pela maior parte um fenômeno
da guerra II do borne-Mundo, desde que mais de 800.000 Puerto Ricans 
vieram aos estados unidos entre 1940 e 1969. Mas o immigration 
começou realmente muito mais cedo no século; entre 1915 e 1930
mais de 50.000 Puerto Rican os emigrantes dirigem para os estados 
unidos -- especial New York City. Os immigrants novos 
enfrentaram uma recepção misturada, particularmente dos immigrants 
de outros países. Nesta entrevista para o trabalho de 
Costura"(We do la do en Nosotros Trabajamos do programa de rádio de" 
na indústria do garment), trabalhador Luisa Lopez do garment disse 
como enfrentou a discriminação dos trabalhadores immigrant europeus 
quando foi trabalhar em fábricas do garment nos 1920s. contudo às 
vezes os alliances cruzaram linhas étnicas: Lopez encontrou um 
aliado em um socialist Italiano-Americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pensiamo generalmente ad espansione di Puerto 
Rican al continente degli STATI UNITI come in gran parte fenomeno di 
guerra II del alberino-Mondo, poiché più di 800.000 Puerto Ricans 
sono venuto al unito Dichiarano fra 1940 e 1969. Ma 
l'immigrazione realmente ha cominciato molto più presto nel secolo; 
fra 1915 e 1930 più di 50.000 Puerto Rican i migranti dirigono 
per unito Dichiara -- il especially New York City. I 
nuovi immigranti hanno affrontato una ricezione mixed, specialmente 
dagli immigranti da altri paesi. In questa intervista per il 
lavoro di Costura"(We della La dell'en di Nosotros Trabajamos di 
programma radiofonico" nell'industria dell'indumento), operaio Luisa 
Lopez dell'indumento ha detto a come ha affrontato la distinzione 
dagli operai immigrati europei quando è andato lavorare nelle 
fabbriche dell'indumento negli anni 20 tuttavia a volte le alleanze 
hanno attraversato le righe etniche: Lopez ha trovato un alleato
in un socialista Italiano-Americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκεφτόμαστε γενικά τη μετανάστευση Puerto Rican 
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ηπειρωτική χώρα ως κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος 
μετα-παγκόσμιος πόλεμος ΙΙ το φαινόμενο, δεδομένου ότι 
περισσότερο από 800.000 Puerto Ricans ήρθαν στις Ηνωμένες
Πολιτείες μεταξύ 1940 και 1969. Αλλά η μετανάστευση 
άρχισε πραγματικά πολλή νωρίτερα στον αιώνα  μεταξύ 
1915 και 1930 περισσότεροι από 50.000 μετανάστες Puerto
Rican διευθύνω για τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες -- ειδικά πόλη της 
Νέας Υόρκης. Οι νέοι μετανάστες αντιμετώπισαν μια μικτή 
λήψη, ιδιαίτερα από τους μετανάστες από άλλες χώρες. Σε 
αυτήν την συνέντευξη για τη ραδιο προγράμματος "εργασία Λα 
Costura"(We Nosotros Trabajamos EN στη βιομηχανία 
ενδυμάτων), ο εργαζόμενος Luisa Lopez ενδυμάτων είπε πώς 
αντιμετώπισε τη διάκριση από τους ευρωπαϊκούς που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει εργαζομένους όταν πήγε να εργαστεί στα εργοστάσια 
ενδυμάτων στη δεκαετία του '20 Ακόμα μερικές φορές οι 
συμμαχίες διέσχισαν τις εθνικές γραμμές: ο Lopez βρήκε έναν 
σύμμαχο σε έναν σοσιαλιστή ιταλικός-Αμερικανός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pensamos generalmente en la migración de Puerto 
Rican al continente de ESTADOS UNIDOS como en gran parte fenómeno de 
la guerra II del poste-Mundo, puesto que más de 800.000 Puerto Ricans
vinieron a los Estados Unidos entre 1940 y 1969. Pero la 
inmigración comenzó realmente mucho anterior en el siglo; 
entre 1915 y 1930 más de 50.000 Puerto Rican los nómadas 
dirigieron hacia los Estados Unidos -- especialmente New York City. 
Los nuevos inmigrantes hicieron frente a una recepción 
mezclada, determinado de inmigrantes de otros países. En esta 
entrevista para el trabajo de Costura"(We del la del en de Nosotros 
Trabajamos del programa de radio" en la industria de la ropa), 
trabajador Luisa Lopez de la ropa dijo cómo ella hizo frente a la 
discriminación de trabajadores inmigrantes europeos cuando ella fue a
trabajar en fábricas de la ropa en los años 20 con todo las alianzas
cruzaron a veces líneas étnicas: Lopez encontró a aliado en 
un socialista Italiano-Americano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086301</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103075</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-was-more-of-a-citizen-a-puerto-rican-garment-worker-describes-discrimination-in-the-1920s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
