<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107579</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107579</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087176</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Are Living in a State of Anarchy": Radical Assessments and Agendas in theYear 1968</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir leben in einem Zustand der Anarchie": 
Radikale Einschätzungen und Tagesordnungen theYear 1968</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous vivons dans un état d'Anarchie" : 
Évaluations et ordres du jour radicaux dans 1968 theYear</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós estamos vivendo em um estado de Anarchy": 
Avaliações e agendas radicais em 1968 theYear</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"stiamo vivendo in un Dichiarare di Anarchy": 
Valutazioni ed ordini del giorno radicali in 1968 theYear</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ζούμε σε ένα κράτος της αναρχίασ": Ριζικές 
αξιολογήσεις και ημερήσιες διατάξεις σε theYear 1968</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"estamos viviendo en un estado de la Anarquía": 
Gravámenes y agendas radicales en 1968 theYear</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Protests against party leadership and policies during the 1968 Democratic Party National Convention, held in Chicago, exploded into violent street confrontations. The 10,000 protesters faced more than 20,000 army troops and police officers. The Walker Report, a federal investigation of the incident, characterized the conflict as "a police riot" and blamed Mayor Richard J. Daley in part for the "unrestrained and indiscriminate police violence." While only seven police officers faced dismissal proceedings, eight leaders of protesting organizations were indicted for conspiring to violate the 1968 Anti-Riot Act. Documents from the National Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam (or Mobe) and the Youth International Party (or "Yippies,")-- two groups central in organizing the protest--appeared in the following testimony of activist Tom Hayden at a House Committee on Un-American Activities hearing to investigate "subversive involvement" in the disruption. Hayden co-authored the Port Huron Statement, the founding document of Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), the leading New Left coalition, in 1962. Despite outrage at the current "state of anarchy," he remained devoted to participatory democracy. Although Hayden and four others were convicted of various charges in the sensationalist Chicago Conspiracy trial, an appeals court reversed the verdicts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Proteste gegen Parteiführung und -politische 
Richtlinien während demokratischen Nationalkonventder 
Partei-1968, angehalten in Chicago, explodierten in heftige 
Straße Konfrontationen. Die 10.000 Protesters stellten mehr als
20.000 Armeetruppen und Polizeioffiziere gegenüber. Der 
Wanderer-Report, eine Bundesuntersuchung des Ereignisses, 
kennzeichnete die $überschneidung, wie "Polizei randaliert" und 
getadelter Bürgermeister Richard J. Daley im Teil für die 
"ungehemmte und unterschiedslose Polizeigewalttätigkeit." 
Während nur sieben Polizeioffiziere Entlassungverfahren 
gegenüberstellten, wurden acht Führer des Protestierens von von 
Organisationen angeklagt, damit das Verschw50ren die Anti-Aufstand Tat
Dokumente 1968 vom nationalen Mobilisierung-Ausschuß verletzt, um den
Krieg in Vietnam (oder Mobe) und die Jugend-internationale 
Partei (oder "Yippies,")-- zu beenden zwei Gruppen zentral, 
wenn der Protest organisiert wird --, der im folgenden Zeugnis des 
Aktivisten Tom Hayden an einem Haus-Ausschuß für Un-Amerikanische 
Aktivitäten hörend, um subversivee Miteinbeziehung "in der 
Unterbrechung nachzuforschen" geerschienen wird. Hayden 
Co-schrieb die Porthurone-Anweisung, das gründendokument der 
Kursteilnehmer für eine demokratische Gesellschaft (SDS), die 
führende neue linke Koalition, 1962. Trotz des Verbrechens am 
aktuellen "Zustand der Anarchie," blieb er teilnehmender 
Demokratie gewidmet. Obgleich Hayden und vier andere der 
verschiedenen Ladungen im sensationalist Chicago Verschwörungversuch 
überführt wurden, hob ein Berufungsgericht die Urteilssprüche auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les protestations contre la conduite et les 
politiques de partie pendant la convention nationale du parti 1968 
démocratique, tenue Chicago, ont éclaté dans des confrontations 
violentes de rue. Les 10.000 protestataires ont fait face à 
plus de 20.000 troupes d'armée et officiers de police. L'état 
de marcheur, une recherche fédérale sur l'incident, a caractérisé 
le conflit comme "la police s'ameute" et maire blâmé Richard J. 
Daley en partie pour "la violence non restreinte et aveugle de 
police." Tandis que seulement sept officiers de police faisaient
face à des démarches de renvoi, huit amorces de protester des 
organismes ont été accusées pour que conspirer viole les documents 
1968 de Loi d'Anti-Émeute du Comité national de mobilisation pour 
terminer la guerre au Vietnam (ou Mobe) et la partie internationale de
la jeunesse (ou "Yippies,")-- deux groupes centraux en organisant la 
protestation -- apparue dans le témoignage suivant d'activiste 
Tom Hayden à un comité de Chambre des activités 
Un-Américaines entendant pour étudier "la participation subversive" 
dans l'interruption. Hayden Co-a écrit le rapport gauche 
d'Huron, le document de fondation des étudiants pour une société 
démocratique (SDS), la principale nouvelle coalition gauche, en 1962.
En dépit de l'outrage au l'"état actuel d'anarchie," il 
est resté consacré à la démocratie participatoire. Bien que 
Hayden et quatre autres aient été condamnés de divers frais dans 
l'épreuve sensationnaliste de conspiration de Chicago, une cour d'appels 
a renversé les verdicts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os protestos de encontro à liderança e às 
políticas do partido durante a convenção nacional de partido 1968 
democrático, prendida em Chicago, explodiram em confrontations 
violentos da rua. Os 10.000 protesters enfrentaram mais de 
20.000 tropas do exército e oficiais de polícias. O relatório
do walker, uma investigação federal do incident, caracterizou o 
conflito como "as polícias se amotinam" e mayor responsabilizado 
Richard J. Daley na peça para "a violência unrestrained e 
indiscriminate das polícias." Quando somente sete oficiais de 
polícias enfrentaram continuações do dismissal, oito líderes de 
protestar organizações foram processados conspiring violate os 
originais 1968 do ato do Anti-Motim do comitê nacional do 
mobilization para terminar a guerra em Vietnam (ou Mobe) e o partido 
internacional da juventude (ou "Yippies,")-- dois grupos centrais em 
organizar o protesto -- aparecido no seguinte testimony da activista 
Tom Hayden em um comitê da casa em atividades Un-Americanas que se 
ouve para investigar "a participação subversiva" no rompimento. 
Hayden co-foi o autor da indicação portuária do huron, o 
original fundando dos estudantes para uma sociedade democrática 
(SDS), o coalition esquerdo novo principal, em 1962. Apesar do 
ultraje no "estado atual de anarchy," remanesceu devotado à 
democracia participatory. Embora Hayden e quatro outros 
convicted de várias cargas na experimentação do conspiracy de 
Chicago do sensationalist, uma corte de apelações inverteu os 
verdicts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le proteste contro direzione e le politiche del 
partito durante la convenzione nazionale del partito democratico 1968,
tenuta in Chicago, hanno esploso nei confronti violenti della via. 
I 10.000 contestatori hanno affrontato più di 20.000 truppe 
dell'esercito ed ufficiali di polizia. Il rapporto del 
camminatore, un'indagine federale sull'avvenimento, ha caratterizzato 
il conflitto come "la polizia si solleva" e sindaco incolpato di 
Richard J. Daley in parte per "la violenza unrestrained ed 
indiscriminata della polizia." Mentre soltanto sette ufficiali 
di polizia hanno affrontato gli atti di scioglimento, otto 
capi della protesta delle organizzazioni sono stati 
incriminati affinchè cospirare violino i documenti 1968 di Legge di 
Anti-Tumulto dal comitato nazionale di mobilizzazione per concludere 
la guerra nel Vietnam (o Mobe) ed il partito internazionale della 
gioventù (o "Yippies,")-- due gruppi centrali nell'organizzazione 
della protesta -- comparsa nella seguente testimonianza 
dell'attivista Tom Hayden ad un comitato della Camera delle 
attività ONU-Americane che si sente per studiare "partecipazione 
sovversiva" alla rottura. Hayden co-ha creato l'istruzione port 
del huron, il documento fondante degli allievi per una società 
democratica (SDS), la nuova coalizione di sinistra principale, in 
1962. Malgrado l'oltraggio alla corrente "dichiari di 
anarchy," lui è rimasto devoted alla democrazia partecipe. 
Anche se Hayden e quattro altri sono stati condannati di varie 
spese nella prova di cospirazione del Chicago di sensationalist, una 
corte di appelli ha invertito i verdetti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι διαμαρτυρίες ενάντια στην ηγεσία συμβαλλόμενων 
μερών και οι πολιτικές κατά τη διάρκεια της εθνικής Συνθήκης 
συμβαλλόμενου μέρους του 1968 δημοκρατικής, που διοργανώθηκε 
στο Σικάγο, εξερράγησαν στις βίαιες αντιμετωπίσεις οδών. Οι
10.000 διαμαρτυρόμενοι απασχόλησαν περισσότερους από 20.000 
στρατεύματα στρατού και αστυνομικούς. Η έκθεση περιπατητών,
μια ομοσπονδιακή έρευνα για το γεγονός, χαρακτήρισε τη σύγκρουση 
ως "ταραχή αστυνομίασ" και κατηγόρησε το δήμαρχο Richard J. 
Daley εν μέρει για τη "ασυγκράτητη και άνευ διακρίσεως βία 
αστυνομίας." Ενώ μόνο επτά αστυνομικοί αντιμετώπισαν τα 
πρακτικά απόλυσης, οκτώ ηγέτες της διαμαρτυρίας των οργανώσεων 
κατηγορήθηκαν για τη συνωμοσία να παραβιαστεί ο νόμος 
αντι-ταραχής του 1968. Έγγραφα από την εθνική Επιτροπή 
κινητοποίησης για να τελειώσει τον πόλεμο στο Βιετνάμ (ή Mobe)
και το διεθνές συμβαλλόμενο μέρος νεολαίας (ή "Yippies,") - - 
δύο ομάδες κεντρικές στην οργάνωση της διαμαρτυρίας -- που 
εμφανίζεται στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση του ενεργού στελέχους Tom 
Hayden σε μια Επιτροπή σπιτιών των αντιαμερικανικών 
δραστηριοτήτων που ακούει για να ερευνήσει τη "ανατρεπτική 
συμμετοχή" στη διάσπαση. Hayden συνυπογράφον η huron 
λιμένων δήλωση, το έγγραφο ίδρυσης των σπουδαστών για μια 
δημοκρατική κοινωνία (SDS), ο κύριος νέος αριστερός 
συνασπισμός, σε 1962, Παρά την προσβολή στην παρούσα 
"κατάσταση της αναρχίας," παρέμεινε αφιερωμένος στη συμμετέχουσα 
δημοκρατία. Αν και Hayden και τέσσερα άλλα καταδικάστηκαν
των διάφορων δαπανών στη sensationalist δίκη συνωμοσίας του 
Σικάγου, ένα εφετείο αντέστρεψε τις αποφάσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las protestas contra la dirección y políticas 
del partido durante la convención nacional del partido democrático 
1968, llevada a cabo en Chicago, estallaron en confrontaciones 
violentas de la calle. Los 10.000 manifestantes hicieron frente a 
más de 20.000 tropas del ejército y oficiales de policía. El 
informe del walker, una investigación federal del incidente, 
caracterizó el conflicto como "el policía se desenfrena" y alcalde 
culpado Richard J. Daley en la pieza para "la violencia libre e 
indistinta del policía." Mientras que solamente siete oficiales
de policía hicieron frente a procedimientos del despido, procesaron a
ocho arranques de cinta de protestar organizaciones para que la 
conspiración viole los documentos 1968 del acto del Contra-Alboroto 
del comité nacional de la movilización para terminar la guerra en 
Vietnam (o Mobe) y el partido internacional de la juventud (o 
"Yippies,")-- dos grupos centrales en la ordenación de la protesta --
aparecida en el testimonio siguiente del activista Tom Hayden en un 
comité de la casa sobre actividades Un-Americanas que oye para 
investigar "la implicación subversiva" en la interrupción. 
Hayden co-fue autor de la declaración portuaria del huron, el 
documento de fundación de los estudiantes para una sociedad 
democrática (SDS), la nueva coalición izquierda principal, en 1962. 
A pesar de ultraje en el "estado actual de la anarquía," él 
seguía siendo devoto a la democracia participante. Aunque 
Hayden y cuatro otros fueron condenados por varias cargas en el ensayo
de la conspiración de Chicago del sensationalist, una corte de 
súplicas invirtió los veredictos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087176</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107579</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-are-living-in-a-state-of-anarchy-radical-assessments-and-agendas-in-theyear-1968</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
