<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Petition of Amelia Bloomer Regarding Suffrage in the West</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Petition der Amelia blühenden Pflanze betreffend 
ist Stimmrecht im Westen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pétition de la défaite d'Amelia concernant le 
suffrage dans l'ouest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Petição do bloomer de Amelia a respeito do 
suffrage no oeste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Petizione del bloomer di Amelia per quanto 
riguarda suffrage nell'ovest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αίτηση της Amelia Bloomer σχετικά με την ψήφο στη
δύση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Petición del bloomer de Amelia con respecto a 
sufragio en el oeste</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">gives a facsimile of the handwritten petition of the suffragist, editor, and temperance leader. This lesson relates to the expression of First Amendment rights, including speech and petition, to the expansion of suffrage by means of the 19th Amendment, and to the amendment process described in Article V. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">gibt ein Faksimile der handgeschriebenen Petition 
des suffragist, des Herausgebers und des temperance Führers. 
Diese Lektion steht auf dem Ausdruck der erste Änderung Rechte,
einschließlich Rede und Petition, zur Expansion des Stimmrechts 
mittels der 19. Änderung und zum Änderung Prozeß in Verbindung, der
in Artikel V beschrieben wird. Diese Lektion bezieht mit den 
nationalen Geschichte Standards und den nationalen Standards für 
Gemeinschaftskunde und Sozialwissenschaften aufeinander.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">donne un fac-similé de la pétition manuscrite de
la suffragette, de l'éditeur, et de l'amorce de modération. 
Cette leçon associe à l'expression des droites de premier 
amendement, y compris la parole et la pétition, à l'expansion du 
suffrage au moyen du 19ème amendement, et au procédé d'amendement 
décrit en article V. Cette leçon se corrèle avec les normes 
nationales d'histoire et les normes nationales pour l'éducation 
civique et les sciences sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">dá uma fac-símile da petição escrita à mão 
do suffragist, do editor, e do líder do temperance. Esta 
lição relaciona-se à expressão de direitas da primeira emenda, 
including o discurso e a petição, à expansão do suffrage por meio 
da 19a emenda, e ao processo da emenda descrito no artigo V. 
Esta lição correlaciona aos padrões nacionais do history e 
aos padrões nacionais para o civics e ciências sociais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dà un facsimile della petizione scritta a mano 
del suffragist, dell'editore e del capo di temperance. 
Questa lezione si riferisce all'espressione dei diritti di prima
correzione, compreso discorso e la petizione, all'espansione di 
suffrage per mezzo della diciannovesima correzione ed al processo di 
correzione descritto in articolo V. Questa lezione correla agli 
standard nazionali di storia ed agli standard nazionali per civics e 
le scienze sociali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δίνει ένα αντίγραφο της χειρόγραφης αίτησης 
suffragist, του επεξεργαστή, και του ηγέτη μετριοπάθειας. 
Αυτό το μάθημα αφορά την έκφραση των πρώτων δικαιωμάτων 
τροποποιήσεων, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της ομιλίας και της αίτησης, 
στην επέκταση της ψήφου με τη βοήθεια της 19$ης τροποποίησης, και 
στη διαδικασία τροποποιήσεων που περιγράφεται στο άρθρο Β. 
Αυτό το μάθημα συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας και 
τα εθνικά πρότυπα για Civics και τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">da un facsímil de la petición manuscrita del 
suffragist, del editor, y del arranque de cinta del temperance. 
Esta lección se relaciona con la expresión de las derechas de 
primera enmienda, incluyendo discurso y la petición, a la extensión 
del sufragio por medio de la diecinueveavo enmienda, y al proceso de 
la enmienda descrito en el artículo V. Esta lección 
correlaciona a los estándares nacionales de la historia y a los 
estándares nacionales para el civics y las ciencias sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206393</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105931</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/petition-of-amelia-bloomer-regarding-suffrage-in-the-west</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
