<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103903</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103903</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205927</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An American Ballroom Companion: Dance Instruction Manuals, 1600-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Amerikanischer Ballroom-Begleiter: 
Tanz-Anweisung Handbücher, 1600-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un Compagnon Américain de Salle de bal : 
Manuels d'Instruction de Danse, 1600-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Companheiro Americano Do Ballroom: 
Manuais De Instrução Da Dança, 1600-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Compagno Americano Del Ballroom: Manuali 
d'istruzione Di Ballo, 1600-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας αμερικανικός σύντροφος αιθουσών χορού: 
Εγχειρίδια οδηγίας χορού, 1600-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Compañero Americano Del Salón de baile: 
Manuales De Instrucción De la Danza, 1600-1920</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents a collection of 200 social dance manuals and related materials. Along with dance instruction manuals, this online presentation also includes a significant number of antidance manuals, histories, treatises on etiquette, and items from other conceptual categories. Many of the manuals also provide historical information on theatrical dance.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt eine Ansammlung von 200 
Sozialtanzhandbüchern und von in Verbindung stehenden Materialien 
dar. Zusammen mit Tanzanweisung Handbüchern schließt diese 
Onlinedarstellung auch eine bedeutende Anzahl von antidance 
Handbüchern, Geschichten, Abhandlungen auf Etikette und Einzelteilen 
von anderen Begriffskategorien ein. Viele der Handbücher 
stellen auch historische Informationen auf theatrical Tanz zur 
Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente une collection de 200 manuels sociaux de
danse et de matériaux relatifs. Avec des manuels d'instruction 
de danse, cette présentation en ligne inclut également un nombre 
significatif de manuels, d'histoires, de traités sur l'étiquette, et
d'éléments d'antidance d'autres catégories conceptuelles. 
Plusieurs des manuels fournissent également des informations 
historiques sur la danse théâtrale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta uma coleção de 200 manuais sociais da 
dança e de materiais relacionados. Junto com manuais de 
instrução da dança, esta apresentação em linha inclui também um 
número significativo de manuais, de histories, de treatises no 
etiquette, e de artigos do antidance de outras categorias conceptuais.
Muitos dos manuais fornecem também a informação histórica na
dança theatrical.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta una collezione di 200 manuali sociali di 
ballo e di materiali relativi. Con le manuali d'istruzione di 
ballo, questa presentazione in linea egualmente include un numero 
significativo di manuali, di dati storici, di trattati su etiquette e 
di articoli di antidance da altre categorie concettuali. Molti 
dei manuali egualmente forniscono le informazioni storiche sul ballo 
teatrale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει μια συλλογή 200 κοινωνικών εγχειριδίων 
χορού και των σχετικών υλικών. Μαζί με τα εγχειρίδια 
οδηγίας χορού, αυτή η σε απευθείας σύνδεση παρουσίαση 
περιλαμβάνει επίσης έναν σημαντικό αριθμό εγχειριδίων, 
ιστοριών, πραγματειών στην εθιμοτυπία, και αντικειμένων 
antidance από άλλες εννοιολογικές κατηγορίες. Πολλά από
τα εγχειρίδια παρέχουν επίσης τις ιστορικές πληροφορίες για το 
θεατρικό χορό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta una colección de 200 manuales sociales 
de la danza y de materiales relacionados. Junto con los manuales
de instrucción de la danza, esta presentación en línea también 
incluye un número significativo de los manuales, de las historias, de
los tratados en etiqueta, y de los items del antidance de otras 
categorías conceptuales. Muchos de los manuales también 
proporcionan a la información histórica en danza de teatro.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205927</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103903</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/an-american-ballroom-companion-dance-instruction-manuals-1600-1920</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
