<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106055</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106055</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205621</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">1869: A report on schools in North Carolina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1869: Ein Report über Schulen in 
Nord-Carolina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">1869 : Un état sur des écoles en Caroline 
du nord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">1869: Um relatório em escolas em 
North.carolina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">1869: Un rapporto sulle scuole in 
North.carolina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">1869: Μια έκθεση σχετικά με τα σχολεία στη 
βόρεια Καρολίνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">1869: Un informe sobre escuelas en Carolina 
del Norte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson, students use a guided reading to look at a report on the status of education in North Carolina in 1869, and discuss the reasons given then for why the Governor and Legislature should support educating North Carolina's children. They are provided an opportunity to compare and contrast the 1869 document against their own ideas about the civic duty to attend school through age sixteen, and its relative value to the state and the country.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion benutzen Kursteilnehmer einen 
geführten Messwert, um einen Bericht über den Status der Ausbildung 
in Nord-Carolina 1869 zu betrachten und behandeln die Gründe, die 
dann gegeben werden für, warum der Gouverneur und die Gesetzgebung 
das Erziehen von von Kindern Nord-Carolina unterstützen sollten. 
Ihnen werden einer Gelegenheit, das Dokument 1869 gegen ihre 
eigenen Ideen über die Zivilpflicht zu vergleichen und zu 
kontrastieren, Schule durch Alter sechzehn und sein relativer Wert um 
den Zustand und das Land zu bedienen zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon, les étudiants emploient une 
lecture guidée pour regarder un état sur le statut d'éducation en 
Caroline du nord en 1869, et discutent les raisons données alors 
pour pourquoi le gouverneur et la législature devraient supporter 
instruire les enfants du nord de la Caroline. Ils sont 
fournis une occasion de comparer et contraster le document 1869 contre
leurs propres idées au sujet du devoir civique d'aller à l'école 
par l'âge seize, et sa valeur relative l'état et le pays.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição, os estudantes usam uma leitura 
guiada olhar um relatório no status da instrução em North.carolina 
em 1869, e discutem as razões dadas então para porque o regulador e 
a legislatura devem suportar educar crianças de North.carolina. 
São fornecidos uma oportunidade de comparar e contrastar o 
original 1869 de encontro a suas próprias idéias sobre o dever civic
atender à escola com a idade dezesseis, e seu valor relativo ao 
estado e ao país.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione, gli allievi usano una lettura 
guidata per guardare un rapporto sulla condizione di formazione in 
North.carolina in 1869 e discutono i motivi allora dati per perchè il
regolatore e la legislatura dovrebbero sostenere l'istruzione dei 
bambini del North.carolina. Sono forniti un'occasione 
confrontare e contrapporre il documento 1869 contro le loro proprie 
idee circa il dovere civico assistere alla scuola con l'età sedici ed
il relativo valore relativo al dichiarare ed al paese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν μια 
καθοδηγημένη ανάγνωση για να εξετάσουν μια έκθεση σχετικά με τη 
θέση της εκπαίδευσης στη βόρεια Καρολίνα το 1869, και να 
συζητήσουν τους λόγους που δίνονται έπειτα για γιατί ο 
κυβερνήτης και το νομοθετικό σώμα πρέπει να υποστηρίξουν την 
εκπαίδευση των παιδιών της βόρειας Καρολίνας. Παρέχονται 
μια ευκαιρία να συγκριθεί και να αντιπαραβληθεί το έγγραφο 1869
ενάντια στις ιδέες τους για το πολιτικό καθήκον να ανταποκριθεί 
το σχολείο μέσω της ηλικίας δέκα έξι, και τη σχετική αξία του 
στο κράτος και τη χώρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección, los estudiantes utilizan una 
lectura dirigida para mirar un informe sobre el estatus de la 
educación en Carolina del Norte en 1869, y discuten las razones 
entonces dadas para porqué el gobernador y la legislatura deben 
utilizar educar a los niños de Carolina del Norte. Les 
proporcionan una oportunidad de comparar y de poner en contraste el 
documento 1869 contra sus propias ideas sobre el deber cívico de 
atender a la escuela con la edad dieciséis, y su valor relativo al 
estado y al país.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:VICTORIA SCHAEFER
FN:VICTORIA SCHAEFER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205621</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106055</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/1869-a-report-on-schools-in-north-carolina</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
