<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106924</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106924</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209766</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Creating the 3D Storyboards</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erstellen des 3D Storyboards</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Créer le 3D Storyboards</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Criando o 3D Storyboards</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Creazione del 3D Storyboards</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημιουργία του τρισδιάστατου Storyboards</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Crear el 3D Storyboards</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson, we turn the thumbnail storyboards into very beautiful storyboards using 3D software. Even though we have completed the thumbnail storyboards, we are not ready to begin filming because we do not know the timing, pace and rhythm of the story. To get this, we need an animatic which is movie made from the storyboards. The thumbnail storyboards are very quick sketches used by the director and cinematographer to set up the shots. All that is requires of thumbnail storyboards is the location of the heads of the actors and the direction of their eyes. But thumbnail storyboards do not look very good when turned into an animatic. (At least mine are not very good looking.) Therefore, we need to create better looking storyboard which are also more accurate. We can make these storyboards with 3D software such as FrameForge 3D Studio and DAZ Studio, etc. (Note: This is not programs such as Storyboard Artist which are only 2D programs.) </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion machen wir die thumbnail 
storyboards zu sehr schöne storyboards mit Software 3D. Obwohl 
wir die thumbnail storyboards durchgeführt haben, sind wir nicht 
betriebsbereit, Schmierfilmbildung anzufangen, weil wir nicht die 
Zeitbegrenzung, den Schritt und den Rhythmus der Geschichte kennen. 
Um dieses zu erhalten, benötigen wir ein animatic das der Film 
ist, der von den storyboards gebildet wird. Die thumbnail 
storyboards sind die sehr schnellen Skizzen, die vom Direktor und vom 
Kameramann verwendet werden, um die Schüsse aufzustellen. 
Alles, das ist, benötigt von den thumbnail storyboards ist der 
Standort der Köpfe der Schauspieler und der Richtung ihrer Augen. 
Aber thumbnail storyboards schauen nicht sehr gut, wenn sie zu 
ein animatic gemacht werden. (mindestens Grube sind nicht sehr 
gutes Schauen.) Folglich müssen wir storyboard besser schauen 
erstellen, die auch genauer sind. Wir können diese storyboards 
mit Software 3D wie FrameForge 3D Studio bilden und DAZ Studio, usw.. 
(Anmerkung: Dieses ist nicht Programme wie Storyboard 
Künstler, die nur 2D Programme. sind)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon, nous transformons les 
storyboards d'ongle du pouce en storyboards très beaux en utilisant le 
logiciel 3D. Quoique nous ayons terminé les storyboards 
d'ongle du pouce, nous ne sommes pas prêts à commencer le pelliculage 
parce que nous ne savons pas la synchronisation, le pas et le rythme 
de l'histoire. Pour obtenir ceci, nous avons besoin d'un 
animatic qui est film fait à partir des storyboards. Les 
storyboards d'ongle du pouce sont des croquis très rapides employés 
par le directeur et le cinéaste pour installer les projectiles. 
Tout ce qui est exige des storyboards d'ongle du pouce est 
l'emplacement des têtes des acteurs et de la direction de leurs yeux.
Mais les storyboards d'ongle du pouce ne regardent pas très bons 
une fois transformés en animatic. (au moins la mine ne sont pas
regarder très bon.) Par conséquent, nous devons créer 
regarder mieux le storyboard qui sont également plus précis. 
Nous pouvons faire ces storyboards avec le logiciel 3D tel que 
le studio de FrameForge 3D et le studio de DAZ, etc... (note : 
Ce n'est pas des programmes tels que l'artiste de Storyboard qui
sont seulement les 2D programmes.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição, nós giramos os storyboards do 
thumbnail em storyboards muito bonitos usando o software 3D. 
Mesmo que nós terminemos os storyboards do thumbnail, nós não
estamos prontos para começar o película porque nós não sabemos o 
sincronismo, o ritmo e o ritmo da história. Para começar este,
nós necessitamos um animatic que seja filme feito dos storyboards. 
Os storyboards do thumbnail são esboços muito rápidos usados 
pelo diretor e pelo cinematographer ajustar acima os tiros. Tudo
que é requer de storyboards do thumbnail é a posição das cabeças 
dos atores e do sentido de seus olhos. Mas os storyboards do 
thumbnail não olham muito bons quando girados em um animatic. 
(ao menos a mina não é olhar muito bom.) 
Conseqüentemente, nós necessitamos criar mais melhor olhar o 
storyboard que são também mais exatos. Nós podemos fazer 
estes storyboards com software 3D tal como o estúdio de FrameForge 3D
e o estúdio de DAZ, etc.. (nota: Este não é os 
programas tais como o artista de Storyboard que são somente 2D 
programas.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione, trasformiamo negli storyboards 
del thumbnail gli storyboards molto bei usando il software 3D. 
Anche se abbiamo completato gli storyboards del thumbnail, non 
dobbiamo aspettare per cominciare la contaminazione perché 
non conosciamo la sincronizzazione, il passo ed il ritmo della storia.
Per ottenere questo, abbiamo bisogno di un animatic che è 
film fatto dagli storyboards. Gli storyboards del 
thumbnail sono abbozzi molto rapidi usati dal direttore e dal 
cinematographer per installare i colpi. Tutto che sia richiede 
degli storyboards del thumbnail è la posizione delle teste degli 
attori e del senso dei loro occhi. Ma gli storyboards del 
thumbnail non osservano molto buoni una volta trasformati in un 
animatic. (almeno la miniera non è molto buon osservare.) 
Di conseguenza, dobbiamo creare più meglio osservare lo 
storyboard che sono egualmente più esatti. Possiamo fare questi
storyboards con software 3D quali l'studio di FrameForge 3D e studio 
di DAZ, ecc. (nota: Ciò non è programmi quale l'artista 
di Storyboard che siano soltanto 2D programmi.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα, μετατρέπουμε τα storyboards 
νυχιών του αντίχειρα σε πολύ όμορφα storyboards 
χρησιμοποιώντας το τρισδιάστατο λογισμικό. Ακόμα κι αν 
έχουμε ολοκληρώσει τα storyboards νυχιών του αντίχειρα, δεν 
πρόκειται να αναμείνουμε για να αρχίσουμε τη μαγνητοσκόπηση 
επειδή δεν ξέρουμε το συγχρονισμό, το ρυθμό και το ρυθμό της 
ιστορίας. Για να πάρουμε αυτό, χρειαζόμαστε έναν 
animatic που είναι κινηματογράφος που γίνεται από τα 
storyboards. Τα storyboards νυχιών του αντίχειρα είναι 
πολύ γρήγορα σκίτσα που χρησιμοποιούνται από το σκηνοθέτη και 
cinematographer για να ιδρύσουν τα πλάνα. Όλα αυτά είναι
απαιτούν από τα storyboards νυχιών του αντίχειρα είναι η θέση
των κεφαλιών των δραστών και της κατεύθυνσης των ματιών τους. 
Αλλά τα storyboards νυχιών του αντίχειρα δεν φαίνονται 
πολύ καλά όταν μετατρέπεται σε animatic. (Τουλάχιστον το
ορυχείο δεν είναι πολύ καλό κοίταγμα.) Επομένως, πρέπει 
να δημιουργήσουμε καλύτερα να κοιτάξουμε storyboard που είναι 
επίσης ακριβέστεροι. Μπορούμε να κάνουμε αυτά τα 
storyboards με το τρισδιάστατο λογισμικό όπως το τρισδιάστατο 
στούντιο FrameForge και DAZ το στούντιο, κ.λπ. (σημείωση: 
αυτά δεν είναι προγράμματα όπως ο καλλιτέχνης Storyboard που 
είναι μόνο 2D προγράμματα.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección, damos vuelta a los storyboards 
del thumbnail en storyboards muy hermosos usando el software 3D. 
Aunque hemos terminado los storyboards del thumbnail, no somos 
listos comenzar película porque no sabemos la sincronización, el 
paso y el ritmo de la historia. Para conseguir esto, necesitamos
un animatic que sea película hecha de los storyboards. Los 
storyboards del thumbnail son bosquejos muy rápidos usados por el 
director y el cinematographer para instalar los tiros. Todo que 
es requiere de storyboards del thumbnail es la localización de las 
pistas de los agentes y de la dirección de sus ojos. Pero los 
storyboards del thumbnail no parecen muy buenos cuando están dados 
vuelta en un animatic. (por lo menos la mina no es el mirar muy 
bueno.) Por lo tanto, necesitamos crear mejor mirar storyboard 
que son también más exactos. Podemos hacer estos storyboards 
con el software 3D tal como estudio de FrameForge 3D y estudio de DAZ,
etc. (nota: Éste no es los programas tales como artista 
de Storyboard que son solamente 2.os programas.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209766</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106924</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/creating-the-3d-storyboards</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
