<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107008</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107008</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206791</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Learn About Chemicals Around Your House</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erlernen Sie Über Chemikalien Um Ihr Haus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Renseignez-vous Sur des Produits chimiques Autour 
De Votre Chambre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprenda Sobre Produtos químicos Em torno De Sua 
Casa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Impari Circa I Prodotti chimici Intorno Alla Vostra
Camera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μάθετε για τις χημικές ουσίες γύρω από το σπίτι σας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aprenda Sobre Los Productos químicos Alrededor De 
Su Casa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students answer questions about pesticides and toxic chemicals used around the house. It explains how to read labels and what to do in case of an accident. An online home tour invites students to identify pesticides and toxic substances in a typical kitchen, garage, laundry room, bathroom, and bedroom.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer beantworten Fragen über die
Schädlingsbekämpfungsmittel und giftige Chemikalien, die um das Haus
benutzt werden. Es erklärt, wie man Kennsätze liest und was zu
tun falls von einem Unfall. Eine Onlinehaupttour lädt 
Kursteilnehmer ein, Schädlingsbekämpfungsmittel und giftige 
Substanzen in einer typischen Küche, in einer Garage, in einem 
Wäschereiraum, in einem Badezimmer und in einem Schlafzimmer zu 
kennzeichnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les étudiants d'aides répondent à des questions
au sujet des pesticides et des produits chimiques toxiques utilisés 
autour de la maison. Elle explique comment lire des étiquettes 
et ce qui à faire en cas d'accident. Une excursion à la maison
en ligne invite des étudiants à identifier des pesticides et des 
substances toxiques dans une cuisine, un garage, une salle de 
blanchisserie, une salle de bains, et une chambre à coucher typiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os estudantes das ajudas respondem a perguntas 
sobre os pesticides e os produtos químicos tóxicos usados em torno 
da casa. Explica como ler etiquetas e que a fazer caso que de um
acidente. Uma excursão home em linha convida estudantes 
identificar pesticides e substâncias tóxicas em uma cozinha, em uma 
garagem, em um quarto da lavanderia, em um banheiro, e em um bedroom 
típicos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli allievi di aiuti rispondono alle domande circa
gli antiparassitari ed i prodotti chimici tossici usati intorno alla 
casa. Spiega come leggere le etichette e che cosa da fare nel 
caso di un incidente. Un giro domestico in linea invita gli 
allievi ad identificare gli antiparassitari e le sostanze tossiche in 
una cucina, in un garage, in una stanza della lavanderia, in una 
stanza da bagno ed in una camera da letto tipici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τις ερωτήσεις απάντησης σπουδαστών για τα 
φυτοφάρμακα και τις τοξικές χημικές ουσίες που χρησιμοποιούνται 
γύρω από το σπίτι. Εξηγεί πώς να διαβάσει τις ετικέτες 
και τι να κάνει σε περίπτωση ατυχήματος. Ένας σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση βασικός γύρος προσκαλεί τους σπουδαστές για να 
προσδιορίσει τα φυτοφάρμακα και τις τοξικές ουσίες σε μια 
χαρακτηριστικές κουζίνα, ένα γκαράζ, ένα δωμάτιο πλυντηρίων, 
ένα λουτρό, και μια κρεβατοκάμαρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los estudiantes de las ayudas contestan a 
preguntas sobre los pesticidas y los productos químicos tóxicos 
usados alrededor de la casa. Explica cómo leer escrituras de la
etiqueta y lo que a hacer en caso de que de un accidente. Un 
viaje casero en línea invita a estudiantes que identifiquen los 
pesticidas y las sustancias tóxicas en una cocina, un garage, un 
cuarto del lavadero, un cuarto de baño, y un dormitorio típicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206791</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107008</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/learn-about-chemicals-around-your-house</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
