<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105269</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105269</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205326</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">You Decide: Should boys and girls be educated separately?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sie Entscheiden: Sollten Jungen und Mädchen
separat erzogen werden?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vous Décidez : Les garçons et les filles 
devraient-ils être instruits séparément ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Você Decide-se: Devem os meninos e as 
meninas ser educados separada?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decidete: Dovrebbero i ragazzi e le ragazze 
essere istruiti esclusivamente?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποφασίζετε: Θα έπρεπε τα αγόρια και τα κορίτσια
να εκπαιδευτούν χωριστά;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usted Decide: ¿Deben los muchachos y las 
muchachas ser educados por separado?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This educational guide focuses on single sex schooling and explores the benefits and drawbacks for students. Assumptions and stereotypes about the different ways boys and girls learn are examined to support both single sex and coeducational approaches to learning. Students are invited to examine the arguments on both sides of the debate, developing critical thinking skills as they work through the activities. Students will learn how to support their arguments with evidence and reason. It is expected that at the end of this guide students will determine where they stand on this controversial issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese pädagogische Anleitung konzentriert auf das 
einzelne schulende Geschlecht und erforscht den Nutzen und die 
Nachteile für Kursteilnehmer. Annahmen und Stereotypen über 
die unterschiedlichen Methoden Jungen und die Mädchen erlernen werden
überprüft, um einzelnes Geschlecht und coeducational Annäherungen 
zum Lernen zu unterstützen. Kursteilnehmer werden eingeladen, 
die Argumente auf beiden Seiten der Debatte zu überprüfen und 
entwickeln kritische denkende Fähigkeiten, während sie durch die 
Aktivitäten arbeiten. Kursteilnehmer erlernen, wie man ihre 
Argumente mit Beweis und Grund unterstützt. Es wird erwartet, 
daß am Ende dieser Anleitung Kursteilnehmer feststellen, wo sie zu 
diesem umstrittenen Punkt stehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce guide éducatif se concentre sur le sexe simple 
instruisant et explore les avantages et les inconvénients pour des 
étudiants. Les prétentions et les stéréotypes au sujet des 
différents garçons et filles de voies apprennent sont examinés pour
supporter le sexe simple et les approches coéducationnelles à 
l'étude. Des étudiants sont invités à examiner les arguments
des deux côtés de la discussion, développant des qualifications de 
pensée critiques pendant qu'ils travaillent par les activités. 
Les étudiants apprendront comment supporter leurs arguments 
avec l'évidence et la raison. On s'attend à ce qu'à 
l'extrémité de ce guide les étudiants déterminent où ils se 
tiennent sur cette question controversée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta guia educacional focaliza no único sexo que educa e 
explora os benefícios e os inconvenientes para estudantes. As 
suposições e os stereotypes sobre os meninos e as meninas diferentes
das maneiras aprendem são examinados para suportar  o único sexo e 
aproximações coeducational à aprendizagem. Os estudantes 
estão convidados examinar os argumentos em ambos os lados do debate, 
desenvolvendo habilidades pensando críticas enquanto trabalham com as
atividades. Os estudantes aprenderão como suportar seus 
argumentos com evidência e razão. Espera-se que na extremidade
desta guia os estudantes determinarão onde estão nesta edição 
controversa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa guida educativa mette a fuoco sul singolo sesso che
istruisce ed esplora i benefici e gli svantaggi per gli allievi. 
I presupposti e gli stereotipi circa i ragazzi e le ragazze 
differenti di modi imparano sono esaminati per sostenere sia il 
singolo sesso che i metodi coeducational ad imparare. Gli 
allievi sono invitati ad esaminare gli argomenti da entrambi i lati 
del dibattito, sviluppanti le abilità pensanti critiche mentre 
lavorano con le attività. Gli allievi impareranno come 
sostenere i loro argomenti con prova e motivo. È previsto che 
all'estremità di questa guida allievi determinino dove si levano in 
piedi su questa edizione discutibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εκπαιδευτικός οδηγός εστιάζει στην ενιαία 
εκπαίδευση φύλων και ερευνά τα οφέλη και τα μειονεκτήματα για 
τους σπουδαστές. Οι υποθέσεις και τα στερεότυπα για τα 
διαφορετικά αγόρια και τα κορίτσια τρόπων μαθαίνουν εξετάζονται 
για να υποστηρίξουν και το ενιαίο φύλο και τις μικτής εκπαίδευσης
προσεγγίσεις στην εκμάθηση. Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται για να 
εξετάσουν τα ορίσματα και στις δύο πλευρές της συζήτησης, που 
αναπτύσσει τις κρίσιμες δεξιότητες σκέψης όπως λειτουργούν μέσω
των δραστηριοτήτων. Οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν πώς να 
υποστηρίξουν τα ορίσματά τους με τα στοιχεία και το λόγο. 
Αναμένεται ότι στο τέλος αυτού του οδηγού οι σπουδαστές θα
καθορίσουν όπου στέκονται σε αυτό το αμφισβητούμενο ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía educativa se centra en el solo sexo que enseña
y explora las ventajas y las desventajas para los estudiantes. 
Las asunciones y los estereotipos sobre los diversos muchachos y
muchachas de las maneras aprenden se examinan para utilizar el solo 
sexo y acercamientos coeducacionales a aprender. Se invita a los
estudiantes que examinen los argumentos en ambas caras del discusión,
desarrollando habilidades de pensamiento críticas mientras que 
trabajan con las actividades. Los estudiantes aprenderán cómo 
utilizar sus argumentos con evidencia y razón. Se espera que en
el extremo de esta guía los estudiantes se determinen dónde están 
parados en esta edición polémica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205326</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105269</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/you-decide-should-boys-and-girls-be-educated-separately</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
