<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107058</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107058</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086705</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Our Hearts are Sickened": Letter from Chief John Ross of the Cherokee, Georgia, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"unsere Inneren werden" krank gemacht: 
Zeichen von Hauptjohn Ross vom Cherokee, Georgia, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nos coeurs sont rendus malades" : Lettre de
John en chef Ross du cherokee, la Géorgie, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nossos corações sickened": Letra de John 
principal Ross do cherokee, Geórgia, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i nostri cuori sickened": Lettera da John 
principale Ross del cherokee, Georgia, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι καρδιές μας είναι Sickened": Επιστολή από
Προϊστάμενος John Ross του τσερόκι, Γεωργία, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">se ponen enfermo "nuestros corazones": Carta
de principal Juan Ross del cherokee, Georgia, 1836</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By President Andrew Jackson's election in 1828, the only large concentrations of Indian tribes remaining on the east coast were located in the South. The Cherokee had adopted the settled way of life of the surrounding--and encroaching--white society. They were consequently known, along with the Creek, Seminole, Chickasaw, and Choctaw, as one of the "Five Civilized Tribes." "Civilization," however, was not enough, and the Jackson administration forced most of these tribes west during the first half of the 1830s, clearing southern territory for the use of whites. Chief John Ross was the principal chief of the Cherokee in Georgia; in this 1836 letter addressed to "the Senate and House of Representatives," Ross protested as fraudulent the Treaty of New Etocha that forced the Cherokee out of Georgia. In 1838, federal troops forcibly displaced the last of the Cherokee from their homes; their trip to Indian Territory (Oklahoma) is known as the "Trail of Tears."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Durch Präsident Andrew Jackson Wahl 1828, waren 
die einzigen großen Konzentrationen der indischen Stämme, die auf 
der Ostküste restlich sind, im Süden. Das Cherokee hatte die 
vereinbarte Lebensart der umgebenden -- und eingreifend -- weißen 
Gesellschaft angenommen. Sie bekannt infolgedessen, zusammen mit
dem Nebenfluß, dem Seminole, dem Chickasaw und dem Choctaw, als einer
der "fünf zivilisierten Stämme." "Zivilisation," jedoch, war 
nicht genug und die Jackson Leitung, die die meisten diesen Stämmen 
erzwungen wurde, die während der ersten Hälfte des 1830s West sind 
und löschte südliche Gegend für den Gebrauch von Weiß. 
Hauptjohn Ross war der allgemeine Leiter vom Cherokee in 
Georgia; in diesem Brief 1836, der an "den Senat und das 
Repräsentantenhaus," protestierte Ross adressiert wurde, als 
betrügerisches den Vertrag von neuem Etocha, der das Cherokee aus 
Georgia heraus erzwang. 1838 verlegten Bundestruppen gewaltsam 
das Letzte vom Cherokee von ihren Häusern; ihre Reise zur 
indischen Gegend (Oklahoma) bekannt, wie die "Spur der Risse."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Près d'élection du Président Andrew Jackson en 
1828, les seules grandes concentrations des tribus indiennes restantes
sur la côte est ont été situées dans les Sud. Le 
cherokee avait adopté la façon de vivre arrangée -- et entamant -- 
de la société blanche d'entourage. Ils ont été par 
conséquent connus, avec la crique, le seminole, le chickasaw, et le 
choctaw, en tant qu'une des "cinq tribus civilisées." la 
"civilisation," cependant, n'était pas assez, et la gestion de 
Jackson forcée la plupart de ces tribus occidentales pendant la 
première moitié du 1830s, effaçant le territoire méridional pour 
l'usage des blancs. John en chef Ross était le chef principal 
du cherokee en Géorgie ; dans cette lettre 1836 adressée "au 
sénat et à la chambre des représentants," Ross a protesté en tant 
que frauduleux le Traité de nouvel Etocha qui a expulsé le cherokee 
de la Géorgie. En 1838, les troupes fédérales ont de force 
déplacé le bout du cherokee de leurs maisons ; leur voyage au 
territoire indien (l'Oklahoma) est connu comme la "traînée des 
larmes."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pela eleição do presidente Andrew Jackson em 
1828, as únicas concentrações grandes dos tribes indian restantes 
na costa do leste foram ficadas situadas no sul. O cherokee 
tinha adotado a maneira de vida estabelecida -- e encroaching -- da 
sociedade branca cercando. Foram sabidos conseqüentemente, 
junto com o creek, o seminole, o chickasaw, e o choctaw, como um dos 
"cinco tribes civilized." a "civilização," entretanto, não 
era bastante, e a administração de Jackson forçada a maioria destes
tribes ocidentais durante a primeira metade do 1830s, cancelando o 
território do sul para o uso dos brancos. John principal Ross 
era o chefe principal do cherokee em Geórgia; nesta letra 1836 
dirigida "ao senate e à casa de representantes," Ross protestou como 
fraudulent o tratado de Etocha novo que forçou o cherokee fora de 
Geórgia. Em 1838, as tropas federais deslocaram forçosamente o
último do cherokee de suas HOME; seu desengate ao território 
indian (Oklahoma) é sabido como a "fuga dos rasgos."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tramite l'elezione del presidente Andrew Jackson 
in 1828, le uniche grandi concentrazioni delle tribù indiane restanti
sul litorale orientale sono state situate nel sud. Il cherokee 
aveva adottato il modo di vivere depositato -- ed invadendo -- della 
società bianca circondante. Conseguentemente sono stati 
conosciuti, con l'insenatura, il seminole, il chickasaw ed il choctaw,
come una "delle cinque tribù civilizzate." "la civilizzazione,"
tuttavia, non era abbastanza e la gestione de Jackson forzata la 
maggior parte di queste tribù ad ovest durante la prima metà del 
1830s, annullante il territorio del sud per l'uso dei bianchi. 
John principale Ross era il capo principale del cherokee nella 
Georgia; in questa lettera 1836 indirizzata "al senato ed alla 
Camera dei rappresentanti," Ross ha protestato come fraudolento il 
Trattato di nuovo Etocha che ha espulso il cherokee dalla Georgia. 
In 1838, le truppe federali hanno spostato con forza l'ultimo 
del cherokee dalle loro sedi; il loro viaggio al territorio 
indiano (Oklahoma) è conosciuto come "la traccia delle rotture."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από την εκλογή Προέδρου Andrew Τζάκσον το 1828, 
οι μόνες μεγάλες συγκεντρώσεις των ινδικών φυλών που παραμένουν 
στην ανατολική ακτή βρέθηκαν στο νότο. Ο τσερόκι είχε 
υιοθετήσει τον εγκατεστημένο τρόπο της ζωής της περιβάλλουσας -- 
και καταπατών -- λευκιάς κοινωνίας. Ήταν συνεπώς γνωστοί, 
μαζί με τον κολπίσκο, το Seminole, το Chickasaw, και το 
Choctaw, ως μια από τις "πέντε εκπολιτισμένες φυλές." "Ο 
πολιτισμός," εντούτοις, δεν ήταν αρκετός, και η κυβέρνηση του 
Τζάκσον που αναγκάστηκε την μεγαλύτερη μέρος της δύσης αυτών των
φυλών κατά τη διάρκεια του πρώτου μισού του 1830s, που 
καθαρίζει το νότιο έδαφος για τη χρήση των λευκών. 
Προϊστάμενος John Ross ήταν ο προι4στάμενος προϊστάμενος του
τσερόκι στη Γεωργία  σε αυτήν την επιστολή 1836 που 
απευθύνθηκε "στη Σύγκλητο και τον οίκο των αντιπροσώπων," ο 
Ross διαμαρτυρήθηκε ως ψευδή τη Συνθήκη νέου Etocha που 
ανάγκασε τον τσερόκι από τη Γεωργία. Το 1838, τα 
ομοσπονδιακά στρατεύματα μετατόπισαν βίαια οι τελευταίο του 
τσερόκι από τα σπίτια τους  το ταξίδι τους στο ινδικό 
έδαφος (Οκλαχόμα) είναι γνωστό ως "ίχνος των δακρύων."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por la elección de presidente Andrew Jackson en 
1828, las únicas concentraciones grandes de las tribus indias 
restantes en la costa del este fueron situadas en el sur. El 
cherokee había adoptado la manera de la vida colocada -- y usurpando 
-- de la sociedad blanca que rodeaba. Por lo tanto eran sabidos,
junto con el cala, el seminole, el chickasaw, y el choctaw, como una 
de las "cinco tribus civilizadas." la "civilización," sin 
embargo, no era bastante, y la administración de Jackson forzada la 
mayoría de estas tribus del oeste durante la primera mitad del 1830s,
borrando el territorio meridional para el uso de blancos. 
Principal Juan Ross era el jefe principal del cherokee en 
Georgia; en esta letra 1836 tratada "al senado y a la cámara de
representantes," Ross protestó como fraudulento el tratado de Etocha 
nuevo que forzó el cherokee fuera de Georgia. En 1838, las 
tropas federales desplazaron fuertemente el último del cherokee de 
sus hogares; su viaje al territorio indio (Oklahoma) se sabe 
como el "rastro de rasgones."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086705</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107058</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/our-hearts-are-sickened-letter-from-chief-john-ross-of-the-cherokee-georgia-1836</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
