<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107150</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107150</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086069</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Defending the Wheat Farmer: "The Farmer and Three Dollar Wheat"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verteidigen des Weizen-Landwirts: "der 
Landwirt und drei Dollar-Weizen"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Défendre le fermier de blé : "le fermier 
et blé trois en provenance de la zone dollar"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Defendendo o fazendeiro do trigo: "o 
fazendeiro e trigo de três dólares"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Difendere il coltivatore del frumento: "il 
coltivatore e un frumento tre di provenienza dalla zona del dollaro"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπεράσπιση του αγρότη σίτου: "Ο σίτος αγροτών 
και τριών δολαρίων"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Defender al granjero del trigo: "el granjero
y trigo de tres dólares"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Modern Americans, disconnected from the nation's rural heritage, often imagine farm life of the past as simple and uncomplicated by market pressures. Farmers in the years before World War I, however, faced relentless and thoroughly modern economic stresses and labor conflicts as the scale of their enterprises increased. In the wheat-growing regions of the Midwest and the Great Plains, growing more wheat resulted in lower prices per bushel, ironically increasing costs (for equipment, fertilizer, and labor) and decreasing overall income for farm families. In 1917, viewing wheat production as essential to the war effort, the federal government established price controls for wheat. The plan raised wheat prices, but many Americans, especially those in the labor movement, asked why wheat farmers should be subsidized while wartime laws prevented other workers from seeking higher wages. This 1918  Scribner's Magazine  article answered critics who accused wheat farmers of profiteering, portraying farmers sympathetically, as patriotic businessmen simply trying to make a decent living.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die modernen Amerikaner, getrennt vom 
landwirtschaftlichen Erbe der Nation, stellen häufig sich das 
Bauernhofleben der Vergangenheit als einfaches und unkompliziertes 
durch Marktdruck vor. Landwirte in den Jahren vor dem Ersten 
Weltkrieg jedoch gegenübergestellte unnachgiebige und gänzlich 
moderne ökonomische Drücke und Arbeit $überschneidungen, wie die 
Skala ihrer Unternehmen sich erhöhte. In den Weizen-wachsenden 
Regionen des Mittelwestens und der Prairien, ergab erhöhte das 
Anbauen mehr Weizens niedrigere Preise pro den Scheffel, ironisch 
Kosten (für Ausrüstung, Düngemittel, und Arbeit) und verringert 
gesamtes Einkommen für Bauernhoffamilien. 1917 stellte 
ansehenweizenproduktion, wie wesentlich zur Kriegbemühung, die 
Bundesregierung Preiskontrollen für Weizen her. Der Plan hob 
Weizenpreise, aber viele Amerikaner, besonders die in der 
Arbeiterbewegung an, gefragt, warum Weizenlandwirte subventioniert 
werden sollten, während Krieggesetze andere Arbeiter an suchenden 
höheren Löhnen verhinderten. Artikel 1918 Zeitschrift dieses 
Scribners beantwortete die Kritiker, die Weizenlandwirte vom 
Profiteering beschuldigten und sympathetically schilderte Landwirte, 
als patriotische Geschäftsmänner, die einfach versuchen, ein 
annehmbares Leben zu bilden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Américains modernes, démontés de 
l'héritage rural de la nation, imaginent souvent la vie de ferme du 
passé en tant que simple et peu compliqué par des pressions du 
marché. Fermiers en années avant la Première Guerre Mondiale,
cependant, efforts faits face et conflits économiques implacables et 
complètement modernes de travail à mesure que l'échelle de leurs 
entreprises augmentait. Dans les régions decroissance du 
Midwest et des grandes plaines, cultiver plus de blé a eu comme 
conséquence des prix inférieurs par boisseau, augmentant 
ironiquement des coûts (pour le matériel, l'engrais, et le travail) 
et diminuant le revenu global pour des familles de ferme. En 
1917, la production de visionnement de blé comme essentielle à 
l'effort de guerre, le gouvernement fédéral a établi des contrôles
des prix pour le blé. Le plan a élevé des prix de blé, mais 
beaucoup d'Américains, particulièrement ceux dans le mouvement de 
travail, demandé pourquoi des fermiers de blé devraient être 
subventionnés tandis que les lois de temps de guerre empêchaient 
d'autres ouvriers des salaires plus élevés recherchants. 
L'article 1918 du magazine de ce Scribner a répondu aux 
critiques qui accusent des fermiers de blé du mercantilisme, 
dépeignant des fermiers sympathique, en tant qu'hommes d'affaires 
patriotes essayant simplement de faire une vie décente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os americanos modernos, desconectados do heritage 
rural da nação, imaginam frequentemente a vida da fazenda do passado
como simples e uncomplicated por pressões do mercado. 
Fazendeiros nos anos antes do world.war.i, entretanto, stresses 
enfrentados e conflitos econômicos relentless e completamente 
modernos do trabalho como a escala de suas empresas aumentou. 
Nas regiões trigo-crescentes do Midwest e das planícies 
grandes, crescer mais trigo resultou em uns preços mais baixos por o 
bushel, aumentando ironically custos (para o equipamento, o 
fertilizante, e o trabalho) e diminuindo a renda total para famílias 
da fazenda. Em 1917, a produção de observação do trigo como 
essencial ao esforço da guerra, o governo federal estabeleceu 
controles de preço para o trigo. A planta levantou preços do 
trigo, mas muitos americanos, especial aqueles no movimento labor, 
perguntado porque os fazendeiros do trigo devem subsidized quando as 
leis do wartime impediram outros trabalhadores dos salários mais 
elevados procurando. O artigo 1918 do compartimento deste 
Scribner respondeu aos críticos que acusam fazendeiros do trigo do 
profiteering, portraying fazendeiros sympathetically, como os homens 
de negócios patriotic que tentam simplesmente fazer uma vida decent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli Americani moderni, staccati dall'eredità 
rurale della nazione, immaginano spesso la durata dell'azienda 
agricola dell'esperienza come semplice e semplice dalle pressioni del 
mercato. Coltivatori durante gli anni prima del world.war.i, 
tuttavia, sforzi affrontati e conflitti economici relentless e 
completamente moderni di lavoro come la scala delle loro imprese
è aumentato. Nelle regioni dicrescita del Midwest e delle 
pianure grandi, coltivare più frumento ha provocato i prezzi più 
bassi per il bushel, aumentante ironicamente i costi (per 
apparecchiatura, fertilizzante ed il lavoro) e facente diminuire
il reddito generale per le famiglie dell'azienda agricola. In 
1917, la produzione d'esame del frumento come essenziale allo sforzo 
di guerra, il governo federale ha stabilito i comandi di prezzi per 
frumento. Il programma ha alzato i prezzi del frumento, ma molti
Americani, particolarmente quelli nel movimento di lavoro, chiesto 
perchè i coltivatori del frumento dovrebbero essere sovvenzionati 
mentre le leggi di wartime hanno evitato altri operai gli stipendi 
più alti di ricerca. L'articolo 1918 dello scomparto di questo 
Scribner ha risposto ai critici che accusano i coltivatori del 
frumento dell'affarismo, ritraenti in modo comprensivo i coltivatori, 
come uomini d'affari patriotic che provano semplicemente a fare una 
vita decent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύγχρονοι Αμερικανοί, που αποσυνδέονται από την 
αγροτική κληρονομιά του έθνους, φαντάζονται συχνά την αγροτική 
ζωή του παρελθόντος ως απλός και απλός από τις πιέσεις αγοράς. 
Οι αγρότες στα έτη πριν από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, 
εντούτοις, αντιμετώπισαν τις ανηλεείς και λεπτομερώς σύγχρονες 
οικονομικές πιέσεις και τις συγκρούσεις εργασίας καθώς η κλίμακα
των επιχειρήσεών τους αυξήθηκε. Στις περιοχές 
σίτος-ανάπτυξης midwest και των μεγάλων πεδιάδων, η ανάπτυξη 
περισσότερου σίτου οδήγησε στις χαμηλότερες τιμές ανά μπούσελ, 
ειρωνικά που αυξάνει τις δαπάνες (για τον εξοπλισμό, το λίπασμα, 
και την εργασία) και που μειώνει το γενικό εισόδημα για τις 
αγροτικές οικογένειες. Το 1917, παραγωγή σίτου όψης 
όπως ουσιαστική στην πολεμική προσπάθεια, η ομοσπονδιακή 
κυβέρνηση καθιέρωσε τους ελέγχους τιμών για το σίτο. Το 
σχέδιο αύξησε τις τιμές σίτου, αλλά πολλοί Αμερικανοί, ειδικά 
εκείνοι στη μετακίνηση εργασίας, ρώτησαν γιατί οι αγρότες σίτου
πρέπει να επιχορηγηθούν ενώ οι εν καιρώ πολέμου νόμοι απέτρεψαν
άλλους εργαζομένους από την επιδίωξη των υψηλότερων αμοιβών. 
Το άρθρο περιοδικών αυτού του Scribner 1918 απάντησε 
στους κριτικούς που κατηγόρησαν τους αγρότες σίτου για 
profiteering, που απεικονίζουν τους αγρότες με κατανόηση, ως 
πατριωτικούς επιχειρηματίες που προσπαθούν απλά να βγάλουν 
κόσμια προς το ζειν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los americanos modernos, desconectados de la 
herencia rural de la nación, imaginan a menudo la vida de la granja 
del pasado como simple y sencillo por presiones del mercado. 
Granjeros en los años antes de la Primera Guerra Mundial, sin 
embargo, tensiones hechas frente y conflictos económicos implacables 
y a conciencia modernos del trabajo como la escala de sus empresas 
aumentó. En las regiones trigo-crecientes del Cercano oeste y 
de los grandes llanos, el crecimiento de más trigo dio lugar a 
precios bajos por el celemín, aumentando irónico costes (para el 
equipo, el fertilizante, y el trabajo) y disminuyendo la renta total 
para las familias de la granja. En 1917, la producción del 
trigo que veía como esencial para el esfuerzo de la guerra, el 
gobierno federal estableció los controles de precios para el trigo. 
El plan crió a precios del trigo, pero a muchos americanos, 
especialmente ésos en el movimiento de trabajo, preguntado porqué 
los granjeros del trigo deben ser subvencionados mientras que los 
leyes del tiempo de guerra previnieron a otros trabajadores de 
salarios más altos que buscaban. El artículo 1918 del 
compartimiento de este Scribner contestó a los críticos que acusan a
granjeros del trigo de mercantilismo, retratando a granjeros 
sympathetically, como hombres de negocios patrióticos que intentaban 
simplemente hacer una vida decente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086069</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107150</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/defending-the-wheat-farmer-the-farmer-and-three-dollar-wheat</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
