<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106126</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106126</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085245</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Popular Culture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Populäre Kultur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Culture Populaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cultura Popular</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Coltura Popolare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημοφιλής πολιτισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cultura Popular</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many forms of entertainment and leisure activities people participated in during the early decades of the 20th century are not that different from those we enjoy today. At the turn of the century people found entertainment at carnivals and festivals and exhibitions. Photographs here include the California Midwinter International Exposition in San Francisco in 1894, and the Anaheim Carnival of 1911. Sports were also a popular pastime. Photographs show people participating in tennis and golf, but spectator sports were also popular. In 1929, Miss Jessie Darnley apparently swam her way to the title of Miss Anaheim in a pool filled with three tons of oranges. A number of players became celebrities, as witnessed by publicity stills of baseball greats Babe Ruth, Lou Gehrig, and Carl Klindt. Electricity and improved communications meant that entertainment was no longer confined to live theater. People turned to the radio for both information and entertainment. One photograph shows the family of a Democratic nominee for US Senator, Sheridan Downey, gathered around the radio listening to election results. Another depicts a live radio broadcast. During this era the film industry boomed in Hollywood, generating popular images and mythologies surrounding the movies and movie stars. Photographs in this group include some on-set shots of actors, directors, and movie-making equipment. The owner of the famous Chinese Theater in Hollywood, Sid Grauman, is pictured with film star Mary Pickford. Other images include silent film stars, the original "Our Gang" cast at the opening of the Broadway Theater, and a shot of the Spreckels Theater on the night of a Three Stooges film premiere in 1934.
As had been true for centuries, people enjoyed music, literature, and the arts. Images here include jazz musicians performing and a studio portrait of Roland Hayes, considered one of the greatest tenors in the 1920s. Popular literary figures pictured include author Upton Sinclair, whose 1906 book The Jungle helped raise popular awareness about food processing and contributed in large part to the passage of the Meat Inspection Act and the Pure Food and Drug Act in 1906. Photographs of poets and writers who wrote about or resided in California include Joaquin Miller, George Sterling, Charles Warren Stoddard, Robinson Jeffers, Edwin Markham, and Mary Austin (standing in front of a mural with Mexican artist Diego Rivera).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Formulare Unterhaltung und Freizeitder 
aktivitäten, die Leute innen während der frühen Dekaden des 20. 
Jahrhunderts teilnahmen, sind nicht das, das zu denen unterschiedlich 
ist wir heute genießen. An der Umdrehung der gefundenen 
Unterhaltung des Jahrhunderts Leute an den Karnevalen und Festivals 
und Ausstellungen. Fotographien hier schließen die Kalifornien 
Mitte- des Wintersinternationale Ausstellung in San Francisco 1894 und
den Anaheim Karneval von 1911 ein. Sport war auch ein populärer
Zeitvertreib. Fotographien zeigen die Leute, die am Tennis 
teilnehmen und spielen Golf, aber Zuschauersport war auch populär. 
1929 schwamm Fräulein Jessie Darnley anscheinend ihre Methode 
zum Titel Fräulein Anaheim in einem Pool, das mit drei Tonnen Orangen
gefüllt wurde. Eine Anzahl von Spielern wurde Berühmtheiten, 
wie durch Werbestille des Baseball greats Babys Ruth, Lou Gehrig und 
Karl Klindt gezeugt. Elektrizität und verbesserte 
Kommunikationen bedeuteten, daß Unterhaltung nicht mehr begrenzt 
wurde, um zu leben Theater. Leute wendeten an den Radio zu 
Information und Unterhaltung. Eine Fotographie zeigt die Familie
eines demokratischen Kandidaten für den US Senator, Sheridan Downey, 
erfaßt um den Radio hörend zu den Wahlergebnissen. Anders 
stellt eine Phasenradiosendung bildlich dar. Während dieser 
Ära dröhnte legte die Filmindustrie in Hollywood und populäre 
Bilder und die Mythologien fest, welche die Filme und die Filmstars 
umgeben. Fotographien in dieser Gruppe enthalten einige 
Angriffschüsse der Schauspieler, der Direktoren und des Film-Bildens 
der Ausrüstung. Der Inhaber des berühmten chinesischen 
Theaters in Hollywood, Sid Grauman, wird mit Filmstar Mary Pickford 
dargestellt. Andere Bilder enthalten leise Filmstars, die 
Vorlage "unsere Gruppe", die an der Öffnung des Broadway Theaters 
geworfen wird, und ein Schuß des Spreckels Theaters auf der Nacht 
einer Filmpremiere mit drei Stooges in 1934.As war für Jahrhunderte, 
Leute genossene Musik, Literatur und die künste zutreffend gewesen. 
Bilder hier enthalten die Jazzmusiker, die durchführen und ein 
Studioportrait von Roland Hayes, betrachtet eins der größten 
Beschaffenheit in den dargestellten zwanziger Jahre populären 
literarischen Abbildungen enthalten Autor Upton Sinclair, dessen 1906 
das Dschungel geholfene populäre Bewußtsein der Erhöhung über die 
Nahrungsmittelverarbeitung und im großen Teil zum Durchgang der 
Fleisch-Kontrolle Tat und der reinen Nahrungsmittel-und Droge-Tat 1906
beigetragen anmelden. Fotographien der Dichter und der 
Verfasser, die über schrieben oder in Kalifornien sich befanden, 
enthalten Joaquin Miller, Sterling George, Charles Warren Stoddard, 
Robinson Jeffers, Edwin Markham und Mary Austin (stehend vor einem 
Wandbild mit mexikanischem Künstler Diego Rivera).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup de formes des activités de 
divertissement et de loisirs que les gens ont participées dedans 
pendant les décennies tôt du 20ème siècle ne sont pas celle 
différente de ceux nous apprécions aujourd'hui. À la fin des 
personnes de siècle divertissement trouvé aux carnavals et les 
festivals et les expositions. Les photographies ici incluent 
l'exposition internationale de plein hiver de la Californie dans San 
Francisco en 1894, et le carnaval d'Anaheim de 1911. Les sports
étaient également un passe-temps populaire. Les photographies 
montrent des personnes participant au tennis et jouent au golf, mais 
les sports spectaculaires étaient également populaires. En 
1929, Mlle Jessie Darnley a apparemment nagé sa voie au titre de Mlle
Anaheim dans un regroupement rempli de trois tonnes d'oranges. 
Un certain nombre de joueurs sont devenus des célébrités, 
comme été témoin par des distillateurs de publicité de bébé de 
greats de base-ball Ruth, Lou Gehrig, et Karl Klindt. 
L'électricité et les transmissions améliorées ont signifié 
que le divertissement n'a été plus confiné pour vivre théâtre. 
Les gens se sont tournés vers la radio pour l'information et le
divertissement. Une photographie montre la famille d'un 
dénommé démocratique pour sénateur des USA, Sheridan Downey, 
recueilli autour de la radio écoutant des résultats d'élection. 
Un autre dépeint une émission par radio de phase. 
Pendant cette ère l'industrie de film a grondé dans 
Hollywood, produisant des images populaires et les mythologies 
entourant les films et le film tient le premier rôle. Les 
photographies dans ce groupe incluent quelques projectiles de début 
des acteurs, des directeurs, et de film-faire le matériel. Le 
propriétaire du théâtre chinois célèbre dans Hollywood, Sid 
Grauman, est décrit avec le film tiennent le premier rôle Mary Pickford. 
D'autres images incluent le film silencieux tient le premier rôle, 
l'original "notre troupe" moulée à l'ouverture du théâtre de 
Broadway, et un projectile du théâtre de Spreckels la nuit d'une 
première de film de trois faire-valoir dans 1934.As avait été vrai 
pour des siècles, la musique appréciée par gens, la littérature, 
et les arts. Les images ici incluent des musiciens de jazz 
exécutant et une verticale de studio de Roland Hayes, considérée 
une des plus grandes teneurs dans les chiffres littéraires populaires
des années 20 décrits incluent l'auteur Upton Sinclair, dont les 
1906 réservent la conscience populaire aidée par jungle d'augmenter 
au sujet de la transformation des produits alimentaires et contribuée
dans la grande partie au passage de l'acte d'inspection de viande et 
de la Loi pure de nourriture et de drogue en 1906. Les 
photographies des poèts et des auteurs qui ont écrit au sujet de ou 
ont résidé en Californie incluent Joaquin Miller, George 
sterling, Charles Warren Stoddard, Robinson Jeffers, Edwin Markham, et
Mary Austin (se tenant devant un mural avec artiste mexicain Diego 
Rivera).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos formulários de atividades que do 
entertainment e de lazer os povos participaram dentro durante as 
décadas adiantadas do 20o século não são aquele diferente daqueles
nós apreciamos hoje. Na volta do entertainment encontrado povos
do século em carnivals e festivals e exhibitions. As 
fotografias aqui incluem a exposição internacional do midwinter de 
Califórnia em San Francisco em 1894, e o carnival de Anaheim de 1911.
Os esportes eram também um pastime popular. As 
fotografias mostram os povos que participam no tênis e golf, mas os 
esportes espectadores eram também populares. Em 1929, a 
senhorita Jessie Darnley nadou aparentemente sua maneira ao título da
senhorita Anaheim em um pool enchido com as três toneladas das 
laranjas. Um número de jogadores transformaram-se celebridades,
como testemunhado por destiladores do publicity do babe Ruth, Lou 
Gehrig, e Carl Klindt dos greats do baseball. A eletricidade e 
as comunicações melhoradas significaram que o entertainment era não
mais longo confinado ao teatro vivo. Os povos giraram para o 
rádio para  a informação e o entertainment. Uma fotografia 
mostra a família de um nominee democrático para o senator dos E. U.,
Sheridan Downey, recolhido em torno do rádio escutando resultados de 
eleição. Outro descreve uma transmissão de rádio viva. 
Durante esta era a indústria da película cresceu em Hollywood,
gerando imagens populares e os mythologies que cercam os filmes e as 
estrelas de filme. As fotografias neste grupo incluem alguns 
tiros do início dos atores, dos diretores, e de filme-fazer o 
equipamento. O proprietário do teatro chinês famoso em 
Hollywood, Sid Grauman, é retratado com estrela de película Mary 
Pickford. Outras imagens incluem estrelas de película 
silenciosas, o original "nosso grupo" moldado na abertura do teatro de
Broadway, e um tiro do teatro de Spreckels na noite de uma premier da 
película de três stooges em 1934.As tinha sido verdadeiro para 
séculos, a música apreciada povos, a literatura, e as artes. 
As imagens aqui incluem os músicos do jazz que executam e um 
retrato do estúdio de Roland Hayes, considerado um dos tenors os mais
grandes nas figuras literárias populares dos 1920s. retratadas inclui
o autor Upton Sinclair, cujos 1906 registram a consciência popular 
ajudada selva do aumento sobre processar de alimento e contribuída na
parte grande à passagem do ato da inspeção da carne e do ato puro 
do alimento e da droga em 1906. As fotografias dos poetas e dos 
escritores que escreveram sobre ou residiram em Califórnia incluem 
Joaquin Moleiro, George sterling, Charles Warren Stoddard, Robinson 
Jeffers, Edwin Markham, e Mary Austin (que está na frente de um mural
com artista mexicano Diego Rivera).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molte forme di intrattenimento e di attività di 
svago che la gente ha partecipato dentro durante le decadi in anticipo
del ventesimo secolo non sono quella differente da quelle godiamo 
oggi. Alla fine della gente di secolo intrattenimento trovato ai
carnivals e festival e mostre. Le fotografie qui includono 
l'esposizione internazionale di pieno inverno della California a San 
Francisco in 1894 ed il carnival di Anaheim di 1911. Gli sport 
erano egualmente un pastime popolare. Le fotografie mostrano la 
gente che partecipa al tennis e golf, ma gli sport spectator erano 
egualmente popolari. In 1929, la sig.na Jessie Darnley ha 
nuotato apparentemente il suo modo al titolo della sig.na Anaheim in 
uno stagno riempito di tre tonnellate di aranci. Un certo numero
di giocatori sono diventato celebrities, come testimoniato dagli 
alambicchi di pubblicità del babe Ruth, Lou Gehrig e Carl Klindt dei 
greats di baseball. L'elettricità e le comunicazioni migliorate
hanno significato che l'intrattenimento più non è stato limitato per
vivere teatro. La gente si è girata verso la radio per sia le 
informazioni che l'intrattenimento. Una fotografia mostra la 
famiglia di un nominee democratico per il senatore degli Stati Uniti, 
Sheridan Downey, riunito intorno alla radio ascoltante i 
risultati di elezione. Un altro descrive una radiodiffusione 
radiofonica in tensione. Durante questa era l'industria della 
pellicola ha cresciuto in Hollywood, generando le immagini popolari e 
le mitologie che circondano i film e le stelle di film. 
Le fotografie in questo gruppo includono alcuni colpi di inizio 
degli attori, dei direttori e delle attrezzature di film-making. 
Il proprietario del teatro cinese famoso in Hollywood, Sid 
Grauman, è descritto con la stella di pellicola Mary Pickford. 
Altre immagini includono le stelle di pellicola silenziose, 
l'originale "il nostro gruppo" fuso all'apertura del teatro di 
Broadway e un colpo del teatro di Spreckels sulla notte di un 
prima della pellicola dei tre stooges in 1934.As era stato 
allineare per i secoli, la musica goduta la gente, la letteratura e le
arti. Le immagini qui includono i musicisti di jazz che 
effettuano e un ritratto dell'studio di Roland Hayes, considerato 
uno dei tenori più grandi nella le figure letterarie popolari degli 
anni 20 descritte include l'autore Upton Sinclair, di cui 1906 
prenotano la consapevolezza popolare di aumento aiutata giungla circa 
la trasformazione dei prodotti alimentari e contribuita nella grande 
parte al passaggio della Legge di controllo della carne e della Legge 
pura della droga e dell'alimento in 1906. Le fotografie dei 
poets e dei produttori che hanno scritto circa o hanno riseduto nella 
California includono Joaquin Mugnaio, George sterlina, Charles Warren 
Stoddard, Robinson Jeffers, Edwin Markham e Mary Austin (che si leva 
in piedi davanti un mural con l'artista messicano Diego Rivera).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλές μορφές των ανθρώπων δραστηριοτήτων ψυχαγωγίας 
και ελεύθερου χρόνου συμμετείχαν μέσα κατά τη διάρκεια των 
πρόωρων δεκαετιών του 20ού αιώνα δεν είναι ότι διαφορετικοί 
από εκείνους απολαμβάνουμε σήμερα. Στο γύρισμα του αιώνα 
οι άνθρωποι βρήκαν την ψυχαγωγία στα carnivals και τα φεστιβάλ 
και τις εκθέσεις. Οι φωτογραφίες περιλαμβάνουν εδώ τη 
midwinter Καλιφόρνιας διεθνή έκθεση στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο το 
1894, και το Αναχάιμ καρναβάλι 1911, αθλητισμού ήταν επίσης
ένα δημοφιλές χόμπι. Οι φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν ανθρώπους 
που συμμετέχουν στην αντισφαίριση και το γκολφ, αλλά ο αθλητισμός 
θεατών ήταν επίσης δημοφιλής. Το 1929, η Δεσποινίς 
Jessie Darnley κολύμπησε προφανώς τον τρόπο της στον τίτλο 
της Δεσποινίσς Anaheim σε μια λίμνη που γέμισαν με τρεις τόνους
των πορτοκαλιών. Διάφοροι φορείς έγιναν προσωπικότητες, 
όπως βεβαιώνονται από τους αποστακτήρες δημοσιότητας του 
μπέιζ-μπώλ greats Babe Ruth, Lou Gehrig, και Carl 
Klindt. Η ηλεκτρική ενέργεια και οι βελτιωμένες 
επικοινωνίες σήμαναν ότι η ψυχαγωγία δεν περιορίστηκε πλέον στο 
ζωντανό θέατρο. Οι άνθρωποι γύρισαν στο ραδιόφωνο και για 
τις πληροφορίες και για την ψυχαγωγία. Μια φωτογραφία 
εμφανίζει την οικογένεια ενός δημοκρατικού υποψηφίου για τον 
αμερικανικό γερουσιαστή, Sheridan Downey, που μαζεύεται γύρω
από το ραδιο άκουσμα στα αποτελέσματα εκλογής. Αλλος 
απεικονίζει μια ζωντανή ραδιο ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση. Κατά τη
διάρκεια αυτής της εποχής η βιομηχανία ταινιών βόυιξε σε 
Hollywood, παράγοντας τις δημοφιλείς εικόνες και τις μυθολογίες
που περιβάλλουν τους κινηματογράφους και τα αστέρια 
κινηματογράφων. Οι φωτογραφίες σε αυτήν την ομάδα 
περιλαμβάνουν μερικά πλάνα αρχής των δραστών, των σκηνοθετών, 
και της κινηματογράφος-παραγωγής του εξοπλισμού. Ο 
ιδιοκτήτης του διάσημου κινεζικού θεάτρου σε Hollywood, sid 
Grauman, απεικονίζεται με το αστέρι Mary Pickford ταινιών.
Αλλες εικόνες περιλαμβάνουν τα σιωπηλά αστέρια ταινιών, ο 
αρχικός "η συμμορία μασ" που πετιέται στο άνοιγμα του θεάτρου 
Broadway, και ένα πλάνο του θεάτρου Spreckels στη νύχτα 
ενός πρεμιέρα ταινιών τρία Stooges σε 1934.As ίσχυε 
για αιώνες, άνθρωποι μουσική, λογοτεχνία, και οι τέχνες. Οι
εικόνες περιλαμβάνουν εδώ τους μουσικούς τζαζ που εκτελούν και 
ένα πορτρέτο στούντιο του Roland Hayes, που θεωρείται μια 
από τις μέγιστες γενικές ιδέες στους δημοφιλείς λογοτεχνικούς 
αριθμούς της δεκαετίας του '20 που απεικονίζονται περιλαμβάνει το 
συντάκτη Upton Sinclair, το ο οποίος βιβλίο του 1906 η 
ζούγκλα βοήθησε να βελτιώσει τη δημοφιλή πληροφόρηση για την 
επεξεργασία τροφίμων και συνέβαλε στο μεγάλο μέρος στη μετάβαση 
του νόμου επιθεώρησης κρέατος και του καθαρού νόμου τροφίμων και
φαρμάκων σε 1906, φωτογραφίες των ποιητών και των συγγραφέων 
που έγραψαν για ή κατοίκησαν σε Καλιφόρνια περιλαμβάνουν 
joaquin το μυλωνά, George Sterling, Charles Warren 
Stoddard, Robinson Jeffers, τον Edwin Markham, και 
Mary Ώστιν (που στέκεται μπροστά από μια τοιχογραφία με το 
μεξικάνικο καλλιτέχνη Diego Rivera).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchas formas de hospitalidad y de pasatiempos que
la gente participó adentro durante las décadas tempranas del 
vigésimo siglo no son ésa diferente de ésas gozamos hoy. Al 
final de la gente del siglo hospitalidad encontrada en los carnavales 
y festivales y exposiciones. Las fotografías aquí incluyen la 
exposición internacional del pleno invierno de California en San 
Francisco en 1894, y el carnaval de Anaheim de 1911. Los 
deportes eran también un pasatiempo popular. Las fotografías 
muestran a gente que participa en tenis y golf, pero los deportes 
espectadores eran también populares. En 1929, Srta. Jessie 
Darnley nadó al parecer su manera al título de Srta. Anaheim en una 
piscina llenada de tres toneladas de naranjas. Un número de 
jugadores hicieron celebridades, según lo atestiguado por los 
alambiques de la publicidad del bebé Ruth, Lou Gehrig, y Carl Klindt 
de los greats del béisbol. La electricidad y las comunicaciones
mejoradas significaron que la hospitalidad era no más larga confinada
al teatro vivo. La gente dio vuelta a la radio para la 
información y la hospitalidad. Una fotografía muestra a 
familia de un candidato democrático para senador de los E.E.U.U., 
Sheridan Downey, recolectado alrededor de la radio escuchando los 
resultados de elección. Otro representa una difusión de radio 
viva. Durante esta era la industria de la película creció en 
Hollywood, generando imágenes populares y las mitologías que 
rodeaban a las películas y a las estrellas de cine. Las 
fotografías en este grupo incluyen algunos tiros del inicio de 
agentes, de directores, y de peli'cula-hacer el equipo. 
Representan al propietario del teatro chino famoso en Hollywood,
Sid Grauman, con el actor de cine Maria Pickford. Otras 
imágenes incluyen los actores de cine silenciosos, la original 
"nuestra cuadrilla" echada en la apertura del teatro de Broadway, y un
tiro del teatro de Spreckels en la noche de una premier de la 
película de tres stooges en 1934.As había sido verdad para los 
siglos, la música gozada gente, la literatura, y los artes. Las
imágenes aquí incluyen a músicos del jazz que se realizan y un 
retrato del estudio de Roland Hayes, considerado uno de los tenores 
más grandes de las figuras literarias populares de los años 20 
representadas incluye a autor Upton Sinclair, que 1906 reservan el 
conocimiento popular ayudado selva del aumento sobre la 
transformación de los alimentos y contribuido en parte grande al paso
del acto del examen de la carne y del acto puro del alimento y de la 
droga en 1906. Las fotografías de los poetas y de los programas
de escritura que escribieron sobre o residieron en California incluyen
a Joaquín Molinero, a George esterlina, a Charles Warren Stoddard, a 
Robinson Jeffers, a Edwin Markham, y a Maria Austin (que está parada 
delante de un mural con el artista mexicano Diego Rivera).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085245</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106126</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/popular-culture</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
