<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103490</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103490</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cross Layer Identity Management</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kreuzschicht-Identität Management</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gestion En travers d'Identité De Couche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gerência Transversal Da Identidade Da Camada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gestione Trasversale Di Identità Di Strato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαγώνια διαχείριση ταυτότητας στρώματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gerencia Cruzada De la Identidad De la Capa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This video addresses the problem of today's Internet users who have to pass several authentication and authorization procedures in the usage of Internet services, due to the fact that services consumed require involvement of different service providers. Such a situation exists in a Virtual Organization environment. This video presents the state of the art in federated identity management, the need for cross layer identity management, and approaches followed within the Akogrimo project. This includes technology based on Radius/Diameter, Shibboleth, and SAML.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Bildschirm adressiert das Problem heutigen 
Internet-Benutzern, die mehrere Authentisierung und Ermächtigung 
Prozeduren im Verbrauch der Internet-Dienstleistungen führen müssen,
wegen der Tatsache, daß die verbrauchten Dienstleistungen 
Miteinbeziehung der unterschiedlichen Diensterbringer benötigen. 
Solch eine Situation existiert in einer virtuellen Organisation 
Umgebung. Dieser Bildschirm stellt den Zustand der kunst in zu 
einem Bündnis vereingigtem Identität Management, die Notwendigkeit 
am Kreuzschichtidentität Management dar, und die Annäherungen, die 
innerhalb des Akogrimo gefolgt werden, projizieren sich. Dieses 
schließt die Technologie ein, die auf Radius/Diameter, Shibboleth und
SAML basiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce vidéo adresse le problème des utilisateurs 
d'aujourd'hui d'Internet qui doivent passer à plusieurs des 
procédures d'authentification et d'autorisation dans l'utilisation 
des services d'Internet, étant donné que les services consommés 
exigent la participation de différents fournisseurs de service. 
Une telle situation existe dans un environnement virtuel 
d'organisation. Ce vidéo présente la situation actuelle dans 
la gestion fédérée d'identité, le besoin de gestion en travers 
d'identité de couche, et les approches suivies dans l'Akogrimo 
projettent. Ceci inclut la technologie basée sur 
Radius/Diameter, Doctrine, et SAML.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este vídeo dirige-se ao problema dos usuários de
hoje do Internet que têm que passar a diversos procedimentos do 
authentication e da autorização no uso de serviços do Internet,  
devido ao fato que os serviços consumidos requerem a participação 
de fornecedores de serviço diferentes. Tal situação existe em
um ambiente virtual da organização. Este vídeo apresenta o 
último modelo na gerência federada da identidade, a necessidade para
a gerência transversal da identidade da camada, e as aproximações 
seguidas dentro do Akogrimo projetam-se. Isto inclui a 
tecnologia baseada em Radius/Diameter, em Shibboleth, e em SAML.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo video richiama il problema di odierni 
utenti del Internet che devono passare vari le procedure di 
autorizzazione e di autenticazione nell'uso dei servizi del Internet, 
dato che i servizi consumati richiedono la partecipazione dei 
fornitori di servizio differenti. Una tal situazione esiste in 
un ambiente virtuale di organizzazione. Questo video presenta il
dichiarare dell'arte nella gestione federated di identità, 
l'esigenza della gestione trasversale di identità di strato ed i 
metodi seguiti all'interno del Akogrimo si proiettano. Ciò 
include la tecnologia basata su Radius/Diameter, su Shibboleth e su 
SAML.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το βίντεο εξετάζει το πρόβλημα των σημερινών 
χρηστών Διαδικτύου που πρέπει να περάσουν διάφορες διαδικασίες 
πιστοποίησης ταυτότητας και έγκρισης στη χρήση των υπηρεσιών 
Διαδικτύου, λόγω στο γεγονός ότι οι υπηρεσίες που καταναλώνονται
απαιτούν τη συμμετοχή των διαφορετικών φορέων παροχής υπηρεσιών.
Μια τέτοια κατάσταση υπάρχει σε ένα εικονικό περιβάλλον 
οργάνωσης. Αυτό το βίντεο παρουσιάζει την κατάσταση 
προόδου στη συνενωμένη σε ομοσπονδία διαχείριση ταυτότητας, την 
ανάγκη για τη διαγώνια διαχείριση ταυτότητας στρώματος, και τις 
προσεγγίσεις που ακολουθούνται μέσα στο πρόγραμμα Akogrimo. 
Αυτό περιλαμβάνει την τεχνολογία βασισμένη στην 
ακτίνα/διάμετρος, shibboleth, και SAML.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este vídeo trata el problema de los utilizadores 
de hoy del Internet que tienen que pasar varios procedimientos de la 
autentificación y de la autorización en el uso de los servicios del 
Internet,  debido al hecho de que los servicios consumidos requieren 
la implicación de diversos abastecedores de servicio. Tal 
situación existe en un ambiente virtual de la organización. 
Este vídeo presenta el estado plus ultra en la gerencia 
federada de la identidad, la necesidad de la gerencia cruzada de la 
identidad de la capa, y los acercamientos seguidos dentro del Akogrimo
proyectan. Esto incluye la tecnología basada en 
Radius/Diameter, Shibboleth, y SAML.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:HASAN
FN:HASAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103490</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cross-layer-identity-management</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
