<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104713</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104713</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1562380902</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Evergreen State: Exploring the History of Washington's Forests</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Immergrüner Zustand: Erforschen der 
Geschichte der Wälder Washingtons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">État À feuilles persistantes : Explorer 
l'histoire des forêts de Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estado Evergreen: Explorando o history de 
florestas de Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il evergreen Dichiara: Esplorazione 
della storia delle foreste de Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αειθαλές κράτος: Να ερευνήσει την ιστορία των 
δασών της Ουάσιγκτον</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estado Imperecedero: Explorar la historia de 
los bosques de Washington</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This curriculum packet consists of information and primary documents related to the history of Washington's forests. These materials are intended to provide students with an opportunity to investigate attitudes toward and uses of this natural resource. Middle school students may find some of the documents to be challenging reading, but most of the documents could profitably be used in a middle school, high school, or university course about the history of the Pacific Northwest.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Lehrplanpaket besteht aus den Informationen 
und Primärdokumenten, die auf der Geschichte von Wäldern Washingtons
in Verbindung gestanden werden. Diese Materialien sollen 
Kursteilnehmer mit einer Gelegenheit versehen, Haltung in Richtung zu 
und Gebräuche von diesen Naturresourcen nachzuforschen. 
Kursteilnehmer der mittleren Schule können einige der Dokumente
finden, um schwieriger Messwert zu sein, aber die meisten Dokumenten 
konnten in einer mittleren Schule, in der High School oder im 
Universitätskurs über die Geschichte des pazifischen Nordwestens 
rentabel benutzt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce paquet de programme d'études se compose de 
l'information et des documents primaires liés à l'histoire des 
forêts de Washington. Ces matériaux sont destinés pour 
fournir à des étudiants une occasion d'étudier des attitudes vers 
et des utilisations de cette ressource naturelle. Les étudiants
de collège peuvent trouver certains des documents pour être lecture 
provocante, mais la plupart des documents pourraient profitablement 
être utilisées dans un collège, le lycée, ou le cours 
d'université au sujet de l'histoire du nord-ouest Pacifique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este pacote do curriculum consiste na informação 
e nos originais preliminares relacionados ao history de florestas de 
Washington. Estes materiais são pretendidos fornecer estudantes
com uma oportunidade de investigar atitudes para e usos deste recurso 
natural. Os estudantes da escola média podem encontrar alguns 
dos originais para ser leitura challenging, mas a maioria dos 
originais poderiam profitably ser usados em uma escola média, na High
School, ou no curso da universidade sobre o history do noroeste 
pacífico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo pacchetto di programma di studi consiste 
delle informazioni e dei documenti primari relativi alla storia delle 
foreste de Washington. Questi materiali sono intesi per fornire 
agli allievi un'occasione studiare gli atteggiamenti verso e gli usi 
di queste risorse naturali. Gli allievi della scuola centrale 
possono trovare alcuni dei documenti per essere lettura challenging, 
ma la maggior parte dei documenti potrebbero essere usati 
proficuamente in una scuola centrale, in High School, o nel corso 
dell'università circa la storia del nord-ovest pacifico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το πακέτο προγράμματος σπουδών αποτελείται από 
τις πληροφορίες και τα αρχικά έγγραφα σχετικές με την ιστορία των
δασών της Ουάσιγκτον. Αυτά τα υλικά προορίζονται να 
παρέχουν στους σπουδαστές μια ευκαιρία να ερευνηθεί η στάση 
απέναντι και οι χρήσεις αυτού του φυσικού στοιχείου 
συμπεριφοράς. Οι μέσοι σχολικοί σπουδαστές μπορούν να 
βρούν μερικών από τα έγγραφα την ανάγνωση, αλλά τα περισσότερα 
από τα έγγραφα θα μπορούσαν επικερδώς να χρησιμοποιηθούν σε μια 
δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση, ένα γυμνάσιο, ή μια πανεπιστημιακή 
σειρά μαθημάτων για την ιστορία των ειρηνικών βορειοδυτικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este paquete del plan de estudios consiste en la 
información y los documentos primarios relacionados con la historia 
de los bosques de Washington. Estos materiales se piensan para 
proveer de estudiantes una oportunidad de investigar actitudes hacia y
aplicaciones de este recurso natural. Los estudiantes de la 
escuela media pueden encontrar algunos de los documentos para ser 
lectura desafiadora, pero la mayoría de los documentos se podrían 
utilizar provechoso en una escuela media, High School secundaria, o 
curso de la universidad sobre la historia del noroeste pacífico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1562380902</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104713</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/evergreen-state-exploring-the-history-of-washington-s-forests</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
