<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Essays Written by LGBT Students and Their Friends 2006</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Versuche geschrieben von LGBT Kursteilnehmern und 
von ihren Freunden 2006</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Essais écrits par les étudiants et leurs amis 
2006 de LGBT</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Essays escritos pelos estudantes de LGBT e pelos 
seus amigos 2006</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Saggi scritti dagli allievi del LGBT e dai loro 
amici 2006</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δοκίμια που γράφονται από LGBT τους σπουδαστές και 
τους φίλους τους 2006</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ensayos escritos por los estudiantes y sus amigos 
2006 de LGBT</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Fourteen essays by high school seniors who participated in the Queer Foundation's 2006 high school English essay contest.
Permission is hereby granted to teachers and counselors to reproduce and use these student-produced essays in their schools for educational purposes only, provided that credit is given to the Queer Foundation's Effective Writing and Scholarships Program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vierzehn Versuche durch High School seniors, die 
am eigenartigen High School der Grundlage 2006 englischen Versuch 
contest.Permission teilnahmen, wird hiermit Lehrern und Ratgebern 
bewilligt, um diese Kursteilnehmer-produzierten Versuche in ihren 
Schulen nur zu den pädagogischen Zwecken zu reproduzieren und zu 
verwenden, vorausgesetzt daß Gutschrift zum eigenartigen 
wirkungsvollen Schreiben und Gelehrsamkeit-Programm der Grundlage 
gegeben wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">On accorde par ceci quatorze essais par les 
seniors de lycée qui ont participé à l'essai anglais 
contest.Permission du lycée de la base étrange 2006 aux professeurs 
et aux conseillers pour reproduire et utiliser ces essais 
étudiant-produits dans leurs écoles pour des buts éducatifs 
seulement, à condition que le degré de solvabilité soit donné au programme 
pertinent de l'écriture et des bourses de la base étrange.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quatorze essays pelos seniors da High School que 
participaram no essay inglês contest.Permission da High School da 
fundação estranha 2006 estão concedidos por este meio aos 
professores e aos counselors para reproduzir e usar estes essays 
estudante-produzidos em suas escolas para finalidades educacionais 
somente, contanto que o crédito é dado ao programa eficaz da escrita
e dos scholarships da fundação estranha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quattordici saggi dai seniors della High School 
che hanno partecipato al saggio inglese contest.Permission della High 
School del fondamento strano 2006 è assegnato con ciò agli 
insegnanti ed ai counselors per riprodurre ed usare questi saggi 
allievo-prodotti nelle loro scuole per gli scopi educativi soltanto, a
condizione che l'accreditamento è dato al programma efficace di 
scrittura e di borse della base strana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεκατέσσερα δοκίμια από τους πρεσβυτέρους γυμνασίου 
που συμμετείχαν στην αγγλική δικαιοδοσία διαγωνισμού δοκίμιου 
γυμνασίου του 2006 του αλλόκοτου ιδρύματος χορηγούνται με το 
παρόν έγγραφο στους δασκάλους και στους συμβούλους για να 
αναπαραγάγουν και να χρησιμοποιήσουν αυτά τα 
σπουδαστής-παραχθέντα δοκίμια στα σχολεία τους για εκπαιδευτικούς
λόγους μόνο, υπό τον όρο ότι η πίστωση δίνεται του αλλόκοτου 
ιδρύματος αποτελεσματικού γράψιμο και πρόγραμμα υποτροφιών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Catorce ensayos por los seniors de la High School 
secundaria que participaron en el ensayo inglés contest.Permission de
la High School secundaria de la fundación rara 2006 se conceden por 
este medio a los profesores y a los consejeros para reproducir y para 
utilizar estos ensayos estudiante-producidos en sus escuelas para los 
propósitos educativos solamente, a condición de que el crédito se 
da al programa eficaz de la escritura y de las becas de la fundación 
rara.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:QUEER FOUNDATION
FN:QUEER FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Queer Foundation Educational-User License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108796</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lgbt-student-essays-2006</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
