<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105877</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105877</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087233</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">White Slaveowners Fear that the Haitian Revolution Has Arrived in Charleston, South Carolina, 1797</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weiße Slaveowners Furcht, daß die haitianische 
Umdrehung in Charleston angekommen ist, Südcarolina, 1797</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Crainte blanche de Slaveowners que la révolution 
haïtienne est arrivée à Charleston, Caroline du sud, 1797</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Medo branco que a volta haitian chegou em 
Charleston, carolina sul de Slaveowners, 1797</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Timore bianco che la rivoluzione haitian è 
arrivato a Charleston, Carolina del Sud, 1797 di Slaveowners</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ασπρος Slaveowners φόβος ότι η αϊτινή επανάσταση 
έχει φθάσει στο Τσάρλεστον, νότια Καρολίνα, 1797</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Miedo blanco que la revolución haitiana ha 
llegado en Charleston, Carolina del Sur, 1797 de Slaveowners</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the American South, slaves were typically dispersed among large populations of armed and vigilant whites. As a result, American slave rebellions failed to achieve their goals. This was not the case in the West Indies, where plantation owners remained at home in Europe and left overseers in charge of large populations of slaves. In 1791, a revolution began on the island of St. Domingo (Hispaniola, the home of Haiti and the Dominican Republic). In 1804, after years of fighting, the Republic of Haiti, a black republic composed of former slaves, freed itself from France. News of the Haitian revolution was an inspiration for American slaves but a source of severe anxiety for their masters. The arrival of Haitian refugees--black, white, and mulatto--in American port cities, including Charleston, increased masters' fear that the black revolution would spread to the United States. Slaveowners cracked down, jumpily interpreting every transgression as an uprising in the making.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im amerikanischen Süden wurden Sklaven gewöhnlich
unter großen Bevölkerungen des bewaffneten und aufmerksamen Weiß 
zerstreut. Infolgedessen konnten amerikanische Sklavenaufstände
ihre Ziele erzielen nicht. Dieses war nicht der Fall in den 
Westinseln, in denen Plantageinhaber zu Hause in Europa und in den 
linken Aufsehern verantwortlich für große Bevölkerungen der Sklaven
blieben. 1791 fing eine Umdrehung auf der Insel von Str. Domingo
an (Hispaniola, das Haus von Haiti und die Dominikanische Republik). 
1804 nach Jahren des Kämpfens, die Republik von Haiti, eine 
schwarze Republik bestanden aus ehemaligen Sklaven, freigegeben von 
Frankreich. Nachrichten der haitianischen Umdrehung waren eine 
Inspiration für amerikanische Sklaven aber eine Quelle der strengen 
Angst für ihre Meister. Die Ankunft der haitianischen 
schwarzen, weißen und Mulatto Flüchtlinge -- -- in den 
amerikanischen Portstädte, einschließlich Charleston, erhöhte 
Furcht der Meister, die die schwarze Umdrehung in die Vereinigten 
Staaten verbreiten würde. Slaveowners knackte unten und jumpily
deutete jeden Transgression als Aufstieg im Bilden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les Sud américains, des esclaves ont 
été typiquement dispersés parmi de grandes populations des blancs 
armés et vigilants. En conséquence, les rébellions 
slaves américaines n'ont pas réalisé leurs buts. Ce 
n'était pas le cas en Indes occidentales, où les propriétaires de 
plantation sont restés à la maison dans l'Europe et les contrôleurs
gauches responsable de grandes populations des esclaves. En 
1791, une révolution a commencé sur l'île de la rue Domingo 
(Hispaniola, la maison du Haïti et République Dominicaine 
dominicaine). En 1804, après des années du combat, la 
République du Haïti, une république noire composée d'anciens 
esclaves, libéré de France. Les nouvelles de la révolution 
haïtienne étaient une inspiration pour des esclaves américains mais
une source d'inquiétude grave pour leurs maîtres. L'arrivée 
des réfugiés haïtiens -- noirs, blancs, et mulâtre -- dans les 
villes gauches américaines, y compris Charleston, a augmenté la 
crainte des maîtres que la révolution noire se écarterait aux 
Etats-Unis. Slaveowners a fendu vers le bas, jumpily 
interprétant chaque transgression comme soulèvement dans la 
fabrication.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No sul americano, os escravos foram dispersados 
tipicamente entre populações grandes de brancos armados e vigilant. 
Em conseqüência, as rebeliões slave americanas não 
conseguiram seus objetivos. Este não era o caso nas Índias 
ocidentais, onde os proprietários da plantação remanesceram na HOME
em Europa e em overseers esquerdos na carga de populações grandes 
dos escravos. Em 1791, uma volta começou no console de St. 
Domingo (Hispaniola, a HOME de Haiti e a república dominican). 
Em 1804, após anos da luta, a república de Haiti, uma 
república preta composta de escravos anteriores, livrado de France. 
A notícia da volta haitian era uma inspiração para escravos 
americanos mas uma fonte da ansiedade severa para seus mestres. 
A chegada dos refugees haitian -- pretos, brancos, e mulatto -- 
em cidades portuárias americanas, including Charleston, aumentou o 
medo dos mestres que a volta preta espalharia aos estados unidos. 
Slaveowners rachou para baixo, jumpily interpretando cada 
transgression como um uprising em fazer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel sud americano, gli schiavi sono stati dispersi 
tipicamente fra le grandi popolazioni dei bianchi muniti e vigilanti. 
Di conseguenza, le ribellioni slave americane non sono riuscito
a realizzare i loro obiettivi. Ciò non era il caso in Indie ad 
ovest, in cui i proprietari della piantagione sono rimasto nel paese 
in Europa ed in overseers di sinistra incaricati di grandi popolazioni
degli schiavi. In 1791, un giro ha cominciato sull'isola della 
st Domingo (Hispaniola, la sede dell'Haiti e Repubblica Domenicana). 
In 1804, dopo gli anni di combattimento, la Repubblica di Haiti, 
una repubblica nera composta di schiavi precedenti, liberato dalla 
Francia. Le notizie della rivoluzione haitian erano 
un'ispirazione per gli schiavi americani ma una sorgente di ansia 
severa per i loro supervisori. L'arrivo dei rifugiati haitian --
neri, bianchi e mulatto -- in città port americane, compreso 
Charleston, ha aumentato il timore dei supervisori che la rivoluzione 
nera spargerebbe al unito Dichiara. Slaveowners si è 
spezzato giù, jumpily interpretando ogni trasgressione come 
rivolta nel fare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στον αμερικανικό νότο, οι σκλάβοι διασκορπίστηκαν 
χαρακτηριστικά μεταξύ των μεγάλων πληθυσμών των οπλισμένων και 
άγρυπνων λευκών. Κατά συνέπεια, οι αμερικανικές εξεγέρσεις
σκλάβων απέτυχαν να επιτύχουν τους στόχους τους. Αυτό δεν 
ήταν η περίπτωση στις δυτικές Ινδίες, όπου οι ιδιοκτήτες 
φυτειών παρέμειναν στο σπίτι στην Ευρώπη και άφησαν τα 
overseers υπεύθυνα για τους μεγάλους πληθυσμούς των σκλάβων. 
Το 1791, μια επανάσταση άρχισε στο νησί του ST 
Domingo (Hispaniola, το σπίτι της Αϊτής και της δομινικανής 
Δημοκρατίας). Το 1804, μετά από τα έτη πάλης, η 
Δημοκρατία της Αϊτής, μια μαύρη δημοκρατία που αποτελείται από 
τους προηγούμενους σκλάβους, ελευθερώθηκε από τη Γαλλία. Οι
ειδήσεις της αϊτινής επανάστασης ήταν μια έμπνευση για τους 
αμερικανικούς σκλάβους αλλά μια πηγή αυστηρής ανησυχίας για τους
κυρίους τους. Η άφιξη των αϊτινών προσφύγων -- μαύρων, 
λευκών, και μιγάς -- στις αμερικανικές πόλεις λιμένων, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του Τσάρλεστον, αύξησε το φόβο των κυρίων 
ότι η μαύρη επανάσταση δια:δίδω στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. 
Το Slaveowners ράγισε κάτω, ερμηνεύοντας jumpily κάθε 
καταπάτηση ως έγερση στην παραγωγή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el sur americano, los esclavos fueron 
dispersados típicamente entre las poblaciones grandes de blancos 
armados y vigilantes. Consecuentemente, las rebeliones 
auxiliares americanas no pudieron alcanzar sus metas. Éste no 
era el caso en Indias del oeste, en donde los propietarios de la 
plantación permanecían en el país en Europa y overseers izquierdos 
a cargo de poblaciones grandes de esclavos. En 1791, una 
revolución comenzó por la isla de St. Domingo (Hispaniola, el hogar 
de Haití y la República Dominicana). En 1804, después de 
años de luchar, la república de Haití, una república negra 
integrada por esclavos anteriores, liberado de Francia. Las 
noticias de la revolución haitiana eran una inspiración para los 
esclavos americanos pero una fuente de la ansiedad severa para sus 
amos. La llegada de los refugiados haitianos -- negros, 
blancos, y mulato -- en ciudades portuarias americanas, incluyendo 
Charleston, aumentó el miedo de los amos que la revolución negra 
separaría a los Estados Unidos. Slaveowners se quebró abajo, 
jumpily interpretando cada transgresión como sublevación en la 
fabricación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087233</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105877</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/white-slaveowners-fear-that-the-haitian-revolution-has-arrived-in-charleston-south-carolina-1797</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
