<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106954</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106954</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206665</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">World War II Military Situation Maps, 1944-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weltkrieg-Militärische Situation Karten, 
1944-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cartes Militaires de Situation de la Deuxième 
guerre mondiale, 1944-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mapas Militares Da Situação Da Segunda guerra 
mundial, 1944-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programmi Militari Di Situazione Della Seconda 
guerra mondiale, 1944-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παγκόσμιος πόλεμος ΙΙ στρατιωτικοί χάρτες κατάστασης,
1944-1945</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Correspondencias Militares De la Situación De la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial, 1944-1945</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The World War II Military Situation Maps contains maps showing troop positions beginning on June 6, 1944 to July 26, 1945.  Starting with the D-Day Invasion, the maps give daily details on the military campaigns in Western Europe, showing the progress of the Allied Forces as they push towards Germany. Some of the sheets are accompanied by a declassified "G-3 Report" giving detailed information on troop positions for the period 3 Mar. 1945-26 July 1945. These maps and reports were used by the commanders of the United States forces in their evaluation of the campaigns and for planning future strategies.

The collection consists of 416 printed maps and 115 reports, the originals of which reside in the Library of Congress' Geography and Map Division.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Weltkrieg-militärischen Situation Karten 
enthält die Karten, welche die Truppepositionen zeigen, die an Juni 
6, 1944 bis Juli 26, 1945 anfangen. Beginnend mit der 
D-Taginvasion spezifizieren die Karten tägliche über die 
militärischen Kampagnen in Westeuropa und zeigen den Fortschritt der 
verbündeten Kräfte, während sie in Richtung zu Deutschland 
drücken. Einige der Blätter werden von einem deklassierten 
"Report G-3 begleitet", der ausführliche Informationen über 
Truppepositionen während der Periode März 3 1945-26 Juli 1945 gibt. 
Diese Karten und Reports wurden von den Kommandanten der 
Vereinigte Staaten Kräfte in ihrer Auswertung der Kampagnen verwendet
und für Planung besteht zukünftige strategies.The Ansammlung aus 416
gedruckten Karten und 115 Reports, dessen Vorlagen in der Bibliothek 
der Geographie der Kongresse und der Karte Abteilung sich befinden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les cartes militaires de situation de la deuxième
guerre mondiale contient des cartes montrant des positions de troupe 
commençant 6 juin 1944 juillet à 26, 1945. Commençant par 
l'invasion de jour J, les cartes donnent les détails quotidiens 
sur les campagnes militaires en Europe de l'ouest, montrant le 
progrès des forces alliées pendant qu'elles poussent vers 
l'Allemagne. Certaines des feuilles sont accompagnées "d'un 
état G-3" déclassé fournissant l'information détaillée sur des 
positions de troupe pour la période 3 mars 1945-26 juillet 1945. 
Ces cartes et états ont été employés par les commandants des
forces des Etats-Unis dans leur évaluation des campagnes et pour la 
planification la future strategies.The collection se compose de 416 
cartes imprimées et de 115 états, dont les originaux résident dans 
la bibliothèque de la géographie des congrès et de la Division de 
carte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os mapas militares da situação da segunda guerra
mundial contêm os mapas que mostram as posições da tropa que 
começam junho em 6, 1944 julho a 26, 1945. Começando com a 
invasão de D-Dia, os mapas dão detalhes diários nas campanhas 
militares em Europa ocidental, mostrando o progresso das forças 
aliadas enquanto empurram para Germany. Algumas das folhas são 
acompanhadas "por um relatório G-3 declassified" que dá informação
detalhada em posições da tropa para o período 3 março 1945-26 
julho 1945. Estes mapas e relatórios foram usados pelos 
comandantes das forças unidas dos estados em sua avaliação das 
campanhas e para o planeamento strategies.The a coleção futura 
consiste em 416 mapas impressos e em 115 relatórios, os originais de 
que residem na biblioteca da geografia dos congress' e da divisão do 
mapa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I programmi militari di situazione della seconda 
guerra mondiale contiene i programmi che mostrano le posizioni della 
truppa che cominciano il 6 giugno 1944 a 26 luglio 1945. 
Cominciando dall'invasione di D-Giorno, i programmi forniscono i
particolari quotidiani sulle campagne militari in Europa occidentale, 
mostrante il progresso delle forze alleate mentre spingono verso la 
Germania. Alcuni dei fogli sono accompagnati "da un rapporto 
G-3" declassified che fornisce le informazioni dettagliate sulle 
posizioni della truppa per il periodo il 3 marzo 1945-26 luglio del 
1945. Questi programmi e rapporti sono stati usati dai 
comandanti del unito Dichiara le forze nella loro valutazione 
delle campagne e per la progettazione strategies.The l'accumulazione 
futura consiste di 416 programmi stampati e di 115 rapporti, gli 
originali di cui risiedono nella libreria di geografia dei congressi e
di divisione del programma.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος ΙΙ στρατιωτικοί χάρτες 
κατάστασης περιέχει τους χάρτες που εμφανίζουν θέσεις 
στρατευμάτων που αρχίζουν στις 6 Ιουνίου ..1944 έως τις 26 
Ιουλίου, 1945, Αρχίζοντας από την εισβολή μέρας-μ, οι 
χάρτες δίνουν τις καθημερινές λεπτομέρειες στις στρατιωτικές 
εκστρατείες στη δυτική Ευρώπη, που εμφανίζει την πρόοδο των 
συνδεμένων δυνάμεων καθώς ωθούν προς τη Γερμανία. Μερικά 
από τα φύλλα συνοδεύονται από μια αποταξινομημένη "έκθεση γ-3" 
δίνοντας τις αναλυτικές πληροφορίες για τις θέσεις στρατευμάτων 
για την περίοδο 3 χαλούν. 1945-26 Ιούλιος 1945. 
Αυτοί οι χάρτες και εκθέσεις χρησιμοποιήθηκαν από τους 
διοικητές των Ηνωμένων δυνάμεων αξιολόγησή τους των εκστρατειών 
και για τον προγραμματισμό των μελλοντικών στρατηγικών Η 
συλλογή αποτελείται από 416 τυπωμένους χάρτες και 115 
εκθέσεις, τα πρωτότυπα των οποίων κατοικούν στη γεωγραφία 
βιβλιοθήκης των συνεδρίων και το τμήμα χαρτών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las correspondencias militares de la situación de
la Segunda Guerra Mundial contienen las correspondencias que muestran 
las posiciones de la tropa que comienzan 6 de junio de 1944 al de 
julio 26 de 1945. Comenzando con la invasión del D-Di'a, las 
correspondencias dan los detalles diarios en las campañas militares 
en Europa occidental, mostrando el progreso de las fuerzas aliadas 
mientras que empujan hacia Alemania. Algunas de las hojas son 
acompañadas por "un informe declassified G-3" que da la información 
detallada sobre las posiciones de la tropa para el período el 3 de 
Mrz. 1945-26 julio de 1945. Estas correspondencias e informes 
fueron utilizados por los comandantes de las fuerzas de Estados Unidos
en su evaluación de las campañas y para las hojas de operación 
(planning) strategies.The la colección futura consiste en 416 
correspondencias impresas y 115 informes, las originales de los cuales
residen en la biblioteca de la geografía de los congresos y de la 
división de la correspondencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206665</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106954</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/world-war-ii-military-situation-maps-1944-1945</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
