<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108604</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108604</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202613</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Navigating the Subway: Indicateur des metros</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Steuern der Untergrundbahn: Indicateur DES 
Metros</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Navigation du souterrain : Métros de DES 
d'Indicateur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Navigating o subway: Metros do DES de 
Indicateur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Navigazione del sottopassaggio: Metros del 
DES di Indicateur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πλοήγηση του υπογείου: Indicateur δες μετρος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Navegación del subterráneo: Metros del DES
de Indicateur</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Traveling in a foreign country often requires knowledge of how to use the subway to visit various points of interest in a particular city. The activity is in the form of a role-play in which one student serves as an employee at a government Tourist Office. The other plays the role of a tourist who wants to go to a particular location within the city. He must convey this information to the employee in the target language. The employee then inputs the information into the program and orally gives the directions to the tourist.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>fr</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Reisen in ein Ausland benötigt häufig Wissen
von, wie man die Untergrundbahn benutzt, um verschiedene Punkte des 
Interesses an einer bestimmten Stadt zu besuchen. Die Aktivität
ist in Form der Rolle, in der ein Kursteilnehmer als Angestellter in 
einem Regierung touristischen Büro dient. Das andere spielt die
Rolle eines Touristen, der zu einem bestimmten Standort innerhalb der 
Stadt gehen möchte. Er muß diese Informationen zum 
Angestellten in der Zielsprache übermitteln. Der Angestellte 
gibt dann die Informationen in das Programm ein und gibt dem Touristen
mündlich die Richtungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le déplacement dans un pays étranger exige 
souvent la connaissance de la façon utiliser le souterrain pour 
visiter de divers points d'intérêt pour une ville particulière. 
L'activité est sous forme de jouer un rôle dans lequel un 
étudiant sert d'employé à un bureau de tourisme de gouvernement. 
L'autre joue le rôle d'un touriste qui veut aller à un 
emplacement particulier dans la ville. Il doit donner cette 
information à l'employé dans la langue cible. L'employé entre
alors l'information dans le programme et donne oralement les 
directions au touriste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Viajar em um país extrangeiro requer 
frequentemente o conhecimento de como usar o subway visitar vários 
pontos do interesse em uma cidade particular. A atividade está 
no formulário de um role-play em que um estudante serve como um 
empregado em um escritório tourist do governo. O outro joga o 
papel de um turista que queira ir a uma posição particular dentro da
cidade. Deve fazer saber a esta informação ao empregado na 
língua de alvo. O empregado inputs então a informação no 
programa e dá oral os sentidos ao turista.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Viaggiando in un paese straniero richiede spesso 
la conoscenza di come utilizzare il sottopassaggio per visitare i vari
punti di interesse in una città particolare. L'attività è 
sotto forma d'un atteggiamento in cui un allievo serve da impiegato ad
un ufficio turistico di governo. L'altro svolge il ruolo di un 
turista che desidera andare ad una posizione particolare all'interno 
della città. Deve trasportare queste informazioni all'impiegato
nella lingua di arrivo. L'impiegato allora immette le 
informazioni nel programma ed oralmente dà i sensi al turista.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ταξίδι σε μια ξένη χώρα απαιτεί συχνά τη γνώση 
για το πώς να χρησιμοποιήσει τον υπόγειο για να επισκεφτεί τα 
διάφορα σημεία ενδιαφέροντος για μια ιδιαίτερη πόλη. Η 
δραστηριότητα είναι υπό μορφή ρόλος-παιχνιδιού στο οποίο ένας 
σπουδαστής χρησιμεύει ως ένας υπάλληλος σε ένα γραφείο 
κυβερνητικών τουριστών. Αλλος διαδραματίζει το ρόλο ενός 
τουρίστα που θέλει να πάει σε μια ιδιαίτερη θέση μέσα στην 
πόλη. Πρέπει να μεταβιβάσει αυτές τις πληροφορίες στον 
υπάλληλο στη γλώσσα στόχο. Ο υπάλληλος εισάγει έπειτα τις 
πληροφορίες στο πρόγραμμα και δίνει προφορικά τις κατευθύνσεις 
στον τουρίστα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El viajar en un país extranjero requiere a menudo
conocimiento de cómo utilizar el subterráneo para visitar varias 
puntas del interés en una ciudad determinada. La actividad 
está en la forma de una actuación de papeles en la cual un 
estudiante sirva como empleado en una oficina de turismo del gobierno.
El otro desempeña el papel de un turista que desee ir a una 
localización determinada dentro de la ciudad. Él debe 
transportar esta información al empleado en la lengua objetivo. 
El empleado entonces entra la información en el programa y da 
oral las direcciones al turista.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BOBBY HOBGOOD
FN:BOBBY HOBGOOD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202613</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108604</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/navigating-the-subway-indicateur-des-metros</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
