<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103336</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103336</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207128</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Astro-Venture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Astro-Wagnis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Astro-Entreprise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Astro-Risco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Astro-Impresa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αστρο-επιχείρηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Astro-Empresa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides interactive tutorials on biology, geology, astronomy, and atmospheric sciences. Biology topics include ecosystems, energy, producers and consumers, and the cycle of matter. Geology topics include the effects of heat and pressure on states of matter, density, convection, plate tectonics, volcanoes, the carbon cycle, earth's magnetic field, and radiation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt interaktive Tutorials auf Biologie, 
Geologie, Astronomie und atmosphärischen Wissenschaften zur 
Verfügung. Biologiethemen schließen Oekosysteme, Energie, 
Produzenten und Verbraucher und die Schleife des Stoffes ein. 
Geologiethemen schließen die Wärmewirkungen und Druck auf 
Zuständen des Stoffes, Dichte, Konvektion, Plattentektonik, Vulkane, 
die Carbonschleife ein, bedeckten magnetisches auffangen und 
Strahlung mit Erde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des cours d'instruction interactifs sur la
biologie, la géologie, l'astronomie, et les sciences atmosphériques.
Les sujets de biologie incluent des écosystèmes, énergie, des
producteurs et des consommateurs, et le cycle de la matière. 
Les sujets de géologie incluent les effets de la chaleur et de 
la pression sur des états de matière, densité, convection, 
tectonique de plat, volcans, le cycle de carbone, ont mis à la terre 
le champ magnétique, et le rayonnement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece tutorials interativos na biologia, na 
geologia, na astronomia, e em ciências atmosféricas. Os 
tópicos da biologia incluem ecosystems, energia, produtores e 
consumidores, e o ciclo da matéria. Os tópicos da geologia 
incluem os efeitos de calor e de pressão em estados da matéria, 
densidade, convection, tectonics de placa, vulcões, o ciclo de 
carbono, ligaram à terra o campo magnético, e a radiação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni private interattive su 
biologia, sulla geologia, sull'astronomia e sulle scienze 
atmosferiche. I soggetti di biologia includono gli ecosistemi, 
energia, produttori e consumatori ed il ciclo della materia. I 
soggetti di geologia includono gli effetti del calore e la pressione 
sopra dichiara della materia, la densità, la convezione, la 
tettonica di piastra, i vulcani, il ciclo di carbonio, ha interrato il
campo magnetico e la radiazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα διαλογικά σεμινάρια στη βιολογία, τη 
γεωλογία, την αστρονομία, και τις ατμοσφαιρικές επιστήμες. 
Τα θέματα της βιολογίας περιλαμβάνουν τα οικοσυστήματα, την 
ενέργεια, τους παραγωγούς και τους καταναλωτές, και τον κύκλο της 
ύλης. Τα θέματα γεωλογίας περιλαμβάνουν τα αποτελέσματα της
θερμότητας και της πίεσης στις καταστάσεις του θέματος, της 
πυκνότητας, της μεταφοράς, της τεκτονικής πιάτων, των ηφαιστείων,
του κύκλου άνθρακα, του γήινου μαγνητικού πεδίου, και της 
ακτινοβολίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a guías interactivas en biología, la
geología, la astronomía, y ciencias atmosféricas. Los asuntos
de la biología incluyen ecosistemas, energía, los productores y los 
consumidores, y el ciclo de la materia. Los asuntos de la 
geología incluyen los efectos de calor y presión en estados de la 
materia, densidad, convección, tectónica de placa, volcanes, el 
ciclo de carbón, conectaron a tierra el campo magnético, y la 
radiación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207128</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103336</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/astro-venture</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
