<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107290</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086666</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"No Negroes Allowed": Segregation at the Front in World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Keine Schwarzen Erlaubt": Abtrennung an der 
Frontseite im Ersten Weltkrieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Aucuns Nègres Permis" : Ségrégation à 
l'avant dans la Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nenhuns Negroes Permitidos": Segregation na 
parte dianteira no world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Nessun Negroes Permessi": Segregazione alla 
parte anteriore nel world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Νέγρος που επιτρέπεται κανένασ": Διαχωρισμός 
στο μέτωπο στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ningunos Negros Permitidos": Segregación en
el frente en Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this excerpt from Two Colored Women with the American Expeditionary Forces , Addie W. Hunton and Kathryn M. Johnson told the story of black soldiers and canteen workers. Sponsored by the YMCA and other charitable organizations, canteens were efforts to maintain soldiers' morale and to keep them from vice. Their account commemorated and celebrated African-American participation in the war, even as it noted segregation and discrimination within the effort to "save the world for democracy." The YMCA was one of a very few examples of interracial effort and cooperation during this period; nonetheless, Hunton and Johnson note that some workers of the organization failed to live up to its ideals. German propaganda directed to African-American soldiers used such examples of racism to decry the hypocrisy of the United States and to exhort black soldiers to surrender to the German army.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Excerpt von zwei farbigen Frauen mit den 
amerikanischen Expeditionary Kräften, erklärten Addie W. Hunton und 
Kathryn M. Johnson die Geschichte der schwarzen Soldaten und der 
Kantinearbeiter. Gefördert durch das YMCA und andere 
barmherzige Organisationen, waren Kantinen Bemühungen, Moral der 
Soldaten beizubehalten und sie vom Laster zu halten. Ihr Konto 
gedachte und feierte Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Teilnahme am Krieg, 
selbst als es beachtete Abtrennung und Unterscheidung innerhalb der 
Bemühung "außer der Welt für Demokratie." Das YMCA war eins 
von sehr wenige Beispiele der interracial Bemühung und der Mitarbeit 
während dieser Periode; nichtsdestoweniger beachten Hunton und 
Johnson, daß einige Arbeiter der Organisation bis zu seinen Idealen 
leben nicht konnten. Die deutsche Propaganda, die auf 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Soldaten verwiesen wurde, verwendete solche 
Beispiele von Rassismus, um die Hypokrisie der Vereinigten Staaten
herabzusetzen und exhort schwarze Soldaten, der deutschen Armee zu 
übergeben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cet extrait de deux femmes colorées avec les 
forces Expéditionnaires américaines, Addie W. Hunton et M. Johnson de
Kathryn ont indiqué l'histoire des soldats et des ouvriers noirs de 
cantine. Commandité par le YMCA et d'autres organismes 
charitables, les cantines étaient des efforts de mettre à jour le 
moral des soldats et de les garder du vice. Leur compte a 
commémoré et a célébré la participation afro-américaine à la 
guerre, même pendant qu'il ségrégation et discrimination 
remarquables dans l'effort "économiser le monde pour la démocratie."
Le YMCA était un d'très peu d'exemples d'effort et de 
coopération interracial pendant cette période ; néanmoins, 
Hunton et Johnson notent que quelques ouvriers de l'organisation 
n'ont pas vécu jusqu'à ses idéaux. La propagande allemande 
dirigée vers les soldats afro-américains a employé de tels exemples du 
racisme pour décrier l'hypocrisie des Etats-Unis et recommandez 
instamment les soldats noirs de se rendre à l'armée allemande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste excerpt de duas mulheres coloridas com as 
forças expeditionary americanas, Addie W. Hunton e Kathryn M. Johnson
disseram a história de soldados e de trabalhadores pretos da cantina.
Patrocinado pelo YMCA e por outras organizações charitable, as
cantinas eram esforços manter o morale dos soldados e mantê-los do 
vice. Seu cliente comemorou e comemorou a participação 
Africano-Americana na guerra, mesmo como ele segregation e 
discriminação notáveis dentro do esforço "excepto o mundo para a 
democracia." O YMCA era um do muito poucos exemplos do esforço 
e da cooperação interracial durante este período; 
nonetheless, Hunton e Johnson anotam que alguns trabalhadores da
organização não viveram até seus ideals. O propaganda 
alemão dirigido aos soldados Africano-Americanos usou tais exemplos 
do racism decry o hypocrisy dos estados unidos e exhort soldados 
pretos render-se ao exército alemão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo brano da due donne colorate con le forze 
expeditionary americane, Addie W. Hunton e Kathryn M. Johnson hanno 
detto alla storia dei soldati e degli operai neri dello spaccio di 
bevande. Promosso dal YMCA e da altre organizzazioni 
caritatevoli, gli spacci di bevande erano sforzi effettuare il morale 
dei soldati e mantenerli da vizio. Il loro cliente ha 
commemorato e celebrato la partecipazione Africano-Americana alla 
guerra, proprio mentre esso segregazione e distinzione celebri 
all'interno dello sforzo "risparmi il mondo per la democrazia." 
Il YMCA era uno dell'molto pochi esempi di sforzo e della 
cooperazione interracial durante questo periodo; ciò 
nonostante, Hunton e Johnson notano che alcuni operai 
dell'organizzazione non sono riuscito a vivere fino ai relativi 
ideali. La propaganda tedesca diretta verso i soldati 
Africano-Americani ha usato tali esempi del razzismo per denigrare 
l'ipocrisia del unito Dichiara ed exhort i soldati neri cedere 
all'esercito tedesco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από δύο έγχρωμες γυναίκες με 
τις αμερικανικές εξερευνητικές δυνάμεις, Addie Θ*Ω. Hunton 
και Kathryn Μ. Johnson είπαν την ιστορία των μαύρων 
στρατιωτών και των εργαζομένων καντίνων. Υποστηριγμένες από
το YMCA και άλλες φιλανθρωπικές οργανώσεις, οι καντίνες ήταν 
προσπάθειες να διατηρηθεί το ηθικό των στρατιωτών και να 
κρατηθούν από την κακία. Ο απολογισμός τους τίμησε την 
μνήμη και γιόρτασε της αφρικανικός-αμερικανικής συμμετοχής στον 
πόλεμο, ακόμη και δεδομένου ότι σημείωσε το διαχωρισμό και τη 
διάκριση μέσα στην προσπάθεια "εκτός από τον κόσμο για τη 
δημοκρατία." Το YMCA ήταν ενός υμθα από πολύ λίγα 
παραδείγματα της διαφυλετικών προσπάθειας και της συνεργασίας 
κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της περιόδου  εν τούτοις, Hunton 
και Johnson σημειώνουν ότι μερικοί εργαζόμενοι της οργάνωσης 
απέτυχαν να ζήσουν μέχρι τα ιδανικά του. Η γερμανική 
προπαγάνδα που κατευθύνθηκε στους αφρικανικός-αμερικανικούς 
στρατιώτες χρησιμοποίησε τέτοια παραδείγματα του ρατσισμού για να
επικρίνει την υποκρισία των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών και για να 
προτρέψει τους μαύρους στρατιώτες παραδίνω στο γερμανικό στρατό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este extracto a partir de dos mujeres coloreadas
con las fuerzas expedicionarias americanas, Addie W. Hunton y Kathryn 
M. Johnson contaron la historia de soldados y de trabajadores negros 
de la cantina. Patrocinado por el YMCA y otras organizaciones 
caritativas, las cantinas eran esfuerzos de mantener la moral de los 
soldados y de guardarlas de vicio. Su cuenta conmemoró y 
celebró la participación Africano-Americana en la guerra, incluso 
como ella segregación y discriminación conocidas dentro del esfuerzo
"excepto el mundo para la democracia." El YMCA era uno de muy 
pocos ejemplos del esfuerzo y de la cooperación interracial durante 
este período; no obstante, Hunton y Johnson observan que 
algunos trabajadores de la organización no pudieron vivir hasta sus 
ideales. La propaganda alemana dirigida a los soldados 
Africano-Americanos utilizó tales ejemplos del racismo para denigrar 
la hipocresía de los Estados Unidos y suplique a soldados negros que 
se entreguen al ejército alemán.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086666</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107290</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/no-negroes-allowed-segregation-at-the-front-in-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
