<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107803</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107803</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086902</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Bloody Massacre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Blutige Blutbad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Massacre Sanglant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Massacre Sangrento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Massacre Sanguinante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αιματηρή σφαγή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Masacre Sangrienta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With ongoing protests against the Townshend Duties, waterfront jobs scarce due to nonimportation, and poorly-paid, off-duty British troops competing for jobs, clashes between American laborers and British troops became frequent after 1768. In Boston, tensions mounted rapidly in 1770 until a confrontation left five Boston workers dead when panicky troops fired into a crowd. This print issued by Paul Revere three weeks after the incident and widely reproduced depicted his version of what was quickly dubbed the Boston Massacre." Showing the incident as a deliberate act of murder by the British army</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit fortwährenden Protesten gegen die Townshend 
Aufgaben, knappes wurden der Ufergegendjobs wegen des nonimportation 
und die schlecht-zahlenden, dienstfreien britischen Truppen, die für 
Jobs konkurrieren, das Zusammentreffen zwischen amerikanischen 
Arbeitern und britischen Truppen nach 1768 häufig. In Boston 
hingen Spannkräfte schnell 1770 bis eine Konfrontation nach links 
fünf Boston Arbeiter absolut als die panischen Truppen ein, die in 
eine Masse gefeuert wurden. Dieser Druck herausgegeben von Paul 
Revere, drei Wochen nachdem das Ereignis und weit reproduziert 
bildlich dargestellt seiner Version von, was wurde schnell betitelt 
dem Boston Blutbad." Zeigen des Ereignisses als überlegte Tat 
des Mordes durch die britische Armee</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec des protestations continues contre les 
fonctions de Townshend, en raison rare des travaux de bord de mer du 
nonimportation, et les troupes britanniques pauvre-payées et en 
congé concurrençant pour les travaux, les désaccords entre les 
travailleurs américains et les troupes britanniques sont devenus 
fréquents après 1768. À Boston, les tensions ont monté 
rapidement en 1770 jusqu'à une confrontation à gauche cinq ouvriers 
de Boston complètement quand les troupes paniquées mises le feu dans
une foule. Cette copie émise par Paul vénérer trois semaines 
après que l'incident et largement reproduit représenté sa version 
de ce qui a été rapidement doublé le Massacre de Boston." 
Montrer l'incident comme acte délibéré de meurtre par 
l'armée britannique</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com protestos ongoing de encontro aos deveres de 
Townshend,  escasso dos trabalhos do waterfront devido ao 
nonimportation, e as tropas britânicas deficiente-pagas, off-duty que
competem para trabalhos, os clashes entre laborers americanos e tropas
britânicas tornaram-se freqüentes após 1768. Em Boston, as 
tensões montaram ràpidamente em 1770 até um confrontation à 
esquerda cinco trabalhadores de Boston absolutamente quando as tropas 
panicky ateadas fogo em uma multidão. Esta cópia emitida por 
Paul Revere três semanas depois que o incident e reproduzido 
extensamente descrito sua versão de o que dubbed rapidamente o 
massacre de Boston." Mostrando o incident como um ato deliberado
do assassinato pelo exército britânico</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con le proteste continue contro le funzioni di 
Townshend, limitato di lavori de waterfront dovuto il nonimportation e
le truppe britanniche scarso-poorly-paid e off-duty che competono per 
i lavori, i disaccordi fra i lavoratori americani e le truppe 
britanniche sono diventato frequenti dopo 1768. A Boston, i 
tensionamenti hanno montato velocemente in 1770 fino ad un confronto a
sinistra cinque operai de Boston completamente quando truppe 
dettate dal panico infornate in una folla. Questa stampa pubblicata da 
Paul Revere tre settimane dopo che l'avvenimento ed ampiamente 
riprodotto rappresentato la sua versione di che cosa rapidamente 
dubbed il massacre de Boston." Mostrare l'avvenimento come atto 
intenzionale dell'omicidio dall'esercito britannico</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με τις τρέχουσες διαμαρτυρίες ενάντια στα καθήκοντα 
Townshend, οι εργασίες προκυμαιών λιγοστές λόγω στο 
nonimportation, και τα κακώς-πληρωμένα, εκτός υπηρεσίας 
βρετανικά στρατεύματα που ανταγωνίζονται για τις εργασίες, τις 
διαφωνίες μεταξύ των αμερικανικών laborers και τα βρετανικά 
στρατεύματα έγιναν συχνές μετά από 1768. Στη Βοστώνη, 
οι εντάσεις επικόλλησαν γρήγορα το 1770 έως ότου άφησε μια 
αντιμετώπιση πέντε εργαζομένους της Βοστώνης νεκρούς όταν 
έβαλαν φωτιά τα πανικόβλητα στρατεύματα σε ένα πλήθος. 
Αυτή η τυπωμένη ύλη που εκδίδεται από Paul Revere 
τρεις εβδομάδες μετά από το γεγονός και που αναπαράγεται ευρέως 
απεικονισμένος την έκδοση αυτό που του μεταγλωττίστηκε γρήγορα τη
σφαγή της Βοστώνης." Εμφάνιση του γεγονότος ως σκόπιμη 
πράξη της δολοφονίας από το βρετανικό στρατό</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con protestas en curso contra los deberes de 
Townshend,  escaso de los trabajos de la línea de costa debido al 
nonimportation, y las tropas británicas pobre-pagadas, fuera de 
servicio que competían para los trabajos, los choques entre los 
trabajadores americanos y las tropas británicas llegaron a ser 
frecuentes después de 1768. En Boston, las tensiones montaron 
rápidamente en 1770 hasta una confrontación a la izquierda a cinco 
trabajadores de Boston absolutamente cuando las tropas panicky 
encendidas en una muchedumbre. Esta impresión publicada por 
Paul venerar tres semanas después de que el incidente y reproducido 
extensamente representado su versión de qué rápidamente fue doblada
la Masacre de Boston." Mostrar el incidente como acto 
deliberado del asesinato del ejército británico</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086902</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107803</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-bloody-massacre</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
