<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107652</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107652</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209815</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Circumference of a circle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Umkreis eines Kreises</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Circonférence d'un cercle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Circunferência de um círculo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Circonferenza di un cerchio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιφέρεια ενός κύκλου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Circunferencia de un círculo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the circumference of a circle. The applet shows a circle with a radius line. The radius endpoints are draggable and the circle is resized accordingly. The formula relating radius to circumference is updated continually as you drag. Introduces the idea of Pi. The formula can be hidden for class discussion and estimation. See also the entries for circumference and diameter. See also entries for radius and diameter. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die den Umkreis eines Kreises zeigen. Der applet zeigt
einen Kreis mit einer Radiuszeile. Die Radiusendpunkte sind 
draggable und der Kreis wird dementsprechend die Größe neu bestimmt.
Die Formel, die Radius auf Umkreis in Verbindung steht, wird 
fortwährend aktualisiert, während Sie schleppen. Stellt die 
Idee von PU vor. Die Formel kann für Kategorie Diskussion und 
Schätzung versteckt werden. Sehen Sie auch die Einträge für 
Umkreis und Durchmesser. Sehen Sie auch Einträge für Radius 
und Durchmesser. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch
mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent la circonférence d'un cercle. L'applet montre 
un cercle avec une ligne de rayon. Les points finaux de rayon 
sont draggable et le cercle est remis à la côte en conséquence. 
La formule associant le rayon à la circonférence est mise à 
jour continuellement pendant que vous traînez. Présente 
l'idée de pi. La formule peut être cachée pour la discussion 
et l'évaluation de classe. Voyez également les entrées pour 
la circonférence et le diamètre. Voir également les entrées 
pour le rayon et le diamètre. L'applet peut être agrandi à la
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem a circunferência de um círculo. O applet mostra um 
círculo com uma linha do raio. Os endpoints do raio são 
draggable e o círculo resized conformemente. A fórmula que 
relaciona o raio à circunferência está atualizada continuamente 
enquanto você arrasta. Introduz a idéia do Pi. A 
fórmula pode ser escondida para a discussão e o estimation da 
classe. Veja também as entradas para a circunferência e o 
diâmetro. Veja também entradas para o raio e o diâmetro. 
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano la circonferenza di un cerchio. Il applet mostra un 
cerchio con una riga del raggio. I punti finali del raggio sono 
draggable ed il cerchio è ridimensionato di conseguenza. La 
formula che collega il raggio alla circonferenza è aggiornata 
continuamente mentre vi trascinate. Introduce l'idea del pi. 
La formula può essere nascosta per la discussione e la 
valutazione del codice categoria. Veda inoltre le entrate per la
circonferenza ed il diametro. Veda inoltre le entrate per il 
raggio ed il diametro. Il applet può essere ingrandito al 
formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την περιφέρεια ενός κύκλου. Το applet 
εμφανίζει έναν κύκλο με μια γραμμή ακτίνας. Τα σημεία 
τέλους ακτίνας είναι draggable και ο κύκλος επαναταξινομείται 
αναλόγως. Ο τύπος που αφορά την ακτίνα την περιφέρεια 
ενημερώνεται συνεχώς καθώς σέρνετε. Εισάγει την ιδέα του 
pi. Ο τύπος μπορεί να κρυφτεί για τη συζήτηση και την 
εκτίμηση κλάσης. Δείτε επίσης τις καταχωρήσεις 
για την περιφέρεια και τη διάμετρο. Δείτε επίσης 
τις καταχωρήσεις για την ακτίνα και τη διάμετρο. Το Applet
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran la circunferencia de un círculo. El applet muestra 
un círculo con una línea del radio. Las puntos finales del 
radio son draggable y el círculo se vuelve a clasificar según el 
tamaño por consiguiente. El fórmula que relaciona el radio con
la circunferencia se pone al día continuamente mientras que usted 
arrastra. Introduce la idea del pi. El fórmula se puede 
ocultar para la discusión y la valoración de la clase. Vea 
también las entradas para la circunferencia y el diámetro. Vea
también las entradas para el radio y el diámetro. El applet se
puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209815</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107652</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/circumference-of-a-circle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
