<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Computational Biology: Bioinformatics Unit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Berechnungsbiologie: Bioinformatics 
Maßeinheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Biologie de calcul : Unité De 
Bioinformatics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biologia Computacional: Unidade De 
Bioinformatics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Biologia Di calcolo: Unità Di 
Bioinformatics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η υπολογιστική βιολογία: Μονάδα βιοπληροφορικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biología De cómputo: Unidad De 
Bioinformatics</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features an undergraduate Computational Biology course as part of the Red Layer Microbial Observatory (RLMO) Project's Original Waksman/NSF supported courses and workshops. The course is offered as part of RLMO's education and outreach in order to better prepare students in the widely-applicable field of computational biology. Unit outlines, the syllabus, the project, and presentations and manuscripts about this curriculum can all be downloaded on site. Units include using NCBI, using BW/Datasets, multiple sequence alignment, phylogenetic tree-building, and protein structure. The website also features an image and data (3D viewer required) of the structure of ribosomal proteins and 16S rRNA from T. thermophilus.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale ein Nichtgraduierter 
Berechnungsbiologiekurs als Teil des rote Schicht-Mikrobensternwarte 
(RLMO) ursprünglichen Waksman/NSF unterstützten der Kurse und der 
Werkstätten Projektes. Der Kurs wird als Teil der Ausbildung 
RLMOs angeboten und übertrifft, um Kursteilnehmer im 
breit-anwendbaren besser vorzubereiten auffangen von der 
Berechnungsbiologie. Maßeinheit umreißen, der Syllabus, das 
Projekt und die Darstellungen und die Manuskripte über diesen 
Lehrplan können alle auf Site downloadet werden. Maßeinheiten 
schließen mit NCBI mit BW/Datasets, mehrfacher Reihenfolge 
Ausrichtung, phylogenetischem Baum-Gebäude und Proteinstruktur ein. 
Die Web site kennzeichnet auch ein Bild und Daten (den Projektor
3D benötigt) der Struktur der ribosomal Proteine und des rRNA 16S von
thermophilem T..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs de ce site un cours de calcul de 
biologie d'étudiant préparant une licence en tant qu'élément des 
cours supportés par Waksman/NSF initiaux et des ateliers du projet 
microbien de l'observatoire de couche rouge (RLMO). Le cours est
offert en tant qu'élément de l'éducation de RLMO et dépasse afin 
de préparer mieux des étudiants dans le domaine large-applicable de 
la biologie de calcul. Des contours d'unité, le programme, le 
projet, et des présentations et les manuscrits au sujet de ce 
programme d'études peuvent tout être téléchargés sur le site. 
Les unités incluent en utilisant NCBI, en utilisant 
BW/Datasets, cadrage multiple d'ordre, arbre-bâtiment 
phylogénétique, et structure de protéine. Le site Web 
comporte également une image et des données (visualisateur 3D 
requis) de la structure des protéines et du rRNA 16S ribosomal du T. 
thermophile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Características deste local um curso 
computacional da biologia do undergraduate enquanto a parte do 
Waksman/NSF original do projeto microbial do obervatório da camada 
vermelha (RLMO) suportou cursos e oficinas. O curso é oferecido
como a parte da instrução de RLMO e excede a fim preparar mais 
melhor estudantes no campo largo-aplicável da biologia computacional.
Os esboços da unidade, o syllabus, o projeto, e as 
apresentações e os manuscritos sobre este curriculum podem tudo 
downloaded no local. As unidades incluem usando NCBI, usando 
BW/Datasets, o alinhamento múltiplo da seqüência, o 
árvore-edifício phylogenetic, e a estrutura da proteína. O 
Web site caracteriza também uma imagem e uns dados (visor 3D 
requerido) da estrutura de proteínas e do rRNA 16S ribosomal do T. 
thermophilus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo un corso di 
calcolo di biologia dello studente non laureato come componente del 
Waksman/NSF originale di strato rosso del progetto microbico 
dell'osservatorio (RLMO) hanno sostenuto i corsi ed i workshop. 
Il corso è offerto come componente di formazione del RLMO e 
supera per preparare più meglio gli allievi nel campo 
largo-applicabile di biologia di calcolo. I profili dell'unità,
il programma, il progetto e le presentazioni ed i manoscritti circa 
questo programma di studi possono tutti essere trasferiti sul luogo. 
Le unità includono usando NCBI, usando BW/Datasets, 
l'allineamento multiplo di sequenza, la albero-costruzione 
filogenetica e la struttura della proteina. Il Web site 
egualmente caratterizza un'immagine ed i dati (visore 3D richiesto) 
della struttura delle proteine e del rRNA ribosomal 16S dal T. 
termofilo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει έναν προπτυχιακό φοιτητή
που η υπολογιστική σειρά μαθημάτων της βιολογίας ως τμήμα του 
αρχικών Waksman/toy NSF του κόκκινου στρώματος μικροβιακού 
προγράμματος παρατηρητήριων (RLMO) υποστήριξε τις σειρές 
μαθημάτων και τα εργαστήρια. Η σειρά μαθημάτων προσφέρεται 
ως τμήμα της εκπαίδευσης RLMO και ξεπερνά προκειμένου να 
προετοιμαστούν καλύτερα οι σπουδαστές στο ευρέως-εφαρμόσιμο 
πεδίο της υπολογιστικής βιολογίας. Τα περιγράμματα μονάδων,
η διδακτέα ύλη, το πρόγραμμα, και οι παρουσιάσεις και τα 
χειρόγραφα για αυτό το πρόγραμμα σπουδών μπορούν όλες να 
μεταφορτωθούν στην περιοχή. Οι μονάδες περιλαμβάνουν τη 
χρησιμοποίηση NCBI, χρησιμοποιώντας το bw/ta σύνολα 
δεδομένων, την πολλαπλάσια ευθυγράμμιση ακολουθίας, το 
φυλογενετικό δέντρο-κτήριο, και την πρωτεϊνική δομή. Ο 
ιστοχώρος χαρακτηρίζει επίσης μια εικόνα και ένα στοιχείο 
(τρισδιάστατη εμφάνιση που απαιτείται) της δομής των 
ριβοσωματικών πρωτεϊνών και 16S rRNA από το Τ. 
thermophilus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de este sitio un curso de 
cómputo de la biología del estudiante como parte de los cursos 
utilizados Waksman/NSF originales y de los talleres de la capa roja 
del proyecto microbiano del observatorio (RLMO). El curso se 
ofrece como parte de la educación de RLMO y excede para preparar 
mejor a estudiantes en el campo ancho-aplicable de la biología de 
cómputo. Los contornos de la unidad, el programa, el proyecto, 
y las presentaciones y los manuscritos sobre este plan de estudios se 
pueden todos descargar en sitio. Las unidades incluyen con NCBI,
usando BW/Datasets, la alineación múltiple de la secuencia, el 
a'rbol-edificio phylogenetic, y la estructura de la proteína. 
El Web site también ofrece una imagen y datos (espectador 3D 
requerido) de la estructura de proteínas y del rRNA ribosomal 16S del
T. thermophilus.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SARAH BOOMER
FN:SARAH BOOMER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DANNY LODGE
FN:DANNY LODGE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BRYAN DUTTON
FN:BRYAN DUTTON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KELLY SHIPLEY
FN:KELLY SHIPLEY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WESTERN OREGON UNIVERSITY
FN:WESTERN OREGON UNIVERSITY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104128</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/computational-biology-bioinformatics-unit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
