<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108419</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108419</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087184</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We can take it!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir können sie nehmen!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous pouvons la prendre!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós podemos fazer exame d!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"possiamo prenderli!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μπορούμε να τον πάρουμε!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"podemos tomarla!"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), launched by the federal government in 1933, provided temporary work to three million young men, who lived in semi-military camps, constructed recreation facilities, and carried out conservation projects. This photograph of a young CCC worker epitomizes the agency's emphasis on the morally and physically curative powers of vigorous outdoor life. Building strong bodies is a major CCC objective</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Zivilerhaltung Korps (CCC), ausgestoßen durch die 
Bundesregierung 1933, vorausgesetzt temporäre Arbeit zu drei Million 
jungen Männern, die in den halb-militärischen Lagern lebten, 
Erholungteildienste konstruierte, und führte Erhaltung Projekte 
durch. _ dies Fotographie von eines ein jung ccc Arbeiter geben 
dem d Hauptgewicht der Agentur auf d moralisch und körperlich heilend
Energie von der kräftig im FreienLebensdauer. Starke Körper 
aufzubauen ist ein Haupt-CCC Lernziel</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les corps civils d'économie (ccc), lancés par le 
gouvernement fédéral en 1933, si le travail provisoire à trois 
millions de jeunes hommes, qui ont vécu dans des camps de 
semi-finale-military, construisait des équipements de récréation, et 
ont mis des projets à exécution d'économie. Cette 
photographie d'un jeune ouvrier de ccc résume l'emphase de l'agence 
sur des puissances moralement et physiquement curatives de la vie 
extérieure vigoureuse. Établir des corps forts est un objectif
important de ccc</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O corpo civil do conservation (CCC), lançado pelo governo
federal em 1933, desde que o trabalho provisório a três milhão 
homens novos, que viveram em acampamentos semi-militares, construiu 
facilidades da recreação, e realizou projetos do conservation. 
Esta fotografia de um trabalhador novo do CCC epitomizes a 
ênfase da agência no potências moral e fisicamente curative da vida
ao ar livre vigorosa. Construir corpos fortes é um objetivo 
principal do CCC</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Corpo civile di conservazione (ccc), lanciato dal
governo federale in 1933, se il lavoro provvisorio ai tre milione 
giovani, che hanno vissuto negli accampamenti semi-militari, 
costruisse le attrezzature di ricreazione ed ha effettuato i progetti 
di conservazione. Questa fotografia di un operaio giovane del 
ccc epitomizes l'enfasi dell'agenzia sul le potenzi morale e 
fisicamente curative di vita esterna vigorosa. Lo sviluppo dei 
corpi forti è un obiettivo importante del ccc</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πολιτική συντήρηση Σώμα (Συμβούλιο 
Πολιτιστικής Συνεργασίας), που προωθήθηκε από την ομοσπονδιακή 
κυβέρνηση το 1933, υπό τον όρο ότι η προσωρινή εργασία σε 
τρία εκατομμύριο νεαρούς άνδρες, που έζησαν στα ημι-στρατιωτικά 
στρατόπεδα, κατασκεύασε τις εγκαταστάσεις αναψυχής, και εκτέλεσε 
τα προγράμματα συντήρησης. Αυτή η φωτογραφία ενός νέου 
εργαζομένου Συμβούλιο Πολιτιστικής Συνεργασίας συνοψίζει την 
έμφαση της αντιπροσωπείας στις ηθικά και φυσικά θεραπευτικές 
δυνάμεις της σφριγηλής υπαίθριας ζωής. Η οικοδόμηση των 
ισχυρών οργανισμών είναι ένας σημαντικός στόχος Συμβούλιο 
Πολιτιστικής Συνεργασίας</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El cuerpo civil de la conservación (CCC), lanzado por el 
gobierno federal en 1933, con tal que el trabajo temporal a tres 
millones de hombres jóvenes, que vivieron en campos semi-militares, 
construyera recursos de la reconstrucción, y realizó proyectos de la
conservación. Esta fotografía de un trabajador joven del CCC 
personifica el énfasis de la agencia en potencias moral y 
físicamente curativas de la vida al aire libre vigorosa. La 
construcción de cuerpos fuertes es un objetivo importante del CCC</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087184</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108419</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-can-take-it</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
