<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107426</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107426</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Students' Cloud Observations On-Line (S'COOL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beobachtungen Wolke Der Kursteilnehmer Online 
(S'COOL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Observations du Nuage des Étudiants En ligne 
(S'OOL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Observações Da Nuvem Dos Estudantes Em linha 
(S'COOL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Osservazioni Della Nube Degli Allievi In linea 
(S'COOL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρατηρήσεις σύννεφων σπουδαστών on-line (S'COOL)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Observaciones De la Nube De los Estudiantes En 
línea (S'COOL)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">invites students to observe atmospheric conditions to assist in the validation of the Clouds and the Earth's Radiant Energy Sytem (CERES) - a scientific satellite instrument that orbits the Earth as part of NASA's Earth Science and Technology Enterprise. Observations may be entered online, e-mailed, faxed, or mailed to NASA for entry into an online database. Students can access their results as well as those from other participating schools.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">lädt Kursteilnehmer ein, atmosphärische 
Bedingungen zu beobachten, um in der Gültigkeitserklärung der Wolken
und der leuchtenden Energie Sytem (CERES) - ein wissenschaftliches 
Satelliteninstrument zu unterstützen der Masse, das die Masse als 
Teil der Geowissenschaft der NASAS und des Technologie-Unternehmens in
Umlauf bringt. Beobachtungen können online eingetragen werden, 
zur NASA für Eintrag in eine Onlinedatenbank e-gesendet werden, 
gefaxt werden oder gesendet werden. Kursteilnehmer können auf 
ihre Resultate sowie die von anderen teilnehmenden Schulen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">invite des étudiants à observer des conditions 
atmosphériques pour aider à la validation des nuages et de 
l'énergie radiante Sytem (CERES) - un instrument satellite 
scientifique de la terre qui satellise la terre en tant qu'élément 
de la science de la terre de la NASA et de l'entreprise de 
technologie. Des observations peuvent être écrites en ligne, 
e-expédiées, envoyées, ou expédiées par fax à la NASA pour 
l'entrée dans une base de données en ligne. Les étudiants 
peuvent accéder à leurs résultats aussi bien que ceux d'autres 
écoles participantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">convida estudantes observar circunstâncias 
atmosféricas para ajudar no validation das nuvens e da energia 
radiante Sytem da terra (CERES) - um instrumento satellite científico
que orbite a terra como a parte da ciência de terra da NASA e da 
empresa da tecnologia. As observações podem ser incorporadas 
em linha, e-enviado, faxed, ou enviado à NASA para a entrada em uma 
base de dados em linha. Os estudantes podem alcançar seus 
resultados as.well.as aqueles de outras escolas participando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">invita gli allievi a osservare le circostanze 
atmosferiche per aiutare nella convalida delle nubi e dell'energia 
radiante Sytem (CERES) - uno strumento satellite scientifico della 
terra che orbita intorno alla terra come componente delle scienze 
della terra della NASA e dell'impresa di tecnologia. Le 
osservazioni possono essere inserite in linea, e-essere spedite, 
faxed, o essere spedite alla NASA per l'entrata in una base di dati in
linea. Gli allievi possono accedere ai loro risultati così come
quelli da altre scuole di partecipazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσκαλεί τους σπουδαστές για να παρατηρήσει τις 
ατμοσφαιρικές συνθήκες για να βοηθήσει στην επικύρωση των 
σύννεφων και της γήινης ακτινοβόλου ενέργειας Sytem (CERES) 
- ένα επιστημονικό δορυφορικό όργανο που βάζει τη γη ως τμήμα 
γήινων επιστήμης σε τροχιά και τεχνολογίας της NASA της 
επιχείρησης. Οι παρατηρήσεις μπορούν να εισαχθούν 
on-line, να σταλθούν μήνυμα με το ηλεκτρονικό ταχυδρομείο, να 
σταλούν με φαξ, ή να ταχυδρομηθούν στη NASA για την είσοδο σε 
μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση βάση δεδομένων. Οι σπουδαστές 
μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στα αποτελέσματά τους καθώς επίσης 
και εκείνων από άλλα συμμετέχοντα σχολεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">invita a estudiantes que observen condiciones 
atmosféricas para asistir a la validación de las nubes y de la 
energía radiante Sytem (CERES) - un instrumento basado en los 
satélites científico de la tierra que mueva en órbita alrededor de 
la tierra como parte de la geología de la NASA y de la empresa de la 
tecnología. Las observaciones se pueden incorporar en línea, 
e-enviar, enviar por telefax, o enviar a la NASA para la entrada en 
una base de datos en línea. Los estudiantes pueden tener acceso
a sus resultados así como ésos de otras escuelas que participan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107426</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/students-cloud-observations-on-line-scool</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
