<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106064</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106064</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206993</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Game On! The Ultimate Wellness Challenge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spiel An! Die Entscheidende 
Wellness-Herausforderung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeu En fonction ! Le Défi Final de 
Santé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogo Sobre! O Desafio Final Do Wellness</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioco Sopra! L'Ultima Sfida Di Wellness</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδι επάνω! Η τελευταία πρόκληση Wellness</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juego Encendido! El Último Desafío De la 
Salud</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site is a back-to-school effort to promote nutrition, physical activity, and learning. It includes a database of changes schools can make to improve nutrition and physical activity. Topics in the Resources to Improve Schools database include advertising, after school programs, a la carte foods, assessment tools, childhood obesity, family outreach, nutrition education, physical activity, physical education, school meal programs, and staff wellness.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site ist eine Zurück-zuschule Bemühung, 
Nahrung, körperliche Aktivität und das Lernen zu fördern. Sie
schließt eine Datenbank der Änderungen ein, die Schulen vornehmen 
können, um Nahrung und körperliche Aktivität zu verbessern. 
Themen in den Betriebsmitteln, zum der Schuledatenbank zu 
verbessern enthalten das Bekanntmachen, nach Schuleprogrammen, die 
Nahrungsmittel eines La Carte, Einschätzung Hilfsmittel, 
Kindheitkorpulenz, Familie übertreffen, Ernährungsausbildung, 
körperliche Aktivität, Leibeserziehung, Schulmahlzeitprogramme und 
Personal Wellness.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site est un effort d'en arrière-à-école de 
favoriser la nutrition, l'activité physique, et l'étude. Il 
inclut une base de données des changements que les écoles peuvent 
faire pour améliorer la nutrition et l'activité physique. Les 
sujets dans les ressources pour améliorer la base de données 
d'écoles incluent annoncer, après des programmes d'école, des 
nourritures d'une carte de La, outils d'évaluation, obésité 
d'enfance, famille dépassent, enseignment de la nutrition, activité 
physique, éducation physique, programmes de repas scolaire, et 
santé de personnel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local é um esforço da para trás-à-escola 
promover o nutrition, a atividade física, e a aprendizagem. 
Inclui uma base de dados das mudanças que as escolas podem 
fazer para melhorar o nutrition e a atividade física. Os 
tópicos nos recursos para melhorar a base de dados das escolas 
incluem anunciar, após programas da escola, alimentos de um carte do 
la, ferramentas da avaliação, obesity da infância, família 
excedem, instrução de nutrition, atividade física, instrução 
física, programas da refeição de escola, e wellness da equipe de 
funcionários.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo è uno sforzo della 
indietro-$$$-SCUOLA promuovere la nutrizione, l'attività fisica ed 
imparare. Include una base di dati dei cambiamenti che le scuole
possono fare per migliorare la nutrizione e l'attività fisica. 
I soggetti nelle risorse per migliorare la base di dati delle 
scuole includono la pubblicità, dopo i programmi della scuola, degli 
alimenti del carte della La, strumenti di valutazione, l'obesità di 
infanzia, famiglia superano, educazione alimentare, attività fisica, 
formazione fisica, programmi della refezione e wellness del personale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή είναι μια πίσω-$$$-ΣΧΟΛΙΚΉ προσπάθεια
να προωθηθεί η διατροφή, η σωματική δραστηριότητα, και η 
εκμάθηση. Περιλαμβάνει μια βάση δεδομένων των σχολείων 
αλλαγών μπορεί να κάνει για να βελτιώσει τη διατροφή και τη 
σωματική δραστηριότητα. Τα θέματα στα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς
για να βελτιώσουν τη σχολική βάση δεδομένων περιλαμβάνουν τη 
διαφήμιση, μετά από τα σχολικά προγράμματα, των τροφίμων ενός 
Λα carte, εργαλεία αξιολόγησης, παχυσαρκία παιδικής ηλικίας, η
οικογένεια ξεπερνά, εκπαίδευση διατροφής, σωματική 
δραστηριότητα, φυσική αγωγή, προγράμματα σχολικού γεύματος, και 
wellness προσωπικού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio es un esfuerzo de la detra's-a-escuela 
de promover la nutrición, la actividad física, y aprender. 
Incluye una base de datos de cambios que las escuelas pueden 
realizar para mejorar la nutrición y la actividad física. Los 
asuntos en los recursos para mejorar la base de datos de las escuelas 
incluyen la publicidad, después de programas de la escuela, de los 
alimentos de un carte del la, herramientas del gravamen, obesidad de 
la niñez, familia exceden, educación de nutrición, actividad 
física, educación física, los programas de la comida de escuela, y 
salud del personal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206993</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106064</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/game-on-the-ultimate-wellness-challenge</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
