<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106060</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106060</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206851</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Manassas Battlefield History</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Manassas Schlachtfeld Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire de Champ de bataille de Manassas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History Do Campo de batalha De Manassas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia Del Campo di battaglia Di Manassas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία πεδίων μαχών Manassas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia Del Campo de batalla De Manassas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts two Civil War battles fought in Manassas, Virginia. The first battle marked the first clash of the Northern and Southern armies. As the battle approached, enthusiastic young volunteers were confident the other side would run at the first shot. At day's end, nearly 900 men lay lifeless on the fields The second battle at Manassas took place a year later, in 08/1862. It covered three days, left 3,300 dead, and brought the Confederacy to the height of its power.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachzählungen zwei Bürgerkriegschlachten 
kämpften in Manassas, Virginia. Die erste Schlacht 
kennzeichnete das erste Zusammentreffen der Nord- und südlichen 
Armeen. Da die Schlacht sich näherte, waren enthusiastische 
junge Freiwilliger die andere Seite würden laufen am ersten Schuß 
überzeugt. Am Ende des Tages legen fast 900 Männer lebloses 
auf auffängt die zweite Schlacht bei Manassas stattfanden 
ein Jahr später, in 08/1862. Es umfaßte drei Tage, nach links 
3.300 tot und holte die Konföderation zur Höhe seiner Energie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les recomptes deux batailles de guerre civile ont 
combattu dans Manassas, la Virginie. La première bataille a 
marqué le premier désaccord des armées nordiques et méridionales. 
Car la bataille s'est approchée, les jeunes volontaires 
enthousiastes étaient confiants l'autre côté exécuteraient au 
premier projectile. À l'extrémité du jour, presque 900 hommes
étendent sans vie sur les zones que la deuxième bataille chez 
Manassas a eu lieu un an après, dans 08/1862. Il a couvert 
trois jours, à gauche 3.300 morts, et a apporté la confédération 
à la taille de sa puissance.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os recounts duas batalhas da guerra civil lutaram 
em Manassas, Virgínia. A primeira batalha marcou o primeiro 
clash dos exércitos do norte e do sul. Porque a batalha se 
aproximou, os voluntários novos entusiásticos eram confiáveis o 
outro lado funcionariam no primeiro tiro. Na extremidade do dia,
quase 900 homens colocam lifeless nos campos que a segunda batalha em 
Manassas ocorreu um ano mais tarde, em 08/1862. Cobriu três 
dias, à esquerda 3.300 inoperantes, e trouxe o confederacy à altura 
de sua potência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i conteggi due battaglie di guerra civile hanno 
combattuto in Manassas, la Virginia. La prima battaglia ha 
contrassegnato il primo disaccordo degli eserciti nordici e del sud. 
Poichè la battaglia si è avvicinata a, i volontari giovani 
entusiastici erano sicuri l'altro lato funzionerebbero al primo colpo.
All'estremità del giorno, quasi 900 uomini pongono lifeless sui
campi che la seconda battaglia a Manassas ha avvenuto un anno più 
successivamente, in 08/1862. Ha riguardato tre giorni, a 
sinistra 3.300 guasti ed ha portato il confederacy all'altezza della 
relativa potenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δεύτερες καταμετρήσεις δύο μάχες εμφύλιου πολέμου 
που παλεύουν σε Manassas, Βιρτζίνια. Η πρώτη μάχη 
χαρακτήρισε την πρώτη διαφωνία των βόρειων και νότιων στρατών. 
Δεδομένου ότι η μάχη που προσεγγίστηκαν, οι ενθουσιώδεις 
νέοι εθελοντές ήταν βέβαιοι η άλλη πλευρά θα έτρεχε στο πρώτο 
πλάνο. Στο τέλος της ημέρας, σχεδόν 900 άτομα βρέθηκαν 
άψυχα στα πεδία που η δεύτερη μάχη σε Manassas 
πραγματοποιήθηκε ένα έτος αργότερα, στο 08/1862. Κάλυψε 
τρεις ημέρες, άφησε 3.300 νεκρά, και έφερε τη συνομοσπονδία 
στο ύψος της δύναμής του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los recuentos dos batallas de la guerra civil 
lucharon en Manassas, Virginia. La primera batalla marcó el 
primer choque de los ejércitos norteños y meridionales. Pues 
la batalla se acercó, los voluntarios jóvenes entusiásticos eran 
confidentes la otra cara se ejecutarían en el primer tiro. En 
el extremo del día, casi 900 hombres ponen sin vida en los campos que
ocurrió la segunda batalla en Manassas un año más adelante, en 
08/1862. Cubrió tres días, a la izquierda 3.300 muertos, y 
trajo el confederacy a la altura de su potencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206851</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106060</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/manassas-battlefield-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
