<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107420</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107420</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Science Family Fun Night</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft Familie Spaß-Nacht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nuit d'Amusement de Famille de la Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Noite Do Divertimento Da Família Da Ciência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Notte Di Divertimento Della Famiglia Di Scienza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νύχτα οικογενειακής διασκέδασης επιστήμης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Noche De la Diversión De la Familia De la 
Ciencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One night a month Vivian Smith opens her classroom to families where they work together to solve logic problems and conduct experiments. Learn how this science teacher increases family involvement in her students' education and find ideas for science experiments, webquests, projects, and construction contests.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Nacht ein Monat Vivian Smith öffnet ihr 
Klassenzimmer zu den Familien, in denen sie zusammen arbeiten, um 
Logikprobleme zu lösen und Experimente zu leiten. Erlernen Sie,
wie dieser Wissenschaft Lehrer Familie Miteinbeziehung in der 
Ausbildung ihrer Kursteilnehmer erhöht und finden Sie Ideen für 
Wissenschaft Experimente, webquests, Projekte und Aufbauwettbewerbe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une nuit par mois Vivian Smith ouvre sa salle de 
classe aux familles où elles travaillent ensemble pour résoudre des 
problèmes de logique et pour entreprendre des expériences. 
Apprenez comment ce professeur de la science augmente la 
participation de famille dans l'éducation de ses étudiants et 
trouvez les idées pour des expériences de la science, des webquests,
des projets, et des concours de construction.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma noite um o mês Vivian Smith abre sua sala de 
aula às famílias onde trabalham junto para resolver problemas de 
lógica e para conduzir experiências. Aprenda como este 
professor da ciência aumenta a participação da família na 
instrução dos seus estudantes e encontre idéias para experiências 
da ciência, webquests, projetos, e competições da construção.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una notte un il mese Vivian Smith apre la sua aula
alle famiglie in cui funzionano insieme per risolvere i problemi di 
logica e per eseguire gli esperimenti. Impari come questo 
insegnante di scienza aumenta la partecipazione della famiglia alla 
formazione dei suoi allievi e trovi le idee per gli esperimenti di 
scienza, i webquests, i progetti ed i concorsi della costruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια νύχτα μηνιαίως Vivian Smith ανοίγει την τάξη
της στις οικογένειες όπου λειτουργούν μαζί για να λύσουν τα 
προβλήματα λογικής και να πραγματοποιήσουν τα πειράματα. 
Μάθετε πώς αυτός ο καθηγητής θετικών επιστημών αυξάνει 
την οικογενειακή συμμετοχή στην εκπαίδευση των σπουδαστών της και 
βρείτε τις ιδέες για τα πειράματα επιστήμης, webquests, τα 
προγράμματα, και τους διαγωνισμούς κατασκευής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una noche al mes Vivian Smith abre su sala de 
clase en las familias donde trabajan juntas para solucionar problemas 
de lógica y para conducir experimentos. Aprenda cómo este 
profesor de la ciencia aumenta la implicación de la familia en la 
educación de sus estudiantes y encuentre las ideas para los 
experimentos de la ciencia, los webquests, los proyectos, y las 
competencias de la construcción.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WAVERLY HARRELL
FN:WAVERLY HARRELL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107420</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/science-family-fun-night</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
