<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104218</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104218</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087234</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Who Was Shut Out?: Immigration Quotas, 1925-1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wer Heraus? Geschlossen Wurde: 
Immigration-Quoten, 1925-1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Qui A été fermé Dehors ? : Quotes-parts 
d'Immigration, 1925-1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quem Foi fechado Para fora?: Quotas Do 
Immigration, 1925-1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Chi È stato chiuso Fuori?: Quote Di 
Immigrazione, 1925-1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποιος ήταν αποκλεισμένος;: Ποσοστώσεις 
μετανάστευσης, 1925-1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Quién Fue cerrada Hacia fuera?: 
Contingentes De la Inmigración, 1925-1927</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In response to growing public opinion against the flow of immigrants from Southern and Eastern Europe in the years following World War I, Congress passed first the Quota Act of 1921 then the even more restrictive Immigration Act of 1924 (the Johnson-Reed Act). Initially, the 1924 law imposed a total quota on immigration of 165,000--less than 20 percent of the pre-World War I average. It based ceilings on the number of immigrants from any particular nation on the percentage of each nationality recorded in the 1890 census--a blatant effort to limit immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe, which mostly occurred after that date. In the first decade of the 20th century, an average of 200,000 Italians had entered the United States each year. With the 1924 Act, the annual quota for Italians was set at less than 4,000. This table shows the annual immigration quotas under the 1924 Immigration Act.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In Erwiderung auf das Wachsen der öffentlichen 
Meinung gegen den Fluß der Immigranten von südlichem und des 
Osteuropas in den Jahren dem Ersten Weltkrieg folgend, führte 
Kongreß zuerst die Quote-Tat von 1921 dann die sogar 
einschränkendere Immigration-Tat von 1924 (die Johnson-Schilf Tat). 
Zuerst erlegte das Gesetz 1924 eine Gesamtquote Immigration von 
165.000 -- weniger als 20 Prozent des Durchschnittes des 
VorWeltkrieges I auf. Es gründete Decken auf der Zahl 
Immigranten von jeder bestimmten Nation auf dem Prozentsatz jeder 
Nationalität, die in der 1890 Zählung -- eine krasse Bemühung, 
Immigration von Süd- und Osteuropa zu begrenzen gespeichert wurde, 
das meistens nach diesem Datum auftrat. In der ersten Dekade des
20. Jahrhunderts, hatte ein Durchschnitt von 200.000 Italienern die 
Vereinigten Staaten jedes Jahr betreten. Mit der Tat 1924 wurde 
die jährliche Quote für Italiener an weniger als 4.000 eingestellt. 
Diese Tabelle zeigt die jährlichen Immigrationquoten unter der 
Immigration-Tat 1924.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En réponse à accroître l'opinion publique 
contre l'écoulement des immigrés de méridional et de l'Europe de 
l'Est en années suivant la Première Guerre Mondiale, le congrès a 
passé d'abord à l'acte de quote-part de 1921 puis l'acte bien plus 
restrictif d'immigration de 1924 (l'acte de Johnson-reed). Au 
commencement, la loi 1924 a imposé une quote-part totale à 
l'immigration de 165.000 -- moins de 20 pour cent de la moyenne de la 
guerre I de pré-Monde. Elle a basé des plafonds sur le nombre 
d'immigrés de n'importe quelle nation particulière sur le 
pourcentage de chaque nationalité enregistrée dans 1890 le 
recensement -- un effort flagrant de limiter l'immigration de l'Europe
méridionale et orientale, qui s'est la plupart du temps produite 
après cette date. Dans la première décennie du 20ème 
siècle, une moyenne de 200.000 Italiens était entrée dans tous les 
ans les Etats-Unis. Avec la Loi 1924, le contingent annuel pour 
des Italiens a été placé moins de à 4.000. Cette table 
montre les contingents annuels d'immigration sous la Loi 1924 
d'immigration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em resposta a crescer a opinião pública de 
encontro ao fluxo dos immigrants de do sul e da Europa Oriental nos 
anos que seguem o world.war.i, o congress passou primeiramente ao ato 
do quota de 1921 então o ato mesmo mais restritivo do immigration de 
1924 (o ato da Johnson-Lingüeta). Inicialmente, a lei 1924 
impôs um quota total em um immigration de 165.000 -- mais menos de 20
por cento da média da guerra I do pre-Mundo. Baseou tetos no 
número dos immigrants de toda a nação particular na porcentagem de 
cada nacionalidade gravada 1890 no census -- um esforço blatant 
limitar o immigration de do sul e de Europa Oriental, que ocorreram na
maior parte após essa data. À primeira década do 20o século,
uma média de 200.000 italianos tinha incorporado os estados unidos 
cada ano. Com o ato 1924, o quota anual para italianos foi 
ajustado menos em de 4.000. Esta tabela mostra os quotas anuais 
do immigration sob o ato 1924 do immigration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In risposta a sviluppare l'opinione pubblica 
contro il flusso degli immigranti da del sud e dell'Europa Orientale 
durante gli anni che seguono il world.war.i, il congresso ha passato 
in primo luogo alla Legge di quota di 1921 allora la Legge ancor più 
restrittiva di immigrazione di 1924 (la Legge della Johnson-Canna). 
Inizialmente, la legge 1924 ha imposto una quota totale 
all'immigrazione di 165.000 -- più meno di 20 per cento della media 
di guerra I del pre-Mondo. Ha basato i soffitti sul numero di 
immigranti da tutta la nazione particolare sulla percentuale di ogni 
nazionalità registrata 1890 nel censimento -- uno sforzo blatant 
limitare l'immigrazione da del sud e dall'Europa Orientale, che 
principalmente si sono presentati dopo quella data. Nella prima 
decade del ventesimo secolo, una media di 200.000 italiani aveva 
registrato unito Dichiara ogni anno. Con la Legge 1924, 
il contingente annuale per gli italiani è stato regolato più meno a 
di 4.000. Questa tabella mostra i contingenti annuali di 
immigrazione a norma della legge 1924 di immigrazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε απάντηση στην ανάπτυξη της κοινής γνώμης ενάντια 
στη ροή των μεταναστών από νότιο και την Ανατολική Ευρώπη στα 
έτη μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, το συνέδριο πέρασε πρώτα 
το νόμο ποσόστωσης του 1921 έπειτα ο ακόμα πιό περιοριστικός 
νόμος μετανάστευσης του 1924 (ο νόμος ιοχνσον-καλάμων). 
Αρχικά, ο νόμος του 1924 επέβαλε μια συνολική ποσόστωση 
στη μετανάστευση 165.000 -- λιγότερο από 20 τοις εκατό του 
προ-παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι μέσος όρος. Βάσισε τα ανώτατα 
όρια στον αριθμό μεταναστών από οποιοδήποτε ιδιαίτερο έθνος στο
ποσοστό κάθε υπηκοότητας που καταγράφηκε στην απογραφή 1890 --
μια κραυγαλέα προσπάθεια να περιοριστεί η μετανάστευση από νότιο
και την Ανατολική Ευρώπη, οι οποίοι εμφανίστηκαν συνήθως μετά 
από εκείνη την ημερομηνία. Στην πρώτη δεκαετία του 20ού 
αιώνα, όρος 200.000 Ιταλών είχε πάει στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες
κάθε έτος. Με το νόμο του 1924, η ετήσια ποσόστωση για 
Ιταλούς τέθηκε σε λιγότερο από 4.000. Αυτός ο πίνακας 
παρουσιάζει ετήσιες ποσοστώσεις μετανάστευσης στο πλαίσιο του 
νόμου μετανάστευσης του 1924.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En respuesta a crecer la opinión pública contra 
el flujo de inmigrantes de meridional y de Europa Oriental en los 
años que seguían Primera Guerra Mundial, el congreso pasó primero 
el acto del contingente de 1921 entonces el acto aún más restrictivo
de la inmigración de 1924 (el acto de la Johnson-Caña). 
Inicialmente, la ley 1924 impuso un contingente total ante la 
inmigración de 165.000 -- menos de 20 por ciento del promedio de la 
guerra I del pre-Mundo. Basó techos en el número de 
inmigrantes de cualquier nación determinada en el porcentaje de cada 
nacionalidad registrada en 1890 el censo -- un esfuerzo evidente de 
limitar la inmigración de meridional y de Europa Oriental, que 
ocurrieron sobre todo después de esa fecha. En la primera 
década del vigésimo siglo, un promedio de 200.000 italianos había 
entrado en los Estados Unidos cada año. Con el acto 1924, el 
contingente anual para los italianos fue fijado en menos de 4.000. 
Este vector muestra los contingentes anuales de la inmigración 
bajo acto 1924 de la inmigración.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087234</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104218</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/who-was-shut-out-immigration-quotas-1925-1927</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
