<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103062</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103062</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206552</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Californio to American: A Study in Cultural Change</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Californio zum Amerikaner: Eine Studie in 
der kulturellen Änderung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Californio à l'Américain : Une étude dans
le changement culturel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Californio ao americano: Um estudo na 
mudança cultural</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Californio all'americano: Uno studio nel 
cambiamento culturale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Californio σε Αμερικανό: Μια μελέτη στην 
πολιτιστική αλλαγή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Californio al americano: Un estudio en 
cambio cultural</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at an area that was once part of an Indian village, then an outpost shelter for vaqueros (cowhands), and then the site where Californios (Spanish settlers in what is now the state of California) built small adobe dwellings in the midst of their cattle ranges. Successive owners altered one dwelling into the elegant 18-room ranch house there today -- Rancho Los Alamitos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">betrachtet einen Bereich, der einmal Teil eines 
indischen Dorfs, dann des Vorpostenschutz für vaqueros (cowhands) und
dann die Site war, in der Californios (spanische Siedleren in, was 
jetzt der Zustand von Kalifornien ist) kleine Ziegelsteinwohnungen in 
der Mitte ihrer Viehstrecken aufbaute. Die aufeinanderfolgenden 
Inhaber änderten ein dort bleibend in die elegante 18-Raum Ranch-Haus
heute -- Ranch Los Alamitos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regarde une zone qui était par le passé une 
partie d'un village indien, puis d'un abri d'avant-poste pour les 
vaqueros (cowhands), et puis le site où Californios (colons espagnols
dans ce qui est maintenant l'état de la Californie) a construit de 
petits logements d'adobe au milieu de leurs intervalles de bétail. 
Les propriétaires successifs ont modifié un demeurant dans le 
rancho élégant Los Alamitos de maison de ranch de 18-pièce là 
aujourd'hui --.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olha uma área que seja uma vez parte de uma vila 
indian, a seguir de um abrigo do outpost para vaqueros (cowhands), e 
então o local onde Californios (settlers espanhóis em o que é agora
o estado de Califórnia) construiu moradias pequenas do adôbe no meio
de suas escalas do gado. Os proprietários sucessivos alteraram 
um que residem no rancho elegante Los Alamitos da casa do rancho do 
18-quarto lá hoje --.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">guarda una zona che faceva parte una volta di un 
villaggio indiano, quindi di un riparo dell'avamposto per i vaqueros
(cowhands) ed allora il luogo in cui Californios (settlers spagnoli in
che cosa ora è il dichiarare della California) ha costruito le 
piccole dimore dell'adobe in mezzo a le loro gamme dei bestiami. 
I proprietari successivi hanno alterato uno che abitano nel 
rancho elegante Los Alamitos della casa del ranch della 18-stanza là 
oggi --.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει μια περιοχή που ήταν μιά φορά μέρος ενός 
ινδικού χωριού, κατόπιν ένα καταφύγιο φυλακίων για τα 
vaqueros (cowhands), και έπειτα την περιοχή όπου 
Californios (ισπανικοί άποικοι σε αυτό που είναι τώρα η 
κατάσταση Καλιφόρνιας) έχτισε τις μικρές κατοικίες πλίθας στη 
μέση των σειρών βοοειδών τους. Οι διαδοχικοί ιδιοκτήτες 
άλλαξαν μια κατοικία στο κομψό σπίτι αγροκτημάτων 18room εκεί
σήμερα -- rancho Los Alamitos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">mira un área que era una vez parte de una aldea 
india, después de un abrigo del puesto avanzado para los vaqueros 
(cowhands), y entonces el sitio en donde Californios (colonos 
españoles en cuál ahora es el estado de California) construyó las 
viviendas pequeñas del adobe en el medio de sus rangos de los 
ganados. Los propietarios sucesivos alteraron uno que moraban en
el rancho elegante Los Alamitos de la casa del rancho del 18-cuarto 
allí hoy --.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206552</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103062</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/californio-to-american-a-study-in-cultural-change</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
