<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103424</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103424</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201364</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Exploring Regional Differences in Climate Change</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Erforschende regionale Unterschiede bezüglich der 
Klima-Änderung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Différences régionales les explorant dans le changement de 
climat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Diferenças regionais explorando na mudança do clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Differenze regionali d'esplorazione nel cambiamento di clima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: Να 
ερευνήσει τις περιφερειακές διαφορές στην αλλαγή κλίματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Diferencias regionales que exploran en cambio del clima</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, users download and graph modeled climate data to explore variability in climate change. Most people know that climate changes are predicted over the next hundred years, but they may not be aware that these changes are likely to vary from region to region. Using data from the University of New Hampshire's Earth Science Information Partner, a digital library of Earth Science data, users will obtain annual predictions for minimum temperature, maximum temperature, precipitation, and solar radiation for each of these 5 states: New York, Georgia, Colorado, Minnesota, and California. Data will span the years 2000 through 2100. Users will import the data into Excel and analyze it to see what, if any, regional variability exists. Finally, they will download data for their own state, compare these results to the results from the other five states and use their results to answer a series of questions related to climate change.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität formten Benutzer Download und 
Diagramm Klimadaten, um Veränderlichkeit in der Klimaänderung zu 
erforschen. Die meisten Leute wissen, daß Klimaänderungen 
über den folgenden hundert Jahren vorausgesagt werden, aber sie 
können möglicherweise nicht beachten, daß diese Änderungen 
wahrscheinlich sind, von Region zu Region zu schwanken. Mit 
Daten von der Universität des Geowissenschaft-Informationen Partners 
New-Hampshires, erreicht eine digitale Bibliothek von 
Geowissenschaft-Daten, Benutzer jährliche Vorhersagen für minimale 
Temperatur, maximale Temperatur, Niederschlag und Solarstrahlung für 
jeden dieser 5 Zustände: New York, Georgia, Kolorado, Minnesota
und Kalifornien. Daten überspannen die Jahre 2000 bis 2100. 
Benutzer importieren die Daten in übertreffen und analysieren 
sie, um zu sehen, was, wenn irgendein, regionale Veränderlichkeit 
existiert. Schließlich downloaden sie Daten für ihren eigenen 
Zustand, diese Resultate mit den Resultaten von den anderen fünf 
Zuständen zu vergleichen und ihre Resultate zu verwenden, um eine 
Reihe Fragen zu beantworten, die auf Klima in Verbindung gestanden 
werden, ändern Sie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les utilisateurs 
téléchargement et le graphique ont modelé des données de climat 
pour explorer la variabilité dans le changement de climat. La 
plupart des personnes savent que des changements de climat sont 
prévus au cours des cent années à venir, mais ils peuvent ne pas se
rendre compte que ces changements soient susceptibles de changer de la
région à la région. En utilisant des données de 
l'université de l'associé de l'information de science de la terre du
New Hampshire, une bibliothèque digitale des données de science de 
la terre, utilisateurs obtiendra des prévisions annuelles pour la 
température minimum, la température maximale, la précipitation, et 
le rayonnement solaire pour chacun de ces 5 états : New York, 
Géorgie, Colorado, le Minnesota, et Californie. Les données 
enjamberont les années 2000 à 2100. Les utilisateurs 
importeront les données dans l'excellent et analysent pour voir ce 
qui, le cas échéant, variabilité régionale existe. En 
conclusion, ils téléchargeront des données pour leur propre état, 
comparer ces résultats aux résultats les cinq des autres états et 
employer leurs résultats pour répondre à une série de questions 
liées au climat changez.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os usuários download e o gráfico
modelaram dados do clima para explorar o variability na mudança do 
clima. A maioria de povos sabem que as mudanças do clima estão
preditas sobre os cem anos seguintes, mas não podem estar cientes que
estas mudanças são prováveis variar da região à região. 
Usando dados da universidade do sócio da informação da 
ciência de terra de New Hampshire, uma biblioteca digital de dados da
ciência de terra, usuários obterá predições anuais para a 
temperatura mínima, a temperatura máxima, a precipitação, e a 
radiação solar para cada um destes 5 estados: New York, 
Geórgia, Colorado, Minnesota, e Califórnia. Os dados medirão 
os anos 2000 a 2100. Os usuários importarão os dados em excel 
e analisam-na para ver que, se algum, variability regional existir. 
Finalmente, download dados para seu próprio estado, para 
comparar estes resultados aos resultados de outros cinco estados e 
para usar seus resultados responder a uma série das perguntas 
relacionadas ao clima mude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli utenti trasferimento dal 
sistema centrale verso i satelliti ed il grafico hanno modellato i 
dati di clima per esplorare la variabilità nel cambiamento di clima. 
La maggior parte della gente sa che i cambiamenti di clima sono 
previsti nel corso dei cento anni futuri, ma non possono essere 
informati che questi cambiamenti sono probabili variare dalla regione 
alla regione. Usando i dati dall'università di socio delle 
informazioni di scienze della terra del New Hampshire, una libreria 
digitale dei dati di scienze della terra, utenti otterrà le 
previsioni annuali per la temperatura minima, la temperatura massima, 
precipitazione e la radiazione solare per ciascuno di questi 5 
dichiara: New York, Georgia, Colorado, il Minnesota e 
California. I dati misureranno gli anni da 2000 a 2100. 
Gli utenti importeranno i dati in la eccellono ed analizzano per
vedere che cosa, all'occorrenza, variabilità regionale esiste. 
Per concludere, trasferiranno i dati dal sistema centrale verso 
i satelliti per il loro propri dichiarano, confrontano questi 
risultati ai risultati dagli altri cinque dichiarano ed usano i 
loro risultati per rispondere ad una serie di domande relative al 
cambiamento di clima.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι χρήστες μεταφορτώνουν 
και διαμορφωμένα γραφική παράσταση στοιχεία κλίματος για να 
ερευνήσουν τη μεταβλητότητα στην αλλαγή κλίματος. Οι 
περισσότεροι άνθρωποι ξέρουν ότι οι αλλαγές κλίματος 
προβλέπονται κατά τη διάρκεια των επόμενων εκατό ετών, αλλά 
μπορούν να μην γνωρίσουν ότι αυτές οι αλλαγές είναι πιθανό να 
ποικίλουν από την περιοχή στην περιοχή. Χρησιμοποιώντας τα 
στοιχεία από το πανεπιστήμιο του συνεργάτη πληροφοριών γήινης 
επιστήμης του Νιού Χάμσαιρ, μια ψηφιακή βιβλιοθήκη των στοιχείων
γήινης επιστήμης, χρήστες θα λάβει τις ετήσιες προβλέψεις για 
την ελάχιστη θερμοκρασία, τη μέγιστη θερμοκρασία, την πτώση, και 
την ηλιακή ακτινοβολία για κάθε ένα από αυτά τα 5 κράτη: 
Νέα Υόρκη, Γεωργία, Κολοράντο, Μινεσότα, και Καλιφόρνια. 
Τα στοιχεία θα εκταθούν τα έτη 2000 μέχρι 2100, χρήστες 
θα εισαγάγουν τα στοιχεία σε Excel και θα τα αναλύσουν για να 
δουν ποια, ενδεχομένως, περιφερειακή μεταβλητότητα 
υπάρχει. Τέλος, θα μεταφορτώσουν τα στοιχεία για το κράτος 
τους, θα συγκρίνουν αυτά τα αποτελέσματα με τα αποτελέσματα από 
τα άλλα πέντε κράτη και θα χρησιμοποιήσουν τα αποτελέσματά τους 
για να απαντήσουν σε μια σειρά ερωτήσεων σχετικών με την αλλαγή 
κλίματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los utilizadores transferencia 
directa y el gráfico modelaron datos del clima para explorar 
variabilidad en cambio del clima. La mayoría de la gente sabe 
que los cambios del clima están predichos durante los cientos años 
próximos, pero pueden no estar enterados que estos cambios son 
probables variar de la región a la región. Usando datos de la 
universidad del socio de la información de la geología de New 
Hampshire, una biblioteca digital de los datos de la geología, 
utilizadores obtendrá las predicciones anuales para la temperatura 
mínima, la temperatura máxima, la precipitación, y la radiación 
solar para cada uno de estos 5 estados: Nueva York, Georgia, 
Colorado, Minnesota, y California. Los datos atravesarán los 
años 2000 a 2100. Los utilizadores importarán los datos en la 
sobresalen y analizan para ver lo que, si existe cualquiera, 
variabilidad regional. Finalmente, descargarán los datos para 
su propio estado, comparar estos resultados a los resultados de los 
otros cinco estados y utilizar sus resultados para contestar a una 
serie de preguntas relacionadas con el clima cambie.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DENISE BLAHA
FN:DENISE BLAHA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201364</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103424</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-exploring-regional-differences-in-climate-change</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
