<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108323</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108323</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202576</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Outfitting a World War I Soldier - Teaching US Social Sciences with Primary Sources</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einen Weltkrieg-Soldaten ausstatten - 
unterrichtende US Sozialwissenschaften mit Primärquellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Équipant un soldat de Première Guerre Mondiale -
USA d'enseignement les sciences sociales avec des sources primaires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Equipando um soldado do world.war.i - E. U. 
ensinando ciências sociais com fontes preliminares</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rifornendo di un soldato di world.war.i - Stati 
Uniti d'istruzione scienze sociali con le sorgenti primarie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξοπλίζοντας έναν παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι στρατιώτης - 
αμερικανικές κοινωνικές επιστήμες διδασκαλίας με τις αρχικές 
πηγές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Equipando a un soldado de la Primera Guerra 
Mundial - los E.E.U.U. de enseñanza ciencias sociales con fuentes 
primarias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">What do soldiers wear? Students will say a uniform and mention boots. However, many of the necessities of soldiers are often overlooked by civilians whether the items be standard issue or personal. This lesson gives students the opportunity to not only look at William B. Umstead's artifacts from World War I, but gain insight into how and why each item was used.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Was tragen Soldaten? Kursteilnehmer sagen 
eine Uniform und erwähnen Aufladungen. Jedoch werden viele der 
Notwendigkeiten der Soldaten häufig von den Zivilisten übersehen, ob
die Einzelteile Standardausgabe oder persönlich sind. Diese 
Lektion gibt Kursteilnehmern die Gelegenheit, William B. Umsteads 
Kunstprodukte vom Ersten Weltkrieg nicht nur zu betrachten, aber 
gewinnt Einblick in wie und in warum jedes Einzelteil benutzt wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Que les soldats portent-ils ? Les étudiants
diront un uniforme et mentionneront des initialisations. 
Cependant, plusieurs des nécessités des soldats sont souvent 
négligées par des civils si les éléments soient issue ou 
personnels standard. Cette leçon donne à des étudiants 
l'occasion de regarder non seulement des objets façonnés de William 
B. Umstead's de la Première Guerre Mondiale, mais gagne 
l'perspicacité dans la façon dont et pourquoi chaque élément a 
été utilisé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Que os soldados desgastam? Os estudantes 
dirão um uniforme e mencionarão carregadores. Entretanto, 
muitas das necessidades dos soldados são negligenciadas 
frequentemente por civis se os artigos sejam edição ou pessoais 
padrão. Esta lição dá a estudantes a oportunidade de olhar 
não somente artifacts de William B. Umstead do world.war.i, mas ganha
a introspecção em como e em porque cada artigo foi usado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Che cosa i soldati portano? Gli allievi 
diranno un'uniforme ed accenneranno i caricamenti del sistema. 
Tuttavia, molte delle necessità dei soldati sono trascurate 
spesso dai civili se gli articoli sono edizione o personali standard. 
Questa lezione dà ad allievi l'occasione guardare non soltanto 
i manufatti del William B. Umstead dal world.war.i, ma guadagna la 
comprensione in come ed in perchè ogni articolo è stato usato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τι οι στρατιώτες φορούν; Οι σπουδαστές θα πουν 
έναν ομοιόμορφο και θα αναφέρουν τις μπότες. Εντούτοις, 
πολλές από τις ανάγκες των στρατιωτών αγνοούνται συχνά από τους
πολίτες εάν τα αντικείμενα είναι πρότυπος ζήτημα ή προσωπικά. 
Αυτό το μάθημα δίνει στους σπουδαστές την ευκαιρία όχι 
μόνο να εξετάσει τα χειροποίητα αντικείμενα William B. 
Umstead's από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, αλλά αποκτά την 
επίγνωση το πώς και γιατί κάθε αντικείμενο χρησιμοποιήθηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Qué los soldados desgastan? Los 
estudiantes dirán un uniforme y mencionarán cargadores del 
programa inicial. Sin embargo, muchas de las necesidades de 
soldados son pasadas por alto a menudo por los civiles si los items 
sean edición o personales estándar. Esta lección da a 
estudiantes la oportunidad de mirar no solamente los artefactos de 
Guillermo B. Umstead de la Primera Guerra Mundial, pero gana la 
penetración en cómo y porqué cada item fue utilizado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAULETTE SCOTT
FN:PAULETTE SCOTT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202576</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108323</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/outfitting-a-world-war-i-soldier-teaching-us-social-sciences-with-primary-sources</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
