<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108015</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108015</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087437</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Bigger Than Anything We Understood:" Cathy Wilkerson On The Political Culture of SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Grösser Als Alles, das Wir Verstanden:" 
Cathy Wilkerson auf der politischen Kultur von SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Plus grand Que Quelque chose Que Nous Avons 
compris :" Cathy Wilkerson sur la culture politique du SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Mais grande Do que Qualquer coisa Que Nós 
Compreendemos:" Cathy Wilkerson na cultura política do SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Più grande Di Qualche cosa Che Capiamo:" 
Cathy Wilkerson sulla coltura politica di SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μεγαλύτερος από τίποτα καταλάβαμε:" Θ*Θατχυ 
Wilkerson στον πολιτικό πολιτισμό SDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Más grande Que Cualquier cosa Que Entendíamos:" 
Cathy Wilkerson en la cultura política del SDS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Student radicalism and the New Left contributed to the rise of a "counterculture" during the 1960's, as millions of Americans questioned traditional forms of monogamy and family, suburban life, materialism, and scientific rationality and emotional repression. Outwardly, this cultural shift was marked by the rise of rock music, the growing use of marijuana and other drugs, and the end of many sexual taboos. For some, like SDS organizer Cathy Wilkerson, drugs represented a distraction from more serious cultural and political questioning and activism. Wilkerson edited the SDS newspaper,  New Left Notes,  and opened a regional SDS office in Washington, DC in 1968. [The material in brackets was added to the transcript shortly after the recorded interview.]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">KursteilnehmerRadikalismus und das neue links 
trugen zum Anstieg eines "counterculture" während der sechziger Jahre
bei, da Millionen Amerikaner traditionelle Formulare von monogamy und 
Familie, Vorstadtlebensdauer, Materialismus und wissenschaftliche 
Vernunft- und emotionaleunterdrückung fragten. Nach außen 
wurde diese kulturelle Schicht durch den Anstieg von Rockmusik, 
den wachsenden Gebrauch des Marihuanas und anderer Drogen und das Ende
vieler sexueller Tabus gekennzeichnet. Für einiges wie
SDS Organisator Cathy Wilkerson, Drogen stellte eine Ablenkung vom 
ernsteren kulturellen und politischen Ausfragen und vom Aktivismus 
dar. Wilkerson bearbeitete die SDS Zeitung, neue linke 
Anmerkungen und öffnete ein regionales SDS Büro in Washington, 
Gleichstrom 1968. [ das Material in den Haltewinkeln wurde der 
Abschrift kurz nach dem gespeicherten Interview. hinzugefügt ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le radicalisme d'étudiant et la nouvelle gauche 
ont contribué à l'élévation d'un "counterculture" pendant les 
années 60, car les millions d'Américains ont remis en cause les 
formes traditionnelles de monogamy et famille, vie suburbaine, 
matérialisme, et répression de rationalité et émotive 
scientifique. Extérieurement, ce décalage culturel a été 
marqué par l'élévation de musique de roche, l'utilisation 
croissante de la marijuana et d'autres drogues, et la fin de beaucoup 
de tabous sexuels. Pour certains, comme l'organisateur 
Cathy Wilkerson de SDS, des drogues a représenté une distraction 
d'une interrogation plus sérieuse et d'un activisme culturels et 
politiques. Wilkerson a édité le journal de SDS, nouvelles 
notes gauches, et a ouvert un bureau régional de SDS à Washington, 
C.C en 1968. [ le matériel entre parenthèses a été ajouté 
à la transcription peu de temps après l'entrevue enregistrée. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O radicalism do estudante e a esquerda nova 
contribuíram à ascensão de um "counterculture" durante os 1960's, 
porque os milhões dos americanos questionaram formulários 
tradicionais de monogamy e família, vida suburbana, materialism, e 
repression científico do rationality e o emocional. Externa, 
esta SHIFT cultural foi marcada pela ascensão da música da rocha, 
pelo uso de crescimento do marijuana e das outras drogas, e pelo fim 
de muitos tabus sexual. Para algum, como o organizer Cathy 
Wilkerson do SDS, drogas representou um distraction de questionar mais
sério e de activism cultural e políticos. Wilkerson editou o 
jornal do SDS, notas esquerdas novas, e abriu um escritório regional 
do SDS em Washington, C.C. em 1968. [ o material nos suportes 
foi adicionado ao transcript logo depois que a entrevista gravada. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il radicalism dell'allievo e la nuova parte di 
sinistra hanno contribuito all'aumento "di un counterculture" durante 
gli anni 60, poichè milioni di Americani hanno messo in discussione 
le forme tradizionali di monogamy e famiglia, vita suburbana, 
materialism e repressione impressionabile scientifica e di 
razionalità. Esteriormente, questo spostamento culturale è 
stato contrassegnato dall'aumento di musica della roccia, 
dall'utilizzazione crescente di marijuana e di altre droghe e dalla 
conclusione di molti taboos sessuali. Per alcuno, come 
l'organizzatore Cathy Wilkerson di SDS, droghe ha rappresentato una 
distrazione dall'interrogazione più seria e dal activism culturali e 
politici. Wilkerson ha stampato il giornale di SDS, nuove note 
di sinistra ed ha aperto un ufficio regionale di SDS in Washington, DC
in 1968. [ il materiale tra parentesi è stato aggiunto alla 
trascrizione subito dopo l'intervista registrata. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ριζοσπαστισμός σπουδαστών και το νέο αριστερό 
συνέβαλαν στην άνοδο ενός "counterculture" κατά τη διάρκεια 
της δεκαετίας του '60, δεδομένου ότι τα εκατομμύρια Αμερικανών 
εξέτασαν τις παραδοσιακές μορφές της μονογαμίας και της 
οικογένειας, της προαστιακής ζωής, του υλισμού, και της 
επιστημονικής συναισθηματικής καταστολής ορθολογιστικής 
ικανότητας και. Φαινομενικώς, αυτή η πολιτιστική μετατόπιση
χαρακτηρίστηκε από την άνοδο της μουσικής ροκ, την αυξανόμενη 
χρήση της μαριχουάνα και άλλων φαρμάκων, και το τέλος πολλών 
σεξουαλικών taboos. Για μερικούς, όπως SDS το 
διοργανωτή Cathy Wilkerson, τα φάρμακα αντιπροσώπευσαν μια 
απόσπαση της προσοχής από τη σοβαρότερη πολιτιστική και πολιτική
επερώτηση και τον ακτιβισμό. Το Wilkerson επιμελήθηκε τη 
SDS εφημερίδα, νέες αριστερές σημειώσεις, και άνοιξε ένα 
περιφερειακό γραφείο SDS στην Ουάσιγκτον, DC το 1968. 
[ Το υλικό εντός παρενθέσεως προστέθηκε στο αντίγραφο 
αμέσως μετά από την καταγραμμένη συνέντευξη. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El radicalismo del estudiante y la nueva izquierda 
contribuyeron a la subida de un "counterculture" durante los años 60,
pues millones de americanos preguntaron formas tradicionales de 
monogamy y familia, vida suburbana, materialism, y represión 
científica del racionalidad y emocional. Exterior, esta 
rotación cultural fue marcada por la subida de música de la roca, la
utilización creciente de la marijuana y de otras drogas, y el final 
de muchos tabúes sexuales. Para alguno, como el organizador 
Cathy Wilkerson del SDS, las drogas representó una distracción de 
preguntar más serio y del activismo culturales y políticos. 
Wilkerson corrigió el periódico del SDS, nuevas notas 
izquierdas, y abrió una oficina regional del SDS en Washington, C.C. 
en 1968. [ el material en corchetes fue agregado a la 
transcripción poco después la entrevista registrada. ]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087437</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108015</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bigger-than-anything-we-understood-cathy-wilkerson-on-the-political-culture-of-sds</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
