<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108668</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108668</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206009</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Why Files</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Warum Dateien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le pourquoi Fichiers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Porque Limas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Perchè Archivi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γιατί αρχεία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Porqué Ficheros</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">feature the latest news in science, math and technology. Learn how infrared vision works, the science behind cloning, or the statistical calculations that make political polling possible. Visitors can also join the site's online forum to participate in various science related discussions such as why the night sky is dark, interstellar distances, Einstein's influence, and much more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnen Sie die neuesten Nachrichten in der 
Wissenschaft, in Mathe und in der Technologie. Erlernen Sie wie 
Infrarotanblick arbeitet, die Wissenschaft hinter Klonen oder die 
statistischen Berechnungen, die politische Wahl 
ermöglichen. Besucher können das Onlineforum der Sites auch 
verbinden, um teilzunehmen an verschiedene Wissenschaft in Verbindung 
gestandenen Diskussionen wie, warum der Nachthimmel dunkle, 
interstellar Abstände, Einfluß Einsteins ist-, und viel mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comportez les dernières nouvelles en science, 
maths et technologie. Apprenez comment la vision infrarouge 
travaille, la science derrière le clonage, ou les calculs 
statistiques qui rendent l'interrogation politique possible. Les
visiteurs peuvent également joindre le forum en ligne du site pour 
participer aux discussions telles que pourquoi le ciel de nuit est des
distances foncées et interstellaires, l'influence d'Einstein, et 
beaucoup plus associés la diverse par science.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracterize a notícia a mais atrasada na 
ciência, no math e na tecnologia. Aprenda como a visão 
infravermelha trabalha, a ciência atrás do cloning, ou os cálculos 
estatísticos que fazem a votação política possível. Os 
visitantes podem também juntar o forum em linha do local para 
participar em discussões tais como porque o céu da noite está a 
umas distâncias escuras, interstellar, influência de Einstein, e 
muito mais relacionados vária ciência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizzi le ultime notizie nella scienza, nel 
per la matematica e nella tecnologia. Impari come la visione 
infrarossa funziona, scienza dietro clonazione, o i calcoli statistici
che permettono la votazione politica. Gli ospiti possono anche 
unire la tribuna in linea del luogo per partecipare alle discussioni 
come perchè il cielo di notte è distanze scure e interstellar, 
influenza del Einstein e molto più riferiti la varia scienza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίστε τις πιό πρόσφατες ειδήσεις στην 
επιστήμη, math και την τεχνολογία. Μάθετε πώς το 
υπέρυθρο όραμα λειτουργεί, η επιστήμη πίσω από την κλωνοποίηση,
ή οι στατιστικοί υπολογισμοί που καθιστούν την πολιτική 
ψηφοφορία πιθανή. Οι επισκέπτες μπορούν επίσης να ενώσουν 
το σε απευθείας σύνδεση φόρουμ της περιοχής για να συμμετέχουν 
στις διάφορες σχετικές με την επιστήμη συζητήσεις όπως γιατί ο 
ουρανός νύχτας είναι σκοτεινές, interstellar αποστάσεις, 
επιρροή Einstein, και πολύ περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrezca las noticias más últimas de la ciencia, 
de la matemáticas y de la tecnología. Aprenda cómo la visión
infrarroja trabaja, la ciencia detrás de la reproducción, o los 
cálculos estadísticos que hacen la interrogación política posible.
Los visitantes pueden también ensamblar el foro en línea del 
sitio para participar en discusiones tales como porqué el cielo de la
noche es distancias oscuras, interestelares, influencia de Einstein, y
mucho más relacionada varia ciencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206009</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108668</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-why-files</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
