<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107907</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107907</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086821</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Shaping Mental and Moral Forces": Memo on Propaganda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", die Geistes- und moralischen Kräfte formend": 
Protokoll auf Propaganda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"formant les forces mentales et morales" : 
Note sur la propagande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"dando forma a forças mentais e morais": 
Memorando no propaganda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"modellando le forze mentali e morali": 
Appunto su propaganda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Διαμορφώνοντας τις διανοητικές και ηθικές δυνάμεισ": 
Υπόμνημα στην προπαγάνδα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"formando fuerzas mentales y morales": Nota 
en propaganda</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The U.S. government rarely used the word propaganda during World War II when referring to its extensive use of radio, film, newspapers, posters, and leaflets to bolster public support for the war effort. It preferred, instead, terms like "education and information," "psychological warfare," or "morale building." Under whatever rubric, U.S. government media production during World War II was a massive and expensive undertaking. Politicians, public relations experts, and social scientists increasingly heralded film as the ideal medium for domestic propaganda, especially because of the increasing number of sixteen-millimeter projectors in schools, civic centers, and military training facilities. In a 1942 memo on film and propaganda, Eric Knight, a writer in the U.S. army's Morale Branch, argued that "shaping the mental and moral forces on the home front" was as important as, if not more important than, influencing either enemy or neutral nations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung verwendete selten
die Wortpropaganda während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, als, seinen 
umfangreichen Gebrauch des Radios, des Filmes, der Zeitungen, der 
Plakate, und der Blättchen ansprechend, allgemeinen Support für die 
Kriegbemühung zu polstern. Sie bevorzugte, stattdessen, 
Bezeichnungen wie "Ausbildung und Informationen," "psychologische 
Kriegsführung," oder "Moralgebäude." Unter, was Rubrik, 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung Mediaproduktion während des Zweiten 
Weltkrieges eine massive und kostspielige Übernahme war. 
Politiker, Öffentlichkeitsarbeitexperten und 
Sozialwissenschaftler kündigten in zunehmendem Maße Film als der 
ideale Medium für inländische Propaganda, besonders wegen der 
zunehmenden Zahl Sechzehnmillimeter Projektoren in den Schulen, in den
Behördenvierteln und in den militärisches Training Teildiensten an. 
In einem Protokoll 1942 auf Film und Propaganda, Eric Ritter, 
ein Verfasser im Moral-Zweig der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Armee, 
argumentiert, daß, "die Geistes- und moralischen Kräfte auf der 
Hauptfrontseite zu formen" so wichtig wie war, wenn nicht wichtiger 
als, entweder die feindlichen oder Nullnationen beeinflussend.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS a rarement utilisé
la propagande de mot pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale en se 
rapportant à son utilisation étendue de radio, de film, de journaux,
d'affiches, et de feuillets de soutenir le soutien public de l'effort 
de guerre. Il a préféré, au lieu de cela, des limites comme 
l'"éducation et l'information," "guerre psychologique," ou "bâtiment
de moral." Sous quelque rubrique, production de medias de 
gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale ait 
été une entreprise massive et chère. Les politiciens, les 
experts en matière de relations publiques, et les sociologues ont de 
plus en plus annoncé le film comme support idéal pour la propagande 
domestique, particulièrement en raison du nombre croissant de 
projecteurs de seize-millimètre dans les écoles, les centres 
municipaux, et les équipements de formation militaire. Dans une
note 1942 sur le film et la propagande, le chevalier d'Eric, un auteur
dans le branchement du moral de l'armée des ETATS-UNIS, argué du 
fait que la "formation des forces mentales et morales sur l'avant à 
la maison" était aussi importante que, si plus important que, 
influençant les nations ennemies ou neutres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS usou raramente o 
propaganda da palavra durante a segunda guerra mundial ao consultar a 
seu uso extensivo do rádio, da película, dos jornais, dos posteres, 
e dos leaflets bolster a sustentação pública para o esforço da 
guerra. Preferiu, instead, termos como a "instrução e a 
informação," "ação psicológico," ou do "edifício morale." 
Sob o que rubric, produção dos media do governo de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS durante a segunda guerra mundial era um empreendimento maciço 
e caro. Os políticos, os peritos das relações públicas, e os
cientistas sociais heralded cada vez mais a película como o media 
ideal para o propaganda doméstico, especial por causa do número 
crescente de projetores de dezesseis-milímetro nas escolas, em 
centros civic, e em facilidades de treinamento militar. Em um 
memorando 1942 na película e no propaganda, o knight de Eric, um 
escritor na filial do morale do exército de ESTADOS UNIDOS, discutida
isso "que dá forma às forças mentais e morais na parte dianteira 
home" eram tão importantes quanto, if.not mais importante do que, 
influenciando as nações inimigas ou neutras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il governo degli STATI UNITI ha usato raramente la
propaganda di parola durante la seconda guerra mondiale quando si 
riferisce al relativo vasto uso della radio, della pellicola, dei 
giornali, dei manifesti e degli opuscoli sostenere il sostegno 
pubblico lo sforzo di guerra. Ha preferito, invece, i termini 
come "formazione e le informazioni," "guerra psicologica," o 
"costruzione di morale." Sotto che cosa rubrica, produzione di 
media di governo degli STATI UNITI durante la seconda guerra mondiale 
era un'impresa voluminosa e costosa. I politici, gli esperti di 
pubbliche relazioni ed i sociologi sempre più hanno annunziato la 
pellicola come il media ideale per la propaganda domestica, 
particolarmente a causa del numero aumentante di proiettori di 
sedici-millimetro in scuole, nei centri cittadini e nelle possibilità
di formazione militari. In un appunto 1942 sulla pellicola e 
sulla propaganda, il cavaliere di Eric, un produttore nel ramo di 
morale dell'esercito degli STATI UNITI, discusso quello "che modella 
le forze mentali e morali sulla parte anteriore domestica" erano 
importanti quanto, se non più importante di, influenzando le nazioni 
nemiche o neutre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ κυβέρνηση χρησιμοποίησε σπάνια την την 
προπαγάνδα λέξης κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ 
κατά αναφορά στην εκτενή χρήση της ραδιοφώνου, ταινίας, 
εφημερίδων, αφισών, και φυλλάδιων για να υποστηρίξει τη δημόσια 
υποστήριξη για την πολεμική προσπάθεια. Προτίμησε, αντ' 
αυτού, τους όρους όπως "την εκπαίδευση και τις πληροφορίες," 
"ψυχολογική εχθροπραξία," ή "οικοδόμηση ηθικού." Κάτω από
ο,τιδήποτε ρουμπρίκα, παραγωγή μέσων ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης 
κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ ήταν ογκώδης και 
ακριβή επιχείρηση. Οι πολιτικοί, οι εμπειρογνώμονες 
δημόσιων σχέσεων, και οι κοινωνικοί επιστήμονες ανακοίνωσαν όλο 
και περισσότερο την ταινία ως ιδανικό μέσο για την εσωτερική 
προπαγάνδα, ειδικά λόγω του αυξανόμενου αριθμού προβολέων δέκα 
έξι-χιλιοστόμετρου στα σχολεία, τα πολιτικά κέντρα, και τις 
εγκαταστάσεις στρατιωτικής κατάρτισης. Σε ένα υπόμνημα του 
1942 στην ταινία και την προπαγάνδα, Eric Knight, ένας 
συγγραφέας στον κλάδο ηθικού του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ στρατού, υποστήριξε
ότι "η διαμόρφωση των διανοητικών και ηθικών δυνάμεων στο βασικό
μέτωπο" ήταν τόσο σημαντική όπως, εάν μη σημαντικότερος από, 
επηρεάζοντας είτε τα εχθρικά είτε ουδέτερα έθνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS utilizó raramente 
la propaganda de la palabra durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial al 
referir a su uso extenso de la radio, de la película, de periódicos,
de carteles, y de prospectos de alentar la ayuda pública para el 
esfuerzo de la guerra. Prefirió, en lugar, términos como la 
"educación y la información," "guerra psicologica," o "edificio de 
la moral." Bajo cualquier rúbrica, producción de los media del
gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial era una 
empresa masiva y costosa. Los políticos, los expertos de las 
relaciones públicas, y los científicos sociales anunciaron cada vez 
más la película como el media ideal para la propaganda doméstica, 
especialmente debido a el número de aumento de los proyectores del 
diecise'is-mili'metro en escuelas, centros cívicos, y recursos de 
entrenamiento militar. En una nota 1942 en la película y la 
propaganda, el caballero de Eric, un programa de escritura en la 
ramificación de la moral del ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS, discutida 
eso "que formaba las fuerzas mentales y morales en el frente casero" 
eran tan importantes como, si no más importante que, influenciando 
las naciones enemigas o neutrales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086821</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107907</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shaping-mental-and-moral-forces-memo-on-propaganda</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
