<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103673</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103673</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086872</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Suspicion of Subversion: Congressional Conservatives Attack the Federal Theater Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Misstrauen der Subversion: 
Kongreßkonservative nehmen das Bundestheater-Projekt in 
Angriff</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Soupçon de subversion : Les conservateurs 
congressionnels attaquent le projet fédéral de théâtre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Suspeita do subversion: Os conservadores 
congressionais atacam o projeto federal do teatro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sospetto della sovversione: I Conservatori 
congressuali attacano il progetto federale del teatro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποψία της ανατροπής: Τα του Κογκρέσου 
συντηρητικά επιτίθενται στο ομοσπονδιακό πρόγραμμα θεάτρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Suspicacia de la subversión: Los 
conservadores del congreso atacan el proyecto federal del teatro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Part of the New Deal's Works Progress Administration (WPA), the Federal Theatre Project (FTP) was one indication of the breadth of that program. Perhaps best known for its trenchant political satire and innovative presentations, the FTP actually represented a much broader range of activity. But the FTP's mandate proved fragile. When the House Committee on Un-American Activities was established in May 1938, one of its first targets was the FTP, which it labeled a subversive organization. When FTP director Hallie Flanagan testified before HUAC in December 1938, she fought back against these attacks. But the FTP still fell victim to the Congressional cuts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zerteilen Sie von der Fortschritt-Leitung Arbeiten 
des neuen Abkommens (WPA), das Bundestheater-Projekt (ftp) war eine 
Anzeige über die Breite dieses Programms. Möglicherweise gut 
gewußt für seine trenchant politische Satire und 
erfinderischen Darstellungen, stellte das ftp wirklich eine viel 
ausgedehntere Strecke der Aktivität dar. Aber die Vollmacht des
ftp prüfte zerbrechliches. Als der Haus-Ausschuß für 
Un-Amerikanische Aktivitäten im Mai 1938 hergestellt wurde, war eins 
seiner ersten Ziele das ftp, das es eine subversivee Organisation 
beschriftete. Als ftp Direktor Hallie Flanagan vor HUAC im 
Dezember 1938 bezeugte, kämpfte sie zurück gegen diese Angriffe. 
Aber das ftp fiel noch Opfer zu den Kongreßschnitten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Partie de la gestion d'avancement des travaux de 
nouvelle affaire (WPA), le projet fédéral de théâtre (ftp) était 
une indication de la largeur de ce programme. Peut-être mieux 
connu pour son satire politique incisive et présentations 
innovatrices, le ftp a représenté réellement un intervalle beaucoup
plus large d'activité. Mais le mandat du ftp a prouvé fragile.
Quand le comité de Chambre des activités Un-Américaines a 
été établi en mai 1938, une de ses premières cibles était le ftp,
qu'elle a étiqueté une organisation subversive. Quand 
directeur Hallie Flanagan de ftp a témoigné avant HUAC en décembre 
1938, elle a lutté en arrière contre ces attaques. Mais le ftp
tombait toujours victime aux coupes congressionnelles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Parte da administração do progresso de trabalhos 
de negócio novo (WPA), o projeto federal do theatre (ftp) era uma 
indicação da largura desse programa. Sabido talvez melhor para
seus satire político trenchant e apresentações inovativas, o ftp 
representou realmente uma escala muito mais larga da atividade. 
Mas o mandato do ftp provou frágil. Quando o comitê da 
casa em atividades Un-Americanas foi estabelecido em maio 1938, um de 
seus primeiros alvos era o ftp, que etiquetou uma organização 
subversiva. Quando o diretor Hallie Flanagan do ftp testified 
antes de HUAC em dezembro 1938, lutou para trás de encontro a estes 
ataques. Mas o ftp caiu ainda vítima aos cortes congressionais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parte della gestione di progresso degli impianti 
del nuovo affare (WPA), il progetto federale del teatro (ftp) era 
un'indicazione della larghezza di quel programma. Saputo forse 
il più bene per il relativi satire politico trenchant e presentazioni
innovarici, il ftp realmente ha rappresentato una gamma molto più 
vasta di attività. Ma il mandato del ftp ha dimostrato fragile.
Quando il comitato della Camera delle attività ONU-Americane è
stato istituito nel mese di maggio 1938, uno dei relativi primi 
obiettivi era il ftp, che ha identificato un'organizzazione 
sovversiva. Quando il direttore Hallie Flanagan del ftp ha 
testimoniato prima di HUAC nel mese di dicembre del 1938, ha 
combattuto indietro contro questi attacchi. Ma il ftp ancora è 
caduto vittima ai tagli congressuali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέρος της διοίκησης προόδου εργασιών της νέας 
διαπραγμάτευσης (WPA), το ομοσπονδιακό έργο θεάτρων (FTP) 
ήταν μια ένδειξη του εύρους εκείνου του προγράμματος. Ίσως
γνωστό καλύτερα για την οξεία πολιτική σάτυρα και τις καινοτόμες
παρουσιάσεις του, το FTP αντιπροσώπευσε πραγματικά ένα πολύ 
ευρύτερο φάσμα της δραστηριότητας. Αλλά η εξουσιοδότηση του
FTP αποδείχθηκε εύθραυστη. Όταν η Επιτροπή Βουλών των 
αντιαμερικανικών δραστηριοτήτων καθιερώθηκε σε Μάιος το 
1938, ένας από τους πρώτους στόχους του ήταν το FTP, το 
οποίο ονόμασε μια ανατρεπτική οργάνωση. Όταν το FTP 
σκηνοθέτης Hallie Flanagan πιστοποίησε πριν από HUAC τον 
Δεκέμβριο του 1938, πάλεψε πίσω ενάντια σε αυτές τις 
επιθέσεις. Αλλά το FTP μειώθηκε ακόμα θύμα στις του 
Κογκρέσου αποκοπές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Parte de la administración del progreso de 
trabajos del nuevo reparto (WPA), el proyecto federal del teatro (ftp)
era una indicación de la anchura de ese programa. Sabido 
quizás lo más mejor posible para su sátira política mordaz y 
presentaciones innovadoras, el ftp representó realmente un rango 
mucho más amplio de la actividad. Pero el mandato del ftp 
probó frágil. Cuando establecieron al comité de la casa sobre
actividades Un-Americanas en mayo de 1938, una de sus primeras blancos
era el ftp, que etiquetó una organización subversiva. Cuando 
director Hallie Flanagan del ftp atestiguó antes de HUAC en diciembre
de 1938, ella luchó detrás contra estos ataques. Pero el ftp 
todavía cayó víctima a los cortes del congreso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086872</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103673</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/suspicion-of-subversion-congressional-conservatives-attack-the-federal-theater-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
