<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105605</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105605</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086749</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Plunkitt's Plain Talk: Satirizing Steffens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Plunkitts Normales Gespräch: Satirizing 
Steffens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Entretien Ordinaire de Plunkitt : 
Satiriser Steffens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Conversa Lisa De Plunkitt: Satirizing 
Steffens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Colloquio Normale Del Plunkitt: Satirizing 
Steffens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαφής συζήτηση Plunkitt: Διακωμόδηση 
Steffens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Charla Llana De Plunkitt: Satirizing 
Steffens</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The reform-minded journalists of the early 20th century were the ancestors of today's investigative reporters. Known as "muckrakers" (so named by President Theodore Roosevelt after the muckrake in Bunyan's  Pilgrim's Progress  who could "look no way but downward, with a muckrake in his hands"), these journalists published their sensational articles in the inexpensive mass circulation magazines that became possible and popular in the 1890s. The "muckrakers" wrote on many subjects, such as child labor, prisons, religion, corporations, and insurance companies, but urban political corruption remained a particularly popular target. Lincoln Steffens was famous for his investigations of urban politics. In 1904 he collected his writings on St. Louis, Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, Philadelphia, Chicago, and New York into  The Shame of the Cities . New York political boss George Washington Plunkitt offered his own skeptical and humorous view of Steffens' book as one chapter in a series of "Plain Talks on Very Practical Politics," published in 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die verbessern-gekümmerten Journalisten des 
frühen 20. Jahrhunderts waren die Vorfahren der heutigen 
Untersuchungsreporter. Bekannt als "muckrakers" (so benannt vom 
Präsidenten Theodore Roosevelt nach dem muckrake im Fortschritt des 
Pilgrims Bunyans, der "keine Methode schauen könnte, aber abwärts, 
mit einem muckrake in seinen Händen"), veröffentlichten diese 
Journalisten ihre sensational Artikel in den billigen 
Massenzirkulation Zeitschriften, die möglich und im 1890s populär 
wurden. Die "muckrakers" schrieben auf viele Themen, wie 
Kinderarbeit, Gefängnisse, Religion, Korporationen und 
Versicherungsgesellschaften, aber städtische politische Korruption 
blieb ein besonders populäres Ziel. Lincoln Steffens war für 
seine Untersuchungen der städtischen Politiken berühmt. 1904 
sammelte er seine Schreiben auf St. Louis, Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, 
Philadelphia, Chicago und New York in die Schande der Städte. 
New York politischer Chef George Washington Plunkitt bot sein 
eigenes skeptisches an und humorvolle Ansicht von Buch Steffens' als 
einem Kapitel in einer Reihe von "normalen Gesprächen auf sehr 
praktischen Politiken," veröffentlichte 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les journalistes reformer-occupés du début du 
20ème siècle étaient les ancêtres des journalistes investigateurs 
d'aujourd'hui. Connu en tant que "muckrakers" (ainsi nommés par
le Président Theodore Roosevelt après le muckrake dans le progrès 
du pélerin de Bunyan qui ne pourrait "regarder aucune voie mais en 
bas, avec un muckrake dans des ses mains"), ces journalistes ont 
édité leurs articles sensationnels dans les magazines de masse peu 
coûteux de circulation qui sont devenus possibles et populaires dans 
le 1890s. Les "muckrakers" ont écrit sur beaucoup de sujets, 
tels que le travail des enfants, prisons, religion, sociétés, et 
compagnies d'assurance, mais la corruption politique urbaine est 
demeurée une cible particulièrement populaire. Lincoln 
Steffens était célèbre pour ses investigations sur la politique 
urbaine. En 1904 il a rassemblé ses écritures sur St Louis, 
Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, Philadelphie, Chicago, et New York dans la 
honte des villes. Le patron politique George Washington 
Plunkitt de New York a offert son propre sceptique et la vue pleine 
d'humour du livre de Steffens en tant qu'un chapitre dans une série 
"d'entretiens ordinaires sur la politique très pratique," a édité 
en 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os journalists reform-ocupados do 20o século 
adiantado eram os antepassados de repórteres investigative de hoje. 
Sabido como os "muckrakers" (nomeados assim pelo presidente 
Theodore Roosevelt após o muckrake no progresso do pilgrim de Bunyan 
que não poderia "não olhar nenhuma maneira mas para baixo, com um 
muckrake em suas mãos"), estes journalists publicaram seus artigos do
sensational nos compartimentos maciços baratos da circulação que se
tornaram possíveis e populares no 1890s. Os "muckrakers" 
escreveram em muitos assuntos, tais como o trabalho de criança, em 
prisões, em religião, em corporation, e em companhias de seguro, mas
o corruption político urbano remanesceu um alvo particularmente 
popular. Lincoln Steffens era famoso para suas investigações 
da política urbana. Em 1904 coletou suas escritas em St. Louis,
Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, Filadélfia, Chicago, e New York no shame das
cidades. A saliência política George Washington Plunkitt de 
New York ofereceu seu próprio skeptical e a vista humorous do livro 
de Steffens' como um capítulo em uma série "de conversas lisas na 
política muito prática," publicou em 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I giornalisti riform-occupati di di inizio del 
20esimo secolo erano gli antenati di odierni reporter 
investigativi. Conosciuto come "muckrakers" (così chiamati dal 
presidente Theodore Roosevelt dopo il muckrake nel progresso del 
pilgrim del Bunyan che non potrebbe "non osservare modo ma verso il 
basso, con un muckrake in sue mani"), questi giornalisti hanno 
pubblicato i loro articoli di sensational negli scomparti totali 
economici di circolazione che sono diventato possibili e popolari nel 
1890s. "i muckrakers" hanno scritto su molti oggetti, quale il 
lavoro del bambino, sulle prigioni, sulla religione, sulle 
società e sulle società di assicurazioni, ma la corruzione politica 
urbana è rimasto un obiettivo particolarmente popolare. Lincoln
Steffens era famosa per le sue indagini sulle politiche urbane. 
In 1904 ha raccolto le sue scritture su St. Louis, su 
Minneapolis, su Pittsburgh, su Filadelfia, su Chicago e su New York 
nella Vergogna delle città. La sporgenza politica George 
Washington Plunkitt de New York ha offerto il suo proprio scettico e 
la vista divertente del libro dello Steffens come un capitolo in serie
"di Colloqui normali sulle politiche molto pratiche," ha pubblicato
in 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι μεταρρύθμιση-απασχολημένοι δημοσιογράφοι του 
πρόωρου 20ού αιώνα ήταν οι πρόγονοι των σημερινών εξεταστικών 
δημοσιογράφων. Γνωστοί ως "muckrakers" (έτσι ονομασμένος 
από τον Πρόεδρο Theodore Roosevelt μετά από το muckrake 
στην πρόοδο του προσκυνητή Bunyan που δεν θα μπορούσε "να φανεί
κανένας τρόπος αλλά προς τα κάτω, με ένα muckrake στα χέρια 
του"), αυτοί οι δημοσιογράφοι δημοσίευσαν τα συγκλονιστικά άρθρα 
τους στα ανέξοδα περιοδικά μαζικής κυκλοφορίας που ήταν δυνατό 
και δημοφιλή στο 1890s. Τα "muckrakers" έγραψαν σε 
πολλά θέματα, όπως η παιδική εργασία, τις φυλακές, τη θρησκεία,
τις εταιρίες, και τις ασφαλιστικές εταιρείες, αλλά η αστική 
πολιτική δωροδοκία παρέμεινε ένας ιδιαίτερα δημοφιλής στόχος. 
Το Λίνκολν Steffens ήταν διάσημο για τις έρευνες για 
αστική πολιτική του. Το 1904 συνέλεξε τις γραφές του στο 
ST Louis, Μινεάπολη, Πίτσμπουργκ, Φιλαδέλφεια, Σικάγο, και 
Νέα Υόρκη στην ντροπή των πόλεων. Η Νέα Υόρκη πολιτικός 
κύριος George Ουάσιγκτον Plunkitt πρόσφερε τη δύσπιστη και 
χιουμοριστική όψη του βιβλίου Steffens ως ένα κεφάλαιο σε μία
σειρά των "σαφών συζητήσεων στην πολύ πρακτική πολιτική," 
δημοσιευμένος το 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los periodistas reformar-importados del vigésimo 
siglo temprano eran los antepasados de reporteros investigadores de 
hoy. Conocido como "muckrakers" (nombrados tan por presidente 
Theodore Roosevelt después del muckrake en el progreso del peregrino 
de Bunyan que no podría "mirar ninguna manera pero hacia abajo, con 
un muckrake en sus manos"), estos periodistas publicaron sus 
artículos del sensational en los compartimientos totales baratos de 
la circulación que llegaron a ser posibles y populares en el 1890s. 
Los "muckrakers" escribieron en muchos temas, tales como trabajo
de niño, prisiones, la religión, corporaciones, y compañías de 
seguros, pero la corrupción política urbana seguía siendo una 
blanco determinado popular. Lincoln Steffens era famosa por sus 
investigaciones de políticas urbanas. En 1904 él recogió sus 
escrituras en St. Louis, Minneapolis, Pittsburgh, Philadelphia, 
Chicago, y Nueva York en la vergüenza de las ciudades. El jefe 
político George Washington Plunkitt de Nueva York ofreció su propio 
escéptico y la vista chistosa del libro de Steffens como un capítulo
en una serie de "negociaciones llanas sobre políticas muy 
prácticas," publicó en 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086749</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105605</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/plunkitts-plain-talk-satirizing-steffens</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
