<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105358</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105358</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Looking at Ourselves and Others</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Betrachten uns selbst und andere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Regarder nous-mêmes et d'autres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Olhando nos e outros</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Guardando noi stessi ed altri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξέταση μας και άλλους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mirar a nosotros mismos y a otros</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">introduces students to the concepts of perspective, culture, and cross-cultural relations. The guide is designed to help students recognize and appreciate differences in perception among individuals and cultures, define culture and recognize its role in developing perceptions of ourselves and others, challenge assumptions, promote cross-cultural awareness, and provide opportunities to practice the behaviors that make cross-cultural communication possible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Kursteilnehmer zu den Konzepten der 
Perspektive, der Kultur und der Kreuz-kulturellen Relationen vor. 
Die Anleitung ist konzipiert, um Kursteilnehmern zu helfen, 
Unterschiede bezüglich der Vorstellung unter Einzelpersonen und 
Kulturen zu erkennen und zu schätzen, Kultur zu definieren und seine 
Rolle in sich entwickelnden Vorstellungen von uns selbst und andere, 
Herausforderung Annahmen zu erkennen, Kreuz-kulturelles Bewußtsein zu
fördern und Gelegenheiten zur Verfügung zu stellen, das Verhalten zu
üben, das Kreuz-kulturelle Kommunikation ermöglichen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente des étudiants aux concepts de la 
perspective, de la culture, et des relations croix-culturelles. 
Le guide est conçu pour aider des étudiants à identifier et 
apprécier des différences dans la perception parmi des individus et 
des cultures, à définir la culture et à identifier son rôle dans 
des perceptions se développantes de nous-mêmes et d'autres, des 
prétentions de défi, à favoriser la conscience croix-culturelle, et
à fournir des occasions de pratiquer les comportements qui rendent la
transmission croix-culturelle possible.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">introduz estudantes aos conceitos do perspective, 
da cultura, e de relações cruz-cross-cultural. A guia é 
projetada ajudar a estudantes reconhecer e apreciar diferenças na 
percepção entre indivíduos e culturas, definir a cultura e 
reconhecer seu papel em percepções tornando-se de nos e outros, 
suposições do desafio, promover a consciência cruz-cross-cultural, 
e fornecer oportunidades de praticar os comportamentos que fazem uma 
comunicação cruz-cross-cultural possível.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">introduce gli allievi ai concetti della 
prospettiva, della coltura e dei rapporti traversa-culturali. La
guida è destinata per aiutare gli allievi a riconoscere ed apprezzare
le differenze nella percezione fra gli individui e colture, a definire
la coltura e riconoscere il relativo ruolo nelle percezioni di 
sviluppo di noi stessi ed altri, presupposti di sfida, a promuovere la
consapevolezza traversa-culturale ed a fornire le occasioni 
esercitarsi nei comportamenti che permettono la comunicazione 
traversa-culturale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εισάγει τους σπουδαστές στις έννοιες της προοπτικής, 
του πολιτισμού, και των διαπολιτισμικών σχέσεων. Ο οδηγός 
σχεδιάζεται για να βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές να αναγνωρίσουν και να
εκτιμήσουν τις διαφορές στην αντίληψη μεταξύ των ατόμων και των 
πολιτισμών, να καθορίσουν τον πολιτισμό και να αναγνωρίσουν το 
ρόλο του στην ανάπτυξη των αντιλήψεων για μας και άλλους, 
υποθέσεις πρόκλησης, να προωθήσουν τη διαπολιτισμική 
συνειδητοποίηση, και να παρέχουν τις ευκαιρίες να ασκηθούν οι 
συμπεριφορές που καθιστούν τη διαπολιτισμική επικοινωνία πιθανή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">introduce a estudiantes a los conceptos de la 
perspectiva, de la cultura, y de las relaciones cruz-culturales. 
La guía se diseña para ayudar a estudiantes a reconocer y a 
apreciar diferencias en la opinión entre individuos y las culturas, a
definir la cultura y a reconocer su papel en opiniones que se 
convierten de nosotros mismos y otros, las asunciones del desafío, a 
promover conocimiento cruz-cultural, y a proporcionar a oportunidades 
de practicar los comportamientos que hacen la comunicación 
cruz-cultural posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105358</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/looking-at-ourselves-and-others</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
