<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085257</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Civil Rights Movement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Zivilrecht-Bewegung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Mouvement de Droits Civiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Movimento Das Direitas Civis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Movimento Di Diritti Civili</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Κίνημα αστικών δικαιωμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Movimiento De las Derechas Civiles</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1948, President Harry Truman took an early step towards civil rights reform by issuing Executive Order 9981, which eliminated racial segregation in the military. After World War II, African Americans ? then often called Negroes or "coloreds," began to mobilize against discrimination. They demanded an end to segregation and fought for equality in education, housing, and employment opportunities. The images in this topic show that by the 1960s, their struggle ? which began in the segregated South ? had reached California. As a number of photographs in this topic show, many Californians showed their support for Civil Rights activists and victims of racial discrimination in the South by holding marches, rallies, and demonstrations urging equality for African Americans. In one image three white children in San Francisco hold a sign in support of the four young black girls killed in the 1963 bombing of the 16th Street Baptist Church in Birmingham, Alabama. Photographs also show people in San Francisco boycotting Kress and Woolworth's department stores, sites of racial discrimination in the South. Documents shown here include a flyer urging the boycott of the stores; and a Western Union telegram sent in 1963, stating that Civil Rights activists Roy Wilkins and Medgar Evers were arrested attempting to picket Woolworth's in Jackson, Mississippi. Two photographs of memorials for slain civil rights leaders ? a march in honor Medgar Evers in 1963, in Los Angeles, and a memorial in the San Francisco Bay Area for Martin Luther King, Jr., in 1968 ? show racially mixed crowds in attendance. But not all Californians sympathized with the Civil Rights movement. Images of racial hatred and prejudice are reflected in the photograph of an African American woman holding a rock that had been thrown through an office window, and Klu Klux Klan graffiti spray-painted on a home. Various groups formed to fight in the struggle for equal rights. The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), formed in 1909, entered a new phase during this period, leading in the organized struggle for civil rights. An example of how the NAACP communicated about events is reflected in a letter from the Alameda County branch of the NAACP on June 13, 1950, which reported segregation on the Southern Pacific Railroad trains leaving Los Angeles. A flyer promoting the boycott of California grapes exemplifies NAACP support for other rights movements, in this case the United Farm Workers. Other flyers urged Californians to fight sharecropper wages and "Keep Mississippi Out of California." Groups such as the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE) and student groups also protested segregation and incidents of racial discrimination in the South. Several important African American leaders ? including Martin Luther King, Jr., Malcolm X, Thurgood Marshall, and Ralph Abernathy ? all came to California, as documented by photographs included here. Sometimes, the price of fighting for social justice was high. Two images capture events held for leaders in the social justice movement who were assassinated: the 1963 memorial march in Los Angeles for civil rights leader Medgar Evers; and a crowd attending a Martin Luther King, Jr., Memorial Rally in honor of the slain civil rights leader.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1948 unternahm Präsident Harry Truman einen 
frühen Jobstep in Richtung zur Zivilrechtverbesserung, indem er 
Ausführungsverordnung 9981 herausgab, die rassische Abtrennung im 
Militär beseitigte. Nach Dem Zweiten Weltkrieg Afrikanische 
Amerikaner? dann häufig angerufener fingen Negroes oder 
"coloreds," an, gegen Unterscheidung zu mobilisieren. Sie 
verlangten ein Ende zur Abtrennung und kämpften für Gleichheit in 
der Ausbildung, im Gehäuse und in den Beschäftigungsmöglichkeiten. 
Die Bilder in diesem Thema zeigen daß bis zum den sechziger 
Jahren, ihr Kampf? welches fing im getrennten Süden an? 
hatte Kalifornien erreicht. Wie eine Anzahl von 
Fotographien in diesem Themaerscheinen, viele Kalifornier ihren 
Support für Zivilrechtaktivisten und Opfer der rassischen 
Unterscheidung im Süden zeigte, indem sie Märze, Sammlungen und die 
Demonstrationen, die Gleichheit für afrikanische Amerikaner drängen 
anhielt. In den weißen Kindern eines Bildes drei im San 
Francisco Einfluß ein Zeichen zur Unterstützung der vier jungen 
schwarzen Mädchen beendet in der Bombardierung 1963 der 16. Straße 
Baptist-Kirche in Birmingham, Alabama. Fotographien zeigen auch 
die Leute in San Francisco Kress und Woolworths Abteilung 
boykottierend Speicher, Sites der rassischen Unterscheidung im Süden.
Die Dokumente, die hier gezeigt werden, enthalten einen Flieger,
der den Boykott der Speicher drängt; und ein westliches 
Anschlußtelegramm gesendet 1963, angebend, daß Zivilrechtaktivisten 
Roy Wilkins und Medgar Evers festgehaltenes Versuchen waren, 
Woolworths in Jackson, Mississippi einzupfählen. Zwei 
Fotographien der Denkmäler für getötete Zivilrechtführer? 
ein März in der Ehre Medgar Evers 1963, in Los Angeles und ein 
Denkmal im San Francisco Bucht-Bereich für Martin Luther König, jr.,
1968? zeigen Sie rassisch Mischmassen anwesend. Aber nicht
alle Kalifornier sympathisierten mit der Zivilrechtbewegung. 
Bilder des rassischen Hasses und des Vorurteils werden in der 
Fotographie einer afrikanischen amerikanischen Frau reflektiert, die 
einen Felsen anhält, der durch ein Bürofenster geworfen worden war, 
und Klu Klux Klan den Graffiti, der auf einem Haus Spray-gemalt wird. 
Verschiedene Gruppen bildeten sich, um im Kampf für gleiche 
Rechte zu kämpfen. Die nationale Verbindung für die Zuführung
der Farbiger (NAACP), gebildet 1909, erreichte eine neue Phase 
während dieser Periode und führte im organisierten Kampf für 
Zivilrechte. Ein Beispiel von, wie das NAACP, das über Fälle 
mitgeteilt wird, in einem Zeichen vom Alameda Grafschaftzweig des 
NAACP an Juni 13, 1950 reflektiert wird, der über Abtrennung auf den 
südlichen pazifischen Eisenbahnserien berichtete, die Los Angeles 
verlassen. Ein Flieger, der den Boykott der Kalifornien Trauben 
fördert, illustriert NAACP Support für andere Rechtbewegungen, in 
diesem Fall die vereinigten Landarbeiter. Andere Flieger 
drängten Kalifornier, sharecropper Löhne zu kämpfen und "halten Sie
Mississippi aus Kalifornien heraus." Gruppen wie der Kongreß 
der rassischen Gleichheit (KERN) und Studentengruppen protestierten 
auch Abtrennung und Ereignisse der rassischen Unterscheidung im 
Süden. Einige wichtige afrikanische amerikanische Führer? 
einschließlich Martin Luther König, jr., Malcolm X, Thurgood 
Marschall und Ralph Abernathy? alle kamen zu Kalifornien, wie 
durch die Fotographien dokumentiert, die hier eingeschlossen waren. 
Manchmal war der Preis des Kämpfens für Sozialgerechtigkeit 
hoch. Zwei Bildsicherung Fälle hielten für Führer in der 
Sozialgerechtigkeitbewegung an, die ermordet wurden: der 
Erinnerungsmärz 1963 in Los Angeles für Zivilrechtführer Medgar 
Evers; und eine Masse, die einen Martin Luther König, jr., 
Erinnerungssammlung zu Ehren des getöteten Zivilrechtführers 
bedient.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1948, le Président Harry Truman a pris une 
mesure tôt vers la réforme de droits civiques en émettant la 
commande exécutive 9981, qui a éliminé la ségrégation raciale 
dans les militaires. Après La Deuxième guerre mondiale, 
Américains Africains ? puis Negroes ou "coloreds souvent 
appelés," a commencé à mobiliser contre la discrimination. 
Ils ont exigé une extrémité à la ségrégation et ont 
combattu pour l'égalité dans l'éducation, le logement, et les 
offres d'emploi. Les images dans ce sujet prouvent que par les 
années 60, leur lutte ? qu'a commencé dans les Sud 
isolés ? avait atteint la Californie. Car un certain 
nombre de photographies dans ce sujet montrent, beaucoup de 
Californiens ont montré leur soutien des activistes de droits 
civiques et des victimes de discrimination raciale dans les 
Sud en tenant mars, rassemblements, et démonstrations 
poussant l'égalité pour les Américains africains. Dans les 
enfants blancs d'une image trois dans la prise de San Francisco un 
signe à l'appui des quatre jeunes filles noires détruites dans le 
bombardement 1963 de la 16ème église de baptiste de rue à 
Birmingham, Alabama. Les photographies montrent également des 
personnes dans San Francisco boycottant les grands magasins de Kress 
et de Woolworth, sites de discrimination raciale dans les Sud.
Les documents montrés ici incluent un insecte encourageant le 
boycott des mémoires ; et un télégramme occidental des 
syndicats introduit 1963, déclarant que les activistes Roy Wilkins et
Medgar Evers de droits civiques étaient essayer arrêté de 
palissader Woolworth à Jackson, Mississippi. Deux photographies
des mémoriaux pour les amorces de droits civiques massacrées ? 
une marche dans l'honneur Medgar Evers en 1963, à Los Angeles, 
et un mémorial dans la région de compartiment de San Francisco pour
le roi de Martin Luther, Jr., en 1968 ? montrez les foules 
racial mélangées de service. Mais non tous les Californiens 
ont sympathisé avec le mouvement de droits civiques. Des images
de la haine et du préjudice raciaux sont reflétées dans la 
photographie d'une femme américaine africaine tenant une roche qui 
avait été jetée par une fenêtre de bureau, et le graffiti de Klu 
Klux Klan jet-peint sur une maison. Les divers groupes ont 
formé pour combattre dans la lutte pour l'égalité des droits. 
L'association nationale pour l'avancement des personnes de 
couleur (NAACP), formé en 1909, a écrit une nouvelle phase pendant 
cette période, menant dans la lutte organisée pour des droits 
civiques. Un exemple de la façon dont le NAACP communiqué au 
sujet des événements est reflété dans une lettre du branchement du
comté d'Alameda du NAACP 13 juin 1950, qui a enregistré la 
ségrégation sur les trains Pacifiques méridionaux de chemin de fer 
quittant Los Angeles. Un insecte favorisant le boycott des 
raisins de la Californie exemplifie le soutien de NAACP d'autres 
mouvements de droites, dans ce cas-ci les ouvriers unis de ferme. 
D'autres insectes ont invité des Californiens à combattre des 
salaires de métayer et "gardez le Mississippi hors de la 
Californie." Les groupes tels que le congrès de l'égalité 
raciale (NOYAU) et les groupes d'étudiants ont également protesté 
la ségrégation et les incidents de la discrimination raciale dans 
les Sud. Plusieurs amorces américaines africaines 
importantes ? y compris le roi de Martin Luther, le Jr., le 
Malcolm X, le maréchal de Thurgood, et le Ralph Abernathy ? 
tous sont venus à la Californie, comme documenté par des 
photographies incluses ici. Parfois, le prix du combat pour la 
justice sociale était élevé. Deux événements de saisie 
d'images se sont tenus pour les amorces dans le mouvement social de 
justice qui ont été assassinées : la marche 1963 
commémorative à Los Angeles pour le Chef Medgar Evers de droits 
civiques ; et une foule servant un roi de Martin Luther, Jr., 
rassemblement commémoratif en l'honneur de l'amorce de droits 
civiques massacrée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1948, o presidente Harry Truman fêz exame de 
uma etapa adiantada para a reforma das direitas civis emitindo a ordem
executiva 9981, que eliminou o segregation racial nas forças armadas.
Após A Segunda guerra mundial, Americanos Africanos? 
então Negroes ou os "coloreds frequentemente chamados," 
começaram a mobilize de encontro à discriminação. Exijiram 
uma extremidade ao segregation e lutaram-na pela igualdade na 
instrução, na carcaça, e nas oportunidades de emprego. As 
imagens neste tópico mostram que pelos 1960s, seu esforço? 
qual começou no sul segregado? tinha alcançado 
Califórnia. Porque um número de fotografias neste tópico 
mostram, muitos californians mostraram sua sustentação para 
activistas das direitas civis e vítimas da discriminação racial no 
sul prendendo marços, rallies, e demonstrações que incitam a 
igualdade para americanos africanos. Nas crianças brancas de 
uma imagem três na preensão do San Francisco um sinal na 
sustentação das quatro meninas pretas novas matadas no bombardeio 
1963 da 1ã igreja de baptist da rua em Birmingham, Alabama. As 
fotografias mostram também os povos em San Francisco que boycotting 
as lojas de departamento de Kress e de Woolworth, locais da 
discriminação racial no sul. Os originais mostrados aqui 
incluem um insecto que incita o boycott das lojas; e um 
telegrama ocidental da união emitido em 1963, indicando que as 
activistas Roy Wilkins e Medgar Evers das direitas civis eram tentar 
prendido picket Woolworth em Jackson, Mississippi. Duas 
fotografias dos memorials para chefes dos direitos civis slain? 
um março na honra Medgar Evers em 1963, em Los Angeles, e um 
memorial na área da baía do San Francisco para o rei de Martin 
Luther, Jr., em 1968? mostre multidões racial misturadas no 
comparecimento. Mas não todos os californians sympathized com o
movimento das direitas civis. As imagens do hatred e do 
preconceito raciais são refletidas na fotografia de uma mulher 
americana africana que prende uma rocha que seja jogada através de 
uma janela do escritório, e o graffiti de Klu Klux Klan 
pulverizador-pintado em uma HOME. Os vários grupos deram forma 
para lutar no esforço por direitas iguais. A associação 
nacional para o avanço dos povos coloridos (NAACP), dado forma em 
1909, incorporou uma fase nova durante este período, conduzindo ao 
esforço organizado para direitas civis. Um exemplo de como o 
NAACP comunicado sobre eventos é refletido em uma letra da filial do 
condado de Alameda do NAACP junho em 13, 1950, que relatou o 
segregation nos trens pacíficos do sul da estrada de ferro que saem 
de Los Angeles. Um aviador que promove o boycott de uvas de 
Califórnia exemplifies a sustentação de NAACP para outros 
movimentos das direitas, neste caso os trabalhadores de fazenda 
unidos. Outros insectos incitaram californians lutar salários 
do sharecropper e "mantenha Mississippi fora de Califórnia." Os
grupos tais como o congress de grupos raciais da igualdade (NÚCLEO) e
de estudante protestaram também o segregation e os incidents da 
discriminação racial no sul. Diversos líderes americanos 
africanos importantes? including o rei de Martin Luther, o Jr., 
o Malcolm X, o marshall de Thurgood, e o Ralph Abernathy? todos 
vieram a Califórnia, como documentado pelas fotografias incluídas 
aqui. Às vezes, o preço da luta pela justiça social era 
elevado. Dois eventos da captação das imagens prenderam para 
os líderes no movimento social da justiça que assassinated: o 
março 1963 memorial em Los Angeles para chefes dos direitos civis 
Medgar Evers; e uma multidão que atende a um rei de Martin 
Luther, Jr., rally memorial na honra chefes dos direitos civis slain.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1948, il presidente Harry Truman ha preso una 
misura iniziale verso la riforma di diritti civili pubblicando 
l'ordine esecutivo 9981, che ha eliminato la segregazione razziale nei
militari. Dopo La Seconda guerra mondiale, Americani Africani? 
allora Negroes o "i coloreds spesso chiamati," ha cominciato a 
mobilitare contro distinzione. Hanno richiesto un'estremità 
alla segregazione ed hanno combattuto per uguaglianza nella 
formazione, in alloggiamento e nelle possibilità d'impiego. Le 
immagini in questo soggetto indicano che entro gli anni 60, la loro 
lotta? quale ha cominciato nel sud segregato? aveva 
raggiunto la California. Poichè un certo numero di fotografie 
in questo soggetto mostrano, molti californians hanno mostrato il loro
sostegno gli attivisti di diritti civili e le vittime di distinzione
razziale nel sud tramite marzo, raduni e le dimostrazioni della 
tenuta che sollecitano l'uguaglianza per gli Americani africani. 
Nei bambini bianchi di un'immagine tre nella stretta de San 
Francisco un segno a sostegno delle quattro ragazze nere giovani 
uccise nel bombardamento 1963 della chiesa Battista della sedicesima
via a Birmingham, Alabama. Le fotografie egualmente mostrano la 
gente a San Francisco che boicotta grandi magazzini del Woolworth e di
Kress, luoghi di distinzione razziale nel sud. I documenti 
indicati qui includono un'aletta di filatoio che sollecita il 
boicottaggio dei depositi; e un telegramma occidentale del 
sindacato introdotto 1963, dichiarando che gli attivisti Roy 
Wilkins e Medgar Evers di diritti civili erano tentare arrestato di 
steccare Woolworth a Jackson, Mississippi. Due fotografie dei 
memoriali per i capi slain di diritti civili? un 
procedere nel honor Medgar Evers in 1963, a Los Angeles e un memoriale
nella zona della baia de San Francisco per il re del Martin Luther, 
Jr., in 1968? mostri le folle razziale mixed a disposizione. 
Ma non tutti i californians sympathized con il movimento di 
diritti civili. Le immagini di odio e del pregiudizio razziali 
sono riflesse nella fotografia di una tenuta americana africana 
della donna una roccia che era stata gettata attraverso una finestra 
dell'ufficio e graffiti di Klu Klux Klan spruzzo-verniciato su una 
sede. I vari gruppi hanno formato per combattere nella lotta per
i diritti uguali. L'associazione nazionale per l'avanzamento 
della gente colorata (NAACP), formato in 1909, ha fornito una nuova 
fase durante questo periodo, conducente nella lotta organizzata per i 
diritti civili. Un esempio di come il NAACP comunicato circa gli
eventi è riflesso in una lettera dal ramo della contea di Alameda del
NAACP il 13 giugno 1950, che ha segnalato la segregazione sui treni 
pacifici del sud della ferrovia che lasciano Los Angeles. 
Un'aletta di filatoio che promuove il boicottaggio dell'uva 
della California esemplifica il sostegno di NAACP altri movimenti di 
diritti, in questo caso la manodopera agricola unita. Altre 
alette di filatoio hanno invitato i californians a combattere gli 
stipendi dello sharecropper e "mantenga il Mississippi dalla 
California." I gruppi quale il congresso di uguaglianza razziale
(NUCLEO) ed i gruppi di studenti egualmente hanno protestato la 
segregazione e gli avvenimenti di distinzione razziale nel sud. 
Parecchi capi americani africani importanti? 
compreso il re del Martin Luther, il Jr., Malcolm X, il marshall
di Thurgood e Ralph Abernathy? tutti sono venuto alla 
California, come documentato dalle fotografie incluse qui. A 
volte, il prezzo di combattimento per giustizia sociale era elevato. 
Due eventi di bloccaggio di immagini hanno tenuto per i 
capi nel movimento sociale della giustizia che sono stati 
assassinati: il procedere commemorativo 1963 a Los Angeles per 
il capo Medgar Evers di diritti civili; e una folla che 
assiste ad un re del Martin Luther, Jr., raduno commemorativo in onore
del capo slain di diritti civili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1948, ο Πρόεδρος Harry Truman πήρε ένα 
πρόωρο βήμα προς τη μεταρρύθμιση αστικών δικαιωμάτων με την 
έκδοση της εκτελεστικής εντολής 9981, η οποία εξάλειψε το 
φυλετικό διαχωρισμό στους στρατιωτικούς. Μετά από τον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ, αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί; κατόπιν οι 
συχνά αποκαλούμενοι νέγροι ή "coloreds," άρχισαν να 
κινητοποιούν ενάντια στη διάκριση. Απαίτησαν ένα τέλος στο
διαχωρισμό και πάλεψαν για την ισότητα στην εκπαίδευση, την 
κατοικία, και τις ευκαιρίες απασχόλησης. Οι εικόνες σε αυτό
το θέμα δείχνουν αυτό μέχρι τη δεκαετία του '60, η προσπάθειά 
τους; όποιος άρχισε στο διαχωρισμένο νότο; είχε 
φθάσει σε Καλιφόρνια. Όπως διάφορες φωτογραφίες σε αυτό το
θέμα εμφανίζουν, πολλοί Καλιφόρνιοι εμφάνισαν υποστήριξή τους 
για τα ενεργά στελέχη αστικών δικαιωμάτων και τα θύματα της 
φυλετικής διάκρισης στο νότο με την πραγματοποίηση των πορειών, 
των συναθροίσεων, και των επιδείξεων ωθώντας την ισότητα για 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. Σε μια εικόνα τρεις τα λευκά 
παιδιά στη λαβή του Σαν Φρανσίσκο ένα σημάδι υπέρ των τεσσάρων 
νέων μαύρων κοριτσιών σκότωσαν στο βομβαρδισμό του 1963 της 
βαπτιστικής εκκλησίας 16$ων οδών στο Μπέρμιγχαμ, Αλαμπάμα. 
Οι φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν επίσης ανθρώπους στο Σαν 
Φρανσίσκο που μποϊκοτάρουν τα καταστήματα τμημάτων Kress και 
Woolworth, περιοχές της φυλετικής διάκρισης στο νότο. Τα 
έγγραφα που εμφανίζονται εδώ περιλαμβάνουν ένα ιπτάμενο ωθώντας
το μποϊκοτάρισμα των καταστημάτων  και ένα τηλεγράφημα 
Δυτικής Ένωσης που στέλνεται το 1963, δηλώνοντας ότι τα 
ενεργά στελέχη Roy Wilkins και Medgar Evers αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων ήταν συλλήφθείη προσπάθεια να περιφραχθεί 
Woolworth στο Τζάκσον, Μισισιπής. Δύο φωτογραφίες των 
μνημείων για τους σκοτωμένους ηγέτες αστικών δικαιωμάτων; 
ένας Μάρτιος στην τιμή Medgar Evers το 1963, στο Λος
Αντζελες, και ένα μνημείο στην περιοχή κόλπων του Σαν Φρανσίσκο 
για Martin Luther King, νεώτερος, το 1968; 
εμφανίστε racially μικτά πλήθη παρόντα. Αλλά δεν 
συμμερίστηκαν όλοι οι Καλιφόρνιοι τη μετακίνηση αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων. Οι εικόνες της φυλετικών έχθρας και της 
προκατάληψης απεικονίζονται στη φωτογραφία μιας αφρικανικής 
αμερικανικής γυναίκας που κρατά έναν βράχο που είχε ριχτεί 
μέσω ενός παραθύρου γραφείων, και των γκράφιτι Klu 
Klux Klan ψεκασμός-που χρωματίστηκαν σε ένα σπίτι. Οι 
διάφορες ομάδες διαμόρφωσαν για να παλεψουν στην προσπάθεια για τα
ίσα δικαιώματα. Η εθνική ένωση για την πρόοδο των έγχρωμων
ανθρώπων (NAACP), που διαμορφώθηκε το 1909, εισήγαγε μια νέα
φάση κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της περιόδου, που οδηγεί στην 
οργανωμένη προσπάθεια για τα αστικά δικαιώματα. Ένα 
παράδειγμα για το πώς το NAACP που επικοινωνούν για τα γεγονότα
απεικονίζεται σε μια επιστολή από το alameda κλάδο νομών του 
NAACP στις 13 Ιουνίου ..1950, ο οποίος εξέθεσε το 
διαχωρισμό στο νότιο ειρηνικό σιδηρόδρομο εκπαιδεύει να 
αποχωρήσει από το Λος Αντζελες. Ένα ιπτάμενο που προωθεί 
το μποϊκοτάρισμα των σταφυλιών Καλιφόρνιας εξηγεί NAACP την 
υποστήριξη για άλλες μετακινήσεις δικαιωμάτων, σε αυτήν την 
περίπτωση οι ενωμένοι αγρότες. Αλλα ιπτάμενα ώθησαν 
Καλιφόρνιους για να παλεψουν τις αμοιβές επίμορτων καλλιεργητών 
και "να κρατήσουν το Μισισιπή από Καλιφόρνια." Οι ομάδες 
όπως το συνέδριο των φυλετικών ομάδων ισότητας (ΠΥΡΗΝΑΣ) και 
σπουδαστών διαμαρτυρήθηκαν επίσης το διαχωρισμό και τα γεγονότα 
της φυλετικής διάκρισης στο νότο. Διάφοροι σημαντικοί 
αφρικανικοί αμερικανικοί ηγέτες; συμπεριλαμβανομένου 
Martin Luther King, νεώτερος, Malcolm X, Thurgood 
τακτοποιεί, και Ralph Abernathy; όλοι ήρθαν σε 
Καλιφόρνια, όπως τεκμηριώνεται από τις φωτογραφίες 
συμπεριλαμβανόμενες εδώ. Μερικές φορές, η τιμή της πάλης 
για την κοινωνική δικαιοσύνη ήταν υψηλή. Δύο εικόνες 
συλλαμβάνουν τα γεγονότα που διοργανώνονται για τους ηγέτες στην 
κοινωνική μετακίνηση δικαιοσύνης που δολοφονήθηκαν: το 
1963 αναμνηστικός Μάρτιος στο Λος Αντζελες για τον ηγέτη 
Medgar Evers αστικών δικαιωμάτων  και ένα πλήθος που 
παρευρίσκεται σε έναν Martin Luther King, νεώτερος, 
αναμνηστική συνάθροιση στην τιμή του σκοτωμένου ηγέτη αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1948, presidente Harry Truman tomó una medida 
temprana hacia reforma de las derechas civiles publicando la orden 
ejecutiva 9981, que eliminó la segregación racial en los militares. 
¿Después De la Segunda Guerra Mundial, Americanos Africanos? 
entonces Negroes o los "coloreds a menudo llamados," comenzó a 
movilizar contra la discriminación. Exigieron un extremo a la 
segregación y lucharon para la igualdad en la educación, la 
cubierta, y posibilidades de empleo. ¿Las imágenes en este 
asunto muestran que por los años 60, su lucha? ¿cuál comenzó 
en el sur segregado? había alcanzado California. Pues un 
número de fotografías en este asunto muestran, muchos californians 
mostraron su ayuda para los activistas de las derechas civiles y las 
víctimas de la discriminación racial en el sur celebrando las 
marchas, las reuniones, y las demostraciones que impulsaban la 
igualdad para los americanos africanos. En los niños blancos de
una imagen tres en el asimiento de San Francisco una muestra en la 
ayuda de las cuatro muchachas negras jóvenes matadas en el bombardeo 
1963 de la décimosexto iglesia de Bautista de la calle en Birmingham,
Alabama. Las fotografías también muestran a gente en San 
Francisco que boicotea los almacenes grandes de Kress y de Woolworth, 
sitios de la discriminación racial en el sur. Los documentos 
mostrados aquí incluyen un aviador que impulsa el boicoteo de los 
almacenes; y un telegrama occidental de la unión enviado en 
1963, indicando que los activistas Roy Wilkins y Medgar Evers de las 
derechas civiles eran el procurar arrestado cercar con piquete 
Woolworth en Jackson, Mississippi. ¿Dos fotografías de los 
monumentos para los arranques de cinta de las derechas civiles 
matados? ¿un marzo en el honor Medgar Evers en 1963, en Los 
Ángeles, y un monumento en el área de la bahía de San Francisco 
para el rey de Martin Luther, Jr., en 1968? muestre a 
muchedumbres racial mezcladas en la atención. Pero no todos los
californians comprendieron el movimiento de las derechas civiles. 
Las imágenes del odio y del prejudicar raciales se reflejan en 
la fotografía de una mujer americana africana que lleva a cabo una 
roca que había sido lanzada a través de una ventana de la oficina, y
la pintada de Klu Klux Klan aerosol-pintada en un hogar. Los 
varios grupos formaron para luchar en la lucha para las derechas 
iguales. La asociación nacional para el adelanto de la gente 
coloreada (NAACP), formado en 1909, incorporó una nueva fase durante 
este período, conduciendo en la lucha ordenada para las derechas 
civiles. Un ejemplo de cómo el NAACP comunicado sobre 
acontecimientos se refleja en una carta de la ramificación del 
condado de Alameda del NAACP 13 de junio de 1950, que señaló la 
segregación en los trenes pacíficos meridionales del ferrocarril que
salían de Los Ángeles. Un aviador que promueve el boicoteo de 
las uvas de California ejemplifica la ayuda de NAACP para otros 
movimientos de las derechas, en este caso los trabajadores de granja 
unidos. Otros aviadores impulsaron a californians luchar 
salarios del sharecropper y "guarde Mississippi fuera de California." 
Los grupos tales como el congreso de los grupos raciales de la 
igualdad (BASE) y de estudiante también protestaron la segregación e
incidentes de la discriminación racial en el sur. ¿Varios 
arranques de cinta americanos africanos importantes? ¿incluyendo
el rey de Martin Luther, el Jr., Malcolm X, el ordenar de Thurgood, y 
Ralph Abernathy? todos vinieron a California, según lo 
documentado por las fotografías incluidas aquí. A veces, el 
precio de luchar para la justicia social era alto. Dos 
acontecimientos de la captura de las imágenes sostuvieron para los 
arranques de cinta en el movimiento social de la justicia que fueron 
asesinados: el marzo conmemorativo 1963 en Los Ángeles para el 
arranque de cinta de las derechas civiles Medgar Evers; y una 
muchedumbre que atiende a un rey de Martin Luther, Jr., reunión 
conmemorativa en el honor del arranque de cinta de las derechas 
civiles matado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085257</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106796</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-civil-rights-movement</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
