<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104803</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104803</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087059</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The  Sun  Recalls a Garment Striker's Fate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Sonne erinnert an das Schicksal eines 
Kleid-Schlaggeräts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le soleil rappelle le destin d'une butée de 
vêtement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O sol recorda o fate de um grevista do garment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il sole ricorda il destino del percussore 
dell'indumento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ήλιος υπενθυμίζει τη μοίρα ενός ενδυμάτων απεργού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El sol recuerda el sino de un huelguista de la 
ropa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1909, the predominantly immigrant and female workers in New York City's garment industry staged a series of job walkouts that led to a massive general strike involving more than 20,000 workers. Fifteen-year-old shirtwaist worker Clara Lemlich, a Jewish immigrant from Russia, emerged as a key organizer and speaker. An unprovoked attack on Lemlich and her fellow female strikers by anti-union thugs was recorded by New York  Sun  correspondent McAlister Coleman. He retold the story years later in his article, "All of Which I Saw," published in the  Progressive  in 1950.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1909 inszenierten die überwiegend einwandernden 
und weiblichen Arbeiter in der Kleidindustrie der New York Stadt eine 
Reihe JobArbeitsniederlegungen, die der zu einen massiven Generalstreik 
führte, der mehr als 20.000 Arbeiter mit einbezieht. 
Fünfzehn-Jahr-alter shirtwaist Arbeiter Clara Lemlich, ein 
jüdischer Immigrant von Rußland, aufgetaucht als 
Schlüsselorganisator und Sprecher. Unprovoked Angriff auf 
Lemlich und ihre Mitweiblichen Schlaggeräte durch Anti-Anschluß 
Schurkeen wurden durch New York Sonne entsprechendes McAlister Coleman
gespeichert. Er holte die Geschichtejahre später in seinem 
Artikel, ", den ich sah," veröffentlicht im Progressisten 1950 
wieder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1909, les ouvriers principalement immigrés et 
féminins dans l'industrie du vêtement de la ville de New York ont 
mis en scène une série de grèves surprises du travail que cela a 
menées à une grève massive faisant participer plus de 20.000 
ouvriers. Quinze-année-vieil ouvrier Clara Lemlich de 
chemisier, un immigré juif de Russie, émergée en tant qu'un 
organisateur et orateur principaux. Unprovoked l'attaque sur 
Lemlich et ses butées femelles de camarade par des gangsters 
d'anti-union ont été enregistrées par le soleil McAlister 
correspondant Coleman de New York. Il a raconté de nouveau les ans
après d'histoire en son article, "que j'ai vu," édité dans le 
progressif en 1950.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1909, os trabalhadores predominantly immigrant 
e fêmeas na indústria do garment da cidade de New York encenaram uma
série de walkouts que do trabalho aquele conduziu a uma batida geral 
maciça que envolve mais de 20.000 trabalhadores. trabalhador 
Quinze-ano-velho Clara Lemlich do shirtwaist, um immigrant jewish de 
Rússia, emersa como um organizer e um altofalante chaves. 
Unprovoked o ataque em Lemlich e seus grevistas fêmeas do 
companheiro por thugs da anti-união foram gravados pelo sol McAlister
correspondente Coleman de New York. Retold os anos da história 
mais tarde em seu artigo, "que eu vi," publicado no progressista em 
1950.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1909, gli operai principalmente immigrati e 
femminili nell'industria dell'indumento della città de New York hanno
organizzato una serie di walkouts che di lavoro quello ha condotto ad 
un colpo generale voluminoso che fa partecipare più di 20.000 operai.
Quindici-anno-vecchio operaio Clara Lemlich di shirtwaist, un 
immigrante ebreo dalla Russia, emersa come un organizzatore ed 
altoparlante chiave. Unprovoked l'attacco a Lemlich ed i suoi 
percussori femminili del collega dai thugs dell'anti-unione sono stati
registrati dal sole McAlister corrispondente Coleman de New York. 
Retold gli anni di storia più successivamente in suo articolo, 
"che ho visto," pubblicato nel progressive in 1950.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1909, οι κυρίως που έχουν μεταναστεύσει και 
θηλυκοί εργαζόμενοι στη βιομηχανία ενδυμάτων της πόλης της Νέας 
Υόρκης οργάνωσαν μια σειρά απεργιών εργασίας που οδήγησε σε μια 
ογκώδη γενική απεργία που περιλαμβάνει περισσότερους από 
20.000 εργαζομένους. Δεκαπέντε-χρονών ο 
εργαζόμενος Κλάρα Lemlich, ένας εβραϊκός μετανάστης μπλουζών
από τη Ρωσία, προέκυψε ως βασικοί διοργανωτής και ομιλητής. 
Η επίθεση σε Lemlich και οι συντροφικοί θηλυκοί απεργοί 
της από τους κακοποιούς αντι-ένωσης καταγράφηκαν από τον ήλιο 
αντίστοιχο McAlister Coleman της Νέας Υόρκης. 
Επανέλαβε τα έτη ιστορίας αργότερα στο άρθρο του, "που 
Εβλέίδα," δημοσιευμένος στον προοδευτικό το 1950.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1909, los trabajadores predominante inmigrantes
y femeninos en industria de la ropa de la ciudad de Nueva York 
efectuaron una serie de huelgas del trabajo que eso condujo a una 
huelga general masiva que implicaba a más de 20.000 trabajadores. 
Quince-año-viejo trabajador Clara Lemlich del shirtwaist, un 
inmigrante judío de Rusia, emergente como un organizador y locutor 
dominantes. Unprovoked ataque contra Lemlich y sus huelguistas 
femeninos del compañero de los gamberros de la contra-unio'n fueron 
registrados por el sol McAlister correspondiente Coleman de Nueva 
York. Él retold los años de la historia más adelante en su 
artículo, "que vi," publicado en el progresista en 1950.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087059</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104803</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-sun-recalls-a-garment-strikers-fate</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
