<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206676</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ancient World Mapping Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alte Welt, die Mitte Abbildet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Monde Antique Traçant Le Centre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mundo Antigo Que Traça O Centro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mondo Antico Che Traccia Centro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχαίο κέντρο παγκόσμιας χαρτογράφησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mundo Antiguo Que asocia El Centro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">promotes cartography, historical geography, and geographical information science within the field of ancient studies. It is developing a community of scholars, teachers, and specialists to collaborate in the updating and expansion of the spatial and historical reference information assembled by the Classical Atlas Project. The Center also offers free digital maps of the ancient world for educational use. For most maps, a blank version suitable for quizzes and customization is provided.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">fördert Cartography, historische Geographie und 
geographische Informationswissenschaft innerhalb auffangene der 
alten Studien. Es entwickelt eine Gemeinschaft von Gelehrtem, 
von Lehrern und von Fachleuten, um in der Aktualisierung und in der 
Expansion der räumlichen und historischen Bezugsinformationen 
zusammenzuarbeiten, die durch das klassische Atlas-Projekt 
zusammengebaut werden. Die Mitte bietet auch freie digitale 
Karten der alten Welt für pädagogischen Gebrauch an. Für die 
meisten Karten wird eine unbelegte Version, die für Quizen verwendbar
sind und Kundenbezogenheit zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">favorise la cartographie, la géographie 
historique, et la science géographique de l'information dans la zone 
des études antiques. Elle développe une communauté des 
disciples, des professeurs, et des spécialistes pour collaborer à la
mise à jour et à l'expansion d'information de référence spatiale 
et historique assemblée par le projet classique d'atlas. Le 
centre offre également les cartes digitales libres du monde antique 
pour l'usage éducatif. Pour la plupart des cartes, une version 
blanc appropriée aux jeux et la personnalisation est donnée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">promove o cartography, a geografia histórica, e a
ciência de informação geográfica dentro do campo de estudos 
antigos. Está desenvolvendo uma comunidade de scholars, de 
professores, e de specialists para collaborate em atualizar e na 
expansão da informação de referência spatial e histórica montada 
pelo projeto classical do atlas. O centro oferece também mapas 
digitais livres do mundo antigo para o uso educacional. Para a 
maioria de mapas, uma versão em branco apropriada para quizzes e o 
customization são fornecidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">promuove la cartografia, la geografia storica e la
scienza dell'informazione geografica all'interno del campo degli studi
antichi. Sta sviluppando una Comunità degli eruditi, degli 
insegnanti e degli esperti per collaborare all'aggiornamento ed 
all'espansione delle informazioni di riferimento spaziali e storiche 
montate dal progetto classico dell'atlante. Il centro egualmente
offre i programmi digitali liberi del mondo antico per uso educativo. 
Per la maggior parte dei programmi, una versione in bianco 
adatta a quiz e l'adattamento è fornita.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προωθεί τη χαρτογραφία, την ιστορική γεωγραφία, και τη
γεωγραφική επιστήμη των πληροφοριών μέσα στο πεδίο των αρχαίων 
μελετών. Αναπτύσσει μια κοινότητα των μελετητών, των 
δασκάλων, και των ειδικών για να συνεργαστεί στην ενημέρωση και 
την επέκταση των χωρικών και ιστορικών πληροφοριών αναφοράς που 
συγκεντρώνονται από το κλασσικό πρόγραμμα ατλάντων. Το 
κέντρο προσφέρει επίσης τους ελεύθερους ψηφιακούς χάρτες του 
αρχαίου κόσμου για την εκπαιδευτική χρήση. Για τους 
περισσότερους χάρτες, μια κενή έκδοση κατάλληλη για τους 
διαγωνισμοους γνώσεων και η προσαρμογή παρέχονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">promueve la cartografía, la geografía 
histórica, y las ciencias de la información geográficas dentro del 
campo de estudios antiguos. Está desarrollando a comunidad de 
eruditos, de profesores, y de especialistas para colaborar en la 
puesta al día y la extensión de la información de referencia 
espacial e histórica ensamblada por el proyecto clásico del atlas. 
El centro también ofrece correspondencias digitales libres del 
mundo antiguo para el uso educativo. Para la mayoría de las 
correspondencias, una versión en blanco conveniente para los 
concursos y el arreglo para requisitos particulares se proporciona.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206676</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102990</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ancient-world-mapping-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
