<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107771</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107771</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087270</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"1500 Doomed":  People's Press  Reports on the Gauley Bridge Disaster</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"1500 verurteilt": Presse-Berichte der Leute
über den Gauley Brücke Unfall</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"1500 condamnés" : États de presse des 
personnes sur le désastre de passerelle de Gauley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"1500 doomed": Relatórios de imprensa do 
pessoa no disastre da ponte de Gauley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"1500 condannati": Notizie stampa della 
gente sul disastro del ponticello di Gauley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"1500 Που καταδικάζονται": Εκθέσεις Τύπου 
ανθρώπων σχετικά με την καταστροφή γεφυρών Gauley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"1500 condenados": Informes de prensa de la 
gente sobre el desastre del puente de Gauley</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The deadly lung disease silicosis is caused when miners, sandblasters, and foundry and tunnel workers inhale fine particles of silica dust--a mineral found in sand, quartz, and granite. In 1935, approximately 1,500 workers--largely African Americans who had come north to find work--were killed by exposure to silica dust while building a tunnel in Gauley Bridge, West Virginia. Ordinarily, silicosis takes a several years to develop, but these West Virginia tunnel workers were falling ill in a matter of months because of exposure to unusually high concentrations of silica dust. The crisis over silicosis suddenly became a national issue, as seen in this article in the radical newspaper  Peoples' Press . In 1936 congressional hearings on the Gauley Bridge disaster, it was revealed that company officials and engineers wore masks to protect themselves when they visited the tunnel, but they failed to provide masks for the tunnelers themselves, even when the workers requested them.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die tödliche Lungenkrankheitsilikose wird 
verursacht, wenn Bergmänner, Sandstrahler und Gießerei- und 
Tunnelarbeiter Feinpartikel des Silikonstaubes -- ein Mineral 
inhalieren, das im Sand, im Quarz und im Granit gefunden wird. 
1935 wurden ungefähr 1.500 Arbeiter -- groß afrikanische 
Amerikaner, die nördlich gekommen waren, Arbeit zu finden -- durch 
Belastung durch Silikonstaub beim Aufbauen eines Tunnels in der Gauley
Brücke, West Virginia beendet. Gewöhnlich dauert Silikose 
einige Jahre, um sich zu entwickeln, aber diese West Virginia 
Tunnelarbeiter waren fallender Kranke in einem Stoff von Monaten wegen
der Aussetzung zu den ungewöhnlich hohen Konzentrationen des 
Silikonstaubes. Die Krise Übersilikose wurde plötzlich eine 
Inlandsemission, wie in diesen Artikel in der radikalen Presse der 
Zeitung Völker gesehen. In 1936 Kongreßhörfähigkeiten auf 
dem Gauley Brücke Unfall, wurde es aufgedeckt, daß Firmabeamte und 
-ingenieure Schablonen trugen, um sich zu schützen, als sie den 
Tunnel besuchten, aber sie konnten Schablonen für die tunnelers zur 
Verfügung stellen selbst nicht, selbst wenn die Arbeiter sie 
anforderten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La silicose mortelle d'affection pulmonaire est 
causée quand les mineurs, les sableuses, et les ouvriers de fonderie 
et de tunnel inhalent les particules fines de la poussière de silice 
-- un minerai trouvé en sable, quartz, et granit. En 1935, 
approximativement 1.500 ouvriers -- les Américains en grande partie 
africains qui étaient venus au nord pour trouver le travail -- ont 
été détruits par exposition à la poussière de silice tout en 
construisant un tunnel dans la passerelle de Gauley, la Virginie 
Occidentale. D'habitude, la silicose prend des plusieurs années
pour se développer, mais ces ouvriers de tunnel de la Virginie 
Occidentale étaient défectuosité en chute dans une question des 
mois en raison d'exposition aux concentrations exceptionnellement 
élevées de la poussière de silice. La silicose finie de crise
est soudainement devenue une issue nationale, comme vu en cet article 
dans la presse des peuples radicaux de journal. Dans 1936 
auditions congressionnelles sur le désastre de passerelle de Gauley, 
on l'a indiqué que les fonctionnaires et les ingénieurs de compagnie
ont porté des masques pour se protéger quand ils ont visité le 
tunnel, mais ils n'ont pas fourni les masques pour les tunnelers 
eux-mêmes, même lorsque les ouvriers les ont demandés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O silicosis mortal da doença de pulmão é 
causado quando os mineiros, os sandblasters, e os trabalhadores do 
foundry e do túnel inhale partículas finas da poeira de silicone -- 
um mineral encontrado na areia, no quartzo, e no granito. Em 
1935, aproximadamente 1.500 trabalhadores -- os americanos pela maior 
parte africanos que tinham vindo para o norte encontrar o trabalho -- 
foram matados pela exposição à poeira de silicone ao construir um 
túnel na ponte de Gauley, Virgínia ocidental. Ordinariamente, 
o silicosis faz exame de diversos anos para tornar-se, mas estes 
trabalhadores do túnel de Virgínia ocidental eram mal de queda em 
uma matéria dos meses por causa da exposição às concentrações 
raramente elevadas da poeira de silicone. O silicosis excedente 
da crise transformou-se de repente uma edição nacional, como visto 
neste artigo na imprensa dos povos radicais do jornal. Em 1936 
hearings congressionais no disastre da ponte de Gauley, revelou-se que
os oficiais e os coordenadores da companhia desgastaram máscaras para
se proteger quando visitaram o túnel, mas não forneceram as 
máscaras para os tunnelers elas mesmas, mesmo quando os trabalhadores
os pediram.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La silicosi mortale di affezione polmonare è 
causata quando i minatori, i sabbiatori e gli operai del traforo e 
della fonderia inalano le particelle fini della polvere di silicone --
un minerale trovato in sabbia, quarzo e granito. In 1935, circa 
1.500 operaio -- Americani in gran parte africani che erano venuto a 
nord trovare il lavoro -- è stato ucciso tramite esposizione alla 
polvere di silicone mentre costruivano un traforo in ponticello di 
Gauley, la Virginia dell'Ovest. Ordinariamente, la silicosi 
occorre i parecchi anni per svilupparsi, ma questi operai del traforo 
della Virginia dell'Ovest erano ill cadente in un aspetto dei mesi a 
causa di esposizione alle concentrazioni insolitamente alte della 
polvere di silicone. La silicosi eccessiva di crisi si è 
transformata in improvvisamente in un'edizione nazionale, come visto 
in questo articolo nella pressa della gente radicale del giornale. 
In 1936 udienze congressuali sul disastro del ponticello di 
Gauley, è stato rivelato che i funzionari e gli assistenti tecnici 
dell'azienda hanno portato le mascherine per proteggersi quando hanno 
visitato il traforo, ma non sono riuscito a fornire le mascherine per 
i tunnelers essi stessi, anche quando gli operai li hanno chiesti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η θανάσιμη πυριτίαση ασθενειών πνευμόνων προκαλείται 
όταν εισπνέουν οι ανθρακωρύχοι, sandblasters, και οι 
εργαζόμενοι χυτηρίων και σηράγγων τα λεπτά μόρια της σκόνης 
πυριτίου -- ένα μετάλλευμα που βρίσκεται στην άμμο, το χαλαζία, 
και το γρανίτη. Το 1935, περίπου 1.500 εργαζόμενοι -- 
κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί που είχαν έρθει 
βόρεια να βρούν την εργασία -- σκοτώθηκαν από την έκθεση στη 
σκόνη πυριτίου χτίζοντας μια σήραγγα Gauley στη γέφυρα, 
δυτική Βιρτζίνια. Συνήθως, η πυριτίαση διαρκεί αρκετά έτη
που αναπτύσσονται, αλλά αυτοί οι εργαζόμενοι σηράγγων της 
δυτικής Βιρτζίνια έπεφταν άρρωστοι σε ένα θέμα μηνών λόγω της 
έκθεσης στις κατ'ασυνήθιστο τρόπο υψηλές συγκεντρώσεις της 
σκόνης πυριτίου. Η κρίση πέρα από την πυριτίαση έγινε 
ξαφνικά ένα εθνικό ζήτημα, όπως βλέπει σε αυτό το 
άρθρο στον Τύπο των ριζικών λαών εφημερίδων. Στις του 
Κογκρέσου ακροάσεις του 1936 στην καταστροφή γεφυρών Gauley,
αποκαλύφθηκε ότι τα στελέχη και οι μηχανικοί επιχείρησης φόρεσαν
τις μάσκες για να προστατευθούν όταν επισκέφτηκαν τη σήραγγα, 
αλλά απέτυχαν να παρέχουν τις μάσκες για τα tunnelers οι 
ίδιοι, ακόμη και όταν τα ζήτησαν οι εργαζόμενοι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Se causa la silicosis mortal de la enfermedad de 
la pulmón cuando los mineros, los sandblasters, y los trabajadores de
la fundición y del túnel inhalan partículas finas del polvo de 
silicona -- un mineral encontrado en arena, cuarzo, y granito. 
En 1935, la exposición al polvo de silicona mataron a 
aproximadamente 1.500 trabajadores -- los americanos en gran parte 
africanos que habían venido al norte encontrar el trabajo -- mientras
que construían un túnel en el puente de Gauley, Virginia Occidental.
Ordinariamente, la silicosis toma varios años para convertirse,
pero estos trabajadores del túnel de Virginia Occidental eran 
enfermedad descendente en una cuestión de meses debido a la 
exposición a las concentraciones inusualmente altas del polvo de 
silicona. La silicosis excesiva de la crisis se convirtió en 
repentinamente una edición nacional, según lo considerado en este 
artículo en la prensa de la gente radical del periódico. En 
1936 audiencias del congreso en el desastre del puente de Gauley, fue 
revelado que los funcionarios y los ingenieros de la compañía 
desgastaron máscaras para protegerse cuando visitaron el túnel, pero
no pudieron proporcionar a las máscaras para los tunnelers ellos 
mismos, incluso cuando los trabajadores los solicitaron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087270</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107771</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/1500-doomed-peoples-press-reports-on-the-gauley-bridge-disaster</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
