<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108567</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108567</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212929</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">University of California's Museum of Paleontology: Geologic Timeline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Universität von Museum Kaliforniens von 
Paläontologie: Geologisches Timeline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Université du musée de la Californie de la 
paléontologie : Chronologie géologique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Universidade do museu de Califórnia do 
paleontology: Timeline Geologic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Università di museo della California di 
paleontologia: Timeline Geologico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πανεπιστήμιο του μουσείου Καλιφόρνιας της 
παλαιοντολογίας: Γεωλογική υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Universidad del museo de California de la 
paleontología: Timeline Geológico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">University of California's Museum of Paleontology has created a hyperlinked Geologic Timeline with all sorts of details about each time unit that may be useful later in the course. Each hyperlink contains a variety of information including stratigraphy, ancient life, localities and tectonics associated with that specific time period. Users can also link to an Introduction to Geology page and a description of the Museum's geology wing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Universität von Museum Kaliforniens von 
Paläontologie hat a hyperlinked geologisches Timeline mit allen 
Sortierungen der Details über jede Zeitmaßeinheit erstellt, die im 
Kurs nützlich später sein kann. Jeder Hypertext-Link enthält 
eine Vielzahl der Informationen einschließlich die Stratigraphie, 
alte Lebensdauer, Stellen und Tectonics, die mit dieser Periode des 
spezifischen Zeitpunktes verbunden sind. Benutzer können mit 
einer Einleitung mit Geologieseite auch binden und einer Beschreibung 
des Geologieflügels des Museums.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'université du musée de la Californie de la 
paléontologie a créé a hyperlinked la Chronologie géologique avec 
tous les tris des détails environ chaque fois que l'unité qui peut 
être utile plus tard dans le cours. Chaque hyperlien contient 
une variété d'information comprenant la stratigraphie, la vie 
antique, les localités et la tectonique liées à cette période 
d'instant spécifique. Les utilisateurs peuvent également 
joindre à une introduction à la page de géologie et à une 
description de l'aile de la géologie du musée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A universidade do museu de Califórnia do 
paleontology criou a hyperlinked Timeline geologic com todas as sortes
dos detalhes aproximadamente cada vez que a unidade que pode ser útil
mais tarde no curso. Cada hyperlink contem uma variedade da 
informação including o stratigraphy, a vida antiga, os localities e 
o tectonics associados com esse período de tempo específico. 
Os usuários podem também ligar a uma introdução à página 
da geologia e a uma descrição da asa da geologia do museu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'università di museo della California della 
paleontologia ha creato la a hyperlinked Timeline geologico con tutti 
gli ordinamenti dei particolari circa ogni volta unità che può 
essere utile più successivamente nel corso. Ogni hyperlink 
contiene una varietà di informazioni compreso stratigraphy, vita 
antica, le località e la tettonica connessi con quel periodo di tempo
specifico. Gli utenti possono anche collegarsi ad 
un'introduzione alla pagina di geologia e ad una descrizione dell'ala 
di geologia del museo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πανεπιστήμιο του μουσείου Καλιφόρνιας της 
παλαιοντολογίας έχει δημιουργήσει το α η γεωλογική υπόδειξη ως 
προς το χρόνο με όλα τα είδη των λεπτομερειών περίπου κάθε φορά
που μονάδα που μπορεί να είναι χρήσιμη αργότερα στη σειρά 
μαθημάτων. Κάθε σύνδεσμος υπερ-κειμένου περιέχει ποικίλες 
πληροφορίες συμπεριλαμβανομένης της στρωματογραφίας, της αρχαίας 
ζωής, των τοποθεσιών και της τεκτονικής που συνδέονται με εκείνο 
το συγκεκριμένο χρονικό διάστημα. Οι χρήστες μπορούν 
επίσης να συνδέσουν με μια εισαγωγή στη σελίδα γεωλογίας και μια 
περιγραφή του φτερού γεωλογίας του μουσείου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La universidad del museo de California de la 
paleontología ha creado a hyperlinked Timeline geológico con todas 
las clases de detalles alrededor cada vez que la unidad que puede ser 
útil más adelante en el curso. Cada hyperlink contiene una 
variedad de información incluyendo el stratigraphy, la vida antigua, 
los lugares y la tectónica asociados a ese período del momento 
específico. Los utilizadores pueden también conectar a una 
introducción a la paginación de la geología y a una descripción 
del ala de la geología del museo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ALLEN COLLINS
FN:ALLEN COLLINS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BRIAN SPEER
FN:BRIAN SPEER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212929</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108567</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/university-of-californias-museum-of-paleontology-geologic-timeline</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
