<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103712</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103712</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205744</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Visionaries: Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanische Visionäre: Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Visionnaires Américains : Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Visionaries Americanos: Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Visionari Americani: Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικοί οραματιστές: Θ*Τχομας Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Visionarios Americanos: Thomas Moran</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features paintings and sketches of the noted American landscape painter. Moran's pencil and watercolor field sketches and paintings captured the grandeur and documented the extraordinary terrain and natural features of the Yellowstone region. His artwork was presented to members of Congress by park proponents and helped inspire Congress to establish the National Park System in 1916.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Anstriche und Skizzen des beachteten 
amerikanischen Landschaftsmalers. Bleistift und watercolor 
Morans fangen Skizzen auf und Anstriche erfaßten die 
Herrlichkeit und dokumentierten das außerordentliche Gelände und die
natürlichen Merkmale der Yellowstone Region. Seine 
Gestaltungsarbeit wurde Bauteilen des Kongresses von den 
Parkantragstellern dargestellt und geholfen, Kongreß anzuspornen, das
Nationalpark-System 1916 herzustellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">peintures de dispositifs et croquis du peintre 
américain remarquable d'horizontal. Les croquis et les 
peintures de gisement du crayon et du watercolor de Moran ont capturé
la splendeur et ont documenté le terrain extraordinaire et les 
dispositifs normaux de la région de Yellowstone. Son 
dessin-modèle a été présenté aux membres du congrès par des 
partisans de parc et aidé pour inspirer le congrès établir le 
système de parc national en 1916.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">pinturas das características e esboços do pintor
americano notável da paisagem. Os esboços e as pinturas do 
campo do lápis e do watercolor de Moran capturaram o grandeur e 
documentaram o terreno extraordinário e as características naturais 
da região de Yellowstone. Sua arte -final foi apresentada aos 
membros do congress por proponents do parque e ajudada inspirar o 
congress estabelecer o sistema do parque nacional em 1916.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">pitture delle caratteristiche ed abbozzi del 
pittore americano celebre di paesaggio. Gli abbozzi e le pitture
del giacimento della matita e di watercolor del Moran hanno bloccato 
il grandeur ed hanno documentato il terreno straordinario e le 
caratteristiche naturali della regione di Yellowstone. La sua 
illustrazione è stata presentata ai membri del congresso dai fautori 
del parco ed è stata contribuita per ispirare il congresso stabilire 
il sistema del parco nazionale in 1916.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">έργα ζωγραφικής χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων και 
σκίτσα του σημειωμένου αμερικανικού ζωγράφου τοπίων. Τα 
σκίτσα και τα έργα ζωγραφικής πεδίων μολυβιών και watercolor 
του Moran συνέλαβαν το μεγαλείο και τεκμηρίωσαν την 
εξαιρετική έκταση και τα φυσικά χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα της 
περιοχής Yellowstone. Το έργο τέχνης του παρουσιάστηκε 
στα μέλη του συνεδρίου από τους υπερασπιστές πάρκων και 
ενισχύθηκε να εμπνεύσει το συνέδριο για να καθιερώσει το εθνικό 
σύστημα πάρκων το 1916.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">pinturas de las características y bosquejos del 
pintor americano conocido del paisaje. Los bosquejos y las 
pinturas del campo del lápiz y del watercolor de Moran capturaron el 
grandeur y documentaron el terreno extraordinario y las 
características naturales de la región de Yellowstone. Sus 
ilustraciones fueron presentadas a los miembros del congreso por los 
autores del parque y ayudadas para inspirar a congreso que establezca 
el sistema del parque nacional en 1916.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205744</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103712</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-visionaries-thomas-moran</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
