<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107734</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107734</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201400</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth's Radiation Budget: Part 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Etat Strahlung Der Masse: Teil 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Budget du Rayonnement de la Terre : Partie 
1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Orçamento Da Radiação Da Terra: Parte 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Preventivo Di Radiazione Della Terra: Parte 
1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προϋπολογισμός γήινης ακτινοβολίας: Μέρος 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presupuesto De la Radiación De la Tierra: 
Parte 1</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity students explore the Earth's radiation budget using Earth radiation Budget Experiment (ERBE) data archived at the IRI/LDEO Climate Data Library. This archive is complete with visualization tools for easy assessment and visualization of large data sets. Students also use photometers and light sources to work through several hands-on activities related to basic radiation concepts. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität erforschen Kursteilnehmer den
Etat Strahlung der Masse mit den Daten des Masse Strahlung 
Etat-Experimentes (ERBE), die an der IRI/LDEO Klima-Daten-Bibliothek 
archiviert werden. Dieses Archiv ist mit 
Sichtbarmachunghilfsmitteln für einfache Einschätzung und 
Sichtbarmachung der großen Dateien komplett. Kursteilnehmer 
verwenden auch Fotometer und Lichtquellen, um durch einige 
Blindeinschub Aktivitäten zu arbeiten, die auf grundlegenden 
Strahlung Konzepten in Verbindung gestanden werden. Auf dieser 
Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen über die 
erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité les étudiants explorent le 
budget du rayonnement de la terre en utilisant des données de 
l'expérience de budget de rayonnement de la terre (ERBE) archivées 
à la bibliothèque de données de climat d'IRI/LDEO. Ces 
archives sont complètes avec des outils de visualisation pour 
l'évaluation et la visualisation faciles de grands Modem. Les 
étudiants emploient également des photomètres et des sources 
lumineuses pour travailler par plusieurs activités à commande 
manuelle liées aux concepts de base de rayonnement. À cette 
page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux 
informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les 
extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade os estudantes exploram o 
orçamento da radiação da terra usando os dados da experiência do 
orçamento da radiação da terra (ERBE) archived na biblioteca dos 
dados do clima de IRI/LDEO. Este arquivo está completo com as 
ferramentas do visualization para a avaliação e o visualization 
fáceis de séries de dados de grandes. Os estudantes usam 
também fotômetros e fontes claras trabalhar com diversas atividades 
hands-on relacionadas aos conceitos básicos da radiação. 
Nesta página do ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a 
informação sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, 
contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de 
ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as referências e os tópicos 
cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività allievi esplorano il 
preventivo di radiazione della terra usando i dati di esperimento del 
preventivo di radiazione della terra (ERBE) archiviati alla libreria 
di dati di clima di IRI/LDEO. Questo archivio è completo con 
gli strumenti di visualizzazione per la valutazione e la 
visualizzazione facili di grandi insiemi di dati. Gli allievi 
egualmente usano i fotometri e le fonti di luce per lavorare con 
parecchie attività hands-on relative ai concetti di base di 
radiazione. A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti 
possono accedere alle informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti 
dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di istruzione, di uso note 
e, i materiali didattici, le idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i 
soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα οι σπουδαστές ερευνούν τον 
προϋπολογισμό γήινης ακτινοβολίας χρησιμοποιώντας τα στοιχεία 
πειράματος προϋπολογισμών γήινης ακτινοβολίας (ERBE) που 
αρχειοθετούνται στη βιβλιοθήκη στοιχείων του κλίματος 
IRI/$l*LDEO. Αυτό το αρχείο είναι πλήρες με τα εργαλεία 
απεικόνισης για την εύκολες αξιολόγηση και την απεικόνιση των 
μεγάλων συνόλων στοιχείων. Οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν 
επίσης τα φωτόμετρα και τις πηγές φωτός για να εργαστούν μέσω 
διάφορων εμπράγματων δραστηριοτήτων σχετικών με τις βασικές 
έννοιες ακτινοβολίας. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι 
χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους 
στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις 
σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις 
ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad los estudiantes exploran el 
presupuesto de la radiación de la tierra usando los datos del 
experimento del presupuesto de la radiación de la tierra (ERBE) 
archivados en la biblioteca de los datos del clima de IRI/LDEO. 
Este archivo es completo con las herramientas de la 
visualización para el gravamen y la visualización fáciles de los 
modems grandes. Los estudiantes también utilizan los 
fotómetros y las fuentes de luz para trabajar con varias actividades 
con manos relacionadas con los conceptos básicos de la radiación. 
En esta paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores 
pueden tener acceso a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del
ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza 
las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las 
referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY EARTH AND ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE FACULTY
FN:COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY EARTH AND ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE FACULTY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201400</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107734</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earths-radiation-budget-part-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
