<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104695</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104695</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212443</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Teaching with Data</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterricht mit Daten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enseignement avec des données</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ensino com dados</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Insegnamento con i dati</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διδασκαλία με τα στοιχεία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Enseñanza con datos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Starting Point module is written to assist geoscience faculty who want to utilize learning processes that use observations, defined in the most general sense, as a fundamental component of student learning. It provides information on what Teaching with Data is, why it is useful, how to make use of it and an annotated list of references and resources about Teaching with Data.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Vorlage geoscience Lehrkörper dieses 
Ausgangspunktmodul wird geschrieben, die die Lernprozesse verwenden 
möchten, die Beobachtungen verwenden, definiert in der allgemeinsten 
Richtung, als grundlegender Bestandteil des Kursteilnehmerlernens. 
Es stellt Informationen auf zur Verfügung, was Unterricht mit 
Daten ist, warum es nützlich ist, wie man sie und eine angemerkte 
Liste von Referenzen und von Betriebsmitteln über das Unterrichten 
mit Daten gebraucht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module de point de départ est écrit au corps 
enseignant de geoscience d'aide qui veulent utiliser les 
apprentissages qui utilisent les observations, définis dans le sens 
le plus général, comme composant fondamental de l'étude 
d'étudiant. Il fournit des informations sur ce qu'est 
l'enseignement avec des données, pourquoi il est utile, comment se 
servir d'elles et d'une liste annotée de références et de 
ressources au sujet de l'enseignement avec des données.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo do ponto começar é escrito à 
faculdade do geoscience da assistência que querem utilizar os 
processos de aprendizagem que usam as observações, definidos no 
sentido o mais geral, como um componente fundamental da aprendizagem 
do estudante. Fornece a informação em o que o ensino com dados
é, porque é útil, como empregar a e uma lista anotada das 
referências e dos recursos sobre ensinar com dados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo del punto di partenza è scritto alla
facoltà di geoscience di aiuto che desiderano utilizzare gli 
apprendimento che usano le osservazioni, definiti nel senso più 
generale, come componente fondamentale di imparare dell'allievo. 
Fornisce le informazioni su che cosa l'insegnamento con i dati 
è, perchè è utile, come usare esso e una lista annotata dei 
riferimenti e delle risorse circa l'istruzione con i dati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα αφετηρίας γράφεται για να βοηθήσει τη 
σχολή geoscience που θέλει να χρησιμοποιήσει τις διαδικασίες 
εκμάθησης που χρησιμοποιούν τις παρατηρήσεις, που ορίζονται υπό 
τη γενικότερη έννοια, ως θεμελιώδες συστατικό της εκμάθησης 
σπουδαστών. Παρέχει τις πληροφορίες σε ποια διδασκαλία με τα
στοιχεία είναι, γιατί είναι χρήσιμος, πώς να χρησιμοποιήσει τον
και έναν σχολιασμένο κατάλογο αναφορών και στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς για τη διδασκαλία με τα στοιχεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo del punto de partida se escribe a la 
facultad del geoscience de la ayuda que desean utilizar los procesos 
de aprendizaje que utilizan las observaciones, definidos en el sentido
más general, como componente fundamental de aprender del estudiante. 
Proporciona a la información en cuáles es la enseñanza con 
datos, porqué es útil, cómo hacer uso la y una lista anotada de 
referencias y de recursos sobre la enseñanza con datos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MACKAY
FN:ROBERT MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212443</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104695</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/teaching-with-data</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
