<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103246</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103246</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087228</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Wheel of Fortune: Frances Willard Discovers the Bicycle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rad des Vermögens: Frances Willard entdeckt 
das Fahrrad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Roue de la fortune : Frances Willard 
découvre la bicyclette</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Roda da fortuna: Frances Willard descobre a 
bicicleta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rotella di fortuna: Frances Willard scopre la
bicicletta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρόδα της τύχης: Θ*Φρανθες Willard Discovers 
το ποδήλατο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rueda de la fortuna: Frances Willard descubre
la bicicleta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Frances Willard (1839-1898), leader of the Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU), was a complex and energetic figure in American feminism and social reform. Willard and the WCTU upheld traditional notions of gender and Victorian ideals of the "true woman," but she was also willing to use these notions as part of a larger demand for female citizenship. Although Willard proclaimed the virtues of traditional domesticity for women, she was not bound by those conventional ideas in her own private life. After an unhappy engagement to Charles Henry Fowler, she never married. For many years, she lived with Anna Gordon, who served as her secretary as well as her aide and confidante. Willard's spirit of personal adventure and liberation led her to take up bicycle riding in her fifties, the last decade of her life. As she described in her enthusiastic book about the experience,  A Wheel within a Wheel; How I Learned to Ride the Bicycle , she viewed the "conquest" of the bicycle as similar to the mastery that women needed to achieve over the "wider world."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frances Willard (1839-1898), Führer des 
christlichen Anschlußes Temperance der Frauen (WCTU), war eine 
komplizierte und energische Abbildung im amerikanischen Feminismus und
in der Sozialverbesserung. Willard und die WCTU unterstützten 
traditionellen Begriffe des Geschlechtes und viktorianisch die Ideale der
"zutreffenden Frau," aber sie willten auch, diese Begriffe als Teil 
einer größeren Nachfrage für weibliche Staatsbürgerschaft zu 
verwenden. Obgleich Willard die Tugenden des traditionellen 
Domesticity für Frauen proklamierte, wurde sie nicht durch jene 
herkömmlichen Ideen in ihrer eigenen privaten Lebensdauer gesprungen.
Nach einer unglücklichen Verpflichtung zum Charles Henry 
Fowler, verband sie nie. Für viele Jahre lebte sie mit Anna 
Gordon, der sowie ihren Adjutanten und Vertrauten diente als ihre 
Sekretärin. Geist Willards des persönlichen Abenteuers und der
Befreiung führte sie, Fahrradreiten in ihren fünfziger Jahren, die 
letzte Dekade ihrer Lebensdauer aufzunehmen. Wie sie in ihrem 
enthusiastischen Buch über die Erfahrung beschrieb, ein Rad innerhalb
eines Rades; Wie ich erlernte, Fahrrad zu fahren, sah sie die 
"Eroberung" des Fahrrades an, wie ähnlich der Beherrschung, die die 
Frauen dieser ist, die benötigt wurden, um Überschuß zu erzielen 
die "breitere Welt."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Frances Willard (1839-1898), amorce de l'union 
chrétienne de la Modération des femmes (WCTU), était une figure 
complexe et énergique dans le féminisme américain et la réforme 
sociale. Willard et les notions traditionnelles confirmées par 
WCTU du genre et les idéaux victoriens "de la femme vraie," mais 
d'elle étaient prêts également pour utiliser ces notions en tant 
qu'élément d'une plus grande demande pour la citoyenneté femelle. 
Bien que Willard ait proclamé les vertus de la domesticité 
traditionnelle pour des femmes, elle n'a pas été liée par ces 
idées conventionnelles dans sa propre vie privée. Après un 
enclenchement malheureux à Henry Fowler de Charles, elle ne s'est
jamais mariée. Pendant beaucoup d'années, elle a vécu avec 
Anna Gordon, qui a servi de son secrétaire aussi bien que son 
aide et confidant. L'esprit de Willard de l'aventure et de la 
libération personnelles l'a menée à prendre l'équitation de 
bicyclette en quelques ses années '50, la dernière décennie de sa 
vie. Comme elle a décrit en son livre enthousiaste concernant 
l'expérience, une roue dans une roue ; Comment j'ai appris à 
monter la bicyclette, elle a visualisé la "conquête" de la 
bicyclette comme semblable à la maîtrise cette des femmes requises 
pour réaliser l'excédent "le monde plus large."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Frances Willard (1839-1898), líder da união 
christian de Temperance das mulheres (WCTU), era uma figura complexa e
energética no feminismo americano e na reforma social. Willard 
e as noções tradicionais upheld WCTU do gender e os ideals de 
Victorian "da mulher verdadeira," mas da ela estavam querendo também 
usar estas noções como a parte de uma demanda maior para o 
citizenship fêmea. Embora Willard proclamasse os virtues da 
domesticidade tradicional para mulheres, não foi limitada por aquelas
idéias convencionais em sua própria vida confidencial. Após 
um acoplamento infeliz ao Henry Fowler de Charles, nunca casou-se. 
Por muitos anos, viveu com Anna Gordon, que serviu como sua 
secretária as.well.as seus aide e confidante. O espírito de 
Willard da aventura e do liberation pessoais conduziu-lhe fazer exame 
acima da equitação em seus fifties, a última década da bicicleta 
de sua vida. Como descreveu em seu livro entusiástico sobre a 
experiência, uma roda dentro de uma roda; Como eu aprendi 
montar a bicicleta, viu o "conquest" da bicicleta como similar ao 
mastery esse as mulheres necessitadas conseguir o excesso "o mundo 
mais largo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Frances Willard (1839-1898), capo 
dell'unione cristiana di Temperance delle donne (WCTU), era una figura
complessa ed energica nel feminism americano e nella riforma sociale. 
Willard e le nozioni tradizionali sostenute WCTU del genere e 
gli ideali di Victorian "della donna allineare," ma della lei 
egualmente stavano volendo usare queste nozioni come componente di 
più grande richiesta per la cittadinanza femminile. Anche se 
Willard ha affermato le virtù di domesticity tradizionale per le 
donne, non è stata limitata da quelle idee convenzionali nella sua 
propria vita riservata. Dopo un aggancio infelice al henry 
Fowler del Charles, non si è sposata mai. Per molti anni, ha 
vissuto con Anna Gordon, che ha servito da sua segretaria così come 
il suo aiutante e confidante. Lo spirito del Willard 
dell'avventura e della liberazione personali la ha condotta prendere 
il riding nei suoi anni '50, l'ultima decade della bicicletta della 
sua vita. Come ha descritto in suo libro entusiastico 
sull'esperienza, una rotella all'interno di una rotella; Come ho
imparato guidare la bicicletta, ha osservato "la conquista" della 
bicicletta come simile alla padronanza quella donne state necessarie 
per realizzare l'eccedenza "il mondo più largo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Frances Willard (1839-1898), ηγέτης της 
χριστιανικής ένωσης μετριοπάθειας των γυναικών (WCTU), ήταν 
ένας σύνθετος και ενεργητικός αριθμός στον αμερικανικό φεμινισμό
και την κοινωνική μεταρρύθμιση. Το Willard και το WCTU 
υποστήριξαν τις παραδοσιακές έννοιες του γένους και τα βικτοριανά
ιδανικά της "αληθινής γυναίκας," αλλά ήταν επίσης πρόθυμη να 
χρησιμοποιήσει αυτές τις έννοιες ως τμήμα μιας μεγαλύτερης 
ζήτησης για τη θηλυκή υπηκοότητα. Αν και Willard 
πιστοποίησε τις αρετές της παραδοσιακής νοικοκυροσύνης για τις 
γυναίκες, δεν δεσμεύθηκε από εκείνες τις συμβατικές ιδέες στην 
ιδιωτική ζωή της. Μετά από μια δυστυχισμένη δέσμευση σε 
Charles Henry Fowler, δεν πάντρεψε ποτέ. Για πολλά 
έτη, έζησε με Anna Gordon, η οποία εχρησίμευσε ως το 
γραμματέα της καθώς επίσης και ο βοηθός της και confidante. 
Το πνεύμα του Willard της προσωπικών περιπέτειας και της 
απελευθέρωσης την οδήγησε για να λάβει την οδήγηση ποδηλάτων στη 
δεκαετία του '50 της, η τελευταία δεκαετία ζωής της. 
Δεδομένου ότι περιέγραψε στο ενθουσιώδες βιβλίο της για την
εμπειρία, μια ρόδα μέσα σε μια ρόδα  Πώς έμαθα να οδηγώ 
το ποδήλατο, εμφάνισε τη "κατάκτηση" του ποδηλάτου όπως 
παρόμοιος με την κυριότητα που οι γυναίκες έπρεπε να επιτύχουν 
πέρα από το "ευρύτερο κόσμο."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Frances Willard (1839-1898), arranque de cinta de 
la unión cristiana de Temperance de las mujeres (WCTU), era una 
figura compleja y enérgia en feminismo americano y reforma social. 
Willard y las nociones tradicionales mantenidas WCTU del género
y los ideales de Victorian de la "mujer verdadera," pero de la ella 
también querían utilizar estas nociones como parte de una demanda 
más grande para la ciudadanía femenina. Aunque Willard 
proclamó las virtudes de la domesticidad tradicional para las 
mujeres, ella no fue limitada por esas ideas convencionales en su 
propia vida privada. Después de un contrato infeliz al Henrio 
Fowler de Charles, ella nunca casó. Por muchos años, ella 
vivió con Ana Gordon, que sirvió como su secretaria así como su 
ayudante y confidante. El alcohol de Willard de la aventura y de
la liberación personales la condujo a tomar el montar a caballo en 
sus años '50, la década pasada de la bicicleta de su vida. 
Como ella describió en su libro entusiástico acerca de la 
experiencia, una rueda dentro de una rueda; Cómo aprendí 
montar la bicicleta, ella vio la "conquista" de la bicicleta como 
similar a la maestría esa las mujeres necesitadas para alcanzar el 
excedente el "mundo más ancho."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087228</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103246</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/wheel-of-fortune-frances-willard-discovers-the-bicycle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
