<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106733</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106733</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086710</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Our Plantation Is Very Weak": The Experiences of an Indentured Servant in Virginia, 1623</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Unsere Plantage Ist" Sehr Schwach: Die 
Erfahrungen eines Indentured Bediensteten in Virginia, 1623</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Notre Plantation Est Très Faible" : Les 
expériences d'un domestique d'Indentured en Virginie, 1623</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nossa Plantação É Muito Fraca": As 
experiências de um empregado de Indentured em Virgínia, 1623</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Nostra Piantagione È Molto Debole": Le 
esperienze in un servo di Indentured nella Virginia, 1623</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η φυτεία μας είναι πολύ αδύνατη": Η εμπειρία 
ενός υπαλλήλου Indentured στη Βιρτζίνια, 1623</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Nuestra Plantación Es Muy Débil": Las 
experiencias de un criado de Indentured en Virginia, 1623</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Planters in early seventeenth-century Virginia had bountiful amounts of land and a profitable crop in tobacco, but they needed labor to till their fields. They faced resistance from the local Indian people and were unable to enslave them, so they recruited poor English adults as servants. These young men and women signed indentures, or contracts, for four to seven year terms of work in exchange for their passage to North America. Richard Frethorne came to Jamestown colony in 1623 as an indentured servant. In this letter dated March 20, 1623, written just three months after his entry into the colony, he described the death and disease all around him. Two thirds of his fellow shipmates had died since their arrival. Those without capital suffered particularly precarious situations with the lack of supplies and loss of leaders. Frethorne pleaded with his parents to redeem (buy out) his indenture.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pflanzer im frühen Seventeenthjahrhundert 
Virginia hatten freigebige Mengen des Landes und des rentablen 
Getreides im Tabak, aber sie benötigten Arbeit zu, bis ihr 
auffängt. Sie stellten Widerstand von den lokalen 
indischen Leuten gegenüber und waren nicht imstande, sie zu 
versklaven, also zogen sie arme englische Erwachsene als Bedienstete 
ein. Diese jungen Männer und Frauen unterzeichneten errichtete 
Urkunden oder Verträge, für vier bis sieben Jahrbezeichnungen der 
Arbeit gegen ihren Durchgang nach Nordamerika. Richard Frethorne
kam zur Jamestown Kolonie in 1623, während Bediensteten indentured. 
In diesem Zeichen, das März 20, 1623, gerade drei Monate nach 
seinem Eintrag in die Kolonie geschrieben datiert wurde, beschrieb er 
den Tod und die Krankheit ganz um ihn. Zwei an dritter Stelle 
seiner Gefährteshipmates waren seit ihrer Ankunft gestorben. 
Die ohne Kapital erlitten besonders prekäre Situationen mit dem
Mangel an Zubehör und Verlust der Führer. Frethorne plädierte
mit seinen Eltern, um (kaufen Sie heraus), seine errichtete Urkunde 
zurückzukaufen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les planteurs en dix-septième-siècle tôt la 
Virginie ont eu des quantités bienfaisantes de terre et d'une 
collecte profitable dans le tabac, mais ils ont eu besoin du travail 
à jusqu'à leurs zones. Ils ont fait face à la résistance des
indiens locaux et ne pouvaient pas les asservir, ainsi ils ont 
recruté de pauvres adultes anglais comme domestiques. Ces 
jeunes hommes et femmes ont signé des contrat synallagmatique 
bilatéraux, ou des contrats, pour quatre à sept limites d'an de 
travail en échange de leur passage en Amérique du nord. 
Richard Frethorne est venu chez la colonie de Jamestown dans 
1623 pendant qu'indentured l'domestique. Dans cette lettre 
datée 20 mars 1623, écrite juste trois mois après son entrée dans
la colonie, il a décrit la mort et la maladie tout autour de lui. 
Deux tiers de ses compagnons de bord de camarade étaient morts depuis
leur arrivée. Ceux sans capital ont souffert en particulier des
situations périlleuses avec le manque d'approvisionnements et la 
perte d'amorces. Frethorne a parlé en faveur avec ses parents 
pour racheter (rachetez la part) son contrat synallagmatique 
bilatéral.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os plantadores no décimo-século adiantado 
Virgínia tiveram quantidades bountiful de terra e de uma colheita 
profitable no tabaco, mas necessitaram o trabalho até a seus campos. 
Enfrentaram a resistência dos povos indian locais e foram 
incapazes de enslave os, assim que recrutaram adultos ingleses 
deficientes como empregados. Estes homens novos e mulheres 
assinaram indentures, ou contratos, para quatro a sete termos do ano 
do trabalho na troca para sua passagem a America do Norte. 
Richard Frethorne veio à colônia de Jamestown em 1623 enquanto
indentured o empregado. Nesta letra datada março 20, 1623, 
escrita apenas três meses após sua entrada na colônia, descreveu a 
morte e a doença toda em torno dele. Dois em terceiro lugar de 
seus shipmates do companheiro tinham morrido desde sua chegada. 
Aqueles sem capital sofreram particularmente situações 
precarious com a falta das fontes e perda dos líderes. 
Frethorne pleaded com seus pais para redeem (compre para fora) 
seu indenture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le piantatrici nel diciassettesimo-secolo in 
anticipo la Virginia hanno avute importi bountiful di terra e del 
raccolto vantaggioso in tabacco, ma hanno avuto bisogno del 
lavoro lavorare ai loro campi. Hanno affrontato la 
resistenza dalla gente indiana locale e non potevano asservirle, in 
modo da hanno reclutato i poveri adulti inglesi come servi. 
Questi giovani e donne hanno firmato i indentures, o i 
contratti, per quattro - sette termini di anno di lavoro in cambio del
loro passaggio in America del Nord. Richard Frethorne è venuto 
alla colonia di Jamestown in 1623 mentre indentured il servo. In
questa lettera datata 20 marzo 1623, scritta appena tre mesi dopo la 
sua entrata nella colonia, ha descritto la morte e la malattia 
interamente intorno lui. Due terzo dei suoi shipmates del 
collega erano morto dal loro arrivo. Quelli senza capitale hanno
sofferto specialmente le situazioni rischiose con la mancanza di 
rifornimenti e la perdita dei capi. Frethorne ha 
supplicato con i suoi genitori per riacquistare (compri fuori) il suo 
indenture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι καλλιεργητές στον πρόωρο δέκατος-αιώνα Βιρτζίνια 
είχαν τα γενναιόδωρα ποσά εδάφους και μιας κερδοφόρας συγκομιδής
στον καπνό, αλλά χρειάστηκαν την εργασία για να οργώσουν τα 
πεδία τους. Αντιμετώπισαν την αντίσταση από τους τοπικούς 
ινδικούς ανθρώπους και ήταν ανίκανοι να τους υποδουλώσουν, έτσι 
στρατολόγησαν τους φτωχούς αγγλικούς ενηλίκους ως υπαλλήλους. 
Αυτοί οι νεαροί άνδρες και γυναίκες υπέγραψαν τα 
indentures, ή τις συμβάσεις, για τους όρους τεσσάρων έως επτά
ετών της εργασίας σε αντάλλαγμα της μετάβασής τους στη Βόρεια 
Αμερική. Το Richard Frethorne ήρθε στην αποικία 
Jamestown το 1623 δεδομένου ότι ο υπάλληλος. Σε αυτήν 
την επιστολή της 20ης Μαρτίου ..1623, γραπτός ακριβώς τρεις 
μήνες μετά από την είσοδό του μέσα σε την αποικία, περιέγραψε 
το θάνατο και την ασθένεια όλους γύρω από τον. Τα δύο 
τρίτα των συντροφικών συνναυτών του είχαν πεθάνει από την 
άφιξή τους. Εκείνοι χωρίς κεφάλαιο υπέστησαν ιδιαίτερα 
τις επισφαλείς καταστάσεις με την έλλειψη προμηθειών και την 
απώλεια ηγετών. Το Frethorne παρακάλεσε με τους γονείς 
του για να εξαγοράσει (εξαγοράστε) το indenture του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los plantadores en el decimose'ptimo-siglo 
temprano Virginia tenían cantidades generosas de pista y de una 
cosecha provechosa en tabaco, pero necesitaron el trabajo hasta a sus 
campos. Hicieron frente a resistencia de la gente india local y 
no podían esclavizarla, así que reclutaron a adultos ingleses pobres
como criados. Estos hombres jóvenes y mujeres firmaron 
contratos, o contratos, para cuatro a siete términos del año del 
trabajo en el intercambio para su paso a Norteamérica. Richard 
Frethorne vino a la colonia de Jamestown en 1623 mientras que 
indentured a criado. En esta carta anticuada de marcha la 20 de 
1623, escrita apenas tres meses después de su entrada en la colonia, 
él describió la muerte y la enfermedad todo alrededor de él. 
Dos tercero de sus shipmates del compañero habían muerto desde
su llegada. Ésos sin capital sufrieron determinado situaciones 
precarias con la carencia de fuentes y la pérdida de arranques de 
cinta. Frethorne abogó por con sus padres para redimir (compre 
hacia fuera) su contrato.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086710</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106733</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/our-plantation-is-very-weak-the-experiences-of-an-indentured-servant-in-virginia-1623</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
