<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105129</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105129</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201487</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Engineering Career Options</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Technik-Karriere-Optionen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Options de Carrière d'Ingénierie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Opções Da Carreira Da Engenharia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Opzioni Di Carriera Di Ingegneria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προαιρετικές δυνατότητες σταδιοδρομίας εφαρμοσμένης 
μηχανικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Opciones De la Carrera De la Ingeniería</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The profession of engineering is grouped into specialized disciplines that have developed in response to societal needs. No matter what their field, whether one of the "big four" fields of civil, computer, electrical, or mechanical engineering, or a specialty discipline like ocean engineering, all engineers possess a mix of creativity and smarts. They excel in mathematics or science and spatial relations, and they use these talents to synthesize information, solve problems, and innovate. In this collection of images adapted from The American Society for Engineering Education, learn more about the many fields that make up the engineering profession. Grades 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Beruf der Technik wird in fachkundige 
Disziplinen gruppiert, die sich in Erwiderung auf gesellschaftliche 
Notwendigkeiten entwickelt haben. Egal was ihr 
auffangen Sie, ob eins der "grossen vier" von Zivil 
auffängt, besitzen der Computer, elektrisch oder der 
Maschinenbauingenieur oder eine Spezialgebiet Disziplin wie 
Ozeantechnik, alle Ingenieure eine Mischung der Kreativität und der 
smarts. Sie übertreffen in der Mathematik oder Wissenschaft und
räumliche Relationen, und sie verwenden diese Talente synthetisieren 
Informationen, lösen Probleme und erneuern. In dieser 
Ansammlung Bildern paßte sich von der amerikanischen Gesellschaft 
für Technik-Ausbildung, erlernen an, daß mehr über die vielen 
auffängt, die den Technikberuf bilden. Grade 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La profession de l'ingénierie est groupée dans 
les disciplines spécialisées qui se sont développées en réponse 
aux besoins sociaux. N'importe ce que leur zone, si une des 
"grandes quatre" zones de civil, ordinateur, électriques, ou 
ingénieur mécanicien, ou une discipline de spécialité comme 
l'ingénierie d'océan, tous les ingénieurs possèdent un mélange de
la créativité et des smarts. Ils excellent dans les 
mathématiques ou la science et les relations spatiales, et ils 
utilisent ces talents synthétisent l'information, résolvent des 
problèmes, et innovent. Dans cette collection d'images s'est 
adapté de la société américaine pour l'éducation d'ingénierie, 
apprennent plus au sujet des nombreuses zones qui composent la 
profession d'ingénierie. Catégories 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A profissão da engenharia é agrupada nas 
disciplinas especializadas que se tornaram em resposta às 
necessidades societal. Não importa o que seu campo, se um "dos 
quatro" campos grandes de civil, computador, elétricos, ou engenharia
mecânica, ou uma disciplina do specialty como a engenharia do oceano,
todos os coordenadores possui uma mistura da creatividade e dos 
smarts. Excel na matemática ou a ciência e relações spatial,
e usam estes talents synthesize a informação, resolvem problemas, e 
innovate. Nesta coleção das imagens adaptou-se da sociedade 
americana para a instrução da engenharia, aprendem mais sobre muitos
campos que fazem acima a profissão da engenharia. Classes 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La professione di ingegneria è raggruppata nelle 
discipline specializzate che si sono sviluppate in risposta ai bisogni
sociali. Qualunque cosa il loro campo, se uno "dei quattro" 
campi grandi di civile, calcolatore, elettrici, o ingegnere meccanico,
o una disciplina di specialità come ingegneria dell'oceano, tutti gli
assistenti tecnici possiede una miscela di creatività e di smarts. 
Eccellono nella matematica o la scienza e rapporti spaziali ed 
usano questi talenti sintetizzano le informazioni, risolvono i 
problemi ed innovate. In questa accumulazione delle immagini si 
è adattato dalla società americana per formazione di ingegneria, 
imparano più circa i molti campi che compongono la professione di 
ingegneria. Gradi 3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το επάγγελμα της εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής ομαδοποιείται 
στις εξειδικευμένες πειθαρχίες που έχουν αναπτυχθεί σε απάντηση 
στις κοινωνικές ανάγκες. Το του οποίου πεδίο τους, είτε 
ένα από τα "μεγάλα τέσσερα" πεδία αστικού, ο υπολογιστής, η 
ηλεκτρική, είτε μηχανική εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική, είτε μια 
πειθαρχία ειδικότητας όπως την ωκεάνια εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική, 
όλοι οι μηχανικοί κατέχουν ένα μίγμα της δημιουργικότητας και 
smarts. Υπερέχουν στα μαθηματικά ή την επιστήμη και τις 
χωρικές σχέσεις, και χρησιμοποιούν αυτά τα ταλέντα για να 
συνθέσουν τις πληροφορίες, να λύσουν τα προβλήματα, και να 
καινοτομήσουν. Σε αυτήν την συλλογή των εικόνων που 
προσαρμόζονται από την αμερικανική κοινωνία για την εκπαίδευση 
εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής, μάθετε περισσότερων για τα πολλά πεδία 
που αποτελούν το επάγγελμα εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής. Βαθμοί 
3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La profesión de la ingeniería se agrupa en las 
disciplinas especializadas que se han convertido en respuesta a 
necesidades societal. No importa qué su campo, si uno de los 
"cuatro" campos grandes de civil, ordenador, eléctricos, o ingeniero 
industrial, o una disciplina de la especialidad como la ingeniería 
del océano, todos los ingenieros posee una mezcla de la creatividad y
de los smarts. Sobresalen en matemáticas o ciencia y las 
relaciones espaciales, y utilizan estos talentos sintetizan la 
información, solucionan problemas, e innovan. En esta 
colección de imágenes se adaptó de la sociedad americana para la 
educación de la ingeniería, aprenden más sobre los muchos campos 
que hacen para arriba la profesión de la ingeniería. Grados 
3-12.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
FN:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201487</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105129</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/engineering-career-options</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
