<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107588</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107588</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206867</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Historic Charleston's Religious and Community Buildings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Historischen Charlestons fromm und 
Gemeinschaftsgebäude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Charleston historique religieux et bâtiments de 
la Communauté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Charleston historic religioso e edifícios da 
comunidade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Charleston storico religioso e costruzioni della 
Comunità</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θρησκευτικά και κοινοτικά κτήρια του ιστορικού 
Τσάρλεστον</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Charleston histórica religiosa y edificios de la 
comunidad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores Charleston's heritage by examining 42 historic places. More than 300 years of history are covered, including the Walled City of the British colony, the growth of the shipping industry and surrounding plantations, the city's role in the events leading up to the Civil War, the resurgence of the community during the late 19th century, and the establishment of one of the most complete and intact historic districts in the country.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht Erbe Charlestons indem das Überprüfen 
von von 42 historischen Plätzen. Mehr als 300 Jahre Geschichte 
werden, einschließlich die Walled Stadt der britischen Kolonie, des 
Wachstums der Verschiffenindustrie und der umgebenden Plantagen, der 
Rolle der Stadt in den Fällen umfaßt, die bis zum Bürgerkrieg 
führen, des Wiederauflebens der Gemeinschaft während des des späten
19. jahrhunderts Jahrhunderts und der Einrichtung von einem der 
komplettesten und intaktsten historischen Bezirke im Land.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore l'héritage de Charleston en examinant 42 
endroits historiques. Plus de 300 ans d'histoire sont couverts, 
y compris la ville murée de la colonie britannique, de la croissance 
de l'industrie d'expédition et des plantations environnantes, du 
rôle de la ville dans les événements amenant à la guerre civile, 
de la réapparition de la communauté pendant la fin du 19me siècle, 
et de l'établissement d'une des zones historiques les plus complètes
et les plus intactes dans le pays.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora o heritage de Charleston examinando 42 
lugares historic. Mais de 300 anos do history são cobertos, 
including a cidade walled da colônia britânica, do crescimento da 
indústria de transporte e das plantações circunvizinhas, do papel 
da cidade nos eventos que conduzem à guerra civil, do resurgence da 
comunidade durante o 1ø século atrasado, e do estabelecimento de um 
dos distritos historic os mais completos e os mais intatos no país.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora l'eredità de Charleston esaminando 42 
posti storici. Più di 300 anni di storia sono coperti, compreso
la città walled della colonia britannica, dello sviluppo 
dell'industria cantieristica e delle piantagioni circostanti, del 
ruolo della città negli eventi che portano alla guerra civile, della 
risurrezione della Comunità durante il fine del 19esimo secolo e 
dell'istituzione di uno dei distretti storici più completi e più 
intatti nel paese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά την κληρονομιά του Τσάρλεστον με την εξέταση 
42 ιστορικών θέσεων. Περισσότερο από 300 έτη 
ιστορίας καλύπτονται, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της περιτοιχισμένης 
πόλης της βρετανικής αποικίας, της αύξησης της ναυπηγικής 
βηομηχανίας και των περιβαλλουσών φυτειών, του ρόλου της πόλης 
στα γεγονότα που καταλήγουν στον εμφύλιο πόλεμο, της αναβίωσης 
της κοινότητας κατά τη διάρκεια του πρόσφατου 19$ου αιώνα, και 
της καθιέρωσης μια από τις πληρέστερες και άθικτες ιστορικές 
περιοχές στη χώρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora la herencia de Charleston examinando 42 
lugares históricos. Más de 300 años de historia se cubren, 
incluyendo la ciudad emparedada de la colonia británica, del 
crecimiento de la industria de envío y de las plantaciones 
circundantes, del papel de la ciudad en los acontecimientos que 
conducen a la guerra civil, del resurgimiento de la comunidad durante 
la a fines del siglo XIX, y del establecimiento de uno de los 
districtos históricos más completos y más intactos del país.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206867</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107588</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/historic-charlestons-religious-and-community-buildings</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
