<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105630</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105630</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206483</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Back Stairs at Brucemore: Life as Servants in Early 20th Century America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rückseitige Treppe bei Brucemore: Leben als
Bedienstete früh im 20. Jahrhundert Amerika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Escaliers arrières chez Brucemore : La vie 
comme domestiques en début du 20ème siècle Amérique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escadas traseiras em Brucemore: Vida como 
empregados cedo no 20o século América</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scale posteriori a Brucemore: Vita come 
servi nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκάλες υπηρεσιακής χρήσης σε Brucemore: Ζωή 
ως υπαλλήλους στο 20ό νωρίς αιώνα Αμερική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escaleras posteriores en Brucemore: Vida 
como criados en temprano el vigésimo siglo América</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at the role of servants at a 33-acre estate during the early 1900s. The 21-room mansion was built in Cedar Rapids, Iowa, in the 1880s with a separate entrance, dining area, and stairs for servants. Servants cleaned house, supervised children, washed laundry, cooked meals, cared for the garden and farm animals, and maintained carriages and cars. Floor plans, photos, and diary excerpts are included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die Rolle der Bediensteter an einem 
Zustand 33-acre während der frühen 1900s. Die 21-Räume Villa 
wurde in der Zeder Rapids, Iowa, im 1880s mit einem unterschiedlichen 
Eingang aufgebaut und speiste Bereich und Treppe für Bedienstete. 
Bedienstete säuberten Haus, überwachten Kinder, gewaschene 
Wäscherei, die gekochten Mahlzeiten, interessiert für die Garten- 
und Bauernhoftiere und die beibehaltenen Wagen und die Autos. 
Fußbodenpläne, Fotos und Tagebuchexcerpts sind enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards au rôle des domestiques à un domaine 
33-acre pendant les années 1900 tôt. Le manoir de 21-pièces a
été construit dans le cèdre Rapids, Iowa, dans le 1880s avec une 
entrée séparée, dinant la zone, et les escaliers pour des 
domestiques. Les domestiques ont nettoyé la maison, ont dirigé
des enfants, blanchisserie lavée, plats cuisinés, entretenus les 
animaux de jardin et de ferme, et les chariots et les voitures mis à 
jour. Les plans d'étage, les photos, et les extraits d'agenda 
sont inclus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares no papel dos empregados em uma propriedade
33-acre durante os 1900s adiantados. O mansion dos 21-quartos 
foi construído no cedro Rapids, Iowa, no 1880s com uma entrada 
separada, jantando a área, e as escadas para empregados. Os 
empregados limparam a casa, supervisionaram crianças, lavanderia 
lavada, refeições cozinhadas, importadas com os animais do jardim e 
de fazenda, e carros e carros mantidos. As plantas de assoalho, 
as fotos, e os excerpts do diário são incluídos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi al ruolo dei servi ad una proprietà 
33-acre durante i 1900s in anticipo. Il mansion delle 21-stanze 
è stato costruito in cedro Rapids, Iowa, nel 1880s con un'entrata 
separata, pranzando la zona e le scale per i servi. I servi 
hanno pulito la casa, hanno sorvegliato i bambini, lavanderia lavata, 
piatti cucinati, preoccupati per gli animali da fattoria e del 
giardino ed i carrelli e gli automobili effettuati. I programmi 
di pavimento, le foto ed i brani del diario sono inclusi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει το ρόλο των υπαλλήλων σε ένα κτήμα 
33-στρέμματος κατά τη διάρκεια των πρόωρων δεκαετιών του 20ου 
αιώνα. Το μέγαρο 21room χτίστηκε στον κέδρο Rapids, 
Iowa, στο 1880s με μια χωριστή είσοδο, να δειπνήσει μια 
περιοχή, και τα σκαλοπάτια για τους υπαλλήλους. Οι υπάλληλοι
καθάρισαν το σπίτι, επόπτευσαν τα παιδιά, πλυμένο πλυντήριο, 
μαγειρευμένα γεύματα, φρόντισαν για τα ζώα κήπων και 
αγροκτημάτων, και διατήρησαν τις μεταφορές και τα αυτοκίνητα. 
Τα σχέδια ορόφων, οι φωτογραφίες, και τα αποσπάσματα 
ημερολογίων συμπεριλαμβάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en el papel de criados en un estado 
33-acre durante los 1900s tempranos. La mansión de los 
21-cuartos fue construida en el cedro Rapids, Iowa, en el 1880s con 
una entrada separada, cenando área, y las escaleras para los criados.
Los criados limpiaron la casa, supervisaron a niños, lavadero 
lavado, comidas cocinadas, cuidadas para los animales del jardín y 
del campo, y los carros y los coches mantenidos. Los planes de 
suelo, las fotos, y los extractos del diario son incluidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206483</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105630</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/back-stairs-at-brucemore-life-as-servants-in-early-20th-century-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
