<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106182</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106182</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209763</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Storyboard Artwork Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Storyboard Gestaltungsarbeit Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Projet de Dessin-modèle de Storyboard</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Projeto Da Arte -final De Storyboard</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Dell'Illustrazione Di Storyboard</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα έργου τέχνης Storyboard</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Proyecto De las Ilustraciones De Storyboard</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this project, you create educational materials for schools. If you like to draw human figures or if you have Poser or DAZ Studio, you can join. The artwork that you will create in this project turns Tux Paint into a storyboarding program. The artwork is a human figure viewed from many angles. Once you have drawn the artwork, you mask the figures so they can be used as "stamps" in Tux Paint for kids to create storyboards for motion pictures. These special stamps allow Tux Paint to work like a simple version of Storyboard Quick and Storyboard Artist. Hopefully, this project teaches you everything you need to know to create storyboarding stamps for Tux Paint. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Projekt erstellen Sie pädagogische 
Materialien für Schulen. Wenn Sie menschliche Abbildungen 
zeichnen mögen, oder wenn Sie Poser oder DAZ Studio haben, können 
Sie verbinden. Die Gestaltungsarbeit, die Sie in dieser 
Projektumdrehungen Smoking-Farbe in ein storyboarding Programm 
herstellen. Die Gestaltungsarbeit ist eine menschliche 
Abbildung, die von vielen Winkeln angesehen wird. Sobald Sie die
Gestaltungsarbeit gezeichnet haben, verdecken Sie die Abbildungen, 
also können sie benutzt werden, wie in der Smoking-Farbe 
"stempelt", damit Zicklein storyboards für Bewegung Abbildungen 
erstellen. Diese speziellen Stempel lassen Smoking-Farbe wie 
eine einfache Version von Storyboard und von Storyboard Künstler 
schnell arbeiten. Hoffnungsvoll unterrichtet dieses Projekt Sie,
daß alles, das Sie wissen müssen, um storyboarding Stempel für 
Smoking-Farbe zu erstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans ce projet, vous créez les matériaux 
éducatifs pour des écoles. Si vous aimez dessiner les figures 
humaines ou si vous avez la Colle ou le studio de DAZ, vous 
pouvez vous joindre. Le dessin-modèle que vous créerez en 
cette peinture de Tux de tours de projet dans un programme 
storyboarding. Le dessin-modèle est une figure humaine 
visualisée de beaucoup d'angles. Une fois que vous avez 
dessiné le dessin-modèle, vous masquez les figures ainsi elles 
peuvent être utilisées comme "emboutit" en peinture de Tux pour que 
les gosses créent des storyboards pour des films cinématographiques.
Ces timbres spéciaux permettent à la peinture de Tux de 
fonctionner comme une version simple de Storyboard vite et d'artiste 
de Storyboard. Si tout va bien, ce projet vous enseigne que tout
que vous devez savoir pour créer les timbres storyboarding pour la 
peinture de Tux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste projeto, você cría materiais educacionais 
para escolas. Se você gostar de desenhar figuras humanas ou se 
você tiver Poser ou estúdio de DAZ, você pode juntar. A arte 
-final que você criará nesta pintura de Tux das voltas do projeto em
um programa storyboarding. A arte -final é uma figura humana 
vista de muitos ângulos. Uma vez que você desenhou a arte 
-final, você mascara as figuras assim que podem ser usadas como 
"carimba" na pintura de Tux para que os miúdos críem storyboards 
para retratos de movimento. Estes selos especiais permitem que a
pintura de Tux trabalhe como uma versão simples de Storyboard 
rapidamente e de artista de Storyboard. Esperançosamente, este 
projeto ensina-o que tudo que você necessita saber para criar selos 
storyboarding para a pintura de Tux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo progetto, create i materiali educativi 
per le scuole. Se gradite dissipare le figure umane o se avete 
Poser o studio di DAZ, potete unirsi. L'illustrazione che 
creerete in questa vernice di Tux di girate di progetto in un 
programma storyboarding. L'illustrazione è una figura umana 
osservata da molti angoli. Una volta che avete dissipato 
l'illustrazione, mascherate le figure in modo da possono essere usate 
come "timbra" in vernice di Tux affinchè i capretti creino gli 
storyboards per il cinema. Questi bolli speciali permettono che 
la vernice di Tux funzioni come una versione semplice di Storyboard 
rapidamente e dell'artista di Storyboard. Eventualmente, questo 
progetto li insegna che tutto dobbiate sapere per creare i bolli 
storyboarding per la vernice di Tux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το πρόγραμμα, δημιουργείτε τα εκπαιδευτικά 
υλικά για τα σχολεία. Εάν επιθυμείτε να σύρετε τους 
ανθρώπινους αριθμούς ή εάν έχετε το πρόβλημα ή το στούντιο 
DAZ, μπορείτε να ενώσετε. Το έργο τέχνης που θα 
δημιουργήσετε σε αυτό το έργο μετατρέπει το χρώμα Σμόκιν
σε storyboarding πρόγραμμα. Το έργο τέχνης είναι ένας 
ανθρώπινος αριθμός που εμφανίζεται από πολλές γωνίες. 
Μόλις σύρετε το έργο τέχνης, καλύπτετε τους αριθμούς έτσι
μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν ως "γραμματόσημα" στο χρώμα 
Σμόκιν για τα κατσίκια για να δημιουργήσουν τα 
storyboards για τις ταινίες. Αυτά τα ειδικά γραμματόσημα 
επιτρέπουν στο χρώμα Σμόκιν για να λειτουργήσουν όπως μια
απλή έκδοση του καλλιτέχνη Storyboard γρήγορα και 
Storyboard. Ενδεχομένως, αυτό το πρόγραμμα σας διδάσκει 
όλα που πρέπει να ξέρετε για να δημιουργείτε τα storyboarding 
γραμματόσημα για το χρώμα Σμόκιν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este proyecto, usted crea los materiales 
educativos para las escuelas. Si usted tiene gusto de trazar 
figuras humanas o si usted tiene Poser o estudio de DAZ, usted puede 
ensamblar. Las ilustraciones que usted creará en esta pintura 
de Tux de las vueltas del proyecto en un programa storyboarding. 
Las ilustraciones son una figura humana vista de muchos 
ángulos. Una vez que usted haya trazado las ilustraciones, 
usted enmascara las figuras así que pueden ser utilizadas como 
"estampa" en la pintura de Tux para que los cabritos creen los 
storyboards para las películas. Estos sellos especiales 
permiten que la pintura de Tux trabaje como una versión simple de 
Storyboard aprisa y del artista de Storyboard. Esperanzadamente,
este proyecto le enseña que todo que usted necesita saber para crear 
los sellos storyboarding para la pintura de Tux.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209763</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106182</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-storyboard-artwork-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
