<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104744</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104744</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087508</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Continued Employment after the War?": The Women's Bureau Studies Postwar Plans of Women Workers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"setzte Beschäftigung nach dem Krieg?" fort: 
Das Büro der Frauen studiert Nachkriegspläne der 
Frau-Arbeiter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"suite l'emploi après la guerre?" : Le 
bureau des femmes étudie des plans d'après-guerre des ouvrières de 
femmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"continuou o emprego após a guerra?": O 
departamento das mulheres estuda plantas postwar de trabalhadores das 
mulheres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ha continuato l'occupazione dopo la guerra?": 
L'ufficio delle donne studia i programmi dopoguerra degli operai
delle donne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Συνεχής απασχόληση μετά από τον πόλεμο;": Το 
γραφείο των γυναικών μελετά τα μεταπολεμικά σχέδια των 
εργαζομένων γυναικών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"continuó el empleo después de la guerra?": 
La oficina de las mujeres estudia planes de la posguerra de los 
trabajadores de las mujeres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War II, the defense industry expanded and American men mobilized for military service. Many women found jobs previously unavailable to them in aircraft plants, shipyards, manufacturing companies, and the chemical, rubber, and metals factories producing war materials. These jobs paid higher salaries than those traditionally categorized as "women's work," such as teaching, domestic service, clerical work, nursing, and library science. Married women were discouraged from working outside the home during the Depression to lower competition with men for limited jobs. After the U.S. entered the war, though, the Federal government encouraged housewives to join the work force as a patriotic duty. The number of employed women grew from 14 million in 1940 to 19 million in 1945, rising from 26 to 36 percent of the work force. Most industry analysts and government planners expected this situation to be temporary. At the end of the war, the Women's Bureau of the Department of Labor asked women workers about their future work plans. The bulletin excerpted below revealed that most women wanted to keep their present jobs. Immediately after the war, the percentage of women who worked fell as factories converted to peacetime production and refused to rehire women. In the next few years, the service sector expanded and the number of women in the workforce--especially older married women--increased significantly, despite the dominant ideology of woman as homemaker and mother. The types of jobs available to these women, however, were once again limited to those traditionally deemed "women's work."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, der 
Verteidigungindustrie erweitert und der amerikanischen Männer 
mobilisiert für militärischen Service. Viele Frauen gefundene 
Jobs vorher nicht erreichbar zu ihnen in den Flugzeugbetrieben, 
Werfte, Produktionsgesellschaften und die Chemikalie, der Gummi und 
die Metallfabriken, Kriegmaterialien produzierend. Diese Jobs 
zahlten höhere Gehälter als die, die traditionsgemäß als "Arbeit 
der Frauen," wie Unterrichten, inländischer Service, 
Verwaltungsarbeit, Krankenpflege und Bibliothekwissenschaft 
kategorisiert wurden. Verheiratete Frauen wurden vom Arbeiten 
entmutigt, außerhalb des Hauses während des Tiefstands, zum der 
Konkurrenz mit Männern für begrenzte Jobs zu senken. Nachdem 
die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN den Krieg eintrugen, obwohl, die angeregten 
Hausfrauen der Bundesregierung, zum der Arbeit Kraft als patriotische 
Aufgabe zu verbinden. Die Zahl beschäftigten Frauen wuchs von 
14 Million 1940 bis 19 Million 1945, steigende von 26 bis 6 Prozent 
der Arbeit Kraft. Die meisten Industrieanalytiker und die 
Regierung Planer erwarteten diese Situation, um temporär zu sein. 
Am Ende des Krieges, bat das Büro der Frauen des 
Arbeitsministeriums Frauen um um Arbeiter nach ihren zukünftige 
Arbeit Plänen. Die Nachricht excerptiert unter aufgedeckt, daß
die meisten Frauen ihre anwesenden Jobs halten wollten. Sofort 
nach dem Krieg fiel der Prozentsatz der Frauen, die arbeiteten, als 
Fabriken, die in Friedensproduktion umgewandelt wurden und zu den 
rehire Frauen abgelehnt waren. In den nächsten Jahren 
erweiterte der Dienstleistungssektor und die Zahl Frauen in der 
Mannschaft -- besonders ältere verheiratete Frauen -- erheblich 
erhöht, trotz der dominierenden Ideologie der Frau als 
Hauswirtschaftsleiterin und Mutter. Die Typen der Jobs, die für
diese Frauen jedoch vorhanden sind wurden begrenzt noch einmal auf die
Arbeit der traditionsgemäß gemeinten "Frauen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, l'industrie 
de la défense augmentée et les hommes américains mobilisés pour le
service militaire. Beaucoup de travaux trouvés par femmes 
précédemment indisponibles à eux aux usines d'avion, les chantiers 
navals, les compagnies de fabrication, et le produit chimique, le 
caoutchouc, et les usines en métal produisant des matériaux de 
guerre. Ces travaux ont payé des salaires plus élevés que 
ceux traditionnellement classés par catégorie en tant que "travail 
des femmes," comme l'enseignement, le service domestique, le travail 
de bureau, les soins, et la science de bibliothèque. Des femmes
mariées ont été découragées de travailler en dehors de la maison 
pendant la dépression pour abaisser la concurrence avec les hommes 
pour les travaux limités. Après que les ETATS-UNIS aient 
écrit la guerre, bien que, les femmes au foyer encouragées de 
gouvernement fédéral pour joindre la main-d'oeuvre comme devoir 
patriotique. Le nombre de femmes employées s'est développé de
14 millions en 1940 à 19 millions de 1945, de 26 à 36 pour cent de 
montée de la main-d'oeuvre. La plupart des analystes 
industriels et planificateurs de gouvernement se sont attendus à ce 
que cette situation soit provisoire. À la fin de la guerre, le 
bureau des femmes du service du travail a demandé à des femmes des 
ouvriers sur leurs plans de travaux futurs. Le bulletin extrait 
au-dessous d'indiqué que la plupart des femmes ont voulu garder leurs
travaux. Juste après la guerre, le pourcentage des femmes qui 
ont travaillé est tombé comme usines converties en production en 
temps de paix et refusées aux femmes de rehire. En années à 
venir, le secteur de service a augmenté et le nombre de femmes dans 
la main d'oeuvre -- particulièrement des femmes mariées plus âgées
-- accrue sensiblement, en dépit de l'idéologie dominante de la 
femme comme ménagère et mère. Les types de travaux 
disponibles à ces femmes, cependant, ont été limités de nouveau à
ceux travail le "des femmes traditionnellement considérées."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a segunda guerra mundial, a indústria da 
defesa expandida e os homens americanos mobilized para o serviço 
militar. Muitos trabalhos encontrados mulheres previamente 
unavailable a eles em plantas do avião, shipyards, companhias de 
manufacturing, e o produto químico, a borracha, e as fábricas dos 
metais produzindo materiais da guerra. Estes trabalhos pagaram 
uns salários mais elevados do que aqueles categorizados tradicional 
como das "o trabalho mulheres," como ensinar, serviço doméstico, 
trabalho de escritório, cuidados, e ciência da biblioteca. As 
mulheres casadas foram desanimadas de trabalhar fora da HOME durante o
depression para abaixar a competição com os homens para trabalhos 
limitados. Depois que os ESTADOS UNIDOS incorporaram a guerra, 
embora, os housewives incentivados do governo federal para juntar a 
força de trabalho como um dever patriotic. O número de 
mulheres empregadas cresceu de 14 milhões em 1940 a 19 milhões em 
1945,  26 a 36 por cento levantando-se da força de trabalho. A 
maioria analistas de indústria e de planners do governo esperaram 
esta situação ser provisória. No fim da guerra, o 
departamento das mulheres do departamento de trabalho pediu a mulheres
trabalhadores sobre suas plantas de trabalho futuro. O boletim 
excerpted abaixo do revelado que a maioria de mulheres quiseram manter
seus trabalhos atuais. Imediatamente depois da guerra, a 
porcentagem das mulheres que trabalharam caiu como as fábricas 
convertidas à produção pacífica e recusadas às mulheres do 
rehire. Em poucos anos seguintes, o setor de serviço expandiu e
o número das mulheres no workforce -- especial mulheres casadas mais 
velhas -- aumentado significativamente, apesar do ideology dominante 
da mulher como o homemaker e a matriz. Os tipos de trabalhos 
disponíveis a estas mulheres, entretanto, uma vez foram limitados 
outra vez àqueles trabalho das "mulheres tradicional julgadas."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la seconda guerra mondiale, l'industria 
della difesa espansa e gli uomini americani mobilitati per servizio 
militare. Molte donne hanno trovato i lavori precedentemente non
disponibili a loro nelle piante del velivolo, cantieri navali, aziende
di manufacturing ed il prodotto chimico, la gomma e le fabbriche dei 
metalli producendo i materiali di guerra. Questi lavori hanno 
pagato gli più alti stipendi che quelli categorizzati 
tradizionalmente come "lavoro delle donne," quali l'istruzione, il 
servizio domestico, il lavoro d'ufficio, la professione d'infermiera e
la scienza delle biblioteche. Le donne sposate sono state 
scoraggiate dal funzionamento fuori della sede durante la depressione 
per abbassare la concorrenza con gli uomini per i lavori limitati. 
Dopo che gli STATI UNITI entrino nella guerra, benchè, le 
casalinghe consigliate a di governo federale per unire la forza di 
lavoro come dovere patriotic. Il numero di donne impiegate si è
sviluppato da 14 milioni in 1940 - 19 milioni di 1945, 26 - 36 per 
cento aumentanti della forza di lavoro. La maggior parte di 
analista di industria e dei pianificatori di governo hanno invitare 
questa situazione per essere provvisoria. Alla conclusione della
guerra, l'ufficio delle donne del reparto del Lavoro ha chiesto 
a donne agli operai riguardo ai loro programmi dei lavori futuri. 
Il bollettino stralciato sotto rivelatore che la maggior parte 
delle donne hanno desiderato mantenere i loro lavori attuali. 
Subito dopo della guerra, la percentuale delle donne che hanno 
lavorato è caduto come fabbriche convertite in produzione pacifica e 
rifiutate alle donne del rehire. Durante i prossimi anni, il 
settore dei servizi si è espanso ed il numero di donne nella mano 
d'opera -- particolarmente donne sposate più anziane -- aumentata 
significativamente, malgrado l'ideologia dominante della donna come la
casalinga e madre. I tipi di lavori disponibili a queste donne, 
tuttavia, ancora una volta sono stati limitati a quelli lavoro "delle 
donne tradizionalmente ritenute."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, η 
αμυντική βιομηχανία επεκτάθηκε και αμερικανικά άτομα που 
κινητοποιήθηκαν για τη στρατιωτική θητεία. Πολλές γυναίκες 
βρήκαν τις εργασίες προηγουμένως μη διαθέσιμες σε τους στις 
εγκαταστάσεις αεροσκαφών, τα ναυπηγεία, τις κατασκευαστικές 
επιχειρήσεις, και χημικά, τα λαστιχένια, και εργοστάσια μετάλλων 
παράγοντας τα πολεμικά υλικά. Αυτές τις εργασίες που 
πληρώνονται τους υψηλότερους μισθούς από εκείνοι που 
ταξινομούνται παραδοσιακά ως "εργασία των γυναικών," όπως η 
διδασκαλία, η εσωτερική υπηρεσία, η γραφείου εργασία, η 
περιποίηση, και η επιστήμη βιβλιοθηκών. Οι παντρεμένες 
γυναίκες αποθαρρύνθηκαν από την εργασία έξω από το σπίτι κατά 
τη διάρκεια της κατάθλιψης στο χαμηλότερο ανταγωνισμό με τους 
άνδρες για τις περιορισμένες εργασίες. Αφότου εισήγαγαν οι 
ΗΠΑ τον πόλεμο, εν τούτοις, η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση ενθάρρυνε 
τις νοικοκυρές για να προσχωρήσει στο εργατικό δυναμικό ως 
πατριωτικό καθήκον. Ο αριθμός απασχολημένων γυναικών 
αυξήθηκε από 14 εκατομμύρια το 1940 σε 19 εκατομμύρια το 
1945, ανερχόμενος από 26 έως 36 τοις εκατό του εργατικού
δυναμικού. Οι περισσότεροι αναλυτές βιομηχανίας και 
κυβερνητικοί αρμόδιοι για το σχεδιασμό ανέμειναν αυτήν την 
κατάσταση για να είναι προσωρινή. Στο τέλος του πολέμου, το
γραφείο των γυναικών του τμήματος εργασίας ρώτησε τους 
εργαζομένους γυναικών για τα σχέδια μελλοντικής εργασίας τους. 
Το δελτίο κατωτέρω αποκαλυφθείς ότι οι περισσότερες 
γυναίκες θέλησαν να κρατήσουν τις παρούσες εργασίες τους. 
Αμέσως μετά από τον πόλεμο, το ποσοστό των γυναικών που 
εργάστηκαν μειώθηκε ως εργοστάσια που μετατράπηκαν στην εν καιρώ 
ειρήνης παραγωγή και αρνήθηκε στις γυναίκες rehire. Στα 
επόμενα μερικά έτη, ο τομέας των υπηρεσιών επεκτάθηκε και ο 
αριθμός γυναικών στο εργατικό δυναμικό -- ειδικά ηλικιωμένες 
παντρεμένες γυναίκες -- αυξήθηκε σημαντικά, παρά την κυρίαρχη 
ιδεολογία της γυναίκας ως νοικοκύρης και μητέρα. Οι τύποι 
εργασιών διαθέσιμων σε αυτές τις γυναίκες, εντούτοις, 
περιορίστηκαν άλλη μια φορά εργασία εκείνων των στην παραδοσιακά
κριμένη "γυναικών."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, la industria de
la defensa ampliada y los hombres americanos movilizados para el 
servicio militar. Muchos trabajos encontrados mujeres 
previamente inasequibles a ellos en plantas del avión, astilleros, 
compañías de fabricación, y el producto químico, el caucho, y las 
fábricas de los metales produciendo los materiales de la guerra. 
Estos trabajos pagaron sueldos más altos que ésos 
categorizados tradicionalmente como "trabajo de las mujeres," por 
ejemplo la enseñanza, el servicio doméstico, el trabajo de oficina, 
el oficio de enfermera, y la ciencia de la biblioteca. 
Desalentaron a las mujeres casadas del trabajo fuera del hogar 
durante la depresión para bajar la competición con los hombres para 
los trabajos limitados. Después de que los ESTADOS UNIDOS 
incorporaran la guerra, aunque, las amas de casa alentadores del 
gobierno federal para ensamblar la fuerza de trabajo como deber 
patriótico. El número de mujeres empleadas creció a partir de
14 millones en 1940 a 19 millones de 1945, a partir 26 a 36 por ciento
de levantamiento de la fuerza de trabajo. La mayoría de los 
analistas de industria y de los planificadores del gobierno esperaron 
que esta situación fuera temporal. En el final de la guerra, la
oficina de las mujeres del departamento del trabajo pidió a mujeres 
trabajadores acerca de sus planes del trabajo futuro. El 
boletín extractado debajo de revelado que la mayoría de las mujeres 
desearon guardar sus actuales trabajos. Inmediatamente después 
de la guerra, el porcentaje de las mujeres que trabajaron bajó como 
fábricas convertidas a la producción pacífica y rechazadas a las 
mujeres del rehire. En los años próximos, el sector de 
servicio se amplió y el número de las mujeres en la mano de obra -- 
especialmente más viejas mujeres casadas -- creciente 
perceptiblemente, a pesar de la ideología dominante de la mujer como 
casero y madre. Los tipos de trabajos disponibles para estas 
mujeres, sin embargo, fueron limitados de nuevo a ésos trabajo el "de
las mujeres tradicionalmente juzgadas."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087508</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104744</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/continued-employment-after-the-war-the-womens-bureau-studies-postwar-plans-of-women-workers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
