<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104968</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104968</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209905</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Polygon Interior Angles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Polygon-Innere-Winkel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Angles d'Intérieur de Polygone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ângulos Do Interior Do Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Angoli Dell'Interiore Del Poligono</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εσωτερικές γωνίες πολυγώνων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ángulos Del Interior Del Polígono</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate that the interior angles of a polygon always add to a number related only to the number of sides. The applet shows a polygon where the user can drag the vertices to reshape it, alter the number of sides, make it convex or concave, regular or irregular. The applet shows the angle summation in real time, demonstrating that only the number of sides affects the total. The text on the web page gives the formula for the total of the interior angles. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die zeigen, daß die Innenwinkel eines Polygons immer einer 
Zahl hinzufügen, standen nur auf der Zahl Seiten in Verbindung. 
Der applet zeigt einem Polygon, wo der Benutzer die Gipfel 
schleppen kann, um ihn umzugestalten, die Zahl Seiten ändert, sie 
konvex oder konkav bildet, regelmäßig oder unregelmäßig. Der
applet zeigt die Winkelsummierung in der Istzeit und zeigt, daß nur 
die Zahl Seiten die Gesamtmenge beeinflußt. Der Text auf der 
Webseite gibt die Formel für die Gesamtmenge der Innenwinkel. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent que les angles intérieurs d'un polygone ajoutent 
toujours à un nombre ont associé seulement au nombre de côtés. 
L'applet montre à un polygone où l'utilisateur peut traîner 
les sommets pour le restructurer, modifie le nombre de côtés, le 
rend convexe ou concave, régulier ou irrégulier. L'applet 
montre l'addition d'angle en temps réel, démontrant que seulement le
nombre de côtés affecte le total. Le texte sur la page Web 
donne la formule pour le total des angles intérieurs. L'applet 
peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un 
projecteur de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la 
salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrasse que os ângulos interior de um polygon adicionam sempre a
um número relacionaram-se somente ao número dos lados. O 
applet mostra a um polygon onde o usuário pode arrastar os vertices 
para reshape o, altera o número dos lados, o faz convexo ou côncavo,
regular ou irregular. O applet mostra a soma do ângulo no tempo
real, demonstrando que somente o número dos lados afeta o total. 
O texto no Web page dá a fórmula para o total dos ângulos 
interior. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostra che gli angoli interni di un poligono aggiungono sempre ad un
numero si sono riferiti soltanto al numero di lati. Il applet 
mostra ad un poligono dove l'utente può trascinare i vertici per 
rimodellarlo, altera il numero di lati, lo rende convesso o concavo, 
normale o irregolare. Il applet mostra la sommatoria. di angolo 
in tempo reale, dimostrante che soltanto il numero di lati interessa 
il totale. Il testo sul Web page dà la formula per il totale 
degli angoli interni. Il applet può essere ingrandito al 
formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν ότι οι εσωτερικές γωνίες ενός πολυγώνου 
προσθέτουν πάντα σε έναν αριθμό αφορούσαν μόνο τον αριθμό 
πλευρών. Το applet εμφανίζει ένα πολύγωνο όπου ο 
χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει vertices για να το αναδιαμορφώσει, να 
αλλάξει τον αριθμό πλευρών, να το καταστήσει κυρτό ή κοίλο, 
κανονικό ή ανώμαλο. Το applet εμφανίζει άθροισμα γωνίας
στον πραγματικό χρόνο, που καταδεικνύει ότι μόνο ο αριθμός 
πλευρών έχει επιπτώσεις στο σύνολο. Το κείμενο ιστοσελίδας
δίνει τον τύπο για το σύνολο των εσωτερικών γωνιών. Το 
Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη 
χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην 
τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από 
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestra que los ángulos interiores de un polígono agregan siempre 
a un número se relacionaron solamente con el número de caras. 
El applet muestra a polígono donde el utilizador puede 
arrastrar las cimas para restructurarlo, altera el número de caras, 
lo hace convexo o cóncavo, regular o irregular. El applet 
muestra la adición del ángulo en el tiempo real, demostrando que 
solamente el número de caras afecta el total. El texto en el 
Web page da el fórmula para el total de los ángulos interiores. 
El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa 
para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso 
posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra 
vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la 
conexión requerida. Este recurso es un componente del proyecto 
interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la referencia 
abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209905</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104968</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/polygon-interior-angles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
