<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103391</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103391</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201366</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Investigating the Precipitation-Streamflow Relationship</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Nachforschen des Niederschlag-Streamflow Verhältnisses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Investigation du rapport de Précipitation-Streamflow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Investigando o relacionamento da Precipitação-Streamflow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Studio del rapporto della Precipitazione-Streamflow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: Έρευνα 
της σχέσης πτώση- Streamflow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Investigar el lazo de la Precipitacio'n-Streamflow</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This activity prepares you to launch an investigation of the relationship between precipitation and streamflow for a local watershed. It can enrich a study of the water cycle. Following the step-by-step instructions in a case study you will locate, download, format, and finally graph one year of Web-based data for these two variables. The graph highlights the details of this often complex precipitation-streamflow relationship and provides a context for launching a classroom discussion of the balance between surface runoff and infiltration during and after a rain event, soil porosity, soil saturation level, the influence of impervious surfaces in a basin, the impact of slope, wind and air temperature on watershed hydrology, and the influence of high or low vegetation. You should allow at least four 45-minute class sessions if you are planning to use this resource in a school setting.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Aktivität bereitet Sie vor, eine 
Untersuchung des Verhältnisses zwischen Niederschlag und streamflow 
für eine lokale Wasserscheide auszustoßen. Sie kann eine 
Studie der Wasserschleife anreichern. Nach den schrittweiseen 
Anweisungen in einer Fallstudie errichten Sie, downloaden, formatieren
und stellen schließlich ein Jahr Web-gegründete Daten für diese 
zwei Variablen graphisch dar. Das Diagramm markiert die Details 
dieses häufig komplizierten Niederschlag-streamflow Verhältnisses 
und stellt einen Kontext für das Ausstoßen einer 
Klassenzimmerdiskussion über die Balance zwischen Oberflächenabfluß
und Infiltration während und nach eines Regenfalls, Bodenporosität, 
Bodensättigung Stufe, der Einfluß der undurchdringlichen 
Oberflächen in einem Bassin, die Auswirkung der Steigung, Wind- und 
Lufttemperatur auf Wasserscheidehydrologie und der Einfluß der hohen 
oder niedrigen Vegetation zur Verfügung. Sie sollten mindestens
vier Kategorie 45-minute Sitzungen erlauben, wenn Sie planen, dieses 
Hilfsmittel in einer Schuleeinstellung zu benutzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité vous prépare lancer une recherche
sur le rapport entre la précipitation et le streamflow pour une ligne
de partage locale. Elle peut enrichir une étude du cycle de 
l'eau. Après les instructions pas à pas dans une étude de cas
vous plac, téléchargerez, formaterez, et représenterez 
graphiquement finalement un an de données de Web-based pour ces
deux variables. Le graphique met en valeur les détails de ce 
rapport souvent complexe de précipitation-streamflow et fournit un 
contexte pour lancer une discussion de salle de classe de l'équilibre
entre les eaux de surface  et l'infiltration pendant et après un 
événement de pluie, porosité de sol, niveau de saturation de sol, 
l'influence des surfaces imperméables dans un bassin, l'impact de la 
pente, température de l'air de vent et sur l'hydrologie de ligne de 
partage, et l'influence de la végétation élevée ou basse. 
Vous devriez permettre au moins quatre sessions de la classe 
45-minute si vous projetez utiliser cette ressource dans une 
configuration d'école.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade prepara-o para lançar uma 
investigação do relacionamento entre a precipitação e o streamflow
para um watershed local. Pode enriquecer um estudo do ciclo da 
água. Depois das instruções passo a passo em um estudo de 
caso você ficará, download, formatará, e representará graficamente
finalmente um ano de dados Web-baseados para estas duas variáveis. 
O gráfico destaca os detalhes deste relacionamento 
frequentemente complexo da precipitação-streamflow e fornece um 
contexto lançando uma discussão da sala de aula do contrapeso entre 
o runoff de superfície e o infiltration durante e após um evento da 
chuva, porosidade do solo, nível do saturation do solo, a influência
de superfícies impervious em uma bacia, o impacto da inclinação, 
temperatura do vento e de ar no hydrology do watershed, e a 
influência da vegetação elevada ou baixa. Você deve permitir
ao menos quatro sessões da classe 45-minute se você estiver 
planeando usar este recurso em um ajuste da escola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività li prepara per lanciare 
un'indagine sul rapporto fra precipitazione e streamflow per uno 
spartiacque locale. Può arricchire uno studio sul ciclo 
dell'acqua. A seguito delle istruzioni graduali in un'inchiesta 
posizionerete, trasferirete, formatterete ed infine rappresenterete 
graficamente un anno dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti dei dati 
Web-basati per queste due variabili. Il grafico evidenzia i 
particolari di questo rapporto spesso complesso della 
precipitazione-streamflow e fornisce un contesto per il lancio della 
discussione dell'aula sull'equilibrio fra le acque di superficie ed 
infiltrazione durante e dopo l'evento della pioggia, porosità del 
terreno, livello di saturazione del terreno, l'influenza delle 
superfici impermeabili in un bacino, l'effetto del pendio, temperatura
dell'aria e del vento sull'idrologia di spartiacque e l'influenza di 
alta o vegetazione bassa. Dovreste permettere almeno quattro 
sessioni del codice categoria 45-minute se state progettando usare 
questa risorsa in una regolazione della scuola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα σας προετοιμάζει για να προωθήσει
μια έρευνα για τη σχέση μεταξύ της πτώσης και streamflow για 
έναν τοπικό υδροκρίτη. Μπορεί να εμπλουτίσει μια μελέτη 
του κύκλου ύδατος. Μετά από τις βαθμιαίες οδηγίες σε μια 
περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη θα εντοπίσετε, θα μεταφορτώσετε, θα 
σχηματοποιήσετε, και τελικά γραφική παράσταση ένα έτος 
βασισμένων στο WEB στοιχείων για αυτές τις δύο μεταβλητές. 
Η γραφική παράσταση δίνει έμφαση στις λεπτομέρειες αυτής 
της συχνά σύνθετης σχέσης πτώσης -πτώση-στρεαμφλοω και παρέχει 
ένα πλαίσιο για την προώθηση μιας συζήτησης τάξεων της 
ισορροπίας μεταξύ της απορροής επιφάνειας και της διήθησης κατά 
τη διάρκεια και μετά από ένα γεγονός βροχής, το εδαφολογικό 
πορώδες, το επίπεδο εδαφολογικού κορεσμού, την επιρροή των 
αδιαπέραστων επιφανειών σε μια λεκάνη, τον αντίκτυπο της κλίσης, 
τη θερμοκρασία αέρα και αέρα στην υδρολογία υδροκρίτη, και της 
επιρροής της υψηλής ή χαμηλής βλάστησης. Πρέπει να 
επιτρέψετε σε τουλάχιστον τέσσερις 45-μικρές περιόδους 
επικοινωνίας κλάσης εάν προγραμματίζετε να χρησιμοποιήσετε αυτό 
το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς σε μια σχολική τιμή τών παραμέτρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad le prepara para lanzar una 
investigación del lazo entre la precipitación y el streamflow para 
una línea divisoria de las aguas local. Puede enriquecer un 
estudio del ciclo del agua. Después de las instrucciones paso a
paso en un estudio de caso usted establecerá, descargará, 
formatará, y finalmente representará un año gra'ficamente de los 
datos de Web-based para estas dos variables. El gráfico 
destaca los detalles de este lazo a menudo complejo de la 
precipitacio'n-streamflow y proporciona a un contexto para lanzar una 
discusión de la sala de clase del equilibrio entre la salida 
superficial e infiltración durante y después de un acontecimiento de
la lluvia, porosidad del suelo, nivel de la saturación del suelo, la 
influencia de superficies impermeables en un lavabo, el impacto de la 
cuesta, el viento y temperatura del aire en la hidrología de la 
línea divisoria de las aguas, y la influencia de la vegetación alta 
o baja. Usted debe permitir por lo menos cuatro sesiones de la 
clase 45-minute si usted está planeando utilizar este recurso en una 
configuración de la escuela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NICK HADDAD
FN:NICK HADDAD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201366</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103391</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-investigating-the-precipitation-streamflow-relationship</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
