<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107712</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107712</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Module Three: Communication</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Modul Drei: Kommunikation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Module Trois : Transmission</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Módulo Três: Uma comunicação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modulo Tre: Comunicazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενότητα τρία: Επικοινωνία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Módulo Tres: Comunicación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Communication is not a single act but a process involving various elements. The process involves the sending and receiving of messages. Successful living requires effective communication skills. Learners communicate using various elements within the process of communication. In examining communication in life skills it is important that you as the learner focus on the process, methods, barriers, listening skills, conflict resolution and anger management in your day to day interactions with other learners through technology, speech, drama and gestures in your learning environment</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kommunikation ist eine nicht einzelne Tat aber ein
Prozeß, die verschiedene Elemente mit einbeziehen. Der Prozeß 
bezieht das Senden und das Empfangen der Meldungen mit ein. 
Erfolgreiches Leben benötigt wirkungsvolle Kommunikation 
Fähigkeiten. Anfänger stehen mit verschiedenen Elementen 
innerhalb des Prozesses der Kommunikation in Verbindung. In 
überprüfender Kommunikation in den Lebenfähigkeiten ist es daß Sie
da der Anfängerfokus auf dem Prozeß, den Methoden, den Sperren, den 
hörenden Fähigkeiten, der $überschneidungzerlegung und dem 
Zornmanagement in Ihren täglichen Interaktionen mit anderen 
Anfängern durch Technologie, Rede, Drama und Gesten in Ihrer 
erlernenumgebung wichtig</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La transmission n'est pas un acte simple mais un 
processus impliquant de divers éléments. Le processus comporte
l'envoi et la réception des messages. La vie réussie exige des
qualifications pertinentes de transmission. Les étudiants 
communiquent en utilisant de divers éléments dans le processus de 
transmission. Dans la transmission examinante dans des 
qualifications de la vie il est important que vous car le foyer 
d'étudiant sur le processus, les méthodes, les barrières, les 
qualifications d'écoute, la résolution de conflit et la gestion de 
colère dans vos interactions quotidiennes avec d'autres étudiants 
par la technologie, le discours, le drame et les gestes dans votre 
environnement d'étude</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma comunicação é um não único ato mas um 
processo que envolve vários elementos. O processo envolve a 
emissão e a recepção das mensagens. A vida bem sucedida 
requer habilidades eficazes de uma comunicação. Os learners 
comunicam-se usando vários elementos dentro do processo de uma 
comunicação. Em uma comunicação examinando em habilidades da
vida é importante que você porque o foco do learner no processo, nos
métodos, nas barreiras, nas habilidades escutando, na definição do 
conflito e na gerência da raiva em seu dia para interações do dia 
com outros learners com a tecnologia, o discurso, o drama e os gestos 
em seu ambiente de aprendizagem</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La comunicazione è un singolo atto non ma un 
processo che coinvolge i vari elementi. Il processo coinvolge la
trasmissione e la ricezione dei messaggi. La vita riuscita 
richiede le abilità efficaci di comunicazione. I principianti 
comunicano usando i vari elementi all'interno del processo della 
comunicazione. Nella comunicazione esaminante nelle abilità di 
vita è importante che voi poichè il fuoco del principiante sul 
processo, sui metodi, sulle barriere, sulle abilità ascoltanti, sulla
risoluzione di conflitto e sulla gestione di rabbia nelle vostre 
interazioni quotidiane con altri principianti con tecnologia, 
discorso, il dramma ed i gestures nel vostro ambiente imparante</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η επικοινωνία δεν είναι μια Ενιαία Πράξη αλλά μια 
διαδικασία που περιλαμβάνει τα διάφορα στοιχεία. Η 
διαδικασία περιλαμβάνει την αποστολή και τη λήψη των μηνυμάτων. 
Η επιτυχής διαβίωση απαιτεί τις αποτελεσματικές δεξιότητες 
επικοινωνίας. Οι αρχάριοι επικοινωνούν τη χρησιμοποίηση των 
διάφορων στοιχείων μέσα στη διαδικασία της επικοινωνίας. 
Στην εξέταση της επικοινωνίας στις δεξιότητες ζωής είναι 
σημαντικό ότι εσείς ως εστίαση αρχαρίων στη διαδικασία, τις 
μεθόδους, τα εμπόδια, τις δεξιότητες ακούσματος, την επίλυση 
ψυχικών συγκρούσεων και τη διαχείριση θυμού στις καθημερινές 
αλληλεπιδράσεις σας με άλλους αρχαρίους μέσω της τεχνολογίας, της
ομιλίας, του δράματος και των χειρονομιών στο μαθησιακό 
περιβάλλον σας</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La comunicación es una no Acta Única sino un 
proceso que implican varios elementos. El proceso implica enviar
y la recepción de mensajes. La vida acertada requiere 
habilidades eficaces de la comunicación. Los principiantes se 
comunican con varios elementos dentro del proceso de la comunicación.
En la comunicación que examina en habilidades de la vida es 
importante que usted pues el foco del principiante en el proceso, los 
métodos, las barreras, las habilidades que escuchan, la resolución 
del conflicto y la gerencia de la cólera en sus interacciones 
cotidianas con otros principiantes con tecnología, discurso, drama y 
gestos en su ambiente que aprende</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1221201385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107712</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/module-three-communication</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
