<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104091</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104091</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200552</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Atmosphere Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Atmosphäre Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animations de l'Atmosphère</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animations Da Atmosfera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazioni Dell'Atmosfera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωτικότητες ατμόσφαιρας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animaciones De la Atmósfera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Java Applet, QuickTime, and Flash animations that illustrate characteristics and functions of the atmosphere. They show how atmospheric temperature, pressure, and density change with respect to changing altitude, the way different kinds of radiation (x-ray, ultraviolet, visible, and infrared) act in various levels of the atmosphere (troposphere, stratosphere, mesosphere, and thermosphere/ionosphere), how oxygen gas and chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) interact with ultraviolet radiation to create and deplete ozone, and the manner in which radiation is trapped in the atmosphere, causing the greenhouse effect and global warming. The animations can be paused and rewound to stress important points. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Situationsmerkmale Java applet, QuickTime 
und grellen Animationen, die Eigenschaften und Funktionen der 
Atmosphäre veranschaulichen. Sie zeigen, wie atmosphärische 
Temperatur, Druck und Dichteänderung in Bezug auf ändernde Höhe, 
die Methode unterschiedlichen Arten der Strahlung (Röntgenstrahl, 
Ultraviolet, sichtbares und Infrared) in den verschiedenen Stufen der 
Atmosphäre (Troposphäre, Stratosphäre, mesosphere und 
thermosphere/ionosphere) fungieren, wie Sauerstoffgas und 
Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) auf ultraviolette Strahlung einwirken, um 
Ozon herzustellen und zu verbrauchen und der Weise, in der Strahlung 
in der Atmosphäre eingeschlossen wird und den Gewächshauseffekt und 
das globale Wärmen verursacht. Die Animationen können pausiert
werden und gerückspult werden, um wichtige Punkte zu betonen. 
Diese Betriebsmittel sind für Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, in 
den Labors oder in anderen unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces Java applet de dispositifs de site, QuickTime,
et animations instantanées qui illustrent des caractéristiques et 
des fonctions de l'atmosphère. Elles montrent comment la 
température, la pression, et le changement atmosphériques de 
densité en ce qui concerne l'altitude changeante, les différents 
genres de voie de rayonnement (rayon X, ultra-violet, visible, et 
infrarouge) agissent dans divers niveaux de l'atmosphère 
(troposphere, stratosphère, mesosphere, et thermosphere/ionosphère), 
comment le gaz de l'oxygène et les chlorofluorocarbones (CFCs) 
agissent l'un sur l'autre avec le rayonnement ultraviolet pour créer 
et épuiser l'ozone, et de la façon de laquelle le rayonnement est 
emprisonné dans l'atmosphère, entraînant l'effet de serre chaude et
le chauffage global. Les animations peuvent être faites une 
pause et rebobinées pour soumettre à une contrainte les points 
importants. Ces ressources conviennent pour l'usage dans les 
conférences, les laboratoires, ou d'autres activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estes Java applet De características de local, 
QuickTime, e animations flash que ilustram características e 
funções da atmosfera. Mostram como a temperatura, a pressão, 
e a mudança atmosféricas da densidade com respeito à altura em 
mudança, os tipos diferentes da maneira da radiação (raio X, 
ultravioleta, visível, e infrared) agem em vários níveis da 
atmosfera (troposphere, stratosphere, mesosphere, e 
thermosphere/ionosphere), como o gás do oxigênio e os 
chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) interagem com a radiação ultravioleta 
para criar e esgotar o ozônio, e da maneira em que a radiação é 
prendida na atmosfera, causando o efeito da estufa e se aquecer 
global. Os animations podem ser pausados e rebobinado para 
forçar pontos importantes. Estes recursos são apropriados para
o uso nos lectures, nos laboratórios, ou em outras atividades 
ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questi Java applet Delle caratteristiche di luogo,
QuickTime ed animazioni istantanee che illustrano le caratteristiche e
le funzioni dell'atmosfera. Mostrano come la temperatura, la 
pressione ed il cambiamento atmosferici di densità riguardo ad 
altezza cambiante, i generi differenti di modo di radiazione (raggi X,
ultraviolet, visibile ed infrared) si comportano in vari livelli 
dell'atmosfera (troposphere, stratosfera, mesosphere e 
thermosphere/ionosphere), come il gas dell'ossigeno ed i 
chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) si interagiscono con radiazione 
ultravioletta per creare ed esaurire l'ozono e del modo in cui la 
radiazione è bloccata nell'atmosfera, causando l'effetto della serra 
ed il riscaldamento globale. Le animazioni possono essere fatte 
una pausa e riavvolte per sollecitare i punti importanti. Queste
risorse sono adatte ad uso nelle conferenze, in laboratori, o in altre
attività d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει την Ιάβα Applet, 
QuickTime, και ζωτικότητες λάμψης που επεξηγούν τα 
χαρακτηριστικά και τις λειτουργίες της ατμόσφαιρας. 
Επιδεικνύουν πώς ατμοσφαιρικές θερμοκρασία, πίεση, και 
αλλαγή πυκνότητας όσον αφορά το μεταβαλλόμενο ύψος, ο τρόπος 
που τα διαφορετικά είδη ακτινοβολίας (ακτίνα X, υπεριώδης 
ακτίνα, ορατός, και υπέρυθρες ακτίνες) ενεργούν στα διάφορα 
επίπεδα της ατμόσφαιρας (τροπόσφαιρα, στρατόσφαιρα, mesosphere,
και thermosphere/jono'sfajra), πώς το οξυγόνο αέριο και οι 
χλωροφλωροάνθρακες (CFCs) αλληλεπιδρούν με την υπεριώδη 
ακτινοβολία για να δημιουργήσουν και να μειώσουν το όζον, και ο 
τρόπος με τον οποίο η ακτινοβολία είναι παγιδεύω στην 
ατμόσφαιρα, την πρόκληση του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου και την 
παγκόσμια αύξηση της θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του 
θερμοκηπίου. Οι ζωτικότητες μπορούν να σταματηθούν και 
rewound για να τονίζουν τα σημαντικά σημεία. Αυτά τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για τη χρήση στις 
διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Java applet De las características de sitio,
QuickTime, y animaciones de destello que ilustran características y 
las funciones de la atmósfera. Muestran cómo la temperatura, 
la presión, y el cambio atmosféricos de la densidad con respecto a 
altitud que cambia, las diversas clases de la manera de radiación 
(radiografía, ultravioleta, visible, e infrarrojo) actúan en los 
varios niveles de la atmósfera (troposfera, estratosfera, mesosphere,
y thermosphere/ionosphere), cómo el gas y los chlorofluorocarbons 
(CFCs) del oxígeno obran recíprocamente con la radiación 
ultravioleta para crear y para agotar el ozono, y de la manera de la 
cual la radiación se atrapa en la atmósfera, causando el efecto del 
invernadero y calentarse global. Las animaciones se pueden 
detener brevemente y rebobinar para tensionar puntas importantes. 
Estos recursos son convenientes para el uso en conferencias, 
laboratorios, u otras actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200552</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104091</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/atmosphere-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
