<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108797</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108797</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">College Preparatory Physics II</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hochschulvorbereitende Physik II</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Physique Préparatoire II d'Université</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Física Preparatória II Da Faculdade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fisica Preparatoria II Dell'Università</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προπαρασκευαστική φυσική ΙΙ κολλεγίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Física Preparatoria II De la Universidad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to the NROC College Preparatory Physics course. This course is divided into two semesters and is designed to acquaint you with topics in classical and modern physics. The first semester discusses topics in Newtonian mechanics, oscillatory motion, waves and static electricity. The second semester discusses the topics of current electricity, magnetism, electric circuits, sound, fluids and gases, heat, and modern physics. The course emphasizes conceptual understanding of basic physics principles, with some problem solving. There are interactive conceptual and basic problem-solving examples throughout the lessons, as well as interactive lab simulations and in-school labs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zum NROC Hochschulvorbereitenden 
Physikkurs. Dieser Kurs ist in zwei Semester geteilt und ist 
konzipiert, um Sie mit Themen in der klassischen und modernen Physik 
mitzuteilen. Das erste Semester behandelt Themen in den 
newtonischen Mechanikern, in der Schwingungsbewegung, in den Wellen 
und in der statischen Elektrizität. Das zweite Semester 
behandelt die Themen der aktuellen Elektrizität, des Magnetismus, der
elektrischen Stromkreise, des Tones, der Flüssigkeiten und der Gase, 
der Hitze und der modernen Physik. Der Kurs hebt 
Begriffsverständnis der grundlegenden Physikgrundregeln, mit etwas 
Lösen von Problemen hervor. Es gibt interaktive Begriffs- und 
grundlegende problemlösende Beispiele während der Lektionen, sowie 
interaktive Laborsimulationen und Inschule Labors.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue au cours préparatoire de physique 
d'université de NROC. Ce cours est divisé en deux semestres et
est conçu pour vous mettre au courant des sujets dans la physique 
classique et moderne. Le premier semestre discute des sujets 
dans la mécanique newtonienne, le mouvement oscillant, les vagues et 
l'électricité statique. Le deuxième semestre discute les 
sujets de l'électricité actuelle, magnétisme, circuits 
électriques, bruit, fluides et gaz, chaleur, et physique moderne. 
Le cours souligne l'arrangement conceptuel des principes de 
base de physique, avec la résolution des problèmes. Il y a des
exemples de résolution des problèmes conceptuels et de base 
interactifs dans toutes les leçons, comme des simulations 
interactives de laboratoire et des laboratoires de dans-école.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda ao curso preparatório da física da 
faculdade de NROC. Este curso é dividido em dois semesters e 
projetado familiarizá-lo com os tópicos na física classical e 
moderna. O primeiro semester discute tópicos nos mecânicos 
newtonian, no movimento oscilatório, nas ondas e na eletricidade 
estática. O segundo semester discute os tópicos da 
eletricidade atual, o magnetismo, circuitos elétricos, som, líquidos
e gáses, calor, e física moderna. O curso emfatiza a 
compreensão conceptual de princípios básicos da física, com algum 
resolver de problema. Há uns exemplos problem-solving 
conceptuais e básicos interativos durante todo as lições, assim 
como simulações interativas do laboratório e laboratórios da 
em-escola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto al corso preparatorio di fisica 
dell'università di NROC. Questo corso è diviso in due semestri
ed è destinato per informarlo dei soggetti nella fisica classica e 
moderna. Il primo semestre discute i soggetti in meccanici 
newtoniani, nel movimento oscillatorio, in onde e nell'elettricità 
statica. Il secondo semestre discute i soggetti di elettricità 
corrente, magnetismo, circuiti elettrici, suono, liquidi e gas, calore
e la fisica moderna. Il corso dà risalto alla comprensione 
concettuale dei principii fondamentali di fisica, con una certa 
soluzione dei problemi. Ci sono esempi per la risoluzione di 
problemi concettuali e di base interattivi durante le lezioni, come 
pure le simulazioni interattive del laboratorio ed i laboratori della 
in-scuola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στην προπαρασκευαστική σειρά μαθημάτων 
φυσικής κολλεγίου NROC. Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων 
διαιρείται σε δύο εξάμηνα και σχεδιάζεται για να σας εξοικειώσει 
με τα θέματα στην κλασσική και σύγχρονη φυσική. Το πρώτο 
εξάμηνο συζητά τα θέματα στους νευτώνειους μηχανικούς, την 
ταλαντώσεων κίνηση, τα κύματα και τη στατική ηλεκτρική ενέργεια.
Το δεύτερο εξάμηνο συζητά τα θέματα της παρούσας 
ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας, του μαγνητισμού, των ηλεκτρικών κύκλωμα, 
του ήχου, των ρευστών και των αερίων, της θερμότητας, και της 
σύγχρονης φυσικής. Η σειρά μαθημάτων υπογραμμίζει την 
εννοιολογική κατανόηση των βασικών αρχών φυσικής, με κάποια 
επίλυση προβλήματος. Υπάρχουν διαλογικά εννοιολογικά και 
βασικά παραδείγματα επίλυσης προβλήματος σε όλα τα μαθήματα, 
καθώς επίσης και διαλογικές προσομοιώσεις εργαστηρίων 
και-ΣΧΟΛΙΚΑ εργαστήρια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recepción al curso preparatorio de la física de 
la universidad de NROC. Este curso se divide en dos semestres y 
se diseña para conocerle de asuntos en la física clásica y moderna.
El primer semestre discute asuntos en los mecánicos 
neutonianos, el movimiento oscilatorio, ondas y electricidad 
estática. El segundo semestre discute los asuntos de la 
electricidad actual, magnetismo, los circuitos eléctricos, sonido, 
los líquidos y los gases, calor, y física moderna. El curso 
acentúa la comprensión conceptual de los principios básicos de la 
física, con cierto solucionar de problema. Hay ejemplos 
problem-solving conceptuales y básicos interactivos a través de las 
lecciones, tan bien como simulaciones interactivas del laboratorio y 
laboratorios de la en-escuela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
FN:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200950</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108797</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/college-preparatory-physicsii</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
