<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108611</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108611</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973940</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Split Brain Experiment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Aufgeteiltes 
Gehirn-Experiment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Expérience Fendue de 
Cerveau</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Experiência Rachada Do 
Cérebro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Esperimento Spaccato 
Del Cervello</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Διασπασμένο πείραμα 
εγκεφάλου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Experimento Partido 
Del Cerebro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! The brain is made up of two halves, the hemispheres. These hemispheres are united to one another through a system consisting of millions of nerve fibers. Therefore, each hemisphere is continually informed about what is happening in the other. What happens if the connection is broken?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Das Gehirn besteht zwei Hälften, die Hemisphären. Diese 
Hemisphären werden bis eine andere durch ein System vereinigt, das 
aus Millionen Nerv Fasern besteht. Folglich wird jede 
Hemisphäre fortwährend informiert über, was im anderen geschieht. 
Was geschieht, wenn der Anschluß unterbrochen ist?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Le 
cerveau se compose de deux moitiés, les hémisphères. Ces 
hémisphères sont unis à un un autre par des millions se composants 
d'un système de fibres de nerf. Par conséquent, chaque 
hémisphère est continuellement informé au sujet de ce qui se 
produit dans l'autre. Que se produit si la connexion est cassée
?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! O 
cérebro é composto de duas metades, os hemisférios. Estes 
hemisférios são unidos a um outro com os milhões consistindo de um 
sistema de fibras do nervo. Conseqüentemente, cada hemisfério 
é informado continuamente sobre o que está acontecendo no outro. 
Que acontece se a conexão for quebrada?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Il cervello si compone di due 
metà, gli emisferi. Questi emisferi sono uniti ad uno un altro 
con milioni consistenti del sistema di fibre del nervo. Di 
conseguenza, ogni emisfero è informato continuamente circa che cosa 
sta accadendo nell'altro. Che cosa accade se il collegamento è 
rotto?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Ο 
εγκέφαλος αποτελείται από δύο μισά, τα ημισφαίρια. Αυτά 
τα ημισφαίρια είναι ενωμένα στο ένα άλλο μέσω ενός συστήματος 
που αποτελείται από τα εκατομμύρια των ινών νεύρων. 
Επομένως, κάθε ημισφαίριο ενημερώνεται συνεχώς για αυτό 
που συμβαίνει σε άλλο. Αυτό που συμβαίνει εάν η σύνδεση 
είναι σπασμένη;</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! El 
cerebro se compone de dos mitades, los hemisferios. Estos 
hemisferios se unen a uno otro con millones que consisten en de un 
sistema de fibras del nervio. Por lo tanto, cada hemisferio se 
informa continuamente sobre qué está sucediendo en el otro. 
¿Qué sucede si la conexión está quebrada?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973940</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108611</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-split-brain-experiment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
