<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106624</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106624</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101371</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ice Drillers are Hard Core</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eis-Bohrer sind harter Kern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les foreuses de glace sont noyau dur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os perfuradores do gelo são núcleo duro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le perforatrici del ghiaccio sono nucleo duro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα τρυπάνια πάγου είναι σκληρός πυρήνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las taladradoras del hielo son base dura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Deciphering the secrets of past climate hidden in ice cores depends on the technical skills and ingenuity under pressure of drillers from ICDS, the University of Wisconsin-Madison's Ice Coring and Drilling Services. In this video, ICDS staffers Lou, Mike and Jay explain why they enjoy the life of drillers, braving extreme cold in some of the remotest regions of the globe. Mike says drilling requires both science and art, and why he keeps his hand on the cable even when it's minus 20; Lou talks about feeling connected to the equipment in order to keep it running properly, and Jay explains the satisfaction of having fun amidst beautiful scenery, and helping obtain good data for the researchers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Dechiffrieren der Geheimnisse des letzten 
Klimas versteckt in den Eiskernen hängt von den technischen 
Fähigkeiten und vom Scharfsinn unter Druck der Bohrer von ICDS, die 
Universität der Eis-entkernenden und bohrendienstleistungen 
Wisconsin-Madisons ab. In diesem Bildschirm erklären ICDS 
Mitarbeiter Lou, Mike und Eichelhäher, warum sie die 
Lebensdauer der Bohrer genießen und braving extreme Kälte in einigen
der entferntregionen der Kugel. Sagt Mike, daß bohrend 
Wissenschaft und kunst benötigt, und warum er seine Hand auf dem 
Kabel hält, selbst wenn es minus 20 ist; Lou befaßt sich dem 
mit Gefühl, das an die Ausrüstung angeschlossen wird, um sie zu 
halten, richtig zu laufen, und Eichelhäher erklärt die Zufriedenheit
des Habens des Spaßes unter schöner Landschaft, und helfend erhalten
Sie gute Daten für die Forscher.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le déchiffrement des secrets du climat passé 
cachés dans des noyaux de glace dépend des qualifications et de 
l'ingéniosité techniques sous pression des foreuses d'ICDS, 
l'université des services de dénoyautage et de forage de la glace de
Wisconsin-Madis. Dans ce vidéo, les rédacteurs Lou d'ICDS, le 
Mike et le geai expliquent pourquoi ils apprécient la vie des 
foreuses, bravant le froid extrême dans certaines des 
régions les plus à distance du globe. Mike indique que 
forant exige la science et l'art, et pourquoi il garde sa main sur le 
câble même lorsqu'il est sans 20 ; Lou parle du sentiment 
relié au matériel afin de le continuer exécuter correctement, et le
geai explique la satisfaction d'avoir l'amusement parmi le beau 
paysage, et en aidant obtenez les bonnes données pour les chercheurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Decifrar os segredos do clima passado escondidos 
em núcleos do gelo depende das habilidades e do ingenuity técnicos 
sob a pressão dos perfuradores de ICDS, a universidade de serviços 
retirando o núcleo e perfurando do gelo de 
Wisconsin-Wisconsin-Madison. Neste vídeo, os staffers Lou de 
ICDS, o microfone e o jay explicam porque aprecíam a vida dos 
perfuradores, braving o frio extremo em algumas das regiões as mais 
remotas do globo. O microfone diz que perfurando requer  a 
ciência e a arte, e porque mantem sua mão no cabo mesmo quando é 
menos 20; Lou fala sobre o sentimento conectado ao equipamento a
fim mantê-lo funcionar corretamente, e o jay explica a satisfação 
de ter o divertimento entre o cenário bonito, e ajudando obtenha 
dados bons para os investigadores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decifrare i segreti del clima passato nascosti nei
nuclei del ghiaccio dipende dalle abilità e dall'ingegnosità 
tecniche sotto pressione delle perforatrici da ICDS, l'università di 
servizi di detorsolamento e perforanti del ghiaccio 
deWisconsin-Madison. In questo video, i redattori Lou di ICDS, 
il microfono ed il jay spiegano perchè godono la durata delle 
perforatrici, braving il freddo estremo in alcune delle regioni più a
distanza del globo. Il microfono dice che perforando richiede 
sia la scienza che l'arte e perchè mantiene la sua mano sul cavo 
anche quando è meno 20; I colloqui di Lou circa la 
sensibilità hanno collegato all'apparecchiatura per mantenerli 
funzionare correttamente ed il jay spiega la soddisfazione di avere 
divertimento in mezzo di paesaggio bello ed aiutando ottenga i buoni 
dati per i ricercatori.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αποκρυπτογράφηση των μυστικών του προηγούμενου 
κλίματος που κρύβονται στους πυρήνες πάγου εξαρτάται από τις 
τεχνικές δεξιότητες και την ευστροφία διά πίεση των τρυπανιών 
από ICDS, το πανεπιστήμιο των αφαιρώντας τον πυρήνα και 
τρυπώντας με τρυπάνι υπηρεσιών πάγου του Wisconsin-Ma'ntjson. 
Σε αυτό το βίντεο, ICDS οι εργαζόμενοι Lou, Mike και
Jay εξηγούν γιατί απολαμβάνουν τη ζωή των τρυπανιών, poy το
ακραίο κρύο σε μερικές από τις πιό απομακρυσμένες περιοχές της 
σφαίρας. Ο Mike λέει ότι η διάτρηση απαιτεί και την 
επιστήμη και την τέχνη, και γιατί κρατά το χέρι του στο καλώδιο 
ακόμα και όταν είναι μείον 20  Οι συζητήσεις Lou για το 
συναίσθημα που συνδέεται με τον εξοπλισμό προκειμένου να 
κρατηθούν αυτό κατάλληλα, και Jay εξηγούν την ικανοποίηση της 
κατοχής της διασκέδασης στη μέση του όμορφου τοπίου, και της 
βοήθειας να ληφθούν τα καλά στοιχεία για τους ερευνητές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Descifrar los secretos del último clima ocultados
en memorias del hielo depende de las habilidades y de la ingeniosidad 
técnicas bajo presión de las taladradoras de ICDS, la universidad de
los servicios que quitan el corazón y que perforan del hielo de 
Wisconsin-Madison. En este vídeo, los staffers Lou de ICDS, 
Mike y el jay explican porqué gozan de la vida de taladradoras,
braving frío extremo en algunas de las regiones más alejadas del 
globo. Mike dice que perforando requiere ciencia y arte, y
porqué él guarda su mano en el cable incluso cuando está menos 20; 
Lou habla de la sensación conectada con el equipo para 
guardarlo el ejecutarse correctamente, y el jay explica la 
satisfacción del tener diversión en medio del paisaje hermoso, y 
ayudando obtenga los buenos datos para los investigadores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PPZA
FN:PPZA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101371</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106624</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/ice-drillers-are-hard-core</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
