<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105163</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105163</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086074</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Digest Of Jim-Crow Laws Affecting Passengers in Interstate Travel"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Auswahl der Jim-Krähe Gesetze, die Passagiere im
zwischenstaatlichen Spielraum" beeinflussen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"sommaire des lois de Jim-Corneille affectant des 
passagers dans le voyage d'un état à un autre"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"sumário das leis do Jim-Corvo que afetam 
passageiros no curso interstate"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"raccolta di leggi del Jim-Corvo che interessano i
passeggeri nella corsa da uno stato all'altro"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αφομοίωση των νόμων ιημ-κοράκων που έχουν επιπτώσεις
στους επιβάτες στο διακρατικό ταξίδι"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"resumen de los leyes del Jim-Cuervo que afectan a
pasajeros en recorrido de un estado a otro"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The first laws passed in the South to impose statewide segregation in public facilities, instituted in the 1880s and 1890s, applied to railroad car seating. During this period, railway lines spread rapidly from cities to rural communities. In 1896, the U.S. Supreme Court validated these early "Jim Crow" laws when it ruled in  Plessy  v.  Ferguson  that a Louisiana statute requiring "separate but equal" accommodations for white and black railroad passengers did not conflict with the Fourteenth Amendment clause guaranteeing all citizens equal protection of the laws. (Jim Crow, the colloquial term for segregation, referred to a blackface character popular on the minstrel stage.) Jim Crow legislation extended throughout the South to schools, hotels, restaurants, streetcars, buses, theaters, hospitals, parks, courthouses, and even cemeteries. Although the Supreme Court ruled in 1946 that a Virginia statute requiring segregated seating interfered with interstate commerce and was thus invalid, the following Jim Crow travel laws remained in force in 1954. That same year, the Court declared in  Brown  v.  Board of Education  that separate public schools were "inherently unequal" and thus unconstitutional. In 1955, the black community of Montgomery, Alabama, organized a boycott of the city's segregated bus system. In 1956, the Supreme Court ruled Alabama's laws requiring segregated buses unconstitutional. The specific wording of these Jim Crow laws, crafted to maintain the status quo, revealed deep anxieties about race. By allocating to railroad and bus officials "police powers" to enforce segregated seating and in the case of Virginia, power to determine the race of passengers, state legislatures sought to ensure segregation. By exempting certain categories of persons, specifically nurses, servants, and prisoners, the laws also avoided disrupting ways of life that did not threaten tenets of white supremacy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die ersten Gesetze überschritten in den Süden, 
um Nationalabtrennung in den allgemeinen Teildiensten aufzuerlegen, 
eingeleitet im 1880s und im 1890s, angewendet an den 
Eisenbahnautositzplätzen. Während dieser Periode verbritten 
Bahnlinien schnell von den Städte zu den landwirtschaftlichen 
Gemeinschaften. 1896 validierte das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchste 
Gericht diese frühen "Jim Krähe" Gesetze, als es in Plessy V. 
Ferguson anordnete, daß ein benötigendes Louisiana Gesetz "trennen, 
aber" Anpassungen für Weißes entsprechen und schwarze 
Eisenbahnpassagiere nicht mit der vierzehnte Änderung Klausel 
widersprachen, die allem gleichen Schutz der Bürger der Gesetze 
garantiert. (Jim Krähe, die mündliche Bezeichnung für 
Abtrennung, sprach ein blackface Zeichen an, das auf dem 
Minnesängerstadium. populär ist) Jim Krähegesetzgebung dehnte
sich während des Südens auf Schulen, Hotels, Gaststätten, 
streetcars, Busse, Theater, Krankenhäuser, Parks, Gerichte und sogar 
Kirchhöfe aus. Obgleich das Höchste Gericht 1946, daß ein 
Virginia Gesetzbenötigen trennte, Sitzplätze behinderte landesweiten
Handel und war folglich Invalides, die folgende Jim Krähe anordnete, 
Spielraum, dengesetze 1954 in Kraft blieb. Daß das gleiche 
Jahr, das Gericht im braunen v. Brett der Ausbildung erklärte, das 
unterschiedliche allgemeine Schulen und folglich verfassungswidrig "in sich 
selbst ungleich" waren. 1955 organisierte die schwarze 
Gemeinschaft von Montgomery, Alabama, einen Boykott des getrennten 
Bussystems der Stadt. 1956 ordnete das Höchste Gericht die 
Gesetze Alabamas an, welche die getrennten verfassungswidrigen Busse 
benötigen. Der spezifische Wording dieser Jim Krähegesetze, in
Handarbeit gemacht, um den Status Quo beizubehalten, der aufgedeckten 
tiefen Ängste um Rennen. Indem Sie Eisenbahn- und Busbeamten 
"zuordnen, überwachen Sie Energien" polizeilich, getrennte 
Sitzplätze und im Fall von Virginia, Energie zu erzwingen, das Rennen
der Passagiere, die Zustandgesetzgebungen festzustellen, die gesucht 
werden, um Abtrennung sicherzustellen. Indem sie bestimmte 
Kategorien der Personen, spezifisch Krankenschwestern, Bedienstete und
Gefangene befreiten, vermieden die Gesetze auch, Lebensarten zu 
stören, die nicht Lehren der weißen Vorherrschaft 
bedrohten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les premières lois ont passé dans les 
Sud pour imposer la ségrégation par état dans les 
équipements publics, institués dans le 1880s et le 1890s, appliqués
à l'allocation des places de voiture de chemin de fer. Pendant 
cette période, les lignes ferroviaires ont écarté rapidement des 
villes aux communautés rurales. En 1896, la cour suprême des 
ETATS-UNIS a validé ces lois tôt "de corneille de Jim" quand elle a 
régné dans Plessy v. Ferguson qu'un statut de la Louisiane exigeant 
"séparent mais égalent" le logement pour blanc et les passagers 
noirs de chemin de fer n'étaient pas en conflit avec la clause du 
quatorzième amendement garantissant toute la protection égale de 
citoyens des lois. (la corneille de Jim, la limite familière 
pour la ségrégation, s'est rapportée à un caractère de blackface 
populaire sur l'étape de troubadour.) La législation de 
corneille de Jim a étendu dans tous les Sud aux écoles, aux 
hôtels, aux restaurants, aux tramways, aux bus, aux théâtres, 
aux hôpitaux, aux parcs, aux tribunaux, et même aux cimetières. 
Bien que la cour suprême ait régné en 1946 qu'une exigence de
statut de la Virginie a isolé allocations des places ait gêné le 
commerce entre Etats et ait été ainsi invalide, la corneille 
suivante de Jim que des lois de voyage est demeurée en vigueur en 
1954. Que la même année, la cour a déclaré dans le panneau 
brun de v. de l'éducation qui les écoles d'Etat séparées étaient 
"en soi inégales" et ainsi inconstitutionnel. En 1955, la 
communauté noire de Montgomery, Alabama, a organisé un boycott du 
système isolé du bus de la ville. En 1956, la cour suprême a 
régné les lois de l'Alabama exigeant les bus isolés 
inconstitutionnels. Les mots spécifiques de ces lois de 
corneille de Jim, ouvrés pour mettre à jour le statu quo, 
d'inquiétudes profondes indiquées au sujet de course. En 
assignant aux fonctionnaires de chemin de fer et de bus "maintenez 
l'ordre les puissances" d'imposer l'allocation des places isolée et 
dans le cas de la Virginie, puissance de déterminer la course des 
passagers, législatures d'état recherchées pour assurer la 
ségrégation. En exemptant certaines catégories des personnes,
spécifiquement infirmières, domestiques, et prisonniers, les lois 
ont également évité de perturber les façons de vivre qui n'ont pas
menacé des principes de la suprématie blanche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As primeiras leis passaram no sul para impo o 
segregation statewide nas facilidades públicas, instituídas no 1880s
e no 1890s, aplicados ao assento do carro da estrada de ferro. 
Durante este período, as linhas railway espalharam ràpidamente
das cidades às comunidades rurais. Em 1896, a corte suprema de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS validou estas de "leis adiantadas do corvo Jim" quando 
governou em Plessy v. Ferguson que um statute de Louisiana que requer 
"separa mas iguala" acomodações para branco e os passageiros pretos 
da estrada de ferro não opuseram à cláusula da décima quarta 
emenda que garante toda a proteção igual dos cidadãos das leis. 
(corvo de Jim, o termo colloquial para o segregation, consultado
a um caráter do blackface popular no estágio do minstrel.) A 
legislação do corvo de Jim estendeu durante todo o sul às escolas, 
aos hotéis, aos restaurantes, aos streetcars, às barras-ônibus, aos
teatros, aos hospitais, aos parques, aos tribunais, e mesmo aos 
cemeteries. Embora a corte suprema governasse em 1946 que reque 
do statute de Virgínia segregou assentos interferisse com o comércio
interstate e fosse assim invalid, o seguinte corvo de Jim leis do 
curso que remanesceu na força em 1954. Que o mesmo ano, a corte
declarou na placa marrom do v. da instrução que as escolas públicas
separadas eram "inerente desiguais" e assim unconstitutional. Em
1955, a comunidade preta de Montgomery, Alabama, organizou um boycott 
do sistema segregado da barra-ônibus da cidade. Em 1956, a 
corte suprema governou as leis de Alabama que requerem as 
barras-ônibus segregadas unconstitutional. O fraseio 
específico destas leis do corvo de Jim, crafted para manter o quo do 
status, de ansiedades profundas reveladas sobre a raça. 
Alocando aos oficiais da estrada de ferro e da barra-ônibus 
"policie potências" reforçar o assento segregado e no exemplo de 
Virgínia, potência determinar a raça dos passageiros, legislaturas 
de estado procuradas assegurar o segregation. Exempting 
determinadas categorias de pessoas, especificamente enfermeiras, 
empregados, e prisioneiros, as leis evitaram também de disrupting as 
maneiras de vida que não ameaçaram tenets do supremacy branco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le prime leggi hanno passato nel sud per imporre 
la segregazione in tutto lo stato nelle attrezzature pubbliche, 
istituite nel 1880s e nel 1890s, applicati alla disposizione dei posti
a sedere dell'automobile della ferrovia. Durante questo periodo,
le righe ferroviarie si sono sparse velocemente dalle città alle 
Comunità rurali. In 1896, la Corte suprema degli STATI UNITI ha
convalidato queste "leggi iniziali del corvo di Jim" quando ha 
regolato in Plessy v. Ferguson che uno statuto della Luisiana che 
richiede "separa ma è uguali" le sistemazioni per bianco ed i 
passeggeri neri della ferrovia non hanno stato in conflitto con la 
clausola di fourteenth correzione che garantisce tutta la protezione 
uguale dei cittadini delle leggi. (il corvo di Jim, il termine 
familiare per la segregazione, si è riferito ad un carattere del 
blackface popolare sulla fase del minstrel.) La legislazione del
corvo di Jim si è estesa durante il sud fino le scuole, gli hotel, i 
ristoranti, gli streetcars, i bus, i teatri, gli ospedali, i parchi, i
courthouses e perfino i cimiteri. Anche se la Corte suprema ha 
regolato in 1946 che richiedere dello statuto della Virginia ha 
segregato disposizioni dei posti a sedere ha interferito con il 
commercio da uno stato all'altro ed era così invalid, il seguente 
corvo di Jim leggi di corsa che è rimasto in il vigore in 1954. 
Che lo stesso anno, la corte ha dichiarato nel Bordo 
marrone del v. di formazione che le "public school" separate erano 
"inerentemente disuguali" e così inconstituzionale. In 1955, la
Comunità nera di Montgomery, Alabama, ha organizzato un boicottaggio 
del sistema segregato del bus della città. In 1956, la Corte 
suprema ha regolato le leggi dell'Alabama che richiedono i bus 
segregati inconstituzionali. Il wording specifico di queste 
leggi del corvo di Jim, perfezionamento per effettuare status quo, 
delle ansie profonde rivelarici circa la corsa. Assegnando ai 
funzionari del bus e della ferrovia "sorvegli le potenzi" fare 
rispettare la disposizione dei posti a sedere segregata e nel caso 
della Virginia, alimentano per determinare la corsa dei passeggeri, 
dichiarano le legislature cercate per accertare la segregazione.
Esentando determinate categorie di persone, specificamente le 
infermiere, servi e prigionieri, le leggi egualmente hanno evitato di 
interrompere i modo di vivere che non hanno minacciato i tenets del 
supremacy bianco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι πρώτοι νόμοι πέρασαν στο νότο για να επιβάλουν τον
εθνικό διαχωρισμό στις δημόσιες εγκαταστάσεις, που καθιερώθηκαν 
στο 1880s και το 1890s, που εφαρμόστηκαν στη διάταξη θέσεων 
αυτοκινήτων σιδηροδρόμου. Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της 
περιόδου, οι γραμμές σιδηροδρόμων διαδίδουν γρήγορα από τις 
πόλεις στις αγροτικές κοινότητες. Το 1896, το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
ανώτατο δικαστήριο επικύρωσε αυτούς τους πρόωρους "jim 
Crow" νόμους όταν κυβέρνησε Plessy V. Ferguson ότι 
ένα καταστατικό της Λουιζιάνας που απαιτεί τις "χωριστές αλλά 
ίσεσ" στεγάσεις για τους λευκούς και μαύρους επιβάτες 
σιδηροδρόμου δεν συγκρούστηκε με τη δέκατη τέταρτη πρόταση 
τροποποιήσεων εγγμένος σε όλους τους πολίτες την ίση προστασία 
των νόμων. (Jim Crow, ο κοινός όρος για το διαχωρισμό,
αναφέρθηκε σε έναν χαρακτήρα blackface δημοφιλή στο στάδιο 
τροβαδούρων.) Jim Crow η νομοθεσία επεκτάθηκε σε όλο 
το νότο στα σχολεία, τα ξενοδοχεία, τα εστιατόρια, τα τραμ, τους 
διαδρόμους, τα θέατρα, τα νοσοκομεία, τα πάρκα, τα δικαστήρια, 
και ακόμη και τα νεκροταφεία. Αν και το ανώτατο δικαστήριο 
διέταξε το 1946 ότι ένα καταστατικό της Βιρτζίνια που απαιτεί
τη διαχωρισμένη διάταξη θέσεων παρεμπόδισε το διακρατικό εμπόριο
και ήταν έτσι άκυρο, οι ακόλουθοι jim Crow νόμοι ταξιδιού 
παρέμειναν σε ισχύ το 1954. Εκείνο το ίδιο έτος, το 
δικαστήριο δήλωσε Brown V. Board της εκπαίδευσης ότι τα 
χωριστά δημόσια σχολεία ήταν "εγγενώς άνισα" και έτσι 
αντισυνταγματικά. Το 1955, η μαύρη κοινότητα του 
Μοντγκόμερυ, Αλαμπάμα, οργάνωσε ένα μποϊκοτάρισμα του 
διαχωρισμένου συστήματος διαδρόμων της πόλης. Το 1956, το
ανώτατο δικαστήριο διέταξε τους νόμους της Αλαμπάμα που απαιτούν
τους διαχωρισμένους διαδρόμους αντισυνταγματικούς. Η 
συγκεκριμένη διατύπωση αυτών των jim Crow νόμων, που 
επεξεργάστηκε για να διατηρήσει το καθεστώς, αποκάλυψε βαθιές 
ανησυχίες για τη φυλή. Με να δεσμεύσουν στους ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους σιδηροδρόμου και διαδρόμων οι "δυνάμεις αστυνομίασ" 
που επιβάλλουν διαχώρισαν τη διάταξη θέσεων και στην περίπτωση 
της Βιρτζίνια, δύναμη να καθοριστεί η φυλή των επιβατών, τα 
κρατικά νομοθετικά σώματα επιδίωξαν να εξασφαλίσουν διαχωρισμό. 
Με την απαλλαγή ορισμένων κατηγοριών προσώπων, συγκεκριμένα
νοσοκόμες, υπάλληλοι, και φυλακισμένοι, οι νόμοι που αποφεύγονται
επίσης τους τρόπους της ζωής που δεν απείλησαν τις αρχές της 
άσπρης υπεροχής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los primeros leyes pasaron en el sur para imponer 
la segregación estatal en los recursos públicos, instituidos en el 
1880s y el 1890s, aplicados al asiento del coche del ferrocarril. 
Durante este período, las líneas ferroviarias se separaron 
rápidamente de ciudades a las comunidades rurales. En 1896, el 
Tribunal Supremo de ESTADOS UNIDOS validó estos "leyes tempranos del 
cuervo de Jim" cuando gobernó en Plessy v. Ferguson que un estatuto 
de Luisiana que requiere "separa pero iguala" las comodidades para 
blanco y los pasajeros negros del ferrocarril no estuvieron en 
conflicto con la cláusula de la catorcena enmienda que garantizaba 
toda la protección igual de los ciudadanos de los leyes. (el 
cuervo de Jim, el término familiar para la segregación, refirió a 
un carácter del blackface popular en la etapa del minstrel.) La
legislación del cuervo de Jim extendió a través del sur a las 
escuelas, a los hoteles, a los restaurantes, a los streetcars, a los 
megabuses, a los teatros, a los hospitales, a los parques, a los 
palacios de justicia, e incluso a los cementerios. Aunque el 
Tribunal Supremo gobernó en 1946 que el requerir del estatuto de 
Virginia segregó asientos interfirió con comercio de un estado a 
otro y era así invalid, el cuervo siguiente de Jim que los leyes 
seguía habiendo del recorrido en vigor en 1954. Que el mismo 
año, la corte declaró en la tarjeta marrón del v. de la educación 
que las escuelas públicas separadas eran "intrínsecamente 
desiguales" y así inconstitucional. En 1955, la comunidad negra
de Montgomery, Alabama, ordenó un boicoteo del sistema segregado del 
megabus de la ciudad. En 1956, el Tribunal Supremo gobernó los 
leyes de Alabama que requerían los megabuses segregados 
inconstitucionales. La fraseología específica de estos leyes 
del cuervo de Jim, hecha a mano para mantener el status quo, de las 
ansiedades profundas reveladas sobre la raza. Afectando un 
aparato a los funcionarios del ferrocarril y del megabus "limpie las 
potencias" de hacer cumplir el asiento segregado y en el caso de 
Virginia, potencia de determinar a la raza de los pasajeros, 
legislaturas de estado intentadas para asegurar la segregación. 
Eximiendo ciertas categorías de las personas, específicamente 
enfermeras, criados, y presos, los leyes también evitaron de 
interrumpir las maneras de la vida que no amenazaron tenets de la 
supremacía blanca.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086074</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105163</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/digest-of-jim-crow-laws-affecting-passengers-in-interstate-travel</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
