<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103169</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103169</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209956</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Online Science-athon: The Marble Roll</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Onlinewissenschaft-athon: Die Marmorrolle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science-athon En ligne : Le Roulement de 
marbre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência-athon Em linha: O Rolo De mármore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza-athon In linea: Il Rullo Di marmo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε απευθείας σύνδεση επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον: Ο
μαρμάρινος ρόλος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia-athon En línea: El Rodillo De 
mármol</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Online Science-athon offers elementary and middle-grade students opportunities to discover the science in their daily lives. Presented as challenges, the Science-athon asks students to investigate their world in ways that are engaging and fun, easy for teachers to incorporate into their teaching, and instructive. Students doing the Marble Roll select a strip of material that is 61 cm (24 inches) in length to use as a ramp. Then they determine how to maximize the distance their marble rolls across a flat surface by doing such things as experimenting with side or center guides, smoothing surfaces, changing the angle of the ramp, altering its shape, modifying the place where the ramp and ground meet, trying different ramp lengths or widths, and releasing the marble from different spots on the ramp. Reviewing scientific information helps participants improve the effectiveness of their ramp designs and make predictions about which marbles will roll the greatest distance. On Marble Roll Day, students collect and record data to share with other students doing the challenge. Analysis of their data and data collected by others allows participants to formulate explanations and to check these explanations against scientific knowledge and the explanations and experiences of others.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Onlinewissenschaft-athon bietet die 
grundlegende und Mittlergrad Kursteilnehmer Gelegenheiten, die 
Wissenschaft in ihren täglichen Lebensdauern zu entdecken an. 
Dargestellt als Herausforderungen, bittet die Wissenschaft-athon
Kursteilnehmer, ihre Welt in den Methoden, die und sich engagieren, im
Spaß nachzuforschen, einfach, damit Lehrer in ihren Unterricht 
verbinden, und lehrreich. Die Kursteilnehmer, welche die 
Marmorrolle tun, wählen einen Streifen des Materials aus, das 61 
Zentimeter (24 Zoll) als ist Rampe zu verwenden in der Länge. 
Dann stellen sie fest, wie man den Abstand ihre Marmorrollen 
über einer flachen Oberfläche maximiert, indem sie solche Sachen wie
tun, experimentierend mit Seite oder Mitteanleitungen und Oberflächen
glatt machen und den Winkel der Rampe ändern und seine Form ändern 
und den Platz ändern, in dem die Rampe und der Boden trifft, 
unterschiedliche Rampe Längen oder Breiten versuchen, und den Marmor 
von den unterschiedlichen Punkten auf der Rampe freigeben. 
Fachinformation Hilfen Teilnehmer wiederholend, verbessern Sie 
die Wirksamkeit ihrer Rampe Designs und bilden Sie Vorhersagen, über 
die Marmore den größten Abstand rollen. Am Marmorrollentag 
sammeln Kursteilnehmer und speichern Daten, um mit anderen 
Kursteilnehmern zu teilen, welche die Herausforderung tun. 
Analyse ihrer Daten und der Daten sammelte durch andere erlaubt 
Teilnehmern, Erklärungen zu formulieren und diese Erklärungen gegen 
wissenschaftliches Wissen zu überprüfen und die Erklärungen und die
Erfahrungen von anderen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science-athon en ligne offre les étudiants 
élémentaires et de moyen-catégorie des occasions de découvrir la 
science dans leurs vies quotidiennes. Présenté en tant que 
défis, la Science-athon demande à des étudiants d'étudier leur 
monde des voies qui s'engagent et de l'amusement, facile pour des 
professeurs d'incorporer à leur enseignement, et instructif. 
Les étudiants faisant le roulement de marbre choisissent une 
bande du matériel qui est de 61 centimètres (24 pouces) de long à 
utiliser comme rampe. Alors ils déterminent comment maximiser 
la distance leurs roulements de marbre à travers une surface plate en
faisant des choses telles qu'expérimentant avec des guides de côté 
ou de centre, lissant des surfaces, changeant l'angle de la rampe, 
modifiant sa forme, modifiant l'endroit où la rampe et la terre se 
réunissent, essayant différentes longueurs de rampe ou largeurs, et 
libérant le marbre à partir de différentes taches sur la rampe. 
En passant en revue des participants d'aides d'information 
scientifique améliorez l'efficacité de leurs conceptions de rampe et
faites les prévisions au sujet dont les marbres rouleront la plus 
grande distance. Le jour de marbre de roulement, les étudiants 
rassemblent et enregistrent des données pour partager avec d'autres 
étudiants faisant le défi. L'analyse de leurs données et 
données s'est rassemblée par d'autres permet à des participants de 
formuler des explications et de contrôler ces explications contre la 
connaissance scientifique et les explications et les expériences de 
d'autres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Ciência-athon em linha oferece estudantes 
elementares e da médio-classe oportunidades de descobrir a ciência 
em suas vidas diárias. Apresentado como desafios, a 
Ciência-athon pede que os estudantes investiguem seu mundo nas 
maneiras que estão acoplando e no divertimento, fácil para que os 
professores incorporem em seu ensino, e instructive. Os 
estudantes que fazem o rolo de mármore selecionam uma tira do 
material que é 61 cm (24 polegadas) no comprimento a se usar como uma
rampa. Então determinam como maximize a distância seus rolos 
do mármore através de uma superfície plana fazendo coisas como 
experimentando com as guias do lado ou do centro, alisando 
superfícies, mudando o ângulo da rampa, alterando sua forma, 
modificando o lugar onde a rampa e a terra se encontram com, tentando 
comprimentos da rampa ou larguras diferentes, e liberando o mármore 
dos pontos diferentes na rampa. Revendo participants das ajudas 
da informação científica melhore a eficácia de seus projetos da 
rampa e faça as predições sobre que os mármores rolarão a 
distância a mais grande. No dia de mármore do rolo, os 
estudantes coletam e gravam dados para compartilhar com outros 
estudantes que fazem o desafio. A análise de seus dados e dados
coletou por outra permite que os participants formulem explanações e
verifiquem estas explanações de encontro ao conhecimento científico
e as explanações e as experiências de outras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Scienza-athon in linea offre gli allievi del 
centrale-grado ed elementari occasioni scoprire la scienza nelle loro 
vite quotidiane. Presentato come sfide, la Scienza-athon chiede 
agli allievi di studiare il loro mondo nei modi che stanno 
agganciandosi e nel divertimento, facile affinchè gli insegnanti 
incorpori nel loro insegnamento ed istruttivo. Gli allievi che 
fanno il rullo di marmo selezionano una striscia di materiale che è 
di 61 centimetro (24 pollici) per esteso da usare come dilagare. 
Allora determinano come elevare la distanza i loro rulli del 
marmo attraverso una superficie piana facendo tali cose come 
sperimentando con le guide del centro o del lato, lisciando le 
superfici, cambianti l'angolo del dilagare, alterando la relativa 
figura, modificando il posto in cui il dilagare e la terra vengono 
a contatto di, provare differente dilagano le lunghezze o le 
larghezze e liberare il marmo dai punti differenti sul dilagare. 
Rivedendo gli aiuti che di informazione scientifica i 
partecipanti migliorano l'efficacia del loro dilagi i 
disegni e faccia le previsioni circa cui i marmi rotoleranno la 
distanza più grande. Il giorno di marmo del rullo, gli allievi 
raccolgono e registrano i dati per ripartirsi con altri allievi che 
fanno la sfida. L'analisi dei loro dati e dati ha raccolto da 
altre permette che i partecipanti formulino le spiegazioni e 
controllino queste spiegazioni contro conoscenza scientifica e le 
spiegazioni e le esperienze in altre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σε απευθείας σύνδεση επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον 
προσφέρει τις στοιχειώδεις και μέσες ευκαιρίες σπουδαστών να 
ανακαλύψουν την επιστήμη στις καθημερινές ζωές τους. 
Παρουσιασμένη ως προκλήσεις, η επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον 
ζητά από τους σπουδαστές για να ερευνήσει τον κόσμο τους στους 
τρόπους που δεσμεύουν και διασκέδαση, εύκολη για τους δασκάλους 
να ενσωματώσουν στη διδασκαλία τους, και διδακτική. Οι 
σπουδαστές που κάνουν το μαρμάρινο ρόλο επιλέγουν μια λουρίδα 
του υλικού που είναι 61 εκατ. (24 ίντσες) στο μήκος που 
χρησιμοποιεί ως κεκλιμένη ράμπα. Κατόπιν καθορίζουν πώς να
μεγιστοποιήσουν την απόσταση το μάρμαρό που τους κυλά πέρα από 
μια επίπεδη επιφάνεια με να κάνει τέτοια πράγματα σαν 
πειραματιμένος με τους οδηγούς πλευράς ή κέντρων, λειαίνοντας 
επιφάνειες, που αλλάζουν τη γωνία της κεκλιμένης ράμπας, που 
αλλάζει τη μορφή του, που τροποποιεί τη θέση όπου η κεκλιμένη 
ράμπα και το έδαφος συναντιούνται, δοκιμάζοντας τα διαφορετικά 
μήκη κεκλιμένων ραμπών ή τα πλάτη, και εκδίδοντας το μάρμαρο 
από τα διαφορετικά σημεία στην κεκλιμένη ράμπα. Η 
αναθεώρηση των επιστημονικών πληροφοριών βοηθά τους συμμετέχοντες
να βελτιώσουν την αποτελεσματικότητα των σχεδίων κεκλιμένων 
ραμπών τους και να κάνουν τις προβλέψεις για τις οποίες τα 
μάρμαρα θα κυλήσουν τη μέγιστη απόσταση. τη μαρμάρινη 
ημέρα ρόλων, οι σπουδαστές συλλέγουν και τα στοιχεία αρχείων που
μοιράζονται με άλλους σπουδαστές που κάνουν την πρόκληση. Η
ανάλυση των στοιχείων τους και των στοιχείων που συλλέγονται από 
άλλα επιτρέπει στους συμμετέχοντες για να διατυπώσει τις 
εξηγήσεις και για να ελέγξει αυτές τις εξηγήσεις σε σχέση με την 
επιστημονική γνώση και τις εξηγήσεις και την εμπειρία άλλες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Ciencia-athon en línea ofrece a estudiantes 
elementales y del medio-grado las oportunidades de descubrir la 
ciencia en sus vidas diarias. Presentado como desafíos, la 
Ciencia-athon pide que los estudiantes investiguen su mundo de las 
maneras que están enganchando y de la diversión, fácil para que los
profesores incorporen en su enseñanza, e instructivo. Los 
estudiantes que hacen el rodillo de mármol seleccionan una tira del 
material que es 61 centímetros (24 pulgadas) en la longitud a 
utilizar como rampa. Entonces se determinan cómo maximizar la 
distancia sus rodillos del mármol a través de una superficie plana 
haciendo las cosas tales como experimentando con las guías de la cara
o del centro, alisando superficies, cambiando el ángulo de la rampa, 
alterando su dimensión de una variable, modificando el lugar en donde
la rampa y la tierra satisfacen, intentando diversas longitudes de la 
rampa o anchuras, y release/versión el mármol de diversos puntos en 
la rampa. Repasando a participantes de las ayudas de la 
información científica mejore la eficacia de sus diseños de la 
rampa y haga las predicciones sobre las cuales los mármoles rodarán 
la distancia más grande. En el día de mármol del rodillo, los
estudiantes recogen y registran datos para compartir con otros 
estudiantes que hacen el desafío. El análisis de sus datos y 
los datos recogió por otros permite que los participantes formulen 
explicaciones y que controlen estas explicaciones contra conocimiento 
científico y las explicaciones y las experiencias de otras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209956</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103169</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/marble-roll</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
