<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105081</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105081</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086685</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Oh God, For One More Breath": Early 20th century Tennessee Coal Miners' Last Words</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"OH- Gott, Für Einen Weiteren Atem": Früh 
dauern der 20. Jahrhundert Tennessee Kohle-Bergmänner Wörter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Dieu de l'OH, Pour Un Plus de Souffle" : 
Les début du 20ème mineurs du Tennessee de siècle durent des 
mots</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Do "Deus Oh, Para Uma Mais Respiração": 
Cedo os 20os mineiros de carvão de Tennessee do século duram 
palavras</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Dio Dell'OH, Per Un Nuovo Alito": Gli 
inizio del 20esimo minatori delle miniere di carbone del Tennessee di 
secolo durano le parole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Θεός OH, για μια περισσότερη αναπνοή": Νωρίς
οι ανθρακωρύχοι του Tennessee του 20ού αιώνα διαρκούν τις 
λέξεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Dios Del Oh, Para Una Más Respiración": 
Los vigésimos mineros de carbón de Tennessee del siglo duran 
temprano palabras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Coal mining and railroad work were the two most dangerous trades in the United States in the early 20th century. Coal miners frequently died in spectacular explosions and cave-ins that could kill dozens or even hundreds at a time. Although most testimony about coal mining disasters came from survivors and observers, the men who suffocated to death in the Fraterville, Tennessee mines in May 1902 left behind their own grim account. Trapped in the mine after an explosion and with their air rapidly depleting, they wrote letters to their loved ones describing their final moments.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kohlenbergbau und Eisenbahnarbeit waren der zwei 
gefährlichste Handel in den Vereinigten Staaten im frühen 20. 
Jahrhundert. Kohlebergmänner starben häufig in den 
großartigen Explosionen und in den Einstürzen, die Dutzende oder 
sogar Hunderte hintereinander beenden konnten. Obgleich das 
meiste Zeugnis über Kohlengrubeunfälle von den Überlebenden und von
den Beobachtern kam, die Männer, die zum Tod im Fraterville, 
Tennessee Gruben im Mai 1902 nach links hinter ihrem eigenen grimmigen
Konto erstickten. Eingeschlossen in der Grube nach einer 
Explosion und mit ihrer Luft, die schnell verbraucht, schrieben sie 
Briefe zu ihrem liebten eine, die ihre abschließenden Momente 
beschreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'extraction de charbon et le travail de chemin de
fer étaient les deux échanges les plus dangereux des Etats-Unis en 
début du 20ème siècle. Les mineurs sont fréquemment morts 
dans les explosions et les éboulements spectaculaires qui pourraient 
détruire des douzaines ou même des centaines à la fois. Bien 
que la plupart de témoignage au sujet des désastres de mine de 
houille soit venu des survivants et des observateurs, les hommes qui 
ont suffoqué à la mort dans le Fraterville, mines du Tennessee en 
mai 1902 à gauche derrière leur propre compte sinistre. 
Emprisonné dans la mine après une explosion et avec du leur 
air épuisant rapidement, ils ont écrit des lettres au leur ont aimé
ceux décrivants leurs moments finals.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A mineração de carvão e o trabalho da estrada 
de ferro eram os dois comércios os mais perigosos nos estados unidos 
no 20o século adiantado. Os mineiros de carvão morreram 
freqüentemente nas explosões e nos cave-ins espectaculares que 
poderiam matar dúzias ou mesmo centenas em um momento. Embora a
maioria de testimony sobre disastres da mineração de carvão viesse 
dos sobreviventes e dos observadores, os homens que sufocaram à morte
no Fraterville, minas de Tennessee em maio 1902 à esquerda atrás de 
seu próprio cliente grim. Prendido na mina após uma explosão 
e com seu ar que esgota ràpidamente, escreveram letras ao seu amaram
  que descrevem seus momentos finais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'estrazione di carbone ed il lavoro della 
ferrovia erano i due commerci più pericolosi di unito Dichiara
nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo. I minatori delle miniere di 
carbone sono morto frequentemente nelle esplosioni e nei franamenti 
spettacolari che potrebbero uccidere le dozzine o persino le centinaia
alla volta. Anche se la maggior parte della testimonianza circa 
i disastri di miniera di carbone è venuto dai superstiti e dagli 
osservatori, gli uomini che hanno soffocato alla morte nel 
Fraterville, miniere del Tennessee in maggio 1902 a sinistra dietro il
loro proprio cliente torvo. Intrappolato nella miniera dopo 
un'esplosione e con la loro aria che esaurisce velocemente, hanno 
scritto le lettere al loro amavano ones che descrivono i loro momenti 
finali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μεταλλεία άνθρακα και η εργασία σιδηροδρόμου ήταν 
δύο τα πιό επικίνδυνοτα εμπόριο στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες στις 
αρχές του 20ού αιώνα. Οι ανθρακωρύχοι πέθαναν συχνά στις 
θεαματικά εκρήξεις και cave-ins που θα μπορούσαν να σκοτώσουν 
τις δωδεκάδες ή ακόμα και τις εκατοντάδες σε έναν χρόνο. 
Αν και η περισσότερη κατάθεση για τις καταστροφές μεταλλείας
άνθρακα προήλθε από τους επιζόντες και τους παρατηρητές, τα 
άτομα που ασφύκτιαν στο θάνατο στο Fraterville, ορυχεία του 
Tennessee σε Μάιος το 1902 αριστερά πίσω από τον 
απαίσιο απολογισμό τους. Παγιδευμένοι στο ορυχείο μετά από
μια έκρηξη και με τον αέρα τους που μειώνει γρήγορα, έγραψαν τις 
επιστολές στους αγαπημένους αυτούς τους περιγράφοντας τις τελικές
στιγμές τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La explotación hullera y el trabajo del 
ferrocarril eran los dos comercios más peligrosos de los Estados 
Unidos en el vigésimo siglo temprano. Los mineros de carbón 
murieron con frecuencia en las explosiones y los derrumbamientos 
espectaculares que podrían matar a docenas o aún a centenares al 
mismo tiempo. Aunque la mayoría del testimonio sobre desastres 
de la mina de carbón vino de sobrevivientes y de observadores, los 
hombres que sofocaron a la muerte en el Fraterville, minas de 
Tennessee en mayo 1902 a la izquierda detrás de su propia cuenta 
severa. Atrapado en la mina después de una explosión y con su 
aire que agotaba rápidamente, escribieron letras a su amaron unos que
describían sus momentos finales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086685</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105081</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/oh-god-for-one-more-breath-early-20th-century-tennessee-coal-miners-last-words</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
