<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108031</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108031</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086297</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Subscribe Myself a Friend to the Oppressed": Henry Bibb Writes to his Former Master, 1844</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich unterzeichne mich ein Freund zu 
unterdrückt": Henry-Mastbacke schreibt zu seinem ehemaligen 
Meister, 1844</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je me souscris un ami au opprimé" : Le 
robinet d'Henry écrit à son ancien maître, 1844</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu subscrevo-me um amigo ao oppressed": O 
bibb do Henry escreve a seu mestre anterior, 1844</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"mi abbono un amico al oppressed": Il 
rubinetto di henry scrive al suo supervisore precedente, 1844</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"προσυπογράφομαι ένας φίλος καταπιεσμένη": 
Θ*Χενρυ Bibb Writes στον προηγούμενο κύριό του, 1844</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"me suscribo un amigo al opreso": El grifo 
del Henrio escribe a su amo anterior, 1844</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Thousands of free and escaped African Americans played significant roles in the antebellum abolitionist movement. Henry Bibb was born into slavery in Kentucky in 1815. His autobiography recounted his sufferings, escapes, recapture, and efforts to free his family. Upon his final escape he became active in politics. He was a founder of the Liberty Party in 1840 in Michigan and the Free Soil Party in 1848. While attending a political convention, he contacted his former master in Kentucky and began a correspondence, excerpted here. After the passage of the Fugitive Slave Law by Congress in 1850, Bibb fled to Canada and helped form the Refugee's Home colony for escaped slaves.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tausenden der freien und entgangenen afrikanischen
Amerikaner spielten bedeutende Rollen in der antebellum abolitionist 
Bewegung. Henry-Mastbacke wurde in Sklaverei in Kentucky 1815 
getragen. Seine Autobiographie zählte seine Sufferings, 
Entweichen nach, erlangt und Bemühungen, seine Familie freizugeben 
wieder. Nach seinem abschließenden Entweichen wurde er in der 
Politik aktiv. Er war ein Gründer der Freiheit-Partei 
1840 in Michigan und der freien Boden-Partei 1848. Beim 
Bedienen einer politischen Versammlung, trat er mit seinem ehemaligen 
Meister in Kentucky in Verbindung und fing eine Korrespondenz an, hier
excerptiert. Nach dem Durchgang des Flüchtling-Sklave Gesetzes 
durch Congress 1850, die Mastbacke geflohen nach Kanada und Formular 
geholfen die Hauptkolonie des Flüchtlings für entgangene Sklaven.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les milliers d'Américains africains libres et 
échappés ont joué des rôles significatifs dans le mouvement 
d'avant-guerre d'abolitionniste. Le robinet d'Henry a été 
soutenu dans l'esclavage au Kentucky en 1815. Son autobiographie
a raconté ses douleurs, évasions, les reprend, et des efforts de 
libérer sa famille. Sur sa évasion finale il est devenu actif 
dans la politique. Il était un fondateur de la partie de 
liberté en 1840 au Michigan et de la partie de sol libre en 1848. 
Tout en servant une convention politique, il a entré en contact
avec son ancien maître au Kentucky et a commencé une correspondance,
extraite ici. Après le passage de la loi Slave de 
fugitif par Congress en 1850, le robinet sauvé au Canada et aidé la 
forme la colonie à la maison du réfugié pour les esclaves 
échappés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os milhares de americanos africanos livres e 
escapados jogaram papéis significativos no movimento antebellum do 
abolitionist. O bibb do Henry foi carregado no slavery em 
Kentucky em 1815. Seu autobiography recounted seus sofrimentos, 
escapes, recaptura-os, e esforços livrar sua família. Em cima 
de seu escape final tornou-se ativo na política. Era um founder
do partido de liberdade em 1840 em Michigan e do partido de solo livre
em 1848. Ao atender a uma convenção política, contatou seu 
mestre anterior em Kentucky e começou uma correspondência, excerpted
aqui. Após a passagem da lei do escravo do fugitive por 
Congress em 1850, por bibb fujido a Canadá e ajudado o formulário a 
colônia home do refugee para escravos escapados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le migliaia degli Americani africani liberi e 
fuoriusciti hanno svolto i ruoli significativi nel movimento 
antebellum di abolitionist. Il rubinetto di henry è stato 
sopportato in slavery nel Kentucky in 1815. Il suo autobiography
ha raccontato i suoi sufferings, fughe, riprende e sforzi liberare la 
sua famiglia. Sulla sua fuga finale è diventato attivo nella 
politica. Era un fondatore del partito di libertà in 1840 nel 
Michigan e del partito di terreno libero in 1848. Mentre 
assisteva ad una convenzione politica, si è messo in contatto con il 
suo supervisore precedente nel Kentucky ed ha cominciato una 
corrispondenza, stralciata qui. Dopo il passaggio della legge 
dello schiavo del fuggitivo da Congress in 1850, il rubinetto è 
fuggito nel Canada ed aiutato la forma la colonia domestica del 
rifugiato per gli schiavi fuoriusciti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χιλιάδες ελεύθεροι και δραπετευμένοι αφρικανικοί 
Αμερικανοί διαδραμάτισαν τους σημαντικούς ρόλους στην προπολεμική
μετακίνηση ρεφορμιστών. Θ*Χενρυ Bibb γεννήθηκε στη 
σκλαβιά στο Κεντάκυ σε 1815, Η αυτοβιογραφία του 
εξιστόρησε τα βάσανά του, διαφυγές, συλλαμβάνει εκ νέου, και 
προσπάθειες ελεύθερες η οικογένειά του. Επάνω στην τελική 
διαφυγή του έγινε ενεργός στην πολιτική. Ήταν ιδρυτής του 
συμβαλλόμενου μέρους ελευθερίας το 1840 στο Μίτσιγκαν και του 
ελεύθερου εδαφολογικού συμβαλλόμενου μέρους το 1848. Σε 
μια πολιτική σύμβαση, ήρθε σε επαφή με τον προηγούμενο κύριό 
του στο Κεντάκυ και άρχισε μια αλληλογραφία, εδώ. Μετά από
τη μετάβαση του νόμου σκλάβων προσφύγων από το συνέδριο το 
1850, bibb που στον Καναδά και την ενισχυμένη μορφή την 
αποικία "Οικιαών του πρόσφυγα για τους δραπετευμένους σκλάβους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los millares de americanos africanos libres y 
escapados desempeñaron papeles significativos en el movimiento 
antebellum del abolitionist. El grifo del Henrio fue llevado en 
esclavitud en Kentucky en 1815. Su autobiografía contó de 
nuevo sus sufrimientos, escapes, los recobra, y los esfuerzos de 
liberar a su familia. Sobre su escape final él hizo activo en 
política. Él era un fundador del partido de libertad en 1840 
en Michigan y del partido de suelo libre en 1848. Mientras que 
atendía a una convención política, él entró en contacto con su 
amo anterior en Kentucky y comenzó una correspondencia, extractada 
aquí. Después del paso de la ley del esclavo del fugitivo por 
Congress en 1850, el grifo huido a Canadá y ayudado la forma la 
colonia casera del refugiado para los esclavos escapados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086297</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108031</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-subscribe-myself-a-friend-to-the-oppressed-henry-bibb-writes-to-his-former-master-1844</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
