<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107319</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107319</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087329</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Quaker Abolitionist Travels Through Maryland and Virginia: The Journal of John Woolman, 1757</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Quäker Abolitionist reist durch Maryland und 
Virginia: Das Journal von John Woolman, 1757</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un Abolitionniste de quaker voyage par le Maryland et
la Virginie : Le journal de John Woolman, 1757</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um quaker Abolitionist viaja através de Maryland 
e de Virgínia: O jornal de John Woolman, 1757</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un quaker Abolitionist attraversa through Maryland
e la Virginia: Il giornale di John Woolman, 1757</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ταξίδια κουάκερα ρεφορμιστών μέσω της Μέρυλαντ και 
της Βιρτζίνια: Το περιοδικό John Woolman, 1757</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un quaker Abolitionist viaja a través de Maryland
y de Virginia: El diario de Juan Woolman, 1757</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In both Britain and the United States, Quakers were among the first to denounce slavery in the 18th century. This was due to the efforts of Quaker abolitionist leaders such as John Woolman. Born in New Jersey in 1720, Woolman was a tailor and shopkeeper. Continual encounters with slavery in his own neighborhood--notably an incident in which his employer asked him to write out a bill of sale for a slave--convinced him that he could not, in good conscience, continue to have anything more to do with slavery. In 1756, the year he began his journal, he gave up most of his business to devote himself to anti-slavery. This selection from Woolman's journal, published in 1774 after his death, records a trip in May 1757, through Maryland and Virginia, to spread his anti-slavery message among fellow Quakers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">in Großbritannien und in den Vereinigten Staaten
gehörten Quäker zu dem ersten kündigen Sklaverei im 18. 
Jahrhundert. Dieses lag an den Bemühungen der Quäker 
abolitionist Führer wie John Woolman. Getragen in Neu-Jersey 
1720, war Woolman ein Schneider und ein Ladenbesitzer. 
Kontinuierliches Treffen mit Sklaverei in seiner eigenen 
Nachbarschaft -- vornehmlich ein Ereignis, in dem sein Arbeitgeber ihn
bat, einen Kaufvertrag für einen Sklaven auszuschreiben -- überzeugt
ihm, daß er nicht, in der guten Gewissenhaftigkeit, mehr 
fortzufahren, nichts zu haben, mit Sklaverei zu tun könnte. 
1756 gab das Jahr, das er sein Journal, er anfing, oben die 
meisten seines Geschäfts, um sich Anti-Sklaverei zu widmen. 
Diese Auswahl vom Journal Woolmans, veröffentlicht 1774 nach 
seinem Tod, speichert eine Reise im Mai 1757, durch Maryland und 
Virginia, um seine Anti-Sklaverei Meldung unter Gefährtequäkern zu 
verbreiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En Grande-Bretagne et aux Etats-Unis, les quakers 
étaient parmi le premier dénoncent l'esclavage au 18ème siècle. 
C'était dû aux efforts des amorces d'abolitionniste de quaker 
telles que John Woolman. Soutenu dans New Jersey en 1720, 
Woolman était un tailleur et un commerçant. Rencontre 
continuelle avec l'esclavage dans son propre voisinage -- notamment un
incident dans lequel son employeur lui a demandé d'écrire un acte de
vente pour un slave -- convinced il qu'il ne pourrait pas, dans 
la bonne conscience, continuer à avoir n'importe quoi davantage faire
avec l'esclavage. En 1756, l'année où il a commencé son 
journal, il a donné vers le haut la majeure partie de ses affaires 
pour se consacrer au l'anti-esclavage. Cette sélection à 
partir du journal de Woolman, édité en 1774 après sa mort, 
enregistre un voyage en mai 1757, par le Maryland et la Virginie, pour
propager son message d'anti-esclavage parmi des quakers de camarade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">em Grâ Bretanha e nos estados unidos, os quakers
eram entre o primeiro denounce o slavery no 18o século. Isto 
era  devido aos esforços de líderes do abolitionist do quaker tais 
como John Woolman. Carregado em Novo-Jersey em 1720, Woolman era
um alfaiate e um shopkeeper. Encontro contínuo com slavery em 
sua própria vizinhança -- notàvelmente um incident em que seu 
empregador pediu que escrevesse para fora de uma conta de venda para 
um escravo -- convencida lhe que não poderia, no conscience bom, para
continuar mais a ter qualquer coisa fazer com slavery. Em 1756, 
o ano onde começou seu jornal, ele deu acima a maioria de seu 
negócio para devotar-se ao anti-anti-slavery. Esta seleção do
jornal de Woolman, publicado em 1774 após sua morte, grava um 
desengate em maio 1757, através de Maryland e de Virgínia, para 
espalhar sua mensagem do anti-anti-slavery entre quakers do 
companheiro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sia in Gran-Bretagna che uniti Dichiara, 
quakers erano fra il primo denunciano lo slavery nel diciottesimo 
secolo. Ciò era dovuto gli sforzi dei capi di 
abolitionist del quaker quale John Woolman. Sopportato in 
Nuovo-Jersey in 1720, Woolman era un sarto e un commerciante. 
Incontro continuo con slavery nella sua propria vicinanza -- 
considerevolmente un avvenimento in cui il suo datore di lavoro gli ha
chiesto di scrivere una fattura della vendita per uno schiavo -- 
convinta lui che non potrebbe, nella buona coscienza, continuare ad 
avere qualche cosa di più fare con slavery. In 1756, l'anno che
ha cominciato il suo giornale, lui ha dato in su la maggior parte del 
suo commercio per dedicarsi aanti-anti-slavery. Questa selezione
dal giornale del Woolman, pubblicato in 1774 dopo la sua morte, 
registra un viaggio nel mese di maggio 1757, attraverso Maryland e la 
Virginia, per propagare il suo messaggio di anti-anti-slavery tra i 
quakers del collega.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Και στη Μεγάλη Βρετανία και στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, 
Quakers ήταν μεταξύ του πρώτου για να καταγγείλει σκλαβιά στο 
18$ο αιώνα. Αυτό οφειλόταν στις προσπάθειες των κουάκερων 
ηγετών ρεφορμιστών όπως John Woolman. Γεννημένος στο 
Νιου Τζέρσευ! το 1720, Woolman ήταν ράφτης και 
καταστηματάρχης. Οι συνεχείς συγκρούσεις με τη σκλαβιά στη 
γειτονιά του -- ειδικότερα ένα γεγονός στο οποίο ο εργοδότης του
τον ζήτησε για να καταγράψει έναν λογαριασμό της πώλησης για 
έναν σκλάβο -- τον έπεισαν ότι δεν θα μπορούσε, στην καλή 
συνείδηση, να συνεχίσει να έχει τίποτα περισσότερο που κάνει με 
τη σκλαβιά. Το 1756, το έτος που άρχισε το περιοδικό του,
σταμάτησε την μεγαλύτερη μέρος της επιχείρησής του για να 
αφιερώνεται σε ενάντιο στη δουλεία. Αυτή η επιλογή από το 
περιοδικό Woolman, που δημοσιεύεται το 1774 μετά από το 
θάνατό του, καταγράφει ένα ταξίδι σε Μάιος 1757, μέσω 
της Μέρυλαντ και της Βιρτζίνια, για να διαδώσει το ενάντιο στη 
δουλεία μήνυμά του μεταξύ συντροφικού Quakers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En Gran Bretaña y los Estados Unidos, los quakers
estaban entre el primer denunci esclavitud en el décimo octavo siglo.
Esto era debido a los esfuerzos de los arranques de cinta del 
abolitionist del quaker tales como Juan Woolman. Llevado en 
Nuevo-Jersey en 1720, Woolman era personalización y comerciante. 
Encuentro continuo con la esclavitud en su propia vecindad -- 
notablemente un incidente en el cual su patrón pidió que él pusiera
una cuenta en escrito de la venta para un esclavo -- convencida le que
él no podría, en buena conciencia, continuar teniendo cualquier cosa
más hacer con esclavitud. En 1756, el año que él comenzó su 
diario, él dio para arriba la mayoría de su negocio para dedicarse a
la contra-esclavitud. Esta selección del diario de Woolman, 
publicado en 1774 después de su muerte, registra un viaje en mayo de 
1757, a través de Maryland y de Virginia, para separar su mensaje de 
la contra-esclavitud entre quakers del compañero.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087329</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107319</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-quaker-abolitionist-travels-through-maryland-and-virginia-the-journal-of-john-woolman-1757</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
