<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104296</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104296</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201470</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Energized Learning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit Energie versorgtes Lernen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude Activée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem Energizada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparare Eccitato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενεργοποιημένη εκμάθηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Aprender Energizado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Berkeley Lab's Environmental Energy Technologies Division develops technology that uses, converts and stores energy more efficiently and with less environmental impact, and studies the link between energy use and the environment. An important outcome of its work is the development of technologies and processes to mitigate the environmental effects of energy use.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ENERGIE-Technologie-Abteilung des Berkeley Labors 
entwickelt KlimaTechnologie, die Energie leistungsfähiger und mit 
weniger Klimaauswirkung verwendet, umwandelt und speichert, und 
studiert das Link zwischen Energiegebrauch und der Umgebung. Ein
wichtiges Resultat seiner Arbeit ist die Entwicklung der Technologien 
und der Prozesse, zum der Umweltfolgen des Energiegebrauches 
abzuschwächen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Division de technologies environnementale de 
l'énergie du laboratoire de Berkeley développe la technologie qui 
utilise, convertit et enregistre l'énergie plus efficacement et avec 
moins d'incidences sur l'environnement, et étudie le lien entre 
l'utilisation d'énergie et l'environnement. Des résultats 
importants de son travail sont le développement des technologies et 
des processus pour atténuer les effets sur l'environnement de 
l'utilisation d'énergie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A divisão de tecnologias ambiental da energia do 
laboratório de Berkeley desenvolve a tecnologia que usa, converte e 
armazena a energia mais eficientemente e com menos impacto ambiental, 
e estuda a ligação entre o uso da energia e o ambiente. Um 
resultado importante de seu trabalho é o desenvolvimento das 
tecnologias e dos processos para mitigate os efeitos ambientais do uso
da energia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La sezione tecnica ambientale di energia del 
laboratorio del Berkeley sviluppa la tecnologia che usa, converte e 
memorizza l'energia più efficientemente e con meno impatto ambientale
e studia il collegamento fra uso di energia e l'ambiente. Un 
risultato importante del relativo lavoro è lo sviluppo delle 
tecnologie e dei processi per attenuare le conseguenze sull'ambiente 
di uso di energia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το περιβαλλοντικό τμήμα ενεργειακών τεχνολογιών του 
εργαστηρίου του Μπέρκλευ! αναπτύσσει την τεχνολογία που 
χρησιμοποιεί, μετατρέπει και καταχωρεί την ενέργεια 
αποτελεσματικότερα και με τη λιγότερη περιβαλλοντική επίδραση, και
μελετά τη σύνδεση μεταξύ της ενεργειακής χρήσης και του 
περιβάλλοντος. Μια σημαντική έκβαση της εργασίας της είναι 
η ανάπτυξη των τεχνολογιών και των διαδικασιών για να μετριάσει 
τις περιβαλλοντικές επιπτώσεις της ενεργειακής χρήσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La división tecnológica ambiental de la energía
del laboratorio de Berkeley desarrolla la tecnología que utiliza, 
convierte y salva energía más eficientemente y con menos 
consecuencias para el medio ambiente, y estudia la conexión entre el 
uso de la energía y el ambiente. Un resultado importante de su 
trabajo es el desarrollo de las tecnologías y de los procesos para 
atenuar los efectos ambientales del uso de la energía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201470</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104296</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/energized-learning</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
