<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104623</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104623</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087334</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Separate Peace: Alice Henry on Women and Unions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Unterschiedlicher Frieden: Alice Henry 
auf Frauen und Anschlüßen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Paix Séparée : Henry de Alice sur des 
femmes et des syndicats</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma Paz Separada: Henry de Alice em mulheres
e em uniões</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una Pace Separata: Henry della Alice sulle 
donne e sui sindacati</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια χωριστή ειρήνη: Θ*Αληθε Henry στις 
γυναίκες και τις Ενώσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Paz Separada: Henrio de Alicia en 
mujeres y uniones</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Women's Trade Union League (WTUL), established in 1903 by reformers seeking to combine the forces of trade unionism and feminism, faced particular obstacles when organizing women into unions. In this 1915 essay, published in  The Trade Union Woman , WTUL leader Alice Henry discussed some of those problems and advocated separate women's locals as a possible solution. Another important organizing problem, which Henry did not discuss, was the tension between the middle-class reformers of the WTUL and the working-class women they wanted to organize but sometimes viewed with condescension. Henry was an Australian journalist of pro-labor and anti-imperialist sympathies. In 1906, she immigrated to the U.S., joined the fight for suffrage, and became a leader of the WTUL. Although she started out sharing the racist views of many Australians (where a "White Australia" policy was widely accepted), her time in America led her to adopt more favorable views of African Americans and immigrants.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Gewerkschaft-Liga der Frauen (WTUL), 
hergestellt 1903 von den Reformern, die suchen, die Kräfte von 
Geschäftsunionism und von Feminismus zu kombinieren, stellte 
bestimmte Hindernisse gegenüber, als, Frauen in Anschlüße 
organisierend. In diesem Versuch 1915 veröffentlicht in der 
Gewerkschaft-Frau, behandelte WTUL Führer Alice Henry einige jener 
Probleme und befürwortete Einheimische der unterschiedlichen Frauen 
als mögliche Lösung. Ein anderes wichtiges organisierendes 
Problem, das Henry nicht behandelte, war die Spannkraft zwischen den 
MittelklasseReformern des WTUL und den Arbeiterklassefrauen, die 
sie organisieren wollten aber manchmal angesehen mit Herablassung. 
Henry war ein australischer Journalist von Pro-bearbeiten und 
Anti-Imperialist Sympathien. 1906 wanderte sie in die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN ein, verbunden dem Kampf für Stimmrecht und wurde
ein Führer des WTUL. Obgleich sie aus dem Teilen der 
rassistischen Ansichten vieler Australier begann (wo eine "weißes 
Australien" Politik weit angenommen wurde), führte ihre Zeit in 
Amerika sie, vorteilhaftere Ansichten der afrikanischen Amerikaner und
der Immigranten anzunehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La ligue du syndicat des femmes (WTUL), établie 
en 1903 par des réformateurs recherchant à combiner les forces du 
syndicalisme et du féminisme commerciaux, a fait face à des obstacles 
particuliers en organisant des femmes en syndicats. Dans cet 
essai 1915, édité dans la femme de syndicat, Henry de Alice du Chef 
de WTUL a discuté certains de ces problèmes et a préconisé les 
gens du pays des femmes séparées comme solution possible. Un 
autre problème d'organisation important, qu'Henry n'a pas discuté, 
était la tension entre les réformateurs de classe moyenne du WTUL et 
les femmes de classe ouvrière qu'ils ont voulu organiser mais parfois
visualisé avec la condescendance. Henry était un journaliste 
australien de pro-travaillent et des sympathies d'anti-impérialiste. 
En 1906, elle a immigré aux ETATS-UNIS, jointifs le combat pour
le suffrage, et est devenue une amorce du WTUL. Bien qu'elle ait
commencé hors de partager les opinions racistes de beaucoup 
d'Australiens (où une politique "de l'Australie blanche" a été 
largement reçue), son temps en Amérique l'a menée à adopter des 
vues plus favorables des Américains et des immigrés africains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A liga da união de comércio das mulheres (WTUL),
estabelecida em 1903 pelos reformers que procuram combinar as forças 
do unionism e do feminismo de comércio, enfrentou obstáculos 
particulares ao organizar mulheres em uniões. Neste essay 1915,
publicado na mulher da união de comércio, o Henry de Alice do líder
de WTUL discutiu alguns daqueles problemas e advogou locals das 
mulheres separadas como uma solução possível. Um outro 
problema organizando importante, que o Henry não discutisse, era a 
tensão entre os reformers do middle-class do WTUL e as mulheres que 
do working-class quis organizar mas visto às vezes com condescension.
O Henry era um journalist australian de pro-trabalha e 
sympathies do anti-anti-imperialist. Em 1906, immigrated aos 
ESTADOS UNIDOS, juntados a luta para o suffrage, e transformou-se um 
líder do WTUL. Embora começasse para fora de compartilhar das 
opiniões racist muitos australians (onde "uma política de Austrália
branca" foi aceitada extensamente), seu tempo em América conduziu-lhe
adotar umas opiniões mais favoráveis americanos e immigrants 
africanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lega del sindacato delle donne (WTUL), 
stabilita in 1903 dai reformers che cercano di unire le forze del 
unionism e del feminism commerciali, ha affrontato gli ostacoli 
particolari quando organizza le donne nei sindacati. In questo 
saggio 1915, pubblicato nella donna del sindacato, il henry della 
Alice del capo di WTUL ha discusso alcuni di quei problemi ed 
ha sostenuto i locals delle donne separate come soluzione possibile. 
Un altro problema d'organizzazione importante, che il henry non 
ha discusso, era il tensionamento fra i reformers della classe media 
del WTUL e le donne che della classe operaia hanno desiderato 
organizzare ma a volte osservato con condescension. Il henry era
un giornalista australiano di pro-lavoro e di compassione del 
anti-anti-imperialist. In 1906, immigrated negli STATI UNITI, 
uniti la lotta per suffrage ed è diventato un capo del WTUL. 
Anche se ha cominciato verso l'esterno la compartecipazione dei 
punti di vista razzisti di molti australiani (dove "una politica 
dell'Australia bianca" ampiamente è stata accettata), il suo tempo in
America la ha condotta adottare i punti di vista più favorevoli degli
Americani e degli immigranti africani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ένωση συνδικάτου των γυναικών (WTUL), που 
καθιερώθηκε το 1903 από την τους μεταρρυθμιστές που επιδιώκουν 
να συνδυάσει τις δυνάμεις του εμπορικών συνδικαλισμού και του 
φεμινισμού, αντιμετώπισε τα ιδιαίτερα εμπόδια κατά οργάνωση των 
γυναικών στις ενώσεις. Σε αυτό το δοκίμιο του 1915, που 
δημοσιεύθηκε στη γυναίκα συνδικάτου, WTUL ο ηγέτης Alice 
Henry συζήτησε μερικών από εκείνα τα προβλήματα και 
υποστήριξε τα locals των χωριστών γυναικών ως πιθανή λύση. 
Ένα άλλο σημαντικό πρόβλημα οργάνωσης, που Henry δεν 
συζήτησε, ήταν η ένταση μεταξύ των μεταρρυθμιστών μεσαίων 
τάξεων του WTUL και των γυναικών εργατικών τάξεων που θέλησαν 
να οργανώσουν αλλά μερικές φορές εμφάνισαν με τη συγκατάβαση. 
Θ*Χενρυ ήταν αυστραλιανός δημοσιογράφος των συμπονοιών 
υπέρ-εργασίας και αντι-ιμπεριαλιστών. Το 1906, 
μετανάστευσε στις ΗΠΑ, ένωσε την πάλη για την ψήφο, και έγινε 
ηγέτης του WTUL. Αν και άρχισε τις ρατσιστικές όψεις 
πολλών Αυστραλών (όπου μια πολιτική της "λευκιάς Αυστραλίασ" 
έγινε αποδεκτή ευρέως), ο χρόνος της στην Αμερική την οδήγησε 
για να υιοθετήσει περισσότερες ευνοϊκές όψεις αφρικανικών 
Αμερικανών και των μεταναστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La liga del sindicato de las mujeres (WTUL), 
establecida en 1903 por los reformadores que intentaban combinar las 
fuerzas del unionism y del feminismo comerciales, hizo frente a 
obstáculos determinados al ordenar a mujeres en uniones. En 
este ensayo 1915, publicado en la mujer del sindicato, el Henrio de 
Alicia del arranque de cinta de WTUL discutió algunos de esos 
problemas y abogó a locals de las mujeres separadas como solución 
posible. Otro problema de ordenación importante, que el Henrio 
no discutió, era la tensión entre los reformadores de la clase media 
del WTUL y las mujeres de la clase obrera que él deseó ordenar pero 
visto a veces con el condescension. El Henrio era periodista 
australiano de favorable-trabaja y condolencias del 
contra-imperialista. En 1906, ella immigrated a los ESTADOS 
UNIDOS, unidos la lucha para el sufragio, e hizo un arranque de cinta 
del WTUL. Aunque ella comenzó fuera de compartir las opiniones 
racist muchos australianos (donde una política de "Australia blanca" 
fue validada extensamente), su tiempo en América la condujo a adoptar
opiniones más favorables americanos e inmigrantes africanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087334</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104623</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-separate-peace-alice-henry-on-women-and-unions</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
