<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107083</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107083</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203585</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kamchatka: Siberia's Forbidden Wilderness</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kamchatka: Sibiriens Verbotene Wildnis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Kamtchatka : Le Désert Interdit de la 
Sibérie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Kamchatka: Região selvagem Proibida De 
Sibéria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Kamchatka: Selva Proibita a Della Siberia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Kamchatka: Απαγορευμένη αγριότητα της 
Σιβηρίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Kamchatka: Yermo Prohibido De Siberia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This "Living Edens" PBS site features the historical, biological, and geological wonders of the Kamchatka Peninsula. Many aspects of Kamchatka are explored within the topic headings: The ring of fire, Remote secret, Kamchatka creatures, Bountiful breed, and Bering Island. The site also provides links to additional web resources, a teacher resource page including lesson plans on Kamchatka's Valley of Geysers and salmon populations, other "Living Edens" programs, the PBS home page, and a link to purchase this program video.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses "lebendes Edens" PBS Situationsmerkmale die
historischen, biologischen und geologischen Wunder der Kamchatka 
Halbinsel. Viele Aspekte von Kamchatka werden innerhalb der 
Themakopftexte erforscht: Der Ring des Feuers, des 
Remotegeheimnisses, der Kamchatka Geschöpfe, der freigebigen Brut und
der Bering Insel. Die Site stellt auch Links zu den 
zusätzlichen Web-Betriebsmitteln, zu einem Lehrer Hilfsmittel, 
dasseite einschließlich Lektion auf Senke Kamchatkas der Geysire und 
der Lachsbevölkerungen plant, zu anderen "lebendes Edens" Programmen,
zum PBS Home Page und zu einem Link, diesen Programmbildschirm zu 
kaufen zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs de ce "d'Edens de vie" site de PBS les
merveilles historiques, biologiques, et géologiques de la péninsule 
de Kamtchatka. Beaucoup d'aspects du Kamtchatka sont explorés 
dans les entêtes de sujet : La boucle du feu, du secret à 
distance, des créatures du Kamtchatka, de la race bienfaisante, et de
l'île de Bering. Le site fournit également des liens aux 
ressources supplémentaires de Web, à un professeur que la page de 
ressource comprenant la leçon projette sur la vallée du Kamtchatka 
des geysers et des populations saumonées, à d'autres programmes 
"d'Edens de vie", au Home Page de PBS, et à un lien acheter ce vidéo
de programme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Características deste "local de PBS de Edens 
vivendo" as maravilhas históricas, biológicas, e geological da 
península de kamchatka. Muitos aspectos de Kamchatka são 
explorados dentro dos títulos do tópico: O anel do fogo, do 
segredo remoto, das criaturas de Kamchatka, da raça bountiful, e do 
console de Bering. O local fornece também as ligações aos 
recursos adicionais do Web, a um professor a página do recurso que 
including a lição planeia no vale de Kamchatka dos geysers e das 
populações salmon, a outros "programas de Edens vivendo", ao Home 
Page de PBS, e a uma ligação comprar este vídeo do programa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo "di Edens vivente" luogo
di PBS i wonders storici, biologici e geologici della penisola di 
kamchatka. Molte funzioni di Kamchatka sono esplorate 
all'interno delle intestazioni di soggetto: L'anello di fuoco, 
del segreto a distanza, delle creature del Kamchatka, della razza 
bountiful e dell'isola di Bering. Il luogo egualmente fornisce i
collegamenti alle risorse supplementari di Web, ad un insegnante la 
pagina delle risorse che compreso la lezione progetta sulla valle del 
Kamchatka dei geyser e delle popolazioni di color salmone, ad altri 
"programmi di Edens vivente", al Home Page di PBS e ad un collegamento
comprare questo video di programma.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή "διαβίωσης Edens" PBS 
χαρακτηρίζει τον ιστορικό, βιολογικός, και γεωλογικός αναρωτιέται
της kamchatka χερσονήσου. Πολλές πτυχές kamchatka 
εξερευνιούνται μέσα στους τίτλους θέματος: Το δαχτυλίδι της
πυρκαγιάς, του απομακρυσμένου μυστικού, kamchatka των 
πλασμάτων, της γενναιόδωρης φυλής, και bering του νησιού. 
Η περιοχή παρέχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με τα πρόσθετα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς Ιστού, μια σελίδα των στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς δασκάλων συμπεριλαμβανομένων των σχεδίων μαθήματος 
για kamchatka την κοιλάδα geysers και των πληθυσμών σολομών, 
άλλα προγράμματα "διαβίωση Edens", την αρχική σελίδα PBS, 
και μια σύνδεση για να αγοράσει αυτό το βίντεο προγράμματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de este de "Edens que vive" sitio
de PBS las maravillas históricas, biológicas, y geológicas de la 
península de kamchatka. Muchos aspectos de Kamchatka se 
exploran dentro de los títulos del asunto: El anillo del fuego,
del secreto alejado, de las criaturas de Kamchatka, de la casta 
generosa, y de la isla de Bering. El sitio también proporciona 
a conexiones a recursos adicionales del Web, a un profesor que la 
paginación del recurso incluyendo la lección planea en el valle de 
Kamchatka de géiseres y de poblaciones de color salmón, a otros 
programas de "Edens que vive", al Home Page de PBS, y a una conexión 
comprar este vídeo del programa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PBS ONLINE
FN:PBS ONLINE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SYSTEM
FN:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SYSTEM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203585</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107083</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/kamchatka-siberias-forbidden-wilderness</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
