<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106736</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106736</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086309</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Wove To-day": Elizabeth Fuller Grows Up in Rural Massachusetts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Spann Heute": Volleres Elizabeth 
wächst in landwirtschaftlichem Massachusetts auf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"J'ai tissé Aujourd'hui" : Elizabeth 
plus plein grandit dans le Massachusetts rural</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Teci Hoje": Elizabeth mais cheio cresce 
acima em Massachusetts rural</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ho tessuto Oggi": Elizabeth più pieno si 
sviluppa in su in Massachusetts rurale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"ύφανα σήμερα": Θ*Εληζαψετχ Fuller Grows 
Up στην αγροτική Μασαχουσέτη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Tejí Hoy": Elizabeth más lleno crece para
arriba en Massachusetts rural</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Farm households depended heavily on the work of women and children. At first children were assigned simple tasks; later they learned chores that were differentiated according to gender roles. In the 1790s, young unmarried women such as Elizabeth Fuller pursued work in the dairy or in home manufacturing along with their housework and garden tasks. Fuller lived in the central Massachusetts town of Princeton; her diary recorded her health, social activities, and any unusual events in her life. Mostly, she faced a regular round of household tasks such as making cheese or baking pies. She often washed, carded, and spun wool, since her most significant labor was the household textile production that provided most farm families with their clothing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bewirtschaften Sie Haushalte abhing schwer von der
Arbeit der Frauen und der Kinder. An den ersten Kindern wurden 
einfache Aufgaben zugewiesen; später erlernten sie Chores, die 
entsprechend Geschlechtrollen unterschieden wurden. Im 1790s, in
den jungen unverheiratet Frauen wie Elizabeth vollerer ausgeübter 
Arbeit in der Molkerei oder in der Hauptherstellung zusammen mit ihrer
Hausarbeit und Gartenaufgaben. Volleres gelebt in der zentralen 
Massachusetts Stadt von Princeton; ihr Tagebuch speicherte ihre 
Gesundheit, Sozialaktivitäten und alle ungewöhnlichen Fälle in 
ihrer Lebensdauer. Meistens stellte sie einen regelmäßigen 
Umlauf der Haushalt Aufgaben wie Bilden des Käses oder Backen der 
Torten gegenüber. Sie häufig wusch, kardierte und spann 
Wollen, da ihre bedeutendste Arbeit die Haushalt Textilproduktion war,
die die meisten Bauernhoffamilien mit ihrer Kleidung versah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cultivez les ménages a dépendu fortement du 
travail des femmes et des enfants. Aux premiers enfants ont 
été assignés simple charge ; plus tard ils ont 
appris les corvées qui ont été différenciées selon des rôles de 
genre. Dans le 1790s, les jeunes femmes célibataires telles 
qu'un plus plein travail poursuivi d'Elizabeth dans la laiterie ou 
à la fabrication à la maison avec les leurs travaux domestiques et 
jardin charge. Plus plein vécu dans la ville centrale
du Massachusetts de Princeton ; son agenda a enregistré sa 
santé, activités sociales, et tous les événements peu communs dans
sa vie. La plupart du temps, elle a fait face à un rond 
régulier de ménage charge comme faire le fromage ou faire 
des pâtés en croûte cuire au four. Elle a souvent lavé, a 
cardé, et a tourné des laines, puisque son travail plus significatif
était la production de textile de ménage qui a fourni à la plupart 
des familles de ferme leur habillement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cultive casas dependeu pesadamente do trabalho das
mulheres e das crianças. Em primeiras crianças foram 
atribuídos tarefas simples; mais tarde aprenderam os chores que
foram diferenciados de acordo com papéis do gender. No 1790s, 
nas mulheres solteiras novas tais como o trabalho perseguido mais 
cheio de Elizabeth na leiteria ou no manufacturing home junto com seus
housework e tarefas do jardim. Mais cheio vivido na cidade 
central de Massachusetts de Princeton; seu diário gravou suas 
saúde, atividades sociais, e todos os eventos incomuns em sua vida. 
Na maior parte, enfrentou um círculo regular de tarefas da casa
tais como fazer o queijo ou cozer tortas. Frequentemente lavou, 
carded, e girou lãs, desde que seu trabalho mais significativo era a 
produção de textile da casa que forneceu a maioria de famílias da 
fazenda com sua roupa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Coltivi le famiglie dipendeva pesante dal lavoro 
delle donne e dei bambini. Ai primi bambini sono stati assegnati
le mansioni semplici; più successivamente hanno imparato i 
chores che sono stati differenziati secondo i ruoli di genere. 
Nel 1790s, nelle donne celibi giovani quale il lavoro continuato
più completo di Elizabeth nella latteria o nel manufacturing 
domestico con le loro i lavori domestici e mansioni del giardino. 
Più pieno vivo nella città centrale del Massachusetts di 
Princeton; il suo diario ha registrato la sue salute, attività 
sociali e tutti gli eventi insoliti nella sua vita. 
Principalmente, ha affrontato un tondo normale delle mansioni 
della famiglia come fare il formaggio o cuocere le torte. Spesso
ha lavato, cardato ed ha filato le lane, poiché il suo lavoro 
più significativo era la produzione della tessile della famiglia che 
ha fornito alla maggior parte delle famiglie dell'azienda agricola i 
loro vestiti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αγροτικές οικογένειες εξαρτήθηκαν βαριά από την 
εργασία των γυναικών και των παιδιών. Στα πρώτα παιδιά 
ανατέθηκε τις απλές στοιχειώδεις εργασίες  αργότερα έμαθαν
τις μικροδουλειές που διαφοροποιήθηκαν σύμφωνα με τους ρόλους 
γένους. Στο 1790s, οι νέες ανύπανδρες γυναίκες όπως 
Elizabeth Fuller ακολούθησαν την εργασία στο γαλακτοκομείο ή
στη βασική κατασκευή μαζί με τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες τους 
οικιακών και κήπων. Πληρέστερος έζησε στην κεντρική πόλη 
της Μασαχουσέτης Princeton  το ημερολόγιό της κατέγραψε 
την υγεία, τις κοινωνικές δραστηριότητές της, και οποιαδήποτε 
ασυνήθιστα γεγονότα στη ζωή της. Συνήθως, αντιμετώπισε 
έναν κανονικό κύκλο των οικιακών στοιχειωδών εργασιών όπως η 
κατασκευή του τυριού ή το ψήσιμο των πιτών. Έπλυνε συχνά,
λανάρισε, και περιέστρεψε το μαλλί, δεδομένου ότι η 
σημαντικότερη εργασία της ήταν η οικιακή παραγωγή 
κλωστοϋφαντουργικών που παρείχε στις περισσότερες αγροτικές 
οικογένειες τον ιματισμό τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cultive las casas dependió pesadamente del 
trabajo de mujeres y de niños. En los primeros niños fueron 
asignados tareas simples; aprendieron más adelante las tareas 
que fueron distinguidas según papeles del género. En el 1790s,
las mujeres solteras jóvenes tales como trabajo perseguido más 
completo de Elizabeth en la lechería o en la fabricación casera 
junto con su el quehacer doméstico y tareas del jardín. Más 
lleno vivido en la ciudad central de Massachusetts de Princeton; 
su diario registró su salud, actividades sociales, y cualquier 
acontecimiento inusual en su vida. Sobre todo, ella hizo frente 
a un redondo regular de las tareas de la casa tales como fabricación 
del queso o cocer al horno las empanadas. Ella lavó, carded, e 
hizo girar a menudo las lanas, puesto que su trabajo más 
significativo era la producción del textil de la casa que proveió de
la mayoría de las familias de la granja su ropa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086309</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106736</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-wove-to-day-elizabeth-fuller-grows-up-in-rural-massachusetts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
