<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108012</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108012</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086977</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Last Days Remembered: A Compatriot Recalls the Deaths of Sacco and Vanzetti in 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Letzten Tage Erinnerten Sich: Ein 
Landsmann erinnert an die Todesfälle von Sacco und von Vanzetti 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Derniers Jours Se sont rappelés : Un 
compatriote rappelle les décès de Sacco et de Vanzetti en 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Últimos Dias Recordaram: Um compatriot 
recorda as mortes de Sacco e de Vanzetti em 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli Ultimi Giorni Ricordati di: Un 
compatriot ricorda le morti di Sacco e di Vanzetti in 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι τελευταίες ημέρες αναφερόμενες: Ένας 
συμπατριώτης υπενθυμίζει τους θανάτους Sacco και Vanzetti το 
1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Días Pasados Recordaron: Un compatriot 
recuerda las muertes de Sacco y de Vanzetti en 1927</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The emotional and highly publicized case of Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti became a touchstone and rallying cry for American radicals. In 1920 the two Italian immigrants were accused of murder and although the evidence against them was flimsy, they were readily convicted, in large part because they were immigrants and anarchists. They were executed, despite international protests, on August 23, 1927. Aldino Felicani, printer and publisher of the anarchist paper Controcorrente, was a long-time acquaintance of Sacco and Vanzetti; in 1920 he organized the Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Committee. In this interview with Dean Albertson, recorded in 1954, Felicani recalled his relationships with the accused men and his work on the defense committee. His story gave a sense of the emotion of the last days of Sacco and Vanzetti.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der emotionale und in hohem Grade publizierte 
Kasten von Nicola Sacco und von Bartolomeo Vanzetti wurde ein 
Prüfstein und Sammelnschrei für amerikanische Radikale. In
1920 wurden die zwei italienischen Immigranten vom Mord beschuldigt 
und obgleich der Beweis gegen sie schwach war, wurden sie 
betriebsbereit, im großen Teil überführt, weil sie Immigranten und 
Anarchisten waren. Sie wurden, trotz der internationalen 
Proteste, an August 23, 1927 durchgeführt. Aldino Felicani, 
Drucker und Verleger des Anarchisten tapezieren Controcorrente, waren 
eine langfristige Bekanntschaft von Sacco und von Vanzetti; 1920
organisierte er den Sacco-Vanzetti Schutzverband. In diesem 
Interview mit Dekan Albertson, gespeichert 1954, erinnerte an Felicani
seine Verhältnisse zu den beschuldigten Männern und seine Arbeit 
über den Schutzverband. Seine Geschichte gab eine Richtung des 
Gefühls der letzten Tage von Sacco und von Vanzetti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La caisse émotive et fortement annoncée de 
Nicola Sacco et de Bartolomeo Vanzetti est devenue une pierre de touche et 
cri de rassemblement pour les radicaux américains. Dans 1920 
les deux immigrés italiens ont été accusés du meurtre et bien que 
l'évidence contre eux ait été fragile, ils ont été aisément 
condamnés, dans la grande partie parce qu'ils étaient des immigrés 
et des anarchistes. On les a exécuté, en dépit des 
protestations internationales, 23 août 1927. Aldino Felicani, 
imprimante et éditeur de l'anarchiste empaquettent Controcorrente, 
étaient une connaissance à long terme de Sacco et de Vanzetti ; 
en 1920 il a organisé le comité de défense de Sacco-Vanzetti.
Dans cette entrevue avec doyen Albertson, enregistré en 1954, 
Felicani a rappelé ses rapports avec les hommes accusés et son 
travail sur le comité de défense. Son histoire a donné un 
sens de l'émotion des derniers jours de Sacco et de Vanzetti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A caixa emocional e altamente publicized de Nicola
Sacco e de Bartolomeo Vanzetti transformou-se um touchstone e grito 
rallying para radicais americanos. Em 1920 os dois immigrants 
italianos foram acusados do assassinato e embora a evidência de 
encontro a eles fosse frágil, convicted prontamente, na parte grande 
porque eram immigrants e anarquistas. Foram executados, apesar 
dos protestos internacionais, agosto em 23, 1927. Aldino 
Felicani, impressora e publisher do anarquista paper Controcorrente, 
era um conhecimento long-time de Sacco e de Vanzetti; em 1920 
organizou o comitê de defesa de Sacco-Vanzetti. Nesta 
entrevista com decano Albertson, gravado em 1954, Felicani recordou 
seus relacionamentos com os homens acusados e seu trabalho no comitê 
de defesa. Sua história deu um sentido da emoção dos últimos
dias de Sacco e de Vanzetti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La cassa impressionabile ed altamente divulg di 
Nicola Sacco e di Bartolomeo Vanzetti si è transformata in in un 
touchstone e radunandosi gridi per i radicali americani. 
In 1920 i due immigranti italiani sono stati accusati 
dell'omicidio ed anche se la prova contro di loro era fragile, sono 
stati condannati prontamente, nella grande parte perché erano 
immigranti ed anarchici. Sono stati eseguiti, malgrado le 
proteste internazionali, il 23 agosto 1927. Aldino Felicani, 
tipografo ed editore dell'anarchico incarta Controcorrente, era una 
conoscenza long-time di Sacco e di Vanzetti; in 1920 ha 
organizzato il comitato di difesa di Sacco-Vanzetti. In questa 
intervista con il decano Albertson, registrato in 1954, Felicani ha 
ricordato i suoi rapporti con gli uomini accusati ed il suo lavoro sul
comitato di difesa. La sua storia ha dato un senso dell'emozione
di ultimi giorni di Sacco e di Vanzetti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η συναισθηματική και ιδιαίτερα κοινοποιημένη περίπτωση
Nicola Sacco και του Bartolomeo Vanzetti έγινε μια 
κραυγή λύδιων λίθων και συνάθροισης για τους αμερικανικούς 
ριζοσπάστες. Το 1920 οι δύο ιταλικοί μετανάστες 
κατηγορήθηκαν για τη δολοφονία και αν και τα στοιχεία ενάντια σε 
τους ήταν ψιλά, καταδικάστηκαν εύκολα, στο μεγάλο μέρος επειδή 
ήταν μετανάστες και αναρχικοί. Εκτελέσθηκαν, παρά τις 
διεθνείς διαμαρτυρίες, στις 23 Αυγούστου, 1927, Aldino 
Felicani, εκτυπωτής και ο εκδότης του εγγράφου Controcorrente
αναρχικών, ήταν μια μακροπρόθεσμη εξοικείωση Sacco και 
Vanzetti  το 1920 οργάνωσε την αμυντική σαθθο- 
Vanzetti Επιτροπή. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη με το Dean 
Albertson, που καταγράφηκε το 1954, Felicani υπενθύμισε τις
σχέσεις του με τα κατηγορούμενα άτομα και την εργασία του για την 
αμυντική επιτροπή. Η ιστορία του έδωσε μια αίσθηση της 
συγκίνησης των τελευταίων ημερών Sacco και Vanzetti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La caja emocional y altamente publicada de Nicola 
Sacco y de Bartolomeo Vanzetti se convirtió en una piedra de toque y grito
de la reunión para los radicales americanos. En 1920 acusaron a
los dos inmigrantes italianos de asesinato y aunque la evidencia 
contra ellos era débil, los condenaron fácilmente, en parte grande 
porque eran inmigrantes y anarquistas. Los ejecutaron, a pesar 
de protestas internacionales, 23 de agosto de 1927. Aldino 
Felicani, impresora y editor del anarquista empapela Controcorrente, 
era un conocido de largo plazo de Sacco y de Vanzetti; en 1920 
él ordenó a comité de defensa de Sacco-Vanzetti. En esta 
entrevista con decano Albertson, registrado en 1954, Felicani recordó
sus lazos con los hombres acusados y su trabajo sobre el comité de 
defensa. Su historia dio un sentido de la emoción de los días 
pasados de Sacco y de Vanzetti.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086977</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108012</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-last-days-remembered-a-compatriot-recalls-the-deaths-of-sacco-and-vanzetti-in-1927</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
