<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103955</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103955</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086389</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ku Klux Klan Violence in Georgia, 1871</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ku Klux Klan Gewalttätigkeit in Georgia, 1871</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Violence de Ku Klux Klan en Géorgie, 1871</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Violência de Ku Klux Klan em Geórgia, 1871</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Violenza di Ku Klux Klan in Georgia, 1871</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βία Klux Klan Ku στη Γεωργία, 1871</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Violencia de Ku Klux Klan en Georgia, 1871</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Following the Civil War, the federal government brought newly freed people into the political and economic sphere through a variety of efforts known as Radical Reconstruction. But planters, unwilling to lose control over African-American laborers, attempted to rule the South through violence and legal and economic intimidation. The secret terrorist organization the Ku Klux Klan was part of the violent white reaction to Reconstruction. Founded by Confederate veterans in Tennessee in 1866, Klan nightriders targeted black veterans and freedmen who had left their employers and those who had succeeded in breaking out of the plantation system. African Americans who transgressed local norms of white supremacy were in particular danger as the testimony from Maria Carter and others at these 1871 Congressional hearings about the Klan made clear. Klan leaders often were prominent planters and their family members while poorer men made up the rank and file.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach dem Bürgerkrieg holte die Bundesregierung 
eben freigegebene Leute in den politischen und ökonomischen Bereich 
durch eine Vielzahl der Bemühungen, die als radikale Rekonstruktion 
bekannt sind. Aber Pflanzer, abgeneigt, Steuerung über den 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Arbeitern zu verlieren, versucht, um den 
Süden durch Gewalttätigkeit und zugelassene und ökonomische 
Einschüchterung anzuordnen. Die geheime Terroristorganisation 
das Ku Klux Klan war ein Teil der heftigen weißen Reaktion zur 
Rekonstruktion. Gegründet durch Confederate Veterane in 
Tennessee 1866, zielten Klan nightriders schwarze Veterane und 
Freedmen, die ihre Arbeitgeber gelassen hatten und die, die gefolgt 
hatten, mit, des Plantagesystems auszubrechen. Afrikanische 
Amerikaner, die lokale Normen der weißen Vorherrschaft waren 
insbesondere Gefahr als das Zeugnis von Maria Carter transgressed und 
andere an diesen 1871 Kongreßhörfähigkeiten über das Klan bildeten
klar. Klan Führer waren häufig vorstehende Pflanzer und ihre 
Familie Bauteile, während ärmere Männer die Truppe bildeten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après la guerre civile, le gouvernement fédéral
a introduit les personnes nouvellement libres dans la sphère 
politique et économique par une variété d'efforts connus sous le 
nom de reconstruction radicale. Mais planteurs, peu disposés à
détruire le contrôle des travailleurs afro-américains, essayés pour 
régner les Sud par la violence et l'intimidation légale et 
économique. L'organisation secrète de terroriste le Ku Klux 
Klan faisait partie de la réaction blanche violente à la 
reconstruction. Fondé par des vétérans de Confederate au 
Tennessee en 1866, les nightriders de Klan ont visé les vétérans 
noirs et les freedmen qui avaient laissé leurs employeurs et ceux qui
avaient réussis à l'éclatement du système de plantation. Les
Américains africains qui ont transgressé des normes locales de 
la suprématie blanche étaient en particulier danger comme témoignage
de Maria Charretier et d'autres à ces 1871 auditions 
congressionnelles au sujet du Klan ont fait clairement. Les 
amorces de Klan étaient souvent les planteurs en avant et leurs 
membres de famille tandis que de plus pauvres hommes composaient la 
troupe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Depois da guerra civil, o governo federal trouxe 
povos recentemente livrados na esfera política e econômica com uma 
variedade dos esforços sabidos como o reconstruction radical. 
Mas plantadores, unwilling perder o controle sobre os laborers 
Africano-Americanos, tentados governar o sul com a violência e a 
intimidação legal e econômica. A organização secreta do 
terrorista o Ku Klux Klan era parte da reação branca violenta ao 
reconstruction. Fundado por veterans de Confederado em Tennessee
em 1866, os nightriders de Klan alvejaram os veterans pretos e os 
freedmen que tinham deixado seus empregadores e os aqueles que tinham 
sucedido em quebrar fora do sistema da plantação. Os 
americanos africanos que transgressed normas locais do supremacy 
branco estavam no perigo particular como o testimony de Maria Carter e
outros nestes 1871 hearings congressionais sobre o Klan fizeram 
claramente. Os líderes de Klan eram frequentemente plantadores 
proeminentes e seus membros da família quando uns homens mais 
deficientes compuseram o Rank e a lima.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A seguito della guerra civile, il governo federale
ha introdotto la gente recentemente liberata nella sfera politica ed 
economica con una varietà di sforzi conosciuti come ricostruzione 
radicale. Ma piantatrici, poco disposte a perdere controllo 
sopra i lavoratori Africano-Americani, tentati per regolare il sud con
la violenza e l'intimidazione legale ed economica. 
L'organizzazione segreta del terrorista il Ku Klux Klan faceva 
parte della reazione bianca violenta a ricostruzione. Fondato 
dai veterani del Confederate nel Tennessee in 1866, i nightriders di 
Klan hanno designato i veterani neri ed i freedmen che avevano 
lasciato i loro datori di lavoro e coloro come bersaglio che era 
riuscito a scoppiare del sistema della piantagione. Gli 
Americani africani che transgressed le norme locali del supremacy 
bianco erano in particolare pericolo come la testimonianza da Maria 
Carter ed altri a queste 1871 udienza congressuale circa il Klan hanno
fatto chiaramente. I capi di Klan erano spesso 
piantatrici prominenti ed i loro membri della famiglia mentre i più 
poveri uomini hanno composto la truppa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο, η ομοσπονδιακή 
κυβέρνηση έφερε τους πρόσφατα ελευθερωμένους ανθρώπους στην 
πολιτική και οικονομική σφαίρα μέσω ποικίλων προσπαθειών 
γνωστών ως ριζική αναδημιουργία. Αλλά καλλιεργητές, 
απρόθυμοι να χάσουν τον έλεγχο των αφρικανικός-αμερικανικών 
laborers, που προσπαθείται για να κυβερνήσει το νότο μέσω της 
βίας και του νομικού και οικονομικού εκφοβισμού. Η μυστική 
τρομοκρατική οργάνωση το Ku Klux Klan ήταν μέρος της 
βίαιας άσπρης αντίδρασης στην αναδημιουργία. Ιδρυμένα από 
τους ομόσπονδους παλαιμάχους στο Tennessee το 1866, τα 
nightriders Klan στόχευσαν στους μαύρους παλαιμάχους και τους
απελευθέρους που είχαν αφήσει τους εργοδότες τους και εκείνους 
που είχαν πετύχει στο ξέσπασμα του συστήματος φυτειών. 
Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί που παραβίασαν τους τοπικούς κανόνες
της άσπρης υπεροχής ήταν στον ιδιαίτερο κίνδυνο ως κατάθεση από
τη Μαρία Carter και άλλοι σε αυτές τις 1871 του Κογκρέσου 
ακροάσεις για το Klan κατάστησαν σαφές. Οι ηγέτες Klan
ήταν συχνά προεξέχοντες καλλιεργητές και τα οικογενειακά μέλη 
τους ενώ τα φτωχότερα άτομα αποτέλεσαν τις μάζες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de la guerra civil, el gobierno federal 
trajo a gente nuevamente liberada en la esfera política y económica 
con una variedad de esfuerzos conocidos como reconstrucción radical. 
Pero plantadores, poco dispuestos perder control sobre los 
trabajadores Africano-Americanos, procurados para gobernar el sur con 
violencia y la intimidación legal y económica. La 
organización secreta del terrorista el Ku Klux Klan era parte de la 
reacción blanca violenta a la reconstrucción. Fundado por los 
veteranos de Confederate en Tennessee en 1866, los nightriders de Klan
apuntaron a los veteranos negros y a los freedmen que habían dejado a
sus patrones y a los que habían tenido éxito en explotar del sistema
de la plantación. Los americanos africanos que transgressed 
normas locales de la supremacía blanca estaban en peligro determinado 
como el testimonio de Maria Carretero y otros en estas 1871 audiencias
del congreso sobre el Klan hicieron claramente. Los arranques de
cinta de Klan eran a menudo plantadores prominentes y sus miembros de 
la familia mientras que hombres más pobres compusieron a tropa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086389</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103955</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/ku-klux-klan-violence-in-georgia-1871</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
