<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108429</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108429</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202701</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Investigating evaporation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachforschende Verdampfung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Évaporation d'investigation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Evaporação investigando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Evaporazione di studio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξάτμιση έρευνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Evaporación que investiga</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students will investigate evaporation as a cooling process. They will witness that temperature is affected by moisture content and the process of evaporation. Next, they will explore websites related to the processes of evaporation and condensation. Students will apply gained knowledge to real-life situations, and will share their new knowledge with a person outside the classroom.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer forschen Verdampfung als 
abkühlender Prozeß nach. Sie zeugen, daß Temperatur durch 
Feuchtigkeitsgehalt und den Prozeß der Verdampfung beeinflußt wird. 
Zunächst erforschen sie die Web site, die auf den Prozessen der
Verdampfung und der Kondensation in Verbindung gestanden werden. 
Kursteilnehmer wenden gewonnenes Wissen an den real-life 
Situationen an und teilen ihre Neuerkenntnis mit einer Person 
außerhalb des Klassenzimmers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants étudieront l'évaporation comme 
processus de refroidissement. Ils seront témoin que la 
température est affectée par la teneur en humidité et le processus 
de l'évaporation. Ensuite, ils exploreront des sites Web liés 
aux processus de l'évaporation et de la condensation. Les 
étudiants s'appliqueront la connaissance gagnée aux situations 
réelles, et partageront leurs nouvelles connaissances avec une 
personne en dehors de la salle de classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes investigarão a evaporação como um
processo refrigerando. Testemunharão que a temperatura está 
afetada pelo índice de umidade e pelo processo da evaporação. 
Em seguida, explorarão os Web site relacionados aos processos 
da evaporação e da condensação. Os estudantes aplicarão o 
conhecimento ganho às situações real-life, e compartilharão de seu
conhecimento novo com uma pessoa fora da sala de aula.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi studieranno l'evaporazione come 
processo di raffreddamento. Testimonieranno che la temperatura 
è influenzata tramite il tenore d'acqua ed il processo di 
evaporazione. Dopo, esploreranno i Web site relativi ai processi
di evaporazione e di condensazione. Gli allievi applicheranno la
conoscenza guadagnata alle situazioni in vivo e ripartiranno la loro 
conoscenza nuova con una persona fuori dell'aula.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα ερευνήσουν την εξάτμιση ως διαδικασία
ψύξης. Θα βεβαιώσουν ότι η θερμοκρασία επηρεάζεται με την 
περιεκτικότητα σε υγρασία και τη διαδικασία της εξάτμισης. 
Έπειτα, θα ερευνήσουν τους ιστοχώρους σχετικούς με τις 
διαδικασίες της εξάτμισης και της συμπύκνωσης. Οι σπουδαστές
θα εφαρμόσουν την αποκτημένη γνώση στις πραγματικές καταστάσεις, 
και θα μοιραστούν τη νέα γνώση τους με ένα πρόσωπο έξω από την 
τάξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes investigarán la evaporación como
proceso que se refresca. Atestiguarán que la temperatura es 
afectada por el contenido de agua y el proceso de la evaporación. 
Después, explorarán los Web site relacionados con los procesos
de la evaporación y de la condensación. Los estudiantes 
aplicarán conocimiento ganado a las situaciones de la vida real, y 
compartirán su nuevo conocimiento con una persona fuera de la sala de
clase.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JESSICA BOHN
FN:JESSICA BOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202701</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108429</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/investigating-evaporation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
