<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103742</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103742</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207063</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Whitman Mission National Historic Site -- The Learning Place</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Whitman Mission Nationale Historische Site -- Der 
Erlernenplatz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Site Historique National de Mission de Whitman -- 
l'Endroit D'Étude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Local Historic Nacional Da Missão De Whitman -- O 
Lugar De Aprendizagem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luogo Storico Nazionale Di Missione Di Whitman -- 
Il Posto Imparante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ιστορική περιοχή αποστολής Whitman -- η 
θέση εκμάθησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sitio Histórico Nacional De la Misión De Whitman 
-- El Lugar Que aprende</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers a teaching guide about the mission of Marcus and Narcissa Whitman at Waiilatpu, an important way station in the early days of the Oregon Trail. The Whitmans labored to bring Christianity to the Cayuse, but deep cultural differences and a measles epidemic led to violence in which the Cayuse killed the Whitmans and 11 others in November, 1847. The park preserves the site of Whitman's buildings and Mill Pond, a short segment of the Oregon Trail, and the grave where the victims are buried.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet eine unterrichtende Anleitung über die 
Mission von Marcus und von Narcissa Whitman bei Waiilatpu, eine 
wichtige Methode Station an den frühen Tagen der Oregon Spur an. 
Das Whitmans bearbeitete, um Christentum zu holen dem Cayuse, 
aber tiefe kulturelle Unterschiede und eine Masernepidemie führten zu
Gewalttätigkeit, in der das Cayuse das Whitmans und 11 andere im 
November, 1847 beendete. Der Park konserviert die Site von 
Gebäuden Whitmans und von Tausendstel-Teich, ein kurzes Segment der 
Oregon Spur und das Grab, in dem die Opfer begraben werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre un guide d'enseignement au sujet de la 
mission de Marcus et de Narcissa Whitman chez Waiilatpu, une station 
importante de voie en jours tôt de la traînée de l'Orégon. 
Le Whitmans a travaillé pour apporter le christianisme au 
Cayuse, mais les différences culturelles profondes et une épidémie 
de rougeole ont mené à la violence dans laquelle le Cayuse a 
détruit le Whitmans et 11 autres en novembre, 1847. Le parc 
préserve le site des bâtiments de Whitman et de l'étang de moulin, 
un segment court de la traînée de l'Orégon, et la tombe où les 
victimes sont enterrées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece uma guia ensinando sobre a missão de 
Marcus e de Narcissa Whitman em Waiilatpu, uma estação importante da
maneira nos dias adiantados da fuga de Oregon. O Whitmans 
trabalhou para trazer o christianity ao Cayuse, mas as diferenças 
cultural profundas e uma epidemia do sarampo conduziram à violência 
em que o Cayuse matou o Whitmans e 11 outros em novembro, 1847. 
O parque preserva o local de edifícios de Whitman e de lagoa do
moinho, um segmento curto da fuga de Oregon, e a sepultura onde as 
vítimas são enterradas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre una guida d'istruzione circa la missione di 
Marcus e di Narcissa Whitman a Waiilatpu, una stazione importante di 
modo nei giorni in anticipo della traccia dell'Oregon. Il 
Whitmans ha lavorato per portare il christianity al Cayuse, ma le 
differenze culturali profonde e un'epidemia di morbillo hanno condotto
alla violenza in cui il Cayuse ha ucciso il Whitmans e 11 altro in 
novembre, del 1847. Il parco conserva il luogo degli edifici del
Whitman e dello stagno del laminatoio, un segmento corto della traccia
dell'Oregon e la tomba in cui le vittime sono sepolte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει έναν οδηγό διδασκαλίας για την αποστολή του
Marcus και Narcissa Whitman σε Waiilatpu, ένας 
σημαντικός σταθμός τρόπων τις πρώτες ημέρες του ίχνους του 
Όρεγκον. Το Whitmans εργάστηκε για να φέρει το 
χριστιανισμό στο Cayuse, αλλά οι βαθιές πολιτιστικές διαφορές 
και μια επιδημία ιλαράς οδήγησαν στη βία στην οποία το Cayuse 
σκότωσε το Whitmans και 11 άλλα το Νοέμβριο, 1847. 
Το πάρκο συντηρεί την περιοχή των κτηρίων Whitman και της
λίμνης μύλων, ένα σύντομο τμήμα μνήμης του ίχνους του Όρεγκον,
και τον τάφο όπου τα θύματα θάβονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece a guía de enseñanza sobre la misión de 
Marcus y de Narcissa Whitman en Waiilatpu, una estación importante de
la manera en los días tempranos del rastro de Oregon. El 
Whitmans trabajó para traer cristianismo al Cayuse, pero las 
diferencias culturales profundas y una epidemia del sarampión 
condujeron a la violencia en la cual el Cayuse mató al Whitmans y a 
11 otros en noviembre de 1847. El parque preserva el sitio de 
los edificios de Whitman y de la charca del molino, un segmento corto 
del rastro de Oregon, y el sepulcro donde entierran a las víctimas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207063</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103742</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/whitman-mission-national-historic-site-the-learning-place</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
