<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103109</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103109</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086946</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Great Meeting of Foreigners in the Park."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die große Sitzung der Ausländer im Park."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la grande réunion des Étrangers en parc."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a reunião grande dos estrangeiros no parque."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la riunione grande degli stranieri nel parco."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η μεγάλη συνεδρίαση των αλλοδαπών στο πάρκο."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la gran reunión de extranjeros en el parque."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This illustration from an 1855 publication,  The Crisis; or, the Enemies of America Unmasked , depicted a labor demonstration in New York's City Hall Park demanding relief for the unemployed during the 1854-55 panic. Both Germans and Irish took part in the demonstration. The  Crisis 's presentation of "foreign" labor demonstraters was meant to alarm readers who shared its "nativist," anti-immigrant position. This wood engraving was one of the few images of organized working-class action published before the Civil War.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Abbildung von einer 1855 Publikation, die Krise; 
oder, die Feinde von Amerika Unmasked, stellten eine 
Arbeitsdemonstration in fordernder Entlastung des Parks Hall New York 
City für die Arbeitslosen während der Panik 1854-55 bildlich dar. 
nahmen Deutsche und Iren an der Demonstration teil. Die 
Krise ' s Darstellung "der fremden" Arbeitsdemonstraters wurde 
bedeutet, um Leser zu alarmieren, die seinen "Nativist teilten," 
Anti-Immigrant Position. Dieser hölzerne Stich war eins der 
wenigen Bilder der organisierten Arbeiterklassetätigkeit, die vor dem
Bürgerkrieg veröffentlicht wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette illustration 1855 d'une publication, la crise ; 
ou, les ennemis de l'Amérique Démasqués, ont dépeint 
une démonstration de travail dans le soulagement exigeant de parc de 
Hall de New York City pour les chômeurs pendant la panique 1854-55. 
Les Allemands et l'Irlandais ont participé à la 
démonstration. La crise 'présentation de s des demonstraters 
de travail "étrangers" a été censée pour alarmer les lecteurs qui 
ont partagé son "nativiste," position d'anti-immigré. Cette 
gravure du bois était l'une des quelques images de l'action 
organisée de classe ouvrier éditée avant la guerre civile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta ilustração 1855 de uma publicação, a crise; 
ou, os inimigos de América unmasked, descreveram uma 
demonstração labor no relevo exijindo do parque de Salão de New 
York City para os desempregados durante o pânico 1854-55. os 
alemães e o irish fizeram exame da parte na demonstração. A 
crise ' apresentação de s de demonstraters labor "extrangeiros" foi 
significada alarmar os leitores que compartilharam de seu "nativist," 
posição do anti-anti-immigrant. Este engraving de madeira era 
uma de poucas imagens da ação organizada do working-class publicada 
antes da guerra civil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa illustrazione 1855 da una pubblicazione, la crisi; 
o, i nemici dell'America unmasked, hanno descritto una 
dimostrazione di lavoro nel rilievo esigente del parco del Corridoio
de New York City per i disoccupati durante il panico 1854-55. 
Sia i tedeschi che l'Irlandese hanno partecipato alla 
dimostrazione. La crisi 'presentazione di s dei demonstraters 
di lavoro "stranieri" è stata significata per allarmare i lettori 
che hanno ripartito il relativo "nativist," posizione 
dell'anti-immigrante. Questa incisione del legno era una delle 
poche immagini di azione organizzata della classe operaia pubblicata 
prima della guerra civile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η απεικόνιση από μια 1855 δημοσίευση, η κρίση
ή, οι εχθροί της Αμερικής που αποκαλύφθηκαν, απεικόνισαν 
μια επίδειξη εργασίας στην απαιτητική ανακούφιση πάρκων αιθουσών
πόλεων της Νέας Υόρκης για τους ανέργους κατά τη διάρκεια του 
πανικού 1854-55. Και Γερμανοί και Ιρλανδοί συμμετείχαν 
στην επίδειξη. Η παρουσίαση κρίσης "s των" ξένων 
"demonstraters εργασίας προορίστηκε να ανησυχήσει τους 
αναγνώστες που μοιράστηκαν" το nativist του, "αντι-που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει θέση. Αυτή η ξύλινη χάραξη ήταν μια από τις
λίγες εικόνες της οργανωμένης ενέργειας εργατικών τάξεων που 
δημοσιεύθηκε πριν από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta ilustración 1855 de una publicación, la crisis; 
o, los enemigos de América desenmascarados, representaron una 
demostración de trabajo en la relevación exigente del parque de 
Pasillo de New York City para los parados durante el pánico 1854-55. 
Los alemanes y el irlandés participaron en la demostración. 
La crisis ' presentación de s de demonstraters de trabajo "no 
nativos" fue significada para alarmar a los programas de lectura que 
compartieron a su "nativista," posición del contra-inmigrante. 
Este grabado de madera era una de las pocas imágenes de la 
acción ordenada de la clase obrera publicada antes de la guerra 
civil.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086946</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103109</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-great-meeting-of-foreigners-in-the-park</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
