<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107064</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107064</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086662</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Nikos Valence on Organizing Against the North American Free Trade Agreement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nikos Wertigkeit auf dem Organisieren gegen den 
nordamerikanischen Freihandelsvertrag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Valence de Nikos sur organiser contre l'accord de 
libre-échange américain du nord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Valence de Nikos em organizar de encontro ao acordo
de comércio livre norte-americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Valenza di Nikos sull'organizzazione contro 
l'accordo di scambio libero nordamericano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νίκος Valence στην οργάνωση ενάντια στη 
βορειοαμερικανική συμφωνία ελευθεροποίησης των συναλλαγών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Valencia de Nikos en la ordenación contra el 
acuerdo de libre cambio norteamericano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the 1980's and 1990's international free trade agreements encouraged by the United States government increased the power and global reach of multinational corporations. The most controversial of these agreements, the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA), made it easier for U.S. companies to buy low cost goods from Mexico, which were often produced by U.S. subsidiaries that migrated to take advantage of low-cost labor. Organized labor and most liberal Democrats opposed NAFTA because they feared the loss of American jobs and the increased bargaining power of corporations who could easily transfer production overseas. As Nikos Valence, head of the Fair Trade Campaign, explained, these agreements also stimulated international labor solidarity, as workers in different countries struggled against the free reign of capital and in many cases against the same corporations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während der achtziger Jahre und neunziger Jahre 
internationalen Freihandelsverträge, die durch die Vereinigte Staaten
Regierung angeregt wurden, erhöhte die Energie und die globale 
Reichweite von multinationalen Konzernen. Das umstrittenste 
dieser Vereinbarungen, der nordamerikanische Freihandelsvertrag 
(NAFTA), gebildet es einfacher, damit VEREINIGTE STAATEN Firmen Waren 
der niedrigen Kosten von Mexiko kaufen, die häufig durch VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Tochtergesellschaften produziert wurden, die fortzogen, um 
Nutzen aus preiswerter Arbeit zu ziehen. Organisierte Arbeit und
die meisten liberalen Demokraten setzten NAFTA entgegen, weil sie den 
Verlust der amerikanischen Jobs und der erhöhten Verhandlungsstärke 
der Korporationen fürchteten, die Produktion leicht übersee 
übertragen konnten. Als Nikos Wertigkeit regte der Kopf der 
angemessenen Geschäftskampagne, erklärt, diese Vereinbarungen auch 
internationale Arbeitssolidarität an, da Arbeiter in den 
unterschiedlichen Ländern gegen die freie Herrschaft des Kapitals und
in vielen Fällen gegen die gleichen Korporationen kämpften.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant les accords de libre-échange 
internationaux des années 80 et des années 90 encouragés par le 
gouvernement des Etats-Unis a augmenté la puissance et l'extension 
globale des sociétés multinationales multinationales. Le plus 
controversé de ces accords, l'accord de libre-échange américain 
du nord (NAFTA), fait lui plus facile pour des compagnies des 
ETATS-UNIS d'acheter des marchandises à prix réduit du Mexique, qui 
ont été souvent produites par les filiales des ETATS-UNIS qui ont 
passé pour tirer profit du travail peu coûteux. Le travail 
organisé et la plupart des démocrates libéraux se sont opposés à 
NAFTA parce qu'ils ont craint la perte des travaux américains et du 
plus grand pouvoir de négociation des sociétés qui pourraient 
facilement transférer la production outre-mer. Comme valence de
Nikos, la tête de la campagne commerciale juste, expliquée, ces 
accords a également stimulé la solidarité de travail 
internationale, car les ouvriers dans différents pays ont lutté 
contre le règne libre du capital et dans beaucoup de cas contre les 
mêmes sociétés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante os acordos de comércio livres 
internacionais dos 1980's e dos 1990's incentivados pelo governo unido
dos estados aumentou a potência e o alcance global de corporation 
multinacionais. O mais controverso destes acordos, o acordo de 
comércio livre norte-americano (NAFTA), feito lhe mais fácil para 
que as companhias de ESTADOS UNIDOS comprem os bens do custo baixo de 
México, que foram produzidos frequentemente pelas subsidiárias de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS que migraram para fazer exame da vantagem do trabalho 
low-cost. O trabalho organizado e a maioria de democratas 
liberais opuseram NAFTA porque temeu a perda de trabalhos americanos e
da potência negociando aumentada dos corporation que poderiam 
fàcilmente transferir a produção no ultramar. Como o valence 
de Nikos, a cabeça da campanha de comércio justa, explicada, estes 
acordos estimulou também o solidarity labor internacional, porque os 
trabalhadores em países diferentes se esforçaram de encontro ao 
reino livre do capital e em muitos argumentos de encontro aos mesmos 
corporation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante gli anni 80 e gli anni 90 che gli accordi 
di libero scambio internazionali consigliati a dal unito 
Dichiara il governo ha aumentato l'potenza e l'estensione 
globale delle società multinazionali. Il più discutibile di 
questi accordi, l'accordo di libero scambio nordamericano (NAFTA), 
reso esso più facile affinchè aziende degli STATI UNITI comprino le 
merci di basso costo dal Messico, che sono state prodotte spesso dalle
filiali degli STATI UNITI che hanno migrato per approfittare del 
lavoro a basso costo. Il lavoro organizzato e la 
maggior parte delle carbossimetilazioni liberali hanno opposto NAFTA 
perché hanno temuto la perdita dei lavori americani e del potere 
contrattuale aumentato delle società che potrebbero trasferire 
facilmente la produzione oltremare. Come valenza di Nikos, la 
testa della campagna commerciale giusta, spiegata, questi accordi 
egualmente ha stimolato la solidarietà di lavoro internazionale, 
poichè gli operai in paesi differenti hanno lottato contro il 
regno libero di capitale ed in molti casi contro le stesse 
società.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια των διεθνών συμφωνιών 
ελευθεροποίησης των συναλλαγών της δεκαετίας του '80 και της 
δεκαετίας του '90 που ενθαρρύνθηκαν από τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες η 
κυβέρνηση αύξησε τη δύναμη και παγκόσμια προσιτότητα των 
πολυεθνικών εταιριών. Ο πιό αμφισβητούμενος αυτών των 
συμφωνιών, η βορειοαμερικανική συμφωνία ελευθεροποίησης των 
συναλλαγών (BAZES), το κατέστησε ευκολότερο για τις 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΈΣ επιχειρήσεις να αγοράσουν τα αγαθά χαμηλότερου 
κόστους από το Μεξικό, τα οποία παρήχθησαν συχνά από τις 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΈΣ θυγατρικές που μετανάστευσαν για να εκμεταλλευθούν τη
χαμηλού κόστους εργασία. Η οργανωμένη εργασία και οι 
περισσότεροι φιλελεύθεροι δημοκράτες αντέταξαν τη BAZES επειδή
αυτοί φοβισμένοι η απώλεια αμερικανικών εργασιών και η 
αυξανόμενη διαπραγματευτική δύναμη των εταιριών που θα μπορούσαν 
εύκολα να μεταφέρουν την παραγωγή στο εξωτερικό. Σαν Νίκος 
Valence, ο προϊστάμενος της δίκαιης εμπορικής εκστρατείας, 
εξήγησε, αυτές οι συμφωνίες υποκίνησαν επίσης τη διεθνή 
αλληλεγγύη εργασίας, όπως οι εργαζόμενοι στις διαφορετικές χώρες
κατά του ελεύθερου βασιλεύουν του κεφαλαίου και σε πολλές 
περιπτώσεις ενάντια στις ίδιες εταιρίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante los acuerdos de libre cambio 
internacionales de los años 80 y de los años 90 alentadores por el 
gobierno de Estados Unidos aumentó la potencia y el alcance global de
corporaciones multinacionales. El más polémico de estos 
acuerdos, el acuerdo de libre cambio norteamericano (NAFTA), hecho le 
más fácil para que compañías de ESTADOS UNIDOS compren las 
mercancías del bajo costo de México, que fueron producidas a menudo 
por los subsidiarios de ESTADOS UNIDOS que emigraron para aprovecharse
del trabajo barato. El trabajo ordenado y la mayoría de los 
demócratas liberales opusieron NAFTA porque temieron la pérdida de 
trabajos americanos y de la potencia que estipulaba creciente de las 
corporaciones que podrían transferir fácilmente la producción en 
ultramar. Como valencia de Nikos, el jefe de la campaña 
comercial justa, explicado, estos acuerdos también estimuló 
solidaridad de trabajo internacional, pues los trabajadores en 
diversos países lucharon contra el reinado libre del capital y en 
muchos casos contra las mismas corporaciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086662</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107064</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/nikos-valence-on-organizing-against-the-north-american-free-trade-agreement</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
