<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103849</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103849</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211419</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">On the Road Again</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf der Straße wieder</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sur la route encore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na estrada outra vez</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sulla strada ancora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο δρόμο πάλι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el camino otra vez</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The movement of people and goods is an important part of the New York State Global History and Geography Curriculum. It is listed as one of the themes that are emphasized in the core curriculum. Students are expected to understand why people migrate and what the impact of migrations has been on people, nations, and regions. Recently, the PBS WIDE ANGLE documentary series created two programs that relate to the movement of people. 'Border Jumpers' (2005) documents migration between countries in Africa, and 'To Have and Have Not' (2002) deals with migration from rural to urban areas in China. By studying these two migrations, students can deepen their understanding of events and trends in Africa and China since World War II. A study of these two migrations can also provide students with a framework for reviewing other migrations included in the core curriculum and help students to prepare for possible thematic essays on the Regents exam. The purpose of this lesson is to show the reasons why people are migrating in Africa and China today and how these migrations are impacting those regions. In addition, students will be motivated to critically analyze national immigration policies and to consider the relevance of national borders in a world that is experiencing rapid globalization. As a culminating activity, students will outline a response for a sample Regents thematic essay question and will be assigned to write the essay for homework. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Bewegung der Leute und der Waren ist ein 
wichtiges Teil des Staat- New-Yorkglobalen Geschichte und 
Geographie-Lehrplans. Sie wird als eins der Themen ausgedruckt, 
die im Kernlehrplan hervorgehoben werden. Kursteilnehmer werden 
erwartet, zu verstehen, warum Leute fortziehen und was die Auswirkung 
von Migrationen auf Leuten, Nationen und Regionen gewesen ist. 
Vor kurzem erstellte die PBS dokumentarische Weitwinkelserie 
zwei Programme, die auf der Bewegung der Leute in Verbindung stehen. 
' fassen Sie (2005) Dokumentmigration der Überbrücker zwischen
Ländern in Afrika ein, und ' zu haben und zu haben nicht ' (2002) 
beschäftigt Migration von landwirtschaftlichem zu den städtischen 
Bereichen in China. Indem sie diese zwei Migrationen studieren, 
können Kursteilnehmer ihr Verständnis von Fällen und von Tendenzen 
in Afrika und in China seit dem Zweiten Weltkrieg vertiefen. 
Eine Studie dieser zwei Migrationen kann Kursteilnehmer mit 
einem Rahmen für das Wiederholen anderer Migrationen auch versehen, 
die im Kernlehrplan eingeschlossen sind und Kursteilnehmern helfen, 
sich für mögliche thematische Versuche auf der Regents Prüfung 
vorzubereiten. Der Zweck dieser Lektion ist, den Gründen zu 
zeigen, warum Leute in Afrika und in China heute fortziehen und wie 
diese Migrationen jene Regionen auswirken. Zusätzlich werden 
Kursteilnehmer, um nationale Immigrationpolitik kritisch zu 
analysieren motiviert und die Bedeutung der nationalen Ränder in 
einer Welt zu betrachten, die schnelle Globalisierung erfährt. 
Als kulminierende Aktivität umreißen Kursteilnehmer eine 
Antwort für eine Beispielregents thematische Versuchfrage und werden 
zugewiesen, um den Versuch für Heimarbeit zu schreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La circulation des personnes et des marchandises 
est une partie importante du programme d'études global d'histoire et 
de géographie de l'état de New-York. Elle est énumérée en 
tant qu'un des thèmes qui sont soulignés dans le programme d'études
de noyau. On s'attend à ce que des étudiants comprennent 
pourquoi les gens passent et ce qu'a été l'impact des transferts sur
des personnes, des nations, et des régions. Récemment, la 
série documentaire GRANDE-ANGULAIRE de PBS a créé deux programmes 
qui associent au mouvement des personnes. 'encadrez 2005) 
transferts des documents des cavaliers (entre les pays en Afrique, et 
'pour avoir et le Démuni '(2002) traite le transfert de rural aux
zones urbaines en Chine. En étudiant ces deux transferts, les 
étudiants peuvent approfondir leur arrangement des événements et 
des tendances en Afrique et en Chine depuis la deuxième guerre 
mondiale. Une étude de ces deux transferts peut également 
fournir à des étudiants un cadre pour passer en revue d'autres 
transferts inclus dans le programme d'études de noyau et aider des 
étudiants à se préparer aux essais thématiques possibles sur 
l'examen de Régents. Le but de cette leçon est de montrer 
aux raisons pour lesquelles les gens passent en Afrique et en Chine 
aujourd'hui et comment ces transferts effectuent ces régions. 
En outre, des étudiants seront motivés pour analyser en 
critique des politiques nationales d'immigration et pour considérer 
la pertinence des cadres nationaux dans un monde qui éprouve la 
globalisation rapide. Comme activité culminante, les étudiants
traceront les grandes lignes d'une réponse pour une question 
thématique d'essai de Régents témoin et seront assignés pour 
écrire l'essai pour le travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento dos povos e dos bens é uma parte 
importante do curriculum global do history e da geografia do estado de
New York. É alistado como um dos temas que são emfatizados no 
curriculum do núcleo. Os estudantes esperam-se compreender 
porque os povos migram e o que o impacto das migrações foi em povos,
em nações, e em regiões. Recentemente, a série documentary 
do ÂNGULO LARGO de PBS criou dois programas que se relacionam ao 
movimento dos povos. ' limite migrações dos originais das 
ligações em ponte (2005) entre países em África, e ' para ter e 
ter não ' (2002) trata da migração de rural às áreas urbanas em 
China. Estudando estas duas migrações, os estudantes podem 
aprofundar sua compreensão dos eventos e das tendências em África e
em China desde a segunda guerra mundial. Um estudo destas duas 
migrações pode também fornecer estudantes com uma estrutura para 
rever outras migrações incluídas no curriculum do núcleo e ajudar 
a estudantes preparar-se para essays thematic possíveis no exam de 
Regents. A finalidade desta lição é mostrar às razões 
porque os povos estão migrando em África e em China hoje e como 
estas migrações estão impactando aquelas regiões. Além, os 
estudantes motivated para analisar crìticamente políticas nacionais 
do immigration e para considerar a relevância de beiras nacionais em 
um mundo que esteja experimentando o globalization rápido. Como
uma atividade culminando, os estudantes esboçarão uma resposta para 
uma pergunta thematic do essay de Regents da amostra e serão 
atribuídos para escrever o essay para o homework.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento della gente e delle merci è una 
parte importante di New York Dichiara il programma di studi 
globale di geografia e di storia. È elencato come uno dei temi 
che sono dati risalto a nel programma di studi di nucleo. Gli 
allievi si pensano che capiscano perchè la gente migra e che cosa 
l'effetto delle espansioni è stato sulla gente, sulle nazioni e sulle
regioni. Recentemente, la serie documentaria GRANDANGOLARE di 
PBS ha creato due programmi che si riferiscono al movimento della 
gente. 'border 2005) espansioni dei documenti dei ponticelli 
(fra i paesi in Africa e 'avere ed avere non '(2002) si occupa di 
espansione da rurale alle aree urbane in Cina. Studiando queste 
due espansioni, gli allievi possono approfondire la loro comprensione 
degli eventi e delle tendenze in Africa ed in Cina dalla seconda 
guerra mondiale. Uno studio su queste due espansioni può anche 
fornire agli allievi una struttura per la riesaminazione delle altre 
espansioni allegate al programma di studi di nucleo ed aiutare gli 
allievi a prepararsi per i saggi tematici possibili sul exam di 
Regents. Lo scopo di questa lezione è mostrare alle ragioni per
le quali la gente sta migrando oggi in Africa ed in Cina e come queste
espansioni stanno avendo effetto su quelle regioni. In più, gli
allievi saranno motivati per analizzare criticamente le politiche 
nazionali di immigrazione e per considerare l'attinenza dei bordi 
nazionali in un mondo che sta avvertendo il globalization veloce. 
Come attività di culminazione, gli allievi descriveranno una 
risposta per una domanda tematica di saggio di Regents del campione e 
saranno assegnati per scrivere il saggio per lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κυκλοφορία των ατόμων και των εμπορευμάτων είναι 
ένα σημαντικό μέρος του κρατικών σφαιρικού ιστορίας και 
γεωγραφίας της Νέας Υόρκης προγράμματος σπουδών. 
Παρατίθεται ως ένα από τα θέματα που υπογραμμίζονται στο 
πρόγραμμα σπουδών πυρήνων. Οι σπουδαστές αναμένονται για να
καταλάβουν γιατί οι άνθρωποι μεταναστεύουν και τι ο αντίκτυπος 
των μεταναστεύσεων είναι στους ανθρώπους, τα έθνη, και τις 
περιοχές. Πρόσφατα, η αποδεικτική σειρά PBS WIDE.ANGLE
δημιούργησε δύο προγράμματα που αφορούν την κυκλοφορία των 
ατόμων. Η μετανάστευση εγγράφων "αλτών συνόρων" (2005) 
μεταξύ των χωρών στην Αφρική, και "για να έχει και να έχει όχι" 
(2002) εξετάζει τη μετανάστευση από αγροτικές σε αστικές 
περιοχές στην Κίνα. Με τη μελέτη αυτών των δύο 
μεταναστεύσεων, οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να εμβαθύνουν την 
κατανόησή τους γεγονότων και τάσεων στην Αφρική και την Κίνα 
από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Μια μελέτη αυτών των δύο 
μεταναστεύσεων μπορεί επίσης να παρέχει στους σπουδαστές ένα 
πλαίσιο για άλλες μεταναστεύσεις που περιλαμβάνονται στο 
πρόγραμμα σπουδών πυρήνων και να βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές για να 
προετοιμαστεί για τα πιθανά θεματικά δοκίμια στο διαγωνισμό 
αντιβασιλέων. Ο σκοπός αυτού του μαθήματος είναι να 
εμφανιστούν οι λόγοι για τους οποίους οι άνθρωποι μεταναστεύουν 
στην Αφρική και την Κίνα σήμερα και πώς αυτές οι μεταναστεύσεις 
επηρεάζουν εκείνες τις περιοχές. Επιπλέον, οι σπουδαστές θα
παρακινηθούν για να αναλύσουν αυστηρά τις εθνικές πολιτικές 
μετανάστευσης και για να εξετάσουν τη σχετικότητα των εθνικών 
συνόρων σε έναν κόσμο που δοκιμάζει τη γρήγορη παγκοσμιοποίηση. 
Σαν καταλήγοντας δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές θα περιγράψουν
μια απάντηση για μια θεματική ερώτηση δοκίμιου αντιβασιλέων 
δειγμάτων και θα ανατεθούν για να γράψουν το δοκίμιο για την 
εργασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento de la gente y de mercancías es una 
parte importante del plan de estudios global de la historia y de la 
geografía del estado de Nueva York. Se enumera como uno de los 
temas que se acentúan en el plan de estudios de la base. Se 
espera que los estudiantes entiendan porqué emigra la gente y cuáles
ha sido el impacto de migraciones en la gente, naciones, y regiones. 
Recientemente, la serie documental GRANANGULAR de PBS creó dos 
programas que se relacionan con el movimiento de la gente. ' 
confine 2005) migraciones de los documentos de los puentes (entre los 
países en África, y ' tener y tener no ' (2002) se ocupa de la 
migración de rural a las áreas urbanas en China. Estudiando 
estas dos migraciones, los estudiantes pueden profundizar su 
comprensión de acontecimientos y de tendencias en África y China 
desde la Segunda Guerra Mundial. Un estudio de estas dos 
migraciones puede también proveer de estudiantes un marco para 
repasar otras migraciones incluidas en el plan de estudios de la base 
y ayudar a estudiantes a prepararse para los ensayos temáticos 
posibles en el examen de los Regentes. El propósito de esta 
lección es mostrar a las razones por las que la gente está emigrando
en África y China hoy y cómo estas migraciones están afectando esas
regiones. Además, motivarán a los estudiantes para analizar 
críticamente políticas nacionales de la inmigración y para 
considerar la importancia de fronteras nacionales en un mundo que 
esté experimentando el globalization rápido. Como actividad 
que culmina, los estudiantes contornearán una respuesta para una 
pregunta temática del ensayo de los Regentes de la muestra y 
serán asignados para escribir el ensayo para la preparación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MATTHEW ROBERTS
FN:MATTHEW ROBERTS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211419</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103849</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/on-the-road-again</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
