<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105912</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105912</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085901</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A case study of "A Civil Action"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Fallstudie "eines Zivilrechtsstreits"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une étude de cas "d'une action civile"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um estudo de caso "de uma ação civil"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un'inchiesta "di un'azione civile"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη "μιας αστικής ενέργειασ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un estudio de caso "de una acción civil"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is a short, culminating activity that can be used to assess your students' understanding of the steps needed to determine if a water source is contaminated and how it got that way, and to suggest possible methods of cleanup or remediation. Students review a portion of the film "A Civil Action" and identify the problem and the people involved. Students then take the role of environmental scientist and apply their knowledge of water and hazardous waste contamination to create a plan to help lawyer, Jan Schlichtmann, try the case.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist eine kurze, kulminierende Aktivität, 
die verwendet werden kann, um Verständnis Ihrer Kursteilnehmer der 
Jobsteps festzusetzen, die, um festzustellen benötigt werden, wenn 
eine Wasserquelle verschmutzt wird und wie sie so erhielt, und 
mögliche Methoden der Reinigung oder des Remediation vorzuschlagen. 
Kursteilnehmer wiederholen einen Teil des Filmes "ein 
Zivilrechtsstreit" und kennzeichnen das Problem und die Leute, die 
betroffen sind. Kursteilnehmer dann nehmen die Rolle des 
Klimawissenschaftlers und wenden ihr Wissen des Wassers an und die 
gefährliche Vergeudung Verschmutzung, zum eines Planes zu erstellen, 
um Rechtsanwalt, Jan. Schlichtmann zu helfen, versuchen den Fall.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est une activité courte et culminante qui peut
être employée pour évaluer l'arrangement de vos étudiants des 
étapes requises pour déterminer si une source d'eau est souillée et
comment elle a obtenu de cette façon, et pour suggérer des méthodes
possibles de nettoyage ou de remédiation. Les étudiants 
passent en revue une partie du film "une action civile" et identifient
le problème et les personnes impliqués. Les étudiants alors 
prennent le rôle du scientifique environnemental et appliquent leur 
connaissance de l'eau et la contamination de perte dangereuse pour 
créer un plan pour aider l'avocat, janv. Schlichtmann, essayent le 
cas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Isto é uma atividade curta, culminando que possa
ser usada avaliar a compreensão dos seus estudantes das etapas 
necessitadas determinar se uma fonte de água for contaminada e como 
começou essa maneira, e sugerir métodos possíveis do cleanup ou da 
remediação. Os estudantes revêem uma parcela da película 
"uma ação civil" e identificam o problema e os povos envolvidos. 
Os estudantes então fazem exame do papel do cientista ambiental
e aplicam seu conhecimento da água e a contaminação do desperdício
perigoso para criar uma planta para ajudar ao advogado, janeiro 
Schlichtmann, tenta o caso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un'attività corta e di culminazione che 
può essere usata per valutare la comprensione dei vostri allievi dei 
punti stati necessari per determinare se una fonte d'acqua è 
contaminata e come ha ottenuto quel modo e per suggerire i metodi 
possibili di pulizia o di remediation. Gli allievi rivedono una 
parte della pellicola "un'azione civile" ed identificano il problema e
la gente coinvolgere. Gli allievi allora prendono il ruolo dello
scienziato ambientale ed applicano la loro conoscenza di acqua e la 
contaminazione del rifiuto pericoloso per creare un programma per 
aiutare l'avvocato, gennaio Schlichtmann, prova il caso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι μια σύντομη, καταλήγοντας δραστηριότητα 
που μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να αξιολογήσει την κατανόηση των 
σπουδαστών σας των βημάτων που απαιτούνται για να καθορίσουν εάν 
μια πηγή ύδατος είναι μολυσμένη και πώς πήρε εκείνο τον τρόπο,
και για να προτείνει τις πιθανές μεθόδους καθαρισμού ή 
επανόρθωσης. Οι σπουδαστές αναθεωρούν μια μερίδα της 
ταινίας "μια αστική ενέργεια" και προσδιορίζουν το πρόβλημα και 
τους ανθρώπους σχετικούς. Οι σπουδαστές παίρνουν έπειτα το 
ρόλο του περιβαλλοντικού επιστήμονα και εφαρμόζουν τη γνώση τους 
μόλυνσης ύδατος και επιβλαβών αποβλήτων για να δημιουργήσουν ένα
σχέδιο για να βοηθήσουν το δικηγόρο, ο Ιαν. Schlichtmann, να 
δοκιμάσει την περίπτωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Éste es una actividad corta, que culmina que se 
puede utilizar para evaluar la comprensión de sus estudiantes de los 
pasos de progresión necesitados para determinarse si se contamina una
fuente de agua y cómo consiguió esa manera, y para sugerir métodos 
posibles de limpieza o de remediación. Los estudiantes repasan 
una porción de la película "una acción civil" e identifican al 
problema y a gente implicados. Los estudiantes después toman el
papel del científico ambiental y aplican su conocimiento del agua y 
la contaminación de los desechos peligrosos para crear un plan para 
ayudar al abogado, enero Schlichtmann, intenta el caso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MICHELE KLODA
FN:MICHELE KLODA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085901</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105912</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-case-study-of-a-civil-action</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
