<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105558</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105558</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086367</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Job Visited by a Master Tailor from Broadway."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Job besucht von einem Vorlagenschneider von 
Broadway."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">le "travail visité par un tailleur principal de 
Broadway."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"trabalho visitado por um alfaiate mestre de 
Broadway."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"lavoro visitato da un sarto matrice da Broadway."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εργασία που επισκέπτεται από έναν κύριο ράφτη από 
Broadway."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"trabajo visitado por una personalización 
principal de Broadway."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Between 1800 and 1840, improved transportation networks and larger markets altered the way goods were produced, as workshops and factories became larger and fewer goods were produced by household labor. Another effect of growing industrialization was social stratification, as some master craftsmen became businessmen while their journeymen lost their independence and became wage workers. This illustration from the 1841 novel  The Career of Puffer Hopkins  caricatured the growing distinction between masters and journeymen. The master tailor's prosperous outfit, stance, and fancy business address (New York's Broadway) sharply contrasted with the journeyman's wretched appearance and workshop-home.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zwischen 1800 und 1840 änderten verbesserte 
Transportnetze und größere Märkte die Methode, die Waren produziert
wurden, während Werkstätten und Fabriken größer wurden und wenige 
Waren durch Haushalt Arbeit produziert wurden. Ein anderer 
Effekt des Wachsens von von Industrialisierung war soziale Schichtung,
da einige Vorlagenhandwerker Geschäftsmänner wurden, während ihre 
Facharbeiter ihre Unabhängigkeit verloren und Lohnarbeiter wurden. 
Diese Abbildung vom Roman 1841 die Karriere des Puffers Hopkins 
caricatured die wachsende Unterscheidung zwischen Meistern und 
Facharbeitern. Des Vorlagenwohlhabende die Ausstattung 
schneiders, die Position und die Phantasiegeschäftsadresse (Broadway 
New York) kontrastierten scharf zu des wretched dem Aussehen und zum 
Werkstatt-Haus Facharbeiters.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entre 1800 et 1840, les réseaux améliorés de transport 
et les plus grands marchés ont modifié la voie que des marchandises 
ont été produites, pendant que les ateliers et les usines devenaient
plus grands et peu de marchandises étaient produites par le travail 
de ménage. Un autre effet d'accroître l'industrialisation 
était stratification sociale, car quelques artisans principaux sont 
devenus des hommes d'affaires tandis que leurs compagnons 
détruisaient leur indépendance et devenaient des ouvriers de 
salaire. Cette illustration du roman 1841 la carrière du 
décolleur Hopkins caricatured la distinction croissante entre les 
maîtres et les compagnons. L'équipement du tailleur principal,
la position, et l'adresse commerciale prospères de fantaisie 
(Broadway de New York) ont brusquement différé de l'aspect 
misérable et de l'atelier-maison du compagnon.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entre 1800 e 1840, as redes melhoradas do transporte e os 
mercados maiores alteraram a maneira que os bens foram produzidos, 
enquanto as oficinas e as fábricas se tornaram maiores e poucos bens 
foram produzidos pelo trabalho da casa. Um outro efeito de 
crescer o industrialization era stratification social, porque alguns 
artesãos mestres se transformaram homens de negócios quando seus 
journeymen perderam sua independência e se transformaram 
trabalhadores do salário. Esta ilustração da novela 1841 a 
carreira do soprador Hopkins caricatured a distinção crescente entre
mestres e journeymen. O equipamento do alfaiate mestre, o 
stance, e o endereço de negócio prósperos da fantasia (Broadway de 
New York) contrastaram agudamente com a aparência wretched e 
oficina-HOME do journeyman.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fra 1800 e 1840, le reti migliorate del trasporto ed i 
più grandi mercati hanno alterato il modo che le merci sono state 
prodotte, mentre i workshop e le fabbriche sono diventato più grandi 
e poche merci sono state prodotte dal lavoro della famiglia. 
Un altro effetto di crescita dell'industrializzazione era la 
stratificazione sociale, poichè alcuni artigiani matrici sono 
diventato uomini d'affari mentre i loro operai qualificati hanno perso
la loro indipendenza e sono diventato operai dello stipendio. 
Questa illustrazione dal romanzo 1841 la carriera della 
soffiatore Hopkins caricatured la distinzione crescente fra i 
supervisori e gli operai qualificati. L'attrezzatura del sarto 
matrice, la posizione e l'indirizzo prosperosi di affari di 
immaginazione (Broadway de New York) hanno contrapposto acutamente con
l'apparenza wretched e la workshop-sede dell'operaio qualificato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταξύ 1800 και 1840, τα βελτιωμένα δίκτυα 
μεταφορών και οι μεγαλύτερες αγορές άλλαξαν τον τρόπο που τα 
αγαθά παρήχθησαν, καθώς τα εργαστήρια και τα εργοστάσια έγιναν 
μεγαλύτερα και λιγότερα αγαθά παρήχθησαν από την οικιακή 
εργασία. Μια άλλη επίδραση της ανάπτυξης της εκβιομηχάνισης
ήταν κοινωνική στρωματοποίηση, καθώς μερικοί κύριοι βιοτέχνες 
έγιναν επιχειρηματίες ενώ οι τεχνίτες τους έχασαν την 
ανεξαρτησία τους και έγιναν εργαζόμενοι αμοιβών. Αυτή η 
απεικόνιση από το μυθιστόρημα 1841 η σταδιοδρομία του καπνιστή
Hopkins η αυξανόμενη διάκριση μεταξύ των κυρίων και των 
τεχνιτών. Η ακμάζουσα εξάρτηση του κύριου ράφτη, η θέση, 
και η φανταχτερή επιχειρησιακή διεύθυνση (Broadway της Νέας 
Υόρκης) αισθητά αντιπαρέβαλαν με τη δυστυχή εμφάνιση και το 
εργαστήριο-σπίτι του τεχνίτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entre 1800 y 1840, las redes mejoradas del transporte y 
mercados más grandes alteraron la manera que las mercancías fueron 
producidas, mientras que los talleres y las fábricas llegaron a ser 
más grandes y pocas mercancías fueron producidas por el trabajo de 
la casa. Otro efecto de crecer la industrialización era 
estratificación social, pues algunos artesanos principales hicieron 
hombres de negocios mientras que sus oficiales perdieron su 
independencia e hicieron trabajadores del salario. Esta 
ilustración de la novela 1841 la carrera del soplador Hopkins 
caricatured la distinción cada vez mayor entre los amos y los 
oficiales. El equipo de la personalización principal, la 
postura, y la dirección comercial prósperos de la suposición 
(Broadway de Nueva York) pusieron en contraste sostenidamente con el 
aspecto desgraciado y el taller-hogar del oficial.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086367</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105558</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/job-visited-by-a-master-tailor-from-broadway</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
