<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108653</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108653</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205541</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Introduction to musical instruments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einleitung in eine Musikinstrumente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Introduction aux instruments musicaux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Introdução aos instrumentos musicais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Introduzione agli strumenti musicali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εισαγωγή στα μουσικά όργανα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Introducción a los instrumentos musicales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This module features extensive recordings of 18 musical instruments for first steps in musical education. Children (and adults) can use this quiz to learn to identify musical instruments from their sound. Two multiple choice quizzes with different kinds of question are included. Musical instruments have been chosen primarily from Europe, but also from non-European cultures such as the Middle East, India, Japan and Australia. Instruments are illustrated by full-length high-quality MP3 recordings. In many cases the music chosen is some of the most outstanding music ever written for the instruments in question. This enables the learner to gain an unusually good impression of the sound and capabilities of the instruments. Technically this module illustrates some of the media playing capabilities introduced in version 1.2 of Qedoc's quiz creation software. In this particular module, M3U playlists are used to stream MP3's from over the internet. This allows hours of music to be available and yet keeps the module size itself to an absolute minimum. The module also shows how the media playing capabilities can be inserted into both the question and response segments of multiple choice questions. Another important feature demonstrated by this module is a consequence of Qedoc's cooperation with the Magnatune record label and its music hosting site at Magnatune.com. Magnatune itself places thousands of high quality titles at the disposal of internet users. The titles can be accessed and played through a variety of applications, including Qedoc's quiz software. An educator using this software can access the Magnatune music database just as we have done and create high quality musical education resources like this one.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Modul kennzeichnet umfangreiche Aufnahmen 
von 18 Musikinstrumenten für erste Jobsteps in der musikalischen 
Ausbildung. Kinder (und Erwachsene) können diesen Quiz 
verwenden, um zu erlernen, Musikinstrumente von ihrem Ton zu 
kennzeichnen. Zwei mehrfache auserlesene Quizen mit 
unterschiedlichen Arten der Frage sind enthalten. 
Musikinstrumente sind hauptsächlich von Europa, aber auch von 
den außereuropäischen Kulturen wie dem Mittlere Osten, dem Indien, 
dem Japan und dem Australien gewählt worden. Instrumente werden
durch in voller Länge hochwertige Aufnahmen MP3 veranschaulicht. 
In vielen Fällen ist die Musik, die gewählt wird, etwas von 
der hervorragendsten Musik, die überhaupt für die Instrumente in 
Frage geschrieben wird. Dieses aktiviert den Anfänger, einen 
ungewöhnlich guten Eindruck des Tones und der Fähigkeiten der 
Instrumente zu gewinnen. Technisch veranschaulicht dieses Modul 
einige der Media, welche die Fähigkeiten spielen, die in Version 1.2 
der Quiz-Kreation Software Qedocs eingeführt werden. In diesem 
bestimmten Modul werden M3U playlists verwendet, um zu strömen MP3's
über vom Internet. Dieses läßt Stunden von Musik und doch von
Unterhaelten die Modulgröße selbst für ein absolutes Minimum 
vorhanden sein. Das Modul zeigt auch, wie die Media, die 
Fähigkeiten spielen, in die Frage und Wartesegmente der mehrfachen 
auserlesenen Fragen eingesetzt werden können. Ein anderes 
wichtiges Merkmal zeigte durch dieses Modul ist eine Konsequenz von 
Mitarbeit Qedocs mit dem Magnatune Satzkennsatz und seiner Musik, die 
Site an Magnatune.com bewirten. Magnatune selbst stellt 
Tausenden hohe Qualitätsnamen zur die Verfuegung der 
Internet-Benutzer. Die Namen können durch eine Vielzahl von 
Anwendungen, einschließlich Quizsoftware Qedocs erreicht werden und 
gespielt werden. Ein Erzieher, der diese Software verwendet, 
kann auf die Magnatune Musikdatenbank zugreifen gerade wie wir getan 
haben und hohe Qualitätsmusikalische Ausbildung Betriebsmittel wie 
dieses erstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module comporte les enregistrements étendus de
18 instruments musicaux pour les premières étapes dans l'éducation 
musicale. Les enfants (et les adultes) peuvent employer ce jeu 
pour apprendre à identifier les instruments musicaux de leur bruit. 
Deux jeux bien choisis multiples avec différents genres de 
question sont inclus. Des instruments musicaux ont été choisis
principalement de l'Europe, mais également des cultures 
non-européennes telles que le Moyen-Orient, l'Inde, le Japon et 
l'Australie. Des instruments sont illustrés par les 
enregistrements MP3 de haute qualité intégraux. Dans beaucoup 
de cas la musique choisie est une partie de la musique la plus 
exceptionnelle jamais écrite pour les instruments en question. 
Ceci permet à l'étudiant d'avoir une impression 
exceptionnellement bonne du bruit et des capacités des instruments. 
Techniquement ce module illustre certains des medias jouant des 
capacités présentées dans la version 1.2 du logiciel de création 
du jeu de Qedoc. Dans ce module particulier, des playlists de 
M3U sont employés pour couler MP3's de au-dessus de l'Internet. 
Ceci accorde des heures de la musique être disponibles mais des
subsistances la taille de module elle-même à un minimum absolu. 
Le module montre également comment les medias jouant des 
capacités peuvent être insérés dans les segments de question et de
réponse des questions bien choisies multiples. Un autre 
dispositif important a démontré par ce module est une conséquence 
de la coopération de Qedoc avec l'étiquette d'enregistrement de 
Magnatune et sa musique accueillant le site à Magnatune.com. 
Magnatune lui-même met des milliers de titres de haute qualité
à la disposition des utilisateurs d'Internet. Les titres 
peuvent être consultés et joués par une variété d'applications, y
compris le logiciel du jeu de Qedoc. Un éducateur utilisant ce 
logiciel peut accéder à la base de données de musique de Magnatune 
juste comme nous avons fait et créer les ressources musicales 
d'éducation de haute qualité comme celle-ci.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo caracteriza gravações extensivas de
18 instrumentos musicais para primeiras etapas na instrução musical.
As crianças (e adultos) podem usar este quiz aprender 
identificar instrumentos musicais de seu som. Dois quizzes bem 
escolhidos múltiplos com tipos diferentes da pergunta são 
incluídos. Os instrumentos musicais foram escolhidos 
primeiramente de Europa, mas também das culturas non-European tais 
como o Oriente Médio, India, Japão e Austrália. Os 
instrumentos são ilustrados pelas gravações MP3 de alta qualidade 
full-length. Em muitos casos a música escolhida é alguma da 
música a mais proeminente escrita sempre para os instrumentos na 
pergunta. Isto permite o learner de ganhar uma impressão 
raramente boa do som e das potencialidades dos instrumentos. 
Tècnica este módulo ilustra alguns dos media que jogam as 
potencialidades introduzidas na versão 1.2 do software da criação 
do quiz de Qedoc. Neste módulo particular, os playlists de M3U
são usados fluir MP3's sobre do Internet. Isto permite que as 
horas da música estejam disponíveis no entanto dos sustentos o 
tamanho próprio do módulo a um mínimo absoluto. O módulo 
mostra também como os media que jogam potencialidades podem ser 
introduzidos  nos segmentos da pergunta e da resposta de perguntas bem
escolhidas múltiplas. Uma outra característica importante 
demonstrou por este módulo é uma conseqüência da cooperação de 
Qedoc com a etiqueta do registro de Magnatune e sua música que 
hospedam o local em Magnatune.com. Magnatune próprio coloca 
milhares de títulos da qualidade elevada na eliminação de usuários
do Internet. Os títulos podem ser alcançados e jogado com uma 
variedade das aplicações, including o software do quiz de Qedoc. 
Um educador que usa este software pode alcançar a base de dados
da música de Magnatune apenas como nós fizemos e criar recursos 
musicais da instrução da qualidade elevada como este.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo caratterizza lle vaste registrazioni
di 18 strumenti musicali per i primi punti nella formazione musicale. 
I bambini (ed adulti) possono usare questo quiz per imparare 
identificare gli strumenti musicali dal loro suono. Due quiz 
choice multipli con differenti generi di domanda sono inclusi. 
Gli strumenti musicali sono stati scelti soprattutto da Europa, 
ma anche dalle colture non-European quali Medio Oriente, l'India, il 
Giappone e l'Australia. Gli strumenti sono illustrati dalle 
registrazioni di alta qualità integrali MP3. In molti casi la 
musica scelta è alcuna della musica più eccezionale scritta mai per 
gli strumenti in questione. Ciò permette al principiante di 
guadagnare un'impressione insolitamente buona del suono e delle 
possibilità degli strumenti. Questo modulo illustra 
tecnicamente alcuni dei media che giocano le possibilità introdotte 
nella versione 1.2 del software della creazione di quiz del Qedoc. 
In questo modulo particolare, i playlists di M3U sono usati per
effluire MP3's sopra dal Internet. Ciò permette che le ore di 
musica siano disponibili ma delle conservazioni il formato in se del 
modulo ad un minimo assoluto. Il modulo egualmente mostra come i
media che giocano le possibilità possono essere inseriti sia nei 
segmenti di risposta che di domanda delle domande choice multiple. 
Un'altra caratteristica importante ha dimostrato da questo 
modulo è una conseguenza della cooperazione del Qedoc con l'etichetta
del record di Magnatune e la relativa musica che ospitano il luogo a 
Magnatune.com. Magnatune in se dispone le migliaia dei titoli di
alta qualità a disposizione degli utenti del Internet. I titoli
possono essere raggiunti e giocati con una varietà di applicazioni, 
compreso il software di quiz del Qedoc. Un educatore che usando 
questo software può accedere alla base di dati di musica di Magnatune
appena come abbiamo fatto e creare le risorse musicali di formazione 
di alta qualità come questa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα χαρακτηρίζει τις εκτενείς καταγραφές 
18 μουσικών οργάνων για τα πρώτα βήματα στη μουσική 
εκπαίδευση. Τα παιδιά (και ενήλικοι) μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιήσουν αυτόν τον διαγωνισμό γνώσεων για να μάθουν να 
προσδιορίζουν τα μουσικά όργανα από τον ήχο τους. Δύο 
πολλαπλάσιοι διαγωνισμοοι γνώσεων επιλογής με τα διαφορετικά είδη
ερώτησης συμπεριλαμβάνονται. Τα μουσικά όργανα έχουν 
επιλεχτεί πρώτιστα από την Ευρώπη, αλλά και από τους μη 
ευρωπαϊκούς πολιτισμούς όπως η Μέση Ανατολή, η Ινδία, η 
Ιαπωνία και η Αυστραλία. Τα όργανα εμφανίζονται στις 
ολόκληρες υψηλής ποιότητας MP3 καταγραφές. Σε πολλές 
περιπτώσεις η μουσική που επιλέγεται είναι μερικές από τη 
σημαντικότερη μουσική που γράφεται πάντα για τα όργανα εν λόγω. 
Αυτό επιτρέπει στον αρχάριο για να κερδίσει μια 
κατ'ασυνήθιστο τρόπο καλή εντύπωση του ήχου και των ικανοτήτων 
των οργάνων. Τεχνικά αυτή η ενότητα επεξηγεί μερικά από 
τα μέσα που παίζουν τις ικανότητες που εισάγονται στην έκδοση 
1.2 του λογισμικού δημιουργιών διαγωνισμοου γνώσεων Qedoc. 
Σε αυτήν την ιδιαίτερη ενότητα, M3U τα playlists 
χρησιμοποιούνται στο ρεύμα MP3'S από μέσω του Διαδικτύου. 
Αυτό επιτρέπει στις ώρες της μουσικής για να είναι 
διαθέσιμες και όμως περιορίζει το ίδιο το μέγεθος ενότητας στο 
απόλυτο ελάχιστο. Η ενότητα επιδεικνύει επίσης πώς τα 
μέσα που παίζουν τις ικανότητες μπορούν να παρεμβληθούν και στα 
τμήματα μνήμης ερώτησης και απάντησης των πολλαπλάσιων ερωτήσεων
επιλογής. Ένα άλλο σημαντικό χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα που 
καταδεικνύεται από αυτήν την ενότητα είναι μια συνέπεια της 
συνεργασίας Qedoc με την ετικέτα αρχείων Magnatune και η 
φιλοξενώντας περιοχή μουσικής της σε Magnatune.com. Magnatune
το ίδιο τοποθετεί χιλιάδες υψηλής ποιότητας τίτλοι στη διάθεση 
των χρηστών Διαδικτύου. Οι τίτλοι μπορούν να προσεγγιστούν 
και να παιχτούν μέσω ποικίλων εφαρμογών, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του 
λογισμικού διαγωνισμοου γνώσεων Qedoc. Ένας εκπαιδευτικός
που χρησιμοποιεί αυτό το λογισμικό μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση στη 
βάση δεδομένων μουσικής Magnatune ακριβώς όπως έχουμε κάνει 
και δημιουργούμε τα υψηλής ποιότητας μουσικά στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς εκπαίδευσης όπως αυτό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo ofrece las grabaciones extensas de 18
instrumentos musicales para los primeros pasos de progresión en la 
educación musical. Los niños (y adultos) pueden utilizar este 
concurso para aprender identificar los instrumentos musicales de su 
sonido. Dos concursos bien escogidos múltiples con diversas 
clases de pregunta son incluidos. Los instrumentos musicales se 
han elegido sobre todo de Europa, pero también de culturas no 
europeas tales como el Oriente Medio, India, Japón y Australia. 
Los instrumentos son ilustrados por las grabaciones de alta 
calidad integrales MP3. En muchos casos la música elegida es 
algo de la música más excepcional escrita siempre para los 
instrumentos en la pregunta. Esto permite al principiante ganar 
una impresión inusualmente buena del sonido y de las capacidades de 
los instrumentos. Este módulo ilustra técnico algunos de los 
media que juegan las capacidades introducidas en la versión 1.2 del 
software de la creación del concurso de Qedoc. En este módulo 
determinado, los playlists de M3U se utilizan para fluir MP3's sobre 
del Internet. Esto permite que las horas de la música estén 
disponibles pero de los mantienes la talla sí mismo del módulo para 
un mínimo absoluto. El módulo también muestra cómo los media
que juegan capacidades se pueden insertar en los segmentos de la 
pregunta y de la respuesta de preguntas bien escogidas múltiples. 
Otra característica importante demostró por este módulo es 
una consecuencia de la cooperación de Qedoc con la escritura de la 
etiqueta del expediente de Magnatune y su música que recibían el 
sitio en Magnatune.com. Magnatune sí mismo pone millares de 
títulos de la alta calidad en la disposición de los utilizadores del
Internet. Los títulos se pueden alcanzar y jugar con una 
variedad de aplicaciones, incluyendo el software del concurso de 
Qedoc. Un educador que usa este software puede tener acceso a la
base de datos de la música de Magnatune apenas como hemos hecho y 
crear recursos musicales de la educación de la alta calidad como 
éste.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:QEDOC EDUCATIONAL TEAM
FN:QEDOC EDUCATIONAL TEAM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205541</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108653</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/introduction-to-musical-instruments</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
