<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103979</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103979</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087060</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Supreme Court Strikes Down Railroad Regulation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Höchste Gericht Schlägt Hinunter 
Eisenbahn-Regelung An</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Cour Suprême Heurte En bas du Règlement de 
Chemin de fer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Corte Suprema Golpeia Abaixo O Regulamento Da 
Estrada de ferro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Corte suprema Colpisce Giù La Regolazione 
Della Ferrovia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ανώτατο δικαστήριο χτυπά κάτω από τον κανονισμό 
σιδηροδρόμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Tribunal Supremo Pulso Abajo De la Regulación 
Del Ferrocarril</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the "Gilded Age" of the 1880s and 1890s, the influence of large-scale corporations dominated not just the U.S. Congress but also the courts. Nowhere was this more evident than in the U.S. Supreme Court's decision in the 1886  Wabash  case, excerpted below. With  Wabash , the Court overturned its 1879 decision ( Munn v. Illinois ) allowing states to regulate railroads. Perverting the original intent of the Fourteenth Amendment, the Court decreed that corporations were legally "persons" entitled to the Amendment's protections. (Just three years earlier, the Court had ruled the Civil Rights Act of 1875 unconstitutional on the basis that the Fourteenth Amendment was binding only on states, not individuals, thereby severely jeopardizing the very rights--of freed slaves--the amendment was explicitly designed to protect.) The  Wabash  case barred states from regulating interstate commerce, asserting that only the federal government could do so. In 1887, Congress passed the Interstate Commerce Act, which railroad barons found more appealing than the more restrictive state laws.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während "vergoldete Alter" des 1880s und 1890s, 
der Einfluß der großräumigen Korporationen beherrschte nicht gerade
den VEREINIGTE STAATEN Kongreß aber auch die Gerichte. 
Nirgendwo war dieses, das als in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Entscheidung des Höchsten Gerichts im Wabash Fall 1886 
offensichtlicher ist, unten excerptiert. Mit Wabash warf das 
Gericht seine Entscheidung 1879 (Munn V. Illinois) Zustände 
Eisenbahnen regeln lassend um. Perverting die ursprüngliche 
Absicht der vierzehnten Änderung, verordnete das Gericht, daß 
Korporationen erlaubterweise "die Personen waren", die zu den Schutzen
der Änderung erlaubt wurden. (gerade drei Jahre früher, hatte 
das Gericht die Zivilrecht-Tat von 1875 verfassungswidrig auf der Grundlage 
angeordnet, die die vierzehnte Änderung nur auf Zuständen band, 
waren die nicht Einzelpersonen, dadurch streng gefährdet man die 
Rechte -- der freigegebenen Sklaven -- die Änderung, ausdrücklich 
konzipiert, um sich zu schützen.) Der Wabash Fall hielt 
Zustände vom Regeln des landesweiten Handels ab und erklärte, daß 
nur die Bundesregierung so tun könnte. 1887 führte Kongreß 
die Handel-Tat, die Eisenbahn Barons anziehender als die 
einschränkenderen Zustandgesetze fanden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant "l'âge doré" du 1880s et du 1890s, 
l'influence des sociétés de grande puissance a dominé pas 
simplement le congrès des ETATS-UNIS mais également les cours. 
Nulle part était ceci plus évidente que dans la décision de 
cour suprême des ETATS-UNIS dans le cas 1886 de Wabash, extrait 
ci-dessous. Avec Wabash, la cour a retourné sa décision 1879 
(Munn v. l'Illinois) permettant à des états de régler des chemins 
de fer. Pervertissant l'intention initiale du quatorzième 
amendement, la cour a décrété que les sociétés étaient 
légalement des "personnes" eues droit aux protections de 
l'amendement. (juste trois ans de plus tôt, la cour avait 
régné la Loi de droits civiques de 1875 inconstitutionnels sur la 
base que le quatorzième amendement liait seulement sur des états, 
pas des individus, compromettant de ce fait sévèrement les droites 
mêmes -- des esclaves libérés -- l'amendement n'ont été 
explicitement conçus pour se protéger.) Le cas de Wabash a 
empêché des états de régler le commerce entre Etats, affirmant que
seulement le gouvernement fédéral pourrait faire ainsi. En 
1887, le congrès a passé l'acte de commerce entre Etats, que les 
barons de chemin de fer ont trouvé plus attrayant que les lois plus 
restrictives d'état.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante "gilded a idade" do 1880s e 1890s, a 
influência de corporation em grande escala dominou não apenas o 
congress de ESTADOS UNIDOS mas também as cortes. A nenhumaa 
parte era esta mais evidente do que na decisão de corte suprema de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS no exemplo 1886 de Wabash, excerpted abaixo. Com 
Wabash, a corte virou sua decisão 1879 (Munn v. Illinois) que permite
que os estados regulem estradas de ferro. Pervertindo a 
intenção original da décima quarta emenda, a corte decreed que os 
corporation eram legalmente "pessoas" intituladas às proteções da 
emenda. (apenas três anos mais adiantado, a corte tinha 
governado o ato das direitas civis de 1875 unconstitutional na base 
que a décima quarta emenda ligava somente em estados, não os 
indivíduos, jeopardizing desse modo severamente as direitas very -- 
de escravos livrados -- a emenda foram projetados explicitamente 
proteger.) O exemplo de Wabash barrou estados de regular o 
comércio interstate, afirmando que somente o governo federal poderia 
fazer assim. Em 1887, o congress passou o ato do comércio 
interstate, que os barons da estrada de ferro encontraram mais 
atraente do que as leis mais restritivas do estado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante "l'età gilded" del 1880s e del 1890s, 
l'influenza delle società su grande scala ha dominato non appena il 
congresso degli STATI UNITI ma anche le corti. Nessuna parte era
questa più evidente di nella decisione della Corte suprema degli 
STATI UNITI nel caso 1886 di Wabash, stralciato sotto. Con 
Wabash, la corte capovolta la relativa 1879 decisione (Munn v. 
Illinois) che concede dichiara per regolare le ferrovie. 
Pervertendo l'intenzione originale della fourteenth correzione, 
la corte ha decretato che le società erano legalmente "persone" 
aventi diritto alle protezioni della correzione. (più in 
anticipo appena tre anni, la corte aveva regolato i diritti che civili
una Legge di 1875 inconstituzionali sulla base su che la fourteenth 
correzione stava legandosi soltanto dichiara, non individui, 
compromettenti quindi severamente i diritti stessi -- degli schiavi 
liberati -- la correzione esplicitamente è stata destinata a 
proteggere.) Il caso di Wabash escluso dichiara dal 
regolare il commercio da uno stato all'altro, asserente che soltanto 
il governo federale potrebbe fare così. In 1887, il congresso 
ha passato la Legge di commercio da uno stato all'altro, che i barons 
della ferrovia hanno trovato più supplichevole del più restrittivo 
per dichiarare le leggi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια της "επιχρυσωμένης ηλικίασ" του 
1880s και του 1890s, η επιρροή των μεγάλης κλίμακας εταιριών
εξουσίασε όχι μόνο το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ συνέδριο αλλά και τα 
δικαστήρια. Δεν ήταν πουθενά αυτό εμφανέστερο απ'ό,τι στις
ΗΠΑ η απόφαση που του ανώτατου δικαστηρίου στην υπόθεση 1886 
Wabash, κατωτέρω. Με Wabash, το δικαστήριο ανέτρεψε την
απόφαση 1879 του (Munn V. Ιλλινόις) που επιτρέπει στα 
κράτη για να ρυθμίσει τους σιδηροδρόμους. Διαστροφική η 
αρχική πρόθεση της δέκατης τέταρτης τροποποίησης, το δικαστήριο 
θέσπισε ότι οι εταιρίες ήταν νόμιμα "πρόσωπα" που είσχαν το 
δικαίωμα στην προστασία της τροποποίησης. (Ακριβώς τρία 
έτη νωρίτερα, το δικαστήριο είχε διατάξει το νόμο αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων 1875 αντισυνταγματικών στη βάση ότι η δέκατη 
τέταρτη τροποποίηση ήταν δεσμευτική μόνο στα κράτη, όχι τα 
άτομα, με αυτόν τον τρόπο διακινδυνεύοντας σοβαρά τα ίδια τα 
δικαιώματα -- των ελευθερωμένων σκλάβων -- η τροποποίηση είχαν ως
σκοπό ρητά να προστατεύσουν.) Η περίπτωση Wabash έφραξε 
τα κράτη από τη ρύθμιση του διακρατικού εμπορίου, βεβαιώνοντας 
ότι μόνο η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση θα μπορούσε να κάνει έτσι. 
Το 1887, το συνέδριο πέρασε το διακρατικό νόμο εμπορίου,
ποιοι βαρώνοι σιδηροδρόμου βρήκαν να απευθυνθούν από τους πιό 
περιοριστικούς κρατικούς νόμους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la "edad dorada" del 1880s y del 1890s, la
influencia de corporaciones en grande dominó no apenas el congreso de
ESTADOS UNIDOS pero también las cortes. Ninguna parte era ésta
más evidente que en la decisión del Tribunal Supremo de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS en el caso 1886 de Wabash, extractado abajo. Con Wabash, 
la corte volcó su decisión 1879 (Munn v. Illinois) que permitía que
los estados regulen los ferrocarriles. Pervirtiendo el intento 
original de la catorcena enmienda, la corte decretó que las 
corporaciones eran legalmente "personas" dadas derecho a las 
protecciones de la enmienda. (apenas tres años de anterior, la 
corte había gobernado el acto de las derechas civiles de 1875 
inconstitucionales sobre la base que la catorcena enmienda ataba 
solamente en estados, no diseñaron a los individuos, comprometiendo 
de tal modo seriamente las mismas derechas -- de esclavos liberados --
la enmienda explícitamente para proteger.) El caso de Wabash 
barró estados de regular el comercio de un estado a otro, afirmando 
que solamente el gobierno federal podría hacer tan. En 1887, el
congreso pasó el acto del comercio de un estado a otro, que los 
barones del ferrocarril encontraron más atractivo que los leyes más 
restrictivos del estado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087060</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103979</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-supreme-court-strikes-down-railroad-regulation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
