<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207099</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Her Story</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ihre Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Son Histoire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sua História</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Sua Storia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιστορία της</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Su Historia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers photos, diaries, and timelines for learning about women pioneers, women during the Civil War, women's suffrage in the Progressive Era, eight women who served on the front during World War II, First Ladies, literature about women and discrimination, African-American women in the sciences, women in Muslim societies, Native American women writers, Zora Neale Hurston, Margaret Mead, research in women's history, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet Fotos, Tagebücher und timelines für das 
Lernen über Fraupioniere, Frauen während des Bürgerkrieges, 
Stimmrecht der Frauen in der progressiven Ära, acht Frauen, die auf 
der Frontseite während des Zweiten Weltkrieges dienten, erste Damen, 
Literatur über Frauen und Unterscheidung, Afrikanisch-Amerikanische 
Frauen in den Wissenschaften, Frauen in den moslemischen 
Gesellschaften, gebürtige amerikanische Frauverfasser, Zora Neale 
Hurston, Margaret Mead, Forschung in der Geschichte der Frauen und 
mehr an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre des photos, des agendas, et des chronologies
pour se renseigner sur les pionniers de femmes, les femmes pendant la 
guerre civile, le suffrage des femmes dans l'ère progressive, huit 
femmes qui ont servi sur l'avant pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale,
les premières dames, la littérature au sujet des femmes et la 
discrimination, les femmes afro-américaines en sciences, femmes dans les
sociétés musulmanes, auteurs américains indigènes de femmes, Zora 
Neale Hurston, Margaret Mead, recherche chez l'histoire des 
femmes, et davantage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece fotos, diários, e timelines para aprender
sobre os pioneiros das mulheres, as mulheres durante a guerra civil, o
suffrage das mulheres na era progressiva, as oito mulheres que 
serviram na parte dianteira durante a segunda guerra mundial, 
primeiras senhoras, a literatura sobre mulheres e a discriminação, 
mulheres Africano-Americanas nas ciências, mulheres em sociedades 
muçulmanas, escritores americanos nativos das mulheres, Zora Neale 
Hurston, Margaret Mead, pesquisa no history das mulheres, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre le foto, i diari ed i timelines per imparare
circa i pionieri delle donne, le donne durante la guerra civile, il 
suffrage delle donne nell'era progressiva, otto donne che hanno 
servito sulla parte anteriore durante la seconda guerra mondiale, 
prime signore, la letteratura circa le donne e la distinzione, le 
donne Africano-Americane nelle scienze, le donne nelle società 
musulmane, i produttori americani natali delle donne, Zora Neale 
Hurston, Margaret Mead, ricerca nella storia delle donne e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τις φωτογραφίες, τα ημερολόγια, και τις 
υποδείξεις ως προς το χρόνο για την εκμάθηση για τους πρωτοπόρους 
γυναικών, γυναίκες κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου πολέμου, ψήφος
των γυναικών στην προοδευτική εποχή, οκτώ γυναίκες που 
εξυπηρέτησαν στο μέτωπο κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου 
ΙΙ, των πρώτων κυριών, της λογοτεχνίας για τις γυναίκες και της 
διάκρισης, τις αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές γυναίκες στις επιστήμες, 
τις γυναίκες στις μουσουλμανικές κοινωνίες, τους εγγενείς 
αμερικανικούς συγγραφείς γυναικών, τη Zora Neale Hurston, 
τη Margaret Mead, την έρευνα στην ιστορία των γυναικών, και 
περισσότερους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece las fotos, los diarios, y los timelines 
para aprender sobre los pioneros de las mujeres, las mujeres durante 
la guerra civil, el sufragio de las mujeres en la era progresiva, ocho
mujeres que desempen'aron servicios en el frente durante la Segunda 
Guerra Mundial, las primeras señoras, literatura sobre mujeres y la 
discriminación, mujeres Africano-Americanas en las ciencias, mujeres 
en sociedades musulmanas, programas de escritura americanos nativos de
las mujeres, Zora Neale Hurston, Margaret Mead, investigación en la 
historia de las mujeres, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207099</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108732</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/her-story</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
