<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087123</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">To buy is patriotic.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zu kaufen ist patriotisch.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Acheter est patriotique.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comprar é patriotic.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Comprare è patriotic.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να αγοράσει είναι πατριωτική.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comprar es patriótico.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From smoking to skin care, advertisers rushed to identify their products with the war effort once the United States entered World War II. Using the war to pitch products was not the only way American businesses benefited from their association with the conflict. Although the government managed and regulated the wartime economy, it often did so to the benefit of large companies. The top 100 companies turned out 30 percent of the nation's manufactured goods in 1940; by war's end, those same companies held 70 percent of all civilian and military contracts. Business executives sat in many of the key posts of war production agencies, serving as dollar-a-year-men" while remaining on their company payrolls</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vom Rauchen, zum von von Obacht zu enthäuten, hetzten 
Inserenten, um ihre Produkte mit der Kriegbemühung zu kennzeichnen, 
sobald die Vereinigten Staaten den Zweiten Weltkrieg eintrugen. 
Den Krieg zu verwenden, um Produkte zu werfen war nicht die 
einzige Methode amerikanischen Geschäfte, die von ihrer Verbindung 
mit der $überschneidung profitiert wurden. Obgleich die 
Regierung die Kriegwirtschaft handhatte und regelte, tat sie häufig 
so zum Nutzen der großen Firmen. Die oberen 100 Firmen fielen 
30 Prozent der hergestellten Waren der Nation 1940 aus; durch 
Ende des Krieges hielten jene gleichen Firmen 70 Prozent aller Zivil- 
und militärischen Verträge an. Unternehmensleiter sassen in 
vielen der Schlüsselpfosten, der Kriegproduktion Agenturen und 
dienten als Dollar-ein-Jahr-Männer ", wenn restlich auf ihren 
Firmalohn- und Gehaltslisten</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Du tabagisme pour peler le soin, les annonceurs se sont 
précipités pour identifier leurs produits avec l'effort de guerre 
une fois que les Etats-Unis écrivaient la deuxième guerre mondiale. 
L'utilisation de la guerre pour lancer des produits n'était pas
les entreprises américaines de seule voie bénéficiées de leur 
association avec le conflit. Bien que le gouvernement ait 
contrôlé et ait réglé l'économie de temps de guerre, il souvent a
fait ainsi à l'avantage de grandes compagnies. Les 100 
compagnies principales se sont avérées 30 pour cent des produits 
manufacturés de la nation en 1940 ; par l'extrémité de la 
guerre, ces mêmes compagnies ont tenu 70 pour cent de tous les 
contrats civils et militaires. Les cadres d'affaires se sont 
reposés dans plusieurs des poteaux principaux des agences de 
production de guerre, servant de dollar-un-année-hommes "tandis que 
restants sur leurs livres de paie de compagnie</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">De fumar para descascar o cuidado, os publicitários 
apressaram-se para identificar seus produtos com o esforço da guerra 
uma vez que os estados unidos incorporaram a segunda guerra mundial. 
Usar a guerra lançar produtos não era os negócios americanos 
da única maneira beneficiados de sua associação com o conflito. 
Embora o governo controlasse e regulasse a economia do wartime, 
fêz frequentemente assim ao benefício de companhias grandes. 
As 100 companhias superiores giraram para fora de 30 por cento 
dos bens manufactured da nação em 1940; pela extremidade da 
guerra, aquelas mesmas companhias prenderam 70 por cento de todos os 
contratos civis e militares. Os executivos de negócio 
sentaram-se em muitos dos bornes chaves de agências da produção da 
guerra, servindo como dólar-um-ano-homens "quando restantes em suas 
folhas de pagamento da companhia</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dal fumare per pelare la cura, i advertisers hanno scorso 
veloce per identificare i loro prodotti con lo sforzo di guerra una 
volta che unito Dichiara la seconda guerra mondiale inserita. 
Usando la guerra per lanciare i prodotti non era i commerci 
americani di unico modo tratti giovamento dalla loro associazione con 
il conflitto. Anche se il governo ha gestito e regolato 
l'economia di wartime, ha fatto spesso così a vantaggio di grandi 
aziende. Le 100 aziende principali hanno risultato 30 per cento 
delle merci manufactured della nazione in 1940; dall'estremità 
della guerra, quelle stesse aziende hanno tenuto 70 per cento di tutti
i contratti civili e militari. Gli uomini d'affari si sono 
seduti in molti degli alberini chiave delle agenzie di produzione di 
guerra, serventi da dollaro-un-anno-uomini "mentre restanti sui loro 
libri paga dell'azienda</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το κάπνισμα στη φροντίδα δέρματος, οι δηαφημιστές
όρμηξαν για να προσδιορίσουν τα προϊόντα τους με πολεμική 
προσπάθεια μόλις εισήγαγαν οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες τον παγκόσμιο 
πόλεμο ΙΙ. Η χρησιμοποίηση του πολέμου για να ρίξει τα 
προϊόντα δεν ήταν οι μόνες αμερικανικές επιχειρήσεις τρόπων που
ωφελήθηκαν από την ένωσή τους με τη σύγκρουση. Αν και η 
κυβέρνηση διαχειρίστηκε και ρύθμισε την εν καιρώ πολέμου 
οικονομία, έκανε συχνά έτσι προς όφελος των μεγάλων 
επιχειρήσεων. Οι κορυφαίες 100 επιχειρήσεις έβγαλαν 30
τοις εκατό των κατασκευασμένων αγαθών του έθνους το 1940  
από το πολεμικό τέλος, εκείνες οι ίδιες επιχειρήσεις 
κράτησαν 70 τοις εκατό όλων των πολιτικών και στρατιωτικών 
συμβάσεων. Οι επιχειρησιακοί ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι κάθισαν σε 
πολλές από τις βασικές θέσεις των αντιπροσωπειών πολεμικής 
παραγωγής, που χρησιμεύουν ως τα δολάριο-α-έτος-άτομα "υπόλοιποι
στις μισθοδοτικές καταστάσεις επιχείρησής τους</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De fumar para pelar cuidado, los publicistas acometieron 
para identificar sus productos con el esfuerzo de la guerra una vez 
que los Estados Unidos incorporaran la Segunda Guerra Mundial. 
Usar la guerra para echar productos no era los negocios 
americanos de la única manera beneficiados de su asociación con el 
conflicto. Aunque el gobierno manejó y reguló la economía del
tiempo de guerra, hizo a menudo tan a la ventaja de compañías 
grandes. Las 100 compañías superiores resultaron 30 por ciento
de los productos manufacturados de la nación en 1940; al lado 
del extremo de la guerra, esas mismas compañías llevaron a cabo 70 
por ciento de todos los contratos civiles y militares. Los 
ejecutivos de negocio se sentaron en muchos de los postes dominantes 
de las agencias de la producción de la guerra, sirviendo como 
do'lar-uno-año-hombres "mientras que son restantes en sus nóminas de
pago de la compañía</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087123</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106931</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/to-buy-is-patriotic</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
