<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104280</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104280</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211342</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NOAA Photo Library: America's Coastlines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NOAA Foto-Bibliothek: Küstenlinien 
Amerikas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bibliothèque de Photo de NOAA : Les 
Littoraux de l'Amérique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biblioteca Da Foto de NOAA: Coastlines De 
América</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Libreria Della Foto di NOAA: Linee costiere 
Dell'America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βιβλιοθήκη φωτογραφιών NOAA: Ακτές της 
Αμερικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biblioteca De la Foto de NOAA: Líneas de la
costa De América</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">America has 95,000 miles of coastline. In this collection of images from NOAA, the user can view images of America's coasts and adjacent coastal regions. Images include early Nineteenth Century sketches and drawings and modern photographs of waves, rocky shores, sandy beaches, marshes, mangroves, seaside villages, and port cities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerika hat 95.000 Meilen der Küstenlinie. 
In dieser Ansammlung Bildern von NOAA, kann der Benutzer Bilder 
von Küsten und von angrenzenden Küstengebieten Amerikas ansehen. 
Bilder schließen früh 19.jahrhundertskizzen und Zeichnungen 
und moderne Fotographien der Wellen, der felsigen Ufer, der sandigen 
Strände, der Sümpfe, der Mangroven, der Küstedörfer und der 
Kanalstädte ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Amérique a 95.000 milles de littoral. 
Dans cette collection d'images de NOAA, l'utilisateur peut 
visualiser des images des côtes et des régions côtières 
limitrophes de l'Amérique. Les images incluent tôt les 
dix-neuvième croquis de siècle et les schémas et les photographies 
modernes des vagues, des rivages rocheux, des plages sablonneuses, des
marais, des palétuviers, des villages de bord de la mer, et des 
villes de port.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">América tem 95.000 milhas do coastline. 
Nesta coleção das imagens de NOAA, o usuário pode ver imagens
de costas e de regiões litorais adjacentes de América. As 
imagens incluem cedo décimos nonos esboços do século e desenhos e 
fotografias modernas das ondas, de costas rochosas, de praias 
arenosas, de pântanos, de mangroves, de vilas do seaside, e de 
cidades da porta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'America ha 95.000 miglia della linea costiera. 
In questa accumulazione delle immagini da NOAA, l'utente può 
osservare le immagini dei litorali e delle regioni litoranee adiacenti
dell'America. Le immagini includono presto i diciannovesimi 
abbozzi di secolo ed illustrazioni e fotografie moderne delle onde, 
dei puntelli rocciosi, delle spiagge sabbiose, delle paludi, delle 
mangrovie, dei villaggi del seaside e delle città della porta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Αμερική έχει 95.000 μίλια της ακτής. Σε 
αυτήν την συλλογή των εικόνων από NOAA, ο χρήστης μπορεί να 
εμφανίσει τις εικόνες των παρακείμενων παράκτιων περιοχών της 
Αμερικής των ακτών και. Οι εικόνες περιλαμβάνουν νωρίς τα 
σκίτσα του δέκατου έννατου αιώνα και τα σχέδια και τις σύγχρονες
φωτογραφίες των κυμάτων, των δύσκολων ακτών, των αμμωδών 
παραλιών, των ελών, των μαγγροβίων, των χωριών παραλιών, και των 
πόλεων λιμένων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">América tiene 95.000 millas de la línea de la 
costa. En esta colección de imágenes de NOAA, el utilizador 
puede visión imágenes de las costas y de las regiones costeras 
adyacentes de América. Las imágenes incluyen temprano los 
diecinueveavo bosquejos del siglo y los gráficos y las fotografías 
modernas de ondas, de orillas rocosas, de playas arenosas, de 
pantanos, de mangles, de aldeas de la playa, y de ciudades del acceso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211342</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104280</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/noaa-photo-library-americas-coastlines</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
