<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211500</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Paleotopia: Windows to the Past</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Paleotopia: Windows zur Vergangenheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Paleotopia : Windows au passé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Paleotopia: Windows ao passado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Paleotopia: Windows all'esperienza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Paleotopia: Θ*Ωηνδοως στο παρελθόν</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paleotopia: Windows al pasado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website highlights a game designed for students studying earth science, life science and evolution. The game reinforces the principle that fossils reveal a record of life on earth and help students relate and match fossils of specific life forms to information known about those life forms. Students role-play as paleontologists searching the world for the pre-historic remnants and evidence of past life. Students move through a landscape, dig for discoveries and research fossil information. This website contains game objectives, materials needed, time required to play the game, rules, design processes and additional references.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site markiert ein Spiel, das für die 
Kursteilnehmer konzipiert ist, die Geowissenschaft, Lebenwissenschaft 
und Entwicklung studieren. Das Spiel verstärkt die Grundregel, 
daß Fossilien einen Satz des Lebens auf Masse aufdecken und Hilfe 
Kursteilnehmer Fossilien der spezifischen Lebensformen zu den 
Informationen in Verbindung stehen und zusammenbringen, die über jene
Lebensformen bekannt sind. Kursteilnehmer spielen als 
Paläontologen Rolle, die die Welt nach den prähistorischen Resten 
und dem Beweis der letzten Lebensdauer suchen. Kursteilnehmer 
ziehen durch eine Landschaft um, graben zu Entdeckungen und Forschung 
Fossilinformation. Diese Web site enthält Spiellernziele, die 
Materialien, die benötigt werden, die Zeit, die benötigt werden, um 
das Spiel zu spielen, die Richtlinien, die Designprozesse und die 
zusätzlichen Referenzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web met en valeur un jeu conçu pour des 
étudiants étudiant la science de la terre, la science de vie et 
l'évolution. Le jeu renforce le principe que les fossiles 
indiquent un enregistrement de la vie sur terre et des étudiants 
d'aide associent et apparient des fossiles des formes de vie 
spécifiques à l'information connue au sujet de ces formes de vie. 
Les étudiants jouent un rôle comme paléontologistes 
recherchant le monde les restes et l'évidence préhistoriques de la 
vie passée. Les étudiants se déplacent par un horizontal, 
creusent pour des découvertes et l'information de fossile de 
recherches. Ce site Web contient des objectifs de jeu, des 
matériaux requis, le temps requis pour jouer le jeu, des règles, des
processus de conception et des références supplémentaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site destaca um jogo projetado para os 
estudantes que estudam a ciência de terra, a ciência de vida e a 
evolução. O jogo reforça o princípio que os fossils revelam 
um registro da vida na terra e estudantes da ajuda relaciona e combina
fossils de formulários de vida específicos à informação sabida 
sobre aqueles formulários de vida. Os estudantes role-play como
os paleontologists que procuraram o mundo pelos restos e pela 
evidência pré-históricos da vida passada. Os estudantes 
movem-se com uma paisagem, escavam-se para descobertas e informação 
do fossil da pesquisa. Este Web site contem objetivos do jogo, 
materiais necessitados, tempo requerido para jogar o jogo, réguas, 
processos do projeto e referências adicionais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site evidenzia un gioco progettato per 
gli allievi che studiano le scienze della terra, le scienze biologiche
e lo sviluppo. Il gioco rinforza il principio che i fossili 
rivelano un record di vita su terra ed allievi di aiuto collega ed 
abbina i fossili delle forme di vita specifiche alle informazioni 
conosciute circa quelle forme di vita. Gli allievi si atteggiano
come paleontologists che cercano il mondo i resti e la prova 
pre-historic di vita passata. Gli allievi si muovono con un 
paesaggio, scavano per le scoperte e le informazioni del fossile di 
ricerca. Questo Web site contiene gli obiettivi del gioco, i 
materiali stati necessari, il tempo richiesto per giocare il gioco, le
regole, i processi di disegno ed i riferimenti supplementari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος δίνει έμφαση σε ένα παιχνίδι που 
σχεδιάζεται για τους σπουδαστές που μελετούν τη γήινη επιστήμη, 
τη βιολογική επιστήμη και την εξέλιξη. Το παιχνίδι ενισχύει
την αρχή ότι τα απολιθώματα αποκαλύπτουν ένα αρχείο της ζωής 
στη γη και οι σπουδαστές οδηγιών αφορούν και ταιριάζουν με τα 
απολιθώματα των συγκεκριμένων μορφών ζωής τις πληροφορίες που 
είναι γνωστές για εκείνες τις μορφές ζωής. Ρόλος-παιχνίδι
σπουδαστών ως παλαιοντολόγος που ψάχνουν τον κόσμο για τα 
προϊστορικά υπόλοιπα και τα στοιχεία της προηγούμενης ζωής. 
Οι σπουδαστές κινούνται μέσω ενός τοπίου, σκάβουν για τις 
ανακαλύψεις και τις ερευνητικές απολιθωμένες πληροφορίες. 
Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τους στόχους παιχνιδιών, τα 
υλικά που απαιτούνται, το χρόνο που απαιτούνται για να παίξουν το
παιχνίδι, τους κανόνες, τις διαδικασίες σχεδίου και τις πρόσθετες
αναφορές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site destaca un juego diseñado para los 
estudiantes que estudian geología, ciencia de vida y la evolución. 
El juego refuerza el principio que los fósiles revelan un 
expediente de la vida en la tierra y los estudiantes de la ayuda 
relaciona y corresponde con los fósiles de las formas de vida 
específicas a la información sabida sobre esas formas de vida. 
Los estudiantes actúan en papel como paleontólogos que buscan el 
mundo para los remanente y la evidencia prehistóricos de la última 
vida. Los estudiantes se mueven con un paisaje, cavan para los 
descubrimientos y la información del fósil de la investigación. 
Este Web site contiene objetivos del juego, los materiales 
necesitados, el tiempo requerido para jugar el juego, reglas, procesos
del diseño y referencias adicionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JERRY MARINO
FN:JERRY MARINO
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SUSAN CONNELL
FN:SUSAN CONNELL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MATT MCNERNEY
FN:MATT MCNERNEY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211500</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105201</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/paleotopia-windows-to-the-past</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
