<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104910</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104910</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202757</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Improving Student Essay Writing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verbessern Des Kursteilnehmer-Versuch-Schreibens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Amélioration de l'Écriture d'Essai D'Étudiant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Melhorando A Escrita Do Essay Do Estudante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Migliorare Scrittura Di Saggio Dell'Allievo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βελτίωση του γραψίματος δοκίμιου σπουδαστών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mejorar La Escritura Del Ensayo Del Estudiante</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">English II teachers are constantly searching for strategies to improve students' analytical responses to literature. This lesson is designed for all types of learners, offering various activities for all learning styles. Individual, small group, and whole class activities on essay writing culminate with the student writing his or her own formal response to literature.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lehrer Englisch II suchen ständig nach 
Strategien, um analytische Antworten der Kursteilnehmer zur Literatur 
zu verbessern. Diese Lektion ist für alle Typen Anfänger 
bestimmt und bietet verschiedene Aktivitäten für alle erlernenarten 
an. Einzelne, kleine Gruppe und vollständige Kategorie 
Aktivitäten auf Versuchschreiben kulminieren mit dem Kursteilnehmer, 
der seine oder eigene formale Antwort zur Literatur schreibt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les professeurs de l'anglais II recherchent 
constamment des stratégies pour améliorer les réponses analytiques 
des étudiants à la littérature. Cette leçon est conçue pour
tous les types d'étudiants, offrant de diverses activités pour tous 
les modèles d'étude. Le groupe individuel et petit, et les 
activités entières de classe sur l'écriture d'essai culminent avec 
l'étudiant écrivant sa propre réponse formelle à la littérature.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os professores do inglês II estão procurarando 
constantemente por estratégias para melhorar respostas analíticas 
dos estudantes à literatura. Esta lição é projetada para 
todos os tipos de learners, oferecendo várias atividades para todos 
os estilos de aprendizagem. O grupo individual, pequeno, e as 
atividades inteiras da classe na escrita do essay culminam com o 
estudante que escrevem his ou sua própria resposta formal à 
literatura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli insegnanti di inglese II stanno cercando 
costantemente le strategie per migliorare le risposte analitiche degli
allievi a letteratura. Questa lezione è progettata per tutti i 
tipi di principianti, offrenti le varie attività per tutti gli stili 
imparanti. Il gruppo specifico e piccolo e le attività intere 
del codice categoria su scrittura di saggio culminano con l'allievo 
che scrive la sua propria risposta convenzionale a letteratura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αγγλικοί ΙΙ δάσκαλοι ψάχνουν συνεχώς για τις 
στρατηγικές για να βελτιώσουν τις αναλυτικές απαντήσεις των 
σπουδαστών στη λογοτεχνία. Αυτό το μάθημα σχεδιάζεται για 
όλους τους τύπους αρχαρίων, που προσφέρουν τις διάφορες 
δραστηριότητες για όλες τις μορφές εκμάθησης. Η μεμονωμένη,
μικρή ομάδα, και ολόκληρες οι δραστηριότητες κλάσης στο γράψιμο 
δοκίμιου καταλήγουν με το σπουδαστή που γράφει την επίσημη 
απάντησή του/της στη λογοτεχνία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los profesores del inglés II están buscando 
constantemente para estrategias para mejorar las respuestas 
analíticas de los estudiantes a la literatura. Esta lección se
diseña para todos los tipos de principiantes, ofreciendo las varias 
actividades para todos los estilos que aprenden. El grupo 
individual, pequeño, y las actividades enteras de la clase en la 
escritura del ensayo culminan con el estudiante que escribe el suyo o 
su propia respuesta formal a la literatura.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SHAWN PARKER
FN:SHAWN PARKER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202757</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104910</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/improving-student-essay-writing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
