<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104184</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104184</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209858</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Coplanar </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Koplanar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Coplanaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Coplanar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Complanare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συνεπίπεδος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Coplanario</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of coplanar objects - those that lie in the same plane. The applet presents two planes. In one plane there are two rectangles that can be dragged around and which lie in the same plane always. The other is a rectangle that can be dragged but always lies in a plane orthogonal to the first. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept der koplanaren Nachrichten - die zeigen, die
in der gleichen Fläche liegen. Der applet stellt zwei Flächen 
dar. In einer Fläche gibt es zwei Vierecke, die herum 
geschleppt werden können und die in der gleichen Fläche immer 
liegen. Das andere ist ein Viereck, das geschleppt werden kann, 
aber immer in einer Fläche liegt, die zur ersten orthogonal ist. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept des objets coplanaires - ceux qui se 
situent dans le même avion. L'applet présente deux avions. 
Dans un avion il y a deux rectangles qui peuvent être traînés
autour et qui se situent dans le même avion toujours. L'autre 
est un rectangle qui peut être traîné mais se situe toujours dans 
un avion orthogonal au premier. L'applet peut être agrandi à 
la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito de objetos coplanar - aqueles que se encontram 
no mesmo plano. O applet apresenta dois planos. Em um 
plano há dois retângulos que podem ser arrastados ao redor e que se 
encontram no mesmo plano sempre. O outro é um retângulo que 
possa ser arrastado mas se encontre sempre em um plano orthogonal ao 
primeiro. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto degli oggetti complanari - quelli che si 
trovano nello stesso aereo. Il applet presenta due aerei. 
In un aereo ci sono due rettangoli che possono essere trascinati
intorno e che si trovano sempre nello stesso aereo. L'altro è 
un rettangolo che può essere trascinato ma sempre si trova in un 
aereo ortogonale al primo. Il applet può essere ingrandito al 
formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια των συνεπίπεδων αντικειμένων - εκείνοι 
που βρίσκονται στο ίδιο αεροπλάνο. Το applet παρουσιάζει 
δύο αεροπλάνα. Σε ένα αεροπλάνο υπάρχουν δύο ορθογώνια 
που μπορούν να σέρθούν γύρω και που βρίσκονται στο ίδιο 
αεροπλάνο πάντα. Αλλο είναι ένα ορθογώνιο που μπορεί να 
σέρθεί αλλά πάντα βρίσκεται σε ένα αεροπλάνο ορθογώνιο στον 
πρώτο. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος
οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη 
χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον 
πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto de los objetos coplanarios - los que mientan en
el mismo plano. El applet presenta dos planos. En un plano
hay dos rectángulos que pueden ser arrastrados alrededor y que 
mienten en el mismo plano siempre. El otro es un rectángulo que
se puede arrastrar pero miente siempre en un plano orthogonal al 
primer. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla 
completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El 
uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso 
otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin 
la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un componente del 
proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la 
referencia abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209858</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104184</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/coplanar</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
