<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103199</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103199</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200721</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Brave New Biosphere: Story of a Squid</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tapfere Neue Biosphäre: Geschichte eines 
Kalmars</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bravez La Nouvelle Biosphère : 
Histoire d'un calmar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biosphere Novo Bravo: História de um 
calamar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nuova Biosfera Brave: Storia di un calamaro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γενναία νέα βιόσφαιρα: Ιστορία ενός καλαμαριού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nueva Biosfera Valiente: Historia de un 
calamar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Why Files informative page is part of a series that features the narrative of Bob, the bobtail squid. Bob describes the symbiotic relationship formed between his ancestors and the bioluminescent bacteria that offer him protection from predators. The next page in this series describes the relationship from the enslaved bacteria's perspective and features scientist Margaret McFall-Ngai. Links are provided to glossary terms and a bibliography.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses, warum informative Seite der Dateien ein 
Teil einer Serie ist, die die Darstellung von Bob kennzeichnet, der 
bobtail Kalmar. Bob beschreibt das symbiotische Verhältnis, das
zwischen seinen Vorfahren und dem bioluminescent Bakterium, die, 
gebildet wird ihm Schutz vor Fleischfressern anbieten. Die 
folgende Seite in dieser Serie beschreibt das Verhältnis von der 
versklavten Perspektive des Bakteriums und kennzeichnet 
Wissenschaftler Margaret McFall-Ngai. Links werden zu den 
Glossarbezeichnungen und zu einer Bibliographie zur Verfügung 
gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ceci pourquoi la page instructive de fichiers fait
partie d'une série qui comporte le récit de Bob, le calmar de 
bobtail. Bob décrit le rapport symbiotique formé entre ses 
ancêtres et les bactéries bioluminescent qui lui offrent la 
protection contre des prédateurs. La prochaine page de cette 
série décrit le rapport de la perspective des bactéries asservies 
et comporte le scientifique Margaret McFall-Ngai. Des liens 
sont fournis aux limites de glossaire et à une bibliographie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Isto porque a página informative das limas é 
parte de uma série que caracterize a narrativa de Bob, o calamar do 
bobtail. Bob descreve o relacionamento symbiotic dado forma 
entre seus antepassados e as bactérias bioluminescent que lhe 
oferecem a proteção dos predadores. A página seguinte nesta 
série descreve o relacionamento do perspective das bactérias 
enslaved e caracteriza o cientista Margaret McFall-Ngai. As 
ligações são fornecidas aos termos do glossário e a uma 
bibliografia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò perchè la pagina informativa degli archivi 
fa parte di una serie che caratterizza la descrizione di Bob, il 
calamaro del bobtail. Bob descrive il rapporto simbiotico 
formato fra i suoi antenati ed i batteri bioluminescent che gli 
offrono la protezione dai predatori. La pagina seguente in 
questa serie descrive il rapporto dalla prospettiva dei batteri 
asserviti e caratterizza lo scienziato Margaret McFall-Ngai. I 
collegamenti sono forniti ai termini del glossario e ad una 
bibliografia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό γιατί η πληροφοριακή σελίδα αρχείων είναι 
μέρος μιας σειράς που χαρακτηρίζει το αφήγημα του βαριδιού, το 
καλαμάρι bobtail. Το βαρίδι περιγράφει τη συμβιοτική 
σχέση που διαμορφώνεται μεταξύ των προγόνων του και των 
βιοφωτοβόλων βακτηριδίων που του προσφέρουν την προστασία από τα 
αρπακτικά ζώα. Η επόμενη σελίδα σε αυτήν την σειρά 
περιγράφει τη σχέση από την υποδουλωμένη προοπτική των 
βακτηριδίων και χαρακτηρίζει τον επιστήμονα Margaret 
McFall-Ngai. Οι συνδέσεις παρέχονται στους όρους 
γλωσσαριών και μια βιβλιογραφία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto porqué la paginación informativa de los 
ficheros es parte de una serie que ofrezca la narrativa de Bob, el 
calamar del bobtail. Bob describe el lazo simbiótico formado 
entre sus antepasados y las bacterias bioluminescent que le ofrezcan 
la protección contra depredadores. La paginación siguiente en 
esta serie describe el lazo de la perspectiva de las bacterias 
esclavizadas y ofrece a científico Margaret McFall-Ngai. Las 
conexiones se proporcionan a términos del glosario y a una 
bibliografía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:THE WHY FILES
FN:THE WHY FILES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200721</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103199</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/brave-new-biosphere-story-of-a-squid</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
