<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086972</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The ideal picket."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der ideale Pfosten."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le piquet idéal."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o piquete ideal."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il picchetto ideale."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο ιδανικός στύλος."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el piquete ideal."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Labor activism during the 1930s had an impact on U.S. popular culture, especially film--both on screen and behind the camera. The Screen Actors Guild was formed in 1933 and In 1941 trade union organizing reached the workplace where some of the nation's favorite fantasies were produced. After Walt Disney fired union organizers on his art staff, his studio cartoonists went on strike. This cartoon from a newspaper report indicates how Disney strikers brought new skills to labor organizing. "There are mighty few labor disputes," the caption states, "in which just about every striker can make his own picket signs. Consequently, the signs are bright and lively . . . attracting the passerby and winning friends for the Screen Cartoon Guild."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeitsaktivismus während der dreißiger Jahre hatte eine
Auswirkung auf VEREINIGTE STAATEN populäre Kultur, besonders Film -- 
auf Bildschirm und hinter der Kamera. Die 
Bildschirm-Schauspieler-Zünft wurde 1933 gebildet und 1941 
Gewerkschaft erreichte das Organisieren den Arbeitsplatz, in dem 
einige der Lieblingsphantasien der Nation produziert wurden. 
Nachdem Walt Disney Anschlußorganisatoren auf seinem 
kunstpersonal feuerte, streikten seine Studiokarikaturenzeichner. 
Diese Karikatur von einem Zeitung Report zeigt an, wie Disney 
Schlaggeräte neue Fähigkeiten holten, um das Organisieren zu 
bearbeiten. "es gibt wenige arbeitsrechtliche Streitigkeiten," 
die Untertitel-Zustände, "mächtig in, welchem gerade über jedes 
Schlaggerät seine eigenen Pfostenzeichen bilden kann. 
Infolgedessen sind die Zeichen hell und lebhaft. . .
Anziehen des Passanten und Gewinnen der Freunde für die 
Bildschirm-Karikatur-Zünft."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'activisme de travail pendant les années 30 a eu un 
impact sur la culture populaire des ETATS-UNIS, particulièrement film
-- sur l'écran et derrière l'appareil-photo. La guilde 
d'acteurs de cinéma a été formée en 1933 et à 1941 syndicats 
l'organisation a atteint le lieu de travail où certains des 
imaginations préférées de la nation ont été produits. 
Après que Walt Disney ait mis le feu à des organisateurs des 
syndicats sur son personnel d'art, ses réalisateurs de dessins 
animés de studio ont fait la grève. Ce dessin animé d'un 
état de journal indique comment les butées de Disney ont apporté de
nouvelles qualifications pour travailler l'organisation. "il y a
puissant peu de conflits de travail," les états de légende, "dans ce
qui juste au sujet de chaque butée peut faire ses propres signes de 
piquet. En conséquence, les signes sont lumineux et animés. 
. . attraction du passant et gain des amis pour la 
guilde de dessin animé d'écran."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O activism labor durante os 1930s teve um impacto na 
cultura popular de ESTADOS UNIDOS, especial película --  na tela e 
atrás da câmera. O guild dos atores de tela foi dado forma em 
1933 e na união 1941 de comércio organizar alcançou o workplace 
onde alguns dos fantasies favoritos da nação foram produzidos. 
Depois que Walt Disney ateou fogo a organizers da união em sua 
equipe de funcionários da arte, seus cartoonists do estúdio foram na
batida. Este cartoon de um relatório do jornal indica como os 
grevistas de Disney trouxeram habilidades novas para trabalhar 
organizar. "há poderoso poucas disputas labor," os estados do 
subtítulo, "em qual apenas sobre cada grevista pode fazer seus 
próprios sinais do piquete. Conseqüentemente, os sinais são 
brilhantes e vívidos. . . atraindo o transeunte e 
ganhando amigos para o guild do cartoon da tela."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il activism di lavoro durante i 1930s ha avuto un effetto
sulla coltura popolare degli STATI UNITI, particolarmente pellicola --
sia sullo schermo che dietro la macchina fotografica. La 
cooperativa degli attori di schermo è stata formata in 1933 ed in 
1941 sindacati organizzare ha raggiunto il posto di lavoro in cui 
alcune delle fantasie favorite della nazione sono state prodotte. 
Dopo che Walt Disney inforni gli organizzatori del sindacato sul
suo personale di arte, i suoi cartoonists dell'studio sono andato sul 
colpo. Questo fumetto da un rapporto del giornale indica come i 
percussori del Disney hanno portato le nuove abilità 
all'organizzazione di lavoro. "ci è mighty poche dispute di 
lavoro," il titolo dichiara, "in quale appena circa ogni 
percussore può fare i suoi propri segni del picchetto. Di 
conseguenza, i segni sono luminosi e vivaci. . . 
attrarre il passerby e vincere gli amici per la cooperativa del 
fumetto dello schermo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ακτιβισμός εργασίας κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας 
του '30 άσκησε επίδραση στον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ δημοφιλή πολιτισμό, 
ειδικά ταινία -- και στην οθόνη και πίσω από τη φωτογραφική 
μηχανή. Η συντεχνία δραστών οθόνης διαμορφώθηκε το 1933 
και το 1941 η οργάνωση συνδικάτων έφθασε στον εργασιακό χώρο 
όπου μερικές από τις αγαπημένες φαντασίες του έθνους 
παρήχθησαν. Μετά από απολυθέντες τους Disney διοργανωτές
ένωσης Walt στο προσωπικό τέχνης του, οι σκιτσογράφοι 
στούντιό του πήγαν στην απεργία. Αυτά τα κινούμενα σχέδια
από μια έκθεση εφημερίδων δείχνουν πώς οι απεργοί Disney 
έφεραν τις νέες δεξιότητες στην οργάνωση εργασίας. 
"Υπάρχουν δυνατές λίγες διαφωνίες εργασίας," τα κράτη 
τίτλων, "σε όποιος ακριβώς για κάθε απεργό μπορεί να κάνει τα 
σημάδια στύλων του. Συνεπώς, τα σημάδια είναι φωτεινά και 
ζωηρά. .. προσελκύοντας τον περαστικό και κερδίζοντας 
τους φίλους για τη συντεχνία κινούμενων σχεδίων οθόνης."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El activismo de trabajo durante los años 30 tenía un 
impacto en la cultura popular de ESTADOS UNIDOS, especialmente 
película -- en la pantalla y detrás de la cámara fotográfica. 
El gremio de los agentes de pantalla fue formado en 1933 y en 
1941 sindicatos la ordenación alcanzó el lugar de trabajo en donde 
algunas de las fantasías preferidas de la nación fueron producidas. 
Después de que Walt Disney encendiera a organizadores de la 
unión en su personal del arte, sus dibujantes del estudio fueron en 
huelga. Esta historieta de un informe del periódico indica 
cómo los huelguistas de Disney trajeron nuevas habilidades para 
trabajar la ordenación. "hay poderoso pocos conflictos de 
trabajo," los estados del encabezamiento, "en cuál apenas sobre cada 
huelguista puede hacer sus propias muestras del piquete. Por lo 
tanto, las muestras son brillantes y animadas. . . 
atracción del traseúnte y ganar a amigos para el gremio de la 
historieta de la pantalla."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086972</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103953</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-ideal-picket</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
