<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106598</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106598</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087077</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The White Man's Road is Easier!": A Hidatsa Indian Takes up the Ways of the White Man in the Late 19th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die weißen Straße des Mannes ist!" einfacher: 
Ein Hidatsa Inder nimmt die Methoden des weißen Mannes im des 
späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert auf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la route de l'homme blanc est plus facile!" : 
Un Indien de Hidatsa prend les voies de l'homme blanc vers la 
fin du 19ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a estrada do homem branco é mais fácil!": 
Um indian de Hidatsa faz exame acima das maneiras do homem 
branco no 1ø século atrasado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la strada dell'uomo bianco è più facile!": 
Un indiano di Hidatsa prende i modi dell'uomo bianco verso la 
fine del diciannovesimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο άσπρος ανθρώπινος δρόμος είναι ευκολότερος!": 
Ένα Hidatsa Ινδός λαμβάνει τους τρόπους του λευκού 
ατόμου προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el camino del hombre blanco es más fácil!": 
Un indio de Hidatsa toma las maneras del hombre blanco en la a 
fines del siglo XIX</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Following the passage of the Dawes Act in 1887, which forced Plains Indians to give up communal ways of life for individual family farms, many American Indians struggled to adapt to the new ways of life being dictated to them. But while many suffered under the federal government's attempt to exorcise Indian customs and beliefs some, like Edward Goodbird, a member of the Hidatsa tribe in North Dakota, embraced the new order. In this excerpt from his autobiography, Goodbird described the often subtle ways in which Indians managed to retain small aspects of their culture.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach dem Durchgang der Dawes Tat 1887, das die 
vorverlegten Ebenen Inder, zum von von Kommunallebensarten für 
einzelne Familie oben zu geben bewirtschaftet, kämpften viele 
Indianer, um sich den neuen Lebensarten anzupassen vorschreibend zu 
ihnen. Aber während viele, die unter dem Versuch der 
Bundesregierung, indische Gewohnheiten und Glauben zu exorzieren 
einige, wie Edward Goodbird, ein Bauteil des Hidatsa Stammes in North 
Dakota erlitten wurden, die neue Ordnung umfaßten. In diesem 
Excerpt von seiner Autobiographie, beschrieb Goodbird die häufig 
subtilen Methoden, in denen Inder handhatten, kleine Aspekte ihrer 
Kultur beizubehalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après le passage de l'acte de Dawes en 1887, que 
les Indiens de plaines obligatoires pour renoncer à des façons de 
vivre communales pour la famille individuelle cultive, beaucoup 
d'Indiens américains ont lutté pour s'adapter aux nouvelles façons 
de vivre étant dicté à elles. Mais tandis que beaucoup 
soufferts sous la tentative de gouvernement fédéral d'exorcizer des 
coutumes et la croyance indiennes certains, comme Edouard 
Goodbird, un membre de la tribu de Hidatsa au Dakota du nord, 
embrassaient la nouvelle commande. Dans cet extrait de son 
autobiographie, Goodbird a décrit les voies souvent subtiles dans 
lesquelles les Indiens sont parvenus à maintenir de petits aspects de
leur culture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Depois da passagem do ato de Dawes em 1887, que os
indians de planícies forçados para dar acima maneiras de vida 
communal para a família individual cultivam, muitos indians 
americanos esforçaram-se para adaptar-se às maneiras de vida novas 
que está sendo ditada a elas. Mas quando muitos sofridos sob a 
tentativa de governo federal de exorcise costumes e a opinião indian 
alguns, como Edward Goodbird, um membro do tribe de Hidatsa em dakota 
norte, embraced a ordem nova. Neste excerpt de seu 
autobiography, Goodbird descreveu as maneiras frequentemente subtle em
que os indians controlaram reter aspectos pequenos de sua cultura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A seguito del passaggio della Legge di Dawes in 
1887, che gli indiani di pianure forzati per dare in su i modo di 
vivere comunali per la famiglia specifica coltiva, molti indiani 
americani hanno lottato per adattarsi ai nuovi modo di vivere che è 
dettato a loro. Ma mentre molti sofferti sotto il tentativo del 
governo federale di exorcise le abitudini e la credenza indiane 
alcuni, come Edward Goodbird, un membro della tribù di Hidatsa nel 
Dakota del Nord, hanno abbracciato il nuovo ordine. In questo 
brano dal suo autobiography, Goodbird ha descritto i modi spesso 
sottili in cui gli indiani sono riuscito a mantenere le piccole 
funzioni della loro coltura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από τη μετάβαση του νόμου Dawes το 1887, 
που ανάγκασε τις πεδιάδες Ινδοί για να σταματήσει τους 
κοινοτικούς τρόπους της ζωής για τα μεμονωμένα οικογενειακά 
αγροκτήματα, πολλοί αμερικανικοί Ινδοί αγωνίστηκαν να 
προσαρμοστούν στους νέους τρόπους της υπαγόρευσης της ζωής σε 
τους. Αλλά ενώ πολλοί που υποφέρονται κάτω από την 
προσπάθεια της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης το ινδικές τελωνείο και 
οι πεποιθήσεις μερικές, όπως τον Edward Goodbird, ένα μέλος
της φυλής Hidatsa στη βόρεια Ντακότα, αγκαλίασε τη νέα 
κατάταξη. Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από την αυτοβιογραφία του, 
Goodbird περιέγραψε τους συχνά λεπτούς τρόπους με τους οποίους
Ινδοί κατόρθωσαν να διατηρήσουν τις μικρές πτυχές του πολιτισμού
τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después del paso del acto de Dawes en 1887, que 
los indios de llanos forzados para dar para arriba maneras de la vida 
comunales para la familia individual cultivan, muchos indios 
americanos lucharon para adaptarse a las nuevas maneras de la vida que
era dictada a ellas. Pero mientras que muchos sufridos bajo 
tentativa del gobierno federal de exorcise costumbres y creencia 
indios algunos, como Edward Goodbird, un miembro de la tribu de 
Hidatsa en Dakota del Norte, abrazaron la nueva orden. En este 
extracto de su autobiografía, Goodbird describió las maneras a 
menudo sutiles en las cuales los indios manejaron conservar aspectos 
pequeños de su cultura.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087077</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106598</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-white-mans-road-is-easier-a-hidatsa-indian-takes-up-the-ways-of-the-white-man-in-the-late-19th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
