<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107516</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107516</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200821</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Cause of Seasons Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ursache der Jahreszeit-Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cause des animations de saisons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Causa de animations das estações</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Causa delle animazioni di stagioni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αιτία των ζωτικοτήτων εποχών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Causa de las animaciones de las estaciones</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features Flash, QuickTime, and GIF animations that illustrate the cause of seasons, how seasons impact the sun's apparent path across the Earth's sky, the subsolar point, and the circle of illumination. The animations can be paused and rewound to stress important points. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale blinken, QuickTime und 
GIF Animationen, die die Ursache von Jahreszeiten veranschaulichen, 
wie Jahreszeiten den offensichtlichen Pfad des Sonnen über dem Himmel
der Masse, dem subsolar Punkt und dem Kreis der Ablichtung auswirken. 
Die Animationen können pausiert werden und gerückspult werden,
um wichtige Punkte zu betonen. Diese Betriebsmittel sind für 
Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, in den Labors oder in anderen 
unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dispositifs de ce site flashent, QuickTime, et
animations de GIF qui illustrent la cause des saisons, comment les 
saisons effectuent la voie d'accès apparente du soleil à travers le 
ciel de la terre, le point subsolar, et le cercle de l'illumination. 
Les animations peuvent être faites une pause et rebobinées 
pour soumettre à une contrainte les points importants. Ces 
ressources conviennent pour l'usage dans les conférences, les 
laboratoires, ou d'autres activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As características deste local piscam, QuickTime,
e animations do GIF que ilustram a causa das estações, como as 
estações impactam o trajeto aparente do sun através do céu da 
terra, do ponto subsolar, e do círculo da iluminação. Os 
animations podem ser pausados e rebobinado para forçar pontos 
importantes. Estes recursos são apropriados para o uso nos 
lectures, nos laboratórios, ou em outras atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo espongono a flash,
QuickTime ed animazioni del GIF che illustrano la causa delle 
stagioni, come le stagioni hanno effetto sul percorso apparente del 
sun attraverso il cielo della terra, il punto subsolar ed il cerchio 
di illuminazione. Le animazioni possono essere fatte una pausa e
riavvolte per sollecitare i punti importanti. Queste risorse 
sono adatte ad uso nelle conferenze, in laboratori, o in altre 
attività d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις ζωτικότητες λάμψης, 
QuickTime, και GIF που επεξηγούν την αιτία των εποχών, πώς 
οι εποχές επηρεάζουν το προφανές μονοπάτι του ήλιου πέρα από το
γήινο ουρανό, το subsolar σημείο, και τον κύκλο του φωτισμού. 
Οι ζωτικότητες μπορούν να σταματηθούν και rewound για να 
τονίζουν τα σημαντικά σημεία. Αυτά τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για τη χρήση στις διαλέξεις, τα 
εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las características de este sitio contellean, 
QuickTime, y las animaciones del GIF que ilustran la causa de 
estaciones, cómo las estaciones afectan el camino evidente del sun a 
través del cielo de la tierra, de la punta subsolar, y del círculo 
de la iluminación. Las animaciones se pueden detener brevemente
y rebobinar para tensionar puntas importantes. Estos recursos 
son convenientes para el uso en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras 
actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200821</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107516</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/cause-of-seasons-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
