<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108425</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108425</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Housewives in Uniform: Domesticity as Military Duty</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hausfrauen in der Uniform: Domesticity als 
militärische Aufgabe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Femmes au foyer dans l'uniforme : Domesticité
en tant que devoir militaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Housewives no uniforme: Domesticidade como o
dever militar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Casalinghe in Uniforme: Domesticity come 
dovere militare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νοικοκυρές σε ομοιόμορφο: Νοικοκυροσύνη ως 
στρατιωτικό καθήκον</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Amas de casa en Uniforme: Domesticidad 
como deber militar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With U.S. entry into World War I, President Woodrow Wilson appointed Herbert Hoover to head the newly created U.S. Food Administration. A mining engineer who had successfully organized the massive effort to get food to Belgium's citizens after the German army's sweep through that country in 1914, Hoover was now charged with managing domestic agriculture and conservation in order to feed the U.S. Army and assist Allied armies and civilians. "Food Will Win the War," declared the Food Administration through its ubiquitous posters and publicity efforts. Planting gardens, observing voluntary rationing, avoiding waste--these efforts at food conservation all came to be known as "Hooverizing." Women's magazines also took up the home conservation crusade, some employing military analogies to promote the recommendations of the Food Administration. Presenting domestic work as patriotic effort, this U.S. Food Administration campaign in  Good Housekeeping  offered women a membership shield and even provided instructions for sewing a "patriotic" housekeeping uniform.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit VEREINIGTE STAATEN Eintrag in den Ersten 
Weltkrieg, ernannte Präsident Woodrow Wilson Herbert Staubsauger, um 
die eben erstellte VEREINIGTE STAATEN Nahrungsmittelleitung 
voranzugehen. Ein Mineningenieur, der erfolgreich die massive 
Bemühung organisiert hatte, Nahrung an Bürger Belgiens nach der 
deutschen Schleife der Armee durch dieses Land 1914 zu gelangen, 
Staubsauger wurde jetzt mit dem Handhaben der inländischen 
Landwirtschaft und der Erhaltung, um die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Armee 
einzuziehen und verbündete Armeen und Zivilisten zu unterstützen 
aufgeladen. "Nahrung gewinnt den Krieg," erklärte die 
Nahrungsmittelleitung durch seine überall vorhandenen Plakate und 
Werbebemühungen. Gärten errichten, das freiwillige Rationieren
beobachtend und vermeiden Vergeudung -- diese Bemühungen an der 
Nahrungsmittelerhaltung alle kamen, als "Hooverizing bekannt." 
Zeitschriften der Frauen nahmen auch den Haupterhaltung 
Kreuzzug, einige beschäftigende militärische Analogien auf, um die 
Empfehlungen der Nahrungsmittelleitung zu fördern. Inländische
Arbeit als patriotische Bemühung, diese VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Nahrungsmittelleitung Kampagne in der guten Haushaltung darstellen 
Frauen ein Mitgliedschaft Schild und sogar zur Verfügung gestellte 
Anweisungen für das Nähen einer "patriotischen" Haushaltunguniform 
angeboten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec l'entrée des ETATS-UNIS dans la Première 
Guerre Mondiale, le Président Woodrow Wilson a nommé l'aspirateur 
d'Herbert pour diriger la gestion nouvellement créée de nourriture 
des ETATS-UNIS. Un ingénieur des mines qui avait avec succès 
organisé l'effort massif d'obtenir la nourriture aux citoyens de la 
Belgique après le champ de l'armée allemande par ce pays en 1914, 
aspirateur a été maintenant chargé de parvenir l'agriculture et 
l'économie domestiques afin d'alimenter l'armée des ETATS-UNIS et 
aider les armées et les civils alliés. la "nourriture gagnera 
la guerre," a déclaré la gestion de nourriture par ses affiches et 
efforts omniprésents de publicité. Plantant des jardins, 
observant le rationnement volontaire, évitant la perte -- ces efforts
à l'économie de nourriture tous sont venus pour être connus en tant
que "Hooverizing." Les magazines des femmes ont également pris 
la croisade à la maison d'économie, quelques analogies militaires 
d'utilisation pour favoriser les recommandations de la gestion de 
nourriture. Présentant le travail domestique en tant qu'effort 
patriotique, cette campagne de gestion de nourriture des ETATS-UNIS 
dans le bon ménage offert femmes un bouclier d'adhésion et même des
instructions fournies pour coudre un uniforme "patriotique" de 
ménage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS no world.war.i, o 
presidente Woodrow Wilson apontou o hoover de Herbert para dirigir a 
administração recentemente criada do alimento de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Um coordenador de mineração que organizasse com sucesso o 
esforço maciço começar o alimento aos cidadãos de Bélgica após a
varredura do exército alemão através desse país em 1914, hoover 
foi carregado agora com controlar a agricultura e o conservation 
domésticos a fim alimentar o exército de ESTADOS UNIDOS e ajudar a 
exércitos e a civis aliados. o "alimento ganhará a guerra," 
declarou a administração do alimento com seus posteres e esforços 
ubiquitous do publicity. Plantando jardins, observando racionar 
voluntário, evitando o desperdício -- estes esforços no 
conservation do alimento todos vieram ser sabidos como "Hooverizing." 
Os compartimentos das mulheres fizeram exame também acima do 
crusade home do conservation, algumas analogias militares empregando 
para promover as recomendações da administração do alimento. 
Apresentando o trabalho doméstico como o esforço patriotic, a 
esta campanha da administração do alimento de ESTADOS UNIDOS nas 
tarefas domésticas boas oferecidas mulheres um protetor da sociedade 
e mesmo umas instruções fornecidas para sewing um uniforme 
"patriotic" das tarefas domésticas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con l'entrata degli STATI UNITI nel world.war.i, 
il presidente Woodrow Wilson ha nominato il hoover del Herbert per 
dirigere la gestione recentemente creata dell'alimento degli STATI 
UNITI. Un assistente tecnico di estrazione mineraria che aveva 
organizzato con successo lo sforzo voluminoso ottenere l'alimento ai 
cittadini del Belgio dopo la spazzata dell'esercito tedesco attraverso
quel paese in 1914, hoover ora è stato caricato del riuscire 
l'agricoltura e la conservazione domestiche per alimentare l'esercito 
degli STATI UNITI ed aiutare gli eserciti ed i civili alleati. 
"l'alimento vincerà la guerra," ha dichiarato la gestione 
dell'alimento con i relativi manifesti e sforzi ubiquisti di 
pubblicità. Piantando i giardini, osservando razionamento 
volontario, evitante spreco -- questi sforzi a conservazione 
dell'alimento tutti sono venuto essere conosciuti come "Hooverizing." 
Gli scomparti delle donne egualmente hanno preso il crusade 
domestico di conservazione, alcune analogie militari impieganti per 
promuovere le raccomandazioni della gestione dell'alimento. 
Presentando il lavoro domestico come sforzo patriotic, questa 
campagna della gestione dell'alimento degli STATI UNITI nel buon 
governo della casa ha offerto a donne uno schermo di insieme dei 
membri e perfino ha fornito le istruzioni per il cucito 
dell'uniforme "patriotic" di governo della casa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ είσοδο μέσα σε τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο
Ι, ο Πρόεδρος Woodrow Wilson ανέθεσε σε Herbert Hoover 
να διευθύνει την πρόσφατα δημιουργημένη διοίκηση ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ 
τροφίμων. Ένας μηχανικός μεταλλείας που είχε οργανώσει 
επιτυχώς την ογκώδη προσπάθεια να φτάσει τα τρόφιμα στους 
πολίτες του Βελγίου μετά από το σκούπισμα του γερμανικού 
στρατού μέσω εκείνης της χώρας το 1914, Hoover χρεώθηκε 
τώρα με να κατορθώσει την εσωτερικές γεωργία και τη συντήρηση 
προκειμένου να ταϊστεί ο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ στρατός και να βοηθηθούν οι
συνδεμένοι στρατοί και οι πολίτες. "Τα τρόφιμα θα κερδίσουν
τον πόλεμο," δήλωσε τη διοίκηση τροφίμων μέσω των πανταχού 
παρουσών αφισών και των προσπαθειών δημοσιότητάς του. 
Φυτεύοντας τους κήπους, παρατηρώντας την εθελοντική διανομή
με δελτίο, που αποφεύγει τα απόβλητα -- αυτές οι προσπάθειες στη 
συντήρηση τροφίμων όλες ήρθαν να μαθευτούν ως "Hooverizing." 
Τα περιοδικά των γυναικών έλαβαν επίσης τη σταυροφορία 
βασικής συντήρησης, μερικές στρατιωτικές αναλογίες υιοθέτησης 
για να προωθήσουν τις συστάσεις της διοίκησης τροφίμων. 
Παρουσιάζοντας την εσωτερική εργασία ως πατριωτική 
προσπάθεια, αυτή η εκστρατεία διοίκησης ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ τροφίμων 
στην καλή οικοκυρική πρόσφερε στις γυναίκες μια ασπίδα ιδιότητας
μέλους και παρείχε ακόμη και τις οδηγίες για το ράψιμο μιας 
"πατριωτικήσ" οικοκυρικής ομοιόμορφης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS en Primera Guerra
Mundial, presidente Woodrow Wilson designó la aspiradora de Herberto 
para dirigir la administración nuevamente creada del alimento de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS. Ahora cargaron a un ingeniero de explotación 
minera que había ordenado con éxito el esfuerzo masivo de conseguir 
el alimento a los ciudadanos de Bélgica después del barrido del 
ejército alemán a través de ese país en 1914, aspiradora con el 
manejo de agricultura y de la conservación domésticas para alimentar
al ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS y asistir a los ejércitos y a los 
civiles aliados. el "alimento ganará la guerra," declaró la 
administración del alimento con sus carteles y esfuerzos ubicuos de 
la publicidad. Plantando jardines, observando racionar 
voluntario, evitando la basura -- estos esfuerzos en la conservación 
del alimento todos vinieron ser conocidos como "Hooverizing." 
Los compartimientos de las mujeres también tomaron la 
cruzada casera de la conservación, algunas analogías militares de
empleo para promover las recomendaciones de la administración del 
alimento. Presentando el trabajo doméstico como esfuerzo 
patriótico, esta campaña de la administración del alimento de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en las buenas operacíones de entretenimiento ofrecidas
mujeres un blindaje de la calidad de miembro e incluso instrucciones 
proporcionadas para coser un uniforme "patriótico" de las 
operacíones de entretenimiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108425</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/housewives-in-uniform-domesticity-as-military-duty</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
