<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105567</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105567</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212379</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sustainable Agriculture Research and Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stützbare Landwirtschaft Forschung und Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Recherche et éducation soutenables d'agriculture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pesquisa e instrução sustainable da agricultura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ricerca e formazione sostenibili di agricoltura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βιώσιμες έρευνα και εκπαίδευση γεωργίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Investigación y educación sostenibles de la 
agricultura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Sustainable Agriculture Research and Education (SARE) is a research and education grants program. The goal of the program is to advance farming systems that are profitable, environmentally sound and good for communities. The website includes funding opportunities for farmers, ranchers, educators and students. Funded projects are searchable by region or topic and include reports, summaries and proposals. SARE also publishes books, bulletins and online resources highlighting SARE-funded project results and other innovative research. Most of the publications are available in print and online.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stützbare Landwirtschaft Forschung und Ausbildung 
(SARE) ist eine Forschung und eine Ausbildung bewilligt Programm. 
Das Ziel des Programms ist, das Bewirtschaften der Systeme 
vorzurücken, die rentabel sind, umweltsmäßig stichhaltig und gut 
für Gemeinschaften. Die Web site schließt 
finanzierengelegenheiten für Landwirte, Viehzüchter, Erzieher und 
Kursteilnehmer ein. Finanzierte Projekte sind durch Region oder 
Thema auffindbar und schließen Reports, Zusammenfassungen und 
Anträge ein. SARE veröffentlicht auch die Bücher, Nachrichten
und Onlinebetriebsmittel, die SARE-finanzierte Projektresultate und 
andere erfinderische Forschung markieren. Die meisten 
Publikationen sind im Druck und online vorhanden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La recherche d'agriculture et l'éducation 
soutenables (SARE) est une recherche et une éducation accorde le 
programme. Le but du programme est d'avancer cultiver les 
systèmes qui sont profitables, ambiant sain et bon pour les 
communautés. Le site Web inclut des occasions de placement pour
des fermiers, des propriétaires d'un ranch, des éducateurs et des 
étudiants. Les projets placés sont rechercheables par région 
ou sujet et incluent des états, des sommaires et des propositions. 
SARE édite également des livres, des bulletins et des 
ressources en ligne mettant en valeur des résultats SARE-placés de 
projet et toute autre recherche innovatrice. La plupart des 
publications sont disponibles dans la copie et en ligne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A pesquisa da agricultura e a instrução 
sustainable (SARE) são uma pesquisa e uma instrução concedem o 
programa. O objetivo do programa é avançar cultivar os 
sistemas que são profitable, ambiental sadio e bom para comunidades. 
O Web site inclui oportunidades financiando para fazendeiros, 
rancheiros, educadores e estudantes. Os projetos financiados 
são searchable pela região ou pelo tópico e incluem relatórios, 
sumários e propostas. SARE publica também os livros, os 
boletins e os recursos em linha destacando resultados SARE-financiados
do projeto e a outra pesquisa inovativa. A maioria das 
publicações estão disponíveis na cópia e em linha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La ricerca di agricoltura e la formazione 
sostenibili (SARE) è una ricerca e una formazione assegna il 
programma. L'obiettivo del programma è di avanzare 
l'agricoltura dei sistemi che sono vantaggiosi, in condizioni 
ambientali sano e buon per le Comunità. Il Web site include le 
occasioni costituenti un fondo per per i coltivatori, i ranchers, gli 
educatori e gli allievi. I progetti costituiti un fondo per sono
reperibili dalla regione o dal soggetto ed includono i rapporti, i 
sommari e le proposte. SARE egualmente pubblica i libri, i 
bollettini e le risorse in linea evidenzianti i risultati 
SARE-costituiti un fondo per di progetto e l'altra ricerca 
innovatrice. La maggior parte delle pubblicazioni sono 
disponibili in stampa ed in linea.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η βιώσιμες έρευνα και η εκπαίδευση γεωργίας (SARE) 
είναι μια έρευνα και η εκπαίδευση χορηγεί το πρόγραμμα. Ο 
στόχος του προγράμματος είναι να προωθηθούν τα συστήματα 
καλλιέργειας που είναι κερδοφόρα, περιβαλλοντικά υγιής και καλά 
για τις κοινότητες. Ο ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει τις ευκαιρίες 
χρηματοδότησης για τους αγρότες, τα ranchers, τους 
εκπαιδευτικούς και τους σπουδαστές. Τα χρηματοδοτημένα 
προγράμματα είναι εξερευνήσιμα από την περιοχή ή το θέμα και 
περιλαμβάνουν τις εκθέσεις, τις περιλήψεις και τις προτάσεις. 
SARE δημοσιεύει επίσης τα βιβλία, τα δελτία και τα σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς που δίνουν έμφαση στα 
σαρε-χρηματοδοτημένα αποτελέσματα προγράμματος και άλλη καινοτόμο
έρευνα. Οι περισσότερες από τις δημοσιεύσεις είναι 
διαθέσιμες στην τυπωμένη ύλη και on-line.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La investigación y la educación sostenibles 
(SARE) de la agricultura es una investigación y una educación 
concede programa. La meta del programa es avanzar cultivar los 
sistemas que son provechosos, ambientalmente sano y bueno para las 
comunidades. El Web site incluye las oportunidades de 
financiamiento para los granjeros, los rancheros, los educadores y los
estudiantes. Los proyectos financiados son investigables por la 
región o el asunto e incluyen informes, los resúmenes y las ofertas.
SARE también publica los libros, los boletines y los recursos 
en línea destacando los resultados SARE-financiados del proyecto y la
otra investigación innovadora. La mayoría de las publicaciones
están en la impresión y en línea disponibles.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212379</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105567</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sustainable-agriculture-research-and-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
