<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106399</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106399</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085238</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Transcontinental Railroad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Transkontinentale Eisenbahn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Chemin de fer Transcontinental</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Estrada de ferro Transcontinental</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Ferrovia Transcontinentale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο διηπειρωτικός σιδηρόδρομος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Ferrocarril Transcontinental</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1862, Congress passed and President Lincoln signed the Pacific Railroad Bill, which granted public land and funds to build a transcontinental railroad. The Central Pacific Railroad would lay tracks from California heading east, and the Union Pacific Railroad would lay tracks from the Missouri River west. The photograph taken in Placer County, "Grading the Central Pacific Railroad," shows some of the construction. Work on the railroad was physically difficult and at times dangerous, and attracting workers was a challenge. The majority of the Central Pacific's laborers were Chinese. A Chinese worker is shown in the image "Heading (top cut) of East Portal, Tunnel No. 8." Both railroad companies actively recruited Chinese laborers because they were regarded as hard workers and were willing to accept a lower wage than white workers, mostly Irish immigrants. As construction progressed, the Central Pacific and the Union Pacific competed to see which could lay the most track each day. A photograph of a sign near Promontory Park, Utah, commemorates the day that Central Pacific crews laid an unprecedented 10 miles of track. The meeting of the two sets of tracks ? the "gold spike" ceremony ? took place on May 10, 1869. Several photographs and drawings depict this historic moment. Now the country was connected as never before: a journey between San Francisco and New York that previously took up to six months now took only days. The photograph "High Bridge in Loop," from Views from a Trip to California, shows a train passing quickly through a mountain pass. The transcontinental railroad allowed people to travel more, farther, and in pleasant conditions, as reflected in the photograph "Commissary Car, 'Elkhorn Club.'" The photograph "Knights of Pythias at the Santa Fe Railway Station, Anaheim" shows an example of the popularity of trains. Even as the transcontinental railroad brought the new country together, it brought change to the world of Native Americans. The tracks ran through a number of tribal territories, bringing into conflict cultures that held very different views of the land and how it might be used and lived on. The painting The First Train, by Herbert Schuyler, depicts three Indians pointing past their encampment at a train in the far distance. The railroad also brought an increasing number of European Americans west. One consequence of this influx was the depletion of the buffalo herds, a major food source for Plains Indians. European Americans would often shoot buffalo for sport from the train; by 1880, the buffalo were mostly gone and Plains Indians had been gathered onto reservations. Millions of acres of open grassland were being settled by the people moving west. Eventually, much of this land became the farmland that fed a growing nation. The transcontinental railroad opened up the West to the rest of the country, even if they never made the trip themselves. A Currier &amp; Ives hand-colored lithograph depicts a train running along the Truckee River in Northern California. The San Francisco publishing firm of Lawrence &amp; Houseworth hired photographers and published photographic tourist catalogs containing views of the West, which they sold commercially. The railroad took hold in popular culture, as shown by sheet music for the song "New Express Galop [sic]." There was even a railroad board game illustrating "Railroads Between New York and San Francisco, California, with Scenes on the Way."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1862 unterzeichneten der geführte Kongreß und der
Präsident Lincoln die pazifische Eisenbahn-Rechnung, die allgemeines 
Land und Kapital bewilligte, um eine transkontinentale Eisenbahn 
aufzubauen. Die zentrale pazifische Eisenbahn würde Spuren vom 
Kalifornien Kopftextosten legen, und die Anschluß-pazifische 
Eisenbahn würde Spuren vom Missouri Flußwesten legen. Die 
Fotographie, die in der Seifenerz-Grafschaft, "genommen wird, die 
zentrale pazifische Eisenbahn ordnend,", zeigt etwas von dem Aufbau. 
Arbeit über die Eisenbahn war und manchmal gefährlich 
physikalisch schwierig, und Arbeiter anzuziehen war eine 
Herausforderung. Die Majorität der zentralen Arbeiter des 
Pazifiks waren chinesisch. Ein chinesischer Arbeiter wird 
gezeigt im Bild "Kopftext (die Oberseite geschnitten) nach Osten des 
Portals, Tunnel Nr. 8." Beide Eisenbahnfirmen zogen aktiv 
chinesische Arbeiter, weil sie als harte Arbeiter betrachtet wurden 
und bereit waren, einen untereren Lohn als weiße Arbeiter anzunehmen,
meistens irische Immigranten ein. Während Aufbau weiterkam, 
konkurrierten das zentrale pazifische und der Anschluß Pazifik, um zu
sehen, welches die meiste Spur jeden Tag legen könnte. Eine 
Fotographie eines Zeichens nahe Vorgebirge-Park, Utah, gedenkt den 
Tag, daß zentrale pazifische Mannschaften beispiellosen 10 Meilen der
Spur legten. Die Sitzung der zwei Schienen? die 
"Goldspitze" Zeremonie? fand an Mai 10, 1869 statt. Einige
Fotographien und Zeichnungen stellen diesen historischen Moment 
bildlich dar. Jetzt wurde das Land als nie vorher angeschlossen:
eine Reise zwischen San Francisco und New York, die vorher zu 
sechs Monaten jetzt aufnahmen, dauerte nur Tage. Die Fotographie
"hohe Brücke in der Schleife," von den Ansichten von einer Reise zu 
Kalifornien, Erscheinen eine Serie, die schnell durch einen 
Gebirgsdurchlauf überschreitet. Die transkontinentale Eisenbahn
die Leute erlaubt, zum mehr zu reisen, weiter und in den angenehmen 
Bedingungen, wie in der Fotographie "Beauftragt-Auto reflektiert, ' 
Elkhorn Verein.'" Die Fotographie "Ritter von Pythias am Santa 
Fe Bahnhof, Anaheim" zeigt ein Beispiel der Popularität der Serien. 
Selbst als die transkontinentale Eisenbahn das neue Land 
zusammen holte, holte sie Änderung an der Welt der gebürtigen 
Amerikaner. Die Spuren liefen durch eine Anzahl von Stammes- 
Gegenden und holten in $überschneidung Kulturen, die sehr 
unterschiedliche Meinungen des Landes vertraten und wie es benutzt 
werden konnte und an lebte. Der Anstrich die erste Serie, durch 
Herbert Schuyler, stellt drei Inder bildlich dar, die hinter ihr Lager
auf eine Serie im weiten Abstand zeigen. Die Eisenbahn holte 
auch eine zunehmende Anzahl von europäischen Amerikanern nach Westen.
Eine Konsequenz dieses Zuflusses war die Entleerung der 
Büffelherden, eine Hauptnahrungsmittelquelle für Ebenen Inder. 
Europäische Amerikaner würden häufig Büffel für Sport von 
der Serie schießen; bis zum 1880 wurden der Büffel meistens 
gegangen und Ebenen Inder waren auf Reservierungen erfaßt worden. 
Millionen Morgen der geöffneten Wiese wurden durch den 
beweglichen Westen der Leute vereinbart. Schließlich wurde viel
dieses Landes das Ackerland, das eine wachsende Nation einzog. 
Die transkontinentale Eisenbahn erschloß den Westen zum Rest 
des Landes, selbst wenn sie nie die Reise selbst bildeten. Ein 
Currier u. Ives eine Hand-farbige Lithographie stellt eine Serie 
bildlich dar, die entlang den Truckee Fluß in Nordkalifornien läuft.
Das San Francisco Verlags- Unternehmen von Lawrence u. von 
Houseworth angestellten Photographen und erschienene fotographische 
touristische Kataloge, die Ansichten des Westens enthalten, den sie 
kommerziell verkauften. Die Eisenbahn nahm Einfluß in der 
populären Kultur, wie durch Blattmusik für das Lied "neues 
ausdrückliches Galop gezeigt [ sic ]." Es gab sogar ein 
Eisenbahnbrettspiel, das veranschaulicht "Eisenbahnen zwischen New 
York und San Francisco, Kalifornien, mit Szenen auf der Methode."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1862, le congrès passé et le Président 
Lincoln ont signé la facture Pacifique de chemin de fer, qui a 
accordé la terre et les fonds publics pour construire un chemin de 
fer transcontinental. Le chemin de fer Pacifique central 
étendrait des pistes d'est d'entête de la Californie, et le chemin 
de fer Pacifique des syndicats étendrait des pistes de l'ouest de 
fleuve du Missouri. La photographie prise dans le comté de 
placer, "évaluant le chemin de fer Pacifique central," montre une 
partie de la construction. Le travail sur le chemin de fer 
était physiquement difficile et parfois dangereux, et l'attraction 
des ouvriers était un défi. La majorité des travailleurs du 
Pacifique central étaient chinoise. Un ouvrier chinois est 
montré dans l'image "entête (dessus coupé) à l'est du portail, le 
numéro 8 de tunnel." Les deux compagnies de chemin de fer ont 
activement recruté les travailleurs chinois parce qu'elles ont été 
considérées comme les ouvriers durs et étaient disposées à 
recevoir un salaire inférieur que les ouvriers blancs, la plupart du 
temps immigrés irlandais. Pendant que la construction 
progressait, le Pacifique central et l'union Pacifique ont 
concurrencé pour voir ce qui pourrait étendre la plupart de piste 
chaque jour. Une photographie d'un signe près de parc de 
promontoire, Utah, commémore le jour que Pacifique central 
sert d'équipier a étendu des 10 milles sans précédent de piste. 
La réunion des deux ensembles de pistes ? la cérémonie 
"de transitoire d'or" ? a eu lieu 10 mai 1869. Plusieurs 
photographies et schémas dépeignent ce moment historique. 
Maintenant le pays a été relié en tant que jamais avant : 
un voyage entre San Francisco et New York qui précédemment 
ont pris à six mois maintenant a pris seulement des jours. La 
photographie "haute passerelle dans la boucle," des vues d'un voyage 
vers la Californie, expositions un train passant rapidement par un 
passage de montagne. Le chemin de fer transcontinental permis 
des personnes à voyager davantage, plus lointaines, et en conditions 
plaisantes, comme reflété dans la photographie "voiture de 
commissaire, à 'club d'Elkhorn.'" La photographie "chevaliers 
de Pythias à la gare de technicien de Santa, Anaheim" montre un 
exemple de la popularité des trains. Même pendant que le 
chemin de fer transcontinental réunissait le nouveau pays, il a 
apporté le changement au monde des Américains indigènes. Les 
pistes ont fonctionné par un certain nombre de territoires tribals, 
introduisant dans le conflit les cultures qui ont tenu des vues très 
différentes de la terre et comment elle pourrait être utilisée et a
vécu en fonction. La peinture le premier train, par Herbert 
Schuyler, dépeint trois Indiens se dirigeant après leur campement à
un train dans la distance lointaine. Le chemin de fer également
a apporté un nombre croissant d'Américains européens à l'ouest. 
Une conséquence de cet afflux était l'épuisement des 
troupeaux de buffle, une source importante de nourriture pour des 
Indiens de plaines. Les Américains européens tireraient 
souvent le buffle pour le sport du train ; d'ici 1880, le buffle
ont été la plupart du temps allés et des Indiens de plaines avaient
été recueillis sur des réservations. Des millions d'acres de 
prairie ouverte étaient arrangés par l'ouest mobile de personnes. 
Par la suite, beaucoup de cette terre est devenue les champs qui
ont alimenté une nation croissante. Le chemin de fer 
transcontinental a ouvert l'ouest au reste du pays, même si ils ne 
faisaient jamais le voyage eux-mêmes. Currier et une 
lithographie main-colorée par Ives dépeint un train fonctionnant le 
long du fleuve de Truckee en Californie nordique. Le San 
Francisco éditant la société de Laurent et des photographes loués
par Houseworth et les catalogues de touristes photographiques édités
contenant des vues de l'ouest, qu'ils ont vendu commercialement. 
Le chemin de fer a pris la prise dans la culture populaire, 
comme montré par la musique de feuille pour la chanson "nouveau Galop
exprès [ sic ]." Il y avait même un jeu de panneau de chemin 
de fer illustrant des "chemins de fer entre New York et San 
Francisco, la Californie, avec des scènes sur le chemin."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1862, o congress passado e o presidente Lincoln 
assinaram a conta pacífica da estrada de ferro, que concedeu a terra 
e fundos públicos para construir uma estrada de ferro 
transcontinental. A estrada de ferro pacífica central colocaria
trilhas do leste do título de Califórnia, e a estrada de ferro 
pacífica da união colocaria trilhas do oeste do rio de Missouri. 
A fotografia feita exame no condado do placer, "classificando a 
estrada de ferro pacífica central," mostra alguma da construção. 
O trabalho na estrada de ferro era fisicamente difícil e às 
vezes perigoso, e atrair trabalhadores era um desafio. A maioria
dos laborers do Pacífico central era chinesa. Um trabalhador 
chinês é mostrado na imagem "título (alto cortado) para o leste do 
portal, túnel no. 8." Ambas as companhias da estrada de ferro 
recrutaram ativamente laborers chineses porque foram consideradas como
trabalhadores duros e eram dispostas aceitar um salário mais baixo do
que os trabalhadores brancos, na maior parte immigrants irish. 
Enquanto a construção progrediu, o pacífico central e a 
união o Pacífico competiram para ver qual poderia colocar a maioria 
de trilha cada dia. Uma fotografia de um sinal perto do parque 
do promontório, Utá, comemora o dia que os grupos pacíficos 
centrais colocaram umas 10 milhas unprecedented da trilha. A 
reunião dos dois jogos de trilhas? do "o ceremony do ponto 
ouro"? ocorreu maio em 10, 1869. Diversos fotografias e 
desenhos descrevem este momento historic. O país foi conectado 
agora como nunca antes: uma viagem entre San Francisco e New 
York que fizeram exame previamente de até seis meses agora fêz exame
somente de dias. A fotografia "ponte elevada no laço," das 
vistas de um desengate a Califórnia, mostras um trem que passa 
rapidamente através de uma passagem da montanha. A estrada de 
ferro transcontinental permitida os povos a viajar mais, mais 
distantes, e em circunstâncias agradáveis, como refletido na 
fotografia do "carro commissary, ' clube de Elkhorn.'" A 
fotografia "knights de Pythias na estação railway de Fe de Santa, 
Anaheim" mostra um exemplo da popularidade dos trens. Mesmo 
enquanto a estrada de ferro transcontinental trouxe o país novo 
junto, trouxe a mudança ao mundo de americanos nativos. As 
trilhas funcionaram através de um número de territórios tribais, 
trazendo no conflito as culturas que prenderam vistas muito diferentes
da terra e como pôde ser usada e viveu sobre. A pintura o 
primeiro trem, por Herbert Schuyler, descreve três indians que 
apontam após seu encampment em um trem na distância distante. 
A estrada de ferro trouxe também um número crescente de 
americanos europeus para o oeste. Uma conseqüência deste 
influx era o depletion dos rebanhos do búfalo, uma fonte principal do
alimento para indians de planícies. Os americanos europeus 
disparariam frequentemente no búfalo para o esporte do trem; 
por 1880, o búfalo foi ido na maior parte e os indians de 
planícies tinham sido recolhidos em reservations. Os milhões 
dos acres do grassland aberto eram estabelecidos pelo oeste movente 
dos povos. Eventualmente, muita desta terra transformou-se a 
terra que alimentou uma nação crescente. A estrada de ferro 
transcontinental abriu acima do oeste ao descanso do país, mesmo se 
nunca fizeram o desengate eles mesmos. Um Currier &amp; um 
lithograph mão-colorido Ives descrevem um trem que funciona ao longo 
do rio de Truckee em Califórnia do norte. A firma publicando do
San Francisco de Lawrence &amp; de fotógrafos empregados Houseworth e 
catálogos tourist fotográficos publicados que contêm vistas do 
oeste, que vendeu comercialmente. A estrada de ferro fêz exame 
da preensão na cultura popular, como mostrado pela música da folha 
para a canção "Galop expresso novo [ sic ]." Havia mesmo um 
jogo de placa da estrada de ferro que ilustra "estradas de ferro entre
New York e San Francisco, Califórnia, com cenas na maneira."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1862, il congresso passato ed il presidente 
Lincoln hanno firmato la fattura pacifica della ferrovia, che ha 
assegnato la terra ed i fondi monetari pubblici per costruire una 
ferrovia transcontinentale. La ferrovia pacifica centrale 
porrebbe le piste dall'est dell'intestazione della California e la 
ferrovia pacifica del sindacato porrebbe le piste dall'ovest del fiume
del Missouri. La fotografia presa nella contea del giacimento 
detritico, "classificando la ferrovia pacifica centrale," mostra 
alcuna della costruzione. Il lavoro sulla ferrovia era 
fisicamente difficile ed occasionalmente pericoloso ed attrarre gli 
operai era una sfida. La maggior parte dei lavoratori del 
Pacifico centrale era cinese. Un operaio cinese è 
indicato nell'immagine "l'intestazione (parte superiore tagliata) 
verso est del portal, il traforo il no. 8." Entrambe le aziende 
della ferrovia attivamente hanno reclutato i lavoratori cinesi 
perché sono state considerare gli operai duri ed erano disposte ad 
accettare uno stipendio più basso che gli operai bianchi, 
principalmente immigranti irlandesi. Mentre la costruzione ha 
progredito, il pacifico centrale e l'unione il Pacifico hanno 
competuto per vedere in grado di porre la maggior parte della pista 
ogni giorno. Una fotografia di un segno vicino al parco del 
promontory, Utah, commemora il giorno che le squadre pacifiche 
centrali hanno posto lle 10 miglia senza precedente della pista. 
La riunione dei due insiemi delle piste? "la cerimonia del
punto dell'oro"? ha avvenuto maggio su 10, 1869. Parecchie
fotografie ed illustrazioni descrivono questo momento storico. 
Ora il paese è stato collegato come mai prima: un viaggio
fra San Francisco e New York che precedentemente ora hanno preso a sei
mesi ha occorr soltanto i giorni. La fotografia "alto ponticello
nel ciclo," dalle viste da un viaggio alla California, esposizioni un 
treno che passa rapidamente attraverso un passaggio della montagna. 
La ferrovia transcontinentale ha permesso che la gente 
viaggiasse di più, più lontano e nelle circostanze piacevoli, come 
riflesso nella fotografia "automobile del commissario, 'randello di 
Elkhorn.'" La fotografia "cavalieri di Pythias alla stazione 
ferroviaria del tecnico di assistenza di Santa, Anaheim" mostra un 
esempio della popolarità dei treni. Proprio mentre la ferrovia 
transcontinentale ha riunito il nuovo paese, ha portato il cambiamento
al mondo degli Americani natali. Le piste hanno funzionato 
attraverso un certo numero di territori tribali, introducenti nel 
conflitto le colture che hanno tenuto le viste molto differenti della 
terra e come potrebbe essere usata ed ha vissuto sopra. La 
pittura il primo treno, da Herbert Schuyler, descrive tre indiani che 
indicano oltre il loro encampment ad un treno nella distanza lontana. 
La ferrovia egualmente ha portato un numero aumentante di 
Americani europei verso ovest. Una conseguenza di questo 
afflusso era lo svuotamento delle greggi del bufalo, una sorgente 
importante dell'alimento per gli indiani di pianure. Gli 
Americani europei sparerebbero spesso il bufalo per lo sport dal 
treno; entro 1880, il bufalo principalmente è stato andato e 
gli indiani di pianure erano stati riuniti sulle 
prenotazioni. Milioni di acri di pascolo aperto stavano 
depositandi dall'ovest commovente della gente. Finalmente, molta
di questa terra si è transformata in nel terreno coltivabile che ha 
alimentato una nazione crescente. La ferrovia transcontinentale 
ha aperto l'ovest al resto del paese, anche se non facessero mai il 
viaggio essi stessi. Un Currier &amp; una litografia mano-colorata 
Ives descrive un treno che funziona lungo il fiume di Truckee nella 
California del Nord. La ditta di pubblicazione de San Francisco 
di Lawrence &amp; di Houseworth ha assunto i photographers ed ha 
pubblicato i cataloghi turistici fotografici che contengono le viste 
dell'ovest, che hanno venduto commercialmente. La ferrovia ha 
preso la stretta nella coltura popolare, come indicato da musica del 
foglio per la canzone "nuovo Galop espresso [ sic ]." Ci era 
persino un gioco del bordo della ferrovia che illustra "le 
ferrovie fra New York e San Francisco, la California, con le scene sul
modo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1862, το συνέδριο πέρασε και ο Πρόεδρος 
Lincoln υπέγραψε τον ειρηνικό σιδηρόδρομο Bill, ο οποίος 
χορήγησε το δημόσια έδαφος και τα κεφάλαια για να χτίσει έναν 
διηπειρωτικό σιδηρόδρομο. Ο κεντρικός ειρηνικός 
σιδηρόδρομος θα έβαζε τις διαδρομές από την ανατολή τίτλων 
Καλιφόρνιας, και ο ειρηνικός σιδηρόδρομος ένωσης θα έβαζε τις 
διαδρομές από τη δύση ποταμών του Μισσούρι. Η φωτογραφία 
που λαμβάνεται στο νομό μεταλλοφόρων κοιτασμάτων, "βαθμολογώντας 
τον κεντρικό ειρηνικό σιδηρόδρομο," εμφανίζει μερικές από την 
κατασκευή. Η εργασία για το σιδηρόδρομο ήταν φυσικά 
δύσκολη και κατά περιόδους επικίνδυνη, και η προσέλκυση των 
εργαζομένων ήταν μια πρόκληση. Η πλειοψηφία των laborers 
του κεντρικού Ειρηνικού ήταν κινεζικά. Ένας κινεζικός 
εργαζόμενος εμφανίζεται τίτλος της εικόνας "(κορυφή που κόβεται)
της ανατολικής πύλης, η σήραγγα αριθ. 8." και οι δύο επιχειρήσεις
σιδηροδρόμου στρατολόγησε ενεργά τα κινεζικά laborers επειδή 
θεωρήθηκαν ως σκληροί εργαζόμενοι και ήταν πρόθυμα να αποδεχθούν
μια χαμηλότερη αμοιβή από τους λευκούς εργαζομένους, συνήθως 
ιρλανδικοί μετανάστες. Καθώς η κατασκευή προχώρησε, ο 
κεντρικός Ειρηνικός και η Ένωση Ειρηνικός ανταγωνίστηκαν για να 
δουν που θα μπορούσε να βάλει την περισσότερη διαδρομή
κάθε ημέρα. Μια φωτογραφία ενός σημαδιού κοντά στο πάρκο 
ακρωτηρίων, Utah, τιμά την μνήμη της ημέρας ότι τα κεντρικά 
ειρηνικά πληρώματα έβαλαν πρωτοφανή 10 μίλια της διαδρομής. 
Η συνεδρίαση των δύο συνόλων διαδρομών; η τελετή 
"χρυσών ακίδων"; πραγματοποιήθηκε σε Μάιος 10, 1869, 
Διάφορα φωτογραφίες και σχέδια απεικονίζουν αυτήν την 
ιστορική στιγμή. Τώρα η χώρα συνδέθηκε όπως ποτέ πριν 
από: ένα ταξίδι μεταξύ του Σαν Φρανσίσκο και της Νέας 
Υόρκης που διάρκεσαν προηγουμένως μέχρι έξι μήνες διάρκεσε 
τώρα μόνο τις ημέρες. Η φωτογραφία "υψηλή γέφυρα στο 
βρόχο," από τις όψεις από ένα ταξίδι σε Καλιφόρνια, εμφανίζει 
ένα τραίνο που περνά γρήγορα μέσω ενός περάσματος βουνών. 
Ο διηπειρωτικός σιδηρόδρομος επέτρεψε στους ανθρώπους για να
ταξιδεψει περισσότερο, μακρύτερα, και στους ευχάριστους όρους, 
όπως απεικονίζονται στη φωτογραφία "commissary αυτοκίνητο," τη 
λέσχη Elkhorn."" Η φωτογραφία "ιππότες Pythias στο 
σιδηροδρομικό σταθμό Φε Santa, Αναχάιμ" εμφανίζει ένα 
παράδειγμα της δημοτικότητας των τραίνων. Ακόμη και καθώς ο
διηπειρωτικός σιδηρόδρομος έφερε τη νέα χώρα μαζί, έφερε την 
αλλαγή στον κόσμο εγγενών Αμερικανών. Οι διαδρομές έτρεξαν
μέσω διάφορων φυλετικών εδαφών, που φέρνουν στη σύγκρουση τους 
πολιτισμούς που είχαν τις πολύ διαφορετικές όψεις του εδάφους 
και πώς να χρησιμοποιηθεί και έζησε επάνω. Η ζωγραφική το 
πρώτο τραίνο, από Herbert Schuyler, απεικονίζει τρεις 
Ινδούς που δείχνουν μετά από τη στρατοπέδευσή τους σε ένα 
τραίνο στη μακρινή απόσταση. Ο σιδηρόδρομος έφερε επίσης 
έναν αυξανόμενο αριθμό ευρωπαϊκής δύσης Αμερικανών. Μια 
συνέπεια αυτής της εισροής ήταν η μείωση των κοπαδιών βούβαλων,
μια σημαντική πηγή τροφίμων για τις πεδιάδες Ινδοί. 
Ευρωπαϊκοί Αμερικανοί θα πυροβολούσαν συχνά τους βούβαλους
για τον αθλητισμό από το τραίνο  από 1880, τους 
βούβαλους πήγαν συνήθως και οι πεδιάδες Ινδοί είχαν μαζευτεί 
επάνω στις επιφυλάξεις. Τα εκατομμύρια των στρεμμάτων του 
ανοικτού λιβαδιού εγκαθίσταντο από τους ανθρώπους που κινούν τη 
δύση. Τελικά, ένα μεγάλο μέρος αυτού του εδάφους έγινε 
το καλλιεργήσιμο έδαφος που τααΐε ένα αυξανόμενο έθνος. Ο
διηπειρωτικός σιδηρόδρομος άνοιξε τη δύση στο υπόλοιπο της 
χώρας, ακόμα κι αν δεν έκαναν ποτέ το ταξίδι οι ίδιοι. Currier &amp; χέρι-χρωματισμένο Ives lithograph απεικονίζουν 
ένα τρέξιμο τραίνων κατά μήκος του ποταμού Truckee σε βόρεια
Καλιφόρνια. Η δημοσιεύοντας εταιρία του Σαν Φρανσίσκο 
Lawrence &amp; Houseworth μίσθωσε τους φωτογράφους και δημοσίευσε
τους φωτογραφικούς καταλόγους τουριστών που περιέχουν τις όψεις 
της δύσης, την οποία πώλησαν εμπορικά. Ο σιδηρόδρομος πήρε
τη λαβή στο δημοφιλή πολιτισμό, όπως εμφανίζεται από τη μουσική
φύλλων για το τραγούδι "νέο σαφές galop [ SIC ]." 
Υπήρξε ακόμη και ένα παιχνίδι πινάκων σιδηροδρόμου που 
επεξηγεί "τους σιδηροδρόμους μεταξύ της Νέας Υόρκης και του Σαν 
Φρανσίσκο, Καλιφόρνια, με τις σκηνές στον τρόπο."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1862, el congreso pasado y presidente Lincoln 
firmaron la cuenta pacífica del ferrocarril, que concedió la pista y
fondos públicos para construir un ferrocarril transcontinental. 
El ferrocarril pacífico central pondría pistas del este del 
título de California, y el ferrocarril pacífico de la unión 
pondría pistas del oeste del río de Missouri. La fotografía 
tomada en condado del placer, "calificando el ferrocarril pacífico 
central," muestra algo de la construcción. El trabajo sobre el 
ferrocarril era físicamente difícil y ocasionalmente peligroso, y la
atracción de trabajadores era un desafío. La mayoría de los 
trabajadores del Pacífico central era china. Muestran un 
trabajador chino en la imagen "título (tapa cortada) al este del 
portal, túnel No. 8." Ambas compañías del ferrocarril 
reclutaron activamente a trabajadores chinos porque las miraron como 
trabajadores duros y estaban dispuestas a validar un salario más bajo
que los trabajadores blancos, sobre todo inmigrantes irlandeses. 
Mientras que progresó la construcción, el pacífico central y 
la unión el Pacífico compitieron para ver cuál podría poner la 
mayoría de la pista cada día. Una fotografía de una muestra 
cerca del parque del promontorio, Utah, conmemora el día que los 
equipos pacíficos centrales pusieron 10 millas sin precedentes de la 
pista. ¿La reunión de los dos conjuntos de pistas? ¿"la 
ceremonia del punto del oro"? ocurrió 10 de mayo de 1869. 
Varias fotografías y gráficos representan este momento 
histórico. Ahora el país fue conectado como nunca antes: 
un viaje entre San Francisco y Nueva York que ahora tomaron 
previamente hasta seis meses tomó solamente días. La 
fotografía "puente alto en bucle," de las visiónes desde un viaje a 
California, demostraciones un tren que pasa rápidamente a través de 
un paso de la montaña. El ferrocarril transcontinental no 
prohibido la gente a viajar más, más lejana, y en condiciones 
agradables, según lo reflejado en la fotografía "coche del 
comisario, ' club de Elkhorn.'" La fotografía "caballeros de 
Pythias en el ferrocarril del FE de santa, Anaheim" muestra un ejemplo
del renombre de trenes. Incluso mientras que el ferrocarril 
transcontinental trajo el país nuevo junto, trajo el cambio al mundo 
de americanos nativos. Las pistas se ejecutaron a través de un 
número de territorios tribales, trayendo en conflicto las culturas 
que llevaron a cabo vistas muy diversas de la pista y cómo puede ser 
que sea utilizada y vivió encendido. La pintura el primer tren,
por Herberto Schuyler, representa a tres indios que señalan más 
allá de su campamento en un tren en la distancia lejana. El 
ferrocarril también trajo un número de aumento de americanos 
europeos al oeste. Una consecuencia de esta afluencia era el 
agotamiento de las manadas del búfalo, una fuente importante del 
alimento para los indios de llanos. Los americanos europeos 
tirarían a menudo al búfalo para el deporte del tren; antes de
1880, el búfalo fue ido sobre todo y habían recolectado a los indios
de llanos sobre reservaciones. Millones de acres del prado 
abierto eran colocados por el oeste móvil de la gente. 
Eventual, mucha de esta pista se convirtió en las tierras de 
labrantío que alimentaron una nación cada vez mayor. El 
ferrocarril transcontinental abrió el oeste al resto del país, 
incluso si nunca hicieron el viaje ellos mismos. Un Currier y 
una litografía mano-coloreada Ives representa un tren que se ejecuta 
a lo largo del río de Truckee en California norteña. La firma 
que publica de San Francisco de Lorenzo y de fotógrafos empleados 
Houseworth y catálogos turísticos fotográficos publicados que 
contienen las vistas del oeste, que él vendió comercialmente. 
El ferrocarril tomó el asimiento en cultura popular, según lo 
mostrado por la música de la hoja para la canción "Galop expreso 
nuevo [ sic ]." Había incluso un juego de tarjeta del 
ferrocarril que ilustraba los "ferrocarriles entre Nueva York y San 
Francisco, California, con escenas en la manera."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085238</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106399</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-transcontinental-railroad</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
