<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222787</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222787</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,27217,35496,19192</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,27217,35496,19192</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,27217,35496,19192</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kesäpäivä Kangasalla [A summer day at Kangasala]</string>
            <string language="fi">Kesäpäivä Kangasalla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kesäpäivä Kangasalla [ A Sommertag bei 
Kangasala ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Kesäpäivä Kangasalla [ jour d'été de A chez 
Kangasala ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Kesäpäivä Kangasalla [ dia do verão de A em 
Kangasala ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Kesäpäivä Kangasalla [ giorno di estate di A a
Kangasala ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Kesδpδivδ Kangasalla [ θερινή ημέρα Α σε 
Kangasala ]</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Kesäpäivä Kangasalla [ día del verano de A en
Kangasala ]</string>
          </title>
          <language>de</language>
          <language>fi</language>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A summer day at Kangasala contains information on this poem and composition, its makers, the poem itself, the sheet music, as well as MIDI and audio files. In order to view the sheet music, users need the following free add-ons in their browsers: Scorch (for the Sibelius files, can also be used to play, transport and print music) and Acrobat reader (for PDF files, can only be used for viewing and printing sheet music). The poem was written by Sakari Topelius, composed by Gabriel Linsén, and the current words in Finnish for the song have been written by P.J. Hannikainen. The words are available in Finnish, Swedish, English, German, Karelian, Esperanto and also in Helsinki slang. The sheet music is for mixed choir and children’s choir. The pages also include a facsimile of the notation in Linsén’s own handwriting from 1864. In the Tips for schools section, teachers can download a PowerPoint presentation of the song, its genesis and writers. MP3 audio files "Sakari Topelius’ account of the creation of the poem" and "An account by Gabriel Linsén’s daughter of the creation of the song" can also be downloaded from the same page.</string>
            <string language="fi">Kesäpäivä Kangasalla sisältää tietoa tästä runosta ja sävellyksestä, sen tekijöistä, itse runon, nuotit, sekä MIDI- ja äänitiedostot. Nuottien katselua varten tarvitaan selaimeen seuraavat ilmaiset lisäpalikat: Scorch (Sibelius-tiedostoja varten, sen avulla voi myös soittaa, transportoida ja tulostaa nuotit) ja Acrobat reader (PDF-tiedostoja varten, sen avulla voi ainoastaan katsoa ja tulostaa nuotit). Runon on kirjoittanut Sakari Topelius, säveltänyt Gabriel Linsén, ja nykyiset suomenkieliset sanat lauluun on tehnyt P.J. Hannikainen. Sanat löytyvät suomeksi, ruotsiksi, englanniksi, saksaksi, karjalaksi, esperantoksi ja myös stadin slangilla. Nuotit ovat sekakuorolle ja lapsikuorolle. Sivuilta löytyy lisäksi Linsénin omakätisen nuotinnoksen näköispainos vuodelta 1864. Vinkkejä kouluun -osiosta opettaja voi ladata PowerPoint-esityksen laulusta, sen synnystä ja tekijöistä. Samalta sivulta voi ladata myös MP3-äänitiedostot "Sakari Topeliuksen kertomus runon synnystä" ja Gabriel Linsénin tyttären kertomus laulun synnystä".</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Sommertag bei Kangasala enthält 
Informationen über dieses Gedicht und Aufbau, seine Hersteller, das 
Gedicht selbst, die Blattmusik, sowie MIDI und Audiodateien. Um 
die Blattmusik anzusehen, benötigen Benutzer die folgenden freien 
Zusätze in ihren Datenbanksuchroutinen: Leser des Brandflecks 
(für die Sibelius Dateien, kann auch verwendet werden, Musik zu 
spielen, zu transportieren und zu drucken) und des Seiltänzers (für 
pdf Dateien, kann für Betrachtung und den Druck von von Blattmusik 
nur verwendet werden). Das Gedicht wurde von Sakari Topelius 
geschrieben, bestanden von Gabriel Linsén, und die aktuellen Wörter 
in finnischem für das Lied sind von P.J. Hannikainen geschrieben 
worden. Die Wörter sind in finnischem, in schwedischem, in 
englischem, in deutschem, in karelischem, Esperanto und auch im 
Helsinki Jargon vorhanden. Die Blattmusik ist für 
Mischchor und children?s singen im Chor. Die Seiten enthalten 
auch ein Faksimile der Darstellung in Linsén?s besitzen Handschrift 
von 1864. In den Spitzen für Schulen Kapitel, können Lehrer 
eine PowerPoint Darstellung des Lieds, seiner Entstehungsgeschichte 
und der Verfasser downloaden. MP3 Audiodateien "Sakari Topelius?
Konto der Kreation des Gedichtes "und" ein Konto durch Gabriel 
Linsén?s Tochter der Kreation des Lieds "können von der gleichen 
Seite auch downloadet werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un jour d'été chez Kangasala contient 
l'information sur ces poésie et composition, ses générateurs, la 
poésie elle-même, la musique de feuille, aussi bien que le MIDI et 
les fichiers sonores. Afin de visualiser la musique de feuille, 
les utilisateurs ont besoin des adjonctions libres suivantes dans 
leurs navigateurs : Lecteur de roussissement (pour les fichiers
de Sibelius, peut également être utilisé pour jouer, transporter et
imprimer la musique) et d'acrobate (pour des fichiers de pdf, peut 
seulement être utilisé pour le visionnement et imprimer la musique 
de feuille). La poésie a été écrite par Sakari Topelius, 
composé par Gabriel Linsén, et les mots actuels dans finlandais pour
la chanson ont été écrits par P.J. Hannikainen. Les mots sont
disponibles dans finlandais, suédois, anglais, allemand, karélien, 
l'espéranto et également dans l'argot de Helsinki. La musique 
de feuille est pour le choeur mélangé et les children?s chantent en 
choeur. Les pages incluent également un fac-similé de la 
notation dans Linsén?s possèdent l'écriture de 1864. Dans les
extrémités pour des écoles section, les professeurs peuvent 
télécharger une présentation de PowerPoint de la chanson, de sa 
genèse et d'auteurs. MP3 fichiers sonores "Sakari Topelius ? 
le compte de la création de la poésie "et" un compte par la 
fille de Gabriel Linsén?s de la création de la chanson "peuvent 
également être téléchargés de la même page.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um dia do verão em Kangasala contem a 
informação nestes poema e composição, seus fabricantes, o poema 
próprio, a música da folha, as.well.as MIDI e limas audio. A 
fim ver a música da folha, os usuários necessitam os seguintes 
add-ons livres em seus browsers: Leitor do scorch (para as limas
de Sibelius, pode também ser usado jogar, transportar e imprimir a 
música) e do acrobat (para limas do pdf, pode somente ser usado para 
a visão e imprimir a música da folha). O poema foi escrito por
Sakari Topelius, composto por Gabriel Linsén, e as palavras atuais em
finnish para a canção foram escritas por P.J. Hannikainen. As 
palavras estão disponíveis em finnish, em sueco, em inglês, em 
alemão, em karelian, o esperanto e também no slang de Helsínquia. 
A música da folha é para choir misturado e os children?s 
choir. As páginas incluem também uma fac-símile da notação 
em Linsén?s possuem o handwriting de 1864. Nas pontas para 
escolas seção, os professores podem download uma apresentação de 
PowerPoint da canção, de seu genesis e de escritores. MP3 
limas audio "Sakari Topelius? o cliente da criação do poema 
"e" um cliente pela filha de Gabriel Linsén?s da criação da 
canção "podem também downloaded da mesma página.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un giorno di estate a Kangasala contiene le 
informazioni su questi poem e composizione, i relativi creatori, il 
poem in se, la musica del foglio, così come il MIDI e gli archivi 
audio. Per osservare la musica del foglio, gli utenti hanno 
bisogno di seguenti adjunte libere in loro browsers: Lettore del
acrobat e) la musica stampare e trasportare, giocare essere usato 
anche può, gli archivi di Sibelius per (di bruciatura (per gli 
archivi del pdf, può essere usato soltanto per l'osservazione e la 
stampa della musica del foglio). Il poem è stato scritto da 
Sakari Topelius, composto da Gabriel Linsén e le parole correnti in 
finlandese per la canzone sono state scritte da P.J. Hannikainen. 
Le parole sono disponibili in finlandese, in svedese, in 
inglese, in tedesco, in karelian, esperanto ed anche nello slang de 
Helsinki. La musica del foglio è per il choir mixed ed i 
children?s choir. Le pagine egualmente includono un facsimile 
della notazione in Linsén?s possiedono la scrittura a mano da 1864. 
Nelle punte per le scuole sezione, gli insegnanti possono 
trasferire una presentazione dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti 
del PowerPoint della canzone, della relativa genesi e dei produttori. 
MP3 archivi audio "Sakari Topelius? il cliente della 
creazione del poem "e" un cliente dalla figlia del Gabriel Linsén?s 
della creazione della canzone "possono anche essere trasferiti dalla 
stessa pagina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια θερινή ημέρα σε Kangasala περιέχει τις 
πληροφορίες για αυτό το ποίημα και τη σύνθεση, τους κατασκευαστές
της, το ίδιο το ποίημα, τη μουσική φύλλων, καθώς επίσης και τα 
ηχητικών αρχεία του MIDI και. Προκειμένου να εμφανιστεί η
μουσική φύλλων, οι χρήστες χρειάζονται ακόλουθο τον ελεύθερο 
προσθέτουν -προσθέτω-ονς στους ξεφυλλιστές τους: Scorch 
(για τα αρχεία Sibelius, μπορεί επίσης να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να
παίξει, να μεταφέρει και να τυπώσει τη μουσική) και αναγνώστης 
ακροβατών (για τα αρχεία PDF, μπορεί μόνο να χρησιμοποιηθεί 
για την όψη και την εκτύπωση της μουσικής φύλλων). Το 
ποίημα γράφτηκε από το Sakari Topelius, που συντέθηκε από 
το Gabriel Linsιn, και οι παρούσες λέξεις στα φιλανδικά για 
το τραγούδι έχουν γραφτεί από P.J. Hannikainen. Οι 
λέξεις είναι διαθέσιμες σε φινλανδικό, σουηδικά, αγγλικά, 
γερμανικά, καρελιανά, την εσπεράντο και επίσης στο λαϊκό ιδίωμα
του Ελσίνκι. Η μουσική φύλλων είναι για τη μικτή χορωδία 
και children?s τη χορωδία. Οι σελίδες περιλαμβάνουν 
επίσης ένα αντίγραφο της σημείωσης στη γραφή Linsιn?s από 
1864. Στις άκρες για το σχολικό τμήμα, οι δάσκαλοι 
μπορούν να μεταφορτώσουν μια παρουσίαση PowerPoint του 
τραγουδιού, της γένεσης και των συγγραφέων του. MP3 
ηχητικά αρχεία "Sakari Topelius; ο απολογισμός της 
δημιουργίας του ποιήματος "και" ένας απολογισμός από την κόρη 
του Gabriel Linsιn?s της δημιουργίας του τραγουδιού "μπορούν
επίσης να μεταφορτωθούν από την ίδια σελίδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un día del verano en Kangasala contiene la 
información sobre este poema y composición, sus fabricantes, el 
poema sí mismo, la música de la hoja, así como MIDI y los ficheros 
audio. Para visión la música de la hoja, los utilizadores 
necesitan las agregaciones libres siguientes en sus browsers: 
Programa de lectura de la quemadura (para los ficheros de 
Sibelius, puede también ser utilizado jugar, transportar e imprimir 
música) y del acróbata (para los ficheros del pdf, puede ser 
utilizado solamente para la visión e imprimir música de la hoja). 
El poema fue escrito por Sakari Topelius, compuesto por Gabriel 
Linsén, y las palabras actuales en finlandés para la canción han 
sido escritas por P.J. Hannikainen. Las palabras están 
disponibles en finlandés, sueco, inglés, alemán, karelian, 
esperanto y también en el argot de Helsinki. La música de la 
hoja está para el coro mezclado y los children?s cantan a coro. 
Las paginaciones también incluyen un facsímil de la notación 
en Linsén?s poseen cursivo a partir de 1864. En las 
extremidades para las escuelas sección, los profesores pueden 
descargar una presentación de PowerPoint de la canción, de su 
génesis y de los programas de escritura. ¿MP3 ficheros audio 
"Sakari Topelius? la cuenta de la creación del poema "y" una 
cuenta de la hija de Gabriel Linsén?s de la creación de la canción 
"se pueden también descargar de la misma paginación.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Arto Joutsimäki
n:Joutsimäki;Arto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Heikki Mäenpää
n:Mäenpää;Heikki
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/464B2A16-72BB-EEE4-E187-F8BEC64AF883</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/464B2A16-72BB-EEE4-E187-F8BEC64AF883</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:41:42.21Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>broadcast</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>presentation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä - Epäkaupallinen - Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>593</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>858</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>991</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>861</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>857</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,27217,35496,19192</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,1329,27217,35496,19192</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
