<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/elintarvikkeidenpakkaaminen</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/elintarvikkeidenpakkaaminen</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/elintarvikkeidenpakkaaminen</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Packaging of Foodstuffs</string>
            <string language="fi">Elintarvikkeiden Pakkaaminen -oppimateriaalin etusivu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verpacken der Nahrungsmittel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Empaquetage des produits alimentaires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Empacotar dos gêneros alimentícios</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imballaggio delle derrate alimentari</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συσκευασία των τροφίμων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Empaquetado de comestibles</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The website is intended mainly for food sector students and professionals. Also pupils studying for food sales and transportation tasks or people working in these will find useful information. Students can use the material to obtain basic information on the materials and methods used in food packages and the tasks of a package as well as on the history of packaging. Packaging is also examined from an environmental viewpoint. The material includes descriptions of the packaging processes of various foodstuffs. The web material can be used as study material in ordinary contact teaching lessons by assigning students various tasks. Examples of possible tasks can also be found on the pages, but they can be built with a little effort by students themselves. The website can also be used as material for a course built on a web learning platform. The website’s theme areas support the aims and content of the study modules referred to in the national core curriculum of the vocational qualification in the food industry.</string>
            <string language="fi">Sivusto on tarkoitettu pääasiassa elintarvikealan opiskelijoille ja ammattilaisille. Myös elintarvikkeiden myynti- ja kuljetustehtäviin opiskelevat tai niissä toimivat löytävät hyödyllisiä tietoja, samoin tavalliset kuluttajat. Materiaalin avulla saa perustiedot elintarvikepakkauksiin käytettävistä materiaaleista, menetelmistä ja pakkauksen tehtävistä sekä pakkaamisen historiasta. Verkkomateriaalia voi käyttää oppimateriaalina tavanomaisilla lähiopetustunneilla antamalla opiskelijoille erilaisia tehtäviä. Sivustoa voi käyttää myös verkko-oppimisalustalle rakennetun kurssin materiaalina. Sivuston aihealueet tukevat elintarvikealan perustutkinnon opetussuunnitelmaperusteissa mainittujen opintokokonaisuuksien tavoitteita ja sisältöjä.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Web site ist hauptsächlich für 
Nahrungsmittelsektorkursteilnehmer und -fachleute bestimmt. Die 
auch Schüler, die für Nahrungsmittelverkäufe und Transportaufgaben 
studieren oder die Leute, die in diesen arbeiten, finden nützliche 
Informationen. Kursteilnehmer können das Material benutzen, um 
grundlegende Informationen über die Materialien und die Methoden, die
in den Nahrungsmittelpaketen verwendet werden und die Aufgaben eines 
Pakets sowie auf der Geschichte des Verpackens zu erhalten. Das 
Verpacken wird auch von einer Klimaveranschaulichung überprüft. 
Das Material schließt Beschreibungen der verpackenprozesse der 
verschiedenen Nahrungsmittel ein. Das Web-Material kann als 
Studie Material benutzt werden in unterrichtenden Lektionen des 
gewöhnlichen Kontaktes, indem man Kursteilnehmern verschiedene 
Aufgaben zuweist. Beispiele der möglichen Aufgaben können auf 
den Seiten auch gefunden werden, aber sie können mit einer wenig 
Bemühung durch Kursteilnehmer selbst aufgebaut werden. Die Web 
site kann wie Material für einen Kurs auch verwendet werden, der auf 
einer erlernenplattform des Webs aufgebaut wird. Die website?s 
Themabereiche unterstützen die Ziele und den Inhalt der Studie 
Module, die im nationalen Kernlehrplan der beruflichen Qualifikation 
in der Lebensmittelindustrie angesprochen werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web est destiné principalement pour des 
étudiants et des professionnels de secteur de nourriture. En 
outre les élèves étudiant en ventes et transport de nourriture 
charge ou les gens travaillant dans ces derniers trouveront 
l'information utile. Les étudiants peuvent employer le 
matériel pour obtenir l'information de base sur les matériaux et les
méthodes employées en modules de nourriture et charge d'un
module aussi bien que sur l'histoire de l'empaquetage. 
L'empaquetage est également examiné d'un point de vue 
environnemental. Le matériel inclut des descriptions des 
processus d'empaquetage de divers produits alimentaires. Le 
matériel de Web peut être utilisé comme matériel d'étude dans des
leçons d'enseignement de contact ordinaire en affectant des 
étudiants divers charge. Les exemples de possible 
charge peuvent également être trouvés aux pages, mais ils
peuvent être établis avec un peu d'effort par des étudiants 
eux-mêmes. Le site Web peut également être utilisé comme 
matériel pour un cours établi sur une plateforme d'étude de Web. 
Les zones de thème de website?s supportent les objectifs et la 
teneur des modules d'étude visés au programme d'études national de 
noyau de la qualification professionnelle dans l'industrie 
alimentaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site é pretendido principalmente para 
estudantes e profissionais do setor do alimento. Também os 
alunos que estudam para vendas do alimento e tarefas do transporte ou 
os povos que trabalham nestes encontrarão a informação útil. 
Os estudantes podem usar o material obter a informação básica
nos materiais e nos métodos usados em pacotes do alimento e as 
tarefas de um pacote as.well.as no history de empacotar. 
Empacotar é examinado também de um viewpoint ambiental. 
O material inclui descrições dos processos empacotando de 
vários gêneros alimentícios. O material do Web pode ser usado
como o material do estudo em lições ensinando do contato ordinário 
atribuindo a estudantes várias tarefas. Os exemplos de tarefas 
possíveis podem também ser encontrados nas páginas, mas podem ser 
construídos com pouco esforço por estudantes ele mesmo. O Web 
site pode também ser usado como material para um curso construído em
uma plataforma de aprendizagem do Web. As áreas do tema dos 
website?s suportam os alvos e o índice dos módulos do estudo 
consultados no curriculum nacional do núcleo da qualificação 
vocacional na indústria de alimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web site è inteso pricipalmente per gli 
allievi ed i professionisti del settore dell'alimento. Inoltre 
gli allievi che studiano per le vendite dell'alimento e le mansioni 
del trasporto o la gente che lavora in questi troveranno le 
informazioni utili. Gli allievi possono usare il materiale per 
ottenere le informazioni di base sui materiali e sui metodi impiegati 
in pacchetti dell'alimento e le mansioni di un pacchetto così come 
sulla storia di imballaggio. L'imballaggio egualmente è 
esaminato da un punto di vista ambientale. Il materiale include 
le descrizioni dei processi impaccanti di varie derrate alimentari. 
Il materiale di Web può essere usato come materiale di studio 
nelle lezioni d'istruzione del contatto ordinario assegnando ad 
allievi le varie mansioni. Gli esempi delle mansioni possibili 
possono anche essere trovati alle pagine, ma possono essere sviluppati
con un poco sforzo dagli allievi essi stessi. Il Web site può 
anche essere usato come materiale per un corso sviluppato su una 
piattaforma imparante di Web. Le zone di tema dei website?s 
sostengono gli obiettivi ed il contenuto dei moduli di studio citati 
nel programma di studi nazionale di nucleo della qualificazione 
professionale nell'industria alimentare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ιστοχώρος προορίζεται κυρίως για τους σπουδαστές και
τους επαγγελματίες τομέα των τροφίμων. Επίσης οι μαθητές 
που μελετούν για τις πωλήσεις τροφίμων και τις στοιχειώδεις 
εργασίες μεταφορών ή οι άνθρωποι που εργάζονται σε αυτές θα 
βρούν τις χρήσιμες πληροφορίες. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιήσουν το υλικό για να λάβουν τις βασικές πληροφορίες 
για τα υλικά και τις μεθόδους που χρησιμοποιούνται στις 
συσκευασίες τροφίμων και τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες μιας 
συσκευασίας καθώς επίσης και για την ιστορία της συσκευασίας. 
Η συσκευασία εξετάζεται επίσης από μια περιβαλλοντική 
άποψη. Το υλικό περιλαμβάνει τις περιγραφές των διαδικασιών
συσκευασίας των διάφορων τροφίμων. Το υλικό Ιστού μπορεί 
να χρησιμοποιηθεί ως υλικό μελέτης στα συνηθισμένα μαθήματα 
διδασκαλίας επαφών με να αναθέσει στους σπουδαστές τις διάφορες 
στοιχειώδεις εργασίες. Τα παραδείγματα των πιθανών 
στοιχειωδών εργασιών μπορούν επίσης να βρεθούν στις σελίδες, 
αλλά μπορούν να χτιστούν με μια μικρή προσπάθεια από τους 
σπουδαστές οι ίδιοι. Ο ιστοχώρος μπορεί επίσης να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί ως υλικό για μια σειρά μαθημάτων που στηρίζεται σε
μια πλατφόρμα εκμάθησης Ιστού. Οι περιοχές θέματος 
website?s υποστηρίζουν τους στόχους και το περιεχόμενο των 
ενοτήτων μελέτης που αναφέρονται στο εθνικό πρόγραμμα σπουδών 
πυρήνων των επαγγελματικών προσόντων στη βιομηχανία τροφίμων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site se piensa principalmente para los 
estudiantes y los profesionales del sector del alimento. 
También las pupilas que estudian para las ventas del alimento y
las tareas del transporte o la gente que trabaja en éstos 
encontrarán la información útil. Los estudiantes pueden 
utilizar el material para obtener la información básica sobre los 
materiales y los métodos usados en conjuntos del alimento y las 
tareas de un conjunto así como en la historia del empaquetado. 
El empaquetado también se examina de un punto de vista 
ambiental. El material incluye descripciones de los procesos de 
empaquetado de varios comestibles. El material del Web se puede 
utilizar como material del estudio en lecciones de enseñanza del 
contacto ordinario asignando a estudiantes varias tareas. Los 
ejemplos de tareas posibles se pueden también encontrar en las 
paginaciones, pero pueden ser construidos con un poco esfuerzo de los 
estudiantes ellos mismos. El Web site se puede también utilizar
como material para un curso construido en una plataforma que aprende 
del Web. Las áreas del tema de los website?s utilizan las 
punterías y el contenido de los módulos del estudio mencionados en 
el plan de estudios nacional de la base de la calificación vocacional
en el sector alimenticio.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jorma Riihikoski
n:Riihikoski;Jorma
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Timo Ingalsuo
n:Ingalsuo;Timo
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Irma Häikiö
n:Häikiö;Irma
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B92F7393-7D6C-585F-87F2-A4560EE38915</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B92F7393-7D6C-585F-87F2-A4560EE38915</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eeva-Liisa Vihinen
n:Vihinen;Eeva-Liisa 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:05.51Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">14-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">ei mainintaa</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>435</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>501</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>506</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>938</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/elintarvikkeidenpakkaaminen</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/elintarvikkeidenpakkaaminen</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
