<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/puhelinvastaaja</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/puhelinvastaaja</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/puhelinvastaaja</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Telephone answering machine</string>
            <string language="fi">Puhelinvastaaja</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anrufbeantworter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Répondeur téléphonique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Máquina respondendo de telefone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Segreteria telefonica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τηλεφωνικός αυτόματος τηλεφωνητής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Contestador automático de teléfono</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The pupil has to find, by listening and deducing, a suitable time for meeting three people. Messages have been left on an answering machine which the pupil can listen to by clicking a button. In the messages, various people say when they are busy and when they have free time in the calendar. By listening carefully, the pupil has to conclude which of the weekdays and times given is the only possible meeting time. In addition to aural comprehension, pupils have to be able to apply given information for solving the task. The program is a downloadable application.</string>
            <string language="fi">Oppilaan on löydettävä kuuntelemalla ja päättelemällä sopiva ajankohta kolmen henkilön tapaamiselle. Puhelinvastaajaan on jätetty viestejä, jotka oppilas voi kuunnella napauttamalla painikkeita. Viesteissä eri ihmiset kertovat, milloin heillä on menoja ja milloin kalenterissa olisi vapaata aikaa. Kuuntelemalla tarkasti oppilaan on pääteltävä, mikä annetuista viikonpäivistä ja kellonajoista on ainoa mahdollinen tapaamisajankohta. Kuullunymmärtämisen lisäksi on siis pystyttävä soveltamaan annettuja tietoja tehtävän ratkaisemiseksi. Ohjelma on ladattava sovellutus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schüler muß finden, indem er, ein passender 
Zeitpunkt für Sitzung drei Leute hört und ableitet. Meldungen 
sind auf einer antwortenden Maschine gelassen worden, die die Schüler
zu, indem er eine Taste hören kann anklickt. In den Meldungen 
sagen verschiedene Völker, wann sie besetzt sind und wann sie freie 
Zeit im Kalender haben. Indem er sorgfältig hört, muß die 
Schüler folgern, welches der Wochentage und der Zeiten gegeben die 
einzige mögliche Sitzung Zeit ist. Zusätzlich zum 
Ohrenerfassen müssen Pupillen können, gegebene Informationen für 
das Lösen der Aufgabe anzuwenden. Das Programm ist eine 
downloadableanwendung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élève doit trouver, par l'écoute et la 
déduction, un temps approprié pour des personnes de la réunion 
trois. Des messages ont été laissés sur un répondeur que 
l'élève peut écouter par cliquer un bouton. Dans les
messages, les diverses personnes disent quand elles sont occupées et 
quand elles ont le temps libre dans le calendrier. En écoutant 
soigneusement, l'élève doit conclure lesquels des jours de la 
semaine et des temps indiqués est le seul temps possible de réunion.
En plus de la compréhension auditive, les pupilles doivent 
pouvoir appliquer l'information fournie pour résoudre le charger. 
Le programme est une application downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O aluno tem que encontrar, escutando e deduzindo, 
uma estadia apropriada para povos da reunião três. As 
mensagens foram deixadas em uma máquina respondendo que o aluno 
pudesse escutar estalar uma tecla. Nas mensagens, os vários 
povos dizem quando são ocupados e quando têm o tempo livre no 
calendário. Escutando com cuidado, o aluno tem que conclir qual
dos weekdays e dos tempos dados é o único tempo possível da 
reunião. Além à compreensão aural, as pupilas têm que poder
aplicar a informação dada para resolver a tarefa. O programa 
é uma aplicação downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo deve trovare, ascoltando e deducendo, un
periodo adatto per la gente di riunione tre. I messaggi sono 
stati lasciati su una macchina di risposta che l'allievo può 
ascoltare scattando un tasto. Nei messaggi, la varia gente dice 
quando sono occupate e quando hanno tempo libero nel calendario. 
Ascoltando con attenzione, l'allievo deve concludere quale dei 
giorni della settimana e dei tempi dati è l'unico tempo possibile di 
riunione. Oltre che la comprensione sonora, le pupille devono 
potere applicare le informazioni fornite per risolvere l'operazione. 
Il programma è un'applicazione downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο μαθητής πρέπει να βρεί, με το άκουσμα και το 
εξαγωγή συμπεράσματος, ένας κατάλληλος χρόνος για τη συνεδρίαση 
τρία άνθρωποι. Τα μηνύματα έχουν αφεθεί σε έναν αυτόματο 
τηλεφωνητή τον οποίο ο μαθητής μπορεί να ακούσει με τον κρότο 
ενός κουμπιού. Στα μηνύματα, οι διάφοροι άνθρωποι λένε 
πότε είναι απασχολημένοι και πότε έχουν τον ελεύθερο χρόνο στο 
ημερολόγιο. Με να ακούσει προσεκτικά, ο μαθητής πρέπει να 
ολοκληρώσει όποιων των εργάσιμων μερών και των χρόνων που 
δίνονται είναι ο μόνος πιθανός χρόνος συνεδρίασης. Εκτός 
από την ακουστική κατανόηση, οι μαθητές πρέπει να είναι σε θέση
να εφαρμόσουν τις δεδομένες πληροφορίες για την επίλυση της 
στοιχειώδους εργασίας. Το πρόγραμμα είναι μια 
τηλεκατεγραφόμενη εφαρμογή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La pupila tiene que encontrar, escuchando y 
deduciendo, un rato conveniente para las personas de la reunión tres.
Los mensajes se han dejado en un contestador automático que la 
pupila puede escuchar haciendo clic un botón. En los mensajes, 
la varia gente dice cuándo ella está ocupada y cuándo ella tiene 
tiempo libre en el calendario. Escuchando cuidadosamente, la 
pupila tiene que concluir cuáles de los días laborables y de los 
tiempos dados es el único tiempo posible de la reunión. 
Además de comprensión aural, las pupilas tienen que poder 
aplicar la información dada para solucionar la tarea. El 
programa es una aplicación downloadable.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet OY
n:Lingonet OY
org:Lingonet OY
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/0243F5F5-BF21-BFC0-A312-D1AE925C3182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/0243F5F5-BF21-BFC0-A312-D1AE925C3182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:25.84Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>709</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>238</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1295</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>461</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>750</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/puhelinvastaaja</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/puhelinvastaaja</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
