<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/78521</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>78521</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/musiikki/folkbox_1/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/musiikki/folkbox_1/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Perinnemusiikin elementtejä - Osa 1: Virittäminen ja sävelkorkeus</string>
            <string language="en">Elements of traditional music - Part 1: Tuning and pitch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elemente der traditionellen Musik - Teil 1: 
Justage und Taktabstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Éléments de la musique traditionnelle - partie 1
: Accord et lancement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Elementos da música tradicional - parte 1: 
Ajustar e passo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elementi di musica tradizionale - parte 1: 
Sintonizzazione e passo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στοιχεία της παραδοσιακής μουσικής - μέρος 1: 
Συντονισμός και πίσσα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elementos de la música tradicional - parte 1: 
El templar y echada</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Perinnemusiikin elementtejä on neljän oppimisaihion sarja, joka on tarkoitettu 11-vuotiaille ja sitä vanhemmille musiikin opetukseen ja monikulttuuriseen kasvatukseen. Tavoitteena on antaa valmiuksia eri maiden kansanmusiikin ymmärtämiseen. Aihiot sopivat itsenäiseen työskentelyyn, mutta paras hyöty saadaan ryhmässä. Tässä Virittäminen ja sävelkorkeus -aihiossa käsitellään seuraavia asioita: sävelkorkeus, ääni, värähtely, taajuus, virittäminen, äänen korkeus. Sisältää erilaisia ääniin ja sävelkorkeuteen ja virittämiseen liittyviä monipuolisia käytännön harjoituksia. Sisältää myös ohjeet opettajalle. Aihiot on toteutettu Flash-tekniikalla. Toimiakseen ne tarvitsevat selaimeen Flash-laajennuksen, jonka voit ladata ilmaiseksi tietokoneellesi.</string>
            <string language="en">Elements of traditional music is a series of four learning objects that is meant for 11-year-olds and older pupils for music teaching and multicultural education. The aim is to equip pupils to understand the folk music of various countries. The objects are suitable for independent work, but the best benefit is obtained in a group. This Tuning and Pitch object examines the following topics: note pitch, sound, vibration, frequency, tuning, sound pitch. Contains a variety of various practical exercises related to sounds and pitch and tuning. Also contains instructions for the teacher. The objects have been implemented with Flash-technology. In order for them to work, they need a Flash add-on in the browser, which you can download for free onto your computer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">virittäminen</string>
            <string language="en">sävelkorkeus,</string>
            <string language="fi">virittäminen</string>
            <string language="fi">sävelkorkeus,</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elemente der traditionellen Musik ist Reihen von 
vier erlernennachrichten, die für 11-year-olds und ältere Pupillen 
für Musikunterricht und multikulturelle Ausbildung bedeutet wird. 
Das Ziel ist ausrüsten Pupillen, um die Volksmusik der 
verschiedenen Länder zu verstehen. Die Nachrichten sind für 
unabhängige Arbeit verwendbar, aber der beste Nutzen wird in einer 
Gruppe erreicht. Diesesjustage und Taktabstand Nachricht 
überprüft die folgenden Themen: beachten Sie Taktabstand, Ton,
Erschütterung, die Frequenz und justieren, Tontaktabstand. 
Enthält eine Vielzahl der verschiedenen praktischen Übungen, 
die auf Tönen und Taktabstand und Justage in Verbindung gestanden 
werden. Enthält auch Anweisungen für den Lehrer. Die 
Nachrichten sind mit Blitz-Technologie eingeführt worden. Damit
sie, um zu arbeiten, sie einen Blitzzusatz in der Datenbanksuchroutine
benötigen, die Sie für freies auf Ihren Computer downloaden können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les éléments de la musique traditionnelle est 
des séries de quatre objets d'étude qui sont signifiées pour 
11-year-olds et pupilles plus anciennes pour l'enseignement de musique
et l'éducation multiculturelle. Le but est équipent des 
pupilles pour comprendre la musique folklorique de divers pays. 
Les objets conviennent au travail indépendant, mais le meilleur
avantage est obtenu en groupe. L'objet d'accord et de lancement 
de ceci examine les sujets suivants : notez le lancement, bruit,
vibration, fréquence, accordant, lancement de bruit. Contient 
une variété de divers exercices pratiques liés aux bruits et le 
lancement et accord. Contient en outre des instructions pour le 
professeur. Les objets ont été mis en application avec la 
Flash-technologie. Afin qu'ils puissent pour fonctionner, ils 
aient besoin d'une adjonction d'instantané dans le navigateur, que 
vous pouvez télécharger pour libre sur votre ordinateur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os elementos da música tradicional são umas 
séries de quatro objetos de aprendizagem que sejam significadas para 
11-year-olds e umas pupilas mais velhas para o ensino da música e a 
instrução multicultural. O alvo é equipa as pupilas para 
compreender a música popular de vários países. Os objetos 
são apropriados para o trabalho independente, mas o mais melhor 
benefício é obtido em um grupo. O objeto ajustar e de passo 
isto examina os seguintes tópicos: anote o passo, som, 
vibração, freqüência, ajustando, passo do som. Contem uma 
variedade dos vários exercícios práticos relacionados aos sons e o 
passo e ajustar. Contem também instruções para o professor. 
Os objetos foram executados com Flash-tecnologia. Para que
para trabalhar, eles necessitam um add-on do flash no browser, que 
você pode download para livre em seu computador.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli elementi di musica tradizionale è una serie 
di quattro oggetti imparanti che è significata per 11-year-olds e le 
più vecchie pupille per insegnamento di musica e formazione 
multicultural. Lo scopo è dota le pupille per capire la musica 
di piega di vari paesi. Gli oggetti sono adatti a lavoro 
indipendente, ma il beneficio migliore è ottenuto in gruppo. 
L'oggetto di sintonizzazione e del passo ciò esamina i seguenti
soggetti: noti il passo, il suono, la vibrazione, la frequenza, 
di sintonia, altezza di suono. Contiene una varietà di varie 
esercitazioni pratiche relative ai suoni e passo e sintonizzare. 
Egualmente contiene le istruzioni per l'insegnante. Gli 
oggetti sono stati effettuati con Flash-tecnologia. Nell'ordine 
affinchè loro funzionino, hanno bisogno di un'adjunta dell'istantaneo
nel browser, che dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti potete 
trasferire per libero sul vostro calcolatore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα στοιχεία της παραδοσιακής μουσικής είναι μια σειρά
τεσσάρων αντικειμένων εκμάθησης που σημαίνουν για το 11-έτος και 
τους παλαιότερους μαθητές για τη διδασκαλία μουσικής και την 
πολυπολιτισμική εκπαίδευση. Ο στόχος είναι να εξοπλιστούν 
οι μαθητές για να καταλάβει τη λαϊκή μουσική των διάφορων 
χωρών. Τα αντικείμενα είναι κατάλληλα για την ανεξάρτητη 
εργασία, αλλά το καλύτερο όφελος λαμβάνεται σε μια ομάδα. 
Αυτό το αντικείμενο συντονισμού και πισσών εξετάζει τα 
ακόλουθα θέματα: πίσσα σημειώσεων, ήχος, δόνηση, 
συχνότητα, συντονισμός, υγιής πίσσα. Περιέχει ποικίλες 
διάφορες πρακτικές ασκήσεις σχετικές με τους ήχους και την πίσσα
και το συντονισμό. Επίσης περιέχει τις οδηγίες για το 
δάσκαλο. Τα αντικείμενα έχουν εφαρμοστεί με την 
στιγμιαίος-τεχνολογία. Για λειτουργούν, χρειάζονται μια 
λάμψη πρόσθετη στον ξεφυλλιστή, τον οποίο μπορείτε να 
μεταφορτώσετε δωρεάν επάνω στον υπολογιστή σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los elementos de la música tradicional son las 
series de cuatro objetos que aprenden que se significan para 
11-year-olds y pupilas más viejas para la enseñanza de la música y 
la educación multicultural. La puntería es equipa pupilas para
entender la música tradicional de varios países. Los objetos 
son convenientes para el trabajo independiente, pero la mejor ventaja se 
obtiene en un grupo. El objeto el templar y de la echada esto 
examina los asuntos siguientes: observe la echada, sonido, 
vibración, frecuencia, templando, echada del sonido. Contiene 
una variedad de varios ejercicios prácticos relacionados con los 
sonidos y echada y el templar. También contiene las 
instrucciones para el profesor. Los objetos se han puesto en 
ejecucio'n con Flash-tecnologi'a. En la orden para que trabajen,
necesitan una agregación del flash en el browser, que usted puede 
descargar para libre sobre su ordenador.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">virittäminen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">sävelkorkeus,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">virittäminen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sävelkorkeus,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">virittäminen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sävelkorkeus,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">virittäminen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sävelkorkeus,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el"></string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">sδvelkorkeus,</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">virittäminen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sävelkorkeus,</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/BACFD2A6-7CB9-2611-9A26-0A49891DD20C</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/BACFD2A6-7CB9-2611-9A26-0A49891DD20C</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anna-Elina Häkkilä
n:Häkkilä;Anna-Elina 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-04-09T19:44:34.85Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">11-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,507,19640</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>856</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1216</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>78521</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/musiikki/folkbox_1/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
