<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222973</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222973</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/vanhustyo</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/vanhustyo</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/vanhustyo</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">If only they asked what I want</string>
            <string language="fi">Kun ne kysyis mitä mä haluun</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn nur sie fragten, was ich wünsche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Si seulement ils demandaient ce que je veux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Se somente perguntarem o que eu quero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Se soltanto chiedessero che cosa desidero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εάν μόνο ρώτησαν τι θέλω</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Si solamente preguntaron lo que deseo</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The learning material examines the competence in work with the elderly required in the work of a practical nurse and teaches the student to discover development challenges in work with the elderly and develops group and project work using various learning methods. The learning material comprises five subareas: individual old age, an elderly person’s resources and ability to function, the elderly person at home, the elderly person in his/her local environment, and the elderly person in society. The user can choose which viewpoint to approach work with the elderly from.</string>
            <string language="fi">Lähihoitajaopiskelijoille tarkoitettu oppimateriaali, jossa  käsitellään lähihoitajan työssä tarvittavaa vanhustyön osaamista sekä opitaan löytämään vanhustyön kehittämishaasteita ja kehitetään ryhmä- ja projektityöskentelyä erilaisin oppimismenetelmin. Oppimateriaali muodostuu viidestä osa-alueesta: yksilöllinen vanhuus, vanhuksen voimavarat ja toimintakyky, vanhus kodissaan, vanhus lähiympäristössään ja vanhus yhteiskunnassa. Käyttäjä voi valita, mistä näkökulmasta vanhustyötä haluaa lähestyä.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das erlernenmaterial überprüft die Kompetenz in 
der Arbeit mit den älteren Personen, die in der Arbeit einer 
praktischen Krankenschwester benötigt werden und unterrichtet den 
Kursteilnehmer, Entwicklung Herausforderungen in der Arbeit mit den 
älteren Personen zu entdecken und entwickelt Gruppe und Projektarbeit
mit verschiedenen erlernenmethoden. Das erlernenmaterial 
enthält fünf Unterregionen: einzelnes altes Alter, ältere 
Personen person?s Betriebsmittel und Fähigkeit, zu Hause zu arbeiten,
die ältere Person, die ältere Person in seiner/ihr lokaler Umgebung 
und die ältere Person in der Gesellschaft. Der Benutzer kann 
wählen, dem die Veranschaulichung, zum sich zu nähern der Arbeit mit
den älteren Personen von.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matériel d'étude examine la compétence dans 
le travail avec les personnes âgées exigées dans le travail d'une 
infirmière pratique et enseigne l'étudiant à découvrir des défis 
de développement dans le travail avec les personnes âgées et 
développe le travail de groupe et de projet en utilisant de diverses 
méthodes d'étude. Le matériel d'étude comporte cinq 
sous-domaines : vieil âge individuel, ressources de person?s de
personnes âgées et capacité de fonctionner, la vieille personne à 
la maison, la vieille personne dans son environnement local, et la 
vieille personne dans la société. L'utilisateur peut dont 
choisir point de vue pour approcher le travail avec les personnes 
âgées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O material de aprendizagem examina o competence no
trabalho com as pessoas idosas requeridas no trabalho de uma 
enfermeira prática e ensina o estudante descobrir desafios do 
desenvolvimento no trabalho com as pessoas idosas e desenvolve o 
trabalho do grupo e de projeto usando vários métodos de 
aprendizagem. O material de aprendizagem compreende cinco 
subareas: idade velha individual, recursos dos person?s das 
pessoas idosas e abilidade funcionar, a pessoa idosa na HOME, a pessoa
idosa em his/her ambiente local, e a pessoa idosa na sociedade. 
O usuário pode escolher de que viewpoint para aproximar o 
trabalho com as pessoas idosas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il materiale imparante esamina la competenza nel 
lavoro con gli anziani richiesti nel lavoro di un'infermiera pratica 
ed insegna l'allievo scoprire le sfide di sviluppo nel lavoro con gli 
anziani ed elabora di progetto di lavoro e del gruppo usando i vari 
metodi imparanti. Il materiale imparante contiene cinque piccole
regioni: età vecchia specifica, risorse dei person?s degli 
anziani e capacità funzionare, la persona anziana nel paese, la 
persona anziana nel suo ambiente locale e la persona anziana nella 
società. L'utente può scegliere da cui punto di vista per 
avvicinarsi al lavoro con gli anziani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το υλικό εκμάθησης εξετάζει την ικανότητα στην 
εργασία με τους ηλικιωμένους που απαιτούνται στην εργασία μιας 
πρακτικής νοσοκόμας και διδάσκει το σπουδαστή για να ανακαλύψει 
τις προκλήσεις ανάπτυξης στην εργασία με τους ηλικιωμένους και 
αναπτύσσει την εργασία ομάδας και προγράμματος χρησιμοποιώντας 
τις διάφορες μεθόδους εκμάθησης. Το υλικό εκμάθησης 
περιλαμβάνει πέντε υποπεριοχές: μεμονωμένα γηρατειά, 
ηλικιωμένη στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς person?s και δυνατότητα να 
λειτουργήσει, το ηλικιωμένο πρόσωπο στο σπίτι, το ηλικιωμένο 
πρόσωπο στο τοπικό περιβάλλον του/της, και το ηλικιωμένο πρόσωπο 
στην κοινωνία. Ο χρήστης μπορεί να επιλέξει ποια άποψη στην
εργασία προσέγγισης με τους ηλικιωμένους από.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El material que aprende examina la capacidad en 
trabajo con los ancianos requeridos en el trabajo de una enfermera 
práctica y enseña a estudiante a descubrir desafíos del desarrollo 
en trabajo con los ancianos y desarrolla el trabajo del grupo y de 
proyecto usando varios métodos que aprenden. El material que 
aprende abarca cinco subzonas: vieja edad individual, recursos 
de los person?s de los ancianos y capacidad de funcionar, la persona 
mayor en el país, la persona mayor en su ambiente local, y la persona
mayor en sociedad. El utilizador puede elegir de quien punto de 
vista para acercar al trabajo con los ancianos.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eila Juutinen
n:Juutinen;Eila
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Seija Rannikko
n:Rannikko;Seija
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ch5 Finland Oy
n:Ch5 Finland Oy
org:Ch5 Finland Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/297D1D6F-EFE6-19E7-3A17-70196386F349</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/297D1D6F-EFE6-19E7-3A17-70196386F349</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eeva-Liisa Vihinen
n:Vihinen;Eeva-Liisa 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T12:04:48.38Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>exploration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>project</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ei mainintaa</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>919</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>582</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>407</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/vanhustyo</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/vanhustyo</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
