<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222742</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222742</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/suihkumoottorit</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/suihkumoottorit</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/suihkumoottorit</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Jet engines</string>
            <string language="fi">Suihkumoottorit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Düsentriebwerke</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voyagez en jet les moteurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Motores de jato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Motori a propulsione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αεριωθούμενες μηχανές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Motores de jet</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Jet engines website has been made to supplement a textbook of the same title with contents presenting an engine’s subsystems, which were omitted from the book, as well as to activate study with exercises on the topic. The question materials used by the FAA (Federal Aviation Administration) have been used as the source of the exercise tasks. The tasks can be used for independent study as they are but the best result is achieved by incorporating them into learning processes adapted for local use. The website also includes a glossary relating to the subject.</string>
            <string language="fi">Suihkumoottorit-sivusto on tehty täydentämään  samannimistä oppikirjaa kirjasta pois jätetyillä moottorin alajärjestelmiä esittelevillä sisällöillä sekä aktivoimaan opiskelua aihealueen harjoituksilla. Harjoitustehtävien lähteenä on käytetty FAA:n (Federal Aviation Administration) käyttämiä kysymysaineistoja. Tehtäviä voidaan käyttää omatoimiseen opiskeluun sellaisinaankin, mutta parhaaseen tulokseen päästään ottamalla ne osiksi paikalliseen käyttöön sovitettuja oppimisprosesseja. Sivustolla on myös aiheeseen liittyvä sanasto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Düsentriebwerkweb site ist gebildet worden, 
um ein Lehrbuch des gleichen Namens mit Inhalt dem Darstellen zu 
ergänzen engine?s Teilsysteme, die vom Buch ausgelassen wurden, 
sowie, Studie mit Übungen auf dem Thema zu aktivieren. Die 
Frage Materialien, die durch das FAA benutzt werden 
(Bundesluftfahrt-Leitung) sind als die Quelle der Übung Aufgaben 
benutzt worden. Die Aufgaben können für unabhängige Studie 
verwendet werden, während sie sind, aber das beste Resultat erzielt 
wird, indem man sie in die Lernprozesse enthält, die für lokalen 
Gebrauch angepaßt werden. Die Web site schließt auch ein 
Glossar in bezug auf das Thema ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web de moteurs de Voyager en jet a été fait
pour compléter un manuel du même titre avec la présentation de 
contenu des engine?s les sous-ensembles, qui ont été omis du livre, 
comme pour lancer l'étude avec des exercices sur le sujet. Les 
matières de question employées par le FAA (gestion fédérale 
d'aviation) ont été utilisées pendant que la source d'exercice 
charge. Charge peut être utilisé pour 
l'étude indépendante pendant qu'elles sont mais le meilleur 
résultat est réalisé en les incorporant dans des apprentissages 
adaptés pour l'usage local. Le site Web inclut également un 
glossaire concernant le sujet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site dos motores de jato foi feito para 
suplementar um textbook do mesmo título com apresentar-se dos 
índices engine?s os subsistemas, que foram omitidos do livro, assim 
como para ativar o estudo com exercícios no tópico. Os 
materiais da pergunta usados pelo FAA (administração federal da 
aviação) foram usados como a fonte das tarefas do exercício. 
As tarefas podem ser usadas para o estudo independente enquanto 
são mas o mais melhor resultado está conseguido incorporando as nos 
processos de aprendizagem adaptados para o uso local. O Web site
inclui também um glossário que relaciona-se ao assunto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web site dei motori a propulsione è stato 
fatto per completare un manuale dello stesso titolo con presentarsi 
del soddisfare engine?s sottosistemi, che sono stati omessi dal libro,
come pure attivare lo studio con le esercitazioni sul soggetto. 
I materiali di domanda utilizzati dal FAA (gestione federale di 
aeronautica) sono stati usati come la sorgente delle mansioni di 
esercitazione. Le mansioni possono essere usate per lo studio 
indipendente mentre sono ma il risultato migliore è raggiunto 
comprendendole negli apprendimento adattati per uso locale. Il 
Web site egualmente include un glossario concernente l'oggetto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ιστοχώρος αεριωθούμενων μηχανών έχει γίνει για να 
συμπληρώσει ένα εγχειρίδιο του ίδιου τίτλου με την παρουσίαση 
περιεχομένου υποσυστήματα engine?s, που παραλείφθηκαν από το 
βιβλίο, καθώς επίσης και για να ενεργοποιήσει τη μελέτη με τις 
ασκήσεις στο θέμα. Τα υλικά ερώτησης που χρησιμοποιούνται 
από το FAA (ομοσπονδιακή διοίκηση αεροπορίας) έχουν 
χρησιμοποιηθεί ως πηγή των στοιχειωδών εργασιών άσκησης. Οι
στοιχειώδεις εργασίες μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για την 
ανεξάρτητη μελέτη δεδομένου ότι είναι μόνο το καλύτερο 
αποτέλεσμα επιτυγχάνονται με την ενσωμάτωση τους στις διαδικασίες 
εκμάθησης που προσαρμόζονται για την τοπική χρήση. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει επίσης ένα γλωσσάρι σχετικά με το θέμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site de los motores de jet se ha hecho 
para suplir un libro de textos del mismo título con la presentación 
del contenido los engine?s los subsistemas, que fueron omitidos del 
libro, tan bien como activar estudio con ejercicios en el asunto. 
Los materiales de la pregunta usados por el FAA (administración
federal de la aviación) se han utilizado como la fuente de las tareas
del ejercicio. Las tareas se pueden utilizar para el estudio 
independiente mientras que son pero el mejor resultado es alcanzado 
incorporándolas en los procesos de aprendizaje adaptados para el uso 
local. El Web site también incluye un glosario referente al 
tema.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Kalevi Känsäkoski
n:Känsäkoski;Kalevi
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lauri Ojansivu
n:Ojansivu;Lauri
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/8175DF58-99F7-7E80-9E7D-C5C671E78B74</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/8175DF58-99F7-7E80-9E7D-C5C671E78B74</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:24.69Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>795</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>34</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/suihkumoottorit</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/suihkumoottorit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
