<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222644</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222644</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=12</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=12</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=12</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Business operations</string>
            <string language="fi">Liiketoiminta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschäftsoperationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Opérations commerciales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Operações de negócio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Funzionamenti di affari</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιχειρησιακές διαδικασίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Operaciones de negocio</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Looks at the basic conditions of business operations and main methods in five parts. The aim is to introduce the salient solutions when launching a business, issues related to planning business operations, and factors crucial in order that the business may become successful.  A further aim is to provide an overview of business activity and particularly of the research, plans and decisions necessary when starting a business and as the operation grows.  Includes exercises, tests, links and further reading.</string>
            <string language="fi">Käsittelee yritystoiminnan perusedellytyksiä ja keskeisiä toimintatapoja viidessä eri osiossa. Tavoitteena on esitellä yritystoiminnan aloittamiseen liittyviä keskeisiä ratkaisuja, yrityksen toiminnan suunnitteluun liittyviä asioita sekä yrityksen menestymisen kannalta olennaisia tekijöitä. Tavoitteena on myös antaa näkemys yritystoiminnan kokonaisuudesta ja erityisesti siitä, mitä selvityksiä, suunnitelmia ja ratkaisuja on yritystoimintaa aloitettaessa ja toiminnan kehittyessä tehtävä. Sisältää tehtäviä, testejä, linkkejä ja lisäkirjallisuutta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die grundlegenden Bedingungen der 
Geschäftsoperationen und der Hauptmethoden in fünf Teilen. Das
Ziel ist, die auffallenden Lösungen vorzustellen, wenn es ein 
Geschäft, die Ausgaben, die auf Planung Geschäftsoperationen in 
Verbindung gestanden werden, und die Faktoren, die ausstößt 
entscheidend sind, so dass das Geschäft erfolgreich werden kann. 
Ein weiteres Ziel ist, einen Überblick über 
Geschäftstätigkeit und besonders über die Forschung, die Pläne und
die Entscheidungen zur Verfügung zu stellen, die notwendig sind, wenn
das Beginnen eines Geschäfts und als die Operation wächst. 
Schließt Übungen, Tests, Links und weiteren Messwert ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Regards aux conditions de base des opérations 
commerciales et des méthodes principales dans cinq parts. Le 
but est de présenter les solutions saillantes en lançant des 
affaires, des issues liées aux opérations commerciales de 
planification, et des facteurs cruciaux pour que les affaires puissent
remporter un grand succès sur. Un autre but est de fournir une 
vue d'ensemble d'activité économique et en particulier de la 
recherche, des plans et des décisions nécessaires quand commencer 
des affaires et comme exécution se développe. Inclut des 
exercices, des essais, des liens et davantage de lecture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Olhares nas condições básicas de operações 
de negócio e de métodos principais em cinco porções. O alvo 
é introduzir as soluções salient ao lançar um negócio, as 
edições relacionadas às operações de negócio do planeamento, e 
os fatores cruciais a fim de que o negócio possa se tornar bem 
sucedido. Um alvo mais adicional é fornecer uma vista geral da 
atividade de negócio e particularmente da pesquisa, das plantas e das
decisões necessárias quando começar um negócio e como a operação
cresce. Inclui exercícios, testes, ligações e uma leitura 
mais adicional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sguardi ai termini di base dei funzionamenti di 
affari e dei metodi principali in cinque parti. Lo scopo è 
introdurre le soluzioni salienti quando lancia un commercio, le 
edizioni relative ai funzionamenti di affari di progettazione ed i 
fattori cruciali affinché il commercio può diventare riuscito. 
Uno scopo ulteriore è fornire una descrizione di attività 
economica e specialmente della ricerca, dei programmi e delle 
decisioni necessari quando iniziare un commercio e come il 
funzionamento si sviluppa. Include le esercitazioni, le prove, i
collegamenti ed ulteriore lettura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξετάζει τους βασικούς όρους των επιχειρησιακών 
διαδικασιών και των βασικών μεθόδων σε πέντε μέρη. Ο 
στόχος είναι να εισαχθούν οι εμφανείς λύσεις κατά την προώθηση 
μιας επιχείρησης, των ζητημάτων σχετικών με τον προγραμματισμό των
επιχειρησιακών διαδικασιών, και των παραγόντων κρίσιμων για η 
επιχείρηση μπορεί να γίνει επιτυχής. Ένας περαιτέρω το 
στόχος είναι να παρασχεθεί μια επισκόπηση της επιχειρησιακής 
δραστηριότητας και ιδιαίτερα της έρευνας, τα σχέδια και οι 
αποφάσεις απαραίτητα κατά έναρξη μιας επιχείρησης και καθώς η 
λειτουργία αυξάνεται. Περιλαμβάνει τις ασκήσεις, τις 
δοκιμές, τις συνδέσεις και την περαιτέρω ανάγνωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Miradas en las condiciones básicas de las 
operaciones de negocio y de los métodos principales en cinco 
porciones. La puntería es introducir las soluciones salientes 
al lanzar un negocio, las ediciones relacionadas con las operaciones 
de negocio de las hojas de operación (planning), y los factores 
cruciales para que el negocio pueda llegar a ser acertado. Otra 
puntería es proporcionar a una descripción de la actividad 
económica y determinado de la investigación, de los planes y de las 
decisiones necesarios cuando comenzar un negocio y como la operación 
crece. Incluye ejercicios, pruebas, conexiones y la lectura 
adicional.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Turun kauppakorkeaekoulun PK-Instituutti
n:Turun kauppakorkeaekoulun PK-Instituutti
org:Turun kauppakorkeaekoulun PK-Instituutti
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/C4D29D38-8633-2261-FA7C-AD5BF5D00892</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/C4D29D38-8633-2261-FA7C-AD5BF5D00892</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:42.30Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>428</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>384</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>779</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1032</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>382</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>429</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>169</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=12</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/yrittajyysvayla/?page=12</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
