<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235345</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235345</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/tunteesta_tunteeseen</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/tunteesta_tunteeseen</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/tunteesta_tunteeseen</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">From emotion to emotion – Instructor’s manual</string>
            <string language="fi">Tunteesta tunteeseen - Ohjaajan opas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von Gefühl zu Gefühl? Instructor?s 
Handbuch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">De l'émotion à l'émotion ? Manuel 
d'Instructor?s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Da emoção à emoção? Manual de 
Instructor?s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Da emozione ad emozione? Manuale di 
Instructor?s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από τη συγκίνηση στη συγκίνηση; Εγχειρίδιο 
Instructor?s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿De la emoción a la emoción? Manual de 
Instructor?s</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Teaching material in emotional skills in education and special education, instructor's manual for the exercise book. The teaching material describes 104 emotions in alphabetical order. The drawing presents the situation and discussion is launched with questions on where and how each emotion is familiar from in everyday life. The objective is to practise identification, naming, expression and regulation of emotions. By learning emotional skills, it is possible to promote good interaction and reduce inner conflicts and conflicts between people.</string>
            <string language="fi">Tunnetaitojen oppimateriaali kasvatukseen ja erityiskasvatukseen : ohjaajan opas harjoituskirjaan. Oppimateriaalissa kuvataan 104 tunnetta aakkosjärjestyksessä. Piirroskuvassa esitetään tilanne ja kysymyksin herätetään keskustelu siitä, missä ja miten kukin tunne on arkielämästä tuttu. Tavoitteena on tunteiden tunnistamisen, nimeämisen, ilmaisemisen ja säätelyn harjoittelu. Tunnetaitoja oppimalla voidaan edistää hyvää vuorovaikutusta ja vähentää ihmisen sisäisiä ja ihmisten välisiä ristiriitoja.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lehrmittel in den emotionalen Fähigkeiten in der 
Ausbildung und in der Spezialausbildung, Handbuch des Ausbilders für 
das Übung Buch. Die Lehrmittel beschreiben 104 Gefühle in 
alphabetischer Reihenfolge. Die Zeichnung stellt die Situation 
dar und Diskussion wird mit Fragen an wo ausgestoßen und wie jedes 
Gefühl in von der täglichen Lebensdauer vertraut ist. Das 
Lernziel ist, Kennzeichen, das Benennen, Ausdruck und Regelung von 
Gefühlen zu üben. Indem man emotionale Fähigkeiten erlernt, 
ist es möglich, gute Interaktion zu fördern und innere 
$überschneidungen zu verringern und widerspricht zwischen Leuten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Matériel didactique dans des qualifications 
émotives dans l'éducation et l'éducation spéciale, le manuel de 
l'instructeur pour le livre d'exercice. Le matériel didactique 
décrit 104 émotions dans l'ordre alphabétique. Le schéma 
expose la situation et la discussion est lancée avec des questions en
fonction où et comment chaque émotion est familière de dans la vie 
quotidienne. L'objectif est de pratiquer l'identification, 
nommer, l'expression et le règlement des émotions. En 
apprenant des qualifications émotives, il est possible de favoriser 
la bonne interaction et de réduire des conflits intérieurs et est en
conflit entre les personnes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Material de ensino em habilidades emocionais na 
instrução e na instrução especial, manual do instrutor para o 
livro do exercício. O material de ensino descreve 104 emoções
na ordem alfabética. O desenho apresenta a situação e a 
discussão é lançada com perguntas sobre onde e como cada emoção 
é familiar na vida diária. O objetivo é praticar a 
identificação, nomear, a expressão e o regulamento das emoções. 
Aprendendo habilidades emocionais, é possível promover a 
interação boa e reduzir conflitos internos e opõe entre povos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Materiale didattico nelle abilità impressionabili 
nella formazione e nella formazione speciale, manuale dell'istruttore 
per il libro di esercitazione. Il materiale didattico descrive 
104 emozioni nell'ordine alfabetico. L'illustrazione presenta la
situazione e la discussione è lanciata con le domande sopra dove e 
come ogni emozione ha familiarità in vita di tutti i giorni. 
L'obiettivo è esercitarsi nell'identificazione, chiamare, 
nell'espressione e nella regolazione delle emozioni. Imparando 
le abilità impressionabili, è possibile promuovere la buona 
interazione e ridurre i conflitti interni ed è in conflitto fra la 
gente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκπαιδευτικό υλικό στις συναισθηματικές δεξιότητες 
στην εκπαίδευση και την ειδική εκπαίδευση, εγχειρίδιο του 
εκπαιδευτικού για το βιβλίο άσκησης. Το εκπαιδευτικό υλικό 
περιγράφει 104 συγκινήσεις κατά αλφαβητική σειρά. Το 
σχέδιο παρουσιάζει την κατάσταση και η συζήτηση προωθείται με τις
ερωτήσεις επάνω όπου και πώς κάθε συγκίνηση είναι γνωστή από 
στην καθημερινή ζωή. Ο στόχος είναι στον προσδιορισμό, την 
ονομασία, την έκφραση και τον κανονισμό πρακτικής των 
συγκινήσεων. Με την εκμάθηση των συναισθηματικών δεξιοτήτων,
είναι δυνατό να προωθηθεί η καλή αλληλεπίδραση και να μειωθούν 
οι εσωτερικές συγκρούσεις και συγκρούεται μεταξύ των ανθρώπων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Material didáctico en habilidades emocionales en 
la educación y la educación especial, manual del instructor para el 
libro del ejercicio. El material didáctico describe 104 
emociones en orden alfabético. El gráfico presenta la 
situación y la discusión se lanza con preguntas encendido donde y 
cómo cada emoción es familiar a partir en de vida diaria. El 
objetivo es practicar la identificación, el nombramiento, la 
expresión y la regulación de emociones. Aprendiendo 
habilidades emocionales, es posible promover la buena interacción y 
reducir conflictos internos y está en conflicto entre la gente.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Kyllikki Kerola
n:Kerola;Kyllikki
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anja Kallio
n:Kallio;Anja
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Sari Kujanpää
n:Kujanpää;Sari
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/743559C9-6619-0E10-A562-6D34BC0EC00E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/743559C9-6619-0E10-A562-6D34BC0EC00E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:11.02Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>presentation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>37</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>420</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1040</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>238</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/tunteesta_tunteeseen</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/tunteesta_tunteeseen</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
