<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235322</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235322</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/yleissivistava_koulutus/aihekokonaisuudet/osallistuva_kansalaisuus_ja_yrittajyys/aktiivinen_kansalaisuus/kuukausiteemat/huhtikuu_valistunut_kuluttaja_ja_lahiymparisto</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/yleissivistava_koulutus/aihekokonaisuudet/osallistuva_kansalaisuus_ja_yrittajyys/aktiivinen_kansalaisuus/kuukausiteemat/huhtikuu_valistunut_kuluttaja_ja_lahiymparisto</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/yleissivistava_koulutus/aihekokonaisuudet/osallistuva_kansalaisuus_ja_yrittajyys/aktiivinen_kansalaisuus/kuukausiteemat/huhtikuu_valistunut_kuluttaja_ja_lahiymparisto</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">April: The enlightened consumer and local environment</string>
            <string language="fi">Huhtikuu: Valistunut kuluttaja ja lähiympäristö</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">April: Der erleuchtete Verbraucher und die 
lokale Umgebung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avril : Le consommateur éclairé et 
l'environnement local</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Abril: O consumidor enlightened e o ambiente
local</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Aprile: Il consumatore chiarito e l'ambiente
locale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Απρίλιος: Ο διαφωτισμένος καταναλωτής και το 
τοπικό περιβάλλον</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Abril: El consumidor aclarado y el ambiente 
local</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The theme months contain material, ideas for action and tasks which can be utilised in education for democratic citizenship and in teaching of topics relating to the Participating and Active Citizenship cross-curricular themes in all subjects and age-groups. The theme month of April looks at considerations combining an ecological approach with civil influencing. In the theme month, the pupil learns more about a school’s environment systems, planning and community planning in a municipality, consumer education and marketing and about architectural and design education. The essential point is to take into account the commitment of the pupils, students and entire work organisation to the development of the local environment – participation, doing and influencing occupy a central position in extensive projects that affect the whole school. Participation and influencing can be reinforced by developing various participation systems.</string>
            <string language="fi">Perusopetukseen ja toisen asteen koulutukseen. Teemakuukaudet sisältävät aineistoa, toimintaideoita ja tehtäviä, joita voi hyödyntää demokraattiseen kansalaisuuteen kasvattamisessa ja Osallistuva ja Aktiivinen kansalaisuus -aihekokonaisuuksiin liittyvien aiheiden opetuksessa kaikissa oppiaineissa ja ikäryhmissä. Huhtikuun teemakuukaudessa käsitellään näkökohtia, joissa yhdistyvät ekologisuus ja kansalaisvaikuttaminen. Teemakuukaudessa perehdytään tarkemmin koulun ympäristöjärjestelmiin, kaavoitukseen ja yhdyskuntasuunnitteluun kunnassa, kuluttajakasvatukseen ja markkinointiin sekä arkkitehtuuri- ja muotoilukasvatukseen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Themamonate enthalten Material, Ideen für 
Tätigkeit und Aufgaben, die in der Ausbildung für demokratische 
Staatsbürgerschaft und im Unterricht von Themen in bezug auf die 
Teilnehmen und aktive StaatsbürgerschaftKreuzlehrplanthemen in allen 
Themen und in Altersklassen verwendet werden können. Der 
Themamonat April betrachtet die Erwägungen, die eine ökologische 
Annäherung mit dem Zivilbeeinflussen kombinieren. Im Themamonat
erlernt die Schüler mehr über eine school?s Umgebung Systeme, 
Planung und Gemeinschaftsplanung in einem Stadtbezirk, 
Verbraucherausbildung und Marketing und über architektonische und 
Designausbildung. Der wesentliche Punkt soll die Verpflichtung 
der Schüler, der Kursteilnehmer und gesamten der Arbeit Organisation 
zur Entwicklung der lokalen Umgebung in Betracht ziehen? die 
Teilnahme, tuend und beeinflussend besetzen eine zentrale Position in 
den umfangreichen Projekten, die die vollständige Schule 
beeinflussen. Teilnahme und das Beeinflussen können durch das 
Entwickeln der verschiedenen Teilnahmesysteme verstärkt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les mois de thème contiennent le matériel, 
idées pour l'action et le chargent qui peut être utilisée 
dans l'éducation pour la citoyenneté démocratique et dans 
l'enseignement des sujets concernant les thèmes croix-curriculaires 
de participation et de citoyenneté active dans tous les sujets et 
groupes d'âge. Le mois de thème d'avril regarde des 
considérations combinant une approche écologique avec influencer 
civil. En mois de thème, l'élève apprend plus au sujet des 
systèmes d'un environnement de school?s, planification et 
planification de la communauté dans une municipalité, éducation du 
consommateur et vente et au sujet de l'éducation architecturale et de
conception. Le point essentiel doit tenir compte de l'engagement
des élèves, des étudiants et de l'organisation du travail entière 
au développement de l'environnement local ? la participation, 
faisant et influençant occupent une position centrale dans les 
projets étendus qui affectent toute l'école. La participation 
et influencer peuvent être renforcés en développant de divers 
systèmes de participation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os meses do tema contêm o material, as idéias 
para a ação e as tarefas que podem ser utilizados na instrução 
para o citizenship democrático e no ensino dos tópicos que se 
relacionam aos temas cruz-cross-curricular participar e de citizenship
ativo em todos os assuntos e age-groups. O mês do tema de abril
olha as considerações que combinam uma aproximação ecological com 
influenciar civil. No mês do tema, o aluno aprende mais sobre 
sistemas de um ambiente dos school?s, planeamento e planeamento da 
comunidade em uma municipalidade, instrução do consumidor e 
marketing e sobre a instrução architectural e do projeto. O 
ponto essencial deve fazer exame no cliente do compromisso dos alunos,
dos estudantes e da organização inteira do trabalho ao 
desenvolvimento do ambiente local? a participação, fazendo e 
influenciando ocupa uma posição central nos projetos extensivos que 
afetam a escola inteira. A participação e influenciar podem 
ser reforçadas desenvolvendo vários sistemas da participação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I mesi di tema contengono il materiale, le idee 
per azione e le mansioni che possono essere utilizzati nella 
formazione per la cittadinanza democratica e nell'insegnamento dei 
soggetti per quanto riguarda i temi traversa-d'insegnamento di 
cittadinanza attiva e di partecipazione in tutti gli oggetti e fasce 
d'età. Il mese di tema di aprile guarda le considerazioni che 
uniscono un metodo ecologico con l'influenza civile. Nel mese di
tema, l'allievo impara più circa i sistemi dell'ambiente degli 
school?s, progettazione e pianificazione della Comunità in un comune,
formazione del consumatore e vendita e circa formazione di disegno ed 
architettonica. Il punto essenziale deve considerare l'impegno 
degli allievi, degli allievi e di intera organizzazione del lavoro 
allo sviluppo dell'ambiente locale? la partecipazione, facente 
ed influenzante occupa una posizione centrale nei vasti progetti che 
interessano la scuola intera. La partecipazione ed influenzare 
possono essere rinforzate sviluppando i vari sistemi di 
partecipazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι μήνες θέματος περιέχουν το υλικό, τις ιδέες για 
την ενέργεια και τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες που μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν στην εκπαίδευση για τη δημοκρατική υπηκοότητα και 
στη διδασκαλία των αντικειμένων σχετικά με τη συμμετοχή και των 
ενεργών διαγώνιος-διδακτικών θεμάτων υπηκοότητας σε όλες τα 
θέματα και τις κλάσεις. Ο μήνας θέματος Απριλίου εξετάζει 
τις εκτιμήσεις που συνδυάζουν μια οικολογική προσέγγιση με τον 
αστικό επηρεασμό. Στο μήνα θέματος, ο μαθητής μαθαίνει 
περισσότερους για τα συστήματα ενός school?s περιβάλλοντος, που
προγραμματίζουν και κοινοτικός που προγραμματίζουν σε έναν δήμο, 
καταναλωτικός εκπαίδευση και που εμπορεύονται και για την 
αρχιτεκτονική και εκπαίδευση σχεδίου. Το ουσιαστικό σημείο 
είναι να ληφθεί υπόψη η δέσμευση των μαθητών, των σπουδαστών και
της ολόκληρης οργάνωσης εργασίας για την ανάπτυξη του τοπικού 
περιβάλλοντος; η συμμετοχή, που κάνει και που επηρεάζει 
καταλαμβάνει μια κεντρική θέση στα εκτενή προγράμματα που έχουν 
επιπτώσεις σε ολόκληρο το σχολείο. Η συμμετοχή και ο 
επηρεασμός μπορούν να ενισχυθούν με την ανάπτυξη των διάφορων 
συστημάτων συμμετοχής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los meses del tema contienen el material, las 
ideas para la acción y las tareas que se pueden utilizar en la 
educación para la ciudadanía democrática y en la enseñanza de 
asuntos referente a los temas cruz-del plan de estudios el participar 
y de la ciudadanía activa en todos los temas y grupos de misma edad. 
El mes del tema de abril mira las consideraciones que combinan 
un acercamiento ecológico con influenciar civil. En el mes del 
tema, la pupila aprende más sobre sistemas de un ambiente de los 
school?s, las hojas de operación (planning) y las hojas de operación
(planning) de la comunidad en un municipio, educación del consumidor 
y comercialización y sobre la educación arquitectónica y del 
diseño. ¿La punta esencial es considerar la consolidación de 
las pupilas, de los estudiantes y de la organización entera del 
trabajo al desarrollo del ambiente local? la participación, 
haciendo e influenciando ocupa una posición central en los proyectos 
extensos que afectan la escuela entera. La participación y el 
influenciar pueden ser reforzados desarrollando varios sistemas de la 
participación.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/146DBDE0-D782-6073-8D8E-D4CA3280450F</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/146DBDE0-D782-6073-8D8E-D4CA3280450F</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:10.34Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>exploration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä - Epäkaupallinen - Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>377</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>431</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>441</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>267</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>388</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/yleissivistava_koulutus/aihekokonaisuudet/osallistuva_kansalaisuus_ja_yrittajyys/aktiivinen_kansalaisuus/kuukausiteemat/huhtikuu_valistunut_kuluttaja_ja_lahiymparisto</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/yleissivistava_koulutus/aihekokonaisuudet/osallistuva_kansalaisuus_ja_yrittajyys/aktiivinen_kansalaisuus/kuukausiteemat/huhtikuu_valistunut_kuluttaja_ja_lahiymparisto</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
