<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102856</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102856</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087317</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Man's Thanksgiving": A Hymn to the God of Business</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Thanksgiving Eines Mannes": Eine 
Hymne zum Gott des Geschäfts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Thanksgiving D'un Homme" : Une hymne à 
Dieu des affaires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Thanksgiving De um Homem": Um hymn ao deus 
do negócio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Thanksgiving Dell'Uomo": Un hymn al dio del
commercio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια ανθρώπινη ημέρα των ευχαριστιών": Ένας 
ύμνος στο Θεό της επιχείρησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Thanksgiving De un Hombre": Un himno al 
dios del negocio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">President Calvin Coolidge captured the spirit of the 1920s when he announced in a speech before the Society of American Newspaper Editors that "the chief business of the American people is business." Coolidge's aphorism revealed the centrality of commerce to the nation and its culture in the 1920s, even while it concealed some of the wrenching cultural changes required to accommodate a commercial civilization. An even more forceful publicist for the view that business and spirituality were compatible was Bruce Barton. The son of a Congregational minister, Barton cofounded one of the nation's largest and best-known advertising agencies. Barton's greatest fame, however, came from the best-selling book that he published in 1925,  The Man Nobody Knows , in which he crafted a new vision of Christ and Christianity that was not simply compatible with, but organically connected to, the business-oriented 1920s. Barton's aggressive efforts to merge business and Christianity may seem comical in the late 20th century, but his exertions were sincerely felt by him and sincerely received by many Americans. The  Jaqua Way , a business publication, offered on its first page the hymn, "A Man's Thanksgiving," in the which author thanked the "God of business men" for "my customers and for the power to serve them faithfully."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Präsident Calvin Coolidge erfaßte den Geist der 
zwanziger Jahre, als er in einer Rede vor der Gesellschaft der 
amerikanischen Zeitungsverleger verkündete, die "das Hauptgeschäft 
der amerikanischen Leute ist Geschäft." Aphorismus Coolidges 
deckte die zentrale Lage des Handels zur Nation und seiner Kultur in 
den zwanziger Jahren auf, sogar während er einige der entreißenden 
kulturellen Änderungen verbarg, die benötigt wurden, um eine 
kommerzielle Zivilisation anzupassen. Ein sogar stärkerer 
Publizist für die Ansicht, die Geschäft und Spirituality kompatibel 
waren, war Bruce Barton. Der Sohn eines Gemeindeministers, 
Barton cofounded eins der größten und bekanntesten Werbebüros der 
Nation. Bartons größter Ruhm kam jedoch vom gut-verkaufenden 
Buch, das er 1925 veröffentlichte, der Mann, den, niemand, in dem er 
einen neuen Anblick von Christ und von Christentum in Handarbeit 
machte, dem nicht mit einfach kompatibel war kennt, aber organisch an 
anschloß, können die business-oriented des zwanziger Jahre Bartons 
konkurrenzfähigen Bemühungen, Geschäft und Christentum zu mergen im
späten 20. Jahrhundert komisch scheinen, aber seine Anstrengungen 
wurden herzlichst von ihm geglaubt und empfangen herzlichst von vielen
Amerikanern. Die Jaqua Methode, eine Wirtschaftspublikation, auf
seiner ersten Seite die Hymne angeboten, "Thanksgiving eines 
Mannes," in, die schreiben gedankt dem "Gott der Geschäftsleute" für
"meine Kunden und für die Energie, sie zuverlässig zu dienen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Président Calvin Coolidge a capturé l'esprit 
des années 20 où il a annoncé dans un discours devant la société 
des éditeurs de journal américains que "les affaires en chef des  
américains sont des affaires." L'aphorisme de Coolidge a 
indiqué la centralité du commerce à la nation et de sa culture dans
les années 20, même tandis qu'il cachait certains des changements 
culturels arrachants exigés pour faciliter une civilisation 
commerciale. Un publiciste bien plus puissant pour la vue qui 
les affaires et le spirituality étaient compatibles était Bruce 
Barton. Le fils d'un ministre en assemblée, Barton cofounded 
une des plus grandes et les plus connues agences de publicité de la 
nation. La plus grande renommée de Barton, cependant, est venue
du livre devente qu'il a édité en 1925, l'homme que personne ne 
connaît, dans laquelle il a ouvré une nouvelle vision du Christ et 
du christianisme avec laquelle n'était pas simplement compatible, 
mais s'est organiquement relié à, les efforts agressifs du Barton 
commercial des années 20 de fusionner des affaires et le 
christianisme peuvent sembler comiques vers la fin du 20ème siècle, 
mais ses efforts ont été sincèrement sentis par lui et sincèrement
reçus par beaucoup d'Américains. La voie de Jaqua, une 
publication d'affaires, offerte à sa première page l'hymne, "le 
Thanksgiving d'un homme," dans qui écrivent remercié "Dieu des hommes 
d'affaires" de "mes clients et de la puissance de les servir 
loyalement."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O presidente Calvin Coolidge capturou o espírito 
dos 1920s em que anunciou em um discurso antes da sociedade dos 
editores de jornal americanos que "o negócio principal dos povos 
americanos é negócio." O aphorism de Coolidge revelou o 
centrality do comércio à nação e da sua cultura nos 1920s, mesmo 
quando escondeu algumas das mudanças cultural wrenching requeridas 
para acomodar uma civilização comercial. Um publicist mesmo 
mais forceful para a vista que o negócio e a espiritualidade eram 
compatíveis era Bruce Barton. O filho de um ministro 
congregational, Barton cofounded uma das agências anunciando as 
maiores e as mais best-known da nação. A fama a mais grande de
Barton, entretanto, veio do livro melhor-vendendo que publicou em 
1925, homem que ninguém conhece, em que crafted uma visão nova de 
Christ e de christianity que não fosse simplesmente compatível com, 
mas conectou orgânica a, os esforços aggressive do Barton de 
negócios dos 1920s. fundir o negócio e o christianity podem parecer 
comical no 20o século atrasado, mas seus exertions foram sentidos 
sincerely por ele e recebidos sincerely por muitos americanos. A
maneira de Jaqua, uma publicação de negócio, oferecida em sua 
primeira página o hymn, "Thanksgiving de um homem," nos que são o 
autor agradecido o "deus de homens de negócio" para "meus clientes e 
para a potência lhes servir fielmente."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il presidente Calvin Coolidge ha bloccato lo 
spirito degli anni 20 in cui ha annunciato in un discorso prima della 
società degli editori di giornale americani che "il commercio 
principale della gente americana è il commercio." Il aphorism 
del Coolidge ha rivelato il centrality del commercio alla nazione e 
della relativa coltura negli anni 20, persino mentre ha celato alcuni 
dei cambiamenti culturali wrenching richiesti per accomodare una 
civilizzazione commerciale. Un publicist ancor più valido per 
la vista che il commercio e lo spirituality erano compatibili era 
Bruce Barton. Il figlio di un ministro congregational, Barton
cofounded una di più grandi e di pubblicità agenzie più note della 
nazione. La fama più grande del Barton, tuttavia, è venuto dal
libro migliore-vendente che ha pubblicato in 1925, l'uomo che nessuno 
conosce, in cui perfezionamento una nuova visione di Christ e di 
christianity che non era semplicemente compatibile con, ma 
organicamente che ha collegato a, gli sforzi aggressivi del Barton 
business-oriented degli anni 20 fondere il commercio ed il 
christianity possono sembrare comical verso la fine del ventesimo 
secolo, ma i suoi sforzi sono stati ritenuti francamente da lui e 
francamente sono stati ricevuti da molti Americani. Il modo di 
Jaqua, una pubblicazione di affari, offerta alla relativa prima pagina
il hymn, "Thanksgiving dell'uomo," in che creano ringraziato "il dio 
degli uomini di affari" per "i miei clienti e per l'potenza servirli 
fedelmente."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Πρόεδρος Calvin Coolidge συνέλαβε το πνεύμα της
δεκαετίας του '20 όταν ανήγγειλε σε μια ομιλία ενώπιον της 
κοινωνίας των αμερικανικών επεξεργαστών εφημερίδων ότι "η 
προϊστάμενος επιχείρηση των αμερικανικών ανθρώπων είναι 
επιχείρηση." Ο αφορισμός του Coolidge αποκάλυψε την 
κεντρικότητα του εμπορίου στο έθνος και του πολιτισμού του στη 
δεκαετία του '20, ακόμη και ενώ έκρυψε μερικών από τις να 
στρέψει πολιτιστικές αλλαγές που απαιτήθηκαν για να προσαρμόσουν 
έναν εμπορικό πολιτισμό. Ένας ακόμα πιό ισχυρός 
πολιτικός αρθρογράφος για την όψη ότι η επιχείρηση και η 
πνευματικότητα ήταν συμβατές ήταν Bruce Barton. Ο γιος
ενός εκκλησιαστικού υπουργού, Barton μιας από τις μεγαλύτερες 
και πιό γνωστές διαφημιστικές αντιπροσωπείες του έθνους. Η 
μέγιστη φήμη του Barton, εντούτοις, προήλθε από το με 
εμπορική επιτυχία βιβλίο που δημοσίευσε το 1925, το άτομο που 
κανένα δεν ξέρει, στο οποίο επεξεργάστηκε ένα νέο όραμα 
Χριστού και του χριστιανισμού που δεν ήταν απλά συμβατό με, αλλά
οργανικά σύνδεσε με, οι επιθετικές προσπάθειες του 
προσανατολισμένου στις επιχειρήσεις Barton της δεκαετίας του '20
να συγχωνευθεί η επιχείρηση και ο χριστιανισμός μπορούν να φανούν
κωμικές προς το τέλος του 20ού αιώνα, αλλά οι ασκήσεις του 
έγιναν αισθητές ειλικρινά από τον και παραλήφθηκαν ειλικρινά 
από πολλούς Αμερικανούς. Ο Jaqua τρόπος, μια 
επιχειρησιακή δημοσίευση, πρόσφερε στην πρώτη σελίδα του τον 
ύμνο, "μια ανθρώπινη ημέρα των ευχαριστιών," που ο συντάκτης 
ευχαρίστησε το "Θεό των επιχειρησιακών ατόμων" για "τους πελάτες 
μου και για τη δύναμη να εξυπηρετήσουν πιστά."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presidente Calvin Coolidge capturó el alcohol de 
los años 20 en que él anunció en un discurso antes de la sociedad 
de los redactores americanos que "el principal negocio de la gente 
americana es negocio." El aphorism de Coolidge reveló el 
centrality del comercio a la nación y de su cultura en los años 20, 
incluso mientras que encubrió algunos de los cambios culturales 
wrenching requeridos para acomodar una civilización comercial. 
Un publicista aún más poderoso para la visión que el negocio 
y la espiritualidad eran compatibles era Bruce Barton. El hijo 
de un ministro congregational, Barton cofounded una de las agencias 
más grandes y más conocidas de la nación de publicidad. La 
fama más grande de Barton, sin embargo, vino del libro 
mejor-vendedor que él publicó en 1925, el hombre que nadie conoce, 
en las cuales él hizo una nueva visión a mano de Cristo y del 
cristianismo con la cual no era simplemente compatible, pero que 
conectó orgánico con, los esfuerzos agresivos del Barton comercial 
de los años 20 de combinar negocio y cristianismo pueden parecerse 
cómicos en el último vigésimo siglo, pero sus esfuerzos eran 
sentidos sinceramente por él y recibidos sinceramente por muchos 
americanos. La manera de Jaqua, una publicación de negocio, 
ofrecida en su primera paginación el himno, "Thanksgiving de un 
hombre," en que son autor agradecido el "dios de los hombres de 
negocios" por "mis clientes y por la potencia de servirlos fielmente."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087317</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102856</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-mans-thanksgiving-a-hymn-to-the-god-of-business</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
