<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/67572651</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>67572651</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202684</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Coastal Weather Issues: Planning for a Hurricane</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Küstenwetter-Ausgaben: Planung für einen 
Hurrikan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Côtier Survivez à Aux Issues : 
Planification pour un ouragan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Edições Litorais Do Tempo: Planear para um 
furacão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Edizioni Litoranee Del Tempo: Progettando per
un uragano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παράκτια καιρικά ζητήματα: Προγραμματισμός για 
έναν τυφώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ediciones Costeras Del Tiempo: El planear 
para un huracán</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The unit is designed for seventh grade students who have been studying Earth and its atmosphere. In this sequence, students are faced with the realistic issue of personal and social decision-making when planning for hurricane strikes, which includes classification, tracking, and monitoring hurricanes, as well as planning for evacuations. The inquiry-based approach involves a WebQuest in which the learner will assume the role of an emergency management team member who must create a preparation plan for the community.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Maßeinheit ist für 7. Gradkursteilnehmer 
konzipiert, die Masse und seine Atmosphäre studiert haben. In 
dieser Reihenfolge werden Kursteilnehmer mit der realistischen Ausgabe
der persönlichen und Sozialbeschlußfassung bei der Planung für 
Hurrikanschläge, die Klassifikation einschließt und aufspürt, und 
Hurrikane überwacht, sowie die Planung für Evakuierungen 
gegenübergestellt. Die Anfrage-gegründete Annäherung bezieht 
ein WebQuest mit ein, in dem der Anfänger die Rolle eines 
Dringlichkeitsmanagement-Teambauteiles annimmt, das einen Vorbereitung
Plan für die Gemeinschaft erstellen muß.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'unité est conçue pour les septièmes 
étudiants de catégorie qui avaient étudié la terre et son 
atmosphère. Dans cet ordre, des étudiants sont confrontés à 
la question réaliste de la prise de décision personnelle et sociale 
en projetant pour des grèves d'ouragan, qui inclut la classification,
dépistant, et surveillant des ouragans, aussi bien que la 
planification pour des évacuations. L'approche enquête-basée 
implique un WebQuest dans lequel l'étudiant assumera le rôle d'un 
membre d'équipe de gestion de secours qui doit créer un plan de 
préparation pour la communauté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A unidade é projetada para os sétimos estudantes 
da classe que têm estudado a terra e a sua atmosfera. Nesta 
seqüência, os estudantes são enfrentados com a introdução 
realística da tomada de decisão pessoal e social ao planear para 
batidas do furacão, que inclui a classificação, seguindo, e 
monitorando furacões, as.well.as planear para evacuações. A 
aproximação inquérito-baseada envolve um WebQuest em que o learner 
suporá o papel de um membro da equipe da gerência da emergência que
deva criar uma planta da preparação para a comunidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'unità è progettata per i settimi allievi del 
grado che stanno studiando la terra ed il relativo atmosfera. In
questa sequenza, gli allievi sono affrontati all'emissione realistica 
di risoluzione personale e sociale quando progetta per i colpi di 
uragano, che include la classificazione, rintracciando e controllando 
gli uragani, così come la progettazione per gli evacuamenti. Il
metodo inchiesta-basato coinvolge un WebQuest in cui il principiante 
ammetterà il ruolo di un membro della squadra della gestione di 
emergenza che deve creare un programma della preparazione per la 
Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μονάδα σχεδιάζεται για τους έβδομους σπουδαστές 
βαθμού που έχουν μελετήσει τη γη και την ατμόσφαιρά του. Σε
αυτήν την ακολουθία, την οι σπουδαστές βρίσκονται αντιμέτωποι με 
το ρεαλιστικό ζήτημα της προσωπικής και κοινωνικής λήψης 
αποφάσεων κατά προγραμματισμό για τις απεργίες τυφώνα, η οποία 
περιλαμβάνει την ταξινόμηση, που ακολουθεί, και τυφώνες ελέγχου, 
καθώς επίσης και προγραμματισμός για τις εκκενώσεις. Η 
έρευνα-βασισμένη στο προσέγγιση περιλαμβάνει ένα WebQuest στο 
οποίο ο αρχάριος θα υποθέσει το ρόλο ενός μέλους διοικητικών 
ομάδων έκτακτης ανάγκης που πρέπει να δημιουργήσει ένα σχέδιο 
προετοιμασιών για την κοινότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La unidad se diseña para los séptimos estudiantes
del grado que han estado estudiando la tierra y su atmósfera. 
En esta secuencia, hacen frente a los estudiantes con la 
aplicación realista la toma de decisión personal y social al planear
para las huelgas del huracán, que incluye la clasificación, 
siguiendo, y vigilando huracanes, así como planear para las 
evacuaciones. El acercamiento pregunta-basado implica un 
WebQuest en el cual el principiante asuma el papel de un miembro del 
equipo de la gerencia de la emergencia que deba crear un plan de la 
preparación para la comunidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KAREN GREENE
FN:KAREN GREENE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202684</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>67572651</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/coastal-weather-issues-planning-for-a-hurricane</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
