<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104323</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104323</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086951</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Hand of God" in the League of Nations: President Woodrow Wilson Presents the Treaty of Paris to the Senate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Hand des Gottes" in der Liga von Nationen: 
Präsident Woodrow Wilson Presents der Vertrag von Paris dem 
Senat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la main de Dieu" dans la ligue des nations : 
Le Président Woodrow Wilson Presents le Traité de Paris au 
sénat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a mão do deus" na liga das nações: 
Presidente Woodrow Wilson Apresentar-se o tratado de Paris ao 
senate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la mano del dio" nella lega delle nazioni: 
Presidente Woodrow Wilson Presents il Trattato di Parigi al 
senato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το χέρι του Θεού" στην ένωση των εθνών: 
Πρόεδρος Woodrow Wilson Presents η Συνθήκη του 
Παρισιού στη Σύγκλητο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la mano del dios" en la liga de naciones: 
Presidente Woodrow Wilson Presents el tratado de París al 
senado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The dispute over whether or not to ratify the Versailles Treaty and approve American participation in the newly formed League of Nations became one of the sharpest foreign policy debates in American history. The League of Nations was President Woodrow Wilson's great hope. He believed that the international organization would mitigate the failures of the Versailles Treaty while ensuring free trade, reducing reparations against Germany, extending self-determination beyond Europe, and punishing aggressor nations. On July 10, 1919, the president presented the 264-page Treaty of Paris to the U.S. Senate for ratification, including the controversial Article 10. Speaking in the style of an evangelical sermon, Wilson presented his case to Congress in this address. But the League faced bitter opposition and stirred nationwide debate. Warren G. Harding's victory in the 1920 presidential election ended the debate and closed the door on American participation in the League of Nations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Debatteüberschuß, ob oder, den Versailles 
Vertrag nicht zu bestätigen und amerikanische Teilnahme an der eben 
gebildeten Liga von Nationen zu genehmigen eine der schärfsten 
Debatten der fremden Politik in der amerikanischen Geschichte wurden. 
Die Liga von Nationen war Präsident Woodrow Wilson große 
Hoffnung. Er glaubte, daß die internationale Organisation die 
Ausfälle des Versailles Vertrags beim Sicherstellen des Freihandels, 
Verringern von von Reparationen gegen Deutschland, Ausdehnen von von 
Self-determination über Europa hinaus und Bestrafen von von 
Angreifernationen abschwächen würde. An Juli 10, 1919, stellte
der Präsident den Vertrag 264-page von Paris dem VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Senat für Bestätigung, einschließlich den umstrittenen Artikel 10 
dar. Sprechend in der Art einer evangelischen Predigt, stellte 
Wilson seinen Fall Kongreß in dieser Adresse dar. Aber die Liga
gegenübergestellte bittere Opposition und die gerührte allgemein 
Debatte. Warren G. Hardings Sieg in der Präsidentenwahl 1920 
beendete die Debatte und schloß die Tür auf amerikanischer Teilnahme
an der Liga von Nationen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'excédent de conflit si ne pas ratifier le 
Traité de Versailles et ne pas approuver la participation américaine
à la ligue nouvellement formée des nations sont devenues l'une des 
discussions les plus pointues de politique étrangère dans l'histoire
américaine. La ligue des nations était grand espoir du 
Président Woodrow Wilson. Il a cru que l'organisation 
internationale atténuerait les pannes du Traité de Versailles tout 
en assurant le libre échange, réduisant des réparations contre 
l'Allemagne, étendant art de l'auto-portrait-determination au delà de l'Europe, 
et punissant des nations d'agresseur. 10 juillet 1919, le 
président a présenté le Traité 264-page de Paris au sénat des 
ETATS-UNIS pour la ratification, y compris l'article controversé 10. 
Parlant dans le modèle d'un sermon évangélique, Wilson a 
présenté son cas au congrès dans cette adresse. Mais 
l'opposition amère faite face par ligue et la discussion dans tout le
pays remuée. La victoire de Warren G. Harding's dans 
l'élection 1920 présidentielle a terminé la discussion et a fermé 
la porte sur la participation américaine à la ligue des nations.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O excesso da disputa se ou não ratificar o 
tratado de Versalhes e não aprovar a participação americana na liga
recentemente dada forma das nações se transformaram um dos debates 
os mais afiados da política extrangeira no history americano. A
liga das nações era esperança grande do presidente Woodrow Wilson. 
Acreditou que a organização internacional mitigate as falhas 
do tratado de Versalhes ao assegurar o comércio livre, ao reduzir 
reparations de encontro a Germany, ao estender o self-determination 
além de Europa, e ao punir nações do agressor. Julho em 10, 
1919, o presidente apresentou o tratado 264-page de Paris ao senate de
ESTADOS UNIDOS para o ratification, including o artigo controverso 10.
Falando no estilo de um sermon evangelical, Wilson apresentou 
seu caso ao congress neste endereço. Mas a oposição amarga 
enfrentada liga e o debate de âmbito nacional agitado. A 
vitória de Warren G. Harding na eleição 1920 presidencial terminou 
o debate e fechou a porta na participação americana na liga das 
nações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'eccedenza di disputa se o non ratificare il 
Trattato de Versailles e non approvare la partecipazione americana 
alla lega recentemente formata delle nazioni si sono transformati in 
in uno dei dibattiti più taglienti di politica straniera nella storia
americana. La lega delle nazioni era speranza grande del 
presidente Woodrow Wilson. Ha creduto che l'organizzazione 
internazionale attenuasse i guasti del Trattato de Versailles mentre 
accertasse il libero scambio, riducendo i reparations contro la 
Germania, estendendo il self-determination oltre Europa e punendo le 
nazioni del aggressor. Il 10 luglio 1919, il presidente ha 
presentato il Trattato 264-page di Parigi al senato degli STATI UNITI 
per la ratifica, compreso l'articolo discutibile 10. Parlando 
nello stile di un sermon evangelical, Wilson ha presentato il suo caso
al congresso in questo indirizzo. Ma l'opposizione amara 
affrontata lega ed il dibattito nazionale mescolato. La vittoria
di Warren G. Harding nell'elezione presidenziale 1920 hanno concluso 
il dibattito e chiuso il portello su partecipazione americana alla
lega delle nazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαφωνία πέρα από εαν πρέπει να επικυρωθεί η 
Συνθήκη των Βερσαλλιών και να εγκριθεί η αμερικανική συμμετοχή 
στην πρόσφατα διαμορφωμένη ένωση των εθνών έγινε μια από τις 
αιχμηρότερες συζητήσεις εξωτερικής πολιτικής στην αμερικανική 
ιστορία. Η ένωση των εθνών ήταν μεγάλη ελπίδα Προέδρου 
Woodrow Wilson's. Θεώρησε ότι ο διεθνής οργανισμός θα 
μετρίαζε τις αποτυχίες της Συνθήκης των Βερσαλλιών εξασφαλίζοντας
ελευθεροποίηση των συναλλαγών, μειώνοντας τις επιδιορθώσεις 
ενάντια στη Γερμανία, επεκτείνοντας την αυτοδιάθεση πέρα από την
Ευρώπη, και τιμωρώντας τα έθνη επιτιθέμενων. Στις 10 
Ιουλίου ..1919, ο Πρόεδρος παρουσίασε τη Συνθήκη 264-σελίδων 
του Παρισιού στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ Σύγκλητο για την επικύρωση, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του αμφισβητούμενου άρθρου 10. μιλώντας στο 
ύφος ενός εβαγγελικού κηρύγματος, Wilson παρουσίασε την 
περίπτωσή του στο συνέδριο σε αυτήν την διεύθυνση. Αλλά η 
ένωση αντιμετώπισε την πικρή αντίθεση και ανακάτωσε τη σε εθνικό
επίπεδο συζήτηση. Warren Γ. Harding's η νίκη στην 
προεδρική εκλογή του 1920 τελείωσε τη συζήτηση και έκλεισε την
πόρτα στην αμερικανική συμμετοχή στην ένωση των εθνών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El excedente del conflicto si o no ratificar el 
tratado de Versalles y no aprobar la participación americana en la 
liga nuevamente formada de naciones se convirtieron en uno de los 
discusiones más sostenidos de la política no nativa de la historia 
americana. La liga de naciones era gran esperanza de presidente 
Woodrow Wilson. Él creyó que la organización internacional 
atenuaría los incidentes del tratado de Versalles mientras que 
aseguraba libre cambio, reduce reparaciones contra Alemania, ampliando
la autodeterminación más allá de Europa, y castigando naciones del 
agresor. 10 de julio de 1919, el presidente presentó el 
tratado 264-page de París al senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS para la 
ratificación, incluyendo el artículo polémico 10. Hablando en
el estilo de un sermón evangélico, Wilson presentó su caso al 
congreso en este direccionamiento. Pero la oposición amarga 
hecha frente liga y el discusión a nivel nacional revuelto. La 
victoria de Warren G. Harding en la elección presidencial 1920 
terminó el discusión y cerró la puerta en la participación 
americana en la liga de naciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086951</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104323</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-hand-of-god-in-the-league-of-nations-president-woodrow-wilson-presents-the-treaty-of-paris-to-the-senate</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
