<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105367</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105367</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206221</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Land Use History of North America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Flächennutzung-Geschichte von Nordamerika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire d'utilisation de la terre de l'Amérique 
du nord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History do uso de terra de America do Norte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia di utilizzazione delle terre dell'America 
del Nord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία χρήσης εδάφους της Βόρειας Αμερικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia de la utilización del suelo de 
Norteamérica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines how we have used land since the 1700s and how the land has changed. Topics include population settlement and farmland, urban sprawl and soil resources, flora species, urbanization in the Baltimore-Washington corridor, landcover changes in the Great Lakes region, vegetation along the upper Mississippi River, biodiversity in the Yellowstone ecosystem, and landscape changes in the Southwest.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft, wie wir Land seit dem 1700s benutzt 
haben und wie das Land geändert hat. Themen schließen 
Bevölkerung Regelung ein und Ackerland, städtische Ausbreitung und 
Bodenbetriebsmittel, Florasorte, Verfeinerung im Baltimore-Washington 
Flur, landcover ändert in der Great Lakes Region, Vegetation entlang 
dem oberen Mississippi Fluß, Biodiversity im Yellowstone Oekosystem, 
und Landschaft ändert im Südwesten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine comment nous avons utilisé la terre 
depuis le 1700s et comment la terre a changé. Les sujets 
incluent le règlement de population et les champs, la position 
abandonnée urbaine et les ressources de sol, les espèces de 
flore, urbanisation dans le couloir de Baltimore-Washington, landcover
changent dans la région de Great Lakes, la végétation le long du 
fleuve supérieur du Mississippi, biodiversité dans l'écosystème de
Yellowstone, et l'horizontal change dans le sud-ouest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina como nós usamos a terra desde o 1700s e 
como a terra mudou. Os tópicos incluem o estabelecimento da 
população e a terra, o alastro urbano e os recursos do solo, 
espécie do flora, urbanization no corredor de Baltimore-Washington, 
landcover mudam na região de Great Lakes, vegetação ao longo do rio
superior de Mississippi, biodiversity no ecosystem de Yellowstone, e a
paisagem muda no sudoeste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina come abbiamo usato la terra dal 1700s e 
come la terra è cambiato. I soggetti includono lo stabilimento 
della popolazione ed il terreno coltivabile, l'espansione urbana e le 
risorse del terreno, la specie della flora, l'urbanizzazione nel 
corridoio deBaltimora-Washington, landcover cambia nella regione dei 
Great Lakes, la vegetazione lungo il fiume superiore del Mississippi, 
biodiversity nell'ecosistema di Yellowstone ed il paesaggio cambia nel
sud-ovest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει πώς έχουμε χρησιμοποιήσει το έδαφος από το 
1700s και πώς το έδαφος έχει αλλάξει. Τα θέματα 
περιλαμβάνουν στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς τακτοποίησης και 
καλλιεργήσιμου εδάφους πληθυσμών, αστικής κατάκλισης και 
χώματος, είδη χλωρίδας, αστικοποίηση στο Βαλτιμόρη-Ουάσιγκτον 
διάδρομο, landcover αλλαγές στη μεγάλη περιοχή λιμνών, τη 
βλάστηση κατά μήκος του ανώτερου ποταμού του Μισισιπή, τη 
βιοποικιλότητα στο οικοσύστημα Yellowstone, και τις αλλαγές 
τοπίων στο νοτιοδυτικό σημείο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina cómo hemos utilizado la pista desde el 
1700s y cómo la pista ha cambiado. Los asuntos incluyen el 
establecimiento de la población y las tierras de labrantío, la 
urbanización irregular y los recursos del suelo, especie de la flora,
urbanización en el pasillo de Baltimore-Washington, landcover cambian
en la región de Great Lakes, vegetación a lo largo del río superior
de Mississippi, biodiversidad en el ecosistema de Yellowstone, y el 
paisaje cambia en el sudoeste.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206221</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105367</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/land-use-history-of-north-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
