<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105468</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105468</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087002</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Negro in America Today": South African Novelist Alan Paton Dissects the Racial Situation in the South in the Year of  Brown  v.  Board of Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Schwarze in Amerika heute": 
Südafrikanischer Novelist Alan Paton zergliedert die rassische 
Situation im Süden im Jahr des braunen v. Brettes der Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le nègre en Amérique aujourd'hui" : Le 
romancier africain du sud Alan Paton dissèque la situation
raciale dans les Sud par année de panneau brun de v. 
d'éducation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o negro em América hoje": O novelist Alan 
Paton do africano sul dissects a situação racial no sul no ano da 
placa marrom do v. da instrução</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il negro in America oggi": Il Romanziere 
sudafricano Alan Paton disseca la situazione razziale nel sud durante 
l'anno del Bordo marrone del v. di formazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο νέγρος στην Αμερική σήμερα": Νοτιοαφρικανικός
μυθιστοριογράφος Alan Paton Dissects η φυλετική κατάσταση 
στο νότο στο έτος Brown V. Board της εκπαίδευσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el negro en América hoy": El novelista 
surafricano Alan Paton diseca la situación racial en el sur en el 
año de la tarjeta marrón del v. de la educación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Alan Paton's first novel,  Cry, the Beloved Country  (1948), communicated the tragic dimensions of South Africa's system of apartheid to a world audience. In 1954, Paton was asked by  Collier's  magazine to observe and interview Americans about this country's system of racial segregation. In the first of two articles, Paton interviewed students, government officials, NAACP members, church leaders, and soldiers in Washington, D.C., and in the Deep South around the time that the Supreme Court, in the landmark case  Brown  v.  Board of Education of Topeka, Kansas,  ruled segregated "separate but equal" public schools unconstitutional. Like earlier visitors from abroad--such as St. Jean de Crevecoeur, Alexis de Tocqueville, and Gunnar Myrdal--Paton offered a uniquely comparative perspective as he searched for answers on the current state of segregation and future prospects for the integration of American institutions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alan Patons erster Roman, Schrei, geliebte Country
(1948), teilte die tragischen Maße von System Südafrikas von 
Apartheid zu einem Weltpublikum mit. 1954 wurde Paton durch 
Zeitschrift Colliers gebeten, Amerikaner über System dieses Landes 
der rassischen Abtrennung zu beobachten und zu interviewen. Im 
ersten von zwei Artikeln, interviewte Paton Kursteilnehmer, 
Regierungsbeamte, NAACP Bauteile, Kircheführer und Soldaten in 
Washington, Gleichstrom und im tiefen Süden um die Zeit, die das 
Höchste Gericht, im Brett des Grenzsteinkasten Braun-V. der 
Ausbildung von Topeka, Kansas trennen, angeordnet getrennt ", aber die
gleichen" allgemeinen verfassungswidrigen Schulen. Wie frühere 
Besucher aus dem Ausland -- wie Str. Jean de Crevecoeur, Alexis de 
Tocqueville und Gunnar Myrdal -- Paton bot eine eindeutig 
vergleichbare Perspektive an, während er nach Antworten auf der 
gegenwärtigen Lage der Abtrennung- und Zukunftaussichten für die 
Integration der amerikanischen Anstalten suchte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le premier roman d'Alan Paton, cri, 
Country aimé (1948), a communiqué les dimensions tragiques du 
système du sud de l'Afrique de la ségrégation à une 
assistance du monde. En 1954, Paton a été invité par le 
magazine de Collier à observer et interviewer des Américains au 
sujet du système de ce pays de la ségrégation raciale. Dans 
le premier de deux articles, Paton a interviewé des étudiants, des 
fonctionnaires de gouvernement, des membres de NAACP, des amorces 
d'église, et des soldats à Washington, C.C, et dans les Sud
profonds autour du temps que la cour suprême, dans le conseil du brun
v. de caisse de borne limite de l'éducation de Topeka, le Kansas, 
régné isolé "séparent mais autour" des écoles d'Etat égales 
inconstitutionnelles. Comme de premiers visiteurs de l'étranger
-- comme la rue Jean de Crevecoeur, Alexis de Tocqueville, et Gunnar 
Myrdal -- Paton a offert une perspective seulement comparative pendant
qu'il recherchait des réponses sur l'état actuel des perspectives de
ségrégation et de futur pour l'intégration des établissements 
américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A primeira novela de Alan Paton, grito, País 
beloved (1948), comunicou as dimensões trágicas do sistema de 
África do Sul do apartheid a uma audiência do mundo. Em 1954, 
Paton foi pedido pelo compartimento de Collier para observar e 
entrevistar americanos sobre o sistema deste país do segregation 
racial. No primeiro de dois artigos, Paton entrevistou 
estudantes, oficiais de governo, membros de NAACP, líderes da igreja,
e soldados em Washington, C.C., e no sul profundo em torno do tempo 
que a corte suprema, na placa do marrom v. da caixa do marco da 
instrução de Topeka, Kansas, governado segregado "separa mas" das 
escolas públicas iguais unconstitutional. Como uns visitantes 
mais adiantados no exterior -- como St. de Jean de Crevecoeur, de 
Alexis de Tocqueville, e de Gunnar Myrdal -- Paton ofereceu um 
perspective excepcionalmente comparativo enquanto procurarou por 
respostas no estado atual de prospetos do segregation e do futuro para
a integração de instituições americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il primo romanzo di Alan Paton, Grida, 
il Country caro (1948), ha comunicato le dimensioni tragiche del 
sistema della Sudafrica di segregazione ad un pubblico del mondo. 
In 1954, Paton è stato chiesto dallo scomparto del Collier di 
osservare ed intervistare gli Americani circa il sistema di questo 
paese della segregazione razziale. Nel primo di due articoli, 
Paton ha intervistato gli allievi, i funzionari di governo, i membri 
di NAACP, i capi della chiesa ed i soldati in Washington, DC e 
nel sud profondo intorno al tempo che la Corte suprema, nel 
Bordo di colore marrone v. della cassa del limite di formazione 
di Topeka, Kansas, regolato segregato "separa ma" alle "public school"
uguali inconstituzionali. Come gli ospiti più in anticipo 
dall'estero -- quale la st Jean de Crevecoeur, Alexis de Tocqueville e
Gunnar Myrdal -- Paton ha offerto una prospettiva unicamente 
comparativa mentre ha cercato le risposte sulla corrente 
dichiara dei prospetti di futuro e di segregazione per 
l'integrazione delle istituzioni americane.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρώτο μυθιστόρημα του Alan Paton's, κραυγή, η 
αγαπημένη χώρα (1948), διαβίβασε τις τραγικές διαστάσεις του 
συστήματος της Νότιας Αφρικής του απαρτχάιντ σε ένα παγκόσμιο 
ακροατήριο. Το 1954, Paton κλήθηκε από το περιοδικό 
του ανθρακωρύχου να παρατηρήσει και να πάρει συνέντευξη από 
Αμερικανούς για το σύστημα αυτής της χώρας του φυλετικού 
διαχωρισμού. Στο πρώτο δύο άρθρων, Paton πήρε 
συνέντευξη από τους σπουδαστές, τους κυβερνητικούς ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους, τα μέλη NAACP, τους ηγέτες εκκλησιών, και τους 
στρατιώτες στην Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ, και στο βαθύ νότο 
γύρω από το χρόνο ότι το ανώτατο δικαστήριο, στην περίπτωση 
Brown V. Board ορόσημων εκπαίδευσης Topeka, Κάνσας, 
διέταξε τα διαχωρισμένα "χωριστά αλλά ίσα" δημόσια σχολεία 
αντισυνταγματικά. Όπως τους πιό πρώτους επισκέπτες από στο
εξωτερικό -- όπως το ST Jean δε Crevecoeur, Αλέξης δε 
Tocqueville, και Gunnar Myrdal -- Paton πρόσφερε μια 
μεμονωμένα συγκριτική προοπτική όπως έψαξε για τις απαντήσεις 
στην παρούσα κατάσταση του διαχωρισμού και τις μελλοντικές 
προοπτικές για την ολοκλήρωση των αμερικανικών οργάνων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La primera novela de Alan Paton, grito, Country 
querido (1948), comunicó las dimensiones trágicas del sistema de 
Suráfrica del apartheid a una audiencia del mundo. En 1954, 
Paton fue pedido por el compartimiento de Collier observar y 
entrevistarse con a americanos sobre el sistema de este país de la 
segregación racial. En el primer de dos artículos, Paton se 
entrevistó con a estudiantes, a oficiales del gobierno, a miembros de
NAACP, a arranques de cinta de la iglesia, y a soldados en Washington,
C.C., y en el sur profundo alrededor del tiempo que el Tribunal 
Supremo, en la tarjeta del marrón v. de la caja de la señal de la 
educación de Topeka, Kansas, gobernado segregado "separa solamente" 
de las escuelas públicas iguales inconstitucionales. Como 
visitantes anteriores del extranjero -- por ejemplo St. Jean de 
Crevecoeur, Alexis de Tocqueville, y Gunnar Myrdal -- Paton ofreció 
una perspectiva únicamente comparativa mientras que él buscó para 
respuestas en el estado actual de las perspectivas de la segregación 
y del futuro de la integración de instituciones americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087002</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105468</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-negro-in-america-today-south-african-novelist-alan-paton-dissects-the-racial-situation-in-the-south-in-the-year-of-brown-v-board-of-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
