<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108111</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108111</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206777</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lizards and Snakes Alive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eidechsen und Schlangen lebendig</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lézards et serpents vivants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lagartos e serpentes vivos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lucertole e serpenti vivi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαύρες και φίδια ζωντανές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lagartos y serpientes vivos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the world of squamates. Learn how chameleons and iguanas rely on vision while other lizards, such as geckos, depend on smell (using their tongues). See boas, mambas, cobras, geckos, skinks, and other squamates. Watch an anaconda slither and a chameleon catch prey with its tongue. Hear rattlesnakes and a barking gecko.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht die Welt von squamates. Erlernen 
Sie, wie Chamäleone und Leguane auf Anblick beruhen, während andere 
Eidechsen, wie Geckos, vom Geruch abhängen (ihre Zungen verwendend). 
Sehen Sie Boas, mambas, Kobren, Geckos, skinks und andere 
squamates. Überwachen Sie ein anaconda slither und ein 
Chamäleonverriegelung Opfer mit seiner Zunge. Hören Sie 
Klapperschlangen und einen Abstreifen Gecko.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore le monde des squamates. Apprenez 
comment les caméléons et les iguanes se fondent sur la vision tandis
que d'autres lézards, tels que des geckos, dépendent de l'odeur (à 
l'aide de leurs langues). Voir des boas, des mambas, des cobras,
des geckos, des skinks, et d'autres squamates. Observez un 
slither d'anaconda et une proie de crochet de caméléon avec sa 
langue. Entendez les serpents à sonnettes et un gecko 
d'écorcement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora o mundo dos squamates. Aprenda como 
os chameleons e os iguanas confiam na visão quando outros lagartos, 
tais como geckos, dependerem do cheiro (que usa suas lingüetas). 
Veja boas, mambas, cobras, geckos, skinks, e outros squamates. 
Preste atenção a um slither do anaconda e a uma rapina do 
prendedor do chameleon com sua lingüeta. Ouça cascavéis e um 
gecko barking.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora il mondo degli squamates. Impari 
come i chameleons ed i iguanas contano sulla visione mentre altre 
lucertole, quali i geckos, dipendono dall'odore (che per mezzo delle 
loro linguette). Veda i boa, i mambas, i cobras, i geckos, gli 
skinks ed altri squamates. Guardi uno slither di anaconda e una 
preda del fermo del chameleon con la relativa linguetta. Senta i
rattlesnakes e un gecko di scortecciamento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξερευνά τον κόσμο των squamates. Μάθετε πώς 
οι χαμαιλέοντες και τα iguanas στηρίζονται στο όραμα ενώ άλλες
σαύρες, όπως τα geckos, εξαρτώνται από τη μυρωδιά (που 
χρησιμοποιεί τις γλώσσες τους). Δείτε boas, τα 
mambas, τα cobras, τα geckos, skinks, και άλλα 
squamates. Προσέξτε ένα anaconda slither και ένα 
θήραμα σύλληψης χαμαιλεόντων με τη γλώσσα του. Ακούστε τους
κροταλίες και ένα gecko αποφλοίωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora el mundo de squamates. Aprenda cómo
los camaleones y los iguanas confían en la visión mientras que otros
lagartos, tales como geckos, dependen del olor (que usa sus 
lengüetas). Vea las boas, los mambas, las cobras, los geckos, 
los skinks, y otros squamates. Mire un slither del anaconda y 
una presa del retén del camaleón con su lengüeta. Oiga 
serpientes de cascabel y un gecko el raspar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206777</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108111</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lizards-and-snakes-alive</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
