<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103675</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103675</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207177</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Prosperity and Thrift: The Coolidge Era and the Consumer Economy, 1921-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wohlstand und Sparsamkeit: Die Coolidge Ära 
und die Verbraucher-Wirtschaft, 1921-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Prospérité et épargne : L'ère de Coolidge
et l'économie du consommateur, 1921-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Prosperidade e thrift: A era de Coolidge e a 
economia do consumidor, 1921-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prosperità e risparmio: L'era di Coolidge e 
l'economia del consumatore, 1921-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ευημερία και thrift: Η εποχή Coolidge και η 
καταναλωτική οικονομία, 1921-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Prosperidad y ahorro: La era y la economía 
del consumidor, 1921-1929 de Coolidge</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">documents the widespread prosperity of the Coolidge years, the nation's transition to a mass consumer economy, and the role of the government in this transition. The collection includes personal and institutional papers, books, pamphlets, legislative documents, trade journals selections, photographs, 5 short films, and 7 audio selections of Coolidge speeches. The collection is particularly strong in advertising and mass-marketing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">dokumentiert den weitverbreiteten Wohlstand der 
Coolidge Jahre, den Übergang der Nation zu einer 
Massenverbraucherwirtschaft und die Rolle der Regierung in diesem 
Übergang. Die Ansammlung schließt die persönlichen und 
Institutionspapiere, die Bücher, die Flugschriften, die 
gesetzgebenden Dokumente, die Handelsblattanwählungen, die 
Fotographien, 5 kurze Filme und 7 Audioanwählungen der Coolidge Reden
ein. Die Ansammlung ist im Bekanntmachen und im Masse-Marketing 
besonders stark.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">documente la prospérité répandue des années de 
Coolidge, la transition de la nation à une économie de masse du 
consommateur, et le rôle du gouvernement dans cette transition. 
La collection inclut les articles personnels et institutionnels,
les livres, les brochures, les documents législatifs, les sélections
de journaux commerciales, les photographies, 5 films courts, et 7 
sélections sonores des discours de Coolidge. La collection est 
particulièrement forte dans la publicité et le masse-marketing.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">documenta a prosperidade difundida dos anos de 
Coolidge, a transição da nação a uma economia maciça do 
consumidor, e o papel do governo nesta transição. A coleção 
inclui papéis pessoais e institutional, livros, panfletos, originais 
legislativos, seleções de jornais de comércio, fotografias, 5 
películas curtas, e 7 seleções audio de discursos de Coolidge. 
A coleção é particularmente forte em anunciar e em 
massa-mass-marketing.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">documenta la prosperità diffusa degli anni di 
Coolidge, la transizione della nazione ad un'economia totale del 
consumatore ed il ruolo del governo in questa transizione. 
L'accumulazione include le carte personali ed istituzionali, i 
libri, gli opuscoli, i documenti legislativi, le selezioni di giornali
commerciali, le fotografie, 5 pellicole corte e 7 selezioni audio dei 
discorsi di Coolidge. L'accumulazione è particolarmente forte 
nella pubblicità e nell'massa-introduzione sul mercato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τεκμηριώνει τη διαδεδομένη ευημερία των ετών 
Coolidge, τη μετάβαση του έθνους σε μια οικονομία μαζικών 
καταναλωτών, και το ρόλο της κυβέρνησης σε αυτήν την μετάβαση. 
Η συλλογή περιλαμβάνει τα προσωπικά και θεσμικά έγγραφα, τα
βιβλία, τα τεύχη, τα νομοθετικά έγγραφα, τις επιλογές εμπορικών 
περιοδικών, φωτογραφίες, 5 μικρού μήκους ταινίες, και 7 ηχητικές
επιλογές των ομιλιών Coolidge. Η συλλογή είναι ιδιαίτερα
ισχυρή στη διαφήμιση και το μάζα-μάρκετινγκ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">documenta la prosperidad extensa de los años de 
Coolidge, la transición de la nación a una economía total del 
consumidor, y el papel del gobierno en esta transición. La 
colección incluye los papeles personales e institucionales, los 
libros, los folletos, los documentos legislativos, las selecciones de 
diarios comerciales, las fotografías, 5 películas cortas, y 7 
selecciones audio de los discursos de Coolidge. La colección es
determinado fuerte en la publicidad y la masa-comercializacio'n.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207177</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103675</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/prosperity-and-thrift-the-coolidge-era-and-the-consumer-economy-1921-1929</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
