<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105512</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105512</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087192</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Had a Habit of Being Vocal:" James Justen Describes UAW Local Activism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir hatten eine Gewohnheit des Seins Vocal:" 
James Justen Beschreibt Uaw Einheimisch-Aktivismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous avons eu une habitude d'être vocaux :" 
James Justen Décrit l'Activisme de Gens du pays de 
T.u.a.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós tivemos um hábito de ser vocais:" 
James Justen Descreve O Activism Do Local do Uaw</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"abbiamo avuti un'abitudine di essere vocali:" 
James Justen Descrive Il Activism Del Local del Uaw</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είχαμε μια συνήθεια της ύπαρξης φωνητικοί:" James Justen Describes UAW Local ακτιβισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"teníamos un hábito de ser vocales:" James
Justen Describe Activismo Del Local del Uaw</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Jim Justen was active union member at the American Motor Company plant in Kenosha, Wisconsin, which later became a Chrysler plant. An active member and leader of the United Auto Workers Local 72, Justen recalled that his local was a "rebel" local, more willing than the International to strike when they found working conditions or contract negotiations unacceptable. During the 1960's and early 1970's, the priorities of many locals, especially in the auto industry, differed from those of the international leadership. While international unions were more interested in wages and job security, many locals were more outspoken about health and safety issues on the job. As Justen recalled, such rank and file militancy often had a more direct and immediate impact on job or plant-specific conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jim Justen war aktives Anschlußbauteil am 
American Motor Company Betrieb in Kenosha, Wisconsin, das später ein 
Chrysler Betrieb wurde. Ein aktives Bauteil und ein Führer des 
vereinigten Selbstarbeiter-Einheimischen 72, Justen riefen wieder auf,
daß sein Einheimischer ein "Aufrührer" Einheimischer war, bereiter 
als das international anzuschlagen, als sie die Arbeitsbedingungen 
oder Vertrag Vermittlungen nicht annehmbar fanden. Während der 
sechziger Jahre und der frühen siebziger Jahre unterschieden sich die
Prioritäten vieler Einheimischer, besonders in der Selbstindustrie, 
von denen der internationalen Führung. Während internationale 
Anschlüße an den Löhnen und an der Arbeitsplatzsicherheit 
interessierter waren, waren viele Einheimische über Gesundheit und 
Sicherheit Ausgaben auf dem Job freimütiger. Da wieder 
aufgerufenes Justen, solcher Truppe Militancy häufig eine direktere 
und sofortigere Auswirkung auf Job oder Betrieb-spezifische 
Bedingungen hatte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jim Justen était travailleur syndiqué actif à 
l'usine d'American Motor Company dans Kenosha, le Wisconsin, qui plus 
tard est devenu une usine de Chrysler. Un membre et une amorce 
actifs des gens du pays automatiques unis 72, Justen d'ouvriers se 
sont rappelés que ses gens du pays étaient des gens du pays de 
"rebelle", plus disposés qu'internationaux à frapper quand ils ont 
trouvé des conditions de travail ou des négociations contractuelles 
inacceptables. Pendant les années 60 et le début des années 
70, les priorités de beaucoup de gens du pays, particulièrement dans
l'industrie automatique, ont différé de ceux de la conduite 
internationale. Tandis que les syndicats internationaux étaient
plus intéressés par les salaires et la sécurité d'emploi, beaucoup
de gens du pays étaient plus francs au sujet des issues de salubrité
et de sûreté sur le travail. Car Justen rappelé, un tel 
militantisme de troupe a souvent eu un impact plus direct et plus 
immédiat sur le travail ou des conditions usine-spécifiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jim Justen era membro de união ativo na planta em
Kenosha, Wisconsin de Americano Motor Companhia, que se transformou 
mais tarde uma planta de Chrysler. Um membro e um líder ativos 
do auto local unido 72 dos trabalhadores, Justen recordaram que seu 
local era um local do "rebel", mais disposto do que internacional 
golpear quando encontraram as condições de funcionamento ou as 
negociações do contrato inaceitáveis. Durante os 1960's e os 
1970's adiantados, as prioridades de muitos locals, especial na auto 
indústria, diferiram daquelas da liderança internacional. 
Quando as uniões internacionais estavam mais interessadas nos 
salários e na segurança de trabalho, muitos locals eram mais 
outspoken sobre edições de saúde e de segurança no trabalho. 
Porque Justen recordado, tal militancy rank e da lima tiveram 
frequentemente um impacto mais direto e mais imediato no trabalho ou 
em circunstâncias planta-específicas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jim Justen era membro attivo del sindacato nella 
pianta in Kenosha, Wisconsin di American Motor Company, che più 
successivamente si è transformato in in una pianta della Chrysler. 
Un membro e un capo attivi del local automatico unito 72,
Justen degli operai hanno ricordato che il suo local era un local "del
ribelle", più disposto dell'internazionale a colpire quando 
hanno trovato le condizioni di lavoro o i negoziati per contratto 
inaccettabili. Durante gli anni 60 e l'inizio degli anni 70, le 
priorità di molti locals, particolarmente nell'industria automatica, 
hanno differito da da quelle della direzione internazionale. 
Mentre i sindacati internazionali erano più interessati negli 
stipendi e nella sicurezza dell'impiego, molti locals erano più 
franchi circa le edizioni di sanità e sicurezza sul lavoro. 
Poichè Justen ricordato, tale militanza della truppa ha 
avuto spesso un effetto più diretto e più immediato sul lavoro o 
sugli stati di plant-specifico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Jim Justen ήταν ενεργό μέλος ένωσης στις 
αμερικανικές εγκαταστάσεις επιχείρησης μηχανών σε Kenosha, 
Wisconsin, το οποίο έγινε αργότερα εγκαταστάσεις Chrysler. 
Ένα ενεργοί μέλος και ένας ηγέτης των ενωμένων αυτόματων 
εργαζομένων τοπικά 72, Justen υπενθύμισαν ότι τοπικός του 
ήταν "επαναστατικόσ" ένας τοπικός, προθυμότερος από διεθνής να 
χτυπήσει όταν βρήκαν τις συνθήκες εργασίας ή τις 
διαπραγματεύσεις συμβάσεων απαράδεκτες. Κατά τη διάρκεια 
της δεκαετίας του '60 και της πρόωρης δεκαετίας του '70, οι 
προτεραιότητες πολλών locals, ειδικά στην αυτόματη βιομηχανία,
διέφεραν από εκείνους της διεθνούς ηγεσίας. Ενώ οι 
διεθνείς ενώσεις ενδιαφέρθηκαν για τις αμοιβές και την ασφάλεια 
εργασίας, πολλά locals ήταν ειλικρινέστερα για τα ζητήματα 
υγείας και ασφάλειας σε εργασία. Σαν Justen που 
υπενθυμίστηκε, τέτοια μαχητικότητα μαζών άσκησε συχνά αμεσότερη
και άμεση επίδραση στην εργασία ή τους 
εγκατάσταση-συγκεκριμένους όρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jim Justen era miembro de unión activo en la 
planta en Kenosha, Wisconsin American Motor Company, que se convirtió
en más adelante una planta de Chrysler. Un miembro y un 
arranque de cinta activos del local auto unido 72, Justen de los 
trabajadores recordaron que su local era un local del "rebelde", más 
dispuesto que el internacional a pulso cuando encontraron las 
condiciones de trabajo o las negociaciones del contrato inaceptables. 
Durante los años 60 y los años 70 tempranos, las prioridades 
de muchos locals, especialmente en la industria auto, diferenciaron de
las de la dirección internacional. Mientras que las uniones 
internacionales estaban más interesadas en salarios y seguridad en el
empleo, muchos locals eran más abiertos sobre ediciones de salud y de
seguridad en el trabajo. Pues Justen recordado, tal militancia 
de la tropa tenía a menudo un impacto más directo y más inmediato 
en trabajo o condiciones planta-especi'ficas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087192</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105512</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-had-a-habit-of-being-vocal-james-justen-describes-uaw-local-activism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
