<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103176</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103176</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086769</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pure Personal Government: Roosevelt Goes Too Far in Packing the Court</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reine Persönliche Regierung: Roosevelt geht
zu, weit, wenn er das Gericht packt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gouvernement Personnel Pur : Roosevelt entre
trop loin en emballant la cour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Governo Pessoal Puro: Roosevelt vai 
demasiado distante em embalar a corte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Governo Personale Puro: Roosevelt va troppo 
lontano nell'imballaggio della corte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθαρή προσωπική κυβέρνηση: Το Roosevelt 
πηγαίνει πάρα πολύ μακριά στη συσκευασία του δικαστηρίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gobierno Personal Puro: Roosevelt entra 
demasiado lejos en la pila de discos de la corte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">President Franklin Roosevelt's 1937 attempt to expand the federal judiciary, known as his "Court-packing plan" by its many critics, met with ferocious opposition. Congressmen who had warily supported the New Deal now backed away, unnerved by the president's willingness to subvert the existing power structure. In the popular press, columns such as Dorothy Thompson's from the Washington  Star  reflected both popular disgust at Roosevelt's plan to increase the number of Supreme Court justices and FDR's continued popularity. Thompson's comparison of Roosevelt to Hitler seems ridiculous now, but others (like Father Charles Coughlin) made such comparisons regularly in 1937. Ironically, over the next four years FDR was able to fill seven vacancies on the Court, largely ending its opposition to the New Deal. By then, however, thanks in large part to public opposition to the Court-packing plan, he had lost the predictable majorities that had easily carried his bills through Congress during his first term.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Präsident Franklin Roosevelts 1937 Versuch, die 
Bundesjustizgewalt zu erweitern, bekannt als sein "Gericht-Verpackung 
Plan" von seinen vielen Kritikern, traf wilde Opposition. 
Kongreßabgeordnete, die warily das neue Abkommen jetzt 
unterstützt hatten, zogen weg, unnerved durch die Bereitwilligkeit 
des Präsidenten, die vorhandene Energie Struktur umzustürzen 
zurück. In der populären Presse reflektierten Spalten wie 
Dorothy Thompson vom Washington Stern beides populären Ekel am Plan 
Roosevelts, zum der Zahl von Gerichtgerechtigkeit und von anhaltender 
Popularität FDR zu erhöhen. Vergleich Thompsons von Roosevelt 
zu Hitler scheint jetzt lächerlich, aber andere (wie Vater Charles 
Coughlin) verglichen solche regelmäßig 1937. Ironisch über 
den folgenden vier Jahren konnte FDR, sieben freie Stellen auf dem 
Gericht zu füllen und groß beendete seine Opposition zum neuen 
Abkommen. Bis dahin jedoch plant Dank im großen Teil der 
allgemeinen Opposition der Gericht-Verpackung, er hatte verloren die 
vorhersagbaren Majoritäten, die leicht seine Rechnungen durch 
Kongreß während seiner ersten Zeitdauer getragen hatten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La tentative du Président Franklin Roosevelt's 
1937 d'augmenter l'ordre judiciaire fédéral, connu sous le nom de 
son "plan de Cour-emballage" par ses nombreux critiques, a rencontré 
l'opposition féroce. Les membres du Congrès qui avaient warily
supporté la nouvelle affaire maintenant ont soutenu loin, 
affaibli par la bonne volonté du président de renverser la
structure existante de puissance. Dans la presse populaire, les 
colonnes telles que Dorothy Thompson de Washington Tiennent le premier rôle 
ont reflété les deux le dégoût populaire au plan de Roosevelt pour
augmenter le nombre de justices de cour suprême et de popularité 
continue du FDR. La comparaison de Thompson de Roosevelt à 
Hitler semble ridicule maintenant, mais d'autres (comme père Charles 
Coughlin) ont fait de telles comparaisons régulièrement en 1937. 
Ironiquement, au cours des quatre années à venir le FDR 
pouvait remplir sept vacances d'emploi sur la cour, terminant en 
grande partie son opposition à la nouvelle affaire. D'ici là, 
cependant, merci dans la grande partie à l'opposition publique au 
Cour-emballage projettent, il avaient détruit les majorités 
prévisibles qui avaient facilement porté ses factures par le 
congrès pendant sa première limite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A tentativa do presidente Franklin Roosevelt 1937 
de expandir o judiciary federal, sabido como sua da "planta 
Corte-embalagem" por seus muitos críticos, encontrou-se com com 
oposição ferocious. Os congressistas que tinham suportado 
warily o negócio novo agora suportaram afastado, unnerved pelo 
voluntariedade do presidente subvert a estrutura existente da 
potência. Na imprensa popular, as colunas tais como Dorothy 
Thompson da estrela de Washington refletiram ambo a aversão popular 
na planta de Roosevelt para aumentar o número de justiças da corte 
suprema e da popularidade continuada do FDR. A comparação de 
Thompson de Roosevelt a Hitler parece ridiculous agora, mas outra 
(como o pai Charles Coughlin) fêz tais comparações regularmente em 
1937. Ironically, sobre os quatro anos seguintes o FDR podia  
encher sete vacâncias na corte, terminando pela maior parte sua 
oposição ao negócio novo. Por então, entretanto, os 
agradecimentos na parte grande à oposição pública à 
Corte-embalagem planeiam, ele tinham perdido as maiorias predictable 
que tinham carregado fàcilmente suas contas através do congress 
durante seu primeiro termo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il tentativo del presidente Franklin Roosevelt 
1937 di espandere l'ordinamento giudiziario federale, conosciuto come 
il suo "programma dell'Corte-imballaggio" dai suoi numerosi critici, 
ha incontrato opposizione ferocious. I membri del Congresso che 
warily ora avevano sostenuto il nuovo affare hanno sostenuto via, 
unnerved dalla compiacenza del presidente subvert la struttura attuale
di potenza. Nella pressa popolare, le colonne quale Dorothy 
Thompson dalla stella de Washington hanno riflesso entrambe la 
repulsione popolare al programma del Roosevelt per aumentare il numero
di giustizie della Corte suprema e di popolarità continuata del FDR. 
Il confronto del Thompson tra Roosevelt e Hitler ora sembra 
ridiculous, ma altri (come il padre Charles Coughlin) hanno fatto 
regolarmente tali confronti in 1937. Ironicamente, nel corso dei
quattro anni successivi il FDR poteva coprire sette posti vacanti 
sulla corte, in gran parte concludente la relativa opposizione al 
nuovo affare. Per allora, tuttavia, i ringraziamenti nella 
grande parte ad opposizione pubblica all'Corte-imballaggio progettano,
lui avevano perso le maggioranze prevedibili che avevano trasportato 
facilmente le sue fatture attraverso il congresso durante il suo primo
termine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προσπάθεια του 1937 Προέδρου Franklin 
Roosevelt's να επεκταθεί ο ομοσπονδιακός δικαστικός, γνωστός ως
το "σχέδιο δικαστήριο-συσκευασίας του" από τους πολλούς 
κριτικούς της, συναντήθηκε με την άγρια αντίθεση. Τα μέλη 
του Κογκρέσσου που είχαν υποστηρίξει warily τη νέα 
διαπραγμάτευση υποστήριξαν τώρα μακριά, εξασθενισμένος από την 
προθυμία του Προέδρου να υπονομεύσει την υπάρχουσα δομή δύναμης.
Στο δημοφιλή Τύπο, οι στήλες όπως Dorothy Thompson's 
από το αστέρι της Ουάσιγκτον απεικόνισαν και ο δύο τη δημοφιλή 
αποστροφή στο σχέδιο Roosevelt για να αυξήσουν τον αριθμό 
συνεχούς δημοτικότητας justices ανώτατου δικαστηρίου και 
FDR. Η σύγκριση Thompson Roosevelt hitler φαίνεται
γελοία τώρα, αλλά άλλοι (όπως τον πατέρα Charles Coughlin)
έκαναν τέτοιες συγκρίσεις τακτικά σε 1937, Ειρωνικά, 
κατά τη διάρκεια των επόμενων τεσσάρων ετών FDR ήταν σε θέση
να γεμίσει επτά κενά στο δικαστήριο, τελειώνοντας κατά ένα 
μεγάλο μέρος την αντίθεσή του στη νέα διαπραγμάτευση. Έως
τότε, εντούτοις, ευχαριστίες στο μεγάλο μέρος στη δημόσια 
αντίθεση στο σχέδιο δικαστήριο-συσκευασίας, είχε χάσει τις 
προβλέψιμες πλειοψηφίες που είχαν φέρει εύκολα τους λογαριασμούς
του μέσω του συνεδρίου κατά τη διάρκεια του πρώτου τριμήνου του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La tentativa de presidente Franklin Roosevelt 1937
de ampliar la judicatura federal, conocida como su "plan del 
Corte-embalaje" por sus muchos críticos, satisfizo con la oposición 
feroz. Los miembros del Congreso que warily ahora habían 
utilizado el nuevo reparto movieron hacia atrás lejos, unnerved por 
la buena voluntad del presidente de derribar la estructura existente 
de la potencia. En la prensa popular, las columnas tales como 
Dorothy Thompson de la estrella de Washington reflejaron ambo 
repugnancia popular en el plan de Roosevelt para aumentar el número 
de las justicias del Tribunal Supremo y del renombre continuado del 
FDR. La comparación de Thompson de Roosevelt a Hitler se parece
ridícula ahora, pero otras (como el padre Charles Coughlin) hicieron 
tales comparaciones regularmente en 1937. Irónico, durante los 
cuatro años próximos el FDR podía llenar siete vacantes en la 
corte, terminando en gran parte su oposición al nuevo reparto. 
Para entonces, sin embargo, las gracias en parte grande a la 
oposición pública al Corte-embalaje planean, él habían perdido a 
mayorías fiables que habían llevado fácilmente sus cuentas a 
través de congreso durante su primer término.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086769</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103176</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/pure-personal-government-roosevelt-goes-too-far-in-packing-the-court</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
