<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102913</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102913</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205657</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Jazz, A Film by Ken Burns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jazz, ein Film durch Ken Burns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jazz, un film par Ken Burns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jazz, uma película por Ken Queimadura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jazz, una pellicola da Ken Burns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τζαζ, μια ταινία από Ken Burns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jazz, una película de Ken Burns</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the companion website to the Ken Burns PBS series that aired in January 2001. Explore cities and clubs where jazz developed; listen to excerpts of bebop, cool jazz and other styles; discover what makes jazz jazz and the theory behind the art form often called the purest expression of American democracy. The site provides biographies of nearly 100 musicians, transcripts of interviews that went into the making of the show, a virtual piano, a study guide and more than a dozen lessons.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Begleiterweb site zur Serie der Ken 
Brände PBS, die im Januar 2001 lüftete. Erforschen Sie Städte
und Vereine, in denen Jazz sich entwickelte; hören Sie zu den 
Excerpts von bebop, von kühlem Jazz und von anderen Arten; 
entdecken Sie, was Jazzjazz und die Theorie hinter der Kunstform
bildet, die häufig den reinsten Ausdruck der amerikanischen 
Demokratie genannt wird. Die Site liefert Biographien von fast 
100 Musikern, Abschriften der Interviews, die in das Bilden des 
Erscheinens, des virtuellen Klaviers, der Studie Anleitung und mehr 
als Lektionen Dutzend einstiegen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le site Web de compagnon à la série des 
brûlures PBS de Ken qui a aéré en janvier 2001. Explorez les 
villes et les clubs où le jazz s'est développé ; écoutez des
extraits de bebop, de jazz frais et d'autres modèles ; 
découvrez ce qui fait le jazz de jazz et la théorie derrière 
la forme d'art souvent appelée l'expression la plus pure de la 
démocratie américaine. Le site fournit des biographies de 
presque 100 musiciens, transcriptions des entrevues qui sont entrées 
dans la fabrication de l'exposition, d'un piano virtuel, d'un guide 
d'étude et de plus que les leçons une douzaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o Web site do companheiro à série das 
queimaduras PBS de Ken que arejou em janeiro 2001. Explore 
cidades e clubes onde o jazz se tornou; escute excerpts do 
bebop, do jazz fresco e dos outros estilos; descubra o que faz o
jazz do jazz e a teoria atrás do formulário de arte chamado 
frequentemente a expressão a mais pura da democracia americana. 
O local fornece biografias de quase 100 músicos, transcripts 
das entrevistas que entraram em fazer da mostra, de um piano virtual, 
de uma guia do estudo e de mais do que as lições uma dúzia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il Web site del compagno alla serie delle 
ustioni PBS di Ken che ha ventilato nel mese di gennaio del 2001. 
Esplori le città ed i randelli in cui il jazz si è sviluppato;
ascolti i brani di bebop, di jazz freddo e di altri stili; 
scopra che cosa fa il jazz di jazz e la teoria dietro la forma 
di arte spesso chiamata l'espressione più pura della democrazia 
americana. Il luogo fornisce le biografie di quasi 100 
musicisti, le trascrizioni delle interviste che hanno entrato nel 
fare dell'esposizione, di un piano virtuale, di una guida di studio e 
di più delle lezioni un dozzina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ο ιστοχώρος συντρόφων στη Ken σειρά 
εγκαυμάτων PBS που αέρισε τις 2001, Ιανουαρίου εξερευνά τις 
πόλεις και τις λέσχες όπου η τζαζ αναπτύχθηκε  ακούστε τα 
αποσπάσματα του bebop, της δροσερής τζαζ και άλλων μορφών  
ανακαλύψτε τι κάνει την τζαζ τζαζ και η θεωρία πίσω από τη 
μορφή τέχνης κάλεσε συχνά την καθαρότερη έκφραση της 
αμερικανικής δημοκρατίας. Η περιοχή παρέχει τις βιογραφίες 
σχεδόν 100 μουσικών, αντίγραφα των συνεντεύξεων που πήγαν στην
παραγωγή της επίδειξης, ένα εικονικό πιάνο, ένας οδηγός 
μελέτης και περισσότερο από δωδεκάα μαθήματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">está el Web site del compañero a la serie de las
quemaduras PBS de Ken que ventiló en enero de 2001. Explore a 
las ciudades y a clubs donde el jazz se convirtió; escuche los 
extractos del bebop, del jazz fresco y de otros estilos; 
descubra qué hace jazz del jazz y la teoría detrás de la 
forma de arte a menudo llamada la expresión más pura de la 
democracia americana. El sitio proporciona a biografías de casi
100 músicos, transcripciones de las entrevistas que entraron la 
fabricación de la demostración, de un piano virtual, de una guía 
del estudio y más que las lecciones una docena.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205657</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102913</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/jazz-a-film-by-ken-burns</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
