<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103670</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103670</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973934</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Immune System Defender</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Immunes System Verteidiger</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Défenseur de Système 
immunitaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Defender Do Sistema 
Imune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Protezione Del 
Sistema Immune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Υπερασπιστής ανοσοποιητικών 
συστημάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Defensor Del Sistema 
Inmune</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Ilya Mechnikov, one of the pioneers of immune system research, inserted a thorn into a larva and noticed strange cells gathering around the thorn. The cells were eating any foreign substances entering the ruptured skin. He called these cells phagocytes meaning "devouring cells." He later shared the 1908 Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine with another pioneer in the same field, Paul Ehrlich.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Ilya Mechnikov, einer der Pioniere der immunes System Forschung,
setzte einen Dorn in eine Larve ein und beachtete merkwürdige Zellen,
um den Dorn zu erfassen. Die Zellen aßen alle fremden 
Substanzen, welche die gebrochene Haut kommen. Er nannte diese 
die Zellen Phagozyten, die bedeuten "verschlingende Zellen." Er 
teilte später den Nobelpreis 1908 in der Physiologie, oder Medizin 
mit einem anderen Pionier imselben fängt, Paul Ehrlich auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Ilya 
Mechnikov, un des pionniers de la recherche de système immunitaire, a
inséré une épine dans une larve et a noté les cellules étranges 
recueillir autour de l'épine. Les cellules mangeaient toutes 
les substances étrangères entrant dans la peau rompue. Il a 
appelé ces derniers des phagocytes de cellules signifiant "les 
cellules dévorantes." Il plus tard a partagé le prix 1908 
Nobel dans la physiologie ou la médecine avec un autre pionnier dans 
le même domaine, Paul Ehrlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Ilya 
Mechnikov, um dos pioneiros da pesquisa do sistema imune, introduziu 
um espinho em uma larva e observou pilhas estranhas recolher em torno 
do espinho. As pilhas comiam todas as substâncias extrangeiras 
que entram na pele rompida. Chamou estes os phagocytes das 
pilhas que significam "pilhas devouring." Compartilhou mais 
tarde do prêmio 1908 de nobel no physiology ou na medicina com um 
outro pioneiro no mesmo campo, Paul Ehrlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Ilya Mechnikov, uno dei 
pionieri di ricerca del sistema immune, ha inserito una spina in una 
larva ed ha notato le cellule sconosciute riunire intorno 
alla spina. Le cellule stavano mangiando tutte le sostanze 
straniere che entrano nella pelle rotta. Ha chiamato questi 
fagociti delle cellule che significano "le cellule devouring." 
Più successivamente ha ripartito il premio 1908 Nobel nella 
fisiologia o nella medicina con un altro pioniere nello stesso campo, 
Paul Ehrlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Το 
Ilya Mechnikov, ένας από τους πρωτοπόρους της έρευνας 
ανοσοποιητικών συστημάτων, παρενέβαλε ένα αγκάθι σε μια προνύμφη
και παρατήρησε τα παράξενα κύτταρα γύρω από το αγκάθι. Τα 
κύτταρα έτρωγαν οποιεσδήποτε ξένες ουσίες που εισάγουν το 
σπασμένο δέρμα. Κάλεσε αυτά τα φαγοκύτταρα κυττάρων 
σημαίνοντας "καταβροχθίζοντας τα κύτταρα." Μοιράστηκε 
αργότερα το βραβείο Νόμπελ του 1908 στη φυσιολογία ή την 
ιατρική με έναν άλλο πρωτοπόρο στο ίδιο πεδίο, Paul 
Ehrlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Ilya 
Mechnikov, uno de los pioneros de la investigación del sistema 
inmune, insertó una espina en una larva y notó las células 
extrañas el recolectar alrededor de la espina. Las células 
comían cualquier sustancia no nativa que entraba en la piel rota. 
Él llamó éstos los fagocitos de las células que significaban
las "células devouring." Él compartió más adelante el premio
1908 Nobel en la fisiología o la medicina con otro pionero en el 
mismo campo, Paul Ehrlich.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973934</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103670</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-immune-system-defender</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
