<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104021</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104021</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206141</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Water on the Web</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wasser auf dem Web</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'eau sur le Web</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Água no Web</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Acqua sul Web</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ύδωρ στον Ιστό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Agua en el Web</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers water science units and tools that help students understand and solve real environmental problems using advanced technology. Learn about aquatic ecology, water quality, and watersheds. See maps, summaries, and information on lakes and rivers nationwide. Use data visualization tools to watch data change through time and explore relationships among variables.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebote wässern Wissenschaft Maßeinheiten und 
Hilfsmittel, die Kursteilnehmern reale, Umweltprobleme mit neuer 
Technologie zu verstehen helfen und zu lösen. Erlernen Sie 
über Wasserökologie, Wasserqualität und Wasserscheiden. Sehen
Sie Karten, Zusammenfassungen und Informationen über Seen und Flüsse
im ganzen Land. Benutzen Sie Datensichtbarmachunghilfsmittel, um
Datenänderung durch Zeit zu überwachen und Verhältnisse unter 
Variablen zu erforschen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les offres arrosent les unités et les outils de 
la science qui aident des étudiants à comprendre et résoudre des 
problèmes écologiques réels en utilisant la technologie de pointe. 
Renseignez-vous sur l'écologie, la qualité de l'eau, et les 
lignes de partage aquatiques. Voir des cartes, des sommaires, et
l'information sur des lacs et des fleuves dans tout le pays. 
Utilisez les outils de visualisation de données pour observer 
le changement de données par le temps et pour explorer des rapports 
parmi des variables.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as ofertas molham as unidades e as ferramentas da 
ciência que ajudam a estudantes compreender e resolver problemas 
ambientais reais usando tecnologia avançada. Aprenda sobre o 
ecology, a qualidade de água, e watersheds aquáticos. Veja 
mapas, sumários, e informação em lagos e em rios por todo o país. 
Use ferramentas do visualization dos dados prestar atenção à 
mudança dos dados com o tempo e explorar relacionamentos entre 
variáveis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le offerte innaffiano le unità e gli strumenti di
scienza che aiutano gli allievi a capire e risolvere i problemi 
ambientali reali usando la tecnologia avanzata. Impari circa 
l'ecologia, la qualità dell'acqua e gli spartiacque acquatici. 
Si veda i programmi, i sommari e le informazioni sui laghi e sui
fiumi in tutta la nazione. Utilizzi gli strumenti di 
visualizzazione di dati per guardare il cambiamento di dati con tempo 
e per esplorare i rapporti fra le variabili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τις μονάδες και τα εργαλεία επιστήμης 
ύδατος που βοηθούν τους σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν και να λύσουν τα
πραγματικά περιβαλλοντικά προβλήματα χρησιμοποιώντας την 
προηγμένη τεχνολογία. Μάθετε για την υδρόβιους οικολογία, 
την ποιότητα νερού, και τους υδροκρίτες. Δείτε 
τους χάρτες, τις περιλήψεις, και τις πληροφορίες για τις λίμνες 
και τους ποταμούς σε εθνικό επίπεδο. Χρησιμοποιήστε τα 
εργαλεία απεικόνισης στοιχείων για να προσέξετε την αλλαγή 
στοιχείων μέσω του χρόνου και να ερευνήσετε τις σχέσεις μεταξύ 
των μεταβλητών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las ofertas riegan las unidades y las herramientas
de la ciencia que ayudan a estudiantes a entender y a solucionar 
problemas ambientales verdaderos usando tecnología avanzada. 
Aprenda sobre la ecología, la calidad del agua, y las líneas 
divisoria de las aguas acuáticas. Vea las correspondencias, los
resúmenes, y la información sobre los lagos y los ríos por toda la 
nación. Utilice las herramientas de la visualización de los 
datos para mirar el cambio de los datos con tiempo y para explorar 
lazos entre variables.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206141</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104021</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/water-on-the-web</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
