<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103512</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103512</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086255</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"How Many Thousands?" Bruce Priebe on AIDS Activism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wieviele Tausenden?" Bruce Priebe auf AIDS 
Aktivismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Combien de Milliers?" Bruce Priebe sur 
l'activisme de SIDA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Quantos Milhares?" Bruce Priebe no activism 
do AIDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Quante Migliaia?" Bruce Priebe su activism 
del AIDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πόσες χιλιάδες;" Bruce Priebe στον 
ακτιβισμό του AIDS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Cuántos Millares?" Bruce Priebe en 
activismo del SIDA</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When AIDS struck the gay community during the early 1980's, many who had not previously consider themselves activists, like Bruce Priebe, became politically active. Militancy, political action, and demands for rights and recognition within the gay and lesbian community had been building throughout the post-war period. While many homosexual men and women first expressed their sexuality during World War II, a period of relative, albeit silent, tolerance, the movement for gay rights became more assertive following the 1969 Stonewall Riot, when New York City police raided a gay club. The burst of community health activism in response to the AIDS epidemic built on these earlier expressions of "gay pride" and activism.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als AIDS die homosexuelle Gemeinschaft während der
frühen achtziger Jahre anschlug, wurden viele, die, vorher hatten 
nicht sich zu halten für Aktivisten, wie Bruce Priebe, politisch 
aktiv. Militancy, politische Klage und Nachfragen auf Rechte und
Anerkennung innerhalb der homosexuellen und lesbischen Gemeinschaft 
waren Gebäude während der Nachkriegsperiode gewesen. Während 
viele homosexuelle Männer und Frauen zuerst ihre Sexualität 
während des Zweiten Weltkrieges ausdrückten, eine Periode des 
Verwandten, obwohl leise, wurde Toleranz, die Bewegung für 
homosexuelle Rechte assertive, dem Stonewall Aufstand 1969 folgend, 
als New York City Polizei eine homosexuelle Verein überfiel. 
Der Impuls von Gemeinschaftsgesundheit Aktivismus in Erwiderung 
auf die AIDS-Epidemie aufgebaut auf diesen früheren Ausdrücken "des 
homosexuellen Stolzes" und des Aktivismus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand le SIDA a heurté la communauté gaie pendant
le début des années 80, beaucoup qui a eu précédemment pour ne pas
se considérer des activistes, comme Bruce Priebe, sont devenus 
politiquement actifs. Le militantisme, l'action politique, et 
les demandes des droites et l'identification au sein de la communauté
gaie et lesbienne avaient été bâtiment tout au long de la période 
d'après-guerre. Tandis que beaucoup d'hommes et femmes 
homosexuels exprimaient la première fois leur sexualité pendant la 
deuxième guerre mondiale, une période de parent, quoique silencieux,
la tolérance, le mouvement pour des droites gaies est devenue plus 
autoritaire suivant l'émeute 1969 de Stonewall, quand la police de 
New York City a pillé un club gai. L'éclat de l'activisme de 
santé de la communauté en réponse à l'épidémie de SIDA établi 
sur ces expressions plus tôt "de fierté gaie" et d'activisme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando o AIDS golpeou a comunidade gay durante os 
1980's adiantados, muitos que tiveram previamente não se considerar 
activistas, como Bruce Priebe, tornaram-se polìtica ativos. O 
militancy, a ação política, e as demandas para direitas e o 
recognition dentro da comunidade gay e lesbian tinham sido edifício 
durante todo o período post-war. Quando muitos homens e 
mulheres homosexual expressaram primeiramente seu sexuality durante a 
segunda guerra mundial, um período do parente, albeit silencioso, a 
tolerância, o movimento para direitas gay tornou-se mais assertive 
seguindo o motim 1969 de Stonewall, quando as polícias de New York 
City invadiram um clube gay. O estouro do activism da saúde da 
comunidade em resposta à epidemia de AIDS construído nestas 
expressões mais adiantadas "do orgulho gay" e do activism.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando il AIDS ha colpito la Comunità di 
gay durante l'inizio degli anni 80, molti che avessero 
precedentemente non considerarsi attivisti, come Bruce Priebe, sono 
diventato politicamente attivi. La militanza, l'azione 
politica e le domande dei diritti ed il riconoscimento all'interno 
della Comunità della lesbica e di gay erano stati costruzione
durante il periodo del dopoguerra. Mentre molti uomini e donne 
omosessuali in primo luogo hanno espresso il loro sexuality durante la
seconda guerra mondiale, un periodo del parente, anche se silenzioso, 
la tolleranza, il movimento per i diritti di gay è diventato 
più assertive seguendo il tumulto 1969 di Stonewall, quando la 
polizia de New York City raided un randello di gay. Il 
burst di activism di salute della Comunità in risposta all'epidemia 
di AIDS sviluppato su queste espressioni più iniziali "di orgoglio di
gay" e di activism.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν το AIDS χτύπησε την ομοφυλοφιλική κοινότητα 
κατά τη διάρκεια της πρόωρης δεκαετίας του '80, πολλές που 
έπρεπε να μην θεωρηθούν προηγουμένως τα ενεργά στελέχη, όπως 
Bruce Priebe, έγιναν πολιτικά ενεργές. Η μαχητικότητα,
η πολιτική ενέργεια, και οι απαιτήσεις για τα δικαιώματα και η 
αναγνώριση εντός της ομοφυλοφιλικής και λεσβιακής κοινότητας 
έχτιζαν καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια της μεταπολεμικής περιόδου. 
Ενώ πολλοί ομοφυλοφιλικοί άνδρες και γυναίκες εξέφρασαν 
αρχικά τη σεξουαλικότητά τους κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου ΙΙ, μια περίοδος συγγενή, αν και σιωπηλός, ανοχή, η 
μετακίνηση για τα ομοφυλόφιλα δικαιώματα έγινε πιό 
κατηγορηματική μετά από την πέτρινη ταραχή του 1969, όταν 
επιτέθηκε η αστυνομία πόλεων της Νέας Υόρκης μια ομοφυλόφιλη 
λέσχη. Η έκρηξη του κοινοτικού ακτιβισμού υγείας σε 
απάντηση στην επιδημία του AIDS που στηρίζεται σε αυτές τις 
προηγούμενες εκφράσεις της "ομοφυλοφιλικής υπερηφάνειασ" και του 
ακτιβισμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando el SIDA pulso a comunidad gay 
durante los años 80 tempranos, muchos que tenían previamente no 
considerarse los activistas, como Bruce Priebe, llegaron a ser 
político activos. La militancia, la acción política, y las 
demandas para las derechas y el reconocimiento dentro de la comunidad 
del gay y de la lesbiana habían sido edificio a través del 
período de la posguerra. Mientras que muchos hombres y mujeres 
homosexuales primero expresaron su sexualidad durante la Segunda 
Guerra Mundial, un período del pariente, no obstante silencioso, la 
tolerancia, el movimiento para las derechas gays llegó a ser 
más asertiva siguiendo el alboroto 1969 de Stonewall, cuando el 
policía de New York City atacó a club gay. La 
explosión del activismo de la salud de la comunidad en respuesta a la
epidemia de SIDA construida en estas expresiones anteriores del 
"orgullo gay" y del activismo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086255</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103512</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/how-many-thousands-bruce-priebe-on-aids-activism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
