<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108810</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108810</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212747</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Tofte Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Tofte Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Projet de Tofte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Projeto De Tofte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Progetto Tofte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα Tofte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Proyecto De Tofte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides a description of a cabin in Tofte, MN on the North Shore of Lake Superior. The new owner of the cabin decided to remake it into a model of sustainable building practices. The site includes several dozen flash animations looking at sustainability from many angles as well as the specifics of the house and its surroundings.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert eine Beschreibung einer Kabine 
in Tofte, Mangan auf dem Nordufer von Lake Superior. Der neue 
Inhaber der Kabine entschied zum Remake es in ein Modell der 
stützbaren Gebäudepraxis. Die Site schließt einige grelle 
Animationen Dutzend ein, die sustainability von vielen Winkeln sowie 
die Besonderen des Hauses und seiner Umlagerungen betrachten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit une description d'une carlingue 
dans Tofte, manganèse sur le rivage du nord du supérieur de lac. 
Le nouveau propriétaire de la carlingue a décidé de la 
refaire dans un modèle des pratiques en matière soutenables de 
bâtiment. Le site inclut plusieurs animations douzaine 
instantanées regardant la durabilité de beaucoup d'angles aussi bien 
que les détails de la maison et de ses environnements.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece uma descrição de uma cabine 
em Tofte, manganês na costa norte do superior de lago. O 
proprietário novo da cabine decidiu-se remake a em um modelo de 
práticas sustainable do edifício. O local inclui diversos 
animations dúzia flash que olham o sustainability de muitos ângulos 
as.well.as os específicos da casa e de seus arredors.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce una descrizione di una 
baracca in Tofte, manganese sul puntello del nord del superiore di 
lago. Il nuovo proprietario della baracca ha deciso refarlo in 
un modello delle pratiche sostenibili della costruzione. Il 
luogo include parecchie animazioni istantanee dozzina che guardano il 
sustainability da molti angoli così come gli specifics della casa e 
dei relativi dintorni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει μια περιγραφή μιας καμπίνας σε
Tofte, ΜΝ στη βόρεια ακτή του ανωτέρου λιμνών. Ο νέος 
ιδιοκτήτης της καμπίνας αποφάσισε να το ανακατασκευάσει σε ένα 
μοντέλο των βιώσιμων πρακτικών οικοδόμησης. Η περιοχή 
περιλαμβάνει αρκετές δωδεκάες ζωτικότητες λάμψης εξετάζοντας την
ικανότητα υποστήριξης από πολλές γωνίες καθώς επίσης και τις 
λεπτομέρειες του σπιτιού και των περιχώρων της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a una descripción de una 
cabina en Tofte, manganeso en la orilla del norte del superior de 
lago. El nuevo propietario de la cabina decidía rehacerla en un
modelo de las prácticas sostenibles del edificio. El sitio 
incluye varias animaciones de destello docena que miran sustainability
de muchos ángulos así como los específicos de la casa y de sus 
alrededores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SARAH NETTLETON
FN:SARAH NETTLETON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212747</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108810</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-tofte-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
