<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108537</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108537</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Napoleon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Napoleon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Napoleon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Napoleon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Napoleon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Napoleon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Napoleon</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a PBS film that chronicles the life of the infamous French leader. The resources offered here are designed to help you use the PBS Napoleon video series and companion website in secondary social studies, civics, religion, and language arts classes. The site is organized into four areas: the man and the myth, Napoleon and Josephine, politics in Napoleon's time, and Napoleon at war. There are four lesson plans, an interactive battlefield simulator, video clips, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein PBS Film, der das Leben des unbeliebten 
französischen Führers aufzeichnet. Die Betriebsmittel, die 
hier angeboten werden, sind konzipiert, um Ihnen zu helfen, die PBS 
Napoleon video Serie und Begleiterweb site in den 
Sekundärsozialstudien, in der Gemeinschaftskunde, in der Religion und
in den Sprachenkunstkategorien zu verwenden. Die Site wird in 
vier Bereiche organisiert: der Mann und der Mythus, das Napoleon
und das Josephine, Politik in der Zeit Napoleons und das Napoleon am 
Krieg. Es gibt vier Lektionpläne, interaktiven Schlachtfeld 
Simulator-, videoclips und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un film de PBS qui fait la chronique de la vie
de l'amorce française infâme. Les ressources offertes ici sont
conçues pour vous aider à utiliser le site Web visuel de série et 
de compagnon de PBS Napoleon dans des études, l'éducation civique, 
la religion, et des classes d'arts sociales secondaires de langage. 
Le site est organisé en quatre zones : l'homme et le 
mythe, le Napoleon et le Josephine, la politique dans le temps de 
Napoleon, et le Napoleon à la guerre. Il y a quatre plans de 
leçon, des clips de simulateur de champ de bataille et visuels 
interactifs, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma película de PBS que chronicles a vida do 
líder francês infamous. Os recursos oferecidos aqui são 
projetados ajudar-lhe usar o Web site video da série e do companheiro
de PBS Napoleon em estudos, no civics, na religião, e em classes de 
artes sociais secundários da língua. O local é organizado em 
quatro áreas: o homem e o mito, o Napoleon e o Josephine, 
política no tempo de Napoleon, e o Napoleon na guerra. Há 
quatro plantas da lição, uns grampos interativos do simulador do 
campo de batalha, os video, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una pellicola di PBS che chronicles la vita del
capo francese malfamato. Le risorse offerte qui sono 
destinate per aiutarle ad usare il video Web site di serie e del 
compagno di PBS Napoleon negli studi, nel civics, nella religione e 
nei codici categoria di arti sociali secondari di linguaggio. Il
luogo è organizzato in quattro zone: l'uomo ed il mito, il 
Napoleon ed il Josephine, politica nel tempo del Napoleon ed il 
Napoleon alla guerra. Ci sono quattro programmi di lezione, lle 
clip interattive del simulatore del campo di battaglia, video e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια ταινία PBS που εξιστορεί κατά γράμμα τη 
ζωή του κακόφημου γαλλικού ηγέτη. Τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς
προσφερθέντα εδώ σχεδιάζονται για να σας βοηθήσουν να 
χρησιμοποιήσετε τον τηλεοπτικό ιστοχώρο σειράς PBS Napoleon 
και συντρόφων στις δευτεροβάθμιες κοινωνικές μελέτες, το 
civics, τη θρησκεία, και τις τάξεις γλωσσικών τεχνών. Η 
περιοχή οργανώνεται σε τέσσερις περιοχές: το άτομο και ο 
μύθος, το Napoleon και το Josephine, η πολιτική στο χρόνο 
Napoleon, και το Napoleon στον πόλεμο. Υπάρχουν τέσσερα
σχέδια μαθήματος, ένας διαλογικός προσομοιωτής πεδίων μαχών, 
τηλεοπτικοί συνδετήρες, και περισσότερος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una película de PBS que chronicles la vida del
arranque de cinta francés infame. Los recursos ofrecidos aquí 
se diseñan para ayudarle a utilizar el Web site video de la serie y 
del compañero de PBS Napoleon en estudios, civics, la religión, y 
clases de artes sociales secundarios del lenguaje. El sitio se 
ordena en cuatro áreas: el hombre y el mito, el Napoleon y el 
Josephine, política en el tiempo de Napoleon, y el Napoleon en la 
guerra. Hay cuatro planes de la lección, clips interactivos del
simulador del campo de batalla, video, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108537</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/napoleon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
