<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108185</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108185</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202988</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Global Warming and the Greenhouse Effect</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Globales Wärmen und der Gewächshaus-Effekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chauffage global et l'effet de serre chaude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aquecer-se global e o efeito da estufa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Riscaldamento globale e l'effetto della serra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παγκόσμια αύξηση της θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου
του θερμοκηπίου και το φαινόμενο του θερμοκηπίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El calentarse global y el efecto del invernadero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Since 1880, the levels of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere and global temperatures have been following a parallel rising path. Is this simply a coincidence? Most scientists don't think so. This video excerpt from Race to Save the Planet describes the relationship between human activities and negative changes to our global climate.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Seit 1880 haben die Stufen des Kohlendioxyds in 
der Atmosphäre und die globalen Temperaturen einem parallelen 
steigenden Pfad gefolgt. Ist dieses einfach eine 
Übereinstimmung? Die meisten Wissenschaftler denken nicht so. 
Dieses videoexcerpt vom Rennen außer zum Planeten beschreibt 
das Verhältnis zwischen menschlichen Aktivitäten und Negativ ändert
zu unserem globalen Klima.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Depuis 1880, les niveaux de l'anhydride carbonique
dans l'atmosphère et les températures globales avaient suivi une 
voie d'accès de montée parallèle. Est-ce que c'est simplement
une coïncidence ? La plupart des scientifiques ne pensent pas 
ainsi. Cet extrait visuel de course à économiser la planète 
décrit le rapport entre les activités humaines et le négatif change
en notre climat global.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Desde 1880, os níveis do dióxido de carbono na 
atmosfera e as temperaturas globais têm seguido um trajeto 
levantando-se paralelo. É isto simplesmente uma coincidência? 
A maioria de cientistas não pensam assim. Este excerpt 
video da raça excepto ao planeta descreve o relacionamento entre 
atividades humanas e o negativo muda a nosso clima global.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dal 1880, i livelli dell'anidride carbonica 
nell'atmosfera e le temperature globali stanno seguendo un percorso 
aumentante parallelo. È semplicemente questo una coincidenza? 
La maggior parte dei scienziati non ritengono così. 
Questo video brano dalla corsa risparmi al pianeta descrive il 
rapporto fra le attività umane e la negazione cambia al nostro clima 
globale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από 1880, τα επίπεδα διοξειδίου του άνθρακα στην 
ατμόσφαιρα και οι διεθνείς θερμοκρασίες έχουν ακολουθήσει ένα 
παράλληλο μονοπάτι αύξησης. Είναι αυτό απλά μια σύμπτωση;
Οι περισσότεροι επιστήμονες δεν σκέφτονται έτσι. Αυτό
το τηλεοπτικό απόσπασμα από τη φυλή για να σώσει τον πλανήτη 
περιγράφει τη σχέση μεταξύ των ανθρώπινων δραστηριοτήτων και των 
αρνητικών αλλαγών στο παγκόσμιο κλίμα μας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Desde 1880, los niveles del bióxido de carbono en
la atmósfera y las temperaturas globales han estado siguiendo un 
camino de levantamiento paralelo. ¿Está esto simplemente una 
coincidencia? La mayoría de los científicos no piensan tan. 
Este extracto video de la raza excepto al planeta describe el 
lazo entre las actividades humanas y la negativa cambia a nuestro 
clima global.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
FN:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202988</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108185</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/global-warming-and-the-greenhouse-effect-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
