<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/184102050</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>184102050</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201289</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dirtland Microbe Zoo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dirtland Mikrobe Zoo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zoo de Microbe de Dirtland</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jardim zoológico Do Micróbio De Dirtland</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giardino zoologico Del Microbo Di Dirtland</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωολογικός κήπος μικροβίων Dirtland</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Parque zoológico Del Microbio De Dirtland</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the Digital Learning Center for Microbial Ecology, this web site features "Dirtland", an interactive microbe zoo. The site explores the endless varieties of microorganisms and the environments they inhabit. These habitats include composts, at home, agriculture, hot springs, snow and ice, mines, root cellars, toxic waste, animals, soil, food, space, and water. Each habitat link provides a description of the environment as well as images and descriptions of particular species of microorganisms that thrive there. The site also contains a "What is a microbe?" link with an interactive image comparing the size of a microbe to a mouse and a tree of life with an outline of the major groups of organisms.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von der Digital, die Mitte für Mikrobenökologie 
erlernt, kennzeichnet diese Web site "Dirtland", ein interaktiver 
Mikrobe Zoo. Die Site erforscht die endlose Vielzahl 
der Mikroorganismen und die Umgebungen, die sie bewohnen. Diese 
Lebensräume enthalten Mischungen, zu Hause, Landwirtschaft, heiße 
Frühlinge, Schnee und Eis, Gruben, Wurzelkeller, giftiger 
Abfallstoff, Tiere, Boden, Nahrung, Platz und Wasser. Jedes 
Lebensraumlink stellt eine Beschreibung der Umgebung sowie Bilder und 
Beschreibungen der bestimmten Sorten der Mikroorganismen zur 
Verfügung, die dort vorwärtskommen. Die Site enthält auch ", 
was ist eine Mikrobe?" binden Sie mit einem interaktiven Bild, 
welches die Größe einer Mikrobe mit einer Maus und des Baums des 
Lebens mit einer umreiß der Hauptgruppen der organismen vergleicht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">De Digital apprenant le centre pour l'écologie 
microbienne, ce site Web comporte "Dirtland", un zoo interactif de 
microbe. Le site explore les variétés sans fin de 
micro-organismes et les environnements qu'ils habitent. Ces 
habitats incluent des composts, à la maison, agriculture, des 
ressorts chauds, neige et glace, des mines, des caves de racine, perte
toxique, des animaux, sol, nourriture, espace, et eau. Chaque 
lien d'habitat fournit une description de l'environnement aussi bien 
que des images et des descriptions des espèces particulières des
micro-organismes qui prospèrent là. Le site contient 
également "ce qui est un microbe?" joignez avec une image 
interactive comparant la taille d'un microbe à une souris et d'un 
arbre de la vie à un contour des groupes principaux d'organizations.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Da Digital que aprende o centro para o ecology 
microbial, este Web site caracteriza "Dirtland", um jardim zoológico 
interativo do micróbio. O local exploram as variedades 
infinitas dos microorganisms e os ambientes que habita. Estes 
habitats incluem composts, na HOME, a agricultura, as molas quentes, a
neve e o gelo, as minas, as adegas da raiz, desperdício tóxico, 
animais, solo, alimento, espaço, e água. Cada ligação do 
habitat fornece uma descrição do ambiente as.well.as imagens e 
descrições de espécies particulares dos microorganisms que 
prosperam lá. O local contem também "o que é um micróbio?" 
ligue com uma imagem interativa que compara o tamanho de um 
micróbio a um rato e de uma árvore da vida com um esboço dos grupos
principais dos organismos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dalla Digital che impara il centro per l'ecologia 
microbica, questo Web site caratterizza "Dirtland", un giardino 
zoologico interattivo del microbo. Il luogo esplora le varietà 
infinite di microorganismi e gli ambienti che abitano. Questi 
habitat includono le composte, nel paese, l'agricoltura, le molle 
calde, neve e ghiaccio, miniere, cantine della radice, spreco tossico,
animali, terreno, alimento, spazio ed acqua. Ogni collegamento 
dell'habitat fornisce una descrizione dell'ambiente così come le 
immagini e le descrizioni delle specie particolari di microorganismi 
che prosperano là. Il luogo egualmente contiene "che cosa è un
microbo?" colleghisi con un'immagine interattiva che confronta 
il formato di un microbo ad un mouse e di un albero di vita ad un 
profilo dei gruppi principali degli organismi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το ψηφιακό κέντρο εκμάθησης για τη μικροβιακή 
οικολογία, χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα "Dirtland" αυτών των 
ιστοχώρων, ένας διαλογικός ζωολογικός κήπος μικροβίων. Η 
περιοχή ερευνά τις ατελείωτες ποικιλίες των μικροοργανισμών και 
των περιβαλλόντων που κατοικούν. Αυτοί οι βιότοποι 
περιλαμβάνουν τα λιπάσματα, στο σπίτι, τη γεωργία, τα καυτά 
ελατήρια, το χιόνι και τον πάγο, τα ορυχεία, τα κελάρια ρίζας, 
τα τοξικά απόβλητα, τα ζώα, το χώμα, τα τρόφιμα, το διάστημα, 
και το ύδωρ. Κάθε σύνδεση βιότοπων παρέχει μια περιγραφή 
του περιβάλλοντος καθώς επίσης και των εικόνων και τις περιγραφές
των ιδιαίτερων ειδών μικροοργανισμών που αναπτύσσονται εκεί. 
Η περιοχή περιέχει επίσης "τι είναι ένα μικρόβιο;" 
σύνδεση με μια διαλογική εικόνα που συγκρίνει το μέγεθος 
ενός μικροβίου με ένα ποντίκι και ενός δέντρου της ζωής με ένα
περίγραμμα των σημαντικότερων ομάδων οργανισμών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De la Digital que aprende el centro para la 
ecología microbiana, este Web site ofrece "Dirtland", un parque 
zoológico interactivo del microbio. El sitio explora las 
variedades sin fin de microorganismos y los ambientes que habitan. 
Estos habitat incluyen los estiércoles vegetales, en el país, 
agricultura, los resortes calientes, nieve e hielo, las minas, los 
sótanos de la raíz, basura tóxica, los animales, suelo, alimento, 
espacio, y agua. Cada conexión del habitat proporciona a una 
descripción del ambiente así como imágenes y descripciones de 
especies determinadas de los microorganismos que prosperan allí. 
El sitio también contiene "cuál es un microbio?" conecte
a una imagen interactiva que compara la talla de un microbio a un 
ratón y de un árbol de la vida con un contorno de los grupos 
principales de organismos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CARRIE HEETER
FN:CARRIE HEETER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DIGITAL LEARNING CENTER FOR MICROBIAL ECOLOGY
FN:DIGITAL LEARNING CENTER FOR MICROBIAL ECOLOGY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201289</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>184102050</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/dirtland-microbe-zoo</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
