<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106983</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106983</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212408</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tardigrada (Water Bears)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tardigrada (Wasser-Bären)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tardigrada (Ours de l'Eau)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tardigrada (Ursos Da Água)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tardigrada (Orsi Dell'Acqua)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Tardigrada (το ύδωρ αντέχει)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tardigrada (Osos Del Agua)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This reference page offers a brief description of Tardigrades, also known as water bears. It includes information about their physical appearance, an explanation of their name, likely habitats, internal organs and other distinguishing features, and a few images. A diagram of a common tardigrade, Macrobiotus macronyx, is also provided via an internal link.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Bezugsseite bietet eine kurze Beschreibung 
von Tardigrades, alias von Wasserbären an. Sie schließt 
Informationen über ihr körperliches Aussehen, eine Erklärung ihres 
Namens, wahrscheinliche Lebensräume, interne Organe und andere 
unterscheidene Merkmale und einige Bilder ein. Ein Diagramm 
eines geläufigen tardigrade, Macrobiotus macronyx, wird auch über 
ein internes Link zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page de référence offre une courte 
description de Tardigrades, également connue sous le nom de l'eau 
soutient. Elle inclut des informations sur leur aspect physique,
une explication de leur nom, les habitats probables, les organes 
internes et d'autres dispositifs de distinction, et quelques images. 
Un diagramme d'un tardigrade commun, macronyx de Macrobiotus, 
est également fourni par l'intermédiaire d'un lien interne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta página da referência oferece uma 
descrição breve de Tardigrades, sabida também enquanto a água 
carrega. Inclui a informação sobre sua aparência física, uma
explanação de seu nome, habitats prováveis, órgãos internos e 
outras características distinguindo, e algumas imagens. Um 
diagrama de um tardigrade comum, macronyx de Macrobiotus, é fornecido
também através de uma ligação interna.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa pagina di riferimento offre una descrizione
sommaria di Tardigrades, anche conosciuta come l'acqua sopporta. 
Include le informazioni sulla loro apparenza fisica, una 
spiegazione del loro nome, habitat probabili, organi interni ed altre 
caratteristiche di distinzione ed alcune immagini. Uno schema di
un tardigrade comune, macronyx di Macrobiotus, egualmente è fornito 
via un collegamento interno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σελίδα αναφοράς προσφέρει μια συνοπτική 
περιγραφή Tardigrades, επίσης γνωστός ως ύδωρ αντέχει. 
Περιλαμβάνει τις πληροφορίες για τη φυσική εμφάνισή τους, 
μια εξήγηση του ονόματός τους, τους πιθανούς βιότοπους, τα 
εσωτερικά όργανα και άλλα ιδιαίτερα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα, 
και μερικές εικόνες. Ένα διάγραμμα κοινός tardigrade, 
Macrobiotus macronyx, παρέχεται επίσης μέσω μιας εσωτερικής 
σύνδεσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta paginación de la referencia ofrece una 
descripción abreviada de Tardigrades, también sabida mientras que el
agua lleva. Incluye la información sobre su aspecto físico, 
una explicación de su nombre, los habitat probables, los órganos 
internos y otras características que distinguen, y algunas imágenes.
Un diagrama de un tardigrade común, macronyx de Macrobiotus, 
también se proporciona vía una conexión interna.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MICROGRAPHIA
FN:MICROGRAPHIA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212408</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106983</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tardigrada-water-bears</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
