<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107985</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107985</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086047</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Crosby on Kipling: A Parody of "The White Man's Burden"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Crosby auf Kipling: Eine Parodie "der
weißen Belastung des Mannes"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Crosby sur Kipling : Une parodie "du fardeau
de l'homme blanc"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Crosby em Kipling: Um parody "do burden do 
homem branco"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Crosby su Kipling: Un parody "della 
difficoltà dell'uomo bianco"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Crosby σε Kipling: Μια παρωδία "του άσπρου 
ανθρώπινου φορτίου"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Crosby en Kipling: Una parodiar "de la carga
del hombre blanco"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In February 1899, British novelist and poet Rudyard Kipling wrote a poem entitled "The White Man's Burden: The United States and The Philippine Islands." In this poem, Kipling urged the U.S. to take up the "burden" of empire, as had Britain and other European nations. Theodore Roosevelt, soon to become vice-president and then president, copied the poem and sent it to his friend, Senator Henry Cabot Lodge, commenting that it was "rather poor poetry, but good sense from the expansion point of view." Not everyone was as favorably impressed. Poet Ernest Crosby penned a parody of Kipling's work, "The Real White Man's Burden," and published it in his 1902 collection of poems  Swords and Plowshares . Crosby also wrote a satirical, anti-imperialist novel,  Captain Jinks, Hero , that parodied the career of General Frederick Funston, the man who had captured Philippine leader Emilio Aguinaldo in 1901.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Februar 1899, schrieben britischer Novelist und
Dichter Rudyard Kipling ein Gedicht, das "die weißen Belastung des 
Mannes erlaubt wurde: Die Vereinigten Staaten und die 
philippinischen Inseln." In diesem Gedicht drängte Kipling die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, die "Belastung" des Reiches, als gehabtes 
Großbritannien und andere europäische Nationen aufzunehmen. 
Theodore Roosevelt, Vizepräsidenten und dann Präsidenten bald 
zu stehen, kopierte das Gedicht und schickte es seinem Freund, Senator
Henry Cabot Lodge und kommentierte, daß es "ziemlich schlechte Poesie
war, aber gute Richtung vom Expansion Gesichtspunkt." Nicht 
jeder war, wie vorteilhaft beeindruckt. Dichter Ernest Crosby 
sperrte eine Parodie von Arbeit Kiplings, "die wirklichen 
weißen Belastung des Mannes," ein und veröffentlichte sie in seiner 
Ansammlung 1902 Gedichte Klingen und Plowshares. Crosby schrieb 
auch satirical, Anti-Imperialist Roman, Kapitän Jinks, Held, der die 
Karriere des Generals Frederick Funston parodied, der Mann, der 
philippinischen Führer Emilio Aguinaldo 1901 erfaßt hatte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En février 1899, le romancier et le poèt 
britanniques Rudyard Kipling ont écrit une poésie intitulée "le 
fardeau de l'homme blanc : Les Etats-Unis et les îles 
philippines." En cette poésie, Kipling a invité les ETATS-UNIS
à prendre le "fardeau" de l'empire, en tant que la Grande-Bretagne 
eue et d'autres nations européennes. Theodore Roosevelt, aller 
bien bientôt au vice-président et puis au président, a copié la 
poésie et l'a envoyée à son ami, le sénateur Henry Cabot Lodge, 
commentant que c'était "poésie plutôt faible, mais bon sens du 
point de vue d'expansion." Pas chacun était comme favorablement
appliqué. Le poèt Ernest Crosby a parqué une parodie du 
travail de Kipling, "du vrai le fardeau homme blanc," et l'a éditée 
dans sa collection 1902 d'épées et de socs de poésies. Crosby
a également écrit un satirique, roman d'anti-impérialiste, 
capitaine Jinks, le héros, qui a parodié la carrière du Général 
Frederick Funston, l'homme qui avait capturé le Chef philippin Emilio
Aguinaldo en 1901.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em fevereiro 1899, o novelist e o poeta 
britânicos Rudyard Kipling escreveram um poema intitulado "o burden 
do homem branco: Os estados unidos e os consoles philippine." 
Neste poema, Kipling incitou os ESTADOS UNIDOS fazer exame acima
do "burden" do império, como Grâ Bretanha tido e outras nações 
européias. Theodore Roosevelt, para assentar bem logo no 
vice-presidente e então no presidente, copí o poema e emitiu-o a seu
amigo, senator Henry Cabot Alojar, comentando que era "poesia rather 
deficiente, mas sentido bom do ponto da expansão da vista." 
Não todos era como impresso favoràvel. O poeta Ernest 
Crosby penned um parody do trabalho de Kipling, "o burden do homem 
branco real," e publicou-o em sua coleção 1902 de espadas e de 
plowshares dos poemas. Crosby escreveu também uma satirical, 
novela do anti-anti-imperialist, capitão Jinks, o herói, que 
parodied a carreira do general Frederick Funston, o homem que tinha 
capturado o líder philippine Emilio Aguinaldo em 1901.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mese di febbraio del 1899, il romanziere ed 
il poet britannici Rudyard Kipling hanno scritto un poem intitolato 
"la difficoltà dell'uomo bianco: Unito Dichiara e le 
isole filippine." In questo poem, Kipling ha invitato gli STATI 
UNITI a prendere "la difficoltà" dell'impero, come la Gran-Bretagna 
avuta ed altre nazioni europee. Theodore Roosevelt, presto stare
bene al vice presidente ed allora al presidente, ha copiato il poem e 
lo ha trasmesso al suo amico, il senatore Henry Cabot Lodge, 
commentante che era "la poesia piuttosto povera, ma buon senso dal
punto di vista di espansione." Non tutto era come impressionato 
favorevole. Il poet Ernest Crosby ha rinchiuso un parody del 
lavoro del Kipling, "la difficoltà dell'uomo bianco reale," e lo ha 
pubblicato nella sua accumulazione 1902 delle spade e dei vomeri dei 
poems. Crosby egualmente ha scritto un satirical, romanzo del 
anti-anti-imperialist, capitano Jinks, hero, che parodied la carriera 
del General Frederick Funston, l'uomo che aveva bloccato il 
capo filippino Emilio Aguinaldo in 1901.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Φεβρουάριο του 1899, ο βρετανικοί 
μυθιστοριογράφος και ο ποιητής Rudyard Kipling έγραψαν ένα 
ποίημα που τιτλοφορήθηκε "άσπρο ανθρώπινο φορτίο: Οι 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες και τα φιλιππινέζικα νησιά." Σε αυτό το 
ποίημα, Kipling πίεσε τις ΗΠΑ για να λάβει το "φορτίο" της 
αυτοκρατορίας, όπως είχε τη Μεγάλη Βρετανία και άλλα ευρωπαϊκά
έθνη. Το Theodore Roosevelt, σύντομα για να γίνει 
αντιπρόεδρος και έπειτα Πρόεδρος, αντέγραψε το ποίημα και το 
έστειλε στο φίλο του, γερουσιαστής Henry Cabot Lodge, που 
σχολιάζει ότι ήταν "μάλλον φτωχή ποίηση, αλλά καλή αίσθηση 
από την άποψη επέκτασης." Όχι ο καθένας ήταν όπως 
ευνοϊκά εντυπωσιάζεται. Ο ποιητής Ernest Crosby 
περιέφραξε μια παρωδία της εργασίας Kipling, "το πραγματικό 
άσπρο ανθρώπινο φορτίο," και την δημοσίευσε στη συλλογή του 
1902 του ξιφών και Plowshares ποιημάτων. Το Crosby 
έγραψε επίσης ένα σατυρικό, αντι-ιμπεριαλιστικό μυθιστόρημα, 
καπετάνιος Jinks, ήρωας, ο οποίος διακωμώδησε τη σταδιοδρομία 
του στρατηγού Frederick Funston, το άτομο που είχε συλλάβει 
το φιλιππινέζικο ηγέτη Emilio Aguinaldo το 1901.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En febrero de 1899, el novelista y el poeta 
británicos Rudyard Kipling escribieron un poema titulado "la carga 
del hombre blanco: Los Estados Unidos y las islas filipinas." 
En este poema, Kipling impulsó los ESTADOS UNIDOS tomar la 
"carga" del imperio, como Gran Bretaña tenida y otras naciones 
europeas. Theodore Roosevelt, pronto sentir bien al vice 
presidente y entonces al presidente, copió el poema y lo envió a su 
amigo, senador Henry Cabot Lodge, comentando que era "poesía algo 
pobre, solamente buen sentido desde el punto de vista de la 
extensión." No cada uno estaba según lo impresionado 
favorable. El poeta Ernest Crosby encerró una parodiar del 
trabajo de Kipling, "la carga del hombre blanco verdadero," y la 
publicó en su colección 1902 de espadas y de rejas de arado de los 
poemas. Crosby también escribió un satírico, novela del 
contra-imperialista, capitán Jinks, el héroe, que parodió la 
carrera de general Frederick Funston, el hombre que había capturado a
arranque de cinta filipino Emilio Aguinaldo en 1901.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086047</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107985</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/crosby-on-kipling-a-parody-of-the-white-mans-burden</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
