<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104580</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104580</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209941</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Area of a triangle (conventional method)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bereich eines Dreiecks (herkömmliche Methode)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zone d'une triangle (méthode conventionnelle)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Área de um triângulo (método convencional)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Zona di un triangolo (metodo convenzionale)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοχή ενός τριγώνου (συμβατική μέθοδος)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Área de un triángulo (método convencional)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that explain the area of a triangle. The applet shows a triangle that can be reshaped by dragging any vertex. As it changes, the area is continually recalculated using the 'half base times height' method. The triangle has a fixed square grid in its interior that can be used to visually estimate the area for later correlation with the calculated value. The calculation can be hidden while estimation is in progress. The text page has links to a similar page that uses Heron's Formula to compute the area. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die den Bereich eines Dreiecks erklären. Der applet 
zeigt ein Dreieck, das umgestaltet werden kann, indem man jeden 
möglichen Gipfel schleppt. Während er ändert, wird der 
Bereich fortwährend mit der ' halbe niedrige Zeithöhe ' Methode 
nachgerechnet. Das Dreieck hat ein örtlich festgelegtes 
quadratisches Rasterfeld in seinem Inneren, das benutzt werden kann, 
um den Bereich für neuere Wechselbeziehung mit dem errechneten Wert 
sichtlich zu schätzen. Die Berechnung kann versteckt werden, 
während Schätzung in Bewegung ist. Die Textseite hat Links zu 
einer ähnlichen Seite, die Formel des Reihers verwendet, um den 
Bereich zu berechnen. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für 
Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui expliquent la zone d'une triangle. L'applet montre une 
triangle qui peut être restructurée en traînant n'importe quel 
sommet. Pendant qu'il change, la zone est continuellement 
recalculée en utilisant la méthode de 'demi de taille de base de 
périodes '. La triangle a une grille carrée fixe dans son 
intérieur qui peut être employé pour estimer visuellement la zone 
pour la corrélation postérieure avec la valeur calculée. Le 
calcul peut être caché tandis que l'évaluation est en marche. 
La page des textes a des liens à une page semblable qui emploie
la formule du héron pour calculer la zone. L'applet peut être 
agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur 
de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de 
classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
expliquem a área de um triângulo. O applet mostra um 
triângulo que possa reshaped arrastando todo o vertex. Enquanto
muda, a área recalculated continuamente usando ' o método da meia 
altura baixa das épocas '. O triângulo tem uma grade quadrada 
fixa em seu interior que pode ser usado estimar visualmente a área 
para uma correlação mais atrasada com o valor calculado. O 
cálculo pode ser escondido quando o estimation for em andamento. 
A página do texto tem as ligações a uma página similar que 
use a fórmula do heron computar a área. O applet pode ser 
ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala 
de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode 
alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca 
com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um 
componente do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da 
referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
spiegano la zona di un triangolo. Il applet mostra un triangolo 
che può essere rimodellato trascinando tutto il vertice. Mentre
cambia, la zona è ricalcolata continuamente usando 'il metodo di 
altezza bassa mezza di periodi '. Il triangolo ha una griglia 
quadrata fissa nel relativo interiore che può essere usato per 
valutare visivamente la zona per correlazione successiva con il valore
calcolato. Il calcolo può essere nascosto mentre la valutazione
è in progresso. La pagina del testo ha collegamenti ad una 
pagina simile che usa la formula del heron per computare la zona. 
Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per
uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione 
nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel 
paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. 
Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del 
manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
εξηγούν την περιοχή ενός τριγώνου. Το applet εμφανίζει 
ένα τρίγωνο που μπορεί να αναδιαμορφωθεί με το σύρσιμο 
οποιουδήποτε vertex. Δεδομένου ότι αλλάζει, η περιοχή 
υπολογίζεται εκ νέου συνεχώς χρησιμοποιώντας τη μέθοδο "μισού 
ύψους βάσεων χρονικού". Το τρίγωνο έχει ένα σταθερό 
τετραγωνικό πλέγμα στο εσωτερικό του που μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί
για να υπολογίσει οπτικά την περιοχή για τον πιό πρόσφατο 
συσχετισμό με την υπολογισμένη αξία. Ο υπολογισμός μπορεί 
να κρυφτεί ενώ η εκτίμηση είναι υπό εξέλιξη. Η σελίδα 
κειμένων έχει τις συνδέσεις με μια παρόμοια σελίδα που 
χρησιμοποιεί τον τύπο του ερωδιού για να υπολογίσει την περιοχή. 
Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης
για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση 
στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
explican el área de un triángulo. El applet muestra un 
triángulo que pueda ser restructurado arrastrando cualquier cima. 
Mientras que cambia, el área se recalcula continuamente usando 
el método de la ' media altura baja de las épocas '. El 
triángulo tiene una rejilla cuadrada fija en su interior que se pueda
utilizar para estimar visualmente el área para una correlación más 
última con el valor calculado. El cálculo puede ser ocultado 
mientras que la valoración está en marcha. La paginación del 
texto tiene conexiones a una paginación similar que utilice el 
fórmula del heron para computar el área. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209941</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104580</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/area-of-a-triangle-conventional-method</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
