<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/3935201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>3935201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203559</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Jurassic Park Debate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jurapark-Debatte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Discussion Jurassique de Parc</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Debate Jurassic Do Parque</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dibattito Jurassic Del Parco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Jurassic συζήτηση πάρκων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Discusión Jurásico Del Parque</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This role-playing exercise casts students as scientific specialists, assigned to a group either supporting or opposing the cloning of dinosaurs. There are 4-6 specialists (or groups of specialists): geneticists, ecologists, etc., on each side. Each side researches for a couple of weeks and presents its argument in class (usually a single class period for each side), and other students can ask the specialists questions. Each student also turns in two pages summarizing his/her arguments as a specialist the day of the presentation. The material provided by the professor for research includes information about cloning technology and about dinosaurs. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Rolle spielendes Übung wirft Kursteilnehmer 
als wissenschaftliche Fachleute, zugewiesen einer Gruppe entweder, die
das Klonen der Dinosauriere unterstützt oder entgegensetzt. Es 
gibt 4-6 Fachleute (oder Gruppen Fachleute): Genetiker, 
Ökologen, etc., auf jeder Seite. Jede Seite erforscht für ein 
Paar von Wochen und stellt sein Argument in der Kategorie 
(normalerweise eine einzelne Kategorie Periode für jede Seite) dar, 
und andere Kursteilnehmer können den Fachleuten Fragen stellen. 
Jeder Kursteilnehmer dreht auch sich in zwei Seiten, die 
seine/ihr Argumente als Fachmann der Tag der Darstellung 
zusammenfassen. Das Material stellte vom Professor für 
Forschung einschließt Informationen über Klonentechnologie und über
Dinosauriere zur Verfügung. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite 
können Benutzer auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung,
Kontext für Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und 
Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen 
zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice jouant un rôle moule des étudiants 
en tant que spécialistes scientifiques, affectés à un groupe 
supportant ou s'opposant au clonage des dinosaurs. Il y a 4-6 
spécialistes (ou groupes de spécialistes) : généticiens, 
écologistes, etc., de chaque côté. Chaque côté recherche 
pour un couple des semaines et présente son argument dans la classe 
(habituellement une seule période de classe pour chaque côté), et 
d'autres étudiants peuvent poser aux spécialistes des questions. 
Chaque étudiant tourne également en deux pages récapitulant 
ses arguments en tant que spécialiste le jour de la présentation. 
Le matériel a fourni par le professeur pour la recherche inclut
des informations au sujet de technologie de clonage et sur des 
dinosaurs. À cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs 
peuvent accéder aux informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice,
contexte pour les extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes
et, le matériel didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les 
références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício role-playing molda estudantes como
os specialists científicos, atribuídos a um grupo que suporta ou que
opõe o cloning dos dinosaurs. Há 4-6 specialists (ou grupos 
dos specialists): geneticists, ecólogos, etc., em cada lado. 
Cada lado pesquisa para um par das semanas e apresenta seu 
argumento na classe (geralmente um único período da classe para cada
lado), e outros estudantes podem fazer aos specialists perguntas. 
Cada estudante gira também em duas páginas que sumariam 
his/her argumentos como um specialist o dia da apresentação. O
material forneceu pelo professor para a pesquisa inclui a informação
sobre a tecnologia do cloning e sobre dinosaurs. Nesta página 
do ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre 
os objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do
uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da 
avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione d'atteggiamento lancia gli 
allievi come esperti scientifici, assegnati ad un gruppo che sostiene 
o che oppone la clonazione dei dinosaurs. Ci sono 4-6 esperti (o
gruppi degli esperti): genetisti, ecologi, ecc., da ogni lato. 
Ogni lato ricerca per una coppia delle settimane e presenta il 
relativo argomento nel codice categoria (solitamente un singolo 
periodo del codice categoria per ogni lato) ed altri allievi possono 
fare agli esperti le domande. Ogni allievo egualmente gira in 
due pagine che ricapitolano i suoi argomenti come esperto il giorno 
della presentazione. Il materiale ha fornito dal professore per 
ricerca include le informazioni su tecnologia della clonazione e sui 
dinosaurs. A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti 
possono accedere alle informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti 
dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di istruzione, di uso note 
e, i materiali didattici, le idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i 
soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ρόλος-παίζοντας άσκηση πετά τους σπουδαστές 
ως επιστημονικούς ειδικούς, που διορίζονται σε μια ομάδα είτε που
υποστηρίζει είτε που αντιτάσσει την κλωνοποίηση των δεινοσαύρων. 
Υπάρχουν 4-6 ειδικοί (ή ομάδες ειδικών): 
γενετησιολόγοι, οικολόγοι, κ.λπ., σε κάθε πλευρά. 
Κάθε οι δευτερεύουσες έρευνες για μερικές εβδομάδες και 
παρουσιάζουν το όρισμά της στην κλάση (συνήθως μια ενιαία 
περίοδος κλάσης για κάθε πλευρά), και άλλοι σπουδαστές μπορούν 
να υποβάλουν τις ειδικές ερωτήσεις. Κάθε σπουδαστής 
γυρίζει επίσης σε δύο σελίδες που συνοψίζουν τα ορίσματά 
του/της ως ειδικό η ημέρα της παρουσίασης. Το υλικό που 
παρέχεται από τον καθηγητή για την έρευνα περιλαμβάνει τις 
πληροφορίες για την τεχνολογία κλωνοποίησης και για τους 
δεινοσαύρους. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες 
μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους 
εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και 
τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες 
αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio de actuación de papeles echa a 
estudiantes como especialistas científicos, asignados a un grupo que 
utiliza o que opone la reproducción de dinosaurios. Hay 4-6 
especialistas (o grupos de especialistas): genetistas, 
ecologistas, etc., en cada cara. Cada cara investiga para un par
de semanas y presenta su argumento en la clase (generalmente un solo 
período de la clase para cada cara), y otros estudiantes pueden hacer
a los especialistas preguntas. Cada estudiante también da 
vuelta en dos paginaciones que resumen su argumentos como especialista
el día de la presentación. El material proporcionó por el 
profesor para la investigación incluye la información sobre 
tecnología de la reproducción y sobre dinosaurios. En esta 
paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso
a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto
para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los 
materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los 
asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CONSTANCE SOJA
FN:CONSTANCE SOJA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DEBORAH HUERTA
FN:DEBORAH HUERTA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203559</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>3935201</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/jurassic-park-debate</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
