<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106852</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106852</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086854</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Stiff upper lip.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Steife obere Lippe.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lèvre supérieure raide.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bordo superior duro.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Labbro superiore rigido.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δύσκαμπτο ανώτερο χείλι.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Labio superior derecho.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Rather than call for the creation of federal relief programs, this 1931 advertisement placed by the President's Organization on Unemployment Relief opts for local voluntary charity as a response to the Great Depression. President Herbert Hoover firmly believed that relief was a local responsibility, although even this step, which proved inadequate, went further than pre-World War I presidents, who stood by passively during financial panics. Few Americans expected the government to take drastic action when the Depression struck. Many turned instead to their employers, merchants, churches, landlords, and local banks, as well as to family networks, for assistance. As the Depression and unemployment deepened, however, it became clear that the moral capitalism" of marketplace institutions was drastically inadequate and aggressive government action was needed."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anstatt entscheidet Aufruf für die Kreation der 
Bundesentlastung Programme, diese Reklameanzeige 1931, die von 
Organization des Präsidenten auf Arbeitslosigkeit Entlastung plaziert
wird, für lokale freiwillige Nächstenliebe als Antwort zum großen 
Tiefstand. Präsident Herbert Hoover glaubte fest, daß 
Entlastung eine lokale Verantwortlichkeit war, obgleich sogar dieser 
Jobstep, der unzulängliches prüfte, weiter als Präsidenten des 
VorWeltkrieges I, die passiv während finanziellen bereitstanden, in 
Panik versetzt ging. Wenige Amerikaner erwarteten die Regierung,
um drastische Maßnahmen zu ergreifen, als der Tiefstand anschlug. 
Viele wendeten anstatt an ihre Arbeitgeber, Kaufleute, Kirchen, 
Hauswirte und örtliche Banken, sowie zu Familie Netzen, für 
Unterstützung. Da der Tiefstand und die Arbeitslosigkeit, die, 
jedoch vertieft wurde, es frei wurde, daß der moralische Kapitalismus
"der Marktanstalten drastisch unzulänglich war und konkurrenzfähige 
Regierung Tätigkeit war erforderlich."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plutôt que l'appel pour la création des programmes 
fédéraux de soulagement, cette publicité 1931 placée par 
Organization du Président sur le soulagement du chômage opte pour la
charité volontaire locale comme réponse à la grande dépression. 
Le Président Herbert Hoover a fermement cru que le soulagement 
était une responsabilité locale, bien que même cette étape, qui a 
prouvé insatisfaisant, ait disparu plus loin que les présidents de 
la guerre I de pré-Monde, qui se sont tenus prêt passivement pendant
le financier panique. Peu d'Américains se sont attendus à ce 
que le gouvernement prenne une mesure énergique quand la dépression 
a frappé. Beaucoup se sont tournés à la place vers leurs 
employeurs, les négociants, églises, propriétaires, et banques 
locales, aussi bien qu'à des réseaux de famille, pour l'aide. 
Car la dépression et le chômage approfondi, cependant, il est 
apparue clairement que le capitalisme moral "des établissements de 
marché était rigoureusement insatisfaisant et l'action agressive de 
gouvernement était nécessaire."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Melhor que o atendimento para a criação de programas 
federais do relevo, esta propaganda 1931 colocada por Organização do
presidente no relevo do desemprego opts para o charity voluntário 
local como uma resposta ao depression grande. O presidente 
Herbert Hoover acreditou firmemente que o relevo era uma 
responsabilidade local, embora mesmo esta etapa, que provou 
inadequado, fosse mais mais do que os presidentes da guerra I do 
pre-Mundo, que estiveram perto passiva durante financeiro se 
apavorasse. Poucos americanos esperaram o governo fazer exame da
ação drástica quando o depression golpeou. Muitos giraram 
preferivelmente para seus empregadores, comerciantes, igrejas, 
landlords, e bancos locais, as.well.as para redes da família, para o 
auxílio. Porque o depression e desemprego aprofundado, 
entretanto, ele se tornou desobstruído que o capitalismo moral "de 
instituições do marketplace era dràstica inadequado e a ação 
aggressive do governo era needed."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Piuttosto che la richiesta per la creazione dei programmi 
federali di rilievo, questa pubblicità 1931 disposta 
dall'Organization del presidente su rilievo di disoccupazione opta per
la carità volontaria locale come risposta alla depressione grande. 
Il presidente Herbert Hoover ha ritenuto saldamente che il 
rilievo fosse una responsabilità locale, anche se persino questo 
punto, che ha dimostrato inadeguato, è andato più ulteriormente dei 
presidenti di guerra I del pre-Mondo, che hanno fatto una pausa 
passivamente durante il finanziario si lascia prendere dal panico. 
Pochi Americani hanno invitare il governo per intraprendere 
l'azione drastica quando la depressione ha colpito. Molti si 
sono girati preferibilmente verso i loro datori di lavoro, 
commercianti, chiese, proprietari e banca locale, così come 
verso le reti della famiglia, per assistenza. Poichè la 
depressione e disoccupazione approfondita, tuttavia, esso è essere 
evidente che il capitalismo morale "delle istituzioni del mercato era 
drasticamente inadeguato e l'azione aggressiva di governo era 
necessaria."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρά να απαιτηθεί η δημιουργία των ομοσπονδιακών 
προγραμμάτων ανακούφισης, αυτή η διαφήμιση του 1931 που 
τοποθετείται από την οργάνωση του Προέδρου στην ανακούφιση 
ανεργίας επιλέγει την τοπική εθελοντική φιλανθρωπία ως απάντηση 
στη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση. Ο Πρόεδρος Herbert Hoover
σταθερά εθεώρησε ότι η ανακούφιση ήταν μια τοπική ευθύνη, αν 
και ακόμη και αυτό το βήμα, που αποδείχθηκε ανεπαρκές, πήγε 
περαιτέρω από τον προ-παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι Πρόεδροι, οι οποίοι 
ανέμειναν παθητικά κατά τη διάρκεια του οικονομικού panics. 
Λίγοι Αμερικανοί ανέμειναν την κυβέρνηση για να λάβουν 
δραστικά μέτρα όταν χτύπησε η κατάθλιψη. Πολλοί γύρισαν 
αντ' αυτού στους εργοδότες, τους εμπόρους, τις εκκλησίες, τους 
ιδιοκτήτες, και τις τοπικές τράπεζές τους, καθώς επίσης και στα 
οικογενειακά δίκτυα, για τη βοήθεια. Δεδομένου ότι η 
κατάθλιψη και η ανεργία εμβάθυναν, εντούτοις, έγινε σαφές ότι η
ηθική κεφαλαιοκρατία "των οργάνων αγορών ήταν δραστικά 
ανεπαρκής και η επιθετική κυβερνητική ενέργεια απαιτήθηκε."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Más bien que la llamada para la creación de los 
programas federales de la relevación, este anuncio 1931 colocado por 
Organization del presidente en la relevación del desempleo opta por 
caridad voluntaria local como respuesta a la gran depresión. 
Presidente Herberto Hoover creyó firmemente que la relevación 
era una responsabilidad local, aunque incluso fue se atierra este paso
de progresión, que probó inadecuado, más lejos que los presidentes 
de la guerra I del pre-Mundo, que hicieron una pausa pasivo durante 
financiero. Pocos americanos esperaron que el gobierno tomara la
acción drástica cuando la depresión pulso. Muchos dieron 
vuelta en lugar de otro a sus patrones, comerciantes, iglesias, 
propietarios, y baterías locales, así como a redes de la familia, 
para la ayuda. Pues la depresión y desempleo profundizado, sin 
embargo, él llegó a estar clara que el capitalismo moral "de las 
instituciones del mercado era drástico inadecuado y la acción 
agresiva del gobierno era necesaria."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086854</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106852</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/stiff-upper-lip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
