<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106279</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106279</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086459</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Manifest Destiny, Continued: McKinley Defends U.S. Expansionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Offenkundiges Schicksal, Fortgesetzt: 
McKinley Verteidigt VEREINIGTE STAATEN Expansionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Destin Manifeste, Continué : McKinley 
Défend les ETATS-UNIS Expansionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Destiny Manifesto, Continuado: McKinley 
Defende ESTADOS UNIDOS Expansionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Destino Manifesto, Continuato: McKinley 
Difende gli STATI UNITI Expansionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προφανές πεπρωμένο, συνεχιζόμενο: McKinley 
υπερασπίζει τις ΗΠΑ Expansionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Destino Manifesto, Continuado: McKinley 
Defiende ESTADOS UNIDOS Expansionism</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1899 Americans divided sharply over whether to annex the Philippines. Annexationists and anti-annexationists, despite their differences, generally agreed that the U.S. needed opportunities for commercial expansion but disagreed over how to achieve that goal. Few believed that the Philippines themselves offered a crucial commercial advantage to the U.S., but many saw them as a crucial way station to Asia. _Had we no interests in China,? noted one advocate of annexation, _the possession of the Philippines would be meaningless.? In the Paris Peace negotiations, President William McKinley demanded the Philippines to avoid giving them back to Spain or allowing a third power to take them. One explanation of his reasoning came from this report of a delegation of Methodist church leaders. The emphasis on McKinley's religious inspiration for his imperialist commitments may have been colored by the religious beliefs of General James Rusling. But Rusling's account of the islands, falling unbidden on the U.S., and the arguments for taking the islands reflect McKinley's official correspondence on the topic. McKinley disingenuously disavowed the U.S. military action that brought the Philippines under U.S. control, and acknowledged, directly and indirectly, the equally powerful forces of racism, nationalism, and especially commercialism, that shaped American actions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf 1899 Amerikaner teilte scharf Überschuß, ob 
man die Philippinen eingliedert. Annexionisten und 
Anti-Annexionisten, trotz ihrer Unterschiede, im Allgemeinen stimmten 
zu, daß die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN Gelegenheiten für kommerzielle 
Expansion benötigten, aberWAREN Überschuß anderer Meinung, wie man 
dieses Ziel erzielt. Wenige glaubten, daß die Philippinen 
selbst einen entscheidenden kommerziellen Vorteil in die VEREINIGTEN 
STAATEN anboten, aber viele sahen sie als entscheidende Methode 
Station nach Asien. _ hatte uns keine Interessen an China? 
beachtet einem Fürsprecher der Annexion, _ der Besitz der 
Philippinen würde sein bedeutungslos? In den Paris 
Friedensvermittlungen verlangte Präsident William McKinley die 
Philippinen, um sie, zurück zu Spanien zu geben oder eine dritte 
Energie zu erlauben zu vermeiden, sie zu nehmen. Eine Erklärung
seiner Argumentation kam von diesem Report einer Delegation der 
Führer der methodistischen Kirche. Das Hauptgewicht auf 
McKinleys frommer Inspiration für seine imperialist Verpflichtungen 
kann durch den frommen Glauben des Generals James Rusling gefärbt 
worden sein. Aber Konto Ruslings der Inseln, fallend unbidden 
auf den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, und die Argumente für das Nehmen der 
Inseln reflektieren McKinleys amtliche Korrespondenz auf dem Thema. 
McKinley leugnete disingenuously die VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
militärische Tätigkeit, die die Philippinen unter VEREINIGTE STAATEN
Steuerung holte, ab und bestätigte, direkt und indirekt, die 
gleichmäßig leistungsfähigen Kräfte von Rassismus, Nationalismus 
und besonders Geschäftsgeist, der amerikanische Tätigkeiten formte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1899 Américains a divisé brusquement 
l'excédent si annexer les Philippines. Les annexionnistes et 
les anti-annexionnistes, en dépit de leurs différences, ont 
généralement convenu que les ETATS-UNIS ont eu besoin des occasions 
pour l'expansion commerciale mais étaient en désaccord excédent 
comment réaliser ce but. Peu ont cru que les Philippines 
elles-mêmes ont offert un avantage commercial crucial aux ETATS-UNIS,
mais beaucoup les ont vus comme station cruciale de voie en Asie. 
_ nous a eus aucuns intérêts en Chine ? remarquable un avocat 
d'annexation, _ la possession des Philippines serait sans 
signification ? Dans les négociations de paix de Paris, le 
Président William McKinley a exigé les Philippines pour éviter de 
les donner de nouveau à l'Espagne ou de permettre une troisième 
puissance de les prendre. Une explication de son raisonnement 
est venue de cet état d'une délégation des amorces d'église 
méthodiste. L'emphase sur l'inspiration religieuse de McKinley 
pour ses engagements impérialistes a pu avoir été colorée par la 
croyance religieuse de James général Rusling. Mais le 
compte de Rusling des îles, tombant unbidden sur les ETATS-UNIS, et 
les arguments pour prendre les îles reflètent la correspondance 
officielle de McKinley sur le sujet. McKinley a sans franchise 
désavoué l'action militaire des ETATS-UNIS qui a apporté les 
Philippines sous la commande des ETATS-UNIS, et l'a reconnu, 
directement et indirectement, les forces également puissantes du 
racisme, nationalisme, et particulièrement mercantilisme commercial, 
qui a formé des actions américaines.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1899 americanos dividiu agudamente o excesso se
anexar as Filipinas. Os annexationists e os 
anti-anti-annexationists, apesar de suas diferenças, geralmente 
concordaram que os ESTADOS UNIDOS necessitaram oportunidades para a 
expansão comercial mas discordaram excesso como conseguir esse 
objetivo. Poucos acreditaram que as Filipinas elas mesmas 
ofereceram uma vantagem comercial crucial aos ESTADOS UNIDOS, mas 
muitas viram-nos como uma estação crucial da maneira a Ásia. 
_ teve-nos nenhuns interesses em China? notável um advogado do 
annexation, _ a possessão das Filipinas seria sem sentido? Nas 
negociações da paz de Paris, o presidente William McKinley exijiu as
Filipinas evitar de dá-las para trás a Spain ou de permitir uma 
terceira potência fazer exame d. Uma explanação de seu 
raciocínio veio deste relatório de um delegation de líderes da 
igreja methodist. A ênfase na inspiração religiosa de 
McKinley para seus compromissos imperialist pode ter sido colorida 
pela opinião religiosa do general James Rusling. Mas o cliente 
de Rusling dos consoles, caindo unbidden nos ESTADOS UNIDOS, e os 
argumentos para fazer exame dos consoles refletem a correspondência 
oficial de McKinley no tópico. McKinley disavowed 
disingenuously a ação militar de ESTADOS UNIDOS que trouxe as 
Filipinas sob o controle de ESTADOS UNIDOS, e reconheceu-a, 
diretamente e indiretamente, as forças ingualmente poderosas do 
racism, nationalism, e especial commercialism, que deu forma a ações
americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1899 Americani ha diviso acutamente l'eccedenza
se annettere le Filippine. I annexationists ed i 
anti-anti-annexationists, malgrado le loro differenze, generalmente 
hanno accosentito che gli STATI UNITI hanno avuto bisogno delle 
occasioni per espansione commerciale ma sono non stato d'accordo 
eccedenza come realizzare quell'obiettivo. Pochi hanno creduto 
che le Filippine essi stessi offrissero un vantaggio commerciale 
cruciale negli STATI UNITI, ma molte li hanno visti come stazione 
cruciale di modo in Asia. _ li ha avuti nessun interessi in 
Cina? celebre un fautore del annexation, _ il possesso delle Filippine
sarebbe insignificante? Nelle trattative di pace de Parigi, il 
presidente William McKinley ha richiesto le Filippine per evitare di 
darle di nuovo alla Spagna o permettere una terza potenza prenderle. 
Una spiegazione del suo ragionamento è venuto da questo 
rapporto di una delegazione dei capi della chiesa methodist. 
L'enfasi su ispirazione religiosa del McKinley per i suoi 
impegni imperialist può essere colorata dalla credenza religiosa del 
General James Rusling. Ma il cliente del Rusling delle isole, 
cadendo unbidden sugli STATI UNITI e gli argomenti per la presa delle 
isole riflettono la corrispondenza ufficiale del McKinley sul 
soggetto. McKinley ha disconosciuto disingenuously l'azione 
militare degli STATI UNITI che ha sottoposto le Filippine a controllo 
degli STATI UNITI ed ha riconosciuto, direttamente ed indirettamente, 
le forze ugualmente potenti del razzismo, nazionalismo e 
particolarmente spirito commerciale, che ha modellato le azioni 
americane.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1899 Αμερικανοί διαίρεσαν αισθητά πέρα από εάν
για να προσαρτήσουν τις Φιλιππίνες. Το Annexationists και 
τα αντι- annexationists, παρά τις διαφορές τους, γενικά 
συμφώνησαν ότι οι ΗΠΑ χρειάστηκαν τις ευκαιρίες για την εμπορική 
επέκταση αλλά διαφώνησαν πέρα από το πώς να επιτύχουν εκείνο 
τον στόχο. Λίγοι εθεώρησαν ότι οι Φιλιππίνες οι ίδιοι 
πρόσφεραν ένα κρίσιμο εμπορικό πλεονέκτημα στις ΗΠΑ, αλλά 
πολλές τα εβλέίδαν ως κρίσιμο σταθμό τρόπων στην Ασία. 
_ Δεν μας είχε κανένα ενδιαφέρον για την Κίνα,; σημείωσε 
έναν συνήγορο της προσάρτησης, _ η κατοχή των Φιλιππινών θα ήταν
χωρίς νόημα; Στις διαπραγματεύσεις ειρήνης του Παρισιού, ο 
Πρόεδρος William McKinley απαίτησε τις Φιλιππίνες για να 
αποφύγει τις πίσω στην Ισπανία ή μια τρίτη δύναμη να τις πάρει.
Μια εξήγηση του συλλογισμού του προήλθε από αυτήν την 
έκθεση μιας αντιπροσωπείας των μεθοδιστών ηγετών εκκλησιών. 
Η έμφαση στη θρησκευτική έμπνευση McKinley's για τις 
ιμπεριαλιστικές υποχρεώσεις του μπορεί να είχε χρωματιστεί από 
τις θρησκευτικές πεποιθήσεις του στρατηγού james Rusling. 
Αλλά ο απολογισμός Rusling των νησιών, πτώση στις ΗΠΑ, 
και τα ορίσματα για τη λήψη των νησιών απεικονίζουν την επίσημη 
αλληλογραφία McKinley's στο θέμα. McKinley ηποκήρυξε 
υποκριτικά την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ στρατιωτική ενέργεια που έθεσε τις 
Φιλιππίνες υπό ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ έλεγχο, και αναγνώρισε, άμεσα και 
έμμεσα, τις εξίσου ισχυρές δυνάμεις του ρατσισμού, του 
εθνικισμού, και ειδικά του μερκαντιλισμού, οι οποίες διαμόρφωσαν 
τις αμερικανικές ενέργειες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1899 americanos dividió sostenidamente el 
excedente si anexar las Filipinas. Los annexationists y los 
contra-anti-annexationists, a pesar de sus diferencias, convinieron 
que los ESTADOS UNIDOS necesitaron las oportunidades para la 
extensión comercial pero discreparon generalmente excedente cómo 
alcanzar esa meta. Pocos creyeron que las Filipinas ellos mismos
ofrecieron una ventaja comercial crucial a los ESTADOS UNIDOS, pero 
muchas los vieron como estación crucial de la manera a Asia. ¿_
nos tenía ningunos intereses en China? observado un abogado de la 
anexión, _ la posesión de las Filipinas sería sin setido? En 
las negociaciones de la paz de París, presidente Guillermo McKinley 
exigió las Filipinas para evitar de darlas de nuevo a España o de 
permitir una tercera potencia de tomarlas. Una explicación de 
su razonamiento vino de este informe de una delegación de los 
arranques de cinta de la iglesia methodist. El énfasis en la 
inspiración religiosa de McKinley para sus consolidaciones 
imperialistas se pudo haber coloreado por la creencia religiosa de 
general James Rusling. Pero la cuenta de Rusling de las islas, 
cayendo unbidden en los ESTADOS UNIDOS, y los argumentos para tomar 
las islas reflejan la correspondencia oficial de McKinley en el 
asunto. McKinley rechazó falsamente la acción militar de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS que trajo las Filipinas bajo control de ESTADOS UNIDOS,
y la reconoció, directamente e indirectamente, las fuerzas igualmente
de gran alcance del racismo, nacionalismo, y especialmente la 
comercialización, que formó acciones americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086459</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106279</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/manifest-destiny-continued-mckinley-defends-u-s-expansionism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
