<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108033</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108033</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086104</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dubbing Debs: An Actor Records a Speech by Eugene Debs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachsynchronisation Debs: Ein Schauspieler 
speichert eine Rede durch Eugene Debs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Doublage Debs : Un acteur enregistre un 
discours par Eugene Debs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dubbing Debs: Um ator grava um discurso por 
Eugene Debs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Doppiatura Debs: Un attore registra un 
discorso da Eugene Debs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταγλώττιση Debs: Ένας δράστης καταγράφει 
μια ομιλία από Eugene Debs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Doblaje Debs: Un agente registra un discurso
de Eugene Debs</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Socialist leader and four-time presidential candidate Eugene V. Debs was known as one of the most gifted orators of his generation. One listener recalled his impact as "something more powerful, penetrating, and articulate than mere words." Although Debs apparently never entered a sound studio, a recording of a Debs speech was widely circulated in the first decade of the 20th century. For many years, the speech was believed to have been in Debs' voice, and it was catalogued as such in libraries and record collections. In fact, the speech was written by Debs but recorded by actor Leonard Spencer, who was famous for his recorded versions of comic and dramatic monologues. It was not uncommon in the early days of recording to have actors read the words of politicians. (This was before actors  became  politicians.) Even if this recording does not give us Debs' actual voice, its circulation indicates his popularity. Faithful socialists wanted to be able to listen at home to Debs' attacks on the rapacious nature of capitalism and his argument that socialism was the only answer to human problems.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialistischer Führer und Vierzeit 
Präsidentenanwärter Eugene V. Debs bekannt als einer der begabtesten
Redner seines Erzeugung. Ein Zuhörer erinnerte an seine 
Auswirkung als "etwas, das leistungsfähiger ist und drang ein, und 
artikuliert als bloße Wörter." Obgleich Debs anscheinend nie 
ein stichhaltiges Studio kam, wurde eine Aufnahme einer Debs Rede weit
in der ersten Dekade des 20. Jahrhunderts verteilt. Für viele 
Jahre wurde die Rede geglaubt, in der Stimme Debs' gewesen zu sein, 
und sie wurde als solcher in den Bibliotheken und in den 
Satzansammlungen Katalogisiert. Tatsächlich wurde die Rede 
geschrieben, von Debs aber gespeichert vom Schauspieler Leonard 
Spencer, der für seine gespeicherten Versionen der komischen und 
drastischen Monologe berühmt war. Es war nicht an den frühen 
Tagen des Speicherns zum Lassen Schauspieler die Wörter der Politiker
lesen selten. (dieses war, bevor Schauspieler Politiker. wurden)
Selbst wenn diese Aufnahme uns Debs' tatsächliche Stimme nicht 
gibt, zeigt seine Zirkulation seine Popularität an. 
Zuverlässige Sozialisten wollten können, zu den Angriffen 
Debs' auf der rapacious Natur von Kapitalismus und von seinem Argument
zu Hause zu hören, daß sozialismus die einzige Antwort zu den 
menschlichen Problemen war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'amorce socialiste et le candidat présidentiel 
Eugene V. Debs de quatre-temps ont été connus en tant qu'un des 
orateurs les plus doués de sa génération. Un auditeur a 
rappelé son impact en tant que "quelque chose plus puissante, 
pénétrant, et articule que de seuls mots." Bien que Debs ne 
soit apparent jamais entré dans un studio sain, un enregistrement 
d'un discours de Debs a été largement distribué dans la première 
décennie du 20ème siècle. Pendant beaucoup d'années, on a 
pensé que le discours est dans la voix de Debs, et il a été 
catalogué en tant que tels dans les bibliothèques et les collections
d'enregistrement. En fait, le discours a été écrit par Debs 
mais enregistré par l'acteur Leonard Spencer, qui était célèbre
pour ses versions enregistrées des monologues comiques et excessifs.
Il n'était pas rare en jours tôt de l'enregistrement pour 
faire lire à des acteurs les mots des politiciens. (c'était 
avant que les acteurs soient devenus des politiciens.) Même si 
cet enregistrement ne nous donne pas la voix réelle de Debs, sa 
circulation indique sa popularité. Les socialistes fidèles ont
voulu pouvoir écouter à la maison les attaques de Debs sur la nature
rapace du capitalisme et de son argument que le socialisme était la 
seule réponse aux problèmes humains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O líder socialist e o candidato presidencial 
Eugene V. Debs do quatro-tempo foram sabidos como um dos orators os 
mais gifted de sua geração. Um ouvinte recordou seu impacto 
como "algo mais poderoso, penetrando, e articula-o do que meras 
palavras." Embora Debs aparentemente nunca entrasse em um 
estúdio sadio, uma gravação de um discurso de Debs foi circulada 
extensamente na primeira década do 20o século. Por muitos 
anos, o discurso foi acreditado para ter estado na voz de Debs', e foi
catalogado como esta'n nas bibliotecas e nas coleções do registro. 
No fato, o discurso foi escrito por Debs mas gravado pelo ator 
Leonard Spencer, que era famoso para suas versões gravadas de 
monologues comic e dramáticos. Não era uncommon nos dias 
adiantados da gravação para mandar atores ler as palavras dos 
políticos. (isto era antes que os atores se transformarem 
políticos.) Mesmo se esta gravação não nos dá a voz real de
Debs', sua circulação indica sua popularidade. Os socialists 
fiéis quiseram poder  escutar na HOME ataques de Debs' na natureza 
rapacious do capitalismo e do seu argumento que o socialismo era a 
única resposta aos problemas humanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il capo socialista ed il candidato 
presidenziale Eugene V. Debs di quattro-tempo sono stati conosciuti 
come uno dei orators più dotati della sua generazione. Un 
ascoltatore ha ricordato il suo effetto come "qualcosa più potente, 
penetrando ed articola che le parole pure." Anche se Debs non ha
entrato apparentemente mai in un studio sano, una registrazione di un 
discorso di Debs ampiamente è stata distribuita nella prima decade 
del ventesimo secolo. Per molti anni, il discorso si è creduto 
per essere nella voce del Debs ed è stato catalogato come tali in 
librerie e nelle collezioni del record. Infatti, il discorso è 
stato scritto da Debs ma è stato registrato dall'attore Leonard 
Spencer, che era famoso per le sue versioni registrate dei monologues 
comic e drammatici. Non era raro nei giorni in anticipo di 
registrazione per fare leggere agli attori le parole dei politici. 
(questo era prima che gli attori diventino politici.) 
Anche se questa registrazione ci non dà la voce reale del Debs,
la relativa circolazione indica la sua popolarità. I socialisti
fedeli hanno desiderato potere ascoltare nel paese gli attacchi del 
Debs alla natura rapacious del capitalismo e del suo argomento che il 
socialism era l'unica risposta ai problemi umani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σοσιαλιστικός ηγέτης και ο τέσσερις-χρονικός 
προεδρικός υποψήφιος Eugene Θ*Β. Debs ήταν γνωστός ως ένας 
από τους πιό ταλαντούχους ομιλητές της γενεάς του. Ένας 
ακροατής υπενθύμισε τον αντίκτυπό του ως "κάτι ισχυρότερο, που 
διαπερνά, και ευκρινής από τις μόνες λέξεις." Αν και 
Debs προφανώς δεν εισήγαγε ποτέ ένα υγιές στούντιο, μια 
καταγραφή μιας ομιλίας Debs κυκλοφόρησαν ευρέως στην πρώτη 
δεκαετία του 20ού αιώνα. Για πολλά έτη, η ομιλία 
θεωρήθηκε στη φωνή Debs, και καταχωρήθηκε υπό αυτήν τη μορφή 
στις βιβλιοθήκες και τις συλλογές αρχείων. Στην 
πραγματικότητα, η ομιλία γράφτηκε από Debs αλλά καταγράφηκε 
από το ιστίο Leonard δραστών, το οποίο ήταν διάσημο για τις 
καταγραμμένες εκδόσεις κωμικών και δραματικών μονολόγων του. 
Δεν ήταν ασυνήθιστο τις πρώτες ημέρες της καταγραφής να 
υπάρξουν οι δράστες να διαβάσουν τις λέξεις των πολιτικών. 
(Αυτό ήταν προτού οι δράστες να γίνουν πολιτικοί.) 
Ακόμα κι αν αυτή η καταγραφή δεν μας δίνει την πραγματική 
φωνή Debs, η κυκλοφορία της δείχνει τη δημοτικότητά του. 
Οι πιστοί σοσιαλιστές θέλησαν να είναι σε θέση να ακούσουν
στο σπίτι τις επιθέσεις Debs στην αρπακτική φύση της 
κεφαλαιοκρατίας και του ορίσματός του ότι ο σοσιαλισμός ήταν η 
μόνη απάντηση στα ανθρώπινα προβλήματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Conocían al arranque de cinta socialista y al 
candidato presidencial Eugene V. Debs del cuatro-tiempo como uno de 
los oradores más dotados de su generación. Un módulo de 
escucha recordó su impacto como "algo más de gran alcance, 
penetrando, y articula que palabras meras." Aunque Debs al 
parecer nunca entró en un estudio de los sonidos, una grabación de 
un discurso de Debs fue circulada extensamente en la primera década 
del vigésimo siglo. Por muchos años, el discurso fue creído 
para haber estado en la voz de Debs, y fue catalogado como tal en 
bibliotecas y colecciones del expediente. En hecho, el discurso 
fue escrito por Debs pero registrado por el agente Leonard Spencer, 
que era famoso por sus versiones registradas de monólogos cómicos y 
dramáticos. No era infrecuente en los días tempranos de la 
registración para hacer que los agentes lean las palabras de 
políticos. (esto era antes de que los agentes hicieron 
políticos.) Incluso si esta grabación no nos da la voz real de
Debs, su circulación indica su renombre. Los socialistas fieles
desearon poder escuchar en el país los ataques de Debs contra la 
naturaleza rapaz del capitalismo y de su argumento que el socialismo 
era la única respuesta a los problemas humanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086104</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108033</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dubbing-debs-an-actor-records-a-speech-by-eugene-debs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
