<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108187</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108187</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200782</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Calibrated Peer Review: Discovering Dinosaurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalibrierte Gleiche Zusammenfassung: 
Entdecken Der Dinosauriere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Examen par les pairs Calibré : Découvrir 
Des Dinosaurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Revisão De Par Calibrada: Descobrindo 
Dinosaurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rassegna Di Pari Calibrata: Scoperta Dei 
Dinosaurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βαθμολογημένη όμοια αναθεώρηση: Ανακάλυψη των 
δεινοσαύρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Revisión De Par Calibrada: Descubrir 
Dinosaurios</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, students write an essay on the history of scientific discoveries in the field of dinosaur paleontology. The essays are then evaluated via Calibrated Peer Review. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität schreiben Kursteilnehmer 
einen Versuch auf die Geschichte der wissenschaftlichen Entdeckungen 
in auffangene von Dinosaurierpaläontologie. Die Versuche 
werden dann über kalibrierte Gleiche Zusammenfassung ausgewertet. 
Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen
über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les étudiants écrivent un 
essai sur l'histoire des découvertes scientifiques dans le domaine de
la paléontologie de dinosaur. Les essais sont alors évalués 
par l'intermédiaire de l'examen par les pairs calibré. À 
cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux 
informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les 
extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os estudantes escrevem um essay 
no history de descobertas científicas no campo do paleontology do 
dinosaur. Os essays são avaliados então através da revisão 
de par calibrada. Nesta página do ponto começar, os usuários 
podem alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do 
exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os 
materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as referências e os 
tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli allievi scrivono un 
saggio sulla storia delle scoperte scientifiche nel campo della 
paleontologia del dinosaur. I saggi allora sono valutati via la 
revisione di pari calibrata. A questa pagina del punto di 
partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sugli 
obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di 
istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le idee di 
valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές γράφουν ένα
δοκίμιο στην ιστορία των επιστημονικών ανακαλύψεων στον τομέα της
παλαιοντολογίας δεινοσαύρων. Τα δοκίμια αξιολογούνται 
έπειτα μέσω της βαθμολογημένης όμοιας αναθεώρησης. Σε 
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los estudiantes escriben un 
ensayo en la historia de descubrimientos científicos en el campo de 
la paleontología del dinosaurio. Los ensayos entonces se 
evalúan vía la revisión de par calibrada. En esta paginación
del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la 
información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para
las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales
didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos 
cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AMANDA PALMER-JULSON
FN:AMANDA PALMER-JULSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELIZABETH HEISE
FN:ELIZABETH HEISE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200782</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108187</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/calibrated-peer-review-discovering-dinosaurs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
