<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106353</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106353</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087073</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The War for Independence Through Seneca Eyes: Mary Jemison Views the Revolution, 1775-79</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Krieg für Unabhängigkeit durch Seneca-Augen:
Mary Jemison sieht die Umdrehung, 1775-79 an</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La guerre pour l'indépendance par des yeux de 
Seneca : Mary Jemison visualise la révolution, 1775-79</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A guerra para a independência através dos olhos 
do seneca: Mary Jemison vê a volta, 1775-79</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La guerra per indipendenza attraverso gli occhi 
del seneca: Mary Jemison osserva la rivoluzione, 1775-79</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πόλεμος για την ανεξαρτησία μέσω Σενέκα Eyes: 
Θ*Μαρυ Jemison Views η επανάσταση, 1775-79</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La guerra para la independencia a través de ojos 
del seneca: Maria Jemison visión la revolución, 1775-79</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The American Revolution divided Indian communities as well as Euro-American ones. Captured at the age of fifteen along the Pennsylvania frontier and adopted and integrated into a Seneca community, Mary Jemison watched the war through the eyes of a wife and mother. The Iroquois attempted to remain neutral in the conflict, and Jemison watched tribal leaders return from a meeting with Patriot colonists at German Flats, secure in their belief that Indian neutrality would be respected. Instead, the British sought to attract Iroquois support and four of the six Iroquois nations declared their allegiance to the crown. Soon, Seneca lands became a battleground and their fields were laid waste by the colonists' scorched earth tactics. Jemison described the ensuing destruction and disease in 1823 when she related her life story to James Seaver, a local doctor near her home among the Iroquois of western New York.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die amerikanische Umdrehung teilte indische 
Gemeinschaften sowie Euro-american eine. Erfaßt am Alter 
von fünfzehn entlang der Pennsylvania Grenze und angenommen und in 
eine Senecagemeinschaft integriert, überwachte Mary Jemison den Krieg
durch die Augen einer Frau und der Mutter. Der Irokese 
versuchte, in der $überschneidung Null zu bleiben, und Jemison 
überwachte Stammes- Führer, von einer Sitzung mit Patriotkolonisten 
an den deutschen Ebenen zurückzukommen, die in ihrem Glauben sicher 
sind, daß indische Neutralität respektiert würde. Stattdessen
suchten die Briten, Irokesesupport anzuziehen und vier der sechs 
Irokesenationen erklärten ihre Untertanentreue zur Krone. Bald 
wurden Senecaländer ein Schlachtfeld und ihr fängt waren 
gelegte Vergeudung durch die versengten Taktiken Masse der Kolonisten 
auf. Jemison beschrieb die folgende Zerstörung und die 
Krankheit 1823, als sie ihre Lebengeschichte auf James Seaver in 
Verbindung stand, einen lokalen Doktor nahe ihrem Haus unter dem 
Irokesen von Westnew York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La révolution américaine a divisé les 
communautés indiennes aussi bien que euro-american ceux. 
Capturé à l'âge de quinze le long de la frontière de la 
Pennsylvanie et adopté et intégré dans Seneca une communauté, 
Mary Jemison a observé la guerre par les yeux d'une épouse et d'une 
mère. Le Iroquois a essayé de rester neutre en conflit, et 
Jemison a observé les amorces tribales retourner d'une réunion avec 
des colons de patriote aux appartements allemands, bloqués dans leur 
croyance que la neutralité indienne serait respectée. Au lieu 
de cela, les Anglais ont recherché à attirer le support de Iroquois 
et quatre des six nations de Iroquois ont déclaré leur allégeance 
à la couronne. Bientôt, les terres de Seneca sont devenues
un champs de bataille et leurs zones étaient perte étendue par la 
tactique roussie de la terre des colons. Jemison a décrit la 
destruction et la maladie suivantes en 1823 quand elle a rapporté sa 
histoire de la vie à James Seaver, un docteur local près de sa 
maison parmi le Iroquois de New York occidental.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A volta americana dividiu comunidades indian 
as.well.as as Euro-Americanas. Capturado na idade de quinze ao 
longo da fronteira de Pensilvânia e adotado e integrado em uma 
comunidade do seneca, Mary Jemison prestou atenção à guerra 
através dos olhos de uma esposa e de uma matriz. O iroquois 
tentou remanescer neutro no conflito, e Jemison prestou atenção a 
líderes tribais retornar de uma reunião com os colonos do patriot 
nos planos alemães, seguros em sua opinião que o neutrality indian 
estaria respeitado. Instead, os Ingleses procuraram atrair a 
sustentação do iroquois e quatro das seis nações do iroquois 
declararam seu allegiance à coroa. Logo, as terras do seneca 
transformaram-se um battleground e seus campos eram desperdício 
colocado pelas táticas chamuscadas da terra dos colonos. 
Jemison descreveu a destruição e a doença seguindo em 1823 
quando relacionou sua história da vida a James Seaver, um doutor 
local perto de sua HOME entre o iroquois de New York ocidental.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La rivoluzione americana ha diviso le Comunità 
indiane così come euro-american un. Bloccato all'età di 
quindici lungo la frontiera della Pensilvania ed adottato ed integrato
in una Comunità del seneca, Mary Jemison ha guardato la guerra 
attraverso gli occhi di una moglie e di una madre. Il iroquois 
ha tentato di rimanere neutro in conflitto e Jemison ha guardato i 
capi tribali ritornare da una riunione con i colonizzatori del 
patriot agli appartamenti tedeschi, sicuri nella loro credenza che la 
neutralità indiana sarebbe rispettata. Invece, i Britannici 
hanno cercato di attrarre il supporto del iroquois e quattro delle sei
nazioni del iroquois hanno dichiarato il loro allegiance alla parte 
superiore. Presto, le terre del seneca si sono transformate in 
in un battleground ed i loro campi erano spreco posto dalle tattiche 
bruciacchiate della terra dei colonizzatori. Jemison ha 
descritto la distruzione e la malattia seguenti in 1823 quando ha 
riferito la sua storia di vita a James Seaver, un medico locale vicino
alla sua sede fra il iroquois di New York occidentale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αμερικανική επανάσταση διαίρεσε ινδικές 
ευρω-αμερικανικοί κοινοτήτων καθώς επίσης και. Συλλήφθείη 
στην ηλικία δεκαπέντε κατά μήκος των συνόρων της Πενσυλβανίας 
και υιοθετημένη και ενσωματωμένη σε μια κοινότητα Σενέκα, Mary 
Jemison πρόσεξε τον πόλεμο μέσω των ματιών μιας συζύγου και 
μιας μητέρας. Iroquois προσπάθησαν να παραμείνουν 
ουδέτεροι σε σύγκρουση, και Jemison πρόσεξε τη φυλετική 
επιστροφή ηγετών από μια συνεδρίαση με τους αποίκους πατριωτών 
στα γερμανικά επίπεδα, ασφαλή στην πεποίθησή τους ότι η ινδική 
ουδετερότητα θα γινόταν σεβόμενη. Αντ' αυτού, οι Βρετανοί 
επιδίωξαν να προσελκύσουν iroquois την υποστήριξη και τέσσερα 
από τα έξι iroquois έθνη δήλωσαν την υποταγή τους στην 
κορώνα. Σύντομα, τα εδάφη Σενέκα έγιναν ένα πεδίο μάχης 
και τα πεδία τους ήταν τοποθετημένα απόβλητα καψαλισμένη γήινη 
τακτική από των αποίκων ". Το Jemison περιέγραψε την 
επόμενες καταστροφή και την ασθένεια το 1823 όταν αφορούσε την
ιστορία ζωής της james Seaver, ένας τοπικός γιατρός κοντά 
στο σπίτι της μεταξύ iroquois της δυτικής Νέας Υόρκης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La revolución americana dividió a comunidades 
indias así como euro-american unos. Capturado en la edad de
quince a lo largo de la frontera de Pennsylvania y adoptado e 
integrado en una comunidad del seneca, Maria Jemison miró la guerra a
través de los ojos de una esposa y de una madre. El iroquois 
procuró seguir siendo neutral en el conflicto, y Jemison miró a 
arranques de cinta tribales volver de una reunión con los colonos del
patriota en los planos alemanes, seguros en su creencia que la 
neutralidad india sería respetada. En lugar, los Británicos 
intentaron atraer la ayuda del iroquois y cuatro de las seis naciones 
del iroquois declararon su lealtad a la corona. Pronto, las 
pistas del seneca se convirtieron en un campo de batalla y sus campos eran 
basura puesta por las táctica chamuscadas de la tierra de los 
colonos. Jemison describió la destrucción y la enfermedad que 
sobrevenían en 1823 cuando ella relacionó su historia de la vida con
James Seaver, doctor local cerca de su hogar entre el iroquois de 
Nueva York occidental.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087073</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106353</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-war-for-independence-through-seneca-eyes-mary-jemison-views-the-revolution-1775-79</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
