<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103243</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103243</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086133</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Everything Was Lively": David Hickman Describes the Prosperity Late Nineteenth-Century Railroads Brought to the West</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Alles War" Lebhaft: David Hickman 
beschreibt die Wohlstand späten 19.-Jahrhundert Eisenbahnen, die zum 
Westen geholt werden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Tout Était Animé" : David Hickman décrit 
les défunts chemins de fer de Dix-neuvième-Siècle de prospérité 
apportés à l'ouest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Tudo Era Vívido": David Hickman descreve as
estradas de ferro atrasadas de Décimo-Século da prosperidade 
trazidas ao oeste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Tutto Era Vivace": David Hickman descrive le
ferrovie ritardate di Diciannovesimo-Secolo di prosperità portate 
all'ovest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όλα ήταν ζωηρά": Δαβίδ Hickman Describes 
οι πρόσφατοι σιδηρόδρομοι δέκατος-αιώνα ευημερίας που 
παρουσιάζονται στη δύση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Todo Era Animado": David Hickman describe 
los últimos ferrocarriles del Diecinueveavo-Siglo de la prosperidad 
traídos al oeste</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The availability of rail connections often determined whether a western community would survive or die. The rails fostered prosperity by bringing both goods and people. This trade, and the local service industries that sprouted up to capitalize on the movement of people and goods, drove many local economies. Here, David Hickman talked about the boom years that followed the arrival of the railroad in the Latah County, Idaho town of Genesee in the 1880s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Verwendbarkeit der Bahnverbindungen stellte 
häufig fest, ob eine westliche Gemeinschaft überleben oder sterben 
würde. Die Schienen förderten Wohlstand, indem sie Waren und 
Leute holten. Dieser Handel und die lokale 
Dienstleistungsindustrie, die bis keimte, schreibt auf der Bewegung 
der Leute und der Waren, antrieben viele lokale Wirtschaftssysteme 
gross. Hier befaßte sich David Hickman mit den 
Hochkonjunkturjahren, die der Ankunft der Eisenbahn in der Latah 
Grafschaft folgten, Idaho Stadt von Genesee im 1880s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La disponibilité des connexions de rail a souvent
déterminé si une communauté occidentale survivrait ou mourrait. 
Les rails ont stimulé la prospérité en apportant des 
marchandises et des personnes. Ce commerce, et le secteur 
tertiaire local qui a poussé jusqu'à profitent de la circulation des
personnes et des marchandises, ont piloté beaucoup d'économies 
locales. Ici, David Hickman a parlé des années de perche qui 
ont suivi l'arrivée du chemin de fer dans le comté de Latah, ville 
de l'Idaho de Genesee dans le 1880s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A disponibilidade de conexões de trilho 
determinou frequentemente se uma comunidade ocidental sobreviveria ou 
morreria. Os trilhos promoveram a prosperidade trazendo  bens e 
povos. Este comércio, e as indústrias de serviço locais que 
sprouted até capitalize no movimento dos povos e dos bens, dirigiram 
muitas economias locais. Aqui, David Hickman falou sobre os anos
que seguiu a chegada da estrada de ferro no condado de Latah, cidade 
do crescimento de Idaho de Genesee no 1880s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La disponibilità dei collegamenti di guida ha 
determinato spesso se una Comunità occidentale sopravvivesse o 
morisse. Le rotaie hanno promosso la prosperità portando sia le
merci che la gente. Questo commercio ed il terziario locale che 
ha germogliato fino a capitalizzano sul movimento della gente e delle 
merci, hanno guidato molte economie locali. Qui, David Hickman 
ha parlato degli anni che hanno seguito l'arrivo della ferrovia nella 
contea di Latah, città dell'asta dell'Idaho di Genesee nel 1880s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαθεσιμότητα των συνδέσεων ραγών συχνά καθόρισε 
εάν μια δυτική κοινότητα θα επιζούσε ή θα πέθαινε. Οι 
ράγες ενθάρρυναν την ευημερία με να φέρουν και τα αγαθά και τους 
ανθρώπους. Αυτό το εμπόριο, και οι τοπικές βιομηχανίες 
υπηρεσιών που βλάστησαν μέχρι κεφαλαιοποιούν στην κυκλοφορία των 
ατόμων και τα αγαθά, οδήγησαν πολλές τοπικές οικονομίες. 
Εδώ, ο Δαβίδ Hickman μίλησε για τα έτη βραχιόνων που 
ακολούθησαν την άφιξη του σιδηροδρόμου στο Latah νομό, πόλη 
του Idaho Genesee στο 1880s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La disponibilidad de las conexiones de carril se 
determinó a menudo si una comunidad occidental sobreviviría o 
moriría. Los carriles fomentaron prosperidad trayendo 
mercancías y a gente. Este comercio, y las industrias de 
servicio locales que brotaron hasta capitalizan en el movimiento de la
gente y de mercancías, condujeron muchas economías locales. 
Aquí, David Hickman habló de los años que siguieron la 
llegada del ferrocarril en el condado de Latah, ciudad del auge de 
Idaho de Genesee en el 1880s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086133</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103243</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/everything-was-lively-david-hickman-describes-the-prosperity-late-nineteenth-century-railroads-brought-to-the-west</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
