<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103588</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103588</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204006</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Minerals Under the Microscope</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mineralien unter dem Mikroskop</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Minerais sous le microscope</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Minerais sob o microscópio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Minerali sotto il microscopio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταλλεύματα κάτω από το μικροσκόπιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Minerales bajo el microscopio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website provides an easy-to-understand introduction to the basics of optical mineralogy. Topics include the polarized light microscope, mineral shape and cleavage, relief, color and pleochroism, interference colors, extinction angles, twinning, opacity, vibration directions and mineral identification. The site features short, clear descriptions accompanied by photographs and drawings. This website would be useful as a concise introduction to the use of a petrographic microscope in identifying minerals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site stellt eine Einfach-zuverstehen 
Einleitung zu den Grundlagen der optischen Mineralogie zur Verfügung.
Themen enthalten das polarisierte helle Mikroskop, Mineraldie 
form und die Spaltung, die Entlastung, die Farbe und das pleochroism, 
die Störung Farben, die Löschungwinkel, twinning, die Opazität, die
Erschütterung Richtungen und das Mineralkennzeichen. Die 
Situationsmerkmale schließen, die freien Beschreibungen kurz, die von
den Fotographien begleitet werden und Zeichnungen. Diese Web 
site würde als kurze Einleitung zum Gebrauch eines petrographic 
Mikroskops nützlich sein, wenn man Mineralien kennzeichnete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web fournit une introduction de 
facile-à-compréhension aux fondations de la minéralogie optique. 
Les sujets incluent le photomicroscope polarisé, la forme et le
fendage minéral, le soulagement, la couleur et le pleochroism, les 
couleurs d'interférence, les angles d'extinction, le jumelage, 
l'opacité, les directions de vibration et l'identification minérale.
Les dispositifs de site court-circuitent, des descriptions 
claires accompagnées des photographies et des schémas. Ce site
Web serait utile comme introduction concise à l'utilisation d'un 
microscope pétrographique en identifiant des minerais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site fornece uma introdução da 
fácil-à-compreensão aos princípios do mineralogy ótico. Os 
tópicos incluem o microscópio claro polarizado, a forma e o cleavage
mineral, o relevo, a cor e o pleochroism, as cores da interferência, 
os ângulos da extinção, twinning, a opacidade, os sentidos da 
vibração e a identificação mineral. As características de 
local short, as descrições desobstruídas acompanhadas por 
fotografias e os desenhos. Este Web site seria útil como uma 
introdução concisa ao uso de um microscópio petrographic em 
identificar minerais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site fornisce un'introduzione di 
facile-$$$-CAP ai principi fondamentali della mineralogia ottica. 
I soggetti includono il microscopio chiaro polarizzato, la 
figura e la fenditura minerale, il rilievo, il colore ed il 
pleochroism, i colori di interferenza, gli angoli di estinzione, il 
gemellaggio, l'opacità, i sensi di vibrazione e l'identificazione 
minerale. Le caratteristiche di luogo mettono, descrizioni 
libere accompagnate dalle fotografie ed illustrazioni. Questo 
Web site sarebbe utile come introduzione concisa all'uso di un 
microscopio petrographic nell'identificare i minerali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος παρέχει ότι εύκολος-$$$-ΚΑΤΑΛΑΒΕΤΕ
την εισαγωγή στα βασικά της οπτικής ορυκτολογίας. Τα θέματα
περιλαμβάνουν το πολωμένο ελαφρύ μικροσκόπιο, την ορυκτό μορφή 
και το σχίσιμο, την ανακούφιση, το χρώμα και το pleochroism, τα 
χρώματα παρέμβασης, τις γωνίες εξάλειψης, το ζευγάρωμα, την 
αδιαφάνεια, τις κατευθύνσεις δόνησης και τον ορυκτό προσδιορισμό.
Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις σύντομες, σαφείς περιγραφές που 
συνοδεύονται από τις φωτογραφίες και τα σχέδια. Αυτός ο 
ιστοχώρος θα ήταν χρήσιμος ως συνοπτική εισαγωγή στη χρήση ενός
petrographic μικροσκοπίου στον προσδιορισμό των μεταλλευμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site proporciona a una introducción del 
fa'cil-a-entender a los fundamentos de la mineralogía óptica. 
Los asuntos incluyen el microscopio ligero polarizado, la 
dimensión de una variable y la hendidura mineral, la relevación, el 
color y el pleochroism, los colores de interferencia, los ángulos de 
la extinción, el hermanar, la opacidad, las direcciones de la 
vibración y la identificación mineral. Las características de
sitio ponen en cortocircuito, las descripciones claras acompañadas 
por las fotografías y los gráficos. Este Web site sería útil
como introducción sucinta al uso de un microscopio petrographic en 
identificar los minerales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CHARLOTTE GLADSTONE
FN:CHARLOTTE GLADSTONE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204006</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103588</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/minerals-under-the-microscope</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
