<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104839</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104839</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203939</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Microbes in Action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mikroben in der Tätigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Microbes dans l'action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Micróbios na ação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Microbi nell'azione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μικρόβια στην ενέργεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Microbios en la acción</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This web site is a product of the Microbes in Action program, which serves to promote an understanding and appreciation of the importance of microorganisms in our world. The program provides scientific information and hands-on activities in microbiology to K-12 teachers via curriculum units, workshops, a newsletter, and this web site. Materials available on this site include: classroom activities, articles and news; techniques and troubleshooting; resources for cultures, media, chemicals, supplies, and equipment; and links to helpful microbiology-related websites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site ist ein Produkt der Mikroben im 
Tätigkeit Programm, das dient, ein Verständnis und eine Anerkennung 
des Wertes der Mikroorganismen in unserer Welt zu fördern. Das 
Programm stellt Fachinformation und Blindeinschub Aktivitäten in der 
Mikrobiologie zu den Lehrern K-12 über Lehrplanmaßeinheiten, 
Werkstätten, ein Rundschreiben und diese Web site zur Verfügung. 
Die Materialien, die auf dieser Site vorhanden sind, schließen 
ein: Klassenzimmeraktivitäten, -artikel und -nachrichten; 
Techniken und Fehlersuche; Betriebsmittel für Kulturen, 
Media, Chemikalien, Zubehör und Ausrüstung; und Links zu den 
nützlichen Mikrobiologie-in Verbindung stehenden Web site.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web est un produit des microbes dans le 
programme d'action, qui sert à favoriser un arrangement et une 
appréciation d'importance des micro-organismes en notre monde. 
Le programme fournit l'information scientifique et les 
activités à commande manuelle en microbiologie aux professeurs K-12 
par l'intermédiaire des unités de programme d'études, des ateliers,
d'un bulletin, et de ce site Web. Les matériaux disponibles sur
ce site incluent : activités, articles et nouvelles de salle de
classe ; techniques et dépannage ; ressources pour des 
cultures, des medias, des produits chimiques, des approvisionnements, 
et le matériel ; et liens aux sites Web microbiologie-connexes 
utiles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site é um produto dos micróbios no 
programa de ação, que serve promover uma compreensão e uma 
apreciação da importância dos microorganisms em nosso mundo. 
O programa fornece a informação científica e atividades 
hands-on no microbiology aos professores K-12 através das unidades do
curriculum, das oficinas, de um boletim de notícias, e deste Web 
site. Os materiais disponíveis neste local incluem: 
atividades, artigos e notícia da sala de aula; técnicas 
e pesquisa de defeitos; recursos para culturas, media, produtos 
químicos, fontes, e equipamento; e ligações aos Web site 
microbiology-relacionados úteis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site è un prodotto dei microbi nel 
programma di azione, che serve a promuovere una comprensione e un 
apprezzamento dell'importanza dei microorganismi in nostro mondo. 
Il programma fornisce l'informazione scientifica e le attività 
hands-on in microbiologia agli insegnanti K-12 via le unità di 
programma di studi, i workshop, un bollettino e questo Web site. 
I materiali disponibili su questo luogo includono: 
attività, articoli e notizie dell'aula; tecniche ed 
effettuare un analisi guasti; risorse per le colture, i media, i
prodotti chimici, i rifornimenti e le attrezzature; e 
collegamenti ai Web site microbiologia-relativi utili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος είναι ένα προϊόν των μικροβίων 
στο πρόγραμμα δράσης, το οποίο χρησιμεύει να προωθήσει μια 
κατανόηση και μια εκτίμηση σπουδαιότητας των μικροοργανισμών στον 
κόσμο μας. Το πρόγραμμα παρέχει τις επιστημονικές 
πληροφορίες και τις εμπράγματες δραστηριότητες στη μικροβιολογία 
σε Κ- 12 δασκάλους μέσω των μονάδων προγράμματος σπουδών, τα 
εργαστήρια, ένα ενημερωτικό δελτίο, και αυτόν τον ιστοχώρο. 
Τα υλικά διαθέσιμα σε αυτήν την περιοχή περιλαμβάνουν: 
δραστηριότητες, άρθρα και ειδήσεις τάξεων  τεχνικές 
και ανίχνευση λαθών  στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς για τους 
πολιτισμούς, τα μέσα, τις χημικές ουσίες, τις προμήθειες, και τον
εξοπλισμό  και συνδέσεις με τους χρήσιμους 
μικροβιολογία-σχετικούς ιστοχώρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site es un producto de los microbios en 
el programa de acción, que sirve para promover una comprensión y un 
aprecio de la importancia de microorganismos en nuestro mundo. 
El programa proporciona a la información científica y a 
actividades con manos en microbiología a los profesores K-12 vía 
unidades del plan de estudios, talleres, un boletín de noticias, y 
este Web site. Los materiales disponibles en este sitio 
incluyen: actividades, artículos y noticias de la sala de 
clase; técnicas y localización de averías; recursos 
para las culturas, los media, los productos químicos, las fuentes, y 
el equipo; y conexiones a los Web site 
microbiologi'a-relacionados provechosos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SCIENCE IN THE REAL WORLD: MICROBES IN ACTION PROGRAM
FN:SCIENCE IN THE REAL WORLD: MICROBES IN ACTION PROGRAM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI - ST LOUIS
FN:UNIVERSITY OF MISSOURI - ST LOUIS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203939</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104839</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/microbes-in-action</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
