<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106473</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106473</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Took Great Store of Codfish and Called it Cape Cod:" Bartholomew Gosnold Sails Along Northeastern North America, 1602</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir nahmen großen Speicher der Kabeljaus und 
nannten ihn Cape Cod:" Bartholomew Gosnold Segel Entlang 
Nordöstlichem Nordamerika, 1602</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous avons pris le grand stock de morues et 
l'avons appelé morue de cap :" Bartholomew Gosnold Navigue Le 
long de l'Amérique du nord du nord-est, 1602</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós fizemos exame da loja grande dos bacalhaus e
chamamo-la bacalhau de cape:" Sails De Bartholomew Gosnold Ao 
longo De America do Norte Do nordeste, 1602</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"abbiamo preso il deposito grande dei merluzzi e 
lo abbiamo chiamato merluzzo di cape:" Vele Di Bartholomew 
Gosnold Lungo L'America del Nord Di nordest, 1602</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πήραμε το μεγάλο κατάστημα των μπακαλιάρων και το 
καλέσαμε βακαλάο ακρωτηρίων:" Πανιά Gosnold 
Bartholomew κατά μήκος της βορειοανατολικής Βόρειας Αμερικής, 
1602</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tomamos el gran almacén de bacalaos y lo 
llamamos bacalao de cabo:" Velas De Bartholomew Gosnold A lo 
largo De Norteamérica Del noreste, 1602</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Compared to the French, Spanish, and Dutch, the English were slow to develop an interest in North American colonization By the later part of the sixteenth century, however, a group of interested and well-connected Englishmen with experience in Irish colonization began to consider permanent settlements in North America. Bartholomew Gosnold undertook a small prospecting expedition on the vessel  Concord  in 1602, passing down the coasts of Maine and Massachusetts to explore the northern Virginia coast. Gosnold was the first European to see and set foot on Cape Cod--which received its name for its abundance of cod fish--and built a small fur trading station there. The successful voyage enticed English colonization efforts to turn toward this part of North America. Four years later, Gosnold commanded a voyage to bring the first colonists to Jamestown, Virginia. Several accounts of the 1602 prospecting expedition quickly appeared in print.; this complete one was first published by Samuel Purchas in 1625.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verglichen mit dem französischen, spanisch und 
holländisch, war Englisch langsam, ein Interesse an der 
nordamerikanischen Besiedlung durch das neuere Teil des sechzehnten 
Jahrhunderts zu entwickeln, jedoch fing eine Gruppe interessierte und 
gut-verbundene Engländer mit Erfahrung in der irischen Besiedlung an,
permanente Regelungen in Nordamerika zu betrachten. Bartholomew 
Gosnold nahm sich eine kleine prospektierenexpedition auf der 
Behälter Übereinstimmung 1602 auf und überschritt hinunter die 
Küsten von Maine und von Massachusetts, um die Nordvirginia Küste zu
erforschen. Gosnold war der erste Europäer, zum des Fusses auf 
Cape Cod zu sehen und einzustellen -- das seinen Namen für seinen 
Überfluß an den Kabeljaufischen empfing -- und dort aufgebaut einer 
handelnden Station des kleinen Pelzes. Die erfolgreiche Reise 
verleitete englische Besiedlungbemühungen, sich in Richtung zu diesem
Teil von Nordamerika zu drehen. Vier Jahre später, beherrschte 
Gosnold eine Reise, um die ersten Kolonisten zu holen Jamestown, 
Virginia. Einige Konten der 1602 prospektierenexpedition 
erschienen schnell im Druck; dieses komplette man wurde zuerst 
von Samuel Purchas 1625 veröffentlicht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comparé au français, espagnol, et hollandais, 
les anglais étaient lents pour développer un intérêt pour la 
colonisation américaine du nord par la partie postérieure du 
seizième siècle, cependant, un groupe d'Anglais intéressés et 
bien-reliés avec l'expérience de la colonisation irlandaise a 
commencé à considérer des règlements permanents en Amérique 
du nord. Bartholomew Gosnold a entrepris une petite 
expédition de prospection sur l'accord de navire en 1602, passant en 
bas des côtes du Maine et du Massachusetts pour explorer la côte 
nordique de la Virginie. Gosnold était le premier Européen 
pour voir et placer le pied sur la morue de cap -- qui a reçu son nom
pour son abondance de poissons de morue -- et construit une station 
marchande de petite fourrure là. Le voyage réussi a attiré 
des efforts anglais de colonisation de tourner vers la présente 
partie de l'Amérique du nord. Quatre ans après, Gosnold a
commandé un voyage pour apporter les premiers colons à Jamestown, le
Virginie. Plusieurs comptes en 1602 expéditions de prospection 
sont rapidement apparus dans la copie ; celui-ci complet a été
édité la première fois par Samuel Purchas en 1625.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comparado ao francês, espanhol, e holandês, os 
ingleses eram lentos desenvolver um interesse na colonização 
norte-americana pela parte mais atrasada do décimo sexto século, 
entretanto, um grupo de ingleses interessados e bem-conectados com 
experiência na colonização irish começou a considerar 
estabelecimentos permanentes em America do Norte. Bartholomew 
Gosnold empreendeu uma expedição prospecting pequena no concord da 
embarcação em 1602, passando abaixo as costas de Maine e de 
Massachusetts para explorar a costa do norte de Virgínia. 
Gosnold era o primeiro europeu para ver e ajustar o pé no 
bacalhau de cape -- que recebeu seu nome para sua abundância de 
peixes do bacalhau -- e construído uma estação negociando da pele 
pequena lá. A viagem bem sucedida seduziu esforços ingleses da
colonização girar para esta parte de America do Norte. Quatro 
anos mais tarde, Gosnold comandou uma viagem para trazer os primeiros 
colonos a Jamestown, Virgínia. Diversos clientes das 1602 
expedições prospecting apareceram rapidamente na cópia; este 
completo foi publicado primeiramente por Samuel Purchas em 1625.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Confrontato al francese, spagnolo ed olandese, gli
inglesi erano lenti sviluppare un interesse nella colonizzazione 
nordamericana dalla parte successiva del sedicesimo secolo, tuttavia, 
un gruppo degli inglesi interessati e bene-collegati con esperienza di
colonizzazione irlandese ha cominciato a considerare gli stabilimenti 
permanente in America del Nord. Bartholomew Gosnold ha 
intrapreso una piccola spedizione di ricerca sull'accordo del vaso in 
1602, passando giù i litorali della Maine e di Massachusetts per 
esplorare il litorale nordico della Virginia. Gosnold era il 
primo europeo per vedere e regolare il piede sul merluzzo di cape -- 
che ha ricevuto il relativo nome per la relativa abbondanza dei pesci 
del merluzzo -- e costruito una stazione commerciale della piccola 
pelliccia là. Il viaggio riuscito ha attratto gli sforzi 
inglesi di colonizzazione girare verso questa zona dell'America del 
Nord. Quattro anni più successivamente, Gosnold ha comandato un
viaggio per portare i primi colonizzatori a Jamestown, la Virginia. 
Parecchi clienti delle 1602 spedizioni di ricerca sono comparso 
rapidamente in stampa; questo completo in primo luogo è stato 
pubblicato da Samuel Purchas in 1625.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έναντι στους Γάλλους, τον Ισπανό, και τους Ολλανδούς, 
οι Αγγλοι ήταν αργοί να αναπτύξουν ένα ενδιαφέρον για τη 
βορειοαμερικανική αποίκιση από το πιό πρόσφατο μέρος του 
δέκατου έκτου αιώνα, εντούτοις, μια ομάδα ενδιαφερόμενων και 
καλά-συνδεμένων Αγγλων με την εμπειρία στην ιρλανδική αποίκιση 
άρχισαν να εξετάζουν τις μόνιμες τακτοποιήσεις στη Βόρεια 
Αμερική. Το Bartholomew Gosnold ανέλαβε μια μικρή 
αποστολή έρευνας στη συμφωνία σκαφών το 1602, που περνά κάτω 
από τις ακτές του Maine και της Μασαχουσέτης για να εξερευνήσει
τη βόρεια ακτή της Βιρτζίνια. Το Gosnold ήταν ο πρώτος 
Ευρωπαίος για να δει και να θέσει το πόδι στο βακαλάο 
ακρωτηρίων -- που έλαβε το όνομά του για την αφθονία του ψαριών 
βακαλάων -- και έχτισε έναν μικρό σταθμό εμπορικών συναλλαγών 
γουνών εκεί. Το επιτυχές ταξίδι προσέλκυσε τις αγγλικές 
προσπάθειες αποίκισης να γυρίσει προς αυτό το μέρος της Βόρειας 
Αμερικής. Τέσσερα έτη αργότερα, Gosnold διέταξε ένα 
ταξίδι για να φέρει τους πρώτους αποίκους σε Jamestown, 
Βιρτζίνια. Διάφοροι απολογισμοί της αποστολής έρευνας 
1602 εμφανίστηκαν γρήγορα στην τυπωμένη ύλη  αυτός ο 
πλήρης ένας δημοσιεύθηκε αρχικά από το Samuel Purchas το 
1625.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comparado al francés, español, y holandés, los 
ingleses eran lentos desarrollar un interés en la colonización 
norteamericana por la parte más última del décimosexto siglo, sin 
embargo, un grupo de ingleses interesados y bien-conectados con 
experiencia en la colonización irlandesa comenzó a considerar 
establecimientos permanentes en Norteamérica. Bartholomew 
Gosnold emprendió a expedición de prospección pequeña en la 
concordia del recipiente en 1602, pasando abajo de las costas de Maine
y de Massachusetts para explorar la costa norteña de Virginia. 
Gosnold era el primer europeo para ver y para fijar el pie en el
bacalao de cabo -- que recibió su nombre para su abundancia de 
pescados del bacalao -- y construido una estación que negociaba de la
piel pequeña allí. El viaje acertado tentó esfuerzos ingleses
de la colonización de dar vuelta hacia esta parte de Norteamérica. 
Cuatro años más tarde, Gosnold ordenó a un viaje que trajera 
a primeros colonos a Jamestown, Virginia. Varias cuentas de las 
1602 expediciones de prospección aparecieron rápidamente en la 
impresión; éste completo primero fue publicado por Samuel 
Purchas en 1625.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106473</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-took-great-store-of-codfish-and-called-it-cape-cod-bartholomew-gosnold-sails-along-northeastern-north-america-1602</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
