<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107747</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107747</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086350</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Was a Mournful Scene Indeed": Solomon Northrup Remembers the New Orleans Slave Market</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es war eine traurige Szene in der Tat": 
Solomon Northrup erinnert sich den an New-Orleans Sklavenmarkt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"c'était une scène triste en effet" : 
Solomon Northrup se rappelle le marché Slave de la 
Nouvelle-Orléans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"era uma cena mournful certamente": Solomon 
Northrup recorda o mercado slave de Nova Orleães</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"era una scena mournful effettivamente": 
Solomon Northrup si ricorda del mercato slave de New Orleans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ήταν μια λυπημένη σκηνή πράγματι": Το 
Solomon Northrup θυμάται την αγορά σκλάβων της Νέας 
Ορλεάνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"era una escena mournful de hecho": Solomon 
Northrup recuerda el mercado auxiliar de New Orleans</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The slave auction was one of the most barbaric practices of the harsh system of slavery. The slave trade within the United States destroyed families and tore apart communities, especially after 1840 when slavery was extended into the newer lands of the lower South and Southwest. Planters in the older settled areas of the upper South could realize substantial profits selling enslaved people, and New Orleans became the center of the trade. The resulting forced migration involved hundreds of thousands of African Americans. Some moved with their masters, but the migration also tore apart slave families residing on different plantations. Others were sold on the block, as Solomon Northrup described in his  Twelve Years a Slave. Narrative of Solomon, a Citizen of New-York, Kidnapped in Washington City in 1841.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Sklave versteigern war einer der 
barbarischesten Praxis des rauhen Systems der Sklaverei. Der 
Sklavenhandel innerhalb der Vereinigte Staaten zerstörten Familien 
und riß Gemeinschaften, besonders nach 1840 auseinander, als 
Sklaverei in die neueren Länder des niedrigeren Südens und des 
Südwestens ausgedehnt war. Pflanzer in den älteren 
vereinbarten Bereichen des oberen Südens konnten die erheblichen 
Profite verwirklichen, die versklavte Leute verkaufen, und New-Orleans
wurde die Mitte des Handels. Das Resultieren erzwang Migration 
mit einbezogene Hunderte Tausenden der afrikanischen Amerikaner. 
Einige, die mit ihren Meistern, aber verschoben wurden, die 
Migration rissen auch die Sklavenfamilien auseinander, die auf 
unterschiedlichen Plantagen sich befinden. Andere wurden auf dem
Block, als Solomon Northrup verkauft, das in seinen zwölf Jahren ein 
Sklave beschrieben wurde. Darstellung von Solomon, ein Bürger 
von New York, entführt in Washington Stadt 1841.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'enchère slave était l'une des pratiques
les plus barbares du système dur de l'esclavage. Le commerce 
slave chez les familles détruites par Etats-Unis et a déchiré
les communautés, particulièrement après 1840 où l'esclavage était
étendu dans les terres plus nouvelles des Sud et du 
sud-ouest inférieurs. Les planteurs dans les zones arrangées 
plus anciennes des Sud supérieurs pourraient réaliser des 
bénéfices substantiels vendant les personnes asservies, et la 
Nouvelle-Orléans est devenue le centre du commerce. Résulter a
forcé des centaines de milliers impliquées par transfert 
d'Américains africains. Certains déplacés avec leurs 
maîtres, mais le transfert ont également déchiré les familles 
slaves résidant sur différentes plantations. D'autres 
ont été vendus sur le bloc, comme Solomon Northrup décrit en ses 
douze années un Slave. Récit de Solomon, un citoyen de 
New York, enlevé dans la ville de Washington en 1841.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O auction slave era uma das práticas as mais 
barbaric do sistema áspero do slavery. O comércio slave dentro
das famílias destruídas estados unidas e rasgou comunidades 
separadas, especial após 1840 em que o slavery era prolongado nas 
terras mais novas do sul e do sudoeste mais baixos. Os 
plantadores nas áreas estabelecidas mais velhas do sul superior 
poderiam realizar os lucros substanciais que vendem povos enslaved, e 
Nova Orleães transformou-se o centro do comércio. Resultar 
forçou centenas envolvidas migração dos milhares de americanos 
africanos. Alguns movidos com seus mestres, mas a migração 
rasgaram também as famílias slave separadas que residem em 
plantações diferentes. Outros foram vendidos no bloco, como 
Solomon Northrup descrito em seus doze anos um escravo. 
Narrativa de Solomon, um cidadão de New York, sequestrado na 
cidade de Washington em 1841.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'asta slave era una delle pratiche più barbaric 
del sistema duro di slavery. Il commercio slave all'interno del 
unito Dichiara le famiglie distrutte ed ha staccato le 
Comunità, particolarmente dopo 1840 in cui lo slavery era esteso 
nelle più nuove terre del sud e del sud-ovest più bassi. Le 
piantatrici nelle più vecchie zone depositate del sud superiore 
potrebbero realizzare i profitti notevoli che vendono la gente 
asservita e New Orleans si è transformata in nel centro del 
commercio. Risultare ha forzato le centinaia dei migliaia in 
causa espansione degli Americani africani. Alcuni spostati con i
loro supervisori, ma l'espansione egualmente hanno staccato le 
famiglie slave che risiedono sulle piantagioni differenti. Altri
sono stati venduti sul blocco, come Solomon Northrup descritto durante
i suoi dodici anni uno schiavo. Descrizione di Solomon, un 
cittadino di New York, rapinato nella città de Washington in 1841.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η δημοπρασία σκλάβων ήταν μια από τις πιό βαρβαρικές
πρακτικές του σκληρού συστήματος της σκλαβιάς. Το εμπόριο 
σκλάβων μέσα στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες κατέστρεψε τις οικογένειες 
και ξέσκισε τις κοινότητες, ειδικά μετά από 1840 όταν 
επεκτάθηκε η σκλαβιά νεώτερα έδαφος του χαμηλότερων νότου και 
του νοτιοδυτικού σημείου. Οι καλλιεργητές στους παλαιότερους
εγκατεστημένους τομείς του ανώτερου νότου θα μπορούσαν να 
πραγματοποιήσουν τα ουσιαστικά κέρδη πωλώντας τους υποδουλωμένους
ανθρώπους, και η Νέα Ορλεάνη έγινε το κέντρο του εμπορίου. 
Η κατάληξη ανάγκασε περιληφθείσες τις μετανάστευση 
εκατοντάδες χιλιάδες αφρικανικών Αμερικανών. Μερικοί 
κινήθηκαν με τους κυρίους τους, αλλά η μετανάστευση ξέσκισε 
επίσης τις οικογένειες σκλάβων που κατοικούν στις διαφορετικές 
φυτείες. Αλλοι πωλήθηκαν στην ομάδα δεδομένων, ως 
Solomon Northrup που περιγράφηκε σε δώδεκα έτη του έναν 
σκλάβο. Αφήγημα Solomon, ένας πολίτης της νέος-Υόρκης, 
που απάγεται στην πόλη της Ουάσιγκτον το 1841.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La subasta auxiliar era una de las prácticas más
barbáricas del sistema áspero de la esclavitud. El comercio 
auxiliar dentro de las familias destruidas Estados Unidos y rompió en
dos a comunidades, especialmente después de 1840 en que la esclavitud
era extendida en las pistas más nuevas del sur y del sudoeste más 
bajos. Los plantadores en las más viejas áreas colocadas del 
sur superior podrían realizar los beneficios substanciales que 
vendían a gente esclavizada, y New Orleans se convirtió en el centro
del comercio. El resultar forzó centenares implicados 
migración de millares de americanos africanos. Algunos movidos 
con sus amos, pero la migración también rompieron en dos a familias 
auxiliares que residían en diversas plantaciones. Otros fueron 
vendidos en el bloque, como Solomon Northrup descrito en sus doce 
años un esclavo. Narrativa de Solomon, ciudadano de Nueva York,
Secuestrado en la ciudad de Washington en 1841.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086350</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107747</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-was-a-mournful-scene-indeed-solomon-northrup-remembers-the-new-orleans-slave-market</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
