<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107193</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107193</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086659</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Natural and Inalienable Right to Freedom": Slaves 'Petition for Freedom to the Massachusetts Legislature, 1777.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"natürliches und unübertragbares Recht zur 
Freiheit": Sklaven ' Petition für Freiheit zur Massachusetts 
Gesetzgebung, 1777.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"droite normale et inaliénable à la liberté" : 
Pétition d'esclaves 'pour la liberté à la législature du 
Massachusetts, 1777.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"direita natural e inalienable à liberdade": 
Petição dos escravos ' para a liberdade à legislatura de 
Massachusetts, 1777.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"destra naturale ed inalienabile a libertà": 
Petizione degli schiavi 'per libertà alla legislatura del 
Massachusetts, 1777.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Φυσικό και αναφαίρετο δικαίωμα στην ελευθερία": 
Αίτηση σκλάβων "για την ελευθερία στο νομοθετικό σώμα της 
Μασαχουσέτης, 1777.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la derecha natural e inalienable a la libertad": 
Petición de los esclavos ' para la libertad a la legislatura de
Massachusetts, 1777.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The colonists 'revolutionary struggle against British political authority also raised issues about equality and human rights at home. Enslaved people throughout the colonies seized upon the rhetoric of liberty and equality to point out the contradiction of fighting Great Britain over principles not fully followed by the colonies themselves; they also appealed to Christian precepts. Scores of petitions flooded the newly established state legislatures. This one, submitted to the Massachusetts General Court in 1777, linked the cause of American freedom with the struggle of African Americans for liberty. Several lawsuits seeking freedom were successful. When Quok Walker sued for his freedom and back wages in 1781, the Massachusetts Chief Justice ruled that his enslavement violated the new state constitution's statement that "men are born free and Equal." His case effectively ended slavery in Massachusetts and other New England states.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Revolutionärer Kampf der Kolonisten ' gegen britische 
politische Berechtigung auch angehobene Ausgaben über Gleichheit und 
menschliche Rechte zu Hause. Versklavte Leute in den Kolonien 
ergriffen nach der Rhetorik der Freiheit und der Gleichheit, um den 
Widerspruch des Kämpfens von von Großbritannien über den 
Grundregeln zu unterstreichen nicht völlig gefolgt von den Kolonien 
selbst; sie gefielen auch christlichen Geboten. Kerben von
Petitionen überschwemmten die eben hergestellten 
Zustandgesetzgebungen. Dieses, eingegeben beim Massachusetts 
allgemeinen Gericht 1777, band die Ursache der amerikanischen Freiheit
mit dem Kampf der afrikanischen Amerikaner für Freiheit. Einige
Prozesse, die Freiheit suchen, waren erfolgreich. Als Quok 
Wanderer für seine Freiheit und rückseitigen Löhne 1781 klagte, 
ordnete der Massachusetts Oberrichter an, daß sein enslavement die 
neuen Anweisung der Zustandbeschaffenheit verletzte, die "Männer sind
getragenes freies und gleich." Sein Fall beendete effektiv 
Sklaverei in Massachusetts und in anderen Neu-England Zuständen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lutte révolutionnaire des colons 'contre les questions à
la maison également augmentées politiques britanniques d'autorité 
au sujet de l'égalité et des droits de l'homme. Personnes 
asservies dans toutes les colonies saisies sur la rhétorique de la 
liberté et de l'égalité pour préciser la contradiction de 
combattre la Grande-Bretagne au-dessus des principes pas entièrement 
suivis des colonies elles-mêmes ; ils ont également fait appel
aux préceptes chrétiens. Une masse de pétitions a inondé les
législatures d'état nouvellement établies. Celui-ci, soumis 
à la cour générale du Massachusetts en 1777, a joint la cause de la
liberté américaine avec la lutte des Américains africains pour la 
liberté. Plusieurs procès recherchant la liberté étaient 
réussis. Quand le marcheur de Quok a poursuivi pour sa liberté
et salaires arrières en 1781, le juge en chef du Massachusetts a 
régné que son asservissement a violé de la nouvelle le rapport 
constitution d'état qui les "hommes sont libres et égaux soutenus." 
Son cas a pertinemment terminé l'esclavage dans le 
Massachusetts et d'autres états de la Nouvelle Angleterre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esforço revolucionário dos colonos ' de encontro às 
edições também levantadas políticas britânicas da autoridade 
sobre a igualdade e às direitas humanas na HOME. Povos enslaved
durante todo as colônias apreendidas em cima do rhetoric da liberdade
e da igualdade para indicar o contradiction de lutar Grâ Bretanha 
sobre os princípios seguidos não inteiramente pelas colônias elas 
mesmas; apelaram também aos precepts christian. As 
contagens das petições inundaram as legislaturas de estado 
recentemente estabelecidas. Este, submetido à corte geral de 
Massachusetts em 1777, ligou a causa da liberdade americana com o 
esforço de americanos africanos para a liberdade. Diversos 
lawsuits que procuram a liberdade eram bem sucedidos. Quando o 
walker de Quok sued para seus liberdade e salários traseiros em 1781,
a justiça principal de Massachusetts governou que seu enslavement 
violated a indicação do constitution novo do estado que os "homens 
são livres e iguais carregados." Seu caso terminou eficazmente 
o slavery em Massachusetts e em outros estados de Nova Inglaterra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lotta rivoluzionaria dei colonizzatori 'contro le edizioni
nel paese anche sollevate politiche britanniche di autorità circa 
uguaglianza ed i diritti dell'uomo. Gente asservita durante le 
colonie grippate su retorica di libertà e di uguaglianza per 
precisare la contraddizione di combattimento Gran Bretagna sopra i 
principii non completamente seguiti dalle colonie essi stessi; 
egualmente hanno fatto appello ai precetti cristiani. 
Massa di petizioni ha sommerso recentemente stabilito 
dichiara le legislature. Questo, presentato alla corte 
generale del Massachusetts in 1777, ha collegato la causa della 
libertà americana con la lotta degli Americani africani per la 
libertà. Parecchie cause che cercano la libertà riuscivano. 
Quando il camminatore di Quok ha citato per la suoi libertà e 
stipendi posteriori in 1781, la giustizia principale del Massachusetts
ha regolato che il suo enslavement ha violato il nuovo 
dichiara l'istruzione della costituzione che "gli uomini sono 
libero ed uguale sopportati." Il suo caso ha concluso 
efficacemente lo slavery in Massachusetts e l'altra Nuova Inghilterra 
dichiara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επαναστατικός αγώνας των αποίκων ο "κατά της 
βρετανικής πολιτικής αρχής προέκυψε επίσης τα ζητήματα για την 
ισότητα και τα ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα στο σπίτι. Οι 
υποδουλωμένοι άνθρωποι σε όλες τις αποικίες εκμεταλλεύτηκαν τη 
ρητορική της ελευθερίας και της ισότητας για να επισημάνουν την 
αντίφαση της παλεύοντας Μεγάλης Βρετανίας πέρα από τις αρχές 
που ακολουθήθηκαν όχι πλήρως από τις αποικίες οι ίδιοι  
απευθύνθηκαν επίσης στα χριστιανικά εντάλματα. Τα 
αποτελέσματα των αιτήσεων πλημμύρισαν τα πρόσφατα καθιερωμένα 
κρατικά νομοθετικά σώματα. Αυτός, που υποβλήθηκε στο 
γενικό δικαστήριο της Μασαχουσέτης το 1777, σύνδεσε την αιτία 
της αμερικανικής ελευθερίας με την προσπάθεια αφρικανικών 
Αμερικανών για την ελευθερία. Διάφορες δίκες που επιδιώκουν
την ελευθερία ήταν επιτυχείς. Όταν ο περιπατητής Quok 
μήνυσε για την ελευθερία και τις πίσω αμοιβές του το 1781, η 
δικαιοσύνη της Μασαχουσέτης Προϊστάμενος κυβέρνησε ότι η 
υποδούλωσή του παραβίασε τη δήλωση του νέου κρατικού 
συντάγματος ότι "τα άτομα είναι γεννημένα ελεύθερα και ίσα." 
Η περίπτωσή του τελείωσε αποτελεσματικά τη σκλαβιά στη 
Μασαχουσέτη και άλλα κράτη της Νέας Αγγλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lucha revolucionaria de los colonos ' contra ediciones 
también en el país planteadas políticas británicas de la autoridad
sobre igualdad y derechos humanos. Gente esclavizada a través 
de las colonias agarradas sobre el retórico de la libertad y de la 
igualdad para precisar la contradicción de luchar Gran Bretaña sobre
los principios seguidos no completamente por las colonias ellos 
mismos; también abrogaron a los preceptos cristianos. Las
cuentas de peticiones inundaron a legislaturas de estado nuevamente 
establecidas. Éste, sometido a la corte general de 
Massachusetts en 1777, conectó la causa de la libertad americana a la
lucha de los americanos africanos para la libertad. Varios 
pleitos que buscaban la libertad eran acertados. Cuando el 
walker de Quok demandó para su libertad y salarios posteriores en 
1781, la principal justicia de Massachusetts gobernó que su 
enslavement violó la declaración de la nueva constitución del 
estado que los "hombres son libres e iguales nacida." Su caso 
terminó con eficacia esclavitud en Massachusetts y otros estados de 
Nueva Inglaterra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086659</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107193</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/natural-and-inalienable-right-to-freedom-slaves-petition-for-freedom-to-the-massachusetts-legislature-1777</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
