<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103851</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103851</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207057</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Anti-Railroad Propaganda Poster: The Growth of Regionalism, 1800-1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anti-Eisenbahn Propaganda-Plakat: Das 
Wachstum von Regionalism, 1800-1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Affiche de Propagande d'Anti-Chemin de fer : 
La croissance du Régionalisme, 1800-1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Poster Do Propaganda Da Anti-Estrada de ferro: 
O crescimento de Regionalism, 1800-1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Manifesto Di Propaganda Della Anti-Ferrovia: 
Lo sviluppo di Regionalism, 1800-1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αντι-σιδηρόδρομος αφίσα προπαγάνδας: Η αύξηση 
του τοπικισμού, 1800-1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cartel De la Propaganda Del Contra-Ferrocarril: 
El crecimiento del Regionalismo, 1800-1860</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">uses a poster decrying the disruptive influence of railroads on local culture to launch a discussion on local differences and their effect on American politics. Explanatory text, materials for teachers, and links to further resources accompany the documents. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences. It also has cross-curricular connections with history, government, and art.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">benutzt ein Plakat, das den Unterbrechungseinfluß
der Eisenbahnen auf lokale Kultur herabsetzt, um eine Diskussion auf 
lokalen Unterschieden und ihren Effekt auf amerikanische Politik 
auszustoßen. Erläuternder Text, Materialien für Lehrer und 
Links zu den weiteren Betriebsmitteln begleiten die Dokumente. 
Diese Lektion bezieht mit den nationalen Geschichte Standards 
und den nationalen Standards für Gemeinschaftskunde und 
Sozialwissenschaften aufeinander. Sie hat auch 
Kreuzlehrplananschlüsse mit Geschichte, Regierung und kunst.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">utilise une affiche décriant l'influence 
disruptive des chemins de fer sur la culture locale pour lancer une 
discussion sur des différences locales et leur effet sur la politique
américaine. Le texte explicatif, les matériaux pour des 
professeurs, et les liens d'autres à ressources accompagnent les 
documents. Cette leçon se corrèle avec les normes nationales 
d'histoire et les normes nationales pour l'éducation civique et les 
sciences sociales. Elle a également les connexions 
croix-curriculaires avec l'histoire, le gouvernement, et l'art.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">usa um poster que decrying a influência 
disruptiva das estradas de ferro na cultura local para lançar uma 
discussão em diferenças locais e seu efeito na política americana. 
O texto explanatório, os materiais para professores, e as 
ligações a uns recursos mais adicionais acompanham os originais. 
Esta lição correlaciona aos padrões nacionais do history e 
aos padrões nacionais para o civics e ciências sociais. Tem 
também conexões cruz-cross-curricular com o history, o governo, e a 
arte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">usa un manifesto che denigra l'influenza 
disgregativa delle ferrovie su coltura locale per lanciare una 
discussione sulle differenze locali ed il loro effetto sulla politica 
americana. Il testo esplicativo, i materiali per gli insegnanti 
ed i collegamenti ad ulteriori risorse accompagnano i documenti. 
Questa lezione correla agli standard nazionali di storia ed agli
standard nazionali per civics e le scienze sociali. Egualmente 
ha collegamenti traversa-d'insegnamento con storia, il governo e 
l'arte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χρησιμοποιεί μια αφίσα επικρίνοντας την 
αποδιοργανωτική επιρροή των σιδηροδρόμων στον τοπικό πολιτισμό 
για να προωθήσει μια συζήτηση σχετικά με τις τοπικές διαφορές και
την επίδρασή τους στην αμερικανική πολιτική. Το 
επεξηγηματικό κείμενο, τα υλικά για τους δασκάλους, και οι 
συνδέσεις με τα περαιτέρω στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς συνοδεύουν τα 
έγγραφα. Αυτό το μάθημα συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα 
ιστορίας και τα εθνικά πρότυπα για Civics και τις κοινωνικές 
επιστήμες. Έχει επίσης τις διαγώνιος-διδακτικές συνδέσεις 
με την ιστορία, την κυβέρνηση, και την τέχνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">utiliza un cartel que denigra la influencia 
quebrantadora de ferrocarriles en cultura local para lanzar una 
discusión sobre diferencias locales y su efecto sobre política 
americana. El texto explicativo, los materiales para los 
profesores, y las conexiones a otros recursos acompañan los 
documentos. Esta lección correlaciona a los estándares 
nacionales de la historia y a los estándares nacionales para el 
civics y las ciencias sociales. También tiene conexiones 
cruz-del plan de estudios con historia, el gobierno, y el arte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207057</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103851</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/anti-railroad-propaganda-poster-the-growth-of-regionalism-1800-1860</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
