<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103276</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103276</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Waterford, Virginia: From Mill Town to National Historic Landmark</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Waterford, Virginia: Von der 
Tausendstel-Stadt zum nationalen historischen Grenzstein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Waterford, La Virginie : De la ville de 
moulin à la borne limite historique nationale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Waterford, Virgínia: Da cidade do moinho ao
marco historic nacional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Waterford, La Virginia: Dalla città del 
laminatoio al limite storico nazionale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Waterford, Βιρτζίνια: Από την πόλη μύλων στο
εθνικό ιστορικό ορόσημο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Waterford, Virginia: De ciudad del molino a 
la señal histórica nacional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of a village west of Washington, D.C. In 1733, Amos Janney purchased 400 acres along Catoctin Creek and built a mill for grinding flour and sawing wood. As fellow Quakers came to the area seeking fertile farmlands, a settlement grew up around Janney's Mill. Renamed Waterford in the 1790s, the settlement prospered. Markets were expanded by the Chesapeake/Ohio Canal and Baltimore/Ohio Railroad. The area was devasted by the Civil War and never returned to its pre-war success.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte eines Dorfs westlich von 
Washington, D.C. In 1733, kauften Amos Janney 400 Morgen entlang 
Catoctin Nebenfluß und bauten ein Tausendstel für reibendes Mehl und
sägendes Holz auf. Während die Gefährtequäker zum Bereich 
fruchtbares Ackerland suchend kamen, wuchs eine Regelung um 
Tausendstel Janneys auf. Umbenanntes Waterford im 1790s, die 
Regelung erweiterte sich. Märkte wurden durch den 
Chesapeake/Ohio Kanal und Baltimore/Ohio Eisenbahn erweitert. 
Der Bereich war devasted durch den Bürgerkrieg und zurückging 
nie zu seinem Vorkriegserfolg.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire d'un village à l'ouest de 
Washington, D.C. In 1733, les AMOS Janney ont acheté 400 acres le 
long de crique de Catoctin et ont construit un moulin pour la farine 
de meulage et le bois sciant. Pendant que les quakers de 
camarade venaient à la zone recherchant les champs fertiles, un 
règlement a grandi autour du moulin de Janney. Waterford 
renommé dans le 1790s, le règlement a prospéré. Des marchés
ont été augmentés par le canal de Chesapeake/Ohio et le chemin de 
fer de Baltimore/Ohio. La zone était devasted par la guerre 
civile et n'est jamais revenue à son succès d'avant-guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história de uma vila ao oeste de 
Washington, C.C.  1733, os Amos Janney compraram 400 acres ao longo do
creek de Catoctin e construíram um moinho para a farinha moendo e a 
madeira sawing. Enquanto os quakers do companheiro vieram à 
área que procuram terras férteis, um estabelecimento cresceu acima 
em torno do moinho de Janney. Waterford rebatizado no 1790s, o 
estabelecimento prospered. Os mercados foram expandidos pelo 
canal de Chesapeake/Ohio e pela estrada de ferro de Baltimore/Ohio. 
A área era devasted pela guerra civil e nunca retornou a seu 
sucesso pre-war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia di un villaggio ad ovest di 
Washington, D.C. In 1733, gli AMO Janney hanno comprato 400 acri lungo
l'insenatura di Catoctin ed hanno costruito un laminatoio per farina 
stridente e legno sawing. Mentre i quakers del collega sono 
venuto alla zona che cercano i terreni coltivabili fertili, uno 
stabilimento si è sviluppato in su intorno al laminatoio del Janney. 
Waterford cambiato titolo nel 1790s, lo stabilimento ha fatto 
prosperare. I mercati sono stati espansi dal canale di 
Chesapeake/Ohio e dalla ferrovia di Baltimore/Ohio. La zona era 
devasted dalla guerra civile e mai non ha ritornato al relativo 
successo prebellico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία ενός χωριού δυτικά της Ουάσιγκτον, 
ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ Το 1733, amos Janney αγόρασαν 400 
στρέμματα κατά μήκος του κολπίσκου Catoctin και έχτισαν έναν 
μύλο για τη λείανση του αλευριού και να πριονίσουν το ξύλο. 
Καθώς συντροφικό Quakers ήρθε στην περιοχή επιδιώκων τα 
εύφορα καλλιεργήσιμα εδάφη, μια τακτοποίηση μεγάλωσε περίπου το 
εκατομμύριο Janney που μετονομάστηκε waterford στο 1790s, η
τακτοποίηση ευημέρησε. Οι αγορές επεκτάθηκαν από 
chesapeake/to κανάλι του Οχάιου και το σιδηρόδρομο της 
Βαλτιμόρης/του Οχάιου. Η περιοχή ήταν από τον εμφύλιο 
πόλεμο και δεν επέστρεψε ποτέ στην προπολεμική επιτυχία της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia de una aldea al oeste de 
Washington, D.C. In 1733, los Amos Janney compraron 400 acres a lo 
largo del cala de Catoctin y construyeron un molino para la harina que
molía y la madera que aserraba. Mientras que los quakers del 
compañero vinieron al área que buscaban tierras de labrantío 
fértiles, un establecimiento creció para arriba alrededor del molino
de Janney. Waterford retitulado en el 1790s, el establecimiento 
prosperó. Los mercados fueron ampliados por el canal de 
Chesapeake/Ohio y el ferrocarril de Baltimore/Ohio. El área era
devasted por la guerra civil y nunca volvió a su éxito de la 
preguerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103276</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/waterford-virginia-from-mill-town-to-national-historic-landmark</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
