<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105363</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105363</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205229</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Proofreading</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Korrekturlesen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Corriger</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Corrigir</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Correzione delle bozze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διόρθωση δοκιμίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El corregir</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The aim of this lesson is to develop students' understanding of the importance of proofreading. It is the sixth lesson in the study skills series and is intended to support adult learners who are embarking on a course of study and need to acquire skills which will help them to be successful. The lessons are designed as a package with key skills reinforced in each subsequent lesson so that a study culture is developed over time. They can be delivered sequentially or used individually, as a whole or in part, to support other programs of study.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel dieser Lektion ist, Verständnis der 
Kursteilnehmer des Wertes des Korrekturlesens zu entwickeln. Es 
ist die 6. Lektion in den Studie Fähigkeiten Serie und soll 
Erwachsenanfänger unterstützen, die auf einem Bildungsweg sich 
einschiffen und Fähigkeiten erwerben müssen, die ihnen helfen, 
erfolgreich zu sein. Die Lektionen sind während ein Paket mit 
den Schlüsselfähigkeiten konzipiert, die in jeder folgenden Lektion 
verstärkt werden, damit eine Studie Kultur über Zeit entwickelt 
wird. Sie können sequentiell geliefert werden oder, als Ganzes 
oder im Teil einzeln benutzt werden, um andere Programme der Studie zu
unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cette leçon est de développer 
l'arrangement des étudiants d'importance de corriger. C'est la
sixième leçon dans les qualifications série d'étude et est 
destiné pour supporter les étudiants d'adulte qui s'embarquent sur 
un cours d'étude et doivent saisir les qualifications qui les 
aideront à être réussies. Les leçons sont conçues pendant 
qu'un module avec les qualifications principales renforcées dans 
chaque leçon ultérieure de sorte qu'une culture d'étude soit 
développée avec le temps. Elles peuvent être livrées 
séquentiellement ou employées individuellement, dans l'ensemble ou 
en partie, pour supporter d'autres programmes d'étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O alvo desta lição é desenvolver a compreensão
dos estudantes da importância de corrigir. É a sexta lição 
nas habilidades série do estudo e é pretendido suportar os learners 
do adulto que embarking em um curso de estudo e necessitam adquirir as
habilidades que lhes ajudarão ser bem sucedidas. As lições 
são projetadas enquanto um pacote com as habilidades chaves 
reforçadas em cada lição subseqüente de modo que uma cultura do 
estudo esteja desenvolvida sobre o tempo. Podem ser entregados 
sequencialmente ou usado individualmente, ao todo ou na parte, 
suportar outros programas do estudo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo di questa lezione è sviluppare la 
comprensione degli allievi dell'importanza di correzione delle bozze. 
È la sesta lezione nelle abilità serie di studio ed è inteso 
sostenere i principianti dell'adulto che stanno intraprendendo un 
corso dello studio e devono acquistare le abilità che le aiuteranno a
riuscire. Le lezioni sono progettate mentre un pacchetto con le 
abilità chiave di rinforzo in ogni lezione successiva in moda da 
sviluppare una coltura di studio col tempo. Possono essere 
trasportate in sequenza o essere usate individualmente, nell'insieme o
in parte, per sostenere altri programmi dello studio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του μαθήματος είναι να αναπτυχθεί η 
κατανόηση των σπουδαστών σπουδαιότητας. Είναι το έκτο 
μάθημα στη σειρά δεξιοτήτων μελέτης και προορίζεται να 
υποστηρίξει τους ενήλικους αρχαρίους που αρχίζουν σπουδές και 
πρέπει να αποκτήσουν τις δεξιότητες που θα τους βοηθήσουν για να 
είναι επιτυχείς. Τα μαθήματα σχεδιάζονται ως συσκευασία με 
τις βασικές δεξιότητες που ενισχύονται σε κάθε επόμενο μάθημα 
έτσι ώστε ένας πολιτισμός μελέτης αναπτύσσεται κατά τη 
διάρκεια του χρόνου. Μπορούν να παραδοθούν διαδοχικά ή να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν χωριστά, συνολικά ή εν μέρει, για να 
υποστηρίξουν άλλα προγράμματα της μελέτης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La puntería de esta lección es desarrollar la 
comprensión de los estudiantes de la importancia de corregir. 
Es la sexta lección en las habilidades serie del estudio y se 
piensa apoyar a los principiantes del adulto que están emprendiendo 
un curso del estudio y necesitan adquirir las habilidades que les 
ayudarán a ser acertadas. Se diseñan las lecciones mientras 
que un conjunto con las habilidades dominantes reforzadas en cada 
lección subsecuente para desarrollar una cultura del estudio en un 
cierto plazo. Pueden ser entregadas secuencialmente o ser 
utilizadas individualmente, en su totalidad o en parte, para utilizar 
otros programas del estudio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205229</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105363</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/proofreading</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
