<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106745</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106745</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087355</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Achieving an Atmosphere of Mutual Trust and Confidence": Henry A. Wallace Offers an Alternative to Cold War Containment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", eine Atmosphäre des gegenseitigen Vertrauens 
und des Vertrauens erzielend": Henry A. Wallace Offers eine 
Alternative kalter Krieg-Eindämmung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"réalisant une atmosphère de confiance et de 
confiance mutuelles" : Henry A. Wallace Offers une alternative 
à la retenue de guerre froide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"conseguindo uma atmosfera da confiança e da 
confiança mútuas": Henry A. Wallace Oferecer uma alternativa 
ao containment da guerra fria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"realizzando un atmosfera di fiducia e di 
riservatezza reciproche": Henry A. Wallace Offers un'alternativa
a contenimento di guerra fredda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Επιτυγχάνοντας μια ατμόσφαιρα της αμοιβαίας 
εμπιστοσύνης και την εμπιστοσύνη": Θ*Χενρυ A. Wallace 
Offers μια εναλλακτική λύση του περιεχομένου ψυχρού πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"alcanzando una atmósfera de la confianza y de la
confianza mutuas": Henrio A. Wallace Offers un alternativa a la 
contención de la guerra fría</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Allies during World War II, the U.S. and the Soviet Union disagreed over a number of issues after the war. These included control of Eastern Europe, division of Germany, atomic energy, international loans, and the Middle East. On February 9, 1946, Soviet premier Josef Stalin asserted that the continued existence of capitalism in the West would inevitably lead to war. Foreign Service senior diplomat George Kennan sent President Harry Truman, still forming a Soviet policy, a lengthy telegram advocating containment. Commerce Secretary Henry A. Wallace--Secretary of Agriculture (1933-1941) and Vice-President from (1941-1945)--was one of the few liberal idealists in Truman's cabinet. Wallace envisioned a "century of the common man" marked by global peace and prosperity. In the following excerpt from a letter dated July 23, 1946, Wallace urged Truman to build "mutual trust and confidence" in order to achieve "an enduring international order." Truman asked Wallace to resign. In March 1947, Truman asked Congress for money "to support free peoples who are resisting attempted subjugation by armed minorities or by outside pressures." Thus articulated, the "Truman Doctrine" of containment served as the rationale for future American Cold War foreign policy initiatives.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verbündete während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, der 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und des Sowjet-AnschlußesWAREN über einer Anzahl
von Ausgaben nach dem Krieg anderer Meinung. Diese schlossen 
Steuerung von Osteuropa, Abteilung von Deutschland, Atomenergie, 
internationale Darlehen und den Mittlere Osten ein. An Februar 
9, 1946, sowjetischer Premier Josef Stalin erklärte, daß das 
anhaltende Bestehen von Kapitalismus im Westen unvermeidlich war 
führen würde. Älterer Diplomat George Kennan des fremden 
Services sendete Präsidenten Harry Truman, die Stille, die eine 
sowjetische Politik bildet, ein langatmiges Telegramm Eindämmung 
befürwortend. Handel-Sekretärinnenhenry A. Wallace -- Minister
fuer Landwirtschaft (1933-1941) und Vizepräsident von (1941-1945) -- 
war- einer der wenigen liberalen Idealisten im Schrank Trumans. 
Wallace stellte sich ein "Jahrhundert des gemeinen Mannes vor", 
der durch globalen Frieden und Wohlstand gekennzeichnet wurde. 
Im folgenden Excerpt von einem datierten Zeichen Juli 23, 1946, 
Wallace drängte Truman, um "gegenseitiges Vertrauen und Vertrauen" 
aufzubauen, um "eine aushaltene internationale Ordnung zu erzielen." 
Truman bat Wallace abzufinden. Im März 1947, bat Truman 
Kongreß um Geld ", freie Völker zu unterstützen, die widerstehen 
versuchtem subjugation durch bewaffnete Minoritäten oder durch 
äußeren Druck." So artikuliert, diente die "Truman Lehre" der 
Eindämmung als das Grundprinzip für zukünftige amerikanische 
Initiativen der fremden Politik des kalten Krieges.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les alliés pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, 
les ETATS-UNIS et l'Union Soviétique étaient en désaccord au-dessus d'un
certain nombre d'issues après la guerre. Ceux-ci ont inclus la 
commande de l'Europe de l'Est, la division de l'Allemagne, l'énergie 
atomique, les prêts internationaux, et le le Moyen-Orient. 
9 février 1946, premier ministre soviétique Josef Stalin a 
affirmé que l'existence continue du capitalisme dans l'ouest 
mènerait inévitablement à faire la guerre. Le diplomate 
aîné George Kennan de service étranger a envoyé le Président
Harry Truman, distillateur formant une politique soviétique, un 
télégramme prolongé préconisant la retenue. Henry A. Wallace
-- secrétaire de l'agriculture (1933-1941) et vice-président de 
secrétaire de commerce de (1941-1945) -- était l'un des quelques 
idéalistes libéraux dans le module de Truman. Wallace a 
envisagé un "siècle de l'homme commun" marqué par paix et 
prospérité globales. Dans l'extrait suivant d'une lettre 
datée 23 juillet 1946, Wallace a invité Truman pour établir "la 
confiance et la confiance mutuelles" afin de réaliser "une commande 
internationale durable." Truman a demandé Wallace de 
démissionner. En mars 1947, Truman a demandé au congrès 
l'argent "de supporter les peuples libres qui résistent à 
l'assujettissement essayé par des minorités armées ou par des pressions
extérieures." Ainsi articulé, la "doctrine de Truman" de la 
retenue a servi de raisonnement à de futures initiatives américaines
de politique étrangère de guerre froide.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os aliados durante a segunda guerra mundial, os 
ESTADOS UNIDOS e a Soviete-união discordaram sobre um número de 
edições após a guerra. Estes incluíram o controle de Europa 
Oriental, a divisão de Germany, a energia atômica, empréstimos 
internacionais, e o Oriente Médio. Fevereiro em 9, 1946, 
premier soviético Josef Stalin afirmou que a existência continuada 
do capitalismo no oeste conduziria inevitàvel para guerrear. O 
diplomata sênior George Kennan do serviço extrangeiro emitiu o 
presidente Harry Truman, destilador que dá forma a uma política 
soviética, um telegrama longo advogando o containment. O Henry 
A. Wallace da secretária do comércio -- secretária de agricultura 
(1933-1941) e vice-presidente de (1941-1945) -- era um de poucos 
idealists liberais no armário de Truman. Wallace envisioned um 
"século do homem comum" marcado pela paz e pela prosperidade globais.
No seguinte excerpt de uma letra datada julho 23, 1946, Wallace 
incitou Truman para construir "a confiança e a confiança mútuas" a 
fim conseguir "uma ordem internacional resistindo." Truman pediu
que Wallace renunciasse. Em março 1947, Truman pediu que o 
congress para o dinheiro "suportasse os povos livres que estão 
resistindo o subjugation tentado por minorities armados ou por 
pressões exteriores." Assim articulado, de "a doutrina Truman" 
do containment serviu como o rationale para as iniciativas americanas 
futuras da política extrangeira de guerra fria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli alleati durante la seconda guerra mondiale, 
gli STATI UNITI e l'Soviet-unione sono non stato d'accordo sopra un 
certo numero di edizioni dopo la guerra. Questi hanno incluso il
controllo dell'Europa Orientale, la divisione della Germania, 
l'energia atomica, i prestiti internazionali e Medio Oriente. Il 9 
febbraio 1946, il primo ministro sovietico Josef Stalin ha asserito che 
l'esistenza continuata del capitalismo nell'ovest condurrebbe 
inevitabilmente per fare la guerra. Il diplomatico maggiore 
George Kennan di servizio straniero ha trasmesso il presidente Harry 
Truman, alambicco che forma una politica sovietica, un telegramma 
lungo sostenente il contenimento. Il henry A. Wallace -- 
segretaria di agricoltura (1933-1941) e vice presidente della 
segretaria di commercio da (1941-1945) -- era uno dei pochi idealists 
liberali in armadietto del Truman. Wallace ha previsto "un 
secolo dell'uomo comune" contrassegnato da pace e dalla prosperità 
globali. Nel seguente brano da una lettera datata 23 luglio 
1946, Wallace ha invitato Truman per sviluppare "la fiducia e la 
riservatezza reciproche" per realizzare "un ordine internazionale 
duraturo." Truman ha chiesto a Wallace di dimettersi. Nel 
mese di marzo del 1947, Truman ha chiesto al congresso soldi "di 
sostenere la gente libera che sta resistendo al subjugation tentato 
dalle minoranze munite o dalle pressioni esterne." Così 
articolato, "la dottrina di Truman" del contenimento ha servito da 
spiegazione razionale per le iniziative americane future di politica 
straniera di guerra fredda.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σύμμαχοι κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου 
ΙΙ, οι ΗΠΑ και η Σοβιετική Ένωση διαφώνησαν πέρα από διάφορα 
ζητήματα μετά από τον πόλεμο. Αυτοί περιέλαβαν τον έλεγχο
της Ανατολικής Ευρώπης, το τμήμα της Γερμανίας, την ατομική 
ενέργεια, τα διεθνή δάνεια, και τη Μέση Ανατολή. Στις 9 
Φεβρουαρίου ..1946, ο σοβιετικός αρχαιότερος Josef Stalin 
βεβαίωσε ότι η συνεχής ύπαρξη της κεφαλαιοκρατίας στη δύση θα 
οδηγούσε αναπόφευκτα στον πόλεμο. Ο ξένος ανώτερος 
διπλωμάτης George Kennan υπηρεσιών έστειλε τον Πρόεδρο 
Harry Truman, διαμορφώνοντας ακόμα μια σοβιετική πολιτική, 
ένα μεγάλο τηλεγράφημα που υποστηρίζει το περιεχόμενο. Το 
εμπόριο Secretary Henry Α. Wallace -- γραμματέας της 
γεωργίας (1933-1941) και αντιπρόεδρος από (19411945) -- ήταν
ένας από τους λίγους φιλελεύθερους ιδεαλιστές στο γραφείο 
Truman. Το Wallace πρόβλεψε έναν "αιώνα του κοινού 
ατόμου" που χαρακτηρίστηκε από την παγκόσμιες ειρήνη και την 
ευημερία. Στο ακόλουθο απόσπασμα από μια επιστολή της 23ης 
Ιουλίου ..1946, Wallace ώθησε Truman για να χτίσει τη 
"αμοιβαίες εμπιστοσύνη και την αξιοπιστία" προκειμένου να 
επιτευχθεί "μια υπομένοντας διεθνής τάξη." Ρωτημένο 
Truman Wallace για να παραιτηθεί. Τον Μάρτιο του 
1947, Truman ζήτησε από το συνέδριο για τα χρήματα "για να 
υποστηρίξει τους ελεύθερους λαούς που αντιστέκονται στην 
αποπειραθείσα υποταγή από τις οπλισμένες μειονότητες ή από τις 
εξωτερικές πιέσεις." Κατά συνέπεια αρθρωμένος, το "δόγμα 
Truman" του περιεχομένου που χρησιμεύεται ως η λογική για τις 
μελλοντικές αμερικανικές πρωτοβουλίες εξωτερικής πολιτικής 
ψυχρού πολέμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los aliados durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, los
ESTADOS UNIDOS y la Soviet-unio'n discreparon sobre un número de 
ediciones después de la guerra. Éstos incluyeron el control de
Europa Oriental, la división de Alemania, la energía atómica, 
préstamos internacionales, y el Oriente Medio. 9 de febrero 
de 1946, primero ministro soviético José Stalin afirmó que la 
existencia continuada del capitalismo en el oeste conduciría 
inevitable para guerrear. El diplomata mayor George Kennan del 
servicio no nativo envió a presidente Harry Truman, alambique que 
formaba una política soviética, un telegrama muy largo abogando la 
contención. El Henrio A. Wallace -- secretaria de la 
agricultura (1933-1941) y vice presidente de la secretaria del 
comercio de (1941-1945) -- era uno de los pocos idealistas liberales 
en la cabina de Truman. Wallace previo un "siglo del hombre 
común" marcado por paz y prosperidad globales. En el extracto 
siguiente de una carta anticuada 23 de julio de 1946, Wallace 
impulsó Truman para construir "confianza y confianza mutuas" para 
alcanzar "una orden internacional que aguantaba." Truman pidió 
que Wallace dimitiera. En marcha de 1947, Truman pidió que el 
congreso dinero "apoyara a gente libre que se está oponiendo al 
subjugation procurado de minorías armadas o por presiones 
exteriores." Así articulado, la "doctrina de Truman" de la 
contención sirvió como el análisis razonado para las iniciativas 
americanas futuras de la política no nativa de la guerra fría.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087355</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106745</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/achieving-an-atmosphere-of-mutual-trust-and-confidence-henry-a-wallace-offers-an-alternative-to-cold-war-containment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
