<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105453</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105453</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206757</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NPS Archeology: Research in the Parks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NPS Archäologie: Forschung in den Parks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Archéologie de NPS : Recherche en parcs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Archeology de NPS: Pesquisa nos parques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Archeologia di NPS: Ricerca nei parchi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχαιολογία NPS: Έρευνα στα πάρκα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Arqueología de NPS: Investigación en los 
parques</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">invites us to discover the resources in our national parks through the eyes of archaeologists Click on the map of states to explore more than 120 national parks and monuments. Learn about the Klondike gold rush, Andersonville, USS Arizona, Nez Perce, Antietam, Truman's home, Little Bighorn, Aztec ruins, Gila cliff dwellings, Fort Union Trading Post, Jamestown, Fort Sumter, Washington's birthplace, Yellowstone, and other important places and events.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">lädt uns ein zu entdecken, daß die 
Betriebsmittel in unseren Nationalparks durch die Augen der 
Archäologen an die Karte der Zustände klicken, um mehr als 120 
Nationalparks und Denkmäler zu erforschen. Erlernen Sie über 
die Klondike Goldanstürme, das Andersonville, USS Arizona, das Nez 
Perce, das Antietam, Trumans Haupt-, kleine der Bighorn, die 
aztekischen Ruinen, die Gila Klippe Wohnungen, 
Fort-Anschluß-handelnder Pfosten, Jamestown, Fort Sumter, Geburtsort 
Washingtons, Yellowstone und andere wichtige Plätze und Fälle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">nous invite à découvrir les ressources en nos 
parcs nationaux par les yeux du Clic d'archéologues sur la 
carte des états pour explorer plus de 120 parcs nationaux et 
monuments. Renseignez-vous sur les précipitations d'or de 
Klondike, l'Andersonville, Arizona d'USS, le Nez Perce, l'Antietam, la
maison de Truman, le Little Bighorn, les ruines aztèques, les logements 
de la falaise de Gila, le comptoir commercial des syndicats de fort, 
le Jamestown, le fort Sumter, le lieu de naissance de Washington, le 
Yellowstone, et d'autres endroits et événements importants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">convida-nos descobrir que os recursos em nossos 
parques nacionais através dos olhos dos arqueólogos estalam sobre o 
mapa dos estados para explorar mais de 120 parques nacionais e 
monumentos. Aprenda sobre moradias as arremetidas do ouro de 
Klondike, o Andersonville, arizona de USS, o Nez Perce, o Antietam, o 
veado selvagem home, pequeno de Truman, as ruínas aztec, do penhasco 
de Gila, borne negociando da união do fort, Jamestown, fort Sumter, 
birthplace de Washington, Yellowstone, e outros lugares e eventos 
importantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">li invita a scoprire che le risorse nei nostri 
parchi nazionali attraverso gli occhi degli archeologhi scattano sopra
il programma del dichiara di per esplorare più di 120 parchi 
nazionali e monumenti. Impari circa dimore gli sbalzi dell'oro 
di Klondike, il Andersonville, Arizona di USS, il Nez Perce, il 
Antietam, il bighorn domestico e piccolo del Truman, le rovine aztec, 
della scogliera di Gila, alberino di commercio Forte del 
sindacato, Jamestown, Sumter Forte, luogo di nascita de 
Washington, Yellowstone ed altri posti ed eventi importanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μας προσκαλεί για να ανακαλύψει ότι τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς στα εθνικά πάρκα μας μέσω των ματιών των 
αρχαιολόγων χτυπούν στο χάρτη των κρατών για να εξερευνήσουν 
περισσότερα από 120 εθνικά πάρκα και μνημεία. Μάθετε 
για τη Klondike χρυσή βιασύνη, Andersonville, USS Αριζόνα,
Nez Perce, Antietam, σπίτι Truman, λίγο Bighorn, των 
Αζτέκων καταστροφές, κατοικίες απότομων βράχων Gila, θέση 
εμπορικών συναλλαγών ένωσης οχυρών, Jamestown, οχυρό 
Sumter, τόπος γεννήσεως της Ουάσιγκτον, Yellowstone, και 
άλλα σημαντικά θέσεις και γεγονότα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">nos invita a que descubramos los recursos en 
nuestros parques nacionales a través de los ojos de arqueólogos 
hagan clic encendido la correspondencia de estados para explorar más 
de 120 parques nacionales y monumentos. Aprenda sobre las 
viviendas las acometidas del oro de Klondike, el Andersonville, 
Arizona de USS, el Nez Perce, el Antietam, el carnero con grandes 
cuernos casero, pequeño de Truman, las ruinas aztec, del acantilado 
de Gila, poste que negocia de la unión de la fortaleza, Jamestown, 
fortaleza Sumter, lugar de nacimiento de Washington, Yellowstone, y 
otros lugares y acontecimientos importantes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206757</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105453</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nps-archeology-research-in-the-parks</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
