<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108408</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108408</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201474</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Energy Balance Climate Model</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Energie-Balance Klima-Modell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Modèle de Climat de Bilan énergétique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Modelo Do Clima Do Contrapeso De Energia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modello Di Clima Del Bilancio energetico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μοντέλο κλίματος ενεργειακής ισορροπίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Modelo Del Clima Del Balance energético</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students explore a Global Energy Balance Climate Model Using Stella II. This Stella model focuses on global energy balance and creating a useful climate model. Students can explore how the model planetary surface and atmospheric temperatures respond to variations in solar input, atmospheric and surface albedo, atmospheric water vapor and carbon dioxide, volcanic eruptions, and mixed layer ocean depth. Climate feedbacks such as water vapor or ice-albedo can be turned on or off. The activity provides guided exploration on energy balance and radiative equilibrium, the concept of radiative forcing, planetary temperature response to variations, transient response with different ocean mixed layer depths; climate feedbacks from temperature induced variations, and interpreting and creating loop diagrams to assess feedback behavior. This activity takes roughly 3 hours to complete and is appropriate for introductory geoscience courses with climate change content and for students with little mathematical background. This site also includes teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas and additional resources. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer erforschen ein globales 
Energie-Balance Klima vorbildliches verwendendes Stella II. 
Dieses Stella vorbildliche Foki auf globaler Energiebalance und 
-erstellen eines nützlichen Klimamodells. Kursteilnehmer 
können erforschen, wie die vorbildliche planetarische Oberfläche und
die atmosphärischen Temperaturen auf Schwankungen des Solarinput, 
atmosphärische und Oberflächenalbedo, atmosphärischer Wasserdampf 
und Kohlendioxyd, vulkanische Eruptionen und Mischschichtozeantiefe 
reagieren. Klimafeedbacks wie Wasserdampf oder Eis-Albedo 
können an oder abgestellt werden. Die Aktivität stellt 
geführte Erforschung auf Energiebalance und Strahlungsgleichgewicht, 
das Konzept des Strahlungserzwingens, planetarische Temperaturantwort 
zu den Varianten, Übergangsfunktion mit unterschiedlicher Ozean 
gemischten Schichttiefen zur Verfügung; Klimafeedbacks von der 
Temperatur verursachen Varianten und die Deutung und das Erstellen der
Schleife Diagramme, um Feedbackverhalten festzusetzen. Diese 
Aktivität dauert ungefähr 3 Stunden, um durchzuführen und ist für 
einleitende geoscience Kurse mit Klimaänderung Inhalt und für 
Kursteilnehmer mit wenig mathematischem Hintergrund angebracht. 
Diese Site schließt auch unterrichtende Anmerkungen und 
Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen und zusätzliche 
Betriebsmittel ein. Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil der 
Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants explorent un climat global Stella 
d'utilisation modèle II de bilan énergétique. Foyers modèles
de ce Stella sur le bilan énergétique et créer global un modèle 
utile de climat. Les étudiants peuvent explorer comment la 
surface planétaire modèle et les températures atmosphériques 
répondent aux variations de l'entrée solaire, l'albedo 
atmosphérique et extérieur, la vapeur d'eau et l'anhydride 
carbonique atmosphérique, les éruptions volcaniques, et la 
profondeur mélangée d'océan de couche. Des feedbacks de 
climat tels que la vapeur d'eau ou le glace-albedo peuvent être 
arrêtés en fonction ou. L'activité fournit l'exploration 
guidée sur le bilan énergétique et l'équilibre radiatif, le 
concept de forcer radiatif, la réponse planétaire de la température
aux variations, réponse passagère avec des profondeurs de couche 
mélangées par océan différent ; les feedbacks de climat de 
la température induisent des variations, et interpréter et créer 
des diagrammes de boucle pour évaluer le comportement de feedback. 
Cette activité prend approximativement 3 heures pour se 
terminer et est appropriée pour des cours préliminaires de 
geoscience avec le contenu de changement de climat et pour des 
étudiants avec peu de fond mathématique. Ce site inclut 
également les notes et les extrémités d'enseignement, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation et les ressources 
supplémentaires. Cette activité fait partie de la collection 
de point de départ : http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes exploram um clima global Stella 
usando-se modelo II do contrapeso de energia. Focos modelo deste
Stella no contrapeso e em criar de energia global um modelo útil do 
clima. Os estudantes podem explorar como a superfície 
planetária modelo e as temperaturas atmosféricas respondem às 
variações na entrada solar, albedo atmosférico e de superfície, 
vapor de água e dióxido de carbono atmosférico, eruptions 
vulcânicos, e profundidade misturada do oceano da camada. Os 
feedbacs do clima tais como o vapor de água ou o gelo-ice-albedo 
podem ser desligados sobre ou. A atividade fornece a 
exploração guiada no contrapeso de energia e o equilíbrio 
radiative, o conceito de forçar radiative, resposta planetária às 
variações, resposta transiente da temperatura com oceano diferente 
profundidades misturadas da camada; os feedbacs do clima da 
temperatura induzem variações, e interpretação e criar de 
diagramas do laço para avaliar o comportamento do feedback. 
Esta atividade faz exame de aproximadamente 3 horas para 
terminar e é apropriada para cursos introdutórios do geoscience com 
índice da mudança do clima e para estudantes com pouco fundo 
matemático. Este local inclui também notas e pontas ensinando,
materiais de ensino, idéias da avaliação e recursos adicionais. 
Esta atividade é parte da coleção do ponto começar: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi esplorano un clima globale Stella 
usando di modello II del bilancio energetico. Fuochi di modello 
di questo Stella sul bilancio energetico e sulla creazione globale del
modello utile di clima. Gli allievi possono esplorare come la 
superficie planetaria di modello e le temperature atmosferiche 
rispondono alle variazioni nell'input solare, albedo atmosferica e di 
superficie, vapore acqueo ed anidride carbonica atmosferica, eruptions
vulcanici e profondità mixed dell'oceano di strato. Le risposte
di clima quali il vapore acqueo o l'ghiaccio-albedo possono essere 
spente sopra o. L'attività fornisce l'esplorazione guidata sul 
bilancio energetico e l'equilibrio radiattivo, il concetto di 
forzatura radiattiva, la risposta planetaria alle variazioni, risposta
transitoria di temperatura con le profondità di strato mescolate 
oceano differente; le risposte di clima dalla temperatura 
inducono le variazioni e l'interpretazione e la creazione degli schemi
del ciclo per valutare il comportamento di risposte. Questa 
attività occorre approssimativamente 3 ore per completare ed è 
adatta per i corsi introduttivi di geoscience con il soddisfare del 
cambiamento di clima e per gli allievi con poca priorità bassa 
matematica. Questo luogo egualmente include le note e punte 
d'istruzione, materiali didattici, idee di valutazione e risorse 
supplementari. Questa attività fa parte dell'accumulazione del 
punto di partenza: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές ερευνούν ένα παγκόσμιο κλίμα η πρότυπη
χρησιμοποιώντας Στέλλα ΙΙ ενεργειακής ισορροπίας. Αυτό το 
μοντέλο της Στέλλα εστιάζει στη σφαιρική ενεργειακή ισορροπία 
και δημιουργία ενός χρήσιμου μοντέλου κλίματος. Οι 
σπουδαστές μπορούν να εξερευνήσουν πώς η πρότυπη πλανητική 
επιφάνεια και οι ατμοσφαιρικές θερμοκρασίες αποκρίνονται στις 
παραλλαγές σε ηλιακή είσοδο, ατμοσφαιρικό και albedo 
επιφάνειας, ατμοσφαιρικό υδρατμό και διοξείδιο του άνθρακα, 
ηφαιστειακές εκρήξεις, και μικτό ωκεάνιο βάθος στρώματος. 
Οι ανατροφοδοτήσεις κλίματος όπως ο υδρατμός ή το 
πάγος-αλψεδο μπορούν να ανοιχτούν ή μακριά. Η 
δραστηριότητα παρέχει την καθοδηγημένη εξερεύνηση στην ενεργειακή
ισορροπία και την της ακτινοβολίας ισορροπία, η έννοια του της 
ακτινοβολίας καταναγκασμού, πλανητική απάντηση θερμοκρασίας στις 
παραλλαγές, παροδική απάντηση με τα διαφορετικά μικτά ωκεανός 
βάθη στρώματος  οι ανατροφοδοτήσεις κλίματος από τη 
θερμοκρασία προέτρεψαν τις παραλλαγές, και ερμηνεία και 
δημιουργώντας των διαγραμμάτων βρόχων για να αξιολογήσουν τη 
συμπεριφορά ανατροφοδότησης. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα διαρκεί 
κατά προσέγγιση 3 ώρες που ολοκληρώνουν και είναι κατάλληλη για 
τις εισαγωγικές σειρές μαθημάτων geoscience με το περιεχόμενο 
αλλαγής κλίματος και για τους σπουδαστές με λίγο μαθηματικό 
υπόβαθρο. Αυτή η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις 
σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις 
ιδέες αξιολόγησης και τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς. 
Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes exploran un clima global Stella 
que usa modelo II del balance energético. Focos modelo de este 
Stella en balance energético y crear global un modelo útil del 
clima. Los estudiantes pueden explorar cómo la superficie 
planetaria modelo y las temperaturas atmosféricas responden a las 
variaciones en la entrada de información solar, albedo atmosférico y
superficial, vapor de agua y bióxido de carbono atmosférico, las 
erupciones volcánicas, y profundidad mezclada del océano de la capa.
Los feedbacces del clima tales como vapor de agua o 
hielo-ice-albedo se pueden dar vuelta encendido o apagado. La 
actividad proporciona a la exploración dirigida en balance 
energético y al equilibrio radiativo, el concepto de forzar 
radiativo, respuesta planetaria a las variaciones, respuesta 
transitoria de la temperatura con profundidades mezcladas diverso 
océano de la capa; los feedbacces del clima de la temperatura 
indujeron variaciones, e interpretar y crear diagramas del bucle para 
evaluar comportamiento del feedback. Esta actividad toma áspero
3 horas para terminar y es apropiada para los cursos introductorios 
del geoscience con el contenido del cambio del clima y para los 
estudiantes con poco fondo matemático. Este sitio también 
incluye notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales 
didácticos, las ideas del gravamen y los recursos adicionales. 
Esta actividad es parte de la colección del punto de partida: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MACKAY
FN:ROBERT MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201474</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108408</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/energy-balance-climate-model</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
