<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104545</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104545</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086863</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Suffer for About the First Six Months After Leaving Home": John Doyle Writes Home to Ireland, 1818</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"leiden Sie für ungefähr die ersten sechs 
Monate, nachdem Sie Haus" verlassen haben: John Doyle schreibt 
nach Hause nach Irland, 1818</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"souffrez pour environ les six premiers mois 
après être parti de la maison" : John Doyle écrit à la 
maison en Irlande, 1818</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"sofra para aproximadamente os primeiros seis 
meses após ter saido da HOME": John Doyle escreve para casa a 
Ireland, 1818</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"soffra per circa i primi sei mesi dopo avere 
lasciato la sede": John Doyle scrive a casa in Irlanda, 1818</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Υποφέρετε για για τους πρώτους έξι μήνες μετά από 
να αφήσει τη"Οικία"": Θ*Ιοχν Doyle Writes Home στην 
Ιρλανδία, 1818</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"sufra para alrededor los primeros seis meses 
después de salir del hogar": Juan Doyle escribe a casa a 
Irlanda, 1818</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the years after the Revolution many immigrants to the United States were political radicals, including John Doyle's father, who participated in the Irish Republican revolt against Great Britain in 1798 and later emigrated to Philadelphia. Like John Doyle, the author of this letter, many migrants brought craft skills and looked for work in the workshops and manufacturies of the new nation. When Doyle crossed the Atlantic in 1818 he quickly learned that small-scale entrepreneurship was more lucrative than sticking with his printing trade. Later immigration swelled as some two million Irish came to the United States between 1820 and 1860. The catastrophic Irish Potato Famine of 1845-49 sent hundreds of thousands (250,000 in 1851 alone) to disembark in cities where they faced economic hardships and ethnic discrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Jahren, nachdem die Umdrehung viele 
Immigranten in die Vereinigten Staaten politische Radikale, 
einschließlich John Doyles Vater waren, der am irischen 
republikanischen Aufruhr gegen Großbritannien 1798 und an späterem 
ausgewandert nach Philadelphia teilnahm. Wie John Doyle, machen 
der Autor dieses Zeichens, viele geholte Wanderer Fähigkeiten und 
gesuchte Arbeit in den Werkstätten und in den manufacturies der neuen
Nation in Handarbeit. Als Doyle den Atlantik 1818 kreuzte, 
erfuhr er schnell, daß kleinräumige Unternehmergeisten lukrativer 
als waren, haftend mit seinem druckenhandel. Neuere Immigration 
schwoll als etwas zwei Million Iren kam in die Vereinigten Staaten 
zwischen 1820 und 1860. Der verhängnisvolle irische 
Kartoffel-Hunger von 1845-49 sendete Hunderte Tausenden (250.000 in 
1851 allein) um in den Städte auszuschiffen, in denen sie 
ökonomische Härten und ethnische Unterscheidung gegenüberstellten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En années après que la révolution beaucoup 
d'immigrés vers les Etats-Unis aient été les radicaux politiques, y
compris le père de John Doyle, qui a participées à la révolte 
républicaine irlandaise contre la Grande-Bretagne en 1798 et à plus 
tard émigré à Philadelphie. Comme John Doyle, l'auteur de 
cette lettre, beaucoup de migrants apportés ouvrent les 
qualifications et le travail recherché dans les ateliers et les 
manufacturies de la nouvelle nation. Quand Doyle a croisé 
l'Océan atlantique en 1818 il a rapidement appris que l'esprit 
d'entreprise de petite taille était plus lucratif que collant avec 
son commerce d'impression. L'immigration postérieure a gonflé 
en tant qu'environ deux millions d'Irlandais est venue aux Etats-Unis 
entre 1820 et 1860. La famine irlandaise catastrophique de pomme
de terre de 1845-49 a envoyé des centaines de milliers (250.000 dans 
1851 seuls) pour débarquer dans les villes où elles ont fait face à
des difficultés économiques et à la discrimination ethnique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos anos depois que a volta muitos immigrants aos 
estados unidos era radicais políticos, including o pai de John Doyle,
que participou na revolta republicana irish de encontro a Grâ 
Bretanha em 1798 e em mais atrasado emigrated a Filadélfia. 
Como John Doyle, o autor desta letra, muitos emigrantes trazidos
craft habilidades e o trabalho procurado nas oficinas e nos 
manufacturies da nação nova. Quando Doyle cruzou o Atlântico 
em 1818 aprendeu rapidamente que o empreendimento small-scale era mais
lucrative do que furando com seu comércio imprimindo. Um 
immigration mais atrasado inchou como um dois milhão irish veio aos 
estados unidos entre 1820 e 1860. O famine irish catastrófico 
da batata de 1845-49 emitiu centenas dos milhares (250.000 em 1851 
sozinhos) para disembark nas cidades onde enfrentaram hardships 
econômicos e a discriminação étnica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante gli anni dopo che la rivoluzione molti 
immigranti al unito Dichiarasse avevano luogo i radicali 
politici, compreso il padre del John Doyle, che ha partecipato alla 
sommossa Repubblicana irlandese contro la Gran Bretagna in 1798 ed a 
successivamente emigrato a Filadelfia. Come John Doyle, l'autore
di questa lettera, molti migranti ha portato le abilità del mestiere 
ed ha cercato il lavoro nei workshop e nei manufacturies di nuova 
nazione. Quando Doyle ha attraversato l'Atlantico in 1818 ha 
imparato rapidamente che l'attività imprenditoriale su scala ridotta 
era più lucrativa dell'attaccando con il suo commercio di stampa. 
L'immigrazione successiva ha gonfiato come circa due milione 
Irlandesi è venuto al unito Dichiara fra 1820 e 1860. La
carestia irlandese catastrofica della patata di 1845-49 ha trasmesso 
le centinaia delle migliaia (250.000 in 1851 soli) per sbarcare in 
città in cui hanno affrontato le difficoltà economiche e la 
distinzione etnica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στα έτη μετά από την επανάσταση πολλοί μετανάστες 
στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες ήταν πολιτικοί ριζοσπάστες, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του πατέρα John Doyle's, ο οποίος 
συμμετείχε στην ιρλανδική δημοκρατική επανάσταση ενάντια στη 
Μεγάλη Βρετανία το 1798 και αργότερα μεταναστεύω στη 
Φιλαδέλφεια. Όπως John Doyle, ο συντάκτης αυτής της 
επιστολής, πολλοί μετανάστες έφεραν τις δεξιότητες τεχνών και 
έψαξαν την εργασία στα εργαστήρια και manufacturies του νέου 
έθνους. Όταν Doyle διέσχισε τον Ατλαντικό το 1818 
γρήγορα έμαθε ότι το μικρής κλίμακας επιχειρηματικό πνεύμα 
ήταν πιό προσοδοφόρο από κολλώντας με το εμπόριο εκτύπωσής 
του. Η πιό πρόσφατη μετανάστευση πρήστηκε καθώς περίπου 
δύο εκατομμύριο Ιρλανδός έρχομαι στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες μεταξύ
1820 και 1860. Η καταστροφική ιρλανδική πείνα πατατών 
1845-49 έστειλε τις εκατοντάδες χιλιάδες (250.000 το 1851 
μόνα) για να αποβηβάσει στις πόλεις όπου αντιμετώπισαν τις 
οικονομικές δυσκολίες και την εθνική διάκριση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años después de que la revolución muchos
inmigrantes a los Estados Unidos fuera radicales políticos, 
incluyendo el padre de Juan Doyle, que participó en la rebelión 
republicana irlandesa contra Gran Bretaña en 1798 y más adelante 
emigrada a Philadelphia. Como Juan Doyle, el autor de 
esta carta, muchos nómadas traídos hace habilidades y el trabajo a 
mano buscado en los talleres y los manufacturies de la nueva nación. 
Cuando Doyle cruzó el Atlántico en 1818 él aprendió 
rápidamente que el espíritu emprendedor en reducida escala era más 
lucrativo que pegándose con su comercio de impresión. Una 
inmigración más última se hinchó como cierto dos millones de 
irlandeses vino a los Estados Unidos entre 1820 y 1860. El 
hambre irlandesa catastrófica de la patata de 1845-49 envió 
centenares de los millares (250.000 en 1851 solos) para desembarcar en
las ciudades en donde hicieron frente a dificultades económicas y a 
la discriminación étnica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086863</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104545</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/suffer-for-about-the-first-six-months-after-leaving-home-john-doyle-writes-home-to-ireland-1818</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
