<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107568</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107568</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087049</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The shame of America."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Schande von Amerika."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la honte de l'Amérique."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o shame de América."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la vergogna dell'America."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η ντροπή της Αμερικής."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la vergüenza de América."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By 1919, the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), an organization founded in 1909 to advocate for political and social equality for African Americans, had 91,000 thousand members. From its earliest years, the NAACP lobbied Congress to pass a federal law against lynching, the violent and public murder of African Americans still carried out by mobs in many southern states in the early twentieth century (and indeed into the 1950s). During November, 1922, the NAACP ran this full-page advertisement in the  New York Times  and other newspapers, pressing for passage of the Dyer anti-lynching bill. Passed in the House of Representatives by a two-to-one majority, the anti-lynching bill was subsequently filibustered and defeated in the U.S. Senate. Despite the NAACP's vigorous efforts through the 1930s and the introduction of several subsequent anti-lynching bills, the U.S. Congress never outlawed lynching.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum 1919 hatten die nationale Verbindung für die 
Zuführung der Farbiger (NAACP), eine Organisation, die 1909 
gegründet wurde, um für politische und Sozialgleichheit für 
afrikanische Amerikaner zu befürworten, 91.000 tausend Bauteile. 
Von seinen frühen Jahren, vom NAACP beeinflußter Kongreß, zum
eines Bundesgesetzes gegen das Lynchen, vom heftigen und allgemeinen 
Mord an den afrikanischen Amerikanern noch durchgeführt durch Pöbel 
in vielen südlichen Zuständen im frühen zwanzigsten Jahrhundert zu 
verabschieden (und in der Tat in die fünfziger Jahre). Während
Novembers 1922, ließ das NAACP diese ganzseitige Reklameanzeige in 
den New York Zeiten und in anderen Zeitungen laufen und betätigte 
sich für Durchgang des Anti-lynchenden Bills des Farbstoffs. 
Überschritten in das Repräsentantenhaus durch a zwei--ein zur 
Majorität, wurde der Anti-lynchende Bill nachher im VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Senat obstruiert und besiegt. Trotz der NAACP's 
kräftigen Bemühungen durch die dreißiger Jahre und der Einleitung 
einiger folgender Anti-lynchender Bille, ächtete der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Kongreß nie das Lynchen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">D'ici 1919, l'association nationale pour l'avancement des 
personnes de couleur (NAACP), une organisation fondée en 1909 pour 
préconiser pour l'égalité politique et sociale pour les Américains
africains, ont eu 91.000 mille membres. De ses premières 
années, du NAACP le congrès incité pour passer une loi fédérale 
contre lyncher, du meurtre violent et public des Américains africains
effectué toujours par des foules dans beaucoup d'états méridionaux 
au vingtième siècle tôt (et en effet dans les années 50). 
Pendant novembre, 1922, le NAACP a exécuté cette publicité 
sur une page entière en temps de New York et d'autres journaux, 
encourageant le passage de la facture anti-lynchante de tinctorial. 
Passé dans la chambre des représentants par a deux--un à la 
majorité, la facture anti-lynchante a été ultérieurement 
flibustée et défaite dans le sénat des ETATS-UNIS. En dépit 
des efforts vigoureux de NAACP's par les années 30 et de 
l'introduction de plusieurs factures anti-lynchantes ultérieures, le 
congrès des ETATS-UNIS n'a jamais proscrit lyncher.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Por 1919, a associação nacional para o avanço dos povos
coloridos (NAACP), uma organização fundada em 1909 para advogar para
a igualdade política e social para americanos africanos, tiveram 
91.000 mil membros. De seus anos mais adiantados, do NAACP 
congress lobbied para passar uma lei federal de encontro a lynching, 
do assassinato violento e público de americanos africanos realizado 
ainda por mobs em muitos estados do sul no vigésimo século adiantado
(e certamente nos 1950s). Durante novembro, 1922, o NAACP 
funcionou esta propaganda full-page nos tempos de New York e em outros
jornais, pressionando para a passagem da conta anti-anti-lynching do 
dyer. Passado na casa de representantes por a dois--um à 
maioria, a conta anti-anti-lynching filibustered e foi derrotada 
subseqüentemente no senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Apesar dos 
esforços vigorosos de NAACP's com os 1930s e da introdução de 
diversas contas anti-anti-lynching subseqüentes, o congress de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS nunca outlawed lynching.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro 1919, l'associazione nazionale per l'avanzamento 
della gente colorata (NAACP), un'organizzazione fondata in 1909 per 
sostenere per uguaglianza politica e sociale per gli Americani 
africani, hanno avute 91.000 mila membri. Dai relativi primi 
anni, il NAACP congresso incitato per approvare una legge federale 
contro lynching, l'omicidio violento e pubblico degli Americani 
africani ancora effettuato dai mobs in molti del sud dichiara 
nel ventesimo secolo in anticipo (ed effettivamente negli anni 50). 
Durante il mese di novembre, del 1922, il NAACP ha fatto 
funzionare questa pubblicità fuori testo in tempi de New York ed 
altri giornali, facenti pressione per il passaggio della fattura 
anti-anti-lynching del tintoriale. Passato nella Camera dei 
rappresentanti dalla a due--u'alla maggioranza, la fattura 
anti-anti-lynching successivamente filibustered e sconfitto stata nel 
senato degli STATI UNITI. Malgrado gli sforzi vigorosi di 
NAACP's con i 1930s e l'introduzione di parecchie fatture 
anti-anti-lynching successive, il congresso degli STATI UNITI non ha 
proscritto mai lynching.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέχρι το 1919, η εθνική ένωση για την πρόοδο των 
έγχρωμων ανθρώπων (NAACP), μιας οργάνωσης που ιδρύθηκε το 
1909 για να υποστηρίξει για την πολιτική και κοινωνική ισότητα 
για αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς, είχε 91.000 χιλιάες μέλη. 
Από των πιό στις αρχές ετών του, το NAACP πίεσε το 
συνέδριο για να περάσει έναν ομοσπονδιακό νόμο ενάντια στο 
λυντσάρισμα, τη βίαια και δημόσια δολοφονία αφρικανικών 
Αμερικανών που πραγματοποιήθηκε ακόμα από τους όχλους σε πολλά 
νότια κράτη στις αρχές του εικοστού αιώνα (και πράγματι στη 
δεκαετία του '50). Κατά τη διάρκεια τον Νοεμβρίου, του 
1922, το NAACP έτρεξε αυτήν την ολόκληρης σελίδας διαφήμιση
στους New York Times και άλλες εφημερίδες, που πατούν για 
τη μετάβαση του dyer αντι-λυντσάροντας δισεκατομμυρίου στον 
οίκο των αντιπροσώπων από μια δύο-$$$-ΜΙΑ πλειοψηφία που πέρασε,
ο λογαριασμός αντι-λυντσαρίσματος ήταν στη συνέχεια και νίκησαν 
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉ Σύγκλητο. Παρά τις έντονες προσπάθειες του
NAACP μέσω της δεκαετίας του '30 και την εισαγωγή διάφορων 
επόμενων λογαριασμών αντι-λυντσαρίσματος, το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ συνέδριο
δεν πρόγραψε ποτέ το λυντσάρισμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes de 1919, la asociación nacional para el adelanto de
la gente coloreada (NAACP), una organización fundada en 1909 para 
abogar para la igualdad política y social para los americanos 
africanos, tenían 91.000 mil miembros. De sus años, del NAACP 
congreso cabildeado para aprobar una ley federal contra lynching, del 
asesinato violento y público de americanos africanos todavía 
realizado por las multitudes en muchos estados meridionales en el 
vigésimo siglo temprano (y de hecho en los años 50). Durante 
noviembre de 1922, el NAACP ejecutó este anuncio full-page en los 
tiempos de Nueva York y otros periódicos, presionando para el paso de
la cuenta contra-anti-lynching el tintóreo. Pasado en la 
cámara de representantes por a dos--uno a mayoría, la cuenta 
contra-anti-lynching filibustered y fue derrotada posteriormente en el
senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS. A pesar de los esfuerzos vigorosos de 
NAACP's con los años 30 y la introducción de varias cuentas 
contra-anti-lynching subsecuentes, el congreso de ESTADOS UNIDOS nunca
proscribió lynching.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087049</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107568</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-shame-of-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
