<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103397</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103397</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202523</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">It's in the Garbage (Archaeology)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Es ist im Abfall (Archäologie)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Il est dans les ordures (archéologie)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Está no lixo (archaeology)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">È nell'immondizia (archaeology)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Είναι στα απορρίματα (αρχαιολογία)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Está en la basura (archaeology)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The unusable or unwanted remnants of everyday life end up in the garbage. By studying what people have thrown away, archaeologists can learn a great deal about a culture. This is true not only of prehistoric peoples who left no written record about their lives, but also of people today. In this lesson, students will examine everyday garbage to hypothesize about the lives of those who used it. This unit is based on Lesson 1.8 in Intrigue of the Past: North Carolina's First Peoples, which is part of a national curriculum-development program called Project Archeology</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die unbrauchbaren oder unerwünschten Reste der 
täglichen Lebensdauer beenden oben im Abfall. Indem sie 
studieren welche Leute weg geworfen haben, können Archäologen über 
eine Kultur sehr viel erlernen. Dieses ist nicht nur von den 
prähistorischen Völkern zutreffend, die link kein schriftlicher Satz
über ihre Lebensdauern, aber auch der Leute heute. In dieser 
Lektion überprüfen Kursteilnehmer täglichen Abfall, um über die 
Leben von denen zu theoretisieren, die ihn benutzten. Diese 
Maßeinheit basiert auf Lektion 1.8 in der Intrige der Vergangenheit: 
Nord-Carolina erste Völker, das ein Teil eines nationalen 
Lehrplan-Entwicklung Programms ist, riefen Project Archeology an</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les restes inutilisables ou non désirés de la 
vie quotidienne terminent vers le haut dans les ordures. En 
étudiant quelles personnes ont jeté loin, les archéologues peuvent 
se renseigner beaucoup sur une culture. C'est vrai non seulement
des peuples préhistoriques qui gauche aucun enregistrement écrit au 
sujet de leurs vies, mais également des personnes aujourd'hui. 
Dans cette leçon, les étudiants examineront les ordures 
journalières pour présumer au sujet des vies de ceux qui les ont 
utilisées. Cette unité est basée sur la leçon 1.8 dans 
l'intrigue du passé : Les premiers peuples du nord de la 
Caroline, qui fait partie d'un programme national de programme 
d'études-développement ont appelé Project Archeology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os restos unusable ou não desejados da vida 
diária terminam acima no lixo. Estudando que povos jogaram 
afastado, os arqueólogos podem aprender bastante sobre uma cultura. 
Isto é verdadeiro não somente dos povos pré-históricos que 
esquerdo nenhum registro escrito sobre suas vidas, mas também dos 
povos hoje. Nesta lição, os estudantes examinarão o lixo 
diário para hypothesize sobre as vidas daqueles que o usaram. 
Esta unidade é baseada na lição 1.8 no intrigue do passado: 
Os primeiros povos de North.carolina, que é parte de um 
programa nacional do curriculum-desenvolvimento chamaram Projeto 
Archeology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I resti inutilizzabili o indesiderabili di vita di
tutti i giorni si concludono in su nell'immondizia. Studiando 
che gente ha gettato via, gli archeologhi possono imparare molto circa
una coltura. Ciò è vero non soltanto per la gente prehistoric 
che di sinistra nessun record scritto circa le loro vite, ma anche 
della gente oggi. In questa lezione, gli allievi esamineranno 
l'immondizia giornaliere per supporre circa le vite di coloro che la 
ha usata. Questa unità è basata sulla lezione 1.8 nell'intrigo
dell'esperienza: La prima gente del North.carolina, che fa parte
di un programma nazionale di programma di studi-sviluppo ha chiamato 
il Project l'Archeology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα ακατάλληλα προς χρήση ή ανεπιθύμητα υπόλοιπα της 
καθημερινής ζωής καταλήγουν στα απορρίματα. Με τη μελέτη 
ποιου άνθρωποι έχουν ρίξει μακριά, οι αρχαιολόγοι μπορούν να 
μάθουν πολύ για έναν πολιτισμό. Αυτό ισχύει όχι μόνο για
τους προϊστορικούς λαούς που δεν άφησαν κανένα γραπτό αρχείο 
για τις ζωές τους, αλλά και των ανθρώπων σήμερα. Σε αυτό το
μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές θα εξετάσουν τα καθημερινά απορρίματα για 
να υποθέσουν για τις ζωές εκείνοι που το χρησιμοποίησαν. 
Αυτή η μονάδα είναι βασισμένη στο μάθημα 1,8 στη 
δολοπλοκία του παρελθόντος: Οι πρώτοι λαοί της βόρειας 
Καρολίνας, που είναι μέρος ενός εθνικού προγράμματος πρόγραμμα 
σπουδών-ανάπτυξης κάλεσαν την αρχαιολογία έργου</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los remanente inutilizables o indeseados de la 
vida diaria terminan para arriba en la basura. Estudiando qué 
gente ha lanzado lejos, los arqueólogos pueden aprender mucho sobre 
una cultura. Esto es verdad no solamente de la gente 
prehistórica que izquierdo ningún expediente escrito sobre sus 
vidas, pero también de la gente hoy. En esta lección, los 
estudiantes examinarán la basura diaria para presumir sobre las vidas
de los que la utilizaron. Esta unidad se basa en la lección 1.8
en el encanto del pasado: La primera gente de Carolina del 
Norte, que es parte de un programa nacional del plan de 
estudios-desarrollo llamó a Proyecto Archeology</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNC ARCHAEOLOGY
FN:UNC ARCHAEOLOGY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202523</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103397</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/its-in-the-garbage-archaeology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
