<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107626</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107626</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086775</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Ration Day."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Zuteilung-Tag."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Jour de Ration."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Da "Dia Ração."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Giorno Della Razione."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ημέρα δελτίων τροφίμων."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Día De la Ración."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A master distributed provisions in an illustration from a weekly newspaper report on the operations of a plantation around 1860. The engraving suggested that this planter provided his slaves with a varied and nutritious diet, which was not usually the case. Slaves typically received a weekly ration of only three and a half pounds of salt pork or bacon and a quarter bushel of cornmeal. Although high in calories needed to perform heavy labor, that diet was seriously deficient nutritionally. This engraving did not show that slaves who wished to supplement their meager and boring diet had to rely on the vegetable gardens and hunting privileges some planters allowed them. Because of their unrelenting workday, slaves had to perform these tasks early in the morning or late at night.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Berichten verteilte Vorlagenbestimmungen in einer 
Abbildung von einer wöchentlichen Zeitung über die Operationen einer
Plantage um 1860. Der Stich schlug vor, daß dieser Pflanzer 
seine Sklaven mit einer mannigfaltigen und nahrhaften Diät versah, 
die nicht normalerweise der Fall war. Sklaven empfingen 
gewöhnlich eine wöchentliche Zuteilung von nur drei und eine Hälfte
zerstößt vom Salzschweinefleisch oder Speck und ein 
Viertelscheffel Getreidemehl. Obgleich Höhe in den Kalorien 
schwere Arbeit durchführen mußte, war diese Diät ernährungsmäßig
ernsthaft unzulänglich. Dieser Stich zeigte nicht, daß 
Sklaven, die ihr mageres ergänzen möchten und Bohrendiät auf die 
Gemüsegärten bauen mußten und die Jagd einige Pflanzer erlaubte sie
privilegiert. Wegen ihres unnachgiebigen Arbeitstags mußten 
Sklaven diese Aufgaben früh morgens oder spät nachts durchführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dispositions distribuées principales dans une 
illustration d'un journal hebdomadaire rendent compte des exécutions 
d'une plantation autour de 1860. La gravure a suggéré que ce 
planteur ait fourni à ses esclaves un régime divers et nutritif, qui
n'était pas habituellement le cas. Les esclaves ont typiquement
reçu une ration hebdomadaire seulement de trois des livres et demi de
porc ou de lard de sel et un boisseau quart de farine d'avoine. 
Bien que la haute dans les calories ait dû exécuter le 
travail lourd, ce régime était sérieusement déficient 
nutritionnellement. Cette gravure n'a pas prouvé que les 
esclaves qui ont souhaité compléter leur maigre et régime de 
sondage ont dû compter sur les potagers et la chasse favorise 
quelques planteurs les a permis. En raison de leur jour ouvrable
persistant, les esclaves ont dû exécuter ces derniers 
charge tôt le matin ou tard la nuit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As provisões distribuídas mestras em uma ilustração de
um jornal semanal relatam nas operações de uma plantação em torno 
de 1860. O engraving sugeriu que este plantador forneceu seus 
escravos com uma dieta variada e nutritious, que não fosse geralmente
o caso. Os escravos receberam tipicamente uma ração semanal de
somente três e as libras de uma metade da carne de porco ou do bacon 
de sal e um bushel de um quarto do cornmeal. Embora a elevação
nos calories necessitasse executar o trabalho pesado, essa dieta era 
seriamente deficient nutritiva. Este engraving não mostrou que 
os escravos que desejaram suplementar seu meager e dieta da 
perfuração tiveram que confiar nos jardins vegetais e a caça 
privilegia alguns plantadores os permitiu. Por causa de seu 
workday unrelenting, os escravos tiveram que executar estas tarefas 
cedo na manhã ou tarde na noite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le disposizioni distribuite matrici in un'illustrazione da
un giornale settimanale segnalano sui funzionamenti di una piantagione
verso 1860. L'incisione ha suggerito che questa piantatrice ha 
fornito ai suoi schiavi una dieta varia e nutriente, che non era 
solitamente il caso. Gli schiavi hanno ricevuto tipicamente una 
razione settimanale di soltanto tre e le libbre di metà del porco o 
della pancetta affumicata del sale e un bushel quarto di farina 
d'avena. Anche se il high nelle calorie ha dovuto effettuare il 
lavoro pesante, quella dieta era nutrizionalmente seriamente 
carente. Questa incisione non ha indicato che gli schiavi che 
hanno desiderato completare il loro meager e dieta dell'alesaggio 
hanno dovuto contare sugli orti e la caccia privilegia alcune 
piantatrici li ha permessi. A causa del loro workday 
inesorabile, gli schiavi hanno dovuto effettuare queste mansioni 
presto alla mattina o in ritardo alla notte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κύριες διανεμημένες παροχές σε μια απεικόνιση από μια
εβδομαδιαία έκθεση εφημερίδων σχετικά με τις διαδικασίες μιας 
φυτείας περίπου 1860. Η χάραξη πρότεινε ότι αυτός ο 
καλλιεργητής παρείχε στους σκλάβους του μια ποικίλη και θρεπτική 
διατροφή, η οποία δεν ήταν συνήθως η περίπτωση. Οι σκλάβοι
έλαβαν χαρακτηριστικά ένα εβδομαδιαίο δελτίο τροφίμων μόνο 
τριών και ένα μισό σφυροκοπά του αλατισμένου χοιρινού κρέατος 
ή του μπέϊκον και ενός μπούσελ τετάρτων cornmeal. Αν 
και υψηλός στις θερμίδες έπρεπε να εκτελέσει τη βαριά εργασία, 
εκείνη η διατροφή ήταν σοβαρά ανεπαρκής θρεπτικά. Αυτή η 
χάραξη δεν έδειξε ότι οι σκλάβοι που επιθύμησαν να συμπληρώσουν 
την πενιχρή και τρυπώντας διατροφή τους έπρεπε να στηριχθούν 
στους φυτικούς κήπους και το κυνήγι παρέχει προνόμια σε μερικούς
καλλιεργητές τους επέτρεψε. Λόγω της άκαμπτης εργάσιμης 
ημέρας τους, οι σκλάβοι έπρεπε να εκτελέσουν αυτές τις 
στοιχειώδεις εργασίες νωρίς το πρωί ή αργά τη νύχτα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las provisiones distribuidas principales en una 
ilustración de un periódico semanal señalan sobre las operaciones 
de una plantación alrededor de 1860. El grabado sugirió que 
este plantador proveiera de sus esclavos una dieta variada y 
nutritiva, que no era generalmente el caso. Los esclavos 
recibieron típicamente una ración semanal de solamente tres y libras
de una mitad de cerdo o de tocino de la sal y un celemín cuarto de 
harina de maíz. Aunque el colmo en calorías necesitó realizar
el trabajo pesado, esa dieta era seriamente deficiente alimenticio. 
Este grabado no mostró que los esclavos que deseaban suplir su 
pobre y dieta del taladro tuvieron que confiar en los jardines 
vegetales y la caza privilegia algunos plantadores los permitió. 
Debido a su día laborable implacable, los esclavos tuvieron que
realizar estas tareas temprano en la mañana o tarde en la noche.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086775</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107626</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/ration-day</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
