<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107370</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107370</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086136</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Executive Order 9066: The President Authorizes Japanese Relocation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausführungsverordnung 9066: Der Präsident 
Authorizes Japanese Relocation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commande Exécutive 9066 : Le Président 
Authorizes Japanese Relocation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ordem Executiva 9066: O Presidente Autorizar 
Japonês Relocation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ordine Esecutivo 9066: Il Presidente 
Authorizes Japanese Relocation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκτελεστική κατάταξη 9066: Ο Πρόεδρος 
Authorizes Japanese Relocation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Orden Ejecutiva 9066: El Presidente 
Authorizes Japanese Relocation</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In an atmosphere of World War II hysteria, President Roosevelt, encouraged by officials at all levels of the federal government, authorized the internment of tens of thousands of American citizens of Japanese ancestry and resident aliens from Japan. Roosevelt's Executive Order 9066, dated February 19, 1942, gave the military broad powers to ban any citizen from a fifty- to sixty-mile-wide coastal area stretching from Washington state to California and extending inland into southern Arizona. The order also authorized transporting these citizens to assembly centers hastily set up and governed by the military in California, Arizona, Washington state, and Oregon. Although it is not well known, the same executive order (and other war-time orders and restrictions) were also applied to smaller numbers of residents of the United States who were of Italian or German descent. For example, 3,200 resident aliens of Italian background were arrested and more than 300 of them were interned. About 11,000 German residents--including some naturalized citizens--were arrested and more than 5000 were interned. Yet while these individuals (and others from those groups) suffered grievous violations of their civil liberties, the war-time measures applied to Japanese Americans were worse and more sweeping, uprooting entire communities and targeting citizens as well as resident aliens.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In einer Atmosphäre der WeltkriegHysterie, 
autorisierte Präsident Roosevelt, angeregt von den Beamten auf allen 
Stufen der Bundesregierung, die Internierung von 10 Tausenden der 
amerikanischen Bürger japanischen Geschlechtes und der 
Residentausländer von Japan. Roosevelts die 
Ausführungsverordnung 9066, datiert Februar 19, 1942, gab die 
militärischen ausgedehnten Energien, irgendeinen Bürger von fünfzig
zum sechzig-Meile-breiten Küstenbereich, der vom Staat Washington zu 
Kalifornien ausdehnen und zum Ausdehnen zu verbieten inländisch in 
südliches Arizona. Die Ordnung auch autorisierte das 
Transportieren dieser Bürger zur Versammlung, die Mitten eilig 
aufstellten und regelte durch das Militär Kalifornien, Arizona-, Im 
Staat Washington und in Oregon. Obgleich sie nicht weithin 
bekannt ist, wurden die gleiche Ausführungsverordnung (und andere 
Kriegordnungen und -beschränkungen) auch an den kleineren Anzahlen 
von Bewohnern der Vereinigten Staaten angewendet, die vom 
italienischen oder deutschen Abfall waren. Z.B. wurden 3.200 
Residentausländer italienischer Hintergrund festgehalten und mehr als
300 von ihnen wurden interniert. Ungefähr 11.000 deutsche 
Bewohner -- einschließlich einige eingebürgerte Bürger -- wurden 
und mehr als 5000 wurden interniert festgehalten. Dennoch, 
während diese Einzelpersonen (und andere von jenen Gruppen) grievous 
Verletzungen ihrer Zivilfreiheiten erlitten, waren die Kriegmasse, die
an den japanischen Amerikanern angewendet wurden und ausgedehntere 
falscher, uprooting gesamte Gemeinschaften und Zielenbürger sowie 
Residentausländer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans une atmosphère d'hystérie de la deuxième 
guerre mondiale, le Président Roosevelt, encouragé par des 
fonctionnaires à tous les niveaux du gouvernement fédéral, a 
autorisé l'internement des dizaines de milliers de citoyens 
américains d'ascendance japonaise et d'étrangers résidents du 
Japon. La commande exécutive 9066 de Roosevelt, datée du 
19 février 1942, a donné les larges puissances militaires 
d'interdire n'importe quel citoyen des cinquante à la zone côtière 
soixante-mille-large s'étendant de l'état de Washington À la 
Californie et à étendre intérieur en l'Arizona méridional. 
La commande a également autorisé transporter ces citoyens à 
l'assemblage que les centres ont installé à la hâte et a régi par 
les militaires l'état de Washington de la Californie, de l'Arizona, 
et en Orégon. Bien qu'elle ne soit pas bien connue, la même 
commande exécutive (et d'autres commandes et restrictions de temps de
guerre) ont été également appliquées à de plus petits nombres de 
résidants des Etats-Unis qui étaient de descente italienne ou 
allemande. Par exemple, 3.200 étrangers résidents de fond 
italien ont été arrêtés et plus de 300 d'entre eux ont été 
internés. Environ 11.000 résidants allemands -- comprenant 
quelques citoyens naturalisés -- ont été arrêtés et plus de 5000 
ont été internés. Pourtant tandis que ces individus (et 
d'autres de ces groupes) souffraient des violations pénibles de leurs
libertés civiles, les mesures de temps de guerre appliquées aux 
Américains japonais étaient plus mauvaises et les communautés 
entières plus rapides et plus déracinantes et des citoyens 
d'optimisation aussi bien que les étrangers résidents.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em uma atmosfera do hysteria da segunda guerra 
mundial, o presidente Roosevelt, incentivado por oficiais em todos os 
níveis do governo federal, autorizou o internamento dos dez dos 
milhares de cidadãos americanos do ancestry japonês e dos 
estrangeiros residentes de Japão. A ordem executiva 9066 de 
Roosevelt, datada fevereiro 19, 1942, deu as potências largas 
militares proibir qualquer cidadão de uns cinqüênta à área 
litoral sessenta-milha-larga que esticam do estado de Washington a 
Califórnia e a estender inland no arizona do sul. A ordem 
também autorizou transportar estes cidadãos ao conjunto que os 
centros se ajustaram hastily acima e governou-o pelas forças armadas 
no estado de Califórnia, de arizona, de Washington, e no Oregon. 
Embora não fosse sabido bom, a mesma ordem executiva (e outras 
ordens e limitações do war-time) foram aplicadas também aos 
números menores dos residentes dos estados unidos que eram da descida
italiana ou alemão. Para o exemplo, 3.200 estrangeiros 
residentes do fundo italiano foram prendidos e mais de 300 deles foram
internados. Aproximadamente 11.000 residentes alemães -- 
including alguns cidadãos naturalizados -- foram prendidos e mais de 
5000 foram internados. Contudo quando estes indivíduos (e 
outros daqueles grupos) sofreram violações grievous de suas 
liberdades civis, as medidas do war-time aplicadas aos americanos 
japoneses eram mais más e umas comunidades inteiras mais 
arrebatadoras, desarraigando e cidadãos da escolha de objectivos 
as.well.as os estrangeiros residentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In un atmosfera di hysteria della seconda guerra 
mondiale, il presidente Roosevelt, consigliato a dai funzionari a 
tutti i livelli del governo federale, ha autorizzato l'internamento 
dei dieci dei migliaia dei cittadini americani dell'ascendenza 
giapponese e degli stranieri residenti dal Giappone. L'ordine 
esecutivo 9066 del Roosevelt, datato 19 febbraio 1942, ha dato le 
vaste potenzi militari vietare qualunque cittadino dai cinquanta a 
zona costiera sessanta-miglio-larga che allunga da Washington 
dichiara alla California ed all'estensione interne in Arizona 
del sud. L'ordine egualmente ha autorizzato il trasporto dei 
questi cittadini al complessivo ch'i centri hanno installato 
frettolosamente ed ha governato dai militari nella California, 
Arizona, Washington dichiara e l'Oregon. Anche se non è 
ben nota, lo stesso ordine esecutivo (ed altri ordini e limitazioni di
war-time) egualmente sono stati applicati ai più piccoli numeri di 
residenti del unito Dichiara chi erano della discesa italiana o
tedesca. Per esempio, 3.200 stranieri residenti di priorità 
bassa italiana sono stati arrestati e più di 300 di loro sono stati 
internati. Circa 11.000 residenti tedeschi -- compreso alcuni 
cittadini naturalizzati -- sono stati arrestati e più di 5000 sono 
stati internati. Tuttavia mentre questi individui (ed altri da 
quei gruppi) hanno sofferto le violazioni grievous delle loro libertà
civili, le misure di war-time applicate agli Americani giapponesi 
erano più difettose e Comunità intere più ampe e di sradicamenti e 
cittadini di ottimizzazione così come gli stranieri residenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε μια ατμόσφαιρα της υστερίας παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, 
ο Πρόεδρος Roosevelt, που ενθαρρύνθηκε από τους ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους σε όλα τα επίπεδα της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης, 
ενέκρινε τον περιορισμό των δεκάδων χιλιάδων αμερικανικοί 
πολίτες της ιαπωνικής καταγωγής και εδρεύοντες αλλοδαποί από την
Ιαπωνία. Η εκτελεστική κατάταξη 9066 του Roosevelt, της
19ης Φεβρουαρίου ..1942, έδωσε τις στρατιωτικές ευρείες 
δυνάμεις να απαγορευθεί οποιοσδήποτε πολίτης από πενήντα - στην 
εξήντα-μίλι-ευρεία έκταση παράκτιας περιοχής από το κράτος της
Ουάσιγκτον σε Καλιφόρνια και να επεκταθεί εσωτερική στη νότια 
Αριζόνα. Η κατάταξη ενέκρινε επίσης τη μεταφορά αυτών των 
πολιτών στα κέντρα συμβολικών γλωσσών που οργανώθηκαν βιαστικά 
και που κυβερνήθηκαν από τους στρατιωτικούς σε Καλιφόρνια, την 
Αριζόνα, το κράτος της Ουάσιγκτον, και το Όρεγκον. Αν και 
δεν είναι ευρέως γνωστό, η ίδια εκτελεστική κατάταξη (και άλλοι
εν καιρώ πολέμου κατατάξεις και περιορισμοί) εφαρμόστηκαν επίσης
στους μικρότερους αριθμούς κατοίκων των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών που 
είμαι ιταλικής ή γερμανικής καταγωγής. Παραδείγματος 
χάριν, 3.200 εδρεύοντες αλλοδαποί του ιταλικού υποβάθρου 
συλλήφθηκαν και περισσότερο από 300 τους θέθηκαν υπό 
περιορισμό. Περίπου 11.000 γερμανικοί κάτοικοι -- 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων μερικών πολιτογραφημένων πολιτών -- 
συλλήφθηκαν και περισσότερο από 5000 θέθηκαν υπό περιορισμό. 
Ακόμα ενώ αυτά τα άτομα (και άλλα από εκείνες τις 
ομάδες) υπέστησαν τις σοβαρές παραβιάσεις των αστικών ελευθεριών
τους, τα εν καιρώ πολέμου μέτρα που εφαρμόστηκαν σε ιαπωνικούς 
Αμερικανούς ήταν χειρότερα και σκουπίζοντας, ξεριζώματος 
ολόκληρες κοινότητες και στοχοθέτηση των πολιτών καθώς επίσης 
και των εδρευόντων αλλοδαπών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En una atmósfera de la histeria de la Segunda 
Guerra Mundial, presidente Roosevelt, alentador por los funcionarios 
en todos los niveles del gobierno federal, autorizó la internación 
de diez de millares de ciudadanos americanos de ascendencia japonesa y
de extranjeros residentes de Japón. La orden ejecutiva 9066 de 
Roosevelt, anticuada 19 de febrero de 1942, dio las amplias 
potencias militares de prohibir a cualquier ciudadano de cincuenta al 
área costera sesenta-milla-ancha que estiraba del estado de 
Washington a California y a extender interior en el Arizona 
meridional. La orden también autorizó el transporte de estos 
ciudadanos al ensamblaje que los centros instalaron precipitado y 
gobernó por los militares en el estado de California, del Arizona, de
Washington, y Oregon. Aunque no es bien sabido, la misma orden 
ejecutiva (y otras órdenes y restricciones del tiempo de guerra) 
también fueron aplicadas a números más pequeños de los residentes 
de los Estados Unidos que estaban de pendiente italiana o alemana. 
Por ejemplo, arrestaron a 3.200 extranjeros residentes de fondo 
italiano y más de 300 de ellos fueron internados. Arrestaron a 
cerca de 11.000 residentes alemanes -- incluyendo algunos ciudadanos 
naturalizados -- y más de 5000 fueron internados. Con todo 
mientras que estos individuos (y otros de esos grupos) sufrieron 
violaciones penosas de sus libertades civiles, las medidas del tiempo 
de guerra aplicadas a los americanos japoneses eran peores y 
comunidades enteras más arrebatadoras, que desarraigaban ma's y los 
ciudadanos el apuntar así como los extranjeros residentes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086136</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107370</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/executive-order-9066-the-president-authorizes-japanese-relocation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
