<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106512</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106512</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202725</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Using Percent of Change to Measure NC Growth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verwenden von von Prozenten Änderung am Maß NC 
Wachstum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisation des pour cent de changement à la 
croissance de la mesure OR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usando por cento da mudança ao crescimento do NC 
da medida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Usando i percento di cambiamento a sviluppo di NC 
di misura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρησιμοποίηση των τοις εκατό της αλλαγής στην αύξηση 
μέτρου NC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usar por ciento de cambio al crecimiento del NC de 
la medida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students will work in small groups to use the Internet to gather data on the population growth for each of the 100 counties in NC from 1992 to 1995. From this data students will find the percent of increase/decrease for the counties they have been assigned. As a follow-up, the students will enter their data into a computer spreadsheet and from that spreadsheet, produce graphs of the information.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer arbeiten in den kleinen Gruppen, um 
das Internet zu benutzen, um Daten bezüglich des Bevölkerung 
Wachstums für jede der 100 Grafschaften in NC von 1992 bis 1995 zu 
erfassen. Von diesen Daten finden Kursteilnehmer die Prozente 
increase/decrease für die Grafschaften, die sie zugewiesen worden 
sind. Als Anschluß geben die Kursteilnehmer ihre Daten in eine 
Computerkalkulationstabelle und von dieser Kalkulationstabelle, 
Erzeugnisdiagramme der Informationen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants travailleront dans de petits groupes
pour employer l'Internet pour recueillir des données sur la 
croissance de population pour chacun des 100 comtés dans l'OR de 1992
à 1995. De ces données les étudiants trouveront les pour cent
d'increase/decrease pour les comtés qu'ils ont été affectés. 
Comme suivi, les étudiants saisiront leurs données dans un 
tableur d'ordinateur et de ce tableur, graphiques de produit 
d'information.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes trabalharão em grupos pequenos para 
usar o Internet recolher dados no crescimento da população para cada
um dos 100 condados no NC de 1992 a 1995. Destes dados os 
estudantes encontrarão os por cento de increase/decrease para os 
condados que foram atribuídos. Como uma continuação, os 
estudantes incorporarão seus dados em um spreadsheet do computador e 
desse spreadsheet, gráficos do produto da informação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi lavoreranno nei piccoli gruppi per 
usare il Internet per riunire i dati sullo sviluppo della 
popolazione per ciascuna delle 100 contee in NC da 1992 a 1995. 
Da questi dati allievi troveranno i percento di 
increase/decrease per le contee che sono stati assegnati. Come 
aggiornamento, gli allievi digiteranno i loro dati in un foglio 
elettronico del calcolatore e da quel foglio elettronico, grafici dei 
prodotti delle informazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα εργαστούν στις μικρές ομάδες για να 
χρησιμοποιήσουν το Διαδίκτυο για να συγκεντρώσουν τα στοιχεία 
όσον αφορά την αύξηση πληθυσμών για κάθε έναν από τους 100 
νομούς σε NC από το 1992 ως το 1995. Από αυτό το 
στοιχείο οι σπουδαστές θα βρούν τα τοις εκατό της αύξησης/της 
μείωσης για τους νομούς που έχουν ανατεθεί. Σαν συνέχιση, 
οι σπουδαστές θα εισαγάγουν τα στοιχεία τους σε έναν υπολογισμό 
με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet) υπολογιστών και από εκείνο 
τον υπολογισμό με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet), να παραγάγουν 
τις γραφικές παραστάσεις των πληροφοριών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes trabajarán en grupos pequeños 
para utilizar el Internet para recopilar datos sobre el crecimiento de
la población para cada uno de los 100 condados en el NC a partir de 
1992 a 1995. De estos datos los estudiantes encontrarán los por
ciento de increase/decrease para los condados que les han asignado. 
Como carta recordativa, los estudiantes incorporarán sus datos 
en una hoja de balance del ordenador y de esa hoja de balance, 
gráficos del producto de la información.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WANDA WASHBURN
FN:WANDA WASHBURN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202725</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106512</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/using-percent-of-change-to-measure-nc-growth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
