<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104437</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104437</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087208</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Unfortunate English People Suffer Here": An English Servant Writes Home</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Unglückliche Englische Leute Leiden Hier": 
Ein Englischer Bediensteter Schreibt Nach Hause</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Les  Anglais Malheureux Souffrons Ici" : 
Un Domestique Anglais Écrit À la maison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Povos Ingleses Infelizes Sofremos Aqui": 
Um Empregado Inglês Escreve Para casa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Gente Inglese Sfavorevole Soffriamo Qui": 
Un Servo Inglese Scrive A casa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ανεπιτυχείς αγγλικοί άνθρωποι υποφέρουμε εδώ": 
Ένας αγγλικός υπάλληλος γράφει τη "Οικία"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Gente Inglesa Desafortunada Sufrimos Aquí": 
Un Criado Inglés Escribe A casa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While some planters in the eighteenth-century Chesapeake began to build spacious mansions and rely on the labor of increasing numbers of white and black dependents, most white southerners lived in far humbler circumstances. In Maryland most small farmers were tenants, renting their land from larger landowners. Landless men and women worked as agricultural tenants, laborers, or domestic servants. Elizabeth Sprigs, a servant in a Maryland household, financed her passage from England in exchange for a term as an indentured servant (a frequent practice in the seventeenth century but more rare by the eighteenth). She wrote to her father in 1756 and complained bitterly of the brutal treatment by her master and the harsh privations of daily life, begging him to send clothing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während einige Pflanzer im Achtzehntjahrhundert 
Chesapeake anfingen, geräumige Villen aufzubauen und auf der Arbeit 
der zunehmenden Anzahlen von weißen und schwarzen Abhängigen zu 
beruhen, lebten die meisten weißen southerners unter weit 
bescheideneren Umständen. In Maryland waren die meisten kleinen
Landwirte die Pächter und mieteten ihr Land von den größeren 
Grundbesitzern. Anschlußlose Männer und Frauen arbeiteten als 
landwirtschaftliche Pächter, Arbeiter oder inländische Bedienstete. 
Elizabeth Sprigs, ein Bediensteter in einem Maryland Haushalt, 
finanziert ihrem Durchgang von England gegen eine Bezeichnung als 
indentured Bediensteten (eine häufige Praxis im seventeenth 
Jahrhundert aber ein seltener durch das achtzehnte). Sie schrieb
ihrem Vater 1756 und beschwerte sich bitterlich von der brutalen 
Behandlung durch ihren Meister und von den rauhen Nöten der 
täglichen Lebensdauer und bat ihn, Kleidung zu senden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que quelques planteurs dans le chesapeake 
de dix-huitième-siècle commençaient à construire les manoirs 
spacieux et à se fonder sur le travail des nombres croissants de 
personnes à charge blanches et noires, la plupart des habitants du sud 
blancs ont vécu dans des circonstances bien plus humbles. Dans 
le Maryland la plupart des petits fermiers étaient des locataires, 
louant leur terre de plus grands propriétaires fonciers. Les 
hommes sans terre et les femmes ont travaillé en tant que les 
locataires agricoles, les travailleurs, ou domestiques domestiques. 
Les Brins d'Elizabeth, un domestique dans un ménage du 
Maryland, financé son passage d'Angleterre en échange d'une limite 
en tant qu'indentured l'domestique (une pratique fréquente au 
dix-septième siècle mais plus rare par le dix-huitième). Elle
a écrit à son père en 1756 et s'est plainte amèrement du 
traitement brutal par son maître et des privations dures de la vie 
quotidienne, le priant d'envoyer l'habillement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando alguns plantadores no chesapeake de 
décimo-século começaram a construir mansions spacious e a confiar 
no trabalho de números crescentes dos dependentes brancos e pretos, a
maioria de southerners brancos viveram em circunstâncias distante 
mais humbler. Em Maryland a maioria de fazendeiros pequenos eram
tenants, alugando sua terra dos latifundiários maiores. Os 
homens e as mulheres landless trabalharam como tenants agriculturais, 
laborers, ou empregados domésticos. Os sprigs de Elizabeth, um 
empregado em uma casa de Maryland, financiada sua passagem de 
Inglaterra na troca para um termo como indentured o empregado (uma 
prática freqüente no décimo séptimo século mas mais raro pelo 
décimo oitavo). Escreveu a seu pai em 1756 e queixou-se 
amargamente do tratamento brutal por seu mestre e dos privations 
ásperos da vida diária, implorando o emitir a roupa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre alcune piantatrici nel chesapeake di 
diciottesimo-secolo hanno cominciato a costruire i mansions spaziosi 
ed a contare sul lavoro dei numeri aumentanti di dipendenti 
bianchi e neri, la maggior parte dei southerners bianchi hanno vissuto
nelle circostanze ben più humbler. In Maryland la maggior parte
di piccoli coltivatori erano inquilini, affittanti la loro terra dai 
più grandi latifondisti. Gli uomini e le donne landless hanno 
lavorato come gli inquilini agricoli, i lavoratori, o servi domestici.
Gli sprigs di Elizabeth, un servo in una famiglia del Maryland, 
finanziata il suo passaggio dall'Inghilterra in cambio di un termine 
come indentured il servo (una frequente pratica nel diciassettesimo 
secolo ma più raro dal diciottesimo). Ha scritto al suo padre 
in 1756 e si è lamentata amaramente del trattamento brutale dal suo 
supervisore e dei privations duri di vita quotidiana, elemosinante lo 
trasmettere i vestiti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ μερικοί καλλιεργητές chesapeake δέκατος-αιώνα 
άρχισαν να χτίζουν τα ευρύχωρα μέγαρα και να στηρίζονται στην 
εργασία των αυξανόμενων αριθμών άσπρων και μαύρων υποτελών, οι 
περισσότεροι λευκοί νότιοι έζησαν humbler μακριά στις 
περιστάσεις. Στη Μέρυλαντ οι περισσότεροι μικροί αγρότες 
ήταν μισθωτές, που νοικιάζουν το έδαφός τους από τα μεγαλύτερα 
landowners. Οι landless άνδρες και οι γυναίκες 
εργάστηκαν ως γεωργικοί μισθωτές, laborers, ή εσωτερικοί 
υπάλληλοι. Θ*Εληζαψετχ Sprigs, ένας υπάλληλος σε μια 
οικογένεια της Μέρυλαντ, χρηματοδότησε τη μετάβασή της από την 
Αγγλία σε αντάλλαγμα ενός όρου δεδομένου ότι ο υπάλληλος (μια 
συχνή πρακτική στο δέκατο έβδομο αιώνα αλλά σπανιότερος από το
δέκατο όγδοο). Έγραψε στον πατέρα της το 1756 και 
παραπονέθηκε πικρά για τη βάναυση συμπεριφορά από τον κύριό της
και τις σκληρές στερήσεις της καθημερινής ζωής, ικετεύοντας τον 
για να στείλει τον ιματισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que algunos plantadores en el chesapeake 
del de'cimo octavo-siglo comenzaron a construir mansiones espaciosas y
a confiar en el trabajo de números de aumento de los dependientes 
blancos y negros, la mayoría de los southerners blancos vivieron en 
circunstancias lejos más humildes. En Maryland la mayoría de 
los granjeros pequeños eran arrendatarios, alquilando su pista de 
terratenientes más grandes. Los hombres y las mujeres sin 
tierras trabajaron como arrendatarios agrícolas, trabajadores, o 
criados domésticos. Las puntillas de Elizabeth, criado en una 
casa de Maryland, financiada su paso de Inglaterra en el intercambio 
para un término como indentured a criado (una práctica frecuente en 
el decimoséptimo siglo pero más raro por el décimo octavo). 
Ella escribió a su padre en 1756 y se quejó amargamente del 
tratamiento brutal por su amo y de los privations ásperos de la vida 
de cada día, pidiéndole a que envíe la ropa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087208</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104437</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-unfortunate-english-people-suffer-here-an-english-servant-writes-home</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
