<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104307</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104307</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207000</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">World Wise Schools</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weltkluge Schulen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Écoles Sages du Monde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escolas Sábias Do Mundo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scuole Saggie Del Mondo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παγκόσμια σοφά σχολεία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escuelas Sabias Del Mundo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">program aims to engage learners in an inquiry about the world, themselves, and others in order to broaden perspectives, promote cultural awareness and encourage service. Students can email currently serving Peace Corps volunteers and build cross-cultural awareness by reading Culture Matters, the workbook used by Peace Corps Volunteers in the field.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Programm zielt darauf ab, sich Anfänger in einer 
Anfrage über die Welt, selbst und andere zu engagieren, um 
Perspektiven zu erweitern, kulturelles Bewußtsein zu fördern und 
Service anzuregen. Kursteilnehmer machen email ein, das aktuell 
Friedenskorpsfreiwilliger dient und bauen Kreuz-kulturelles 
Bewußtsein auf, indem sie Kultur-Stoffe, das Arbeitsbuch lesen, das 
von den Friedenskorps-Freiwilligern in auffangene benutzt wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">le programme vise à engager les étudiants dans 
une enquête au sujet du monde, eux-mêmes, et d'autres afin 
d'élargir des perspectives, favoriser la conscience culturelle et 
encourager le service. Les étudiants mettent en boîte l'email 
servant actuel des volontaires de corps de paix et établissent la 
conscience croix-culturelle en lisant des sujets de culture, le cahier
de travail employé par des volontaires de corps de paix dans le 
domaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o programa aponta acoplar os learners em um 
inquérito sobre o mundo, eles mesmos, e os outros a fim broaden 
perspectives, promover a consciência cultural e incentivar o 
serviço. Os estudantes enlatam o email que serve atualmente a 
voluntários do corpo de paz e constroem a consciência 
cruz-cross-cultural lendo matérias da cultura, o manual de 
instruções usado por voluntários do corpo de paz no campo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">il programma mira ad agganciare i principianti in 
un'inchiesta circa il mondo, essi stessi ed altri per estendere le 
prospettive, promuovere la consapevolezza culturale e consigliare al 
servizio. Gli allievi inscatolano il email attualmente che serve
i volontari di Corpo di pace e sviluppano la consapevolezza 
traversa-culturale leggendo gli argomenti della coltura, il libro di 
esercizi usato dai volontari della Peace corpo nel campo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">το πρόγραμμα στοχεύει να συμμετέχει τους αρχαρίους σε 
μια έρευνα για τον κόσμο, τους ίδιους, και άλλους προκειμένου να 
διευρυνθούν οι προοπτικές, να προωθηθεί η πολιτιστική 
συνειδητοποίηση και να ενθαρρυνθεί η υπηρεσία. Οι σπουδαστές
μπορούν να στείλουν μήνυμα με το ηλεκτρονικό ταχυδρομείο τους 
αυτήν την περίοδο εξυπηρετώντας εθελοντές ειρήνης Σώμα και 
να χτίσουν τη διαπολιτισμική συνειδητοποίηση με την ανάγνωση των 
θεμάτων πολιτισμού, το εγχειρίδιο που χρησιμοποιείται από την 
ειρήνη προσφέρεται εθελοντικά Σώμα στο πεδίο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el programa apunta contratar a los principiantes a
una pregunta sobre el mundo, ellos mismos, y a otros para ensanchar 
perspectivas, promover conocimiento cultural y animar servicio. 
Los estudiantes conservan el email que sirve actualmente a 
voluntarios del cuerpo de paz y construyen conocimiento cruz-cultural 
leyendo las materias de la cultura, el libro de trabajo usado por los 
voluntarios del cuerpo de paz en el campo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207000</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104307</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/world-wise-schools</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
