<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086917</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Class Ceiling: Nearing on Social Mobility</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kategorie Decke: Nähern auf 
Sozialmobilität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Plafond de Classe : Approche sur la 
mobilité sociale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Teto Da Classe: Aproximar-se na mobilidade
social</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Soffitto Del Codice categoria: 
Avvicinandosi sulla mobilità sociale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ανώτατο όριο κλάσης: Πλησίασμα στην 
κοινωνική κινητικότητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Techo De la Clase: Acercamiento en 
movilidad social</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The  Appeal to Reason  was the most popular radical publication in American history. The socialist newspaper, founded in 1895, reached a paid circulation of more than three-quarters of a million people by 1913. During political campaigns and crises, it often sold more than four million individual copies. J. A. Wayland, the paper's founder and publisher until his suicide in 1912, had become a socialist through reading. He built his paper on the conviction that plain talk would convert others to the socialist cause. From its Kansas headquarters, the  Appeal  published an eclectic mix of news (particularly of strikes and political campaigns), essays, poetry, fiction, humor, and cartoons. It ceased publication in November 1922, a victim of editorial instability, the declining fortunes of the Socialist Party, and U.S. government repression of radicalism. In the August 12, 1916 issue, Scott Nearing offered a disheartening prognosis for the social mobility of wage workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anklang an Grund war die populärste radikale 
Publikation in der amerikanischen Geschichte. Die sozialistische
Zeitung, gegründet 1895, erreichte eine zahlende Zirkulation von mehr
als Dreiviertel von Million Leuten bis zum 1913. Während der 
politischen Kampagnen und der Krisen verkaufte sie häufig mehr als 
vier Million einzelne Exemplare. J. A. hatten Wayland, der
Gründer des Papiers und der Verleger bis seinen Selbstmord 1912, 
einem Sozialisten durch Messwert gestanden. Er baute sein Papier
auf der Überzeugung auf, daß normales Gespräch andere in die 
sozialistische Ursache umwandeln würde. Von seinen Kansas 
Hauptsitzen veröffentlichte der Anklang eine eklektische Mischung 
der Nachrichten (besonders von Schlägen und von politischen 
Kampagnen), der Versuche, der Poesie, der Erfindung, der Stimmung und 
der Karikaturen. Er hörte Publikation im November 1922, ein 
Opfer der redaktionellen Instabilität, die abfallenden Vermögen der 
sozialistischen Partei und VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung 
Unterdrückung der Radikalismus auf. Im August 12, geben 
1916, Scott Nähern anboten eine entmutigende Prognose für die 
Sozialmobilität der Lohnarbeiter heraus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'appel à la raison était la plus populaire 
publication radicale dans l'histoire américaine. Le journal 
socialiste, fondé en 1895, a atteint une circulation payée plus de 
de trois quarts de million de personnes d'ici 1913. Pendant des 
campagnes et des crises politiques, il a souvent vendu plus de quatre 
millions de différentes copies. J. A. Wayland, le 
fondateur du papier et l'éditeur jusqu'à son suicide en 1912, 
étaient allés bien à un socialiste par la lecture. Il a 
construit son papier sur la conviction que l'entretien ordinaire 
convertirait d'autres en cause socialiste. De ses sièges 
sociaux du Kansas, l'appel a édité un mélange éclectique des 
nouvelles (en particulier des grèves et des campagnes politiques), 
des essais, de la poésie, de la fiction, de l'humeur, et des dessins 
animés. Il a cessé la publication en novembre 1922, une 
victime d'instabilité éditoriale, les fortunes en baisse du parti 
socialiste, et la répression de gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS du 
radicalisme. En 12 août 1916 émettent, approche de 
Scott ont offert un pronostic décourageant pour la mobilité 
sociale des ouvriers de salaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A apelação à razão era a publicação radical 
a mais popular no history americano. O jornal socialist, fundado
em 1895, alcançou uma circulação paga mais de de três quartos de 
povos de milhão por 1913. Durante campanhas e crises 
políticas, vendeu frequentemente mais de quatro milhão cópias 
individuais. J. A. Wayland, o founder do papel e o 
publisher até seu suicide em 1912, tinham assentado bem em um 
socialist através da leitura. Construiu seu papel na 
convicção que a conversa lisa converteria outra à causa socialist. 
De suas matrizes de Kansas, a apelação publicou uma mistura 
eclectic da notícia (particularmente das batidas e de campanhas 
políticas), dos essays, da poesia, do fiction, do humor, e dos 
cartoons. Cessou a publicação em novembro 1922, uma vítima da
instabilidade editorial, as fortunas declinando do partido socialist, 
e o repression do governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS do radicalism. 
Agosto no 12, 1916 emitem, aproximar-se de Scott ofereceram um 
prognosis disheartening para a mobilidade social de trabalhadores do 
salário.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'appello a motivo era la pubblicazione radicale 
più popolare nella storia americana. Il giornale socialista, 
fondato in 1895, ha raggiunto una circolazione paid più di di tre 
quarti di di milioni di persone entro 1913. Durante le campagne 
e le crisi politiche, ha venduto spesso più di quattro milione 
diverse copie. J. A. Wayland, il fondatore della carta e 
l'editore fino al suo suicide in 1912, avevano stato bene ad un 
socialista attraverso lettura. Ha costruito la sua carta sulla 
convinzione che il colloquio normale convertirebbe altri in causa 
socialista. Dalle relative sedi del Kansas, l'appello ha 
pubblicato una miscela eclettica delle notizie (specialmente dei colpi
e delle campagne politiche), dei saggi, della poesia, del romanzo, 
dell'umore e dei fumetti. Ha cessato la pubblicazione nel mese 
di novembre del 1922, una vittima di instabilità editoriale, le 
fortune declinanti del partito socialista e la repressione di governo 
degli STATI UNITI del radicalism. Nel 12 agosto, 1916 
pubblicano, l'avvicinamento di Scott hanno offerto una prognosi 
disheartening per la mobilità sociale degli operai dello stipendio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η έκκληση στο λόγο ήταν η δημοφιλέστερη ριζική 
δημοσίευση στην αμερικανική ιστορία. Η σοσιαλιστική 
εφημερίδα, που ιδρύθηκε το 1895, έφθασε σε μια πληρωμένη 
κυκλοφορία περισσότερο από των τριών τετάρτων εκατομμύριο 
ανθρώπων από 1913, Κατά τη διάρκεια των πολιτικών 
εκστρατειών και των κρίσεων, πώλησε συχνά περισσότερα από 
τέσσερα εκατομμύριο μεμονωμένα αντίγραφα. Θ*ι. Α. 
Wayland, ο ιδρυτής του εγγράφου και ο εκδότης μέχρι την 
αυτοκτονία του το 1912, είχε γίνει σοσιαλιστής μέσω της 
ανάγνωσης. Στηρίχτηκε το έγγραφό του στην πεποίθηση ότι η 
σαφής συζήτηση θα μετέτρεπε άλλους στη σοσιαλιστική αιτία. 
Από την έδρα του Κάνσας της, η έκκληση δημοσίευσε ένα 
εκλεκτικό μίγμα των ειδήσεων (ιδιαίτερα των απεργιών και των 
πολιτικών εκστρατειών), των δοκίμιων, της ποίησης, της 
μυθιστοριογραφίας, του χιούμορ, και των κινούμενων σχεδίων. 
Έπαψε τη δημοσίευση τον Νοέμβριο του 1922, ένα θύμα της 
εκδοτικής αστάθειας, οι μειωμένος τύχες του Σοσιαλιστικού 
Κόμματος, και της καταστολής ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης της 
ριζοσπαστισμού. Τις 12 Αυγούστου ..1916 εκδώστε, 
Scott που πλησιάζει πρόσφερε μια αποθαρρύνοντας πρόγνωση για 
την κοινωνική κινητικότητα των εργαζομένων αμοιβών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La súplica a la razón era la publicación 
radical más popular de la historia americana. El periódico 
socialista, fundado en 1895, alcanzó una circulación pagada de más 
de tres cuartos millones de personas antes de 1913. Durante 
campañas y crisis políticas, vendió a menudo más de cuatro 
millones de copias individuales. J. A. Wayland, el 
fundador del papel y el editor hasta su suicidio en 1912, habían 
sentido bien a un socialista a través de la lectura. Él 
construyó su documento sobre la convicción que la charla llana 
convertiría otras a la causa socialista. De sus jefaturas de 
Kansas, la súplica publicó una mezcla ecléctica de las noticias 
(determinado de huelgas y de campañas políticas), de los ensayos, de
la poesía, de la ficción, del humor, y de historietas. Cesó 
la publicación en noviembre de 1922, una víctima de la inestabilidad
editorial, las fortunas que declinaban del partido socialista, y la 
represión del gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS del radicalismo. En de 
agosto el 12, 1916 publican, acercamiento de Scott ofrecieron un 
pronóstico disheartening para la movilidad social de los trabajadores
del salario.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086917</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105160</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-class-ceiling-nearing-on-social-mobility</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
