<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104263</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104263</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086240</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"His Act is Doublely Despicable": Albert Parsons Responds to His Condemnation by Terence V. Powderly</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"seine Tat ist schändliches Doublely": 
Albert Pastoren reagiert auf seine Verurteilung durch Terence V.
Powderly</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"son acte est Doublely ignoble" : Les 
pasteurs d'Albert répond à sa condamnation par Terence V. Powderly</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"seu ato é Doublely despicable": Os 
parsons de Albert respondem a seu condemnation por Terence V. 
Powderly</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la sua Legge è Doublely despicable": I 
parsons del Albert risponde alla sua condanna da Terence V. Powderly</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο νόμος του είναι Doublely αξιοκαταφρόνητο": 
Αλβέρτος Parsons Responds στην καταδίκη του από 
Terence Θ*Β. Powderly</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"su acto es Doublely despreciable": Los 
parsons de Albert responden a su condenación por Terence V. Powderly</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the aftermath of the 1886 Haymarket bombing Knights of Labor leader Terence V. Powderly was desperate to distance his organization from the accused anarchists and maintain the order's respectability. The day after the bombing he stated that it was the duty of every organization of working men in America to condemn the outrage committed in Chicago in the name of labor. Though there were exceptions, most assemblies of the Knights followed Powderly's lead. Albert Parsons, a long-time member of the Knights and one of the Haymarket defendants, viewed Powderly's lack of support with bitterness and wrote the following letter from jail on his tenth anniversary of joining the Knights, July 4, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Nachmahd der Haymarket Bombardierung 
Ritter 1886 des Gewerkschaftsführers Terence V. Powderly war 
hoffnungslos, seine Organisation von den beschuldigten Anarchisten zu 
überholen und den Respectability der Ordnung beizubehalten. Der
Tag nach der Bombardierung gab er an, daß es die Aufgabe jeder 
Organisation der Funktion Männer in Amerika war, zum des Verbrechens 
zu verurteilen, das in Chicago im Namen der Arbeit festgelegt wurde. 
Obwohl es Ausnahmen gab, der meiste Zusammenbau von der Ritter 
gefolgten Leitung des Powderlys. Albert Pastoren, ein 
langfristiges Bauteil der Ritter und eins der Haymarket Beklagten, 
Mangel gesehenen Powderlys an Support mit Bitterkeit und schrieben den
folgenden Brief vom Gefängnis auf seinen zehnten Jahrestag des 
Verbindens der Ritter, Juli 4, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans la conséquence des chevaliers 1886 de 
bombardement de Haymarket du dirigeant syndical Terence V. Powderly 
était désespéré pour distancer son organisation des anarchistes 
accusés et pour mettre à jour la respectabilité de la commande. 
Le jour après le bombardement il a déclaré que c'était le 
devoir de chaque organisation des ouvriers en Amérique pour condamner
l'outrage commis Chicago au nom du travail. Bien qu'il y ait eu 
des exceptions, la plupart des assemblages du fil de sortie du 
Powderly suivi par chevaliers. Les pasteurs d'Albert, un membre 
à long terme des chevaliers et un des défendeurs de Haymarket, le 
manque de Powderly visualisé de support avec l'amertume et ont écrit
la lettre suivante de la prison sur son dixième anniversaire de 
joindre les chevaliers, 4 juillet 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No aftermath dos knights 1886 do bombardeio de 
Haymarket do líder labor Terence V. Powderly era desesperado distance
sua organização dos anarquistas acusados e manter o respectability 
da ordem. O dia após o bombardeio indicou que era o dever de 
cada organização de homens de funcionamento em América para condemn
o ultraje cometido em Chicago no nome do trabalho. Embora havia 
umas exceções, a maioria de conjuntos da ligação do Powderly 
seguido knights. Os parsons de Albert, um membro long-time dos 
knights e um dos réus de Haymarket, falta de Powderly visto da 
sustentação com bitterness e escreveram a seguinte letra da cadeia 
em seu décimo anniversary de juntar os knights, julho 4, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel guaime dei cavalieri 1886 del bombardamento 
di Haymarket del capo Di lavoro Terence V. Powderly era 
disperato distance la sua organizzazione dagli anarchici accusati ed 
effettuare il respectability dell'ordine. Il giorno dopo il 
bombardamento che ha dichiarato che era il dovere di ogni 
organizzazione degli uomini di funzionamento in America per condannare
l'oltraggio commesso in Chicago in nome del lavoro. 
Benchè ci siano eccezioni, la maggior parte dei montaggi del 
cavo del Powderly seguito cavalieri. I parsons del Albert, un 
membro long-time dei cavalieri ed uno dei difensori di Haymarket, 
mancanza del Powderly osservato di supporto con amarezza ed hanno 
scritto la seguente lettera dalla prigione sul suo decimo anniversario
di unire i cavalieri, 4 luglio 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη συνέπεια των 1886 βομβαρδίζοντας ιπποτών 
Haymarket της εργασίας ο ηγέτης Terence Θ*Β. Powderly ήταν
απελπισμένος για να απομακρύνει την οργάνωσή του από τους 
κατηγορούμενους αναρχικούς και να διατηρήσει τη σεβασμιότητα της 
κατάταξης. Η ημέρα μετά από το βομβαρδισμό δήλωσε ότι 
ήταν το καθήκον κάθε οργάνωσης των εργαζόμενων ατόμων στην 
Αμερική να καταδικάσει την προσβολή που δεσμεύθηκε στο Σικάγο στο
όνομα της εργασίας. Αν και υπήρξαν εξαιρέσεις, οι 
περισσότερες συμβολικές γλώσσες των ιπποτών ακολούθησαν το 
μόλυβδο Powderly. Αλβέρτος Parsons, ένα μακροπρόθεσμο 
μέλος των ιπποτών και ένας από τους κατηγορουμένους Haymarket,
εμφάνισαν την έλλειψη Powderly υποστήριξης με την πικρία και 
έγραψαν την ακόλουθη επιστολή από τη φυλακή στη δέκατη επέτειό
του ένωσης των ιπποτών, 4 Ιουλίου, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las consecuencias de los caballeros 1886 del 
bombardeo de Haymarket del arranque de cinta de trabajo Terence V. 
Powderly era desesperado distanciar su organización de los 
anarquistas acusados y mantener la respetabilidad de la orden. 
El día después del bombardeo él indicó que era el deber de 
cada organización de los hombres de funcionamiento en América para 
condenar el ultraje confiado en Chicago en el nombre del trabajo. 
Aunque había anomalías, la mayoría de los ensamblajes del 
terminal de componente del Powderly seguido los caballeros. Los 
parsons de Albert, un miembro de largo plazo de los caballeros y uno 
de los demandados de Haymarket, carencia de Powderly visto de la ayuda
con amargura y escribieron la letra siguiente de la cárcel en su 
décimo aniversario de ensamblar a los caballeros, 4 de julio de 
1886.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086240</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104263</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/his-act-is-doublely-despicable-albert-parsons-responds-to-his-condemnation-by-terence-v-powderly</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
