<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104849</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104849</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101446</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Potatoes vs. Late Blight: Plants at War and Peace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kartoffeln gegen späte Trockenfäule: 
Betriebe am Krieg und am Frieden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pommes de terre contre la défunte rouille : 
Usines à la guerre et à la paix</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Batatas contra o blight atrasado: Plantas na
guerra e na paz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Patate contro ruggine ritardata: Piante alla
guerra ed alla pace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πατάτες εναντίον της πρόσφατης σήψης: 
Εγκαταστάσεις στον πόλεμο και την ειρήνη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Patatas contra último destrozo: Plantas en 
la guerra y la paz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Plant genome research is already revolutionizing the field of biology. Currently, scientists are unlocking the secrets of some of the most important plants in our lives, including corn, cotton and potatoes. Secrets of Plant Genomes: Revealed! takes viewers on a lively, upbeat journey that explores how these plants got to be the way they are and investigates how we can make better use of them in the future. Plant scientists are hard at work--in the lab, in the field and at the computer--to increase our understanding of nature. Secrets of Plant Genomes: Revealed! makes the study of plants exciting and relevant by showing how learning more about plants can improve our everyday lives. For further information see: http://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.cfm?med_id=61504&amp;from=vid General Restrictions: Images credited to the National Science Foundation, a federal agency, are in the public domain. The images were created by employees of the United States Government as part of their official duties or prepared by contractors as "works for hire" for NSF. You may freely use NSF-credited images and, at your discretion, credit NSF with a "Courtesy: National Science Foundation" notation. Additional information about general usage can be found in Conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Betriebsgenomforschung revolutioniert bereits 
auffangene der Biologie. Aktuell entsperren Wissenschaftler 
die Geheimnisse von einigen der wichtigsten Betriebe in unseren 
Lebensdauern, einschließlich Mais, Baumwolle und Kartoffeln. 
Geheimnisse der Betriebsgenome: Aufgedeckt! nimmt 
Projektoren auf einer lebhaften, positiven Reise, die erforscht, 
wie diese Betriebe erhielten, die Methode zu sein, die sie sind und 
nachforscht, wie wir besseren Gebrauch von ihnen zukünftig bilden 
können. Botaniker sind hart an der Arbeit -- im Labor, in 
auffangene und am Computer -- unser Verständnis der Natur zu 
erhöhen. Geheimnisse der Betriebsgenome: Aufgedeckt! 
bildet die Studie von den Betrieben aufregend und relevant indem
das Zeigen, wie das Lernen mehr über Betriebe unsere täglichen 
Lebensdauern verbessern kann. Für weitere Informationen sehen 
Sie: 
http://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.cfm?med_id=61504&amp;from=vid 
Allgemeine Beschränkungen: Die Bilder, die zum National Science
Foundation, ein Bundesamt gutgeschrieben werden, sind im public 
domain. Die Bilder wurden von den Angestellten der Vereinigte 
Staaten Regierung als Teil ihrer Dienstpflichten erstellt oder 
vorbereitet durch Fremdfirmen, wie "für Miete" für NSF arbeitet. 
Sie können an NSF-GUTGESCHRIEBENEN Bildern und, an Ihrer 
Rücksicht, Gutschrift NSF frei üben mit einer "Höflichkeit: 
National Science Foundation"Darstellung. Zusätzliche 
Informationen über allgemeinen Verbrauch können in den Bedingungen 
gefunden werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La recherche de génome d'usine révolutionne 
déjà la zone de la biologie. Actuel, les scientifiques 
déverrouillent les secrets de certaines des usines les plus 
importantes en nos vies, y compris le maïs, le coton et des pommes de
terre. Secrets des génomes d'usine : Indiqué ! 
prend des visualisateurs sur un voyage animé et optimiste qui
explore comment ces usines ont obtenu d'être la voie qu'elles sont et
étudie comment nous pouvons faire une meilleure utilisation d'eux à 
l'avenir. Il est difficile au travail -- dans le laboratoire, 
dans le domaine et à l'ordinateur -- d'augmenter des botanistes notre
arrangement de nature. Secrets des génomes d'usine : 
Indiqué ! effectue l'étude des usines passionnante et 
appropriée en montrant comment l'étude de plus au sujet des usines 
peut améliorer nos vies journalières. Pour de plus amples 
informations voyez : Restrictions Générales de 
http://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.cfm?med_id=61504&amp;from=vid : 
Les images créditées au National Science Foundation, une 
agence fédérale, sont dans le public domain. Les images ont 
été créées par des employés du gouvernement des Etats-Unis en 
tant qu'élément de leurs fonctions officielles ou préparées par 
des entrepreneurs comme "travaille pour la location" pour le NSF. 
Vous pouvez librement utiliser les images NSF-CRÉDITÉES et, à
votre discrétion, NSF de degré de solvabilité avec une "courtoisie : 
Notation de National Science Foundation ". Des 
informations supplémentaires sur l'utilisation générale peuvent 
être trouvées en conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A pesquisa do genome da planta revolutionizing já
o campo da biologia. Atualmente, os cientistas estão 
destravando os segredos de algumas das plantas as mais importantes em 
nossas vidas, including o milho, o algodão e as batatas. 
Segredos de genomes da planta: Revelado! faz exame 
de visores em um vívido, a viagem do upbeat que explora como estas 
plantas começaram ser a maneira que são e investiga como nós 
podemos fazer o uso melhor dele no futuro. Os cientistas de 
planta são duros no trabalho -- no laboratório, no campo e no 
computador -- de aumentar nossa compreensão da natureza. 
Segredos de genomes da planta: Revelado! faz o 
estudo das plantas emocionante e relevante mostrando como aprender 
mais sobre plantas pode melhorar nossas vidas diárias. Para uma
informação mais adicional veja: Limitações Gerais De 
http://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.cfm?med_id=61504&amp;from=vid: 
As imagens creditadas ao National Science Foundation, uma 
agência federal, estão no public domain. As imagens foram 
criadas por empregados do governo unido dos estados como a parte de 
seus deveres oficiais ou preparadas por contratantes como "trabalha 
para o hire" para o NSF. Você pode livremente usar as imagens 
NSF-CREDITADAS e, na sua discreção, NSF do crédito com uma 
"cortesia: Notação do National Science Foundation ". A 
informação adicional sobre o uso geral pode ser encontrada nas 
circunstâncias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La ricerca del genome della pianta già sta 
rivoluzionando il campo di biologia. Attualmente, gli scienziati
stanno sbloccando i segreti di alcune delle piante più importanti 
nelle nostre vite, compreso cereale, cotone e le patate. Segreti
dei genomes della pianta: Rivelatore! prende i visori su 
un viaggio vivace e ottimistico che esplora come queste piante hanno 
ottenuto essere il modo che sono e studia come possiamo fare l'uso 
migliore di loro in avvenire. I botanici sono duri sul lavoro --
nel laboratorio, nel campo ed al calcolatore -- da aumentare la nostra
comprensione della natura. Segreti dei genomes della pianta: 
Rivelatore! effettua lo studio delle piante emozionante e 
relativo mostrando come imparare più circa le piante può migliorare 
le nostre vite giornalieri. Per ulteriori informazioni veda: 
Limitazioni Generali Di 
http://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.cfm?med_id=61504&amp;from=vid: 
Le immagini accreditate al National Science Foundation, un ente 
federale, sono nel public domain. Le immagini sono state create 
dagli impiegati del unito Dichiara il governo come componente 
delle loro funzioni ufficiali o preparato dagli appaltatori come 
"funziona per noleggio" per il NSF. Potete usare liberamente le 
immagini NSF-ACCREDITATE e, alla vostra discrezione, NSF di 
accreditamento con "una cortesia: Notazione di National Science 
Foundation ". Le informazioni supplementari su uso generale 
possono essere trovate nelle circostanze.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η έρευνα γονιδιώματος εγκαταστάσεων ξεσηκώνει ήδη το 
πεδίο της βιολογίας. Αυτήν την περίοδο, οι επιστήμονες 
ξεκλειδώνουν τα μυστικά μερικές από τις σημαντικότερες 
εγκαταστάσεις στις ζωές μας, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του καλαμποκιού, 
του βαμβακιού και των πατατών. Μυστικά των γονιδιωμάτων 
εγκαταστάσεων: Αποκαλυφθείς! παίρνει τις εμφανίσεις σε
ένα ζωηρό, οπτιμιστές ταξίδι που εξερευνά πώς αυτές οι 
εγκαταστάσεις πήραν να είναι ο τρόπος που είναι και ερευνούν 
πώς μπορούμε να κάνουμε την καλύτερη χρήση τους στο μέλλον. 
Οι επιστήμονες εγκαταστάσεων είναι δύσκολο στην εργασία -- 
στο εργαστήριο, στο πεδίο και στον υπολογιστή -- να αυξηθεί η 
κατανόηση φύσης μας. Μυστικά των γονιδιωμάτων 
εγκαταστάσεων: Αποκαλυφθείς! κάνει τη μελέτη των 
εγκαταστάσεων που διεγείρουν και σχετικών με την επίδειξη πώς η 
εκμάθηση περισσότερων για τις εγκαταστάσεις μπορεί να βελτιώσει 
τις καθημερινές ζωές μας. Για περισσότερες πληροφορίες 
δείτε: http://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.cfm?med_id=61504&amp;from=vid 
γενικοί περιορισμοί: Οι εικόνες που πιστώνονται στο εθνικό 
ίδρυμα επιστήμης, μια ομοσπονδιακή αντιπροσωπεία, είναι στο 
δημόσιο τομέα. Οι εικόνες δημιουργήθηκαν από τους 
υπαλλήλους της Ηνωμένης κυβέρνησης ως τμήμα των επίσημων 
καθηκόντων τους ή προετοιμάστηκαν από τους αναδόχους ως 
"εργασίες για μίσθωση" για NSF. Μπορείτε ελεύθερα να 
χρησιμοποιήσετε τις νσφ-πιστωμένες εικόνες και, κατά την κρίση 
σας, την πίστωση NSF με μια "ευγένεια: Σημείωση εθνικού 
ιδρύματος επιστήμης ". Οι πρόσθετες πληροφορίες για τη 
γενική χρήση μπορούν να βρεθούν στους όρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La investigación del genoma de la planta 
está revolucionando ya el campo de la biología. Actualmente, 
los científicos están abriendo los secretos de algunas de las 
plantas más importantes de nuestras vidas, incluyendo maíz, algodón
y patatas. Secretos de los Genomas de la planta: 
¡Revelado! toma los espectadores en un animado, el viaje 
del upbeat que explora cómo estas plantas consiguieron ser la manera 
que son e investiga cómo podemos hacer un uso mejor de él en el 
futuro. Los científicos de planta son duros en el trabajo -- en
el laboratorio, en el campo y en el ordenador -- de aumentar nuestra 
comprensión de la naturaleza. Secretos de los Genomas de la
planta: ¡Revelado! hace el estudio de plantas emocionante 
y relevante mostrando cómo aprender más sobre las plantas puede 
mejorar nuestras vidas diarias. Para la información adicional 
vea: Restricciones Generales De 
http://www.nsf.gov/news/mmg/mmg_disp.cfm?med_id=61504&amp;from=vid: 
Las imágenes acreditadas al National Science Foundation, una 
agencia federal, están en el public domain. Las imágenes 
fueron creadas por los empleados del gobierno de Estados Unidos como 
parte de sus deberes oficiales o preparadas por los contratistas como 
"trabaja para el hire" para el NSF. Usted puede utilizar 
libremente las imágenes NSF-ACREDITADAS y, en su discreción, NSF del
crédito con una "cortesía: Notación del National Science 
Foundation ". La información adicional sobre uso general se 
puede encontrar en condiciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NSF
FN:NSF
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101446</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104849</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/potatoes-vs-late-blight-plants-at-war-and-peace</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
