<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107135</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107135</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206078</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploring Earth: Investigations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschende Masse: Untersuchungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Terre L'explorant : Investigations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Terra Explorando: Investigações</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Terra D'Esplorazione: Indagini</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξερεύνηση της γης: Έρευνες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tierra Que explora: Investigaciones</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides more than 75 earth science investigations. Each presents photos and text (and sometimes video) that help students understand key earth science concepts. Among the topics: earth's layers, rocks, volcanoes and plate tectonics, earthquakes and mountains, surface and ground water, wind and currents, atmosphere and weather, climate change, oceans, our moon and solar system, and earth's history.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt mehr als 75 Geowissenschaftuntersuchungen 
zur Verfügung. Jedes stellt Fotos dar und Text (und manchmal 
Bildschirm) diese Hilfe Kursteilnehmer verstehen 
Schlüsselgeowissenschaftkonzepte. Unter den Themen: 
bedeckten Schichten, Felsen, Vulkane und Plattentektonik, 
Erdbeben und Berge, Oberflächen- und Grundwasser, Wind und Ströme, 
Atmosphäre und Wetter, Klimaänderung, Ozeane, unser Mond und 
Solarsystem und Geschichte der Masse mit Erde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit plus de 75 investigations de science de 
la terre. Chacun présente des photos et le texte (et parfois le
vidéo) des étudiants de cette aide comprennent les concepts 
principaux de science de la terre. Parmi les sujets : ont 
mis à la terre des couches, des roches, des volcans et tectonique de 
plat, des tremblements de terre et des montagnes, extérieur et des 
eaux souterraines, vent et des courants, l'atmosphère et 
survivent à, changement de climat, océans, notre lune et 
système solaire, et histoire de la terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece mais de 75 investigações da ciência de
terra. Cada um apresenta fotos e o texto (e às vezes o vídeo) 
estudantes dessa ajuda compreendem os conceitos chaves da ciência de 
terra. Entre os tópicos: ligaram à terra camadas, 
rochas, vulcões e tectonics de placa, terremotos e montanhas, a água
de superfície e à terra, o vento e as correntes, a atmosfera e o 
tempo, a mudança do clima, os oceanos, a nosso lua e sistema solar, e
history da terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce più di 75 indagini di scienze della 
terra. Ciascuno presenta le foto ed il testo (ed a volte video) 
allievi di quell'aiuto capiscono i concetti chiave di scienze della 
terra. Fra i soggetti: hanno interrato gli strati, roccie,
vulcani e la tettonica di piastra, terremoti ed acqua superficiale e 
sotterranea del montagna, vento e correnti, atmosfera e tempo, 
cambiamento di clima, oceani, la nostro luna e sistema solare e storia
della terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει περισσότερες από 75 έρευνες γήινης 
επιστήμης. Κάθε ένας παρουσιάζει τις φωτογραφίες και το 
κείμενο (και μερικές φορές το βίντεο) που βοηθούν τους 
σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν τις βασικές έννοιες γήινης επιστήμης. 
Μεταξύ των θεμάτων: γήινα στρώματα, βράχοι, 
ηφαίστεια και τεκτονική πιάτων, σεισμοί και βουνά, επιφάνεια και
υπόγειο νερό, αέρας και ρεύματα, ατμόσφαιρα και καιρός, αλλαγή 
κλίματος, ωκεανοί, το φεγγάρι και το ηλιακό σύστημά μας, και 
γήινη ιστορία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a más de 75 investigaciones de la 
geología. Cada uno presenta las fotos y el texto (y a veces el 
vídeo) los estudiantes de esa ayuda entienden los conceptos 
dominantes de la geología. Entre los asuntos: conectaron 
a tierra capas, las rocas, los volcanes y tectónica de placa, los 
terremotos y las montañas, superficial y el agua subterránea, viento
y las corrientes, atmósfera y tiempo, cambio del clima, los océanos,
nuestra luna y Sistema Solar, y la historia de la tierra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206078</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107135</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exploring-earth-investigations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
