<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086859</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Strength in Numbers: Kelley on Women, Labor, and the Power of the Ballot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stärke in den Zahlen: Kelley auf Frauen, 
Arbeit und der Energie des Stimmzettels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Force dans les nombres : Kelley sur les 
femmes, le travail, et la puissance du vote</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Força nos números: Kelley em mulheres, em 
trabalho, e na potência da cédula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Resistenza nei numeri: Kelley sulle donne, 
sul Lavoro e sull'potenza della scheda elettorale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δύναμη στους αριθμούς: Kelley στις γυναίκες, 
την εργασία, και τη δύναμη της ψήφου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fuerza en números: Kelley en mujeres, 
trabajo, y la potencia de la balota</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1890, two competing organizations working to gain the right for women to vote joined forces to form the National American Women Suffrage Association (NAWSA). NAWSA campaigned diligently for the vote in a variety of ways, but did not achieve success until the ratification of the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution in 1920. This prolonged struggle entangled female activists in other important political and moral issues that divided the nation along racial, ethnic, and class lines. Florence Kelley, a Chicago-born labor reformer, socialist, and woman suffrage advocate, employed pragmatic arguments in support of women's right to vote. In this selection from a speech to the 1898 NAWSA convention, Kelly argued that working women, particularly factory workers, needed the ballot to protect themselves from exploitation at the hands of their powerful employers. She also argued that working men needed their feminine counterparts to vote in order to strengthen labor's presence at the polls.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1890 zwei konkurrierende Organisationen, die 
arbeiten, um das Recht zu gewinnen, damit Frauen verbindende Kräfte 
wählen, um die nationale amerikanische Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung 
(NAWSA) zu bilden. NAWSA warb mit Sorgfalt für die Stimme in 
einer Vielzahl von Methoden, aber erzielte Erfolg bis die Bestätigung
der 19.änderung nicht zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit 1920. 
Dieser verlängerte Kampf verwickelte weibliche Aktivisten in 
anderen wichtigen politischen und moralischen Ausgaben, die die Nation
entlang rassischem teilten, ethnisch, und in Kategorie Zeilen. 
Florenz Kelley, ein Chicago-getragener ArbeitsReformer, 
Sozialist und Fraustimmrechtfürsprecher, eingesetzte pragmatische 
Argumente zur Unterstützung der Frauen nach rechts zur Stimme. 
In dieser Auswahl von einer Rede zur 1898 NAWSA Versammlung, 
argumentierte Kelly, daß Funktion Frauen, besonders Arbeiter, den 
Stimmzettel benötigten, sich vor Ausnutzung an den Händen ihrer 
leistungsfähigen Arbeitgeber zu schützen. Sie argumentierte 
auch, daß Funktion Männer ihre weiblichen Gegenstücke benötigten 
zu wählen, um Arbeitsanwesenheit an den Abstimmungen zu verstärken.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1890, deux organismes de concurrence 
travaillant pour gagner la droite pour que les femmes votent les 
forces jointives pour former l'association américaine nationale de 
suffrage de femmes (NAWSA). NAWSA a fait campagne diligemment 
pour la voix par une multitude de moyens, mais n'a pas réalisé le 
succès jusqu'à la ratification du dix-neuvième amendement à la 
constitution des ETATS-UNIS en 1920. Cette lutte prolongée a 
empêtré les activistes féminins dans d'autres issues importantes 
qui ont divisé la nation le long de racial, ethnique, et lignes 
politiques et morales de classe. Florence Kelley, un réformateur
de travail Chicago-soutenu, socialiste, et avocat de suffrage de 
femme, arguments pragmatiques utilisés à l'appui des femmes juste à
la voix. Dans cette sélection à partir d'un discours à la 
convention de 1898 NAWSA, la tige carrée d'entraînement a argué du 
fait que les travailleuses actives, en particulier ouvriers d'usine, 
ont eu besoin du vote pour se protéger contre l'exploitation aux 
mains de leurs employeurs puissants. Elle a également argué du
fait que les ouvriers ont eu besoin de leurs contre-parties féminines
pour voter afin de renforcer la présence de travail aux balayages.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1890, duas organizações competindo que 
trabalham para ganhar a direita para que as mulheres votem forças 
juntadas para dar forma à associação americana nacional do suffrage
das mulheres (NAWSA). NAWSA fêz campanha diligently para o voto
em uma variedade das maneiras, mas não conseguiu o sucesso até o 
ratification da décima nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
em 1920. Este esforço prolongado entangled activistas fêmeas 
em outras edições importantes que dividiram a nação ao longo de 
racial, étnico, e linhas políticas e morais da classe. 
Florença Kelley, um reformer labor Chicago-carregado, 
socialist, e advogado do suffrage da mulher, argumentos pragmatic 
empregados na sustentação das mulheres para a direita ao voto. 
Nesta seleção de um discurso à convenção de 1898 NAWSA, o 
kelly discutiu que as mulheres de funcionamento, particularmente 
trabalhadores de fábrica, necessitaram a cédula se proteger da 
exploração nas mãos de seus empregadores poderosos. Discutiu 
também que os homens de funcionamento necessitaram suas contrapartes 
feminine votar a fim strengthen a presença labor nas votações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1890, due organizzazioni competenti che 
lavorano per guadagnare la destra affinchè donne votino le forze 
unite per formare l'associazione americana nazionale di suffrage delle
donne (NAWSA). NAWSA ha fatto una campagna diligente per il voto
in una varietà di modi, ma non ha realizzato il successo fino alla 
ratifica della diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI
UNITI in 1920. Questa lotta prolungata ha impigliato gli 
attivisti femminili in altre edizioni importanti che hanno diviso la
nazione lungo razziale, etnico e righe politiche e morali del codice 
categoria. Firenze Kelley, un reformer di lavoro 
Chicago-sopportato, socialista e fautore di suffrage della donna, 
argomenti pragmatici impiegati a sostegno delle donne a destra al 
voto. In questa selezione da un discorso alla convenzione di 
1898 NAWSA, l'asta quadra di collegamento ha sostenuto che le donne 
lavorarici, specialmente operai di fabbrica, hanno avuto bisogno della
scheda elettorale di proteggersi da sfruttamento alle mani dei loro 
datori di lavoro potenti. Egualmente ha sostenuto che gli uomini
di funzionamento hanno avuto bisogno delle loro controparti femminili 
di votare per rinforzare la presenza di lavoro allo scrutinio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1890, δύο ανταγωνιστικές οργανώσεις εργαζόμενος 
για να κερδίσει το δικαίωμα για τις γυναίκες να ψηφίσουν τις 
ενωμένες δυνάμεις για να διαμορφώσουν την εθνική αμερικανική 
ένωση ψήφου γυναικών (NAWSA). NAWSA έκανε εκστρατεία
επιμελώς για την ψηφοφορία με ποικίλους τρόπους, αλλά δεν 
επέτυχε την επιτυχία μέχρι την επικύρωση της δέκατης έννατης 
τροποποίησης στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ σύνταγμα το 1920. Αυτή η 
παρατεταμένη προσπάθεια έμπλεξε τα θηλυκά ενεργά στελέχη σε 
άλλα σημαντικά πολιτικά και ηθικά ζητήματα που διαίρεσαν το 
έθνος σύμφωνα με φυλετικές, τις εθνικές, και γραμμές κλάσης. 
Η Φλωρεντία Kelley, ένας Σικάγο-γεννημένοι 
μεταρρυθμιστής εργασίας, ένας σοσιαλιστής, και ένας συνήγορος 
ψήφου γυναικών, υιοθέτησαν τα πραγματικά ορίσματα υπέρ του 
δικαιώματος των γυναικών ψηφοφορίας. Σε αυτήν την επιλογή 
από μια ομιλία στη σύμβαση 1898 NAWSA, kelly υποστήριξε 
ότι οι εργαζόμενες γυναίκες, ιδιαίτερα εργαζόμενοι εργοστασίων, 
χρειάστηκαν την ψήφο για να προστατευθούν από την εκμετάλλευση 
στα χέρια των ισχυρών εργοδοτών τους. Επίσης υποστήριξε 
ότι τα εργαζόμενα άτομα χρειάστηκαν τα θηλυκά αντίστοιχά τους 
για να ψηφίσουν προκειμένου να ενισχύσουν την παρουσία της 
εργασίας στις ψηφοφορίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1890, dos organizaciones competentes que 
trabajan para ganar la derecha para que mujeres voten fuerzas unidas 
para formar la asociación americana nacional del sufragio de las 
mujeres (NAWSA). NAWSA hizo campaña diligente para el voto en 
una variedad de maneras, pero no alcanzó éxito hasta la 
ratificación de la diecinueveavo enmienda a la constitución de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1920. Esta lucha prolongada enredó a 
activistas femeninos en otras ediciones importantes que dividieron la 
nación a lo largo de racial, étnico, y líneas políticas y morales 
de la clase. Florencia Kelley, reformador de trabajo 
Chicago-llevado, socialista, y abogado del sufragio de la mujer, 
argumentos pragmáticos empleados en la ayuda de las mujeres a la 
derecha al voto. En esta selección de un discurso a la 
convención de 1898 NAWSA, el kelly discutió que las mujeres de 
funcionamiento, determinado trabajadores de fábrica, necesitaran la 
balota protegerse contra la explotación en las manos de sus patrones 
de gran alcance. Ella también discutió que los hombres de 
funcionamiento necesitaran a sus contrapartes femeninas votar para 
consolidar presencia de trabajo en las encuestas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086859</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108735</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/strength-in-numbers-kelley-on-women-labor-and-the-power-of-the-ballot</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
