<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086970</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Hunters of Kentucky": A Popular Song Celebrates the Victory of Jackson and his Frontier Fighters over the British, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Jäger von Kentucky": Ein populäres 
Lied feiert den Sieg von Jackson und von seinen Grenzkämpfern über 
den Briten, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les chasseurs du Kentucky" : Une chanson 
populaire célèbre la victoire de Jackson et de ses combattants de 
frontière au-dessus des Anglais, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"os caçadores de Kentucky": Uma canção 
popular comemora a vitória de Jackson e de seus lutadores da 
fronteira sobre os Ingleses, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i cacciatori del Kentucky": Una canzone 
popolare celebra la vittoria di Jackson e dei suoi combattenti di 
frontiera sopra i Britannici, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι κυνηγοί του Κεντάκυ": Ένα δημοφιλές 
τραγούδι γιορτάζει τη νίκη του Τζάκσον και των συνοριακών 
μαχητών του πέρα από τους Βρετανούς, 1824</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"los cazadores de Kentucky": Una canción 
popular celebra la victoria de Jackson y de sus combatientes de la 
frontera sobre los Británicos, 1824</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Angered by the effect of the British naval blockade on cotton prices and British support for Indian attacks against white frontier settlers, farmers in the South and West strongly supported the War of 1812. The war ended two years later with few issues settled between the two nations. The most significant battle took place after the peace treaty was signed in 1814, when General Andrew Jackson, a Tennessee slaveholder, decisively defeated the British forces at New Orleans. This resounding victory made him a national hero and symbol of frontier fighters and earned him the nickname "Old Hickory." Although he secured victory using regular troops armed with artillery power, ten years later Samuel Woodward celebrated the role of sharpshooters armed with Kentucky long rifles in his song "The Hunters of Kentucky." This immensely popular song, filled with images of Old Hickory and his men overwhelming the well-trained army of John Bull (a symbol of Britain), became an effective element in Jackson's successful 1828 campaign for president.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verärgert durch den Effekt der britischen 
Marineblockade auf Baumwollpreisen und des Briten Supports für 
Inderangriffe gegen weiße Grenzsiedleren, unterstützten Landwirte im
Süden und Westen stark den Krieg von 1812. Der Krieg beendete 
zwei Jahre später mit wenigen Ausgaben, die zwischen den zwei 
Nationen vereinbart wurden. Die bedeutendste Schlacht fand 
statt, nachdem der Friedensvertrag 1814 unterzeichnet wurde, als 
General Andrew Jackson, ein Tennessee slaveholder, entscheidend die 
britischen Kräfte in New-Orleans besiegte. Dieser resounding 
Sieg bildete ihn einen nationalen Held und ein Symbol von den 
Grenzkämpfern und erwarb ihm den Spitznamen "alten Hickory." 
Obgleich er Sieg mit den regelmäßigen Truppen sicherte, die 
mit Artillerieenergie bewaffnet wurden, feierten 10 Jahre später 
Samuel Woodward die Rolle der Sharpshooters, die lang bewaffnet wurden
mit Kentucky Gewehren in seinem Lied "die Jäger von Kentucky." 
Dieses unermeßlich populäre Lied, gefüllt mit Bildern des 
alten Hickorys und seiner der Männer, welche die gut ausgebildete 
Armee von John Bull überwältigen (ein Symbol von Großbritannien), 
wurde ein wirkungsvolles Element in Jacksons erfolgreicher Kampagne 
1828 für Präsidenten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Irrité par l'effet du blocus naval britannique sur
des prix de coton et du soutien des Anglais des attaques d'Indien 
contre les colons blancs de frontière, les fermiers dans les 
Sud et l'ouest ont fortement supporté la guerre de 1812. 
La guerre a terminé deux ans après avec peu d'issues réglées
entre les deux nations. La bataille la plus significative a eu 
lieu après que le traité de paix ait été signé en 1814, quand le 
Général Andrew un slaveholder de Jackson, Tennessee, a décisivement
défait les forces britanniques à la Nouvelle-Orléans. Cette 
victoire retentissant lui a fait un héros et un symbole nationaux des 
combattants de frontière et lui a valu le surnom "vieil hickory." 
Bien qu'il ait fixé la victoire en utilisant les troupes 
régulières armées avec la puissance d'artillerie, dix ans après de
Samuel Woodward ont célébré le rôle des tireurs d'élite armés 
avec le Kentucky fusille longtemps dans sa chanson "les 
chasseurs du Kentucky." Cette chanson immensément populaire, 
remplie d'images de vieil hickory et ses d'hommes accablant l'armée 
bien élevée de John Bull (un symbole de la Grande-Bretagne), est 
devenue un élément pertinent dans la campagne 1828 réussie de 
Jackson pour le président.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Irritado pelo efeito do blockade naval britânico 
em preços do algodão e da sustentação de Ingleses para ataques do 
indian de encontro aos settlers brancos da fronteira, os fazendeiros 
no sul e o oeste suportaram fortemente a guerra de 1812. A 
guerra terminou dois anos mais tarde com poucas edições 
estabelecidas entre as duas nações. A batalha a mais 
significativa ocorreu depois que o tratado da paz foi assinado em 
1814, quando o general Andrew um slaveholder de Jackson, Tennessee, 
derrotou decisively as forças britânicas em Nova Orleães. 
Esta vitória resounding fêz-lhe um herói e um símbolo 
nacionais de lutadores da fronteira e ganhou-lhe o nickname "hickory 
velho." Embora fixasse a vitória usando as tropas regulares 
armadas com a potência da artilharia, dez anos mais tarde de Samuel 
Woodward comemoraram o papel dos sharpshooters armados com os rifles 
de Kentucky por muito tempo em sua canção "os caçadores de 
Kentucky." Esta canção immensely popular, enchida com as 
imagens do hickory velho e seus dos homens que oprimem o exército bem
treinado de John Bull (um símbolo de Grâ Bretanha), transformou-se 
um elemento eficaz na campanha 1828 bem sucedida de Jackson para o 
presidente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fatto arrabbiare dall'effetto del blocco navale 
britannico sui prezzi del cotone e del sostegno dei Britannici gli 
attacchi dell'indiano contro i settlers bianchi di frontiera, i 
coltivatori nel sud e l'ovest hanno sostenuto fortemente la guerra di 
1812. La guerra si è conclusa due anni più successivamente con
poche edizioni depositate fra le due nazioni. La battaglia più 
significativa ha avvenuto dopo che il trattato di pace fosse firmato 
in 1814, quando il General Andrew uno slaveholder de Jackson, 
Tennessee, decisivamente ha sconfitto le forze britanniche a New 
Orleans. Questa vittoria clamorosa gli ha reso un hero e un 
simbolo nazionali dei combattenti di frontiera e gli ha guadagnato il 
nickname "vecchio hickory." Anche se ha assicurato la vittoria 
usando le truppe normali munite con potenza dell'artiglieria, dieci 
anni successivamente di Samuel Woodward hanno celebrato il ruolo degli
sharpshooters muniti lungamente con i fucili del Kentucky nella sua 
canzone "i cacciatori del Kentucky." Questa canzone immenso 
popolare, riempita di immagini di vecchio hickory e suoi degli uomini 
che sopraffanno l'esercito ben educato di John Bull (un simbolo della 
Gran-Bretagna), si è transformata in in un elemento efficace nella 
campagna riuscita 1828 de Jackson per il presidente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θυμωμένοι από την επίδραση του βρετανικού ναυτικού 
αποκλεισμού στις τιμές βαμβακιού και της βρετανικής υποστήριξης 
για τις ινδικές επιθέσεις ενάντια στους λευκούς συνοριακούς 
αποίκους, οι αγρότες στο νότο και τη δύση υποστήριξαν έντονα τον
πόλεμο 1812. Ο πόλεμος τελείωσε δύο έτη αργότερα με 
λίγα ζητήματα που εγκαταστάθηκαν μεταξύ των δύο εθνών. Η 
σημαντικότερη μάχη πραγματοποιήθηκε αφότου υπογράφηκε η συνθήκη 
ειρήνης το 1814, όταν νίκησε αποφασιστικά ο στρατηγός 
Andrew Τζάκσον, ένα Tennessee slaveholder, τις βρετανικές 
δυνάμεις στη Νέα Ορλεάνη. Αυτή η ηχητική νίκη τον έκανε 
έναν εθνικούς ήρωα και ένα σύμβολο των συνοριακών μαχητών και 
τον κέρδισε το παρωνύμιο "παλαιά άσπρη καρυδιά." Αν και 
εξασφάλισε τη νίκη χρησιμοποιώντας τα κανονικά στρατεύματα που 
οπλίστηκαν με τη δύναμη πυροβολικού, δέκα έτη αργότερα ο 
Samuel Woodward γιόρτασε το ρόλο των άριστων σκοπευτών που 
οπλίστηκαν με τα μακριά τουφέκια του Κεντάκυ στο τραγούδι του 
"τους κυνηγούς του Κεντάκυ." Αυτό το πάρα πολύ δημοφιλές 
τραγούδι, που γέμισαν με τις εικόνες της άσπρης καρυδιάς και των 
ηληκιωμένων του που συντρίβουν τον καλά εκπαιδευμένο στρατό 
John Bull (ένα σύμβολο της Μεγάλης Βρετανίας), έγινε ένα 
αποτελεσματικό στοιχείο στην επιτυχή εκστρατεία 1828 του 
Τζάκσον για τον Πρόεδρο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encolerizado por el efecto del bloqueo naval 
británico en precios del algodón y de la ayuda de Británicos para 
los ataques del indio contra los colonos blancos de la frontera, los 
granjeros en el sur y el oeste utilizaron fuertemente la guerra de 
1812. La guerra terminó dos años más adelante con pocas 
ediciones colocadas entre las dos naciones. La batalla más 
significativa ocurrió después de que el tratado de la paz fuera 
firmado en 1814, cuando general Andrew Tennessee un slaveholder de 
Jackson, decisivo derrotó las fuerzas británicas en New Orleans. 
Esta victoria resounding le hizo un héroe y un símbolo 
nacionales de combatientes de la frontera y le ganó el apodo "vieja 
nuez dura." Aunque él aseguró la victoria usando a tropas 
regulares armadas con potencia de la artillería, diez años más 
adelante de Samuel Woodward celebraron el papel de los tiradores de 
primera armados con los rifles de Kentucky de largo en su canción 
"los cazadores de Kentucky." Esta canción inmenso popular, 
llenada de imágenes de la vieja nuez dura y sus de los hombres que 
abrumaban al ejército bien ensen$ado de Juan Bull (un símbolo de 
Gran Bretaña), se convirtió en un elemento eficaz en la campaña 
acertada 1828 de Jackson para el presidente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086970</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107931</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-hunters-of-kentucky-a-popular-song-celebrates-the-victory-of-jackson-and-his-frontier-fighters-over-the-british-1824</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
