<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108551</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108551</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201056</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Contour Basics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Form-Grundlagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fondations de Découpe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Princípios Do Contorno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Principi fondamentali Di Profilo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βασικά περιγράμματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fundamentos Del Contorno</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Contour Basics is an exercise designed to introduce students to contour plots. The Contour Activity is a great on-line resource that starts slowly and increases in difficulty. It teaches students basic techniques for generating contours, introduces students to the subtleties of generating contour plots with sparse data, provides many opportunities for students to assess their own progress and understanding and has complete on-line drawing capabilities. The exercise is geared toward atmospheric and oceanic sciences but is beneficial for all geoscience students. In addition to the exercise, this site includes information on teaching materials, teaching notes and tips, assessment suggestions and additional references. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Form-Grundlagen sind eine Übung, die konzipiert 
ist, um Kursteilnehmer vorzustellen, um Plots zu umreißen. Die 
Form-Aktivität ist ein großes Onlinehilfsmittel, das langsam beginnt
und der Schwierigkeit sich erhöht. Sie bringt Kursteilnehmern 
grundlegende Techniken für das Festlegen von von Formen bei, stellt 
Kursteilnehmer zu den Feinheiten des Festlegens der Formplots mit 
spärlichen Daten vor, stellt viele Gelegenheiten zur Verfügung, 
damit Kursteilnehmer ihren eigenen Fortschritt und Verständnis 
festsetzen und hat komplette zeichnende Onlinefähigkeiten. Die 
Übung wird in Richtung zu den atmosphärischen übersetzt und 
ozeanischen Wissenschaften aber ist für alle geoscience 
Kursteilnehmer vorteilhaft. Zusätzlich zur Übung schließt 
diese Site Informationen über Lehrmittel, Unterricht Anmerkungen und 
Spitzen, Einschätzung Vorschläge und zusätzliche Referenzen ein. 
Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les fondations de découpe est un exercice conçu 
pour présenter des étudiants pour contourner des traçages. 
L'activité de découpe est une grande ressource en ligne qui 
commence lentement et augmente en difficulté. Elle enseigne à 
des étudiants des techniques de base pour produire des découpes, 
présente des étudiants aux subtilités de produire des traçages de 
découpe avec des données clairsemées, présente beaucoup de moyens 
des étudiants d'évaluer leur propres progrès et arrangement et a 
des capacités de dessin en ligne complètes. L'exercice est 
adapté vers les sciences atmosphériques et océaniques mais est 
salutaire pour tous les étudiants de geoscience. En plus de 
l'exercice, ce site inclut l'information sur le matériel didactique, 
les notes et les extrémités d'enseignement, les suggestions 
d'évaluation et les références supplémentaires. Cette 
activité fait partie de la collection de point de départ : 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os princípios do contorno são um exercício 
projetado introduzir estudantes para contornear lotes. A 
atividade do contorno é um recurso em linha grande que comece 
lentamente e aumente na dificuldade. Ensina a estudantes 
técnicas básicas para gerar contornos, introduz estudantes aos 
subtleties de gerar lotes do contorno com dados escassos, fornece 
muitas oportunidades para que os estudantes avaliem seus próprios 
progresso e compreensão e tem potencialidades desenhando em linha 
completas. O exercício é engrenado para ciências 
atmosféricas e oceanic mas é benéfico para todos os estudantes do 
geoscience. Além ao exercício, este local inclui a 
informação em materiais de ensino, notas e pontas do ensino, 
sugestões da avaliação e referências adicionais. Esta 
atividade é parte da coleção do ponto começar: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I principi fondamentali di profilo sono 
un'esercitazione destinata per introdurre gli allievi per sagomare i 
diagrammi. L'attività di profilo è una risorsa in linea grande
che comincia lentamente ed aumenta in difficoltà. Insegna ad 
allievi le tecniche di base per la generazione dei profili, introduce 
gli allievi ai subtleties di generazione dei diagrammi di profilo con 
i dati sparsi, offre molte occasioni degli allievi valutare il loro 
propri progresso e comprensione ed ha possibilità dissipanti in linea
complete. L'esercitazione è innestata verso le scienze 
atmosferiche ed oceaniche ma è favorevole per tutti gli allievi di 
geoscience. Oltre che l'esercitazione, questo luogo include le 
informazioni sui materiali didattici, note e punte di insegnamento, 
suggerimenti di valutazione e riferimenti supplementari. Questa 
attività fa parte dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα βασικά περιγράμματος είναι μια άσκηση με σκοπό να 
εισαγάγει τους σπουδαστές για να περιγράψουν τις πλοκές. Η 
δραστηριότητα περιγράμματος είναι ένα μεγάλο σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς που αρχίζει αργά και αυξάνεται στη
δυσκολία. Διδάσκει τους σπουδαστές που οι βασικές τεχνικές 
για τα περιγράμματα, εισάγουν τους σπουδαστές στις οξύνοιες της 
παραγωγής των πλοκών περιγράμματος με τα αραιά στοιχεία, 
παρέχουν πολλές ευκαιρίες για τους σπουδαστές να αξιολογηθεί η 
πρόοδός τους και η κατανόηση και έχουν τις πλήρεις σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση ικανότητες σχεδίων. Η άσκηση συνδέεται προς τις 
ατμοσφαιρικές και ωκεάνειες επιστήμες αλλά είναι ευεργετική για 
όλους τους σπουδαστές geoscience. Εκτός από την άσκηση, 
αυτή η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τις πληροφορίες για τα εκπαιδευτικά 
υλικά, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τις προτάσεις 
αξιολόγησης και τις πρόσθετες αναφορές. Αυτή η 
δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los fundamentos del contorno son un ejercicio 
diseñado para introducir a estudiantes para contornear diagramas. 
La actividad del contorno es un gran recurso en línea que 
comienza lentamente y aumenta de dificultad. Enseña a 
estudiantes las técnicas básicas para generar contornos, introduce a
estudiantes a las delicadezas de generar diagramas del contorno con 
datos escasos, proporciona a muchas oportunidades para que los 
estudiantes evalúen su propio progreso y comprensión y tiene 
capacidades que trazan en línea completas. El ejercicio se 
engrana hacia ciencias atmosféricas y oceánicas pero es beneficioso 
para todos los estudiantes del geoscience. Además del 
ejercicio, este sitio incluye la información sobre los materiales 
didácticos, las notas y las extremidades de la enseñanza, las 
sugerencias del gravamen y las referencias adicionales. Esta 
actividad es parte de la colección del punto de partida: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201056</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108551</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/contour-basics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
