<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108004</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108004</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213243</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Yale-New Haven Teachers Institute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Yale-Neues Hafen-Lehrer-Institut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Yale-Nouvel Institut de Professeurs d'Asile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Instituto Yale-Novo Dos Professores Do Haven</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Yale-Nuovo Istituto Degli Insegnanti Del Porto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υαλε-νέος ίδρυμα δασκάλων λιμανιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Instituto Yale-Nuevo De los Profesores Del Asilo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site houses a compilation of curricular materials. Dozens of courses are listed, representing a broad spectrum of topics in the sciences and humanities. Most of the material was written for middle school and high school, but could be adapted to a wider audience. There are several courses in the earth sciences, including geology, global change, and environmental science. Each course includes self-contained modules, lesson plans, student activities and background materials.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site bringt eine Kompilation der 
Lehrplanmaterialien unter. Die Dutzende Kurse werden ausgedruckt
und stellen ein ausgedehntes Spektrum von Themen in den Wissenschaften
und in der Menschlichkeit dar. Die meisten des Materials wurde 
für mittlere Schule und High School geschrieben, aber konnte einem 
breiteren Publikum angepaßt werden. Es gibt einige Kurse in den
Geowissenschaften, einschließlich Geologie, in der globalen Änderung
und in der Klimawissenschaft. Jeder Kurs schließt selbständige
Module, Lektionpläne, Kursteilnehmeraktivitäten und 
Hintergrundmaterialien ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site loge une compilation des matériaux 
curriculaires. Des douzaines de cours sont énumérées, 
représentant un large éventail les sujets en sciences et sciences 
humaines. La majeure partie du matériel a été écrite pour le
collège et le lycée, mais a pu être adaptée à une assistance plus
large. Il y a plusieurs cours en sciences de la terre, y compris
la géologie, changement global, et science environnementale. 
Chaque cours inclut des modules de art de l'auto-portrait-contained, des 
plans de leçon, des activités d'étudiant et des matières de base.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local abriga uma compilação de materiais 
curricular. As dúzias dos cursos são alistadas, representando 
um spectrum largo dos tópicos nas ciências e nos humanities. A
maioria do material foi escrito para a escola média e a High School, 
mas podia ser adaptado a uma audiência mais larga. Há diversos
cursos nas ciências de terra, including a geologia, na mudança 
global, e na ciência ambiental. Cada curso inclui os módulos 
self-contained, as plantas da lição, as atividades do estudante e os
materiais de fundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo alloggia una compilazione dei 
materiali d'insegnamento. Le dozzine dei corsi sono elencate, 
rappresentanti una vasta gamma di soggetti nelle scienze e negli studi
umanistici. La maggior parte del materiale è stato scritto per 
la scuola centrale e la High School, ma ha potuto essere adattato ad 
un pubblico più largo. Ci sono parecchi corsi nelle scienze 
della terra, compreso la geologia, nel cambiamento globale e nella 
scienza ambientale. Ogni corso include i moduli autonomi, i 
programmi di lezione, le attività dell'allievo ed i materiali di 
base.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή στεγάζει μια μεταγλώττιση των 
διδακτικών υλικών. Οι δωδεκάδες των σειρών μαθημάτων 
παρατίθενται, αντιπροσωπεύοντας ένα ευρύ φάσμα των θεμάτων στις 
επιστήμες και τις ανθρωπότητες. Το μεγαλύτερο μέρος του 
υλικού γράφτηκε για τη δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση και το γυμνάσιο, 
αλλά θα μπορούσε να προσαρμοστεί σε ένα ευρύτερο ακροατήριο. 
Υπάρχουν διάφορες σειρές μαθημάτων στις γήινες επιστήμες, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της γεωλογίας, τη σφαιρική αλλαγή, και την 
περιβαλλοντική επιστήμη. Κάθε σειρά μαθημάτων περιλαμβάνει
τις ανεξάρτητες ενότητες, τα σχέδια μαθήματος, τις δραστηριότητες
σπουδαστών και τα υλικά υποβάθρου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio contiene una compilación de materiales
del plan de estudios. Las docenas de cursos se enumeran, 
representando un amplio espectro de asuntos en las ciencias y la 
humanidad. La mayoría del material fue escrito para la escuela 
media y la High School secundaria, pero se podía adaptar a una 
audiencia más ancha. Hay varios cursos en las geologías, 
incluyendo la geología, el cambio global, y la ciencia ambiental. 
Cada curso incluye los módulos autónomos, los planes de la 
lección, las actividades del estudiante y los materiales de base.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213243</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108004</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/yale-new-haven-teachers-institute</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
