<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108546</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108546</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206265</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Environmental Photographs, 1891-1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanische Klimafotographien, 1891-1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Photographies Environnementales Américaines, 
1891-1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fotografias Ambientais Americanas, 1891-1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fotografie Ambientali Americane, 1891-1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικές περιβαλλοντικές φωτογραφίες, 1891-1936</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fotografías Ambientales Americanas, 1891-1936</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">consists of 4,500 photographs of natural environments, ecologies, and plant communities in the United States taken between 1891 and 1936. These photographs show a wide range of American topography and its forestation, aridity, shifting coastal dune complexes, and watercourses. Comparisons of early photographs with later views highlight changes resulting from natural alterations of the landscape, disturbances from industry and development, and effective natural resource usage.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">besteht aus 4.500 Fotographien der natürlichen 
Umgebungen, der ecologies und der Betriebsgemeinschaften in den 
Vereinigten Staaten, die zwischen 1891 und 1936 genommen werden. 
Diese Fotographien zeigen eine breite Strecke der amerikanischen
Topographie und sein forestation, aridity, verschiebenden 
Küstendünekomplexe und Wasserläufe. Vergleiche der frühen 
Fotographien mit neueren Ansichten markieren Änderungen, resultierend
aus natürlichen Änderungen der Landschaft, Störungen von der 
Industrie und von der Entwicklung und wirkungsvollem 
Naturresourceverbrauch.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">se compose de 4.500 photographies des 
environnements, des ecologies, et des communautés normaux d'usine aux
Etats-Unis pris entre 1891 et 1936. Ces photographies montrent 
un éventail de topographie américaine et son forestation, 
aridité, complexes dunaires côtiers de décalage, et cours 
d'eau. Les comparaisons des photographies tôt avec des vues 
postérieures mettent en valeur des changements résultant des 
changements normaux de l'horizontal, des perturbations d'industrie et 
de développement, et de l'utilisation pertinente de ressource 
naturelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">consiste em 4.500 fotografias de ambientes, de 
ecologies, e de comunidades naturais da planta nos estados unidos 
feitos exame entre 1891 e 1936. Estas fotografias mostram uma 
escala larga do topography americano e o seus forestation, aridity, 
complexos litorais deslocando da duna, e watercourses. As 
comparações de fotografias adiantadas com vistas mais atrasadas 
destacam mudanças resultando das alterações naturais da paisagem, 
dos distúrbios da indústria e do desenvolvimento, e do uso eficaz do
recurso natural.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiste di 4.500 fotografie degli ambienti 
naturali, ecologies e le Comunità della pianta in unito 
Dichiara preso fra 1891 e 1936. Queste fotografie 
mostrano una vasta gamma della topografia americana ed il relativi 
forestation, aridity, complessi litoranei mobili della duna e corsi 
d'acqua. I confronti delle fotografie in anticipo con le viste 
successive evidenziano i cambiamenti derivando dalle alterazioni 
naturali del paesaggio, dalle dispersioni da industria e da sviluppo e
dall'uso efficace delle risorse naturali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποτελείται από 4.500 φωτογραφίες των φυσικές 
περιβαλλόντων, των οικολογιών, και κοινότητα εγκαταστάσεων στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες που λαμβάνονται μεταξύ 1891 και 1936. 
Αυτές οι φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν ευρύ φάσμα της 
αμερικανικής τοπογραφίας και της δάσωσής της, ξηρασία, που 
μετατοπίζουν τα παράκτια συγκροτήματα αμμόλοφων, και τις κοίτες. 
Οι συγκρίσεις των πρόωρων φωτογραφιών με τις πιό πρόσφατες 
όψεις δίνουν έμφαση στις αλλαγές ως αποτέλεσμα των φυσικών 
τροποποιήσεων του τοπίου, διαταραχές από τη βιομηχανία και την 
ανάπτυξη, και την αποτελεσματική χρήση των φυσικών στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">consiste en 4.500 fotografías de ambientes, de 
ecologies, y de comunidades naturales de la planta en los Estados 
Unidos tomados entre 1891 y 1936. Estas fotografías muestran 
una amplia gama de la topografía americana y su forestation, aridity,
complejos costeros de la duna que cambian de puesto, y arroyos. 
Las comparaciones de fotografías tempranas con visiónes más 
últimas destacan cambios resultando de las alteraciones naturales del
paisaje, de los disturbios de la industria y del desarrollo, y de uso 
eficaz del recurso natural.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206265</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108546</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-environmental-photographs-1891-1936</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
