<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108485</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108485</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201528</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Environmental Frontlines Issue Summary: mining on public lands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">KlimaFrontlinie-Ausgabe Zusammenfassung: 
Bergbau auf allgemeinen Ländern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sommaire Environnemental d'Issue de Lignes du front :
extraction sur les terres publiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sumário Ambiental Da Edição De Frontlines: 
minar em terras públicas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sommario Ambientale Dell'Edizione Di Frontlines: 
estraendo sulle terre pubbliche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιβαλλοντική περίληψη ζητημάτων πρώτων γραμμών: 
να εξαγάγει στα δημόσια εδάφη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Resumen Ambiental De la Edición De Frontlines: 
el minar en pistas públicas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This case study provided by the Environmental Frontline organization is a summary of the 1872 general mining law reform. It includes background information, facts and figures, 'quotable quotables', and recent actions, as well as links to websites of key players, information sources, and relevant reports. Environmental Frontlines organization monitors current environmental issues and the groups involved with such issues. The Mining on Public Lands case study is part of that monitoring program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Fallstudie stellte von der 
KlimaFrontlinieorganisation ist eine Zusammenfassung der allgemeinen 
gewinnenVerbesserung des gesetzes 1872 zur Verfügung. Sie 
schließt Hintergrundinformationen, Tatsachen und Abbildungen, ' 
zitierfähige quotables' und neue Tätigkeiten, sowie Links zu den Web
site der Schlüsselspieler, der Informationsquellen und der relevanten
Reports ein. KlimaFrontlinieorganisation überwacht aktuelle 
Klimaausgaben und die Gruppen, die in solche Ausgaben mit einbezogen 
werden. Der Bergbau auf Öffentlichkeit Land-Fallstudie ist ein 
Teil dieses Überwachungsprogramms.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette étude de cas a fourni par l'organisation 
environnementale de Ligne du front est un sommaire de la réforme 
d'extraction générale de la loi 1872. Elle inclut 
l'information de fond, les faits et les figures, 'quotables citables, 
et les actions récentes, aussi bien que des liens aux sites Web des 
joueurs principaux, des émetteurs d'informations, et des états 
appropriés. L'organisation environnementale de Lignes du front 
surveille les questions environnementales actuelles et les groupes 
impliqués de telles issues. L'exploitation sur l'étude de cas 
de terres de public fait partie de ce programme de contrôle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este estudo de caso forneceu pela organização 
ambiental de Frontline é um sumário da reforma minando geral da lei 
1872. Inclui a informação de fundo, os fatos e as figuras, ' 
quotables' quotable, e ações recentes, as.well.as as ligações aos 
Web site dos jogadores chaves, das fontes de informação, e de 
relatórios relevantes. A organização ambiental de Frontlines 
monitora edições ambientais atuais e os grupos envolvidos com tais 
edições. A mineração no estudo de exemplo das terras do 
público é parte desse programa de monitoração.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa inchiesta fornita dall'organizzazione 
ambientale di Frontline è un sommario della riforma estraente 
generale di legge 1872. Include le informazioni di base, i fatti
e le figure, 'quotables quotable e le azioni recenti, così come i 
collegamenti ai Web site dei giocatori chiave, delle sorgenti di 
informazioni e dei rapporti relativi. L'organizzazione 
ambientale di Frontlines controlla le questioni ambientali attuali ed 
i gruppi addetti a tali edizioni. L'estrazione mineraria 
sull'inchiesta delle terre del pubblico fa parte di quel programma di 
controllo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη που παρέχεται από την 
περιβαλλοντική οργάνωση πρώτης γραμμής είναι μια περίληψη της 
γενικής μεταρρύθμισης νόμου μεταλλείας 1872. 
Περιλαμβάνει τις βασικές πληροφορίες, τα γεγονότα και τους 
αριθμούς, τα "μνημονεύσιμα quotables", και τις πρόσφατες 
ενέργειες, καθώς επίσης και τις συνδέσεις με τους ιστοχώρους των 
βασικών φορέων, των πηγών πληροφοριών, και των σχετικών 
εκθέσεων. Η περιβαλλοντική οργάνωση πρώτων γραμμών ελέγχει
τα παρόντα περιβαλλοντικά ζητήματα και τις ομάδες που ασχολούνται
με τέτοια ζητήματα. Η μεταλλεία στη δημόσια 
περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη εδαφών είναι μέρος εκείνου του 
προγράμματος ελέγχου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este estudio de caso proporcionó por la 
organización ambiental de Frontline es un resumen de la reforma 
general de la ley que minaba 1872. Incluye la información de 
fondo, hechos y las figuras, ' quotables quotable, y las acciones 
recientes, así como conexiones a los Web site de los jugadores 
dominantes, de las fuentes de información, y de los informes 
relevantes. La organización ambiental de Frontlines vigila a 
ediciones ambientales actuales y a grupos implicados con tales 
ediciones. La explotación minera en estudio de caso de las 
pistas del público es parte de ese programa que vigila.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201528</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108485</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/environmental-frontlines-issue-summary-mining-on-public-lands</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
