<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105932</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105932</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207235</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Traveling the National Road</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reisen die nationale Straße</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voyageant la route nationale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Viajando a estrada nacional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Viaggiando la strada nazionale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ταξίδι του εθνικού δρόμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Viajando el camino nacional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of the first road built with federal funds. Construction of the 632-mile road from Cumberland, Maryland, to Vandalia, Illinois, began in 1811. The aim was to improve trade between the east and the emerging western frontier and to avoid losing western trade to England in Canada or Spain in the Louisiana Territory. The website tells how the road was built, how people traveled on it, accommodations they found along the way, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte der ersten Straße, die 
mit Staatspapieren aufgebaut wird. Aufbau der 632-mile Straße 
von Cumberland, Maryland, zu Vandalia, Illinois, fing 1811 an. 
Das Ziel war, Handel zwischen dem Osten und der auftauchenden 
westlichen Grenze zu verbessern und Schlussen westlichen Handel nach 
England in Kanada oder in Spanien in der Louisiana Gegend zu 
vermeiden. Die Web site erklärt, wie die Straße, wie Leute auf
sie reisten, Anpassungen, die sie entlang der Methode fanden und mehr 
aufgebaut wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire de la première route construite 
avec les fonds fédéraux. La construction 632-mile de la route 
de Cumberland, le Maryland, à Vandalia, l'Illinois, a commencé en 
1811. Le but était améliorer le commerce entre l'est et la 
frontière occidentale naissante et d'éviter le commerce occidental 
perdant en Angleterre au Canada ou en Espagne dans le territoire de la
Louisiane. Le site Web indique que la route a été construite, 
comment les gens ont voyagé là-dessus, logement qu'ils ont trouvé 
le long de la voie, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história da primeira estrada construída 
com fundos federais. A construção 632-mile da estrada de 
Cumberland, Maryland, a Vandalia, Illinois, começou em 1811. O 
alvo era melhorar o comércio entre o leste e a fronteira ocidental 
emergente e evitar comércio ocidental perdedor a Inglaterra em 
Canadá ou em Spain no território de Louisiana. O Web site diz 
como a estrada foi construída, como os povos viajaram nele, 
acomodações que encontraram ao longo da maneira, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia della prima strada costruita con 
i fondi monetari federali. La costruzione 632-mile della strada 
da Cumberland, Maryland, a Vandalia, l'Illinois, ha cominciato in 
1811. Lo scopo era di migliorare il commercio fra l'est e la 
frontiera occidentale d'emersione ed evitare il commercio occidentale 
perdente in Inghilterra nel Canada o in Spagna nel territorio della 
Luisiana. Il Web site dice a come la strada è stata costruita, 
come la gente ha viaggiato su esso, sistemazioni che hanno trovato 
lungo il modo e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία του πρώτου δρόμου που χτίζεται με τα
ομοσπονδιακά κεφάλαια. Η κατασκευή του δρόμου 632-μιλίου 
από το Cumberland, Μέρυλαντ, σε Vandalia, Ιλλινόις, άρχισε 
το 1811. Ο στόχος ήταν να βελτιωθεί το εμπόριο μεταξύ 
της ανατολής και των δυτικών συνόρων ανάδυσης και να αποφύγει το 
δυτικό εμπόριο στην Αγγλία στον Καναδά ή την Ισπανία στο έδαφος
της Λουιζιάνας. Ο ιστοχώρος λέει πώς ο δρόμος χτίστηκε, 
πώς οι άνθρωποι ταξίδεψαν σε τον, στεγάσεις αυτοί βρήκε κατά 
μήκος του τρόπου, και περισσότερων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia del primer camino construido 
con los fondos federales. La construcción 632-mile del camino 
de Cumberland, Maryland, a Vandalia, Illinois, comenzó en 1811. 
La puntería era mejorar comercio entre el este y la frontera 
occidental que emergía y evitar comercio occidental perdidoso a 
Inglaterra en Canadá o España en el territorio de Luisiana. El
Web site dice cómo el camino fue construido, cómo la gente viajó en
él, las comodidades que ella encontró a lo largo de la manera, y 
más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207235</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105932</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/traveling-the-national-road</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
