<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106878</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106878</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203726</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Looking for life in all the wrong places - research on cryptoendoliths</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach dem Leben in allen Unrechtplätzen - 
Forschung auf cryptoendoliths suchen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Recherchant la vie dans tous les endroits de mal -
recherche sur des cryptoendoliths</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Procurando a vida em todos os lugares do erro - 
pesquisa sobre cryptoendoliths</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cercando vita in tutti i posti di torto - ricerca 
sui cryptoendoliths</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψάχνοντας τη ζωή σε όλες τις λανθασμένες θέσεις - 
έρευνα για τα cryptoendoliths</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Buscando la vida en todos los lugares del mal - 
investigación sobre cryptoendoliths</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This article highlights the professional careers of two pioneer microbiologists, Imre Friedmann and his wife Roseli Ocampo-Friedmann. A personal interview with Friedmann gives readers a first hand account of the novel thoughts and discoveries of cryptoendolithic bacteria, or bacteria living within rock. For the past 50 years these two scientists have searched for microbial and algal life among the rocks and sediments of ancient water bodies in deserts, arid polar environments, and other places on earth once thought to be void of all life.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Artikel markiert die professionellen 
Karrieren von zwei Pionierbiologen, von Imre Friedmann und von seiner 
Frau Roseli Ocampo-Friedmann. Ein persönliches Interview mit 
Friedmann berichtet Lesern erstes Handüber den Romangedanken und den 
Entdeckungen des cryptoendolithic Bakteriums oder des Bakteriums, das 
innerhalb des Felsens lebt. Nach den letzten 50 Jahren haben 
diese zwei Wissenschaftler nach Mikroben gesucht und Algenlebensdauer 
unter den Felsen und den Sedimenten der alten Wasserkörper in den 
Wüsten, dachten trockene polare Umgebungen und andere Plätze auf 
Masse einmal, um Lücke aller Lebensdauer zu sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet article met en valeur les carrières 
professionnelles de deux microbiologistes pionniers, d'Imre Friedmann 
et de son épouse Roseli Ocampo-Friedmann. Une entrevue 
personnelle avec Friedmann fait à des lecteurs un exposé de 
première main des pensées de roman et des découvertes des 
bactéries cryptoendolithic, ou des bactéries vivant dans la roche. 
Pendant les 50 dernières années ces deux scientifiques ont 
recherché microbien et la vie d'algues parmi les roches et les 
sédiments des corps antiques de l'eau dans les déserts, les 
environnements polaires arides, et d'autres endroits sur terre ont par
le passé pensé pour être vide de toute la vie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este artigo destaca as carreiras profissionais de 
dois microbiologists pioneiros, de Imre Friedmann e de sua esposa 
Roseli Ocampo-Friedmann. Uma entrevista pessoal com Friedmann 
dá a leitores um primeiro cliente da mão dos pensamentos da novela e
das descobertas das bactérias cryptoendolithic, ou das bactérias que
vivem dentro da rocha. Por os 50 anos passados estes dois 
cientistas procurararam por microbial e vida algal entre as rochas e 
os sedimentos de corpos antigos da água nos desertos, os ambientes 
polares arid, e outros lugares na terra pensaram uma vez para ser 
vácuo de toda a vida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo articolo evidenzia le carriere 
professionali di due microbiologi pionieristici, di Imre Friedmann e 
della sua moglie Roseli Ocampo-Friedmann. Un'intervista 
personale con Friedmann fa a lettori un primo resoconto della mano dei
pensieri del romanzo e delle scoperte dei batteri cryptoendolithic, o 
dei batteri che vivono all'interno della roccia. I 50 anni 
scorsi questi due scienziati hanno cercato microbico e vita d'alghe 
fra le roccie ed i sedimenti degli enti antichi dell'acqua in deserti,
gli ambienti polari aridi ed altri posti su terra hanno pensato una 
volta per essere vuoto di tutta la vita.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το άρθρο δίνει έμφαση στις επαγγελματικές 
σταδιοδρομίες δύο μικροβιολόγων πρωτοπόρων, του Imre 
Friedmann και της συζύγου του Roseli οθαμπο- Friedmann. 
Μια προσωπική συνέντευξη με Friedmann δίνει στους 
αναγνώστες μια πρώτη περιγραφή χεριών των νέων σκέψεων και των 
ανακαλύψεων των cryptoendolithic βακτηριδίων, ή στα βακτηρίδια 
ζωντανός μέσα στο βράχο. Για τα προηγούμενα 50 έτη αυτοί 
οι δύο επιστήμονες έχουν ψάξει για τη μικροβιακή και φυκώδη ζωή
μεταξύ των βράχων και των ιζημάτων των αρχαίων οργανισμών ύδατος
στις ερήμους, τα ξηρά πολικά περιβάλλοντα, και άλλες θέσεις στη 
γη μιά φορά πιθανά κενή όλης της ζωής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este artículo destaca las carreras profesionales 
de dos microbiólogos pioneros, de Imre Friedmann y de su esposa 
Roseli Ocampo-Friedmann. Una entrevista personal con Friedmann 
da a programas de lectura una cuenta de primera mano de los 
pensamientos de la novela y de los descubrimientos de bacterias 
cryptoendolithic, o de bacterias que viven dentro de roca. Por 
los últimos 50 años estos dos científicos han buscado para 
microbiano y vida algal entre las rocas y los sedimentos de los 
cuerpos antiguos del agua en desiertos, los ambientes polares áridos,
y otros lugares en la tierra pensaron una vez para ser vacío de toda 
la vida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WILL-DISCOVER HIVELY
FN:WILL-DISCOVER HIVELY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LOOKSMART, LOOKSMART, LTD.
FN:LOOKSMART, LOOKSMART, LTD.
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203726</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106878</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/looking-for-life-in-all-the-wrong-places-research-on-cryptoendoliths</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
