<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103326</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103326</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086153</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Federal legislation is not needed": Debating the Equal Pay Act of 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Bundesgesetzgebung ist nicht" erforderlich: 
Debattieren der gleiche Bezahlung Tat von 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la législation fédérale n'est pas nécessaire"
: Discussion de l'acte d'égalité de salaires de 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a legislação federal não é needed": 
Debatendo o ato do pagamento igual de 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la legislazione federale non è necessaria": 
Dibattere la Legge di parità salariale di 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η "ομοσπονδιακή νομοθεσία δεν απαιτείται": 
Συζήτηση του νόμου ίσης αμοιβής του 1963</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "legislación federal no es necesaria": 
Discutir el acto de la igualdad de salario de 1963</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Recommendations by the National War Labor Board during World War II to pay male and female workers equal wages yielded few changes in the gender wage gap. Women continued to receive less money for comparable work, and into the 1960s want ads characterized jobs as "male" or "female" with resulting salary differences based on gender. The Equal Pay Act (EPA) made it illegal to pay men and women differently for similar work. Although the EPA was passed in 1963, it was debated in workplaces and courtrooms for decades thereafter. In this statement submitted to the Senate hearing on the EPA, the National Retail Merchant Association (NRMA), an organization representing retail employers, claimed that the legislation was unnecessary, expensive, and impossible to enforce. While professing that equal pay for women was "an admirable principle," the NRMA also argued that high rates of absenteeism and protective legislation made women more expensive to employ than men.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Empfehlungen durch das nationale Krieg-Arbeit 
Brett während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, die männlichen und weiblichen
Arbeiter zu zahlen gleiche Löhne erbrachten wenige Änderungen im 
Geschlechtlohnabstand. Frauen fuhren fort, weniger Geld für 
vergleichbare Arbeit zu empfangen, und in die sechziger Jahre 
wünschen Sie ADS gekennzeichnete Jobs als "Mann" oder "Frau" mit den 
resultierenden Gehalt Unterschieden, die auf Geschlecht basieren. 
Die gleiche Bezahlung Tat (EPA) bildete es ungültig, Männer 
und Frauen für ähnliche Arbeit anders als zu zahlen. Obgleich 
das EPA 1963 geführt wurde, wurde es in den Arbeitsplätzen und in 
den Gerichtssälen für Dekaden danach debattiert. In dieser 
Anweisung gab bei der Senathörfähigkeit auf dem EPA, die nationale 
Kleinkaufmann Verbindung (NRMA), eine Organisation ein, welche die 
Kleinarbeitgeber darstellt, behauptet, daß die Gesetzgebung nicht 
notwendig war, kostspielig, und unmöglich zu erzwingen. 
Während, diese gleiche Bezahlung für Frauen zu erklären "eine
bewundernswerte Grundregel war," argumentierte das NRMA auch, daß 
hohe Abwesenheitsraten und schützende Gesetzgebung Frauen 
kostspieliger als Männer zu beschäftigen bildeten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les recommandations par l'office national de 
travail de guerre pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale de payer les 
ouvriers de sexe masculin et féminins les salaires égaux ont 
rapporté peu de changements de l'écart salarial de genre. Les 
femmes ont continué à recevoir moins d'argent pour le travail 
comparable, et dans les années 60 voulez les travaux caractérisés 
par ADS en tant que le "mâle" ou "femelle" avec des différences 
résultantes de salaire basées sur le genre. La Loi d'égalité
de salaires (EPA) l'a rendu illégal pour payer des hommes et des 
femmes différemment le travail semblable. Bien que l'EPA ait 
été passé en 1963, il a été discuté dans les lieux de travail et
les auditoires de tribunal pendant des décennies ensuite. Dans 
ce rapport a soumis à l'audition de sénat sur l'EPA, l'association 
nationale de marchand au détail (NRMA), une organisation 
représentant les employeurs au détail, réclamés que la 
législation était impossible inutile, chère, et à imposer. 
Tandis que professer cette égalité de salaires pour des femmes
était "un principe excellent," le NRMA a également argué du fait 
que les cadences élevées de l'absentéisme et de la législation 
protectrice ont rendu des femmes plus chères d'utiliser que des 
hommes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As recomendações pela placa nacional do trabalho
da guerra durante a segunda guerra mundial pagar os trabalhadores 
masculinos e fêmeas salários iguais renderam poucas mudanças na 
abertura de salário do gender. As mulheres continuaram a 
receber menos dinheiro para o trabalho comparável, e nos 1960s queira
trabalhos caracterizados ads como o "macho" ou a "fêmea" com as 
diferenças resultantes do salário baseadas no gender. O ato do
pagamento igual (EPA) fêz ilegal para pagar diferentemente homens e 
mulheres pelo trabalho similar. Embora o EPA fosse passado em 
1963, foi debatido nos workplaces e nos courtrooms por décadas depois
disso. Nesta indicação submeteu-se ao hearing no EPA, a 
associação nacional do senate do comerciante de varejo (NRMA), uma 
organização que representa os empregadores de varejo, reivindicados 
que a legislação era desnecessária, cara, e impossível reforçar. 
Quando professar esse pagamento igual para mulheres era "um 
princípio admirable," o NRMA discutiu também que as taxas de 
absentismo elevadas e da legislação protetora fizeram mulheres mais 
caras empregar do que homens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le raccomandazioni dal Bordo Di lavoro di 
guerra nazionale durante la seconda guerra mondiale pagare gli operai 
maschii e femminili stipendi uguali hanno reso pochi cambiamenti nello
spacco di stipendio di genere. Le donne hanno continuato a 
ricevere meno soldi per lavoro paragonabile e negli anni 60 desideri i
lavori caratterizzati ads come "il maschio" o "femmina" con le 
differenze risultanti di stipendio basate sul genere. La Legge 
di parità salariale (EPA) lo ha reso illegale per pagare diversamente
gli uomini e le donne lavoro simile. Anche se il EPA è stato 
passato in 1963, è stato dibattuto da allora in poi in posti di 
lavoro ed in aule di tribunale per le decadi. In questa istruzione ha 
presentato all'udienza sul EPA, l'associazione nazionale del 
commerciante al minuto (NRMA), un'organizzazione del senato che 
rappresenta i datori di lavoro al minuto, sostenuti che la 
legislazione era inutile, costosa ed impossible fare rispettare. 
Mentre professare quella parità salariale per le donne era "un 
principio eccellente," il NRMA egualmente ha sostenuto che gli alti 
tassi di assenteismo e di legislazione protettiva hanno reso le donne 
più costose impiegare che gli uomini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συστάσεις από το εθνικό συμβούλιο πολεμικής 
εργασίας κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ για να 
πληρώσουν στους άνδρες και γυναίκες εργαζομένους τις ίσες 
αμοιβές παρήγαγαν λίγες αλλαγές στο χάσμα αμοιβών γένους. 
Οι γυναίκες συνέχισαν να λαμβάνουν τα λιγότερα χρήματα για 
τη συγκρίσιμη εργασία, και στη δεκαετία του '60 θελήστε 
χαρακτηρισμένες τις αγγελίες εργασίες ως "αρσενικό" ή "θηλυκό" 
με τις προκύπτουσες διαφορές μισθών βασισμένες στο γένος. Ο
νόμος ίσης αμοιβής (EPA) το κατέστησε παράνομο να πληρώσει 
τους άνδρες και τις γυναίκες διαφορετικά για την παρόμοια 
εργασία. Αν και το EPA πέρασαν το 1963, συζητήθηκε 
στους εργασιακούς χώρους και τα δικαστήρια για δεκαετίες έκτοτε. 
Σε αυτήν την δήλωση που υποβλήθηκε στην ακρόαση Συγκλήτου 
στο EPA, η εθνική λιανική εμπορική ένωση (NRMA), μια 
οργάνωση που αντιπροσωπεύει τους λιανικούς εργοδότες, υποστήριξε 
ότι η νομοθεσία ήταν περιττή, ακριβή, και αδύνατη να επιβάλει. 
Δηλώνοντας φανερά εκείνη την ίση αμοιβή για τις γυναίκες 
ήταν "μια αξιοθαύμαστη αρχή," το NRMA επίσης υποστήριξε ότι 
τα υψηλά ποσοστά συστηματικής αποχής απότην εργασία και 
προστατευτικής νομοθεσίας κατέστησαν τις γυναίκες ακριβότερες να 
υιοθετήσουν από τους άνδρες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las recomendaciones por la tarjeta nacional del 
trabajo de la guerra durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial de pagar a 
trabajadores masculinos y femeninos los salarios iguales rindieron 
pocos cambios en el boquete de salario del género. Las mujeres 
continuaron recibiendo menos dinero para el trabajo comparable, y en 
los años 60 desee los trabajos caracterizados ads como "varón" o 
"hembra" con las diferencias del sueldo que resultan basadas en 
género. El acto de la igualdad de salario (EPA) hizo ilegal 
pagar hombres y a mujeres diferentemente trabajo similar. Aunque
el EPA fue pasado en 1963, fue discutido en lugares de trabajo y 
salas de tribunal por décadas después de eso. En esta declaración 
sometió a la audiencia en el EPA, la asociación nacional del 
comerciante al por menor (NRMA), una organización del senado que 
representaba a patrones al por menor, demandados que la legislación 
era innecesaria, costosa, e imposible hacer cumplir. Mientras 
que profesar esa igualdad de salario para las mujeres era "un 
principio admirable," el NRMA también discutió que los altos 
índices del ausentismo y de la legislación protectora hicieran a 
mujeres más costosas emplear que hombres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086153</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103326</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/federal-legislation-is-not-needed-debating-the-equal-pay-act-of-1963</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
