<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104361</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104361</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213120</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Webshaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Webshaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Webshaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Webshaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Webshaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Webshaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Webshaker</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The UC San Diego Webshaker is a live earthquake experiment conducted over the internet. The user can select a historic earthquake or design an earthquake by specifying the frequency, amplitude, and duration. The shake table delivers base motion to the test structure in the same way that an earthquake shakes buildings and other structures. A live video broadcast and precise measurements from sensors located on the test structure are sent to you over the internet. Once the test is complete, the data is sent to your computer and presented in several x-y graphs, displaying the response from different parts of the structure. The web site has supporting readings and homework problems designed to accompany webshaker experiments. There are also sound clips and radio broadcasts from several earthquakes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das UC San Diego Webshaker ist ein 
Phasenerdbebenexperiment, das über das Internet geleitet wird. 
Der Benutzer kann ein historisches Erdbeben auswählen oder ein 
Erdbeben konzipieren, indem er die Frequenz, den Umfang und die Dauer 
spezifiziert. Die Erschütterungtabelle liefert niedrige 
Bewegung an die Teststruktur in der gleichen Methode, daß ein 
Erdbeben Gebäude und andere Strukturen rüttelt. Eine 
lebhaftvideosendung und exakte Messen von den Sensoren, die auf der 
Teststruktur gelegen sind, werden Ihnen über dem Internet geschickt. 
Sobald der Test komplett ist, werden die Daten zu Ihrem Computer
geschickt und dargestellt in einigen x-y Diagrammen und zeigen die 
Antwort von den unterschiedlichen Teilen der Struktur an. Die 
Web site hat unterstützenden Messwerte und die Heimarbeit Probleme, 
die konzipiert sind, um webshaker Experimente zu begleiten. Es 
gibt auch stichhaltige Clips und Radio überträgt von einigen 
Erdbeben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le San UC Diego Webshaker est une expérience de 
phase de tremblement de terre entreprise au-dessus de l'Internet. 
L'utilisateur peut choisir un tremblement de terre historique ou
concevoir un tremblement de terre en indiquant la fréquence, 
l'amplitude, et la durée. La table de secousse fournit le 
mouvement de base à la structure d'essai de la même manière qu'un 
tremblement de terre secoue des bâtiments et d'autres structures. 
Une émission visuelle de phase et des mesures précises des 
capteurs situés sur la structure d'essai vous sont envoyées 
au-dessus de l'Internet. Une fois que l'essai est complet, les 
données sont envoyées à votre ordinateur et présentées dans 
plusieurs graphiques de x/y, affichant la réponse de différentes 
parties de la structure. Le site Web a les lectures et les 
problèmes supportants de travail conçus pour accompagner des 
expériences de webshaker. Il y a également les clips sains et 
la radio annonce de plusieurs tremblements de terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O San UC Diego Webshaker é uma experiência viva 
do terremoto conduzida sobre o Internet. O usuário pode 
selecionar um terremoto historic ou projetar um terremoto 
especificando a freqüência, a amplitude, e a duração. A 
tabela da agitação entrega o movimento baixo à estrutura do teste 
na mesma maneira que um terremoto agita edifícios e outras 
estruturas. Uma transmissão video viva e umas medidas precisas 
dos sensores situados na estrutura do teste são-lhe emitidas sobre o 
Internet. Uma vez que o teste está completo, os dados estão 
emitidos a seu computador e apresentados em diversos gráficos x-y, 
indicando a resposta das partes diferentes da estrutura. O Web 
site tem leituras e os problemas suportando do homework projetados 
acompanhar experiências do webshaker. Há também grampos 
sadios e o rádio transmite de diversos terremotos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">San Diego UC Webshaker è un esperimento in 
tensione di terremoto eseguito sopra il Internet. L'utente può 
selezionare un terremoto storico o progettare un terremoto 
specificando la frequenza, l'ampiezza e la durata. La tabella di
scossa trasporta il movimento basso alla struttura della prova nello 
stesso modo che un terremoto agita le costruzioni ed altre strutture. 
Una video radiodiffusione in tensione e lle misure precise dai 
sensori situati sulla struttura della prova sono trasmesse voi sopra 
il Internet. Una volta che la prova è completa, i dati sono 
trasmessi al vostro calcolatore e sono presentati in parecchi grafici 
di x-y, visualizzanti la risposta dalle parti differenti della 
struttura. Il Web site ha le letture e problemi di sostegno di 
lavoro destinati per accompagnare gli esperimenti del webshaker. 
Ci sono egualmente clip sane e la radio trasmette per radio da 
parecchi terremoti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το UC Σαν Ντιέγκο Webshaker είναι ένα ζωντανό 
πείραμα σεισμού που πραγματοποιείται μέσω του Διαδικτύου. Ο
χρήστης μπορεί να επιλέξει έναν ιστορικό σεισμό ή να σχεδιάσει
έναν σεισμό με τον προσδιορισμό της συχνότητας, του εύρους, και 
της "διάρκεια"ς. Ο πίνακας κουνημάτων παραδίδει την κίνηση 
βάσεων στη δομή δοκιμής με τον ίδιο τρόπο ότι ένας σεισμός 
τινάζει τα κτήρια και άλλες δομές. Μια ζωντανή τηλεοπτική 
ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση και ακριβείς μετρήσεις από τους αισθητήρες 
που βρίσκονται στη δομή δοκιμής σας στέλνονται σε μέσω του 
Διαδικτύου. Μόλις η δοκιμή είναι πλήρης, το στοιχείο 
στέλνεται στον υπολογιστή σας και παρουσιάζεται σε διάφορες 
x-$l*y γραφικές παραστάσεις, που παρουσιάζουν την απάντηση από
τα διαφορετικά μέρη της δομής. Ο ιστοχώρος τις ενισχυτικά 
αναγνώσεις και τα προβλήματα εργασίας να συνοδεύσει webshaker 
τα πειράματα. Υπάρχουν επίσης υγιείς συνδετήρες και ραδιο 
ραδιοφωνικές μεταδόσεις από διάφορους σεισμούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La San Diego UC Webshaker es un experimento vivo 
del terremoto conducido sobre el Internet. El utilizador puede 
seleccionar un terremoto histórico o diseñar un terremoto 
especificando la frecuencia, la amplitud, y la duración. El 
vector de la sacudida entrega el movimiento bajo a la estructura de la
prueba de la misma manera que un terremoto sacudare edificios y otras 
estructuras. Una difusión video viva y las medidas exactas de 
los sensores situados en la estructura de la prueba se envían usted 
sobre el Internet. Una vez que la prueba sea completa, los datos
se envían a su ordenador y se presentan en varios gráficos x-y, 
visualizando la respuesta de diversas partes de la estructura. 
El Web site tiene lecturas y problemas de la preparación que 
utilizan diseñados para acompañar experimentos del webshaker. 
Hay también clips de los sonidos y la radio difunde de varios 
terremotos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213120</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104361</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/webshaker</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
