<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102991</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102991</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201360</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Analyzing the Antarctic Ozone Hole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Analysieren des antarktischen Ozonloches</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Analyse du trou d'ozone antarctique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Analisando o furo de ozônio antarctic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Analizzare il foro di ozono antartico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: Ανάλυση
της ανταρκτικής τρύπας όζοντος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Analizar el agujero de ozono antártico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Users download and analyze satellite images showing the amount of ozone in the stratosphere. They interpret the images to identify the ozone "hole" that develops over Antarctica each summer, and compare its size from year to year. Using freely available image analysis software, ImageJ, users quantify the area of the Antarctic ozone hole each October from 1996 to 2004. Finally, they bring their measurements into a spreadsheet program and create a graph to document changes in the size of the ozone hole.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Benutzer downloaden und analysieren die 
Satellitenbilder, welche die Menge des Ozons in der Stratosphäre 
zeigen. Sie deuten die Bilder, um den Ozon "Bohrung" zu 
kennzeichnen, der Überantarktik jeder Sommer entwickelt und 
vergleichen seine Größe von Jahr zu Jahr. Mit frei vorhandener
Bildanalysesoftware bestimmen ImageJ, Benutzer den Bereich des 
antarktischen Ozonloches jede Oktober von 1996 bis 2004 mengenmäßig.
Schließlich holen sie ihre Messen in ein Kalkulationsprogramm 
und erstellen ein Diagramm, um Änderungen in der Größe des 
Ozonloches zu dokumentieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les utilisateurs téléchargent et analysent des 
images satellites montrant la quantité de l'ozone dans la 
stratosphère. Ils interprètent les images pour identifier 
l'ozone "trou" qui développe l'Antarctique fini chaque été, et 
comparent sa taille d'année en année. En utilisant librement 
le logiciel disponible d'analyse d'image, ImageJ, utilisateurs 
mesurent la zone du trou d'ozone antarctique chaque octobre de 1996 à
2004. En conclusion, ils introduisent leurs mesures dans un 
tableau électronique et créent un graphique pour documenter des 
changements de la taille du trou d'ozone.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os usuários download e analisam as imagens 
satellite que mostram a quantidade de ozônio no stratosphere. 
Interpretam as imagens para identificar o ozônio "furo" que 
desenvolve o antarctica excedente cada verão, e comparam seu tamanho 
do ano ao ano. Usando livremente o software disponível da 
análise de imagem, ImageJ, usuários quantify a área do furo de 
ozônio antarctic cada outubro de 1996 a 2004. Finalmente, 
trazem suas medidas em um programa de spreadsheet e críam um gráfico
para documentar mudanças no tamanho do furo de ozônio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli utenti trasferiscono ed analizzano le immagini
dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti satelliti che mostrano la 
quantità di ozono nella stratosfera. Interpretano le immagini 
per identificare l'ozono "foro" che sviluppa l'Antartide eccessiva 
ogni estate e confrontano il relativo formato di anno in anno. 
Usando liberamente il software disponibile di analisi di 
immagine, ImageJ, utenti misura la zona del foro di ozono antartico 
ogni ottobre da 1996 a 2004. Per concludere, introducono le loro
misure in un foglio elettronico e creano un grafico per documentare i 
cambiamenti nel formato del foro di ozono.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι χρήστες μεταφορτώνουν και αναλύουν τις δορυφορικές 
εικόνες που εμφανίζουν το ποσό όζοντος στη στρατόσφαιρα. 
Ερμηνεύουν τις εικόνες για να προσδιορίσουν το όζον "τρύπα"
που αναπτύσσεται πέρα από την Ανταρκτική κάθε καλοκαίρι, και 
συγκρίνουν το μέγεθός του από χρόνο σε χρόνο. 
Χρησιμοποιώντας ελεύθερα το διαθέσιμο λογισμικό ανάλυσης 
εικόνας, ImageJ, χρήστες ποσολογούν τον τομέα της ανταρκτικής 
τρύπας όζοντος κάθε Οκτώβριος από το 1996 ως το 2004. 
Τέλος, φέρνουν τις μετρήσεις τους σε ένα πρόγραμμα 
υπολογισμών με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet) και δημιουργούν 
μια γραφική παράσταση στις αλλαγές εγγράφων στο μέγεθος της 
τρύπας όζοντος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los utilizadores descargan y analizan las 
imágenes basadas en los satélites que muestran la cantidad de ozono 
en la estratosfera. Interpretan las imágenes para identificar 
el ozono "agujero" que desarrolla el antártida excesivo cada verano, 
y comparan su talla a partir del año al año. Usando libremente
software disponible del análisis de imagen, ImageJ, utilizadores 
cuantifica el área del agujero de ozono antártico cada octubre a 
partir de 1996 a 2004. Finalmente, traen sus medidas en un 
programa de hoja de balance y crean un gráfico para documentar 
cambios en la talla del agujero de ozono.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KRISTINA PICCIRILLI
FN:KRISTINA PICCIRILLI
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LUANN DAHLMAN
FN:LUANN DAHLMAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201360</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102991</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-analyzing-the-antarctic-ozone-hole</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
