<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107382</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107382</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087321</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Mormon Woman's Life in Southern Utah</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leben einer mormonischen Frau in Südutah</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vie d'une femme mormone en Utah méridional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vida de uma mulher mormon em Utá do sul</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vita della donna mormonica nell'Utah del sud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ζωή μιας των Μορμόνων γυναίκας στο νότιο Utah</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vida de una mujer mormónica en Utah meridional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Women who settled the West in the years after the Civil War often faced harsh and unremitting toil. Laboring from well before dawn until well after the sun had set, women helped plant and harvest crops, raised large families, and kept house with rudimentary equipment. Long periods of isolation from neighbors and kin were common; social occasions or visits by travelers and kin were rare and cherished events. Mary Ann Hafen immigrated from Switzerland to Utah with her Mormon family in 1860 at age six and her first husband died when she was barely twenty. In this account, she described her move from Utah to Nevada in 1891 with her second husband and their polygamous family, as well as their subsequent life there.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frauen, die den Westen in den Jahren vereinbarten,
nachdem der Bürgerkrieg häufig rauhe und unaufhörliche 
Mühe gegenüberstellte. Bearbeitung von gut vor 
Dämmerung bis gut, nachdem die Sonne eingestellt hatte, Frauen 
geholfene Betriebs- und Erntegetreide, angehobene große Familien und 
gehaltenes Haus mit rudimentärer Ausrüstung. Lange Perioden 
der Lokalisierung von den Nachbarn und von den Stämmen waren 
geläufig; Sozialgelegenheiten oder Besuche durch Reisende und 
Stämme waren seltene und geschätzte Fälle. Mary Ann Hafen 
wanderte von der Schweiz nach Utah mit ihrer mormonischen Familie 1860
an Alter sechs und ihrem ersten gestorbenen Ehemann ein, als sie kaum 
Zwanzig war. In diesem Konto beschrieb sie ihre Bewegung von 
Utah nach Nevada 1891 mit ihrem zweiten Ehemann und ihrer polygamous 
Familie, sowie ihre folgende Lebensdauer dort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les femmes qui ont arrangé l'ouest en années 
après la guerre civile ont souvent fait face au travail dur dur et 
ininterrompu. Travaillant de bien avant aube jusqu'à ce que 
bien après que le soleil ait placé, collectes d'usine aidées par 
femmes et de moisson, familles nombreuses élevées, et maison gardée
avec le matériel rudimentaire. Les longues périodes de 
l'isolement dans des voisins et des parents étaient communes ; 
les occasions ou les visites sociales par des voyageurs et des 
parents étaient des événements rares et aimés. Mary Ann 
Hafen a immigré de Suisse en Utah avec sa famille mormone en 1860 à 
l'âge six et son premier mari mort quand elle avait à peine vingt 
ans. Dans ce compte, elle a décrit son mouvement d'Utah au 
Nevada en 1891 avec son deuxième mari et leur famille polygame, 
aussi bien que leur vie ultérieure là.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As mulheres que estabeleciram o oeste nos anos 
após a guerra civil enfrentaram frequentemente a labuta áspera e 
unremitting. Trabalhando de bem antes do alvorecer até que bem 
depois que o sol se tinha ajustado, colheitas ajudadas mulheres da 
planta e da colheita, famílias grandes levantadas, e casa mantida com
equipamento rudimentary. Os períodos longos da isolação dos 
vizinhos e dos parentes eram comuns; as ocasiões ou as visitas 
sociais por viajantes e por parentes eram eventos raros e estimados. 
Mary Ann Hafen immigrated de Switzerland a Utá com sua família
mormon em 1860 na idade seis e seu primeiro marido morrido quando era 
mal vinte. Neste cliente, descreveu seu movimento de Utá a 
Nevada em 1891 com seu segundo marido e sua família polygamous, 
as.well.as sua vida subseqüente lá.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le donne che hanno depositato l'ovest durante gli 
anni dopo la guerra civile hanno affrontato spesso il lavoro duro ed 
assiduo. Lavorando da bene prima dell'alba fino a che bene dopo 
che il sole si regoli, i raccolti della raccolta e della pianta 
aiutati donne, grandi famiglie alzate e casa mantenuta con 
apparecchiatura rudimentale. I periodi lunghi di isolamento dai 
vicinoi e dalle parentele erano comuni; le occasioni o le 
chiamate sociali dai viaggiatori e dalle parentele erano eventi rari 
ed affezionati. Mary Ann Hafen immigrated dalla Svizzera 
nell'Utah con la sua famiglia mormonica in 1860 all'età sei ed il suo
primo marito morto quando era a mala pena venti. In questo 
cliente, ha descritto il suo movimento dall'Utah nel Nevada in 1891 
con il suo secondo marito e la loro famiglia polygamous, così come la
loro vita successiva là.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι γυναίκες που εγκατέστησαν τη δύση στα έτη μετά 
από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο αντιμετώπισαν συχνά το σκληρό και 
αδιάλειπτο κόπο. Εργαμένος από πολύ πριν από την αυγή 
μέχρι καλά αφότου είχε θέσει ο ήλιος, οι γυναίκες βοήθησαν να 
φυτεψουν και να συγκομίσουν τις συγκομιδές, μεγάλες οικογένειες, 
και κράτησαν το σπίτι με το στοιχειώδη εξοπλισμό. Οι 
μεγάλες περίοδοι απομόνωσης από τους γείτονες και το σόι ήταν 
κοινές  οι κοινωνικές περιπτώσεις ή οι επισκέψεις από τους
ταξιδιώτες και το σόι ήταν σπάνιες και ελάτρεψαν τα γεγονότα. 
Θ*Μαρυ Ann Hafen μετανάστευσε από την Ελβετία στο 
Utah με την των Μορμόνων οικογένειά της το 1860 στην ηλικία 
έξι και ο πρώτος σύζυγός της πέθανε όταν ήταν μόλις είκοσι. 
Σε αυτόν τον απολογισμό, περιέγραψε την κίνησή της από το 
Utah στη Νεβάδα το 1891 με το δεύτερο σύζυγό της και την 
πολύγαμο οικογένειά τους, καθώς επίσης και την επόμενη ζωή τους
εκεί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las mujeres que colocaron el oeste en los años 
después de la guerra civil hicieron frente a menudo a trabajo áspero
y continuo. Trabajando de bien antes de amanecer hasta que bien 
después de que el sol hubiera fijado, cosechas ayudadas mujeres de la
planta y de la cosecha, familias grandes levantadas, y casa guardada 
con el equipo rudimentario. Los períodos largos del aislamiento
de vecinos y de parentescos eran comunes; las ocasiones o las 
visitas sociales de las hojas de ruta (traveler) y de los parentescos 
eran acontecimientos raros y acariciados. Mary Ann Hafen 
immigrated de Suiza a Utah con su familia mormónica en 1860 en la 
edad seises y su primer marido muerto cuando ella era descubierto 
veinte. En esta cuenta, ella describió su movimiento de Utah a 
Nevada en 1891 con su segundo marido y su familia polygamous, así 
como su vida subsecuente allí.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087321</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107382</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-mormon-womans-life-in-southern-utah</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
