<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107846</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107846</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Cutting a New Path": A World War II Navy Nurse Fights Sexism in the Military</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", einen neuen Pfad schneiden": Eine 
Weltkrieg-Marine-Krankenschwester kämpft Sexism im Militär</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"coupant une nouvelle voie d'accès" : Une 
infirmière de marine de la deuxième guerre mondiale combat Sexism 
dans les militaires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"cortando um trajeto novo": Uma enfermeira 
da marinha da segunda guerra mundial luta Sexism nas forças armadas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tagliando un nuovo percorso": Un'infermiera
del blu marino della seconda guerra mondiale combatte Sexism nei 
militari</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κόβοντας ένα νέο μονοπάτι": Ένας παγκόσμιος 
πόλεμος ΙΙ πάλες Sexism νοσοκόμων ναυτικού στους στρατιωτικούς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cortando un camino nuevo": Una enfermera de
la Marina de guerra de la Segunda Guerra Mundial lucha Sexism en los 
militares</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In World War II soldiers, sailors, nurses, and airmen often found themselves thrown together with fellow Americans whose experiences and backgrounds were drastically different from their own. Racial segregation was an official policy of the War Department, but gender discrimination was a subtler, if no less troublesome, social constraint. Doris Brander, who enlisted shortly after Pearl Harbor in the navy's Womens Auxiliary Voluntary Expeditionary Service (WAVES), felt that she and her fellow WAVES were rebels, going against the tide of convention and pushing the limits on women's opportunity. In this 1992 interview with Rosetta Kamlowsky, Brander described how she and other women fought the sexism they experienced in the military and strove for gender equality.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Weltkriegsoldaten fanden sich Seeleute, 
Krankenschwestern und Flieger häufig geworfen zusammen mit 
Gefährteamerikanern deren Erfahrungen und Hintergründe zu ihren 
Selbst drastisch unterschiedlich waren. Rassische Abtrennung war
eine amtliche Politik der Krieg-Abteilung, aber 
Geschlechtunterscheidung war, wenn keine weniger unangenehme, 
Sozialbegrenzung ein subtileres. Doris Brander, das kurz nach 
Pearl Harbor Womens der Marine im zusätzlichen freiwilligen 
Expeditionary Service (WELLEN), im Filz eintrug, die sie und ihre 
Gefährte-WELLEN Aufrührer waren, gegen die Gezeiten der 
Versammlung ging und die Begrenzungen auf Gelegenheit der Frauen 
drückt. In diesem Interview 1992 mit Rosetta Kamlowsky, 
beschrieb Brander, wie sie und andere Frauen das sexism kämpften, das
sie im Militär erfuhren und bemühte sich um Geschlechtgleichheit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans des soldats de la deuxième guerre mondiale, 
les marins, les infirmières, et les aviateurs se sont souvent 
trouvés jetés ainsi que les Américains de camarade dont des 
expériences et les milieux étaient rigoureusement différents de 
leurs propres. La ségrégation raciale était une politique 
officielle du service de guerre, mais la discrimination de genre 
était une plus subtile, si aucune contrainte moins ennuyeuse et 
sociale. Doris Brander, qui a enrôlé peu de temps après le 
port de perle en service Expéditionnaire volontaire auxiliaire de Womens 
de la marine (VAGUES), feutre qu'elle et ses VAGUES de camarade 
étaient des rebelles, allant à lencontre la marée de la convention 
et poussant les limites sur l'occasion des femmes. Dans cette 
entrevue 1992 avec Rosetta Kamlowsky, Brander décrit comment elle et 
d'autres femmes ont combattu le sexism qu'elles ont éprouvé dans les
militaires et ont essayé d'obtenir l'égalité de genre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em soldados da segunda guerra mundial, os sailors,
as enfermeiras, e os aviadores encontraram-se frequentemente jogados 
junto com os americanos do companheiro cujos experiências e os fundos
eram dràstica diferentes do seus próprios. O segregation 
racial era uma política oficial do departamento de guerra, mas a 
discriminação do gender era uma mais subtler, se nenhum confinamente
mais menos incômodo, social. Doris Brander, que se alistou logo
depois que porto de pérola no serviço expeditionary voluntário 
auxiliar de Womens da marinha (ONDAS), o feltro que e seu companheiro 
ACENAM era rebels, indo de encontro à maré da convenção e 
empurrando os limites na oportunidade das mulheres. Nesta 
entrevista 1992 com Rosetta Kamlowsky, Brander descreveu como e outras
mulheres lutaram o sexism que experimentou nas forças armadas e 
strove para a igualdade do gender.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nei soldati della seconda guerra mondiale, i 
marinai, le infermiere e gli aviatori spesso si sono trovati gettati 
insieme agli Americani del collega di cui esperienze e gli ambiti di 
provenienza erano drasticamente differenti dai loro propri. La 
segregazione razziale era una politica ufficiale del reparto di 
guerra, ma la distinzione di genere era un più sottile, se nessun 
vincolo meno noioso e sociale. Doris Brander, che ha arruolato 
subito dopo il porto di perla in servizio expeditionary volontario 
ausiliario di Womens del blu marino (ONDE), feltro che lei e le sue 
ONDE del collega erano ribelli, andante contro la marea della 
convenzione e spingente i limiti sull'occasione delle donne. In 
questa intervista 1992 con Rosetta Kamlowsky, Brander ha descritto 
come lei ed altre donne hanno combattuto il sexism che hanno 
sperimentato nei militari ed ha tentato d'ottenere uguaglianza di 
genere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ οι στρατιώτες, οι ναυτικοί, 
οι νοσοκόμες, και οι αεροπόροι βρέθηκαν συχνά ριγμένου μαζί με 
συντροφικούς Αμερικανούς η των οποίων εμπειρία και τα υπόβαθρα 
ήταν δραστικά διαφορετικά από δικοί τους. Ο φυλετικός 
διαχωρισμός ήταν μια επίσημη πολιτική του πολεμικού τμήματος, 
αλλά η διάκριση γένους ήταν μια λεπτότερη, εάν όχι λιγότερο 
από τον ενοχλητικό, κοινωνικό περιορισμό. Το Doris 
Brander, που στρατολόγησε αμέσως μετά από το λιμάνι 
μαργαριταριών στη βοηθητική εθελοντική εξερευνητική υπηρεσία 
Womens του ναυτικού (ΚΥΜΑΤΑ), θεώρησε ότι αυτή και τα 
συντροφικά ΚΥΜΑΤΑ της ήταν επαναστάτες, που πηγαίνουν ενάντια 
στην παλίρροια της σύμβασης και που ωθούν τα όρια στην ευκαιρία 
των γυναικών. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη του 1992 με 
Rosetta Kamlowsky, Brander περιέγραψε πώς αυτή και άλλες 
γυναίκες πάλεψαν το sexism που δοκίμασαν στο στρατιωτικό και 
προσπάθησαν για την ισότητα γένους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En soldados de la Segunda Guerra Mundial, los 
marineros, las enfermeras, y los aviadores a menudo se encontraron 
lanzados junto con los americanos del compañero que experiencias y 
fondos eran drástico diferentes sus los propios. La 
segregación racial era una política oficial del departamento de 
guerra, pero la discriminación del género era una más sutil, si 
ningún constreñimiento menos molesto, social. Doris Brander, 
que alistó poco después puerto de perla en el servicio 
expedicionario voluntario auxiliar de Womens de la marina de guerra (ONDAS),
el fieltro que ella y sus ONDAS del compañero eran rebeldes, yendo 
contra la marea de la convención y empujando los límites en la 
oportunidad de las mujeres. En esta entrevista 1992 con Rosetta 
Kamlowsky, Brander describió cómo ella y otras mujeres lucharon el 
sexism que ella experimentó en los militares y se esforzó para la 
igualdad del género.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107846</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cutting-a-new-path-a-world-war-ii-navy-nurse-fights-sexism-in-the-military</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
