<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102895</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102895</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206677</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An American Success Story: The Pope House of Raleigh, NC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Amerikanische Erfolg-Geschichte: Der 
Papst House von Raleigh, NC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Histoire Américaine de Succès : Le 
pape House de Raleigh, OR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma História Americana Do Sucesso: O papa 
Casa de Raleigh, NC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una Storia Americana Di Successo: Il papa 
House di Raleigh, NC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια αμερικανική επιτυχημένη περίπτωση: Το σπίτι 
παπάδων Raleigh, NC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Historia Americana Del Éxito: El papa 
House de Raleigh, NC</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of Manassa Pope, the first black man to receive a medical license in North Carolina (1886). After practicing medicine and helping establish a drug store and insurance company in Charlotte, Pope moved his family to Raleigh. There he continued his medical practice, built an elegant house (equipped with the latest technologies) located in the best place allowed for a black family in a segregated city. He later ran for mayor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte des Manassa Papstes, den 
ersten Schwarzmann, um eine medizinische Lizenz in Nord-Carolina 
(1886) zu empfangen. Nachdem übende Medizin und das Helfen 
einen Drogespeicher und eine Versicherungsgesellschaft in Charlotte 
herstellen, verschob Papst seine Familie auf Raleigh. Dort 
setzte er seine medizinische Praxis fort, aufgebaut einem eleganten 
Haus (ausgerüstet mit den neuesten Technologien) gelegen im besten 
Platz, der eine schwarze Familie in einer getrennten Stadt zugelassen 
wurde. Er lief später für Bürgermeister.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire du pape de Manassa, le premier 
homme de noir pour recevoir un permis médical en Caroline du nord
(1886). Après que la médecine de pratique et aider 
établissent une mémoire de drogue et une compagnie d'assurance à 
Charlotte, le pape a déplacé sa famille à Raleigh. Là il a 
continué sa pratique médicale, établie une maison élégante 
(équipée des dernières technologies) située dans le meilleur 
endroit permis pour une famille noire dans une ville isolée. Il
plus tard a exécuté pour le maire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história do papa de Manassa, primeiro homem
do preto para receber uma licença médica em North.carolina (1886). 
Depois que a medicina praticando e a ajuda estabelecem uma loja 
da droga e uma companhia de seguro em Charlotte, o papa moveu sua 
família para Raleigh. Lá continuou sua prática médica, 
construída uma casa elegante (equipada com as tecnologias as mais 
atrasadas) situada no mais melhor lugar permitido uma família preta 
em uma cidade segregada. Funcionou mais tarde para o mayor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia del papa di Manassa, il primo 
uomo di nero per ricevere un'autorizzazione medica in North.carolina 
(1886). Dopo che la medicina esercitantesi ed aiutare 
istituiscano un deposito della droga e una società di assicurazioni a
Charlotte, il papa ha spostato la sua famiglia verso Raleigh. 
Là ha continuato la sua pratica medica, sviluppata una casa 
elegante (dotata di ultime tecnologie) situata nel posto migliore 
permesso una famiglia nera in una città segregata. Più 
successivamente ha funzionato per il sindaco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει στην ιστορία Manassa του παπά, το πρώτο μαύρο
άτομο για να λάβει μια ιατρική άδεια στη βόρεια Καρολίνα 
(1886). Μετά από την ιατρική άσκησης και βοήθεια να 
ιδρυθεί ένα φαρμακείο και μια ασφαλιστική εταιρεία στο Σαρλόττα,
ο παπάς κίνησε την οικογένειά του προς Raleigh. Εκεί 
συνέχισε την ιατρική πρακτική του, έχτισε ένα κομψό σπίτι (που 
εξοπλίζεται με τις πιό πρόσφατες τεχνολογίες) που βρέθηκε στην 
καλύτερη θέση που είχε την άδεια μια οικογένεια μαύρων σε μια 
διαχωρισμένη πόλη. Έτρεξε αργότερα για το δήμαρχο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia del papa de Manassa, el primer 
hombre del negro para recibir una licencia médica en Carolina del 
Norte (1886). Después de que la medicina practicante y el 
ayudar establezcan a un almacén de la droga y a compañía de seguros
en Charlotte, el papa movió a su familia a Raleigh. Allí él 
continuó su práctica médica, construida una casa elegante (equipada
de las tecnologías más últimas) situada en el mejor lugar permitido
para una familia negra en una ciudad segregada. Él se ejecutó 
más adelante para el alcalde.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206677</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102895</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/an-american-success-story-the-pope-house-of-raleigh-nc</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
