<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104891</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104891</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087066</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The United States and the Mexican Revolution: "A Danger for All Latin American Countries," Letters from Venustiano Carranza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Vereinigten Staaten und die mexikanische 
Umdrehung: "eine Gefahr für alle lateinamerikanischen Länder,"
Zeichen von Venustiano Carranza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Etats-Unis et la révolution mexicaine : 
"un danger pour tous les pays latino-américains," lettres de 
Venustiano Carranza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estados unidos e a volta mexicana: "um 
perigo para todos os países americanos latin," letras de Venustiano 
Carranza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unito Dichiara e la rivoluzione messicana: 
"un pericolo per tutti i paesi dell'America latina," lettere da 
Venustiano Carranza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες και η μεξικάνικη επανάσταση: 
"Ένας κίνδυνος για όλες τις λατινοαμερικανικές χώρες," 
επιστολές από Venustiano carranza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Estados Unidos y la revolución mexicana: 
"un peligro para todos los países americanos latinos," cartas 
de Venustiano Carranza</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1911, Mexicans overthrew a long-standing dictator and brought Francisco I. Madero to power. Two years later, a new repressive dictator, General Victoriano Huerta, deposed and murdered Madero. The Constitutionalists, led in part by liberal reformer VenustianoCarranza, undertook an armed revolt against Huerta's rule. When President Woodrow Wilson took office in 1913, he refused to recognize Huerta's counterrevolutionary government. Moreover, using the slim pretext of a minor insult to the U.S. Navy, Wilson sent troops into Vera Cruz, Mexico, in April 1914. Wilson's strategy--to force Huerta out and gain the support of Venustiano Carranza--backfired, however, and anti-U.S. sentiment erupted throughout Mexico. Carranza wrote the following letters, printed in major Mexican newspapers, to the presidents of Argentina, Brazil, and Chile congratulating them for their solidarity with Mexico and warning of the dangers of U.S. intervention. (An English translation follows the original letters in Spanish.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1911 besiegte Mexikaner einen althergebrachten 
Diktator und holte Francisco I. Madero zur Energie. Zwei Jahre 
später, setzte ein neuer repressiver Diktator, General Victoriano 
Huerta, ab und ermordete Madero. Das Constitutionalists, 
geführt im Teil vom liberalen Reformer VenustianoCarranza, nahm
sich einen bewaffneten Aufruhr gegen Richtlinie Huertas auf. Als
Präsident Woodrow Wilson Amt 1913 übernahm, lehnte er ab, Huertas 
konterrevolutionäre Regierung zu erkennen. Außerdem mit dem 
dünnen Vorwand einer geringen Beleidigung zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Marine, sendete Wilson Truppen in Vera Cruz, Mexiko, im April 1914. 
Strategie Wilsons -- zur Kraft Huerta heraus und gewinnen Sie 
den Support von Venustiano Carranza -- zurückgeknallt, jedoch und 
anti-U.S. Gefühl ausgebrochen in Mexiko. Carranza schrieb den 
Präsidenten von Argentinien, von Brasilien, und von Chile die 
folgenden Briefe, gedruckt in den mexikanischen 
hauptsächlichzeitungen, sie beglückwünschend für ihre solidarität
mit Mexiko und WARNING der Gefahren der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Intervention. (eine englische Übersetzung folgt den 
ursprünglichen Zeichen auf spanisch.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1911, le Mexicain a renversé un dictateur de 
longue date et a apporté Francisco I. Madero à la puissance. 
Deux ans après, un nouveau dictateur répressif, le Général 
Victoriano Huerta, a déposé et a assassiné Madero. Le 
Constitutionalists, mené en partie par le réformateur libéral 
VenustianoCarranza, a entrepris une révolte armée contre la règle 
de Huerta. Quand le Président Woodrow Wilson a pris le bureau 
en 1913, il a refusé d'identifier le gouvernement 
contre-révolutionnaire de Huerta. D'ailleurs, en utilisant le 
prétexte mince d'une insulte mineure à la marine des ETATS-UNIS, 
Wilson a envoyé des troupes dans Vera Cruz, Mexique, en avril 1914. 
La stratégie de Wilson -- à la force Huerta dehors et recevez 
le support de Venustiano Carranza -- pétardée, cependant, et le 
sentiment d'anti-U.S. éclaté dans l'ensemble du Mexique. 
Carranza a écrit les lettres suivantes, imprimées en journaux 
mexicains principaux, aux présidents de l'Argentine, du Brésil, et 
du Chili les félicitant pour leur solidarité avec le Mexique et 
avertissement des dangers de l'intervention des ETATS-UNIS. (une 
traduction en anglais suit les lettres initiales dans l'Espagnol.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1911, o mexicano overthrew um ditador 
long-standing e trouxe Francisco I. Madero à potência. Dois 
anos mais tarde, um ditador repressive novo, general Victoriano 
Huerta, deposed e assassinou Madero. O Constitutionalists, 
conduzido na parte pelo reformer liberal VenustianoCarranza, 
empreendeu uma revolta armada de encontro à régua de Huerta. 
Quando o presidente Woodrow Wilson fêz exame do escritório em 
1913, recusou reconhecer o governo counterrevolutionary de Huerta. 
Além disso, usando o pretext slim de um insulto menor à 
marinha de ESTADOS UNIDOS, Wilson emitiu tropas em Vera Cruz, México,
em abril 1914. Estratégia de Wilson -- à força Huerta para 
fora e ganhe a sustentação de Venustiano Carranza -- dada 
contra-explosão, entretanto, e sentiment de anti-U.S. erupted durante
todo México. Carranza escreveu as seguintes letras, impressas 
em jornais mexicanos principais, aos presidentes de Argentina, de 
Brasil, e de Chile felicitando os para seu solidarity com México e 
aviso dos perigos da intervenção de ESTADOS UNIDOS. (uma 
tradução inglesa segue as letras originais no espanhol.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1911, il mexicans overthrew un dictator di 
vecchia data ed ha portato Francisco I. Madero ad potenza. Due 
anni più successivamente, un nuovo dictator repressivo, il General 
Victoriano Huerta, deposed ed assassinato Madero. Il 
Constitutionalists, condotto in parte da reformer liberale 
VenustianoCarranza, ha intrapreso una sommossa munita contro la regola
del Huerta. Quando il presidente Woodrow Wilson ha preso 
l'ufficio in 1913, ha rifiutato di riconoscere il governo 
counterrevolutionary del Huerta. Inoltre, usando il pretesto 
sottile di un insulto secondario al blu marino degli STATI UNITI, 
Wilson ha trasmesso le truppe in Vera Cruz, Messico, nel mese di 
aprile del 1914. Strategia del Wilson -- a forza Huerta fuori e 
guadagni il supporto di Venustiano Carranza -- fallita, tuttavia e 
sentimento di anti-U.S. scoppiato durante il Messico. 
Carranza ha scritto le seguenti lettere, stampate in giornali 
messicani importanti, ai presidenti dell'Argentina, del Brasile e del
Cile congratulanteseli per la loro solidarietà con il Messico e 
l'avvertimento dei pericoli di intervento degli STATI UNITI. 
(una traduzione in inglese segue le lettere originali nello 
Spagnolo.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1911, μεξικανοί νίκησαν έναν από μακρού 
υφιστάμενο δικτάτορα και έφεραν Francisco Ι. Madero στη 
δύναμη. Δύο έτη αργότερα, ένας νέος κατασταλτικός 
δικτάτορας, στρατηγός Victoriano Huerta, καθαίρεσε και 
δολοφόνησε Madero. Το Constitutionalists, που οδηγήθηκε 
εν μέρει από το φιλελεύθερο μεταρρυθμιστή VenustianoCarranza, 
ανέλαβε μια οπλισμένη επανάσταση ενάντια huerta στον κανόνα. 
Όταν ο Πρόεδρος Woodrow Wilson πήρε το γραφείο το 
1913, αρνήθηκε να αναγνωρίσει huerta την 
counterrevolutionary κυβέρνηση. Επιπλέον, χρησιμοποιώντας 
τη λεπτή πρόφαση μιας δευτερεύουσας προσβολής στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
ναυτικό, Wilson έστειλε τα στρατεύματα στη Βέρα Cruz, 
Μεξικό, που τις 1914, Απριλίου στρατηγική Wilson -- στη 
δύναμη huerta έξω και κερδίστε την υποστήριξη Venustiano 
carranza -- απέτυχαν, εντούτοις, και το συναίσθημα αντι-ΗΠΑ 
εξερράγη σε όλο το Μεξικό. Carranza έγραψε τις 
ακόλουθες επιστολές, που τυπώθηκαν σε σημαντικές μεξικάνικες 
εφημερίδες, στους Προέδρους της Αργεντινής, της Βραζιλίας, και της
Χιλής που συγχαίρει τους για την αλληλεγγύη τους με το Μεξικό και 
που προειδοποιεί για τους κινδύνους της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ επέμβασης. 
(Μια αγγλική μετάφραση ακολουθεί τις αρχικές επιστολές στα 
ισπανικά.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1911, el mexicano derrocó a dictador de muchos
años y trajo Francisco I. Madero a la potencia. Dos años más 
tarde, un nuevo dictador represivo, general Madero de Huerta de 
Victoriano, haber depuesto y asesinado. El 
Constitutionalists, conducido en parte por el reformador liberal 
VenustianoCarranza, emprendió una rebelión armada contra la regla de
Huerta. Cuando presidente Woodrow Wilson tomó la oficina en 
1913, él rechazó reconocer el gobierno contrarrevolucionario de 
Huerta. Por otra parte, usando el pretexto delgado de un insulto
de menor importancia a la Marina de guerra de ESTADOS UNIDOS, Wilson envió 
a tropas en Vera Cruz, México, en abril de 1914. Estrategia de 
Wilson -- a la fuerza Huerta hacia fuera y gane la ayuda de Venustiano
Carranza -- petardeada, sin embargo, y sentimiento de anti-U.S. 
entrado en erupción a través de México. Carranza escribió 
las letras siguientes, impresas en periódicos mexicanos importantes, 
a los presidentes de la Argentina, del Brasil, y de Chile 
felicitándolos para su solidaridad con México y la alerta de los 
peligros de la intervención de ESTADOS UNIDOS. (una traducción
inglesa sigue las cartas originales en español.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087066</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104891</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-united-states-and-the-mexican-revolution-a-danger-for-all-latin-american-countries-letters-from-venustiano-carranza</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
