<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104808</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104808</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086470</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Men Without Women":  Look  Magazine' Offers a Guide to the Unmarried Man</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Männer Ohne Frauen": Schauen Sie 
Zeitschrift ' Angebote eine Anleitung zum unverheiratet Mann</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Hommes Sans Femmes" : Offres regardez 
magasin des 'un guide de l'homme célibataire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Homens Sem Mulheres": Olhe ofertas do 
compartimento ' uma guia ao homem solteiro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Uomini Senza Donne": Osservi offerte dello 
scomparto 'una guida all'uomo celibe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ανδρες χωρίς γυναίκεσ": Φανείτε περιοδικό 
"προσφέρει έναν οδηγό στο ανύπανδρο άτομο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Hombres Sin Las Mujeres": Mire ofertas del 
compartimiento las ' una guía al hombre soltero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the Cold War period of the 1950s and early 1960s, an era in which married life was often idealized as essential for personal happiness and success, non-conformance became a social problem in need of study and explanation. Experts in social science fields of psychology and sociology, and commentators in the popular press conducted research and published findings that sought to account for the relatively large numbers of men and women who remained unmarried despite societal pressures to wed. In this sequel to an earlier article on unmarried women,  Look  magazine writer Eleanor Harris, in response to suggestions of readers, addressed the topic of bachelorhood by presenting testimonies of selected men on the reasons they remained unmarried and conclusions of authorities regarding these explanations. The divergent ways that the two articles presented their subjects revealed some gender biases of the period. Unmarried women were depicted as "depressed" or "frantic," while single men were typed as "fixated on a mother figure," inclined to "antiresponsibility," or "latent homosexuals." Men often failed to find the "perfect" woman; women frequently could not find even an "eligible" man. Ultimately, the articles portrayed the unwed female's predicament far more portentously than the male's: women were "likely to get stranded" if they waited too long to get married, but it was "never too late" for men.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Periode des kalten Krieges der fünfziger 
Jahre und der frühen sechziger Jahre, in denen eine Ära verband, 
wurde das Leben häufig idealisiert, wie für persönliches Glück und
Erfolg, Nichtübereinstimmung ein Sozialproblem mangels der Studie und
der Erklärung wesentlich wurde. Experten in der 
Sozialwissenschaft fängt von der Psychologie und von der 
Soziologie auf, und Kommentatoren in der populären geleiteten Presse 
erforschen und veröffentlichten Entdeckungen, die suchten, die 
verhältnismäßig vielen Männer zu erklären und Frauen, denen trotz
des gesellschaftlichen Drucks unverheiratet blieb zu, wed. In 
dieser Folge zu einem früheren Artikel auf unverheiratet Frauen, 
schauen Sie Zeitschrift Verfasser Eleanor Harris, in Erwiderung auf 
Vorschläge der Leser, adressierte das Thema von Bachelorhood, indem 
Sie Zeugnisse der ausgewählten Männer auf den Gründen darstellen, 
die sie unverheiratet und Zusammenfassungen der Behörden betreffend 
sind diese Erklärungen blieben. Die unterschiedlichen Methoden,
daß die zwei Artikel ihre Themen darstellten, deckten etwas 
Geschlechtvorspannungen der Periode auf. Unverheiratet Frauen 
wurden bildlich dargestellt, wie "niedergedrückt" oder "wild,", 
während einzelne Männer geschrieben wurden, wie "fixiert auf einer 
Mutterabbildung," geneigtes "antiresponsibility," oder "latente 
Homosexuals." Männer konnten häufig finden nicht, Frau "zu 
vervollkommnen"; Frauen konnten nicht sogar einen "geeigneten" 
Mann häufig finden. Schließlich schilderten die Artikel unwed 
Zwangslage der Frau weit portentously als des Mannes: Frauen 
sollten "wahrscheinlich angeschwemmt erhalten", wenn sie zu lang 
warteten, um zu heiraten, aber sie war für Männer "nie zu spät".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans la période de guerre froide des années 50 
et du début des années soixante, une ère lesoù s'est mariée la 
vie a été souvent idéalisée comme essentiel pour le bonheur et le 
succès personnels, nonconformité est devenu un problème social 
nécessitant l'étude et l'explication. Les experts dans les 
domaines sociaux de la science de la psychologie et de la sociologie, 
et les commentateurs dans la presse populaire conduite recherchent et 
ont édité les résultats qui ont recherché à expliquer 
relativement un grand nombre d'hommes et les femmes à qui est resté 
célibataire en dépit des pressions sociales wed. Dans cette 
suite à un article plus tôt sur les femmes célibataires, regardez 
l'auteur Eleanor Harris de magasin, en réponse aux suggestions des 
lecteurs, a adressé le sujet du célibat en présentant des 
témoignages des hommes choisis sur les raisons qu'ils sont demeurées
célibataires et des conclusions des autorités concernant ces 
explications. Les voies divergentes que les deux articles ont 
présenté leurs sujets ont indiqué quelques polarisations de genre 
de la période. Des femmes célibataires ont été dépeintes 
comme "enfoncé" ou "effréné," tandis que des hommes simples 
étaient tapés comme "fixé sur un chiffre de mère," 
"antiresponsibility incliné," ou "les homosexuels latents." Les
hommes souvent n'ont pas trouvé "pour perfectionner" la femme ; 
les femmes fréquemment ne pourraient pas trouver même un homme
"éligible". Finalement, les articles ont dépeint unwed la 
situation fâcheuse de la femelle bien plus portentously que le mâle 
: les femmes devaient "probablement obtenir échouées" si elles
attendaient trop long pour se marier , mais il n'était "jamais trop 
tard" pour les hommes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No período da guerra fria dos 1950s e dos 1960s 
adiantados, uma era em que se casou a vida idealized frequentemente 
como essencial para a felicidade e o sucesso pessoais, non-conformance
se tornou um problema social na necessidade do estudo e da 
explanação. Os peritos em campos sociais da ciência do 
psychology e do sociology, e os comentadores na imprensa popular 
conduzida pesquisam e publicaram os findings que procuraram esclarecer
relativamente um grande número homens e as mulheres a que remanesceu 
solteiro apesar das pressões societal wed. Neste sequel a um 
artigo mais adiantado em mulheres solteiras, olhe o escritor Eleanor 
Harris do compartimento, em resposta às sugestões dos leitores, 
dirigiu-se ao tópico do bachelorhood apresentando testimonies de 
homens selecionados nas razões que remanesceram solteiros e 
conclusões das autoridades a respeito destas explanações. As 
maneiras divergent que os dois artigos apresentaram seus assuntos 
revelaram algumas polarizações do gender do período. As 
mulheres solteiras foram descritas como "comprimido" ou "frantic," 
quando os únicos homens foram datilografados como "fixated em uma 
figura da matriz," "antiresponsibility inclined," ou "os homosexuals 
latentes." Os homens frequentemente não encontraram "para 
aperfeiçoar" a mulher; as mulheres freqüentemente não 
poderiam encontrar mesmo um homem "elegível". Finalmente, os 
artigos portrayed unwed o predicament da fêmea distante mais 
portentously do que o macho: as mulheres deviam "provavelmente 
começar encalhadas" se esperassem demasiado longo para começar 
casadas, mas estava "nunca demasiado atrasado" para homens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel periodo di guerra fredda degli anni 50 e 
dell'inizio degli anni 60, un'era in où si è sposata la vita è 
stata idealizzata spesso come essenziale per felicità e successo 
personali, non-conformance è diventato un problema sociale 
necessitante lo studio e la spiegazione. Gli esperti nelle 
materie sociali di scienza della psicologia e della sociologia ed i 
commentatori nella pressa popolare condotta ricercano e pubblicato i 
risultati che hanno cercato di rappresentare i relativamente 
tantissimi uomini e le donne a che è rimasto celibe malgrado le 
pressioni sociali wed. In questo seguito ad un articolo più in 
anticipo sulle donne celibi, osservi il produttore Eleanor Harris 
dello scomparto, in risposta ai suggerimenti dei lettori, ha 
richiamato il soggetto di bachelorhood presentando le testimonianze 
degli uomini selezionati sui motivi che sono rimasto celibi e 
conclusioni delle autorità per quanto riguarda queste spiegazioni. 
I modi divergenti che i due articoli hanno presentato i loro 
oggetti hanno rivelato alcune polarizzazioni di genere del periodo. 
Le donne celibi sono state descritte come "depresso" o 
"frantic," mentre i singoli uomini sono stati digitati come "fissato 
su una figura della madre," "antiresponsibility propenso," o "gli 
omosessuali latenti." Gli uomini non sono riuscito spesso a 
trovare "per perfezionare" la donna; le donne non potrebbero 
trovare frequentemente neppure un uomo "eleggibile". Infine, gli
articoli hanno ritratto unwed il predicament della femmina molto più 
portentously del maschio: le donne dovevano "probabilmente 
ottenere incagliate" se attendessero troppo lungo per ottenere 
sposate, ma era "mai troppo tardi" per gli uomini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην περίοδο ψυχρού πολέμου της δεκαετίας του '50 και 
της πρόωρης δεκαετίας του '60, μια εποχή στην οποία η παντρεμένη 
ζωή ήταν συχνά εξιδανικευμένη όπως ουσιαστική για την 
προσωπικές ευτυχία και την επιτυχία, η μη-προσαρμογή έγινε ένα 
κοινωνικό πρόβλημα που έχει ανάγκη από μελέτη και εξήγηση. 
Οι εμπειρογνώμονες στα πεδία κοινωνικών επιστημών της 
ψυχολογίας και της κοινωνιολογίας, και οι σχολιαστές στο δημοφιλή 
Τύπο πραγματοποίησαν την έρευνα και δημοσίευσαν τα συμπεράσματα 
που επιδίωξαν να αποτελέσουν τους σχετικά μεγάλους αριθμούς 
ανδρών και γυναικών που παρέμειναν ανύπανδροι παρά τις 
κοινωνικές πιέσεις στο wed. Σε αυτήν την συνέπεια σε ένα
προηγούμενο άρθρο σχετικά με τις ανύπανδρες γυναίκες, φανείτε 
συγγραφέας Eleanor Harris περιοδικών, σε απάντηση στις 
προτάσεις των αναγνωστών, εξέτασε το θέμα της εργένικης ζωής με 
την παρουσίαση των καταθέσεων των επιλεγμένων ανδρών στους λόγους
που παρέμειναν ανύπανδροι και συμπεράσματα των αρχών σχετικά με 
αυτές τις εξηγήσεις. Οι διάφοροι τρόποι ότι τα δύο άρθρα 
παρουσίασαν τα θέματά τους αποκάλυψαν μερικές πολώσεις γένους 
της περιόδου. Οι ανύπανδρες γυναίκες απεικονίστηκαν όπως 
"καταθλιπτικόσ" ή "μανιώδης," ενώ οι ενιαίοι άνδρες 
δακτυλογραφήθηκαν όπως "σταθεροποιούν σε έναν αριθμό μητέρων," 
κλιμένος "στο antiresponsibility," ή τους "λανθάνοντες 
ομοφυλοφίλους." Οι άνδρες απέτυχαν συχνά να βρούν τη 
"τέλεια" γυναίκα  οι γυναίκες δεν θα μπορούσαν συχνά να 
βρούν ούτε έναν "επιλέξιμο" άνδρα. Τελικά, τα άρθρα 
απεικόνισαν η δυσάρεστη κατάσταση του θηλυκού πολύ pjo' 
πορτεντοuσλυ από του αρσενικού: οι γυναίκες ήταν "πιθανό να
πάρουν προσαραγμένεσ" εάν περίμεναν πάρα πολύ πολύ να 
παντρευτούν, αλλά ήταν "ποτέ πάρα πολύ αργά" για τους άνδρες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el período de la guerra fría de los años 50 
y de los años 60 tempranos, una era en los cuales casó la vida fue 
idealizada a menudo como esencial para la felicidad y el éxito 
personales, inconformidad llegó a ser un problema social en la 
necesidad del estudio y de la explicación. Los expertos en 
campos sociales de la ciencia de la psicología y de la sociología, y
los comentaristas en la prensa popular dirigida investigan y 
publicaron los resultados que intentaron explicar a los relativamente 
una gran cantidad de los hombres y las mujeres a quienes seguía 
siendo soltero a pesar de presiones societal wed. En esta 
consecuencia a un artículo anterior sobre mujeres solteras, mire a 
programa de escritura Eleanor Harris del compartimiento, en respuesta 
a sugerencias de programas de lectura, trató el asunto de la 
soltería presentando testimonios de hombres seleccionados en las 
razones que seguían siendo solteros y conclusiones de autoridades con
respecto a estas explicaciones. Las maneras divergentes que los 
dos artículos presentaron sus temas revelaron algunos diagonales del 
género del período. Representaron a las mujeres solteras 
según lo "presionado" o "frenético," mientras que pulsaron los solos
hombres según lo "fijado en una figura de la madre," 
"antiresponsibility inclinado," o a los "homosexuales latentes." 
Los hombres no pudieron a menudo encontrar "para perfeccionar" a
mujer; las mujeres no podrían encontrar con frecuencia incluso 
a un hombre "elegible". En última instancia, los artículos 
retrataron unwed el lío de la hembra lejos ma's portentously que el 
varón: las mujeres debían "probablemente conseguir trenzadas" 
si esperaron demasiado largo para conseguir casadas, pero era "nunca 
demasiado atrasado" para los hombres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086470</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104808</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/men-without-women-look-magazine-offers-a-guide-to-the-unmarried-man</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
