<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104136</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104136</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087239</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">William Manning, "A Laborer," Explains Shays Rebellion in Massachusetts: "In as Plain a Manner as I Am Capable"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bemannender William, "ein Hilfsarbeiter," erklärt 
Shays Aufstand in Massachusetts: "in so deutlich einer Weise, 
wie ich fähig bin"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">William équipant, "un travailleur," explique la 
rébellion de Shays dans le Massachusetts : "aussi tout 
simplement d'une façon que je suis capable"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">William que equipa, "um laborer," explica a 
rebelião de Shays em Massachusetts: "tão claramente em uma 
maneira como eu sou capaz"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">William che equipaggia, "un laborer," spiega la 
Ribellione di Shays in Massachusetts: "semplicemente in un modo
come sono capace"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ωηλληαμ Manning, "ένα Laborer," εξηγεί την 
εξέγερση Shays στη Μασαχουσέτη: "Κατά τρόπο τόσο σαφή 
όσο είμαι ικανόσ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guillermo que sirve, "un laborer," explica la 
rebelión de Shays en Massachusetts: "tan claramente de una 
manera como soy capaz"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The end of the War of Independence in 1783 curtailed wartime loss of life and destruction of property. However, peace also brought economic distress through cycles of depression and glut. These cycles were exacerbated when Massachusetts authorities pursued strict policies on money and debt and British creditors called in their debts during the post-Revolutionary depression. When merchants turned to already pressured farmers and rural traders who had no cash to pay their debts or taxes, courts and jails filled with debtors. In protest, Daniel Shays, a former captain in the revolutionary militia, led an uprising in western and central Massachusetts to close the courts and prevent the seizure of property for unpaid debts. Massachusetts Governor Bowdoin sent a military force that scattered the rebels. In his 1799 treatise to his fellow working men and women, William Manning offered a history of Shay's Rebellion along with his prescription for avoiding such insurrections in the future by an organization of working people.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ende des Krieges von Unabhängigkeit in 1783 
beschränktem Kriegverlust des Lebens und in der Zerstörung der 
Eigenschaft. Jedoch Friedensauch geholte ökonomische 
Bedrängnis durch Schleifen des Tiefstands und der Sättigung. 
Diese Schleifen wurden verbittert, als Massachusetts Behörden 
strenge Politik auf Geld und Schuld und die britischen Gläubiger, die
in ihren Schulden während des Pfosten-Revolutionären Tiefstands 
benannt wurden ausübten. Als Kaufleute an bereits gedrueckte 
Landwirte und landwirtschaftliche Händler wendeten, die kein Bargeld 
hatten, zum ihrer Schulden oder Steuern zu zahlen, füllten Gerichte 
und Gefängnisse mit Schuldnern. Im Protest führte Daniel 
Shays, ein ehemaliger Kapitän in der revolutionären Miliz, einen 
Aufstieg in West- und zentralem Massachusetts, um die Gerichte zu 
schließen und die Ergreifung der Eigenschaft für unbezahlte Schulden
zu verhindern. Massachusetts Regler Bowdoin sendete eine 
militärische Kraft, die die Aufrührer zerstreute. In seiner 
Abhandlung 1799 zu seinen Mitfunktion Männern und Frauen, William bot
das Bemannen eine Geschichte von Aufstand Shays zusammen mit seiner 
Verordnung für solche Aufstände zukünftig vermeiden durch eine 
Organisation der Arbeitsleute an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La fin de la guerre de l'indépendance dans la 
perte de temps de guerre de la vie raccourcie par 1783 et la 
destruction de la propriété. Cependant, détresse économique 
également apportée de paix pendant des cycles de dépression et de 
surabondance. Ces cycles ont été aggravés quand les 
autorités du Massachusetts ont poursuivi des politiques strictes sur 
l'argent et la dette et des créanciers britanniques appelés dans 
leurs dettes pendant la dépression poteau-Révolutionnaire. 
Quand les négociants se sont tournés vers les fermiers déjà 
pressurisés et les commerçants ruraux qui n'ont eu aucun argent 
comptant pour payer leurs dettes ou impôts, les cours et les prisons 
ont rempli de débiteurs. Dans la protestation, Daniel Shays, un
ancien capitaine dans la milice révolutionnaire, a mené un 
soulèvement dans le Massachusetts occidental et central pour fermer 
les cours et pour empêcher la saisie de la propriété pour des 
dettes impayées. Le Gouverneur Bowdoin du Massachusetts a 
envoyé une force militaire qui a dispersé les rebelles. En son
traité 1799 à ses ouvriers et femmes de camarade, équiper de 
William a offert une histoire de la rébellion de Shay avec sa 
prescription pour éviter de telles insurrections à l'avenir par une 
organisation des personnes travaillantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O fim da guerra da independência na perda do 
wartime de vida curtailed 1783 e na destruição da propriedade. 
Entretanto, aflição econômica também trazida da paz através
dos ciclos do depression e do glut. Estes ciclos exacerbated 
quando as autoridades de Massachusetts perseguiram políticas estritas
no dinheiro e no débito e os credores britânicos chamados em seus 
débitos durante o depression borne-Revolucionário. Quando os 
comerciantes giraram para os fazendeiros já exercidos pressão sobre 
e os comerciantes rurais que não tiveram nenhum dinheiro para pagar 
seus débitos ou impostos, as cortes e as cadeias encheram-se com os 
devedores. No protesto, Daniel Shays, um capitão anterior na 
milícia revolucionária, conduziu a um uprising em Massachusetts 
ocidental e central para fechar as cortes e para impedir a apreensão 
da propriedade para débitos por pagar. O regulador Bowdoin de 
Massachusetts emitiu uma força militar que dispersasse os rebels. 
Em seu treatise 1799 a seus homens e mulheres de funcionamento 
do companheiro, equipar de William ofereceu um history da rebelião de
Shay junto com sua prescrição para evitar tais insurrections no 
futuro por uma organização de povos trabalhando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La conclusione della guerra di indipendenza negli 
incidenti mortali di wartime accorciati 1783 e nella distruzione della
proprietà. Tuttavia, afflizione economica anche portata di pace
durante i cicli della depressione e della sovrabbondanza. Questi
cicli sono stati esacerbati quando le autorità del Massachusetts 
hanno perseguito le politiche rigorose su soldi e sul debito ed i 
creditori britannici chiamati nei loro debiti durante la depressione 
alberino-Rivoluzionaria. Quando i commercianti si sono girati 
verso i coltivatori già pressured ed i commercianti rurali che non 
hanno avuti contanti per pagare i loro debiti o tasse, le corti e le 
prigioni si sono riempite di debitori. Nella protesta, Daniel 
Shays, un ex capitano nella milizia rivoluzionaria, ha condotto una 
rivolta in Massachusetts occidentale e centrale per chiudere le 
corti e per impedire il grippaggio della proprietà per i debiti non 
pagati. Il regolatore Bowdoin del Massachusetts ha trasmesso una
forza militare che ha sparso i ribelli. In suo trattato 1799
ai suoi uomini e donne di funzionamento del collega, equipaggiare del 
William ha offerto una storia della Ribellione dello Shay con la sua 
prescrizione per evitare tali insurrections in avvenire da 
un'organizzazione della gente lavorante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το τέλος της επανάστασης στην 1783 περιορισμένη εν 
καιρώ πολέμου απώλεια ζωής και την καταστροφή της ιδιοκτησίας. 
Εντούτοις, η ειρήνη έφερε επίσης τον οικονομικό κίνδυνο 
μέσω των κύκλων της κατάθλιψης και του πλεονάσματος. Αυτοί 
οι κύκλοι επιδεινώθηκαν όταν ακολούθησαν οι αρχές της 
Μασαχουσέτης τις ακριβείς πολιτικές για τα χρήματα και το χρέος 
και τους βρετανικούς πιστωτές που κλήθηκαν στα χρέη τους κατά τη 
διάρκεια της μετα-επαναστατικής κατάθλιψης. Όταν οι έμποροι
γύρισαν στους ήδη πιεσμένους αγρότες και τους αγροτικούς 
εμπόρους που δεν είχαν κανένα μετρητό για να πληρώσουν τα χρέη 
ή τους φόρους τους, τα δικαστήρια και τις φυλακές που γέμισαν με 
τους χρεώστες. Στη διαμαρτυρία, ο Ντάνιελ Shays, ένας 
προηγούμενος καπετάνιος στην επαναστατική πολιτοφυλακή, οδήγησε 
μια έγερση στη δυτική και κεντρική Μασαχουσέτη για να κλείσει τα 
δικαστήρια και να αποτρέψει τη σύλληψη της ιδιοκτησίας για τα 
απλήρωτα χρέη. Ο κυβερνήτης Bowdoin της Μασαχουσέτης 
έστειλε μια στρατιωτική δύναμη που διασκόρπισε τους επαναστάτες. 
Στην πραγματεία 1799 του στους συντροφικούς εργαζόμενους 
άνδρες και τις γυναίκες του, William Manning πρόσφερε μια 
ιστορία της εξέγερσης Shay μαζί με τη συνταγή του για να 
αποφύγει τέτοιες εξεγέρσεις στο μέλλον από μια οργάνωση των 
εργαζόμενων ανθρώπων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El final de la guerra de la independencia en la 
pérdida acortada 1783 del tiempo de guerra de vida y la destrucción 
de la característica. Sin embargo, señal de socorro económica
también traída de la paz durante ciclos de la depresión y de la 
superabundancia. Estos ciclos fueron exacerbados cuando las 
autoridades de Massachusetts persiguieron políticas terminantes en el
dinero y la deuda y los acreedores británicos llamados en sus deudas 
durante la depresión poste-Revolucionaria. Cuando los 
comerciantes dieron vuelta a los granjeros ya ejercidos presión sobre
y a los comerciantes rurales que no tenían ningún efectivo para 
pagar sus deudas o impuestos, las cortes y las cárceles llenaron de 
los deudores. En protesta, Daniel Shays, capitán anterior en la
milicia revolucionaria, condujo una sublevación en Massachusetts 
occidental y central para cerrar las cortes y para prevenir el 
asimiento de la característica para las deudas sin pagar. El 
gobernador Bowdoin de Massachusetts envió una fuerza militar que 
dispersó a rebeldes. En su tratado 1799 a sus hombres y mujeres
de funcionamiento del compañero, el servir de Guillermo ofreció una 
historia de la rebelión de Shay junto con su prescripción para 
evitar tales insurrecciones en el futuro por una organización de la 
gente de trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087239</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104136</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/william-manning-a-laborer-explains-shays-rebellion-in-massachusetts-in-as-plain-a-manner-as-i-am-capable</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
