<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105751</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105751</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213167</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Who Has the Light?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wer hat das Licht?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Qui a la lumière ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quem tem a luz?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Chi ha la luce?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποιος έχει το φως;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Quién tiene la luz?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This NOAA classroom activity explores bioluminescence. This PDF addresses: Which deep-sea organisms are capable of bioluminescence, and how does this ability benefit these organisms? In this activity, students will: compare and contrast chemiluminescence, bioluminescence, fluorescence, and phosphorescence, explain ways in which the ability to produce light may be useful to deep-sea organisms, and explain how scientists may be able to use light-producing processes in deep-sea organisms to observe these organisms in a new way. Several links to related online resources are provided.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese NOAA Klassenzimmeraktivität erforscht 
bioluminescence. Dieses pdf wendet: Welche 
Tiefseeorganismen sind zum bioluminescence und wie diese Fähigkeit 
fördert diese organismen fähig? In dieser Aktivität werden 
Kursteilnehmer: vergleichen Sie und kontrastieren Sie 
Chemolumineszenz, bioluminescence, Fluoreszenz und Phosphoreszenz, 
erklären Sie Methoden, in denen die Fähigkeit, Licht zu produzieren 
zu den Tiefseeorganismen nützlich sein kann, und erklären Sie, wie 
Wissenschaftler können können, das Licht-Produzieren von von 
Prozessen in den Tiefseeorganismen zu verwenden, um diese organismen 
in einer neuen Methode zu beobachten. Einige Links zu in 
Verbindung stehenden Onlinebetriebsmitteln werden zur Verfügung 
gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité de salle de classe de NOAA explore le 
bioluminescence. Ce pdf adresse : Quelles organizations 
hauturières sont capables du bioluminescence, et comment ces 
capacités bénéficie ces organizations ? Dans cette activité,
les étudiants  : comparez et contrastez la chemiluminescence, 
le bioluminescence, la fluorescence, et la phosphorescence, expliquez 
les voies dont la capacité de produire la lumière peut être utile 
aux organizations hauturières, et expliquez comment les scientifiques
peuvent pouvoir utiliser lumière-produire des processus dans les 
organizations hauturières pour observer ces organizations d'une 
nouvelle voie. Plusieurs liens aux ressources en ligne relatives
sont fournis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade da sala de aula de NOAA explora o 
bioluminescence. Este pdf dirige-se: Que organismos 
deep-sea são capazes do bioluminescence, e como esta abilidade 
beneficiam estes organismos? Nesta atividade, os estudantes : 
compare e contraste o chemiluminescence, o bioluminescence, o 
fluorescence, e o phosphorescence, explique as maneiras em que a 
abilidade de produzir a luz pode ser útil aos organismos deep-sea, e 
explique como os cientistas podem poder  usar luz-produzir processos 
em organismos deep-sea para observar estes organismos em uma maneira 
nova. Diversas ligações aos recursos em linha relacionados 
são fornecidas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività dell'aula di NOAA esplora il 
bioluminescence. Questo pdf richiama: Quali organismi di 
alto mare sono capaci del bioluminescence e come questa abilità 
avvantaggia questi organismi? In questa attività, gli allievi 
dovranno: confronti e contrapponga la chemiluminescenza, il 
bioluminescence, la fluorescenza e la fosforescenza, spieghi i modi in
cui la capacità di produrre la luce può essere utile agli organismi 
di alto mare e spieghi come gli scienziati possono potere usare 
luce-produrre i processi negli organismi di alto mare per osservare 
questi organismi in un nuovo modo. Parecchi collegamenti alle 
risorse in linea relative sono forniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα τάξεων NOAA ερευνά τη 
βιολογική ακτινοβολία. Αυτό το PDF εξετάζει: Ποιοι 
βαθύβιοι οργανισμοί είναι ικανοί της βιολογικής ακτινοβολίας, 
και πώς αυτή η δυνατότητα ωφελεί αυτούς τους οργανισμούς; 
Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές: θα 
συγκρίνει και να αντιπαραβάλει chemiluminescence, τη βιολογική 
ακτινοβολία, το φθορισμό, και phosphorescence, να εξηγήσει τους 
τρόπους στους οποίους η δυνατότητα να παραχθεί το φως μπορεί να 
είναι χρήσιμη στους βαθύβιους οργανισμούς, και να εξηγήσει πώς 
οι επιστήμονες μπορούν να είναι σε θέση να χρησιμοποιήσουν τις 
light-producing διαδικασίες στους βαθύβιους οργανισμούς για να 
παρατηρήσουν αυτούς τους οργανισμούς με έναν νέο τρόπο. 
Διάφορες συνδέσεις με τα σχετικά σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς παρέχονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad de la sala de clase de NOAA explora 
bioluminescence. Este pdf trata: ¿Qué organismos de alta 
mar son capaces de bioluminescence, y cómo esta capacidad beneficia 
estos organismos? En esta actividad, los estudiantes : 
compare y ponga en contraste la quimioluminescencia, el 
bioluminescence, la fluorescencia, y la fosforescencia, explique las 
maneras de las cuales la capacidad de producir la luz puede ser útil 
a los organismos de alta mar, y explique cómo los científicos pueden
poder utilizar luz-producir procesos en organismos de alta mar para 
observar estos organismos de una nueva manera. Varias conexiones
a los recursos en línea relacionados se proporcionan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MEL GOODWIN
FN:MEL GOODWIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NOAA OCEAN EXPLORER
FN:NOAA OCEAN EXPLORER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213167</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105751</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/who-has-the-light</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
