<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107050</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107050</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206217</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Molecular Logic Database</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Molekulare Logik-Datenbank</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Base de données Moléculaire de Logique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Base de dados Molecular Da Lógica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Base di dati Molecolare Di Logica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μοριακή βάση δεδομένων λογικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Base de datos Molecular De la Lógica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides 130 model-based activities for learning about interactions of atoms and molecules, and rule-based genetics. Topics include atomic-molecular structures and dynamics, states of matter, reactions, solutions, water and small molecules, bioenergetics, macromolecules, proteins, metabolism regulation, self assembly, and genetic code. Introductory activities serve as stepping stones to 10 physical-chemical principles that underlie many biological processes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt 130 Modell-gegründete Aktivitäten für das
Lernen über Interaktionen der Atome und der Moleküle und rule-based 
Genetik zur Verfügung. Themen schließen Atom-molekulare 
Strukturen und Dynamik, Zustände des Stoffes, Reaktionen, Lösungen, 
Wasser und kleine Moleküle, Bioenergetik, Makromoleküle, Proteine, 
Metabolismusregelung, Selbst- und genetischer Code ein. 
Einleitende Aktivitäten dienen als Tretensteine zu 10 
physikalisch-chemischen Grundregeln, die vielen biologischen Prozessen
zugrunde liegen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit 130 activités modèle-basées pour se 
renseigner sur des interactions des atomes et des molécules, et 
génétique basée sur les règles. Les sujets incluent les 
structures et la dynamique atomique-moléculaire, les états de 
matière, les réactions, les solutions, l'eau et les petites 
molécules, les bioénergétique, les macromolécules, les protéines,
le règlement de métabolisme, l'art de l'auto-portrait, et le code génétique. 
Les activités préliminaires servent de pierres d'progression 
à 10 principes physico-chimiques qui sont à la base de beaucoup de 
processus biologiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece 130 atividades modelo-baseadas aprendendo 
sobre interações dos átomos e das moléculas, e o genetics 
rule-based. Os tópicos incluem estruturas e dinâmica 
atômico-atomic-molecular, estados da matéria, reações, soluções,
água e moléculas pequenas, bioenergetics, macromolecules, 
proteínas, regulamento do metabolism, conjunto do self, e código 
genetic. As atividades introdutórias servem como pedras pisar a
10 princípios physical-chemical que underlie muitos processos 
biológicos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce 130 attività modello-basate per imparare 
circa le interazioni degli atomi e delle molecole e la genetica basata
sulla norma. I soggetti includono le strutture 
atomico-molecolari ed il dynamics, dichiara della materia, 
reazioni, soluzioni, acqua e piccole molecole, bioenergetiche, 
macromolecole, proteine, regolazione del metabolismo, complessivo di 
auto e codice genetico. Le attività introduttive servono da 
pietre fare un passo a 10 principii fisico-chimici che sono alla base 
di molti processi biologici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει 130 πρότυπος-βασισμένες δραστηριότητες για 
την εκμάθηση για τις αλληλεπιδράσεις των ατόμων και των μορίων, 
και τη βασισμένη στους κανόνες γενετική. Τα θέματα 
περιλαμβάνουν τις ατομικός-μοριακή δομές και τη δυναμική, τις 
καταστάσεις του θέματος, τις αντιδράσεις, τις λύσεις, το ύδωρ και
τα μικρά μόρια, τις βιοενεργητικές, τα μακρομόρια, τις 
πρωτεϊ'νες, τον κανονισμό μεταβολισμού, τη μόνη συμβολική 
γλώσσα, και το γενετικό κώδικα. Οι εισαγωγικές 
δραστηριότητες χρησιμεύουν ως να περπατήσουν οι πέτρες σε 10 
φυσές-χημικός αρχές που κρύβονται κάτω από πολλές βιολογικές 
διαδικασίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a 130 actividades modelo-basadas para 
aprender sobre interacciones de átomos y de moléculas, y a genética
basada en las reglas. Los asuntos incluyen las estructuras y 
dinámica ato'mico-molecular, los estados de la materia, las 
reacciones, las soluciones, agua y las moléculas pequeñas, las 
bioenergéticas, las macromoléculas, las proteínas, regulación del 
metabolismo, ensamblaje del uno mismo, y código genético. Las 
actividades introductorias sirven como piedras el caminar a 10 
principios fisicoquímicos que sean la base de muchos procesos 
biológicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206217</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107050</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/molecular-logic-database</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
