<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Electrocardiogram</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Elektrokardiogramm</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Électrocardiogramme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Electrocardiogram</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Elettrocardiogramma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Ηλεκτροκαρδιογράφημα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Electrocardiograma</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! You are practicing as an ECG technician in a health clinic Your job is to perform ECGs on patients referred to you by medical doctors. This game lets you explore the key elements of the electrocardiogram, and in the end there will be a task for you to complete.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Sie üben als ECG Techniker in einer Gesundheit Klinik, die Ihr 
Job ECGs auf Patienten durchführen soll ansprach Sie durch 
medizinische Doktoren. Dieses Spiel läßt Sie die 
Schlüsselelemente des Elektrokardiogramms erforschen, und im Ende 
gibt es eine Aufgabe, damit Sie durchführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Vous 
pratiquez en tant que technicien d'ECG dans une clinique de santé que
votre travail doit pour exécuter ECGs sur des patients s'est 
rapporté à vous par les médecins médicaux. Ce jeu vous 
laisse explorer les éléments principaux de l'électrocardiogramme, 
et à la fin il y aura un charger pour que vous terminiez.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Você 
está praticando como um técnico de ECG em uma clínica que da saúde
seu trabalho deve executar ECGs nos pacientes consultados a você por 
doutores médicos. Este jogo deixa-o explorar os elementos 
chaves do electrocardiogram, e na extremidade haverá uma tarefa para 
que você termine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Iete esercitandosi in come 
tecnico di ECG in una clinica che di salute il vostro lavoro deve per 
effettuare ECGs sui pazienti si è riferito dai medici medici. 
Questo gioco li lascia esplorare gli elementi chiave 
dell'elettrocardiogramma ed alla fine ci sarà un'operazione affinchè
completi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! 
Ασκείτε ως τεχνικός ECG σε μια κλινική υγείας η εργασία 
που σας είναι να εκτελέσετε ECGs στους ασθενείς που αναφέρονται
σε σας από τους ιατρούς. Αυτό το παιχνίδι σας αφήνει να 
ερευνήσετε τα βασικά στοιχεία του ηλεκτροκαρδιογραφήματος, και στο
τέλος θα υπάρξει μια στοιχειώδης εργασία για σας να ολοκληρώσετε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Usted 
está practicando como técnico de ECG en una clínica de la salud que
su trabajo es realizar ECGs en pacientes le refirió de los doctores 
médicos. Este juego le deja explorar los elementos dominantes 
del electrocardiograma, y en el extremo habrá una tarea para que 
usted termine.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103755</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-electrocardiogram</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
