<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203408</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Intimate Strangers: Unseen Life on Earth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vertraute Fremde: Unseen Lebensdauer auf 
Masse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étrangers Intimes : La vie invisible sur 
terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Desconhecido Intimate: Vida despercebida na 
terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sconosciuti Intimi: Vita unseen su terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οικείοι ξένοι: Απαρατήρητη ζωή στη γη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Extranjeros íntimos: Vida no vista en 
la tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This PBS documentary provides an overview of the microbial world and offers an exciting glimpse into the field of microbiology. Meet scientists from around the world investigating the microbial world in diverse locations, from a termite's stomach to a hospital operating room to an African village, and even outer space. These programs - including The Tree of Life, Keepers of the Biosphere, Dangerous Friends and Friendly Enemies, and Creators of the Future - increase the microbial literacy of students, the general public, and biotechnology workers. The site also contains an interactive Game of Life, classroom resources for grades K-12, and information about the companion book published by ASM Press.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser PBS Dokumentarfilm liefert einen Überblick
über die Mikrobenwelt und bietet einen aufregenden Blick in 
auffangene von Mikrobiologie an. Treffen Sie die 
Wissenschaftler um von der Welt die Mikrobenwelt in den verschiedenen 
Standorten, vom Magen einer Termite zu einem funktionierenden Raum des
Krankenhauses zu einem afrikanischen Dorf nachforschend und sogar 
Weltraum. Diese Programme - einschließlich den Baum des Lebens,
Wächter der Biosphäre, gefährliche Freunde und freundliche Feinde 
und Schöpfer der Zukunft - erhöhen den Mikrobenbildungsgrad der 
Kursteilnehmer, der Öffentlichkeit und der Biotechnologiearbeiter. 
Die Site enthält auch ein interaktives Spiel des Lebens, 
Klassenzimmerbetriebsmittel für Grade K-12 und Informationen über 
das Begleiterbuch, das durch ASM Presse veröffentlicht wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce documentaire de PBS fournit une vue d'ensemble 
du monde microbien et offre un aperçu passionnant dans la zone de la 
microbiologie. Rencontrez les scientifiques étudiant de partout
dans le monde le monde microbien dans des emplacements divers, de 
l'estomac d'un termite à une salle fonctionnante d'hôpital à un 
village africain, et même l'espace extra-atmosphérique. Ces 
programmes - comprenant l'arbre de la vie, des gardes de la 
biosphère, des amis dangereux et des ennemis amicaux, et des 
créateurs du futur - augmentent l'instruction microbienne des 
étudiants, du grand public, et des ouvriers de biotechnologie. 
Le site contient également un jeu interactif de la vie, des 
ressources de salle de classe pour les catégories K-12, et des 
informations sur le livre de compagnon édité par la presse d'ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este documentary de PBS fornece uma vista geral do
mundo microbial e oferece um glimpse emocionante no campo do 
microbiology. Encontre-se com os cientistas em torno do mundo 
que investigam o mundo microbial em posições diversas, do estômago 
de uma térmita a um quarto operando-se do hospital a uma vila 
africana, e mesmo o espaço exterior. Estes programas - 
including a árvore da vida, keepers do biosphere, amigos perigosos e 
inimigos amigáveis, e criadores do futuro - aumentam o literacy 
microbial dos estudantes, do público geral, e de trabalhadores do 
biotechnology. O local contem também um jogo interativo da 
vida, recursos da sala de aula para as classes K-12, e informação 
sobre o livro do companheiro publicado pela imprensa de ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo documentary di PBS fornisce una descrizione
del mondo microbico ed offre un glimpse emozionante nel campo di 
microbiologia. Venga a contatto degli scienziati intorno al 
mondo che studiano il mondo microbico nelle posizioni varie, dallo 
stomaco della termite ad una stanza di funzionamento dell'ospedale ad 
un villaggio africano e perfino dello spazio esterno. Questi 
programmi - compresi l'albero di vita, custodi della biosfera, amici 
pericolosi e nemici amichevoli e creatori del futuro - aumentano il 
literacy microbico degli allievi, di grande pubblico e degli operai di
biotecnologia. Il luogo egualmente contiene un gioco interattivo
di vita, le risorse dell'aula per i gradi K-12 e le informazioni sul 
libro del compagno pubblicato dalla pressa dell'ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το ντοκιμαντέρ PBS παρέχει μια επισκόπηση του 
μικροβιακού κόσμου και προσφέρει μια συναρπαστική αναλαμπή στο 
πεδίο της μικροβιολογίας. Συναντήστε τους επιστήμονες από 
σε όλο τον κόσμο που ο μικροβιακός κόσμος στις διαφορετικές 
θέσεις, από το στομάχι ενός τερμίτη σε ένα λειτουργούν δωμάτιο
νοσοκομείων σε ένα αφρικανικό χωριό, και ακόμη και το εξωτερικό 
διάστημα. Αυτά τα προγράμματα - συμπεριλαμβανομένου του 
δέντρου της ζωής, φύλακες της βιόσφαιρας, επικίνδυνοι φίλοι και 
φιλικοί εχθροί, και δημιουργοί του μέλλοντος - αυξάνουν τη 
μικροβιακή βασική εκπαίδευση των σπουδαστών, του ευρέος κοινού, 
και των εργαζομένων βιοτεχνολογίας. Η περιοχή περιέχει 
επίσης ένα διαλογικό παιχνίδι της ζωής, των στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς τάξεων για τους βαθμούς Κ- 12, και των πληροφοριών
για το βιβλίο συντρόφων που δημοσιεύεται από τον Τύπο ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este documentary de PBS proporciona a una 
descripción del mundo microbiano y ofrece una ojeada emocionante en 
el campo de la microbiología. Resuelva los científicos 
alrededor del mundo que investigan el mundo microbiano en 
localizaciones diversas, del estómago de una termita a un cuarto de 
funcionamiento del hospital a una aldea africana, e incluso el espacio
exterior. Estos programas - incluyendo el árbol de la vida, los
encargados de la biosfera, los amigos peligrosos y los enemigos 
cómodos, y los creador del futuro - aumentan la instrucción 
microbiana de los estudiantes, del público en general, y de los 
trabajadores de la biotecnología. El sitio también contiene un
juego interactivo de la vida, los recursos de la sala de clase para 
los grados K-12, y la información sobre el libro del compañero 
publicado por la prensa de ASM.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SERVICE (PBS)
FN:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SERVICE (PBS)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203408</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103520</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/intimate-strangers-unseen-life-on-earth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
