<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106119</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106119</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213085</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Waterfall Formation and Nick Point Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wasserfall-Anordnung und 
Einschnitt-Punkt-Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Formation de chute d'eau et transfert de point 
d'entaille</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Formação da cachoeira e migração do ponto do 
entalhe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Formazione della cascata ed espansione del punto 
della scalfittura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχηματισμός καταρρακτών και μετανάστευση σημείου 
εγκοπών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Formación de la cascada y migración de la punta 
de la mella</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides a variety of visual resources about waterfalls. Flash animations show how waterfalls, plunge pools and gorges are created by the erosion of underlying rock by flowing water. A QuickTime movie gives examples of large-scale waterfalls from around the world, and an interactive diagram illustrates how falling water is used to generate hydroelectric power. These resources are suitable for integration into lectures, labs, or other activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert eine Vielzahl der 
Sichtbetriebsmittel über Wasserfälle. Grelle Animationen 
zeigen, wie Wasserfälle, Messfingerpools und Schluchten durch die 
Abnutzung des zugrundeliegenden Felsens durch flüssiges Wasser 
hergestellt werden. Ein QuickTime Film gibt Beispiele der 
großräumigen Wasserfälle um von der Welt, und ein interaktives 
Diagramm veranschaulicht, wie fallendes Wasser benutzt wird, um 
hydroelektrische Energie festzulegen. Diese Betriebsmittel sind 
für Integration in Vorträge, in Labors oder in andere Aktivitäten 
verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit une variété de ressources 
visuelles au sujet des chutes d'eau. Les animations 
instantanées montrent comment des chutes d'eau, les regroupements de 
plongeon et les gorges sont créés par l'érosion de la roche 
fondamentale par l'eau débordante. Un film de QuickTime donne 
des exemples des chutes d'eau de grande puissance de partout dans le 
monde, et un diagramme interactif illustre comment l'eau en chute est 
employée pour développer l'énergie hydroélectrique. Ces 
ressources conviennent à l'intégration dans des conférences, des 
laboratoires, ou d'autres activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece uma variedade de recursos 
visuais sobre cachoeiras. Os animations flash mostram como as 
cachoeiras, os pools do mergulho e os gorges são criados pela erosão
de rocha subjacente pela água fluindo. Um filme de QuickTime 
dá exemplos de cachoeiras em grande escala em torno do mundo, e um 
diagrama interativo ilustra como a água de queda é usada gerar a 
potência hydroelectric. Estes recursos são apropriados para a 
integração em lectures, em laboratórios, ou em outras atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce una varietà di risorse 
visive circa le cascate. Le animazioni istantanee mostrano come 
le cascate, gli stagni di immersione ed i gorges sono creati tramite 
l'erosione della roccia di fondo da acqua fluente. Un 
film del QuickTime fornisce gli esempi delle cascate su grande
scala intorno al mondo e uno schema interattivo illustra come l'acqua 
cadente è usata per generare la forza idroelettrica. Queste 
risorse sono adatte ad integrazione nelle conferenze, nei laboratori, 
o in altre attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει ποικίλα οπτικά στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς για τους καταρράκτες. Οι ζωτικότητες λάμψης 
επιδεικνύουν πώς οι καταρράκτες, οι λίμνες κατάδυσης και τα 
φαράγγια δημιουργούνται από τη διάβρωση του ελλοχεύοντος βράχου 
από το ρέοντας ύδωρ. Ένας κινηματογράφος QuickTime 
δίνει τα παραδείγματα των μεγάλης κλίμακας καταρρακτών από σε 
όλο τον κόσμο, και ένα διαλογικό διάγραμμα επεξηγεί πώς το 
μειωμένο ύδωρ χρησιμοποιείται για να παραγάγει την υδροηλεκτρική 
δύναμη. Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι κατάλληλα για 
την ένταξη στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες 
δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a una variedad de recursos 
visuales sobre las cascadas. Las animaciones de destello 
muestran cómo las cascadas, las piscinas de la zambullida y los 
gorges son creados por la erosión de la roca subyacente por el agua 
que fluye. Una película de QuickTime da ejemplos de cascadas en
grande alrededor del mundo, y un diagrama interactivo ilustra cómo el
agua que cae se utiliza para generar potencia hidroeléctrica. 
Estos recursos son convenientes para la integración en 
conferencias, laboratorios, u otras actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213085</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106119</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/waterfall-formation-and-nick-point-migration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
