<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106963</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106963</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212969</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Using Ion Exchange Chromatography to Separate Proteins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verwenden der Ionenaustauschchromatographie, um 
Proteine zu trennen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisation par échange ionique de 
chromatographie pour séparer des protéines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usando o chromatography de troca de íon separar 
proteínas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Usando cromatografia di scambio ionico per 
separare le proteine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρησιμοποίηση της χρωματογραφίας ιονικής ανταλλαγής 
στις χωριστές πρωτεϊ'νες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usar la cromatografía de intercambio de ion para 
separar las proteínas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This activity website, hosted by the National Health Museum Activities Exchange, explores protein purification using ion chromatography. Students will separate a positively charged lysozyme from a negatively charged albumin at a neutral pH using ion exchange chromatography. The site includes information for the teacher, instructions and follow-up questions for students, and a list of supplies.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Aktivität Web site, bewirtet durch die 
nationalen Gesundheit Museum Aktivitäten Austausch, erforscht 
Proteinreinigung mit Ionenchromatographie. Kursteilnehmer 
trennen ein positiv belastetes Lysozym von einem negativ belasteten 
Albumin bei einem NullpH mit Ionenaustauschchromatographie. Die 
Site schließt Informationen für den Lehrer, Anweisungen und 
Anschlußfragen für Kursteilnehmer und eine Liste von Zubehör ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web d'activité, accueilli par les 
activités nationales échange de musée de santé, explore la 
purification de protéine en utilisant la chromatographie d'ion. 
Les étudiants sépareront un lysozyme franchement chargé d'une
albumine négativement chargée à un pH neutre en utilisant par 
échange ionique de chromatographie. Le site inclut 
l'information pour le professeur, des instructions et des questions de
suivi pour des étudiants, et une liste d'approvisionnements.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site da atividade, hospedado pelas 
atividades nacionais troca do museu da saúde, explora o purification 
da proteína usando o chromatography do íon. Os estudantes 
separarão um lysozyme positivamente carregado de uma albumina 
negativamente carregada em um pH neutro usando o chromatography de 
troca de íon. O local inclui a informação para o professor, 
instruções e perguntas da continuação para estudantes, e uma lista
das fontes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site di attività, ospitato dalle 
attività nazionali scambio del museo di salute, esplora la 
purificazione della proteina usando la cromatografia dello ione. 
Gli allievi separeranno un lisozima positivamente caricato da 
un'albumina negativamente caricata ad un pH neutro usando la 
cromatografia di scambio ionico. Il luogo include le 
informazioni per l'insegnante, istruzioni e domande di aggiornamento 
per gli allievi e una lista dei rifornimenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος δραστηριότητας, που φιλοξενείται 
από την εθνική ανταλλαγή δραστηριοτήτων μουσείων υγείας, ερευνά
τον πρωτεϊνικό καθαρισμό χρησιμοποιώντας την ιονική 
χρωματογραφία. Οι σπουδαστές θα χωρίσουν θετικά χρεωμένο 
lysozyme από μια αρνητικά χρεωμένη λευκωματίνη σε ένα 
ουδέτερο pH χρησιμοποιώντας τη χρωματογραφία ιονικής 
ανταλλαγής. Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τις πληροφορίες για το 
δάσκαλο, τις οδηγίες και τις ακόλουθες ερωτήσεις για τους 
σπουδαστές, και έναν κατάλογο προμηθειών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site de la actividad, recibido por las 
actividades nacionales intercambio del museo de la salud, explora la 
purificación de la proteína usando la cromatografía del ion. 
Los estudiantes separarán un lysozyme positivamente cargado de 
una albúmina negativamente cargada en un pH neutral usando la 
cromatografía de intercambio de ion. El sitio incluye la 
información para el profesor, las instrucciones y las preguntas de la
carta recordativa para los estudiantes, y una lista de fuentes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELLYN A. DAUGHERTY
FN:ELLYN A. DAUGHERTY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:THE NATIONAL HEALTH MUSEUM: ACCESS EXCELLENCE
FN:THE NATIONAL HEALTH MUSEUM: ACCESS EXCELLENCE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212969</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106963</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/using-ion-exchange-chromatography-to-separate-proteins</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
