<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103189</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103189</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201363</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Creating Custom Map Images of Earth and Other Worlds</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Erstellen der kundenspezifischen Karte Bilder von Masse und von 
anderen Welten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Créer des images faites sur commande de carte de la terre et 
d'autres mondes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Criando imagens feitas sob encomenda do mapa da terra e dos 
outros mundos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Creazione delle immagini su ordinazione del programma di terra e
di altri mondi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: 
Δημιουργία των εικόνων χαρτών συνήθειας της γης και άλλων 
κόσμων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Crear imágenes de encargo de la correspondencia de la 
tierra y de otros mundos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This chapter familiarizes users with Jules Verne Voyager, a freely available online map tool that includes data for Earth as well as 19 other planets and moons. Users create a variety of map images then save and import the images into a presentation or a word-processing document. In the activity, users explore the range of data that are available to create map images: 100 different types of data are available to characterize portions of Earth. In addition, Voyager has at least one type of data for all planets and moons of the inner solar system. Recent data for Jupiter, Saturn, and many of their moons are also available. In the final part of the activity, users learn a technique that is useful for comparative planetology: they create map images to compare features from different worlds at the same scale, including correctly scaled planet-from-space views of each world.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Kapitel macht Benutzer mit Jules Verne 
Voyager, ein frei vorhandenes Onlinekarte Hilfsmittel vertraut, das 
Daten für Masse sowie 19 andere Planeten und Monde einschließt. 
Benutzer erstellen eine Vielzahl der Karte Bilder dann außer 
und importieren die Bilder in eine Darstellung oder in ein 
Textverarbeitungsdokument. In der Aktivität erforschen Benutzer
die Strecke der Daten, die vorhanden sind, Karte Bilder zu erstellen: 
100 unterschiedliche Typen Daten sind vorhanden, Teile Masse zu 
kennzeichnen. Zusätzlich hat Voyager mindestens einen Typen 
Daten für alle Planeten und Monde des inneren Solarsystems. 
Neue Daten für Jupiter, Saturn und viele ihrer Monde sind auch 
vorhanden. Im abschließenden Teil der Aktivität, erlernen 
Benutzer eine Technik, die für vergleichbares planetology nützlich 
ist: sie erstellen Karte Bilder, um Merkmale von den 
unterschiedlichen Welten an der gleichen Skala, einschließlich 
richtig eingestufte Planet-von-Platz Ansichten jeder Welt zu 
vergleichen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce chapitre familiarise des utilisateurs avec 
Jules Verne Voyager, un outil librement accessible en ligne de 
carte qui inclut des données pour la terre aussi bien que 19 autres 
planètes et lunes. Les utilisateurs créent une variété 
d'images de carte puis économiser et importent les images dans une 
présentation ou un document de traitement de texte. Dans 
l'activité, les utilisateurs explorent l'intervalle des données qui 
sont disponibles pour créer des images de carte : 100 types 
différents de données sont disponibles pour caractériser des 
parties de la terre. En outre, Voyager a au moins un type de 
données pour toutes les planètes et lunes du système solaire 
intérieur. Les données récentes pour Jupiter, Saturne, et 
plusieurs de leurs lunes sont également disponibles. Dans la 
partie finale de l'activité, les utilisateurs apprennent une 
technique qui est utile pour le planetology comparatif : ils 
créent des images de carte pour comparer des dispositifs de 
différents mondes à la même échelle, y compris des vues 
correctement mesurées du planète-de-espace de chaque monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este capítulo familiariza usuários com o Jules 
Verne Voyager, uma ferramenta em linha livremente disponível do mapa 
que inclua dados para a terra as.well.as outros 19 planetas e luas. 
Os usuários críam uma variedade de imagens do mapa a seguir 
excepto e importam as imagens em uma apresentação ou em um original 
de processo de texto. Na atividade, os usuários exploram a 
escala dos dados que estão disponíveis para criar imagens do mapa: 
100 tipos diferentes de dados estão disponíveis para 
caracterizar parcelas da terra. Além, Voyager tem ao menos um 
tipo de dados para todos os planetas e luas do sistema solar interno. 
Os dados recentes para Jupiter, Saturno, e muitos de suas luas 
estão também disponíveis. Na parte final da atividade, os 
usuários aprendem uma técnica que seja útil para o planetology 
comparativo: críam imagens do mapa para comparar 
características dos mundos diferentes na mesma escala, including 
vistas corretamente escaladas do planeta-$$$-ESPAÇO de cada mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo capitolo rende familiare gli utenti a Jules
Verne Voyager, uno strumento liberamente accessibile in linea del 
programma che include i dati per terra così come altri 19 pianeti e 
lune. Gli utenti creano una varietà di immagini del programma 
quindi risparmi ed importano le immagini in una presentazione o in un 
documento elaborato a parole. Nell'attività, gli utenti 
esplorano la gamma di dati che sono a disposizione per creare le 
immagini del programma: 100 tipi differenti di dati sono a 
disposizione per caratterizzare le parti di terra. In più, 
Voyager ha almeno un tipo di dati per tutti i pianeti e lune del 
sistema solare interno. I dati recenti per Jupiter, Saturno e 
molti delle loro lune sono egualmente disponibili. Nella parte 
finale dell'attività, gli utenti imparano una tecnica che è utile 
per il planetology comparativo: creano le immagini del programma
per confrontare le caratteristiche dai mondi differenti alla stessa 
scala, compreso le viste correttamente regolate dello 
pianeta-da-spazio di ogni mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το κεφάλαιο εξοικειώνει τους χρήστες με jules 
Verne Voyager, ένα ελεύθερα απευθείας προσβάσιμο εργαλείο 
χαρτών που περιλαμβάνει τα στοιχεία για τη γη καθώς επίσης και 
19 άλλους πλανήτες και φεγγάρια. Οι χρήστες δημιουργούν 
ποικίλες εικόνες χαρτών κατόπιν εκτός από και εισάγουν τις 
εικόνες σε μια παρουσίαση ή ένα έγγραφο επεξεργασίας κειμένου. 
Στη δραστηριότητα, οι χρήστες ερευνούν τη σειρά των 
στοιχείων που είναι διαθέσιμα για να δημιουργήσουν τις εικόνες 
χαρτών: 100 διαφορετικοί τύποι στοιχείων είναι 
διαθέσιμοι για να χαρακτηρίσουν τις μερίδες της γης. 
Επιπλέον, ο ταξιδιώτης έχει τουλάχιστον έναν τύπο 
στοιχείων για όλους τους πλανήτες και τα φεγγάρια του εσωτερικού 
ηλιακού συστήματος. Τα πρόσφατα στοιχεία για Δία, τον 
Κρόνο, και πολλά από τα φεγγάρια τους είναι επίσης διαθέσιμα. 
Στο τελικό μέρος της δραστηριότητας, οι χρήστες μαθαίνουν 
μια τεχνική που είναι χρήσιμη για τη συγκριτική πλανητολογία: 
δημιουργούν τις εικόνες χαρτών για να συγκρίνουν τα 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα από τους διαφορετικούς κόσμους στην 
ίδια κλίμακα, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των σωστά ξελεπιασμένων 
πλανήτης-από-διαστημικών όψεων κάθε κόσμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este capítulo familiariza a utilizadores con 
Julio Verne Voyager, una herramienta libremente accesible en línea de
la correspondencia que incluya los datos para la tierra así como 19 
otros planetas y lunas. Los utilizadores crean una variedad de 
imágenes de la correspondencia después excepto e importan las 
imágenes en una presentación o un documento de proceso de la 
palabra. En la actividad, los utilizadores exploran el rango de 
los datos que están disponibles para crear imágenes de la 
correspondencia: 100 diversos tipos de datos están disponibles 
para caracterizar porciones de tierra. Además, Voyager tiene 
por lo menos un tipo de datos para todos los planetas y lunas de la 
Sistema Solar interna. Los datos recientes para Júpiter, 
Saturno, y muchos de sus lunas están también disponibles. En 
la parte final de la actividad, los utilizadores aprenden una técnica
que sea útil para el planetology comparativo: crean imágenes 
de la correspondencia para comparar características de diversos 
mundos en la misma escala, incluyendo opiniones correctamente 
escaladas del planeta-de-espacio de cada mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LUANN DAHLMAN
FN:LUANN DAHLMAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201363</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103189</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-creating-custom-map-images-of-earth-and-other-worlds</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
