<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104817</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104817</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206883</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology and Invention</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie und Erfindung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie et invention</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia e invenção</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia ed invenzione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία και εφεύρεση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología e invención</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at inventors and inventions that changed our lives: the telegraph, photophone, animation, sewing machine, ice cream cone, nuclear fission, flight, and others. It includes Thomas Edison's journals and failed inventions, and Alexander Graham Bell's notebook entry describing the first successful experiment with the telephone (March 10, 1876). George Westinghouse, James Smithson, Benjamin Banneker, and Samuel Morse are among others profiled.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf Erfinder und Erfindungen, die unsere 
Lebensdauern änderten: der Fernschreiber, der Photophone, die 
Animation, die Nähmaschine, der Eiscremekegel, die Kernspaltung, der 
Flug und die anderen. Sie enthält Thomas Edisons Journale und 
verlassene Erfindungen und Alexander Graham Bell der Notizbucheintrag,
der das erste erfolgreiche Experiment mit dem Telefon beschreibt 
(März 10, 1876). George Westinghouse, James Smithson, Benjamin 
Banneker und Samuel Morse gehören zu ein Profil erstellten anderen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards aux inventeurs et aux inventions qui ont 
changé nos vies : le télégraphe, le photophone, l'animation, 
le cône de crême de machine à coudre et glacée, la fission 
nucléaire, le vol, et les autres. Elle entrée inclut des 
journaux de Thomas Edison et des inventions échouées, et d'Alexandre
Graham Bell cahier décrivant la première expérience réussie avec 
le téléphone (10 mars 1876). George Westinghouse, 
James Smithson, Benjamin Banneker, et Samuel Morse sont entre 
d'autres profilés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares nos inventores e nas invenções que 
mudaram nossas vidas: o telégrafo, o photophone, o animation, a
máquina sewing, o cone do creme de gelo, o fission nuclear, o vôo, e
o outro. Inclui jornais de Thomas Edison e invenções falhadas,
e de caderno de Alexander Graham Bell entrada que descreve a primeira 
experiência bem sucedida com o telefone (março 10, 1876). 
George Westinghouse, James Smithson, Benjamin Banneker, e Samuel
Morse são entre outro perfilado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi agli inventori ed alle invenzioni che 
hanno cambiato le nostre vite: il telegrafo, il photophone, la 
animazione, la macchina per cucire, il cono del gelato, la fissione 
nucleare, il volo e gli altri. Include le pubblicazioni del 
Thomas Edison e le invenzioni guastate ed entrata del taccuino del 
Alexander Graham Bell che descrive il primo esperimento riuscito con 
il telefono (10 marzo 1876). George Westinghouse, James 
Smithson, Benjamin Banneker e Samuel Morse sono tra altri profilati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τους εφευρέτες και τις εφευρέσεις που άλλαξαν
τις ζωές μας: ο τηλέγραφος, το photophone, η ζωτικότητα, η
ράβοντας μηχανή, ο κώνος παγωτού, η πυρηνική διάσπαση, η πτήση,
και άλλες. Περιλαμβάνει τα περιοδικά του Thomas 
Edison's και τις αποτυχημένες εφευρέσεις, και την είσοδο 
σημειωματάριων του Αλεξάνδρου Graham Bell's περιγράφοντας το 
πρώτο επιτυχές πείραμα με το τηλέφωνο (10 Μαρτίου, 1876). 
George Westinghouse, james Smithson, Benjamin 
Banneker, και ο Samuel Morse σχεδιάζουν περίγραμμα μεταξύ 
των άλλων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en los inventores y las invenciones que 
cambiaron nuestras vidas: el telégrafo, el fotófono, la 
animación, la máquina de costura, el cono del helado, la fisión 
nuclear, el vuelo, y los otros. Incluye los diarios de Thomas 
Edison y las invenciones falladas, y entrada del cuaderno de Alexander
Graham Bell que describe el primer experimento acertado con el 
teléfono (de marcha la 10 de 1876). George Westinghouse, James 
Smithson, Benjamin Banneker, y Samuel Morse están entre otros 
perfilados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206883</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104817</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/science-and-technology-and-invention</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
