<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105625</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105625</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973944</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Peace Games: Prisoners of War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Friedensspiele: Kriegsgefangen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Paix : Prisonniers de guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Paz: Prisioneiros de guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Pace: Prigionieri di guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ειρήνης: Αιχμάλωτοι πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Paz: Prisioneros de guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Can people behave as they like during times of war? No, they can't. The Geneva Conventions of written rules and articles make some acts unlawful. Nearly all countries in the world have promised to follow these rules by signing up. The Red Cross ensures that these rules are followed. Among the Red Cross's tasks are to visit prisoners of war (POWs) who are protected by the Geneva Conventions, and provide them with assistance</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Können Leute sich benehmen, während sie während der Zeiten 
des Krieges mögen? Nr., können sie nicht. Die Genfer 
Konventionen der schriftlichen Richtlinien und der Artikel bilden 
einige Taten ungesetzlich. Fast alle Länder in der Welt haben 
versprochen, diesen Richtlinien zu folgen, von oben unterzeichnen. 
Das rote Kreuz stellt sicher, daß diese Richtlinien gefolgt 
sind. Unter roten Kreuz sind die Aufgaben, Kriegsgefangen (POWs)
zu besuchen die von den Genfer Konventionen geschützt werden, und sie
mit Unterstützung zu versehen</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Les gens 
peuvent-ils se comporter pendant qu'ils aiment pendant des périodes 
de guerre ? Non, ils ne peuvent pas. Les conventions de 
Genève des règles et des articles écrits rendent quelques actes 
illégaux. Presque tous les pays dans le monde ont promis de 
suivre ces règles de s'engager. La croix rouge 
s'assure que ces règles sont suivies. Parmi la croix rouge 
charge sont de rendre visite aux prisonniers de guerre 
(prisonniers de guerre) qui sont protégés par les conventions de Genève, et 
de leur fournir l'aide</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Podem 
os povos comportar-se enquanto gostam durante épocas da guerra? 
No., não podem. As convenções de Genebra de réguas e 
de artigos escritos fazem alguns atos ilegais. Quase todos os 
países no mundo prometeram seguir estas réguas assinando acima. 
A cruz vermelha assegura-se de que estas réguas estejam 
seguidas. Entre a cruz vermelha as tarefas são visitar os 
prisioneiros de guerra (POWs) que são protegidos pelas convenções 
de Genebra, e fornecê-las com o auxílio</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Può la gente comportarsi 
mentre gradiscono durante i periodi della guerra? No, non può. 
Le convenzioni di Ginevra delle regole e degli articoli scritti 
rendono alcuni atti illegali. Quasi tutti i paesi nel mondo 
hanno promesso di seguire queste regole firmando in su. La croce
rossa si accerta che queste regole siano seguite. Fra la croce 
rossa le mansioni sono di visitare i prigionieri di guerra (POWs) che 
sono protetti dalle convenzioni di Ginevra e di fornire loro 
assistenza</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! 
Μπορούν οι άνθρωποι να συμπεριφερθούν όπως συμπαθούν κατά 
τη διάρκεια των χρόνων του πολέμου; Όχι. Οι Συνθήκες 
της Γενεύης των γραπτών κανόνων και των άρθρων καθιστούν μερικές
πράξεις παράνομες. Σχεδόν όλες οι χώρες στον κόσμο έχουν 
υποσχεθεί να ακολουθήσουν αυτούς τους κανόνες με να υπογράψουν 
επάνω. Ο Ερυθρός Σταυρός εξασφαλίζει ότι αυτοί οι κανόνες
ακολουθούνται. Μεταξύ του Ερυθρού Σταυρού οι στοιχειώδεις 
εργασίες είναι να επισκεφτούν οι αιχμάλωτοι πολέμου (POWs) που
προστατεύονται από τις Συνθήκες της Γενεύης, και παρέχουν σε τις 
τη βοήθεια</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un descubrimiento
o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! ¿Puede la gente 
comportarse mientras que ella tiene gusto durante épocas de la 
guerra? No, ella no puede. Las convenciones de Ginebra de 
reglas y de artículos escritos hacen algunos actos ilegales. 
Casi todos los países en el mundo han prometido seguir estas 
reglas firmando para arriba. La Cruz Roja se asegura de que 
estas reglas estén seguidas. Entre la Cruz Roja las tareas son 
visitar a los prisioneros de guerra (POWs) que son protegidos por las 
convenciones de Ginebra, y proveer de ellas ayuda</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973944</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105625</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/peace-games-prisoners-of-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
