<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105265</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105265</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206564</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Africa: Peace Corps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Afrika: Friedenskorps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Afrique : Corps de Paix</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">África: Corpo De Paz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'Africa: Corpo di pace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αφρική: Ειρήνη Σώμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">África: Cuerpo De Paz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers lessons on stories, letters, photos, and study units from experiences of Peace Corps volunteers across Africa. Topics include folk tales and patterns in them, racial prejudice in South Africa, life in a village of Tanzania, traditional healers and HIV/AIDS, the meaning of wealth, sharing and generosity, what it takes to be a hero, time and punctuality, perspectives of different cultures, and water.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet Lektionen auf Geschichten, Zeichen, Fotos 
an, und Studie Maßeinheiten von den Erfahrungen der Friedenskorpse 
erbietet sich über Afrika freiwillig. Themen schließen 
Volksgeschichten und Muster in ihnen, rassisches Vorurteil in 
Südafrika, Leben in einem Dorf von Tanzania, traditionelle Heiler und
HIV/AIDS, die Bedeutung von Fülle, Teilen und Großzügigkeit ein, 
was es nimmt, um zu sein ein Held, Zeit und Pünktlichkeit, 
Perspektiven der unterschiedlichen Kulturen und Wasser.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre des leçons sur des histoires, lettres, 
photos, et les unités d'étude des expériences des corps de paix 
offre à travers l'Afrique. Les sujets incluent des contes et 
des configurations folkloriques dans elles, préjudice racial en 
Afrique du sud, vie dans un village de la Tanzanie, des 
guérisseurs traditionnels et HIV/SIDA, la signification de la 
richesse, partage et générosité, ce qu'il prend pour être un 
héros, temps et exactitude, perspectives de différentes cultures, et
eau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece lições em histórias, letras, fotos, e 
as unidades do estudo das experiências de corpos de paz oferecem-se 
através de África. Os tópicos incluem tales e testes padrões
populares nelas, preconceito racial em África do Sul, vida em uma 
vila de Tanzânia, healers tradicionais e HIV/AIDS, o meaning da 
riqueza, compartilhar e generosity, o que faz exame para ser um 
herói, época e punctuality, perspectives de culturas diferentes, e 
água.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre le lezioni sulle storia, le lettere, foto e 
le unità di studio per esperienza nel Corpo di pace si offre 
volontariamente attraverso l'Africa. I soggetti includono i 
racconti e modelli pieghi in loro, pregiudizio razziale in Sudafrica, 
vita in un villaggio della Tanzania, healers tradizionali e HIV/AIDS, 
il significato della ricchezza, ripartirsi e generosity, che cosa 
prende per essere un hero, periodo e punctuality, prospettive delle 
colture differenti ed acqua.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τα μαθήματα προσφορών στις ιστορίες, τις επιστολές, 
τις φωτογραφίες, και τις μονάδες μελέτης από την εμπειρία της 
ειρήνης προσφέρονται εθελοντικά Σώμα πέρα από την Αφρική. 
Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τις λαϊκά ιστορίες και τα πρότυπα 
σε τους, τη φυλετική προκατάληψη στη Νότια Αφρική, τη ζωή σε ένα
χωριό της Τανζανίας, τα παραδοσιακό healers και το VIH/AIDS, 
την έννοια του πλούτου, τη διανομή και τη γενναιοδωρία, τι 
παίρνει για να είναι ήρωας, ένας χρόνος και μια ακρίβεια, 
προοπτικές των διαφορετικών πολιτισμών, και ύδωρ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece lecciones en las historias, cartas, fotos, 
y las unidades del estudio por experiencia de los cuerpos de paz se 
ofrecen voluntariamente a través de África. Los asuntos 
incluyen cuentos y los modelos populares en ellas, prejudicar racial 
en Suráfrica, vida en una aldea de Tanzania, los curadores 
tradicionales e HIV/AIDS, el significado de la abundancia, el 
compartir y generosidad, qué toma para ser un héroe, época y 
puntualidad, perspectivas de diversas culturas, y agua.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206564</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105265</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/africa-peace-corps</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
