<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106117</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106117</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086983</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Man . . . Died on My Lap": One Women Recalls the Memorial Day Massacre of 1937</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Der Mann. . . Gestorben auf 
meinem Schoß ": Frauen eine erinnert an das 
Erinnerungstagesblutbad von 1937</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'Homme. . . Mort sur mon 
recouvrement ": Les femmes une rappelle le Massacre de jour 
commémoratif de 1937</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Homem. . . Morrido em meu 
regaço ": As mulheres uma recordam o massacre do dia memorial 
de 1937</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"L'Uomo. . . Morto sul mio giro 
": Le donne una ricorda il massacre di giorno commemorativo di 
1937</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το άτομο. .. Πεθαμένος στην περιτύλιξή 
μου ": Οι γυναίκες ένα υπενθυμίζουν την αναμνηστική σφαγή 
ημέρας του 1937</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Hombre. . . Muerto en mi 
regazo ": Las mujeres una recuerdan la Masacre del día 
conmemorativo de 1937</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When members of the Steel Workers Organizing Committee (SWOC) decided to strike the "Little Steel"companies in May 1937, they could hardly have expected it to result in a massacre. On the afternoon of Memorial Day, a flag-waving, ethnically diverse group set out for the company_s Republic Steel's main gate but were stopped by a large contingent of policemen. When one of the policemen suddenly and inexplicably fired his revolver into the front of the crowd the march turned into a massacre. In the end, Chicago_s police killed ten fleeing workers, wounded thirty more and beat fifty-five so badly they required hospitalization. Lupe Marshall, a housewife and volunteer social worker in South Chicago was among those beaten. She gave this testimony to the U.S. Senate Committee on Education and Labor, known informally as the La Follette Committee for its chair, Senator Robert La Follette, and charged with investigating the incident.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als Bauteile des 
Stahlarbeiter-Organisationsausschusses (SWOC) entschieden, das "wenige
Steel"companies im Mai 1937 anzuschlagen, konnten sie es kaum erwartet
haben, um ein Blutbad zu ergeben. Am Nachmittag des 
Erinnerungstages, legte ein Markierungsfahne-Wellenartig bewegen, 
ethnisch verschiedene Gruppe dar, für die Hauptleitung des company_s 
Republik-Stahls aber wurde von einem großen Kontingent der Polizisten
gestoppt. Wenn einer der Polizisten plötzlich und unerklärlich
abgefeuert seinem Revolver in die Frontseite der Masse, die der März 
zu ein Blutbad machte. Im Ende beendete Chicago_s Polizei 10 
fliehende Arbeiter, mehr verwundet dreißig und schlug 
fünfundfünfzig, so falsch, das sie Hospitalisierung benötigten. 
Lupe Marschall, ein Hausfrau- und freiwilligersozialarbeiter in 
Südchicago wurden zu denen geschlagen. Sie gab dem VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Senat-Ausschuß für die Ausbildung und Arbeit dieses Zeugnis,
formlos bekannt als der La Follette Ausschuß für seinen Stuhl, 
Senator Robert La Follette, und mit dem Nachforschen des Ereignisses 
aufgeladen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand les membres du Comité d'organisation 
d'ouvriers en acier (SWOC) ont décidé de frapper le "peu de 
Steel"companies en mai 1937, ils pourraient à peine s'être attendus 
à ce qu'il ait comme conséquence un massacre. L'après-midi
du jour commémoratif, indicateur-onduler, groupe éthniquement divers
a visé pour la voie de base de l'acier de République de company_s 
mais a été arrêté par un grand contingent des policiers. 
Quand un des policiers soudainement et inexplicablement mis le 
feu son revolver dans l'avant de la foule que la marche s'est 
transformée en massacre. En fin de compte, la police de 
Chicago_s a détruit dix ouvriers en fuite, enroulés trente davantage
et a battu cinquante-cinq tellement mal qu'elles ont eu besoin de 
l'hospitalisation. Le maréchal de Lupe, une ouvrière sociale 
de femme au foyer et volontaire Chicago du sud parmi ceux ont 
été battus. Elle a donné ce témoignage au comité de sénat 
des ETATS-UNIS de l'éducation et du travail, connus officieusement en
tant que Comité de Follette de La pour sa chaise, le sénateur Robert
La Follette, et chargés d'étudier l'incident.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando os membros do comitê organizando de 
trabalhadores de aço (SWOC) se decidiram golpear "pouco 
Steel"companies em maio 1937, poderiam mal tê-lo esperado resultar em
um massacre. Na tarde do dia memorial, bandeira-acenar, grupo 
étnicamente diverso ajustou-se para fora para a porta principal do 
aço da república dos company_s mas foi-se parado por um contingente 
grande dos polícias. Quando um dos polícias de repente e 
ateado fogo inexplicably seu revólver na parte dianteira da multidão
que o março girou em um massacre. Na extremidade, as polícias 
de Chicago_s mataram dez trabalhadores fujindo, feridos trinta mais e 
bateram fifty-five assim mal que requereram a hospitalização. 
O marshall de Lupe, um trabalhador social do housewife e o 
voluntário em Chicago sul entre aqueles foram batidos. Deu este
testimony ao comitê do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na instrução e no 
trabalho, sabidos informal como o comitê de Follette do la para sua 
cadeira, senator Robert La Follette, e carregados com investigar o 
incident.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando i membri del comitato di organizzazione dei
lavoratori dell'industria siderurgica (SWOC) hanno deciso colpire "il 
poco Steel"companies nel mese di maggio 1937, potrebbero appena 
invitare per provocare un massacre. Sul pomeriggio del giorno 
commemorativo, un bandierina-ondeggiamento, gruppo etnico vario ha 
precisato per il tubo principale dei company_s dell'acciaio della 
Repubblica ma è stato interrotto da un grande contingente dei 
poliziotti. Quando uno dei poliziotti improvvisamente ed 
inexplicably infornato il suo revolver nella parte anteriore della 
folla che il procedere si è trasformato in un massacre. Alla 
fine, la polizia di Chicago_s ha ucciso dieci operai fuggenti, feriti 
trenta di più ed ha battuto fifty-five hanno richiesto così male che
l'ospedalizzazione. Il marshall di Lupe, un operaio sociale 
volontario e del casalinga in Chicago del sud fra quelli sono stati 
battuti. Ha dato questa testimonianza al comitato del senato 
degli STATI UNITI di formazione e del Lavoro, conosciuti senza 
formalità come il comitato di Follette della La per la relativa 
sedia, il senatore Robert La Follette e caricati dello studio 
dell'avvenimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν τα μέλη των εργαζομένων χάλυβα που οργανώνουν 
την Επιτροπή (SWOC) αποφάσισαν να χτυπήσουν το "λίγο 
Steel"companies σε Μάιος το 1937, θα μπορούσαν μετά βίας
να το έχουν αναμείνει για να οδηγήσουν σε μια σφαγή. Στο 
απόγευμα της αναμνηστικής ημέρας, ένας σημαία-κυματισμός, την 
εθνικά διαφορετική ομάδα για τη βασική πύλη του χάλυβα 
Δημοκρατίας company_s αλλά σταμάτησε από ένα μεγάλο 
ενδεχόμενο καθόρισε των αστυνομικών. Όταν ένας από τους 
αστυνομικούς ξαφνικά και ανεξήγητα που απολύθηκαν το περίστροφό 
του στο μέτωπο του πλήθους ο Μάρτιος μετατράπηκε σε σφαγή. 
Στο τέλος, η αστυνομία Chicago_s σκότωσε δέκα φεύγοντας 
εργαζομένους, πληγωμένος τριάντα περισσότερο και κτύπησε πενήντα
πέντε τόσο άσχημα που απαίτησαν την εισαγωγή σε νοσοκομείο. 
Το Lupe τακτοποιεί, μια νοικοκυρά και ένας εθελοντικός 
κοινωνικός λειτουργός στο νότιο Σικάγο ήταν μεταξύ εκείνων που 
κτυπήθηκαν. Έδωσε αυτήν την κατάθεση στην Επιτροπή 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου της εκπαίδευσης και στην εργασία, γνωστή 
ανεπίσημα ως Επιτροπή Λα Follette για την καρέκλα της, 
γερουσιαστής Robert La Follette, και υπεύθυνη για την 
έρευνα του γεγονότος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando los miembros del comité de ordenación de 
los trabajadores de acero (SWOC) decidían pulso el "poco 
Steel"companies en mayo de 1937, habrían podido esperar apenas que 
dé lugar a una masacre. En la tarde del día conmemorativo, 
el indicador-agitar, grupo étnico diverso precisó para el tubo 
principal de los company_s del acero de la república pero fue parado 
por un contingente grande de policías. Cuando uno de los 
policías repentinamente e inexplicablemente encendido su revólver en
el frente de la muchedumbre que el marzo dio vuelta en una masacre.
En el extremo, el policía de Chicago_s mató a diez 
trabajadores que huían, heridos treinta más y batió cincuenta y 
cinco que él requirió tan gravemente la hospitalización. 
Batieron al ordenar de Lupe, a un trabajador social del ama de 
casa y voluntario en Chicago del sur entre ésos. Ella dio este 
testimonio al comité del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre la educación
y el trabajo, conocidos informal como el comité de Follette del la 
para su silla, senador Roberto La Follette, y cargados con investigar 
el incidente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086983</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106117</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-man-died-on-my-lap-one-women-recalls-the-memorial-day-massacre-of-1937</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
