<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103743</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103743</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211256</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration: Fisheries Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale ozeanische und atmosphärische Leitung: 
Fischerei-Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gestion océanique et atmosphérique nationale : 
Homepage de Pêche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Administração oceanic e atmosférica nacional: 
Homepage Dos Fisheries</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gestione oceanica ed atmosferica nazionale: 
Homepage Delle Industrie della pesca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ωκεάνεια και ατμοσφαιρική διοίκηση: 
Αρχική σελίδα αλιείας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Administración oceánica y atmosférica nacional:
Homepage De las Industrias pesqueras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Fisheries is dedicated to protecting and preserving our nation's living marine resources through scientific research, fisheries management, enforcement, and habitat conservation. NOAA Fisheries is a leading voice for commercial and recreational fisheries and continues to focus its efforts on sustaining our marine resources as we face the challenges that the new millennium brings. This clearinghouse website highlights the work of NOAA Fisheries. Topics include marine mammals, fisheries habitat, recreational fisheries, endangered species, commercial fishers and more. Users can access hot fisheries topics, information in the spotlight and other fisheries research organizations. Several image galleries and audio files of whale songs are also available.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale ozeanische und atmosphärische Leitung 
(NOAA) Fischereien wird dem Schützen und dem Konservieren der 
Lebenmarinebetriebsmittel unserer Nation durch wissenschaftliche 
Forschung, Fischereien Management, Durchführung und 
Lebensraumerhaltung eingesetzt. NOAA Fischereien ist eine 
führende Stimme für die kommerziellen und entspannenden Fischereien 
und fährt fort, seine Bemühungen auf das Unterstützen unserer 
Marinebetriebsmittel zu richten, da wir die Herausforderungen 
gegenüberstellen, die das neue Jahrtausend holt. Diese 
Verrechnungszentraleweb site markiert die Arbeit der NOAA Fischereien.
Themen enthalten Meeressäugetiere, Fischereilebensraum, 
entspannende Fischereien, gefährdete Sorte, kommerzielle Fischer und 
mehr. Benutzer können heiße Fischereithemen, Informationen im 
Scheinwerfer und auf andere Fischereiforschung Organisationen 
zugreifen. Einige Bildgalerien und Audiodateien der Walliede 
sind auch vorhanden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La pêche océanique et atmosphérique nationale 
de la gestion (NOAA) est consacrée à protéger et à préserver les 
ressources marines de la vie de notre nation par la recherche 
scientifique, la pêche gestion, l'application, et l'économie 
d'habitat. La pêche de NOAA est une principale voix pour la 
pêche commerciale et récréationnelle et continue à concentrer ses 
efforts sur soutenir nos ressources marines car nous relevons les 
défis que le nouveau millénium apporte. Ce site Web de chambre
de compensation met en valeur le travail de la pêche de NOAA. 
Les sujets incluent les mammifères marins, habitat de pêche, 
pêche récréationnelle, espèces mises en danger, pêcheurs 
commerciaux et plus. Les utilisateurs peuvent accéder à des 
sujets chauds de pêche, à l'information dans le projecteur et à 
d'autres organismes de recherches de pêche. Plusieurs galeries 
d'image et fichiers sonores des chansons de baleine sont également 
disponibles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os fisheries oceanic e atmosféricos nacionais da 
administração (NOAA) são dedicados a proteger e a preservar 
recursos marinhos da vida da nossa nação com a pesquisa científica,
os fisheries gerência, o enforcement, e o conservation do habitat. 
Os fisheries de NOAA são uma voz principal para fisheries 
comerciais e recreacionais e continuam a focalizar seus esforços em 
sustentar nossos recursos marinhos porque nós enfrentamos os desafios
que o millennium novo traz. Este Web site do clearinghouse 
destaca o trabalho de fisheries de NOAA. Os tópicos incluem 
mamíferos marinhos, habitat dos fisheries, fisheries recreacionais, 
espécie posta em perigo, fishers comerciais e mais. Os 
usuários podem alcançar tópicos quentes dos fisheries, informação
no spotlight e outras organizações de pesquisa dos fisheries. 
Diversas galerias da imagem e limas audio de canções da baleia
estão também disponíveis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le industrie della pesca oceaniche ed atmosferiche
nazionali della gestione (NOAA) è dedicata alla protezione ed a 
conservare delle risorse marine di vita della nostra nazione con 
ricerca scientifica, le industrie della pesca gestione, l'applicazione
e la conservazione dell'habitat. Le industrie della pesca di 
NOAA è una voce principale per le industrie della pesca commerciali e
di ricreazione e continua a concentrare i relativi sforzi sul 
sostenimento delle nostre risorse marine poichè affrontiamo le sfide 
che il nuovo millennio porta. Questo Web site della stanza di 
compensazione evidenzia il lavoro delle industrie della pesca di NOAA.
I soggetti includono i mammiferi marini, habitat delle industrie
della pesca, le industrie della pesca di ricreazione, specie in 
pericolo, pescatori commerciali e più. Gli utenti possono 
accedere ai soggetti caldi delle industrie della pesca, alle 
informazioni nel riflettore e ad altri organismi di ricerca delle 
industrie della pesca. Parecchi gallerie di immagine ed archivi 
audio delle canzoni della balena sono egualmente disponibili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εθνική ωκεάνεια και ατμοσφαιρική αλιεία διοίκησης 
(NOAA) αφιερώνεται στην προστασία και τη συντήρηση των 
θαλασσίων πόρων διαβίωσης του έθνους μας μέσω της επιστημονικής 
έρευνας, της διαχείρισης αλιείας, της επιβολής, και της 
συντήρησης βιότοπων. Η αλιεία NOAA είναι μια κύρια φωνή
για την εμπορική και ψυχαγωγική αλιεία και συνεχίζει να στρέφει 
τις προσπάθειές της στη στήριξη των θαλασσίων πόρων μας 
δεδομένου ότι αντιμετωπίζουμε τις προκλήσεις που η νέα χιλιετία 
φέρνει. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος γραφείων συμψηφισμού δίνει 
έμφαση στην εργασία της αλιείας NOAA. Τα θέματα 
περιλαμβάνουν τα θαλάσσια θηλαστικά, βιότοπος αλιείας, 
ψυχαγωγική αλιεία, απειλούμενα υπό εξαφάνιση είδη, εμπορικοί 
ψαράδες και περισσότερο. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στα καυτά θέματα αλιείας, τις πληροφορίες στο επίκεντρο
και άλλες ερευνητικές οργανώσεις αλιείας. Διάφορα στοές 
εικόνας και ηχητικά αρχεία των τραγουδιών φαλαινών είναι επίσης
διαθέσιμες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las industrias pesqueras oceánicas y 
atmosféricas nacionales de la administración (NOAA) se dedican a 
proteger y a preservar los recursos marinas de la vida de nuestra 
nación con la investigación científica, las industrias pesqueras 
gerencia, la aplicación, y la conservación del habitat. Las 
industrias pesqueras de NOAA son una voz principal para las industrias
pesqueras comerciales y recreacionales y continúan centrándose sus 
esfuerzos en sostener nuestros recursos marinas pues hacemos frente a 
los desafíos que el nuevo milenio trae. Este Web site de la 
cámara de compensación destaca el trabajo de las industrias 
pesqueras de NOAA. Los asuntos incluyen los mamíferos marinos, 
habitat de las industrias pesqueras, industrias pesqueras 
recreacionales, especie puesta en peligro, pescadores comerciales y 
más. Los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a asuntos calientes 
de las industrias pesqueras, a la información en el proyector y a 
otras organizaciones de investigación de las industrias pesqueras. 
Varias galerías de la imagen y ficheros audio de las canciones 
de la ballena están también disponibles.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211256</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103743</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-oceanic-and-atmospheric-administration-fisheries-homepage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
