<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108127</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108127</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>746307830</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">jQuizShow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">jQuizShow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">jQuizShow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">jQuizShow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">jQuizShow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">jQuizShow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">jQuizShow</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The jQuizShow is based on the popular "Who Wants to Be a Millionaire" TV game show. It forms the framework around which a group can play their own Millionaire-like quiz show game, with one person acting as the host, one person in the "hot seat," and with the remaining people forming the audience. Three helplines (50/50, ask a friend, and poll the audience) are available to the player. The jQuizShow is fully customizable. It is easy to add your own questions and answers to the database (or use databases others have written), change the sound effects, modify the prize levels, and more. Ideal for use in a classroom or church youth group setting, or at the start of a meeting to break the ice.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das jQuizShow basiert auf dem populären ", wer ein
Millionaire sein möchte" Fernsehapparat Spielerscheinen. Es 
bildet den Rahmen, um den eine Gruppe ihre Selbst Millionaire-wie 
Quizerscheinenspiel spielen kann, wenn eine Person als der 
Hauptrechner dient, eine Person im "heißen Sitz," und mit den 
restlichen Leuten, welche die Publikum bilden. Drei helplines 
(50/50, fragen einen Freund und stimmen die Publikum) ab, sind für 
den Spieler vorhanden. Das jQuizShow ist völlig customizable. 
Es ist einfach, Ihre eigenen Fragen und Antworten der Datenbank 
(oder den Gebrauchdatenbanken hinzuzufügen haben andere geschrieben),
ändert die stichhaltigen Effekte, ändert die prize Stufen und mehr. 
Ideal für Gebrauch in einer Klassenzimmer- oder 
Kirchejugendgruppe Einstellung oder beim Anfang einer Sitzung, das Eis
zu brechen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le jQuizShow est basé sur "qui veut être 
l'exposition populaire de jeu de TV d'un millionnaire". Il forme
le cadre autour dont un groupe peut jouer leurs propres 
Millionnaire-comme le jeu d'exposition de jeu, avec une personne 
agissant en tant que centre serveur, une personne dans "le siège 
chaud," et avec les personnes restantes formant les assistances. 
Trois services d'assistance (50/50, demandent à un ami, et votent les 
assistances) sont à la disposition du joueur. Le jQuizShow est 
entièrement customizable. Il est facile d'ajouter vos propres 
questions et réponses à la base de données (ou aux bases de 
données d'utilisation d'autres ont écrit), change les effets sains, 
modifie les niveaux professionnels, et plus. Idéal pour l'usage
dans une configuration de groupe de la jeunesse de salle de classe ou 
d'église, ou au début d'une réunion de casser la glace.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O jQuizShow é baseado "quem quer ser na mostra 
popular do jogo da tevê de um millionaire". Dá forma à 
estrutura em torno de que um grupo pode jogar seus próprios 
Millionaire-como o jogo da mostra do quiz, com a uma pessoa que age 
como o anfitrião, uma pessoa "no assento quente," e com os povos 
restantes que dão forma às audiências. Três helplines 
(50/50, perguntam a um amigo, e poll as audiências) estão 
disponíveis ao jogador. O jQuizShow é inteiramente 
customizable. É fácil adicionar suas próprias perguntas e 
respostas à base de dados (ou às bases de dados do uso outro 
escreveu), muda os efeitos sadios, modifica os níveis premiados, e 
mais. Ideal para o uso em um ajuste do grupo da juventude da 
sala de aula ou da igreja, ou no início de uma reunião quebrar o 
gelo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il jQuizShow è basato "chi desidera essere 
sull'esposizione popolare del gioco della TV del millionaire". 
Forma la struttura intorno a cui un gruppo può giocare il loro 
propri Millionaire-come il gioco di esposizione di quiz, con una 
persona che funge da calcolatore centrale, una persona "nella sede 
calda," e con la gente restante che forma i pubblici. Tre 
helplines (50/50, chiede ad un amico e vota i pubblici) sono a 
disposizione di il giocatore. Il jQuizShow è completamente 
customizable. È facile da aggiungere le vostre proprie domande 
e risposte alla base di dati (o alle basi di dati di uso altri hanno 
scritto), cambia gli effetti sani, modifica i livelli premiati e più.
Ideale per uso in una regolazione del gruppo della gioventù 
della chiesa o dell'aula, o all'inizio di una riunione rompere il 
ghiaccio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το jQuizShow είναι βασισμένο στο δημοφιλή "ποιος 
θέλουν να είναι παιχνίδι TV εκατομμυριούχοι" εμφανίζουν. 
Διαμορφώνει το πλαίσιο γύρω από το οποίο μια ομάδα μπορεί
να παίξει τους εκατομμυριούχος-όπως το διαγωνισμό γνώσεων 
εμφανίζει στο παιχνίδι, με ένα άτομο που ενεργεί ως ξένιος χ/υ, 
ένα άτομο στο "καυτό κάθισμα," και με τους υπόλοιπους ανθρώπους 
που διαμορφώνουν το ακροατήριο. Τρεις γραμμές βοήθειας (το 
50/50, ρωτά ένας φίλος, και ψηφίζει το ακροατήριο) είναι 
διαθέσιμες στο φορέα. Το jQuizShow είναι πλήρως 
εξατομικεύσιμο. Είναι εύκολο να προστεθούν οι 
ερωταποκρίσεις σας στη βάση δεδομένων (ή οι βάσεις δεδομένων 
χρήσης άλλες έχουν γράψει), να αλλαχτούν τα υγιή αποτελέσματα, 
να τροποποιηθούν τα επίπεδα βραβείων, και περισσότεροι. 
Ιδανικό για τη χρήση σε μια ομάδα νεολαίας τάξεων ή 
εκκλησιών που θέτει, ή στην έναρξη μιας συνεδρίασης για να 
σπάσει τον πάγο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El jQuizShow se basa en "quién desea ser la 
demostración popular del juego de la TV de un millonario". 
Forma el marco alrededor de el cual un grupo sabe jugar sus el 
propios Millonario-como juego de la demostración del concurso, con 
una persona actuando como el ordenador principal, una persona en el 
"asiento caliente," y con la gente restante que forma a las 
audiencias. Tres helplines (50/50, pregunta a amigo, y vota a 
audiencias) están disponibles para el jugador. El jQuizShow es 
completamente customizable. Es fácil agregar sus propias 
preguntas y respuestas a la base de datos (o a las bases de datos del 
uso otros han escrito), cambia los efectos sonoros, modifica los 
niveles premiados, y más. Ideal para el uso en una 
configuración del grupo de la juventud de la sala de clase o de la 
iglesia, o en el comienzo de una reunión de romper el hielo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:STEVE CHEN
FN:STEVE CHEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>746307830</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108127</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/jquizshow</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
