<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106505</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106505</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086998</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The national gesture."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die nationale Geste."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le geste national."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o gesto nacional."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il gesture nazionale."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η εθνική χειρονομία."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el gesto nacional."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1919, Americans ratified the 18th amendment to the Constitution, making it illegal to manufacture, sell, transport, import, or export drinking alcohol. Prohibition, as it was popularly known, proved impossible to enforce, as tens of millions of normally law-abiding Americans either broke the law or abetted those who did. Although the consumption of alcohol did decline, opponents of Prohibition argued that it engendered crime, corruption, and a disregard for law. Organized crime flourished around the profits to be made from selling illegal alcohol, and politicians and police were bought off wholesale. Bribery and corruption, although not always alcohol related, reached into President Harding's cabinetand then onto the front page. This 1926 cartoon by Clive Weed in the satirical weekly  Judge  comments on the escalation of governmental corruption during Prohibition.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1919 bestätigten Amerikaner die 18. Änderung zur 
Beschaffenheit und bildeten sie ungültig, trinkenden Spiritus 
herzustellen, zu verkaufen, zu transportieren, zu importieren oder zu 
exportieren. Verbot, während es populär bekannt, 
nachgewiesenes unmögliches, als 10 Millionen der normalerweise 
gesetzestreu Amerikaner zu erzwingen entweder brach das Gesetz oder 
ermutigte die, die. Obgleich der Verbrauch von Spiritus sank, 
argumentierten Konkurrenten des Verbots, daß er Verbrechen, 
Korruption und eine Mißachtung für Gesetz erzeugte. 
Organisiertes Verbrechen blühte um die vom Verkaufen gebildet 
zu werden Profite, des ungültigen Spiritus, und Politiker und Polizei
wurde weg vom Großverkauf gekauft. Bestechung und Korruption, 
obgleich nicht immer Spiritus in Verbindung stand, erreichten in 
Präsident Hardings cabinetand dann auf die Vorderseite. Diese 
Karikatur 1926 durch Clive Weed im satirical wöchentlichen Richter 
kommentiert die Eskalation von Regierungskorruption während des 
Verbots.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1919, les Américains ont ratifié le 18ème amendement
à la constitution, le rendant illégal pour fabriquer, vendre, 
transporter, importer, ou exporter l'alcool potable. La 
prohibition, pendant qu'on le connaissait populairement, impossible 
prouvé pour imposer, comme dizaines de millions d'Américains 
normalement respectueux des lois a violé la loi ou a encouragé ceux 
qui . Bien que la consommation de l'alcool ait diminué, les 
adversaires de la prohibition ont argué du fait qu'elle a engendré 
le crime, la corruption, et une négligence pour la loi. Le 
crime organisé s'est épanoui autour des bénéfices à faire à 
partir de vendre l'alcool illégal, et des politiciens et la police 
ont été achetés outre de la vente en gros. Le corruption et 
la corruption, bien que pas toujours l'alcool ait associé, ont 
atteint dans le cabinetand du Président Harding's puis sur la page 
avant. Ce dessin animé 1926 par Clive Weed dans le juge 
hebdomadaire satirique présente ses observations sur l'escalade de la
corruption gouvernementale pendant la prohibition.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1919, os americanos ratificaram a 1å emenda ao 
constitution, fazendo a ilegal para manufaturar, vender, transportar, 
importar, ou exportar o álcool bebendo. A proibição, enquanto
se soube popular, impossível provado reforçar, como dez dos milhões
de americanos normalmente law-abiding quebrou a lei ou abetted aquelas
que . Embora o consumo do álcool declinasse, os oponentes da 
proibição discutiram que engendered o crime, o corruption, e uma 
negligência para a lei. O crime organizado floresceu em torno 
dos lucros a ser feitos de vender o álcool ilegal, e os políticos e 
as polícias foram comprados fora da venda por atacado. O 
bribery e o corruption, embora não sempre o álcool se relacionasse, 
alcançaram no cabinetand do presidente Harding então na página 
dianteira. Este cartoon 1926 por Clive Erva daninha no juiz 
semanal satirical comenta no escalation do corruption governamental 
durante a proibição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1919, gli Americani hanno ratificato la diciottesima 
correzione alla costituzione, rendente la illegale per produrre, 
vendere, trasportare, importare, o esportare l'alcool bevente. 
La proibizione, mentre è stato conosciuto popolare, impossible 
provato fare rispettare, come dieci di milioni di Americani 
normalmente law-abiding ha infranto la legge o ha incoraggiato coloro 
che. Anche se il consumo di alcool ha declinato, gli avversari 
della proibizione hanno sostenuto che ha generato il crimine, la 
corruzione e una negligenza per legge. Il crimine organizzato è
fiorito intorno ai profitti da fare dal vendere l'alcool illegale ed i
politici e la polizia sono stati comprati fuori del commercio 
all'ingrosso. La corruzione e la corruzione, anche se l'alcool 
si è riferito non sempre, hanno raggiunto nel cabinetand del 
presidente Harding allora sulla pagina anteriore. Questo fumetto
1926 da Clive Weed nel giudice settimanale satirical commenta 
l'escalation della corruzione governativa durante la proibizione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1919, Αμερικανοί επικύρωσαν τη 18$η τροποποίηση 
στο σύνταγμα, που καθιστά το παράνομο να κατασκευάσουν, να 
πωλήσουν, να μεταφέρουν, να εισαγάγουν, ή εξάγουν το οινόπνευμα 
κατανάλωσης. Η απαγόρευση, δεδομένου ότι ήταν γενικά 
γνωστή, αποδειγμένος αδύνατη να επιβάλει, ως δεκάδες των 
εκατομμυρίων κανονικά νομοταγών Αμερικανών είτε παρέβη το νόμο 
είτε υποκίνησε εκείνων που. Αν και η κατανάλωση 
οινοπνεύματος μειώθηκε, οι αντίπαλοι της απαγόρευσης υποστήριξαν 
ότι προκάλεσε το έγκλημα, τη δωροδοκία, και μια αμέλεια για το 
νόμο. Το οργανωμένο έγκλημα άκμασε γύρω από τα κέρδη που 
γίνονται από την πώληση του παράνομου οινοπνεύματος, και οι 
πολιτικοί και η αστυνομία αγοράστηκαν από το χονδρικό εμπόριο. 
Η δωροδοκία και η δωροδοκία, αν και όχι πάντα το οινόπνευμα
αφορούσε, έφθασαν στον Πρόεδρο Harding's cabinetand έπειτα 
επάνω πρώτη σελίδα. Αυτά τα κινούμενα σχέδια του 1926 από 
Clive Weed στο σατυρικό εβδομαδιαίο δικαστή σχολιάζουν την 
κλιμάκωση της κυβερνητικής δωροδοκίας κατά τη διάρκεια της 
απαγόρευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1919, los americanos ratificaron la décimo octava 
enmienda a la constitución, haciéndola ilegal fabricar, vender, 
transportar, importar, o exportar el alcohol que bebía. La 
prohibición, como era sabido popular, imposible probada hacer 
cumplir, como diez de millones de americanos normalmente observantes 
de la ley rompió la ley o incitó a los que lo hicieron. Aunque
la consumición del alcohol declinó, los opositores de la 
prohibición discutieron que engendrara crimen, la corrupción, y una 
indiferencia para la ley. El crimen ordenado prosperó alrededor
de los beneficios que se harán de vender el alcohol ilegal, y 
compraron a los políticos y al policía de venta al por mayor. 
El soborno y la corrupción, aunque el alcohol se relacionó no 
siempre, alcanzaron en cabinetand de presidente Harding entonces sobre
la paginación delantera. Esta historieta 1926 de Clive Weed en 
el juez semanal satírico comenta respecto a la escalada de la 
corrupción gubernamental durante la prohibición.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086998</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106505</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-national-gesture</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
