<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108401</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108401</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204645</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The African American Experience in NC after Reconstruction</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die afrikanische amerikanische Erfahrung in NC 
nach Rekonstruktion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'expérience américaine africaine de l'OR après
reconstruction</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A experiência americana africana no NC após o 
reconstruction</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'esperienza americana africana di NC dopo 
ricostruzione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αφρικανική αμερικανική εμπειρία σε NC μετά από 
την αναδημιουργία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La experiencia americana africana en el NC 
después de la reconstrucción</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The documents included in this lesson come from The North Carolina Experience collection of Documenting the American South and specifically focus on African Americans and race relations in the early 20th century. The lesson juxtaposes accounts that relate to both the positive improvements of black society and arguments against advancement. Combined, these primary sources and the accompanying lesson plan could be used as a Document Based Question (DBQ) in an advanced US history or African American history course.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Dokumente, die in dieser Lektion 
eingeschlossen sind, kommen von der Nord-Carolina Erfahrung Ansammlung
des Dokumentierens des amerikanischen Südens und spezifisch des Fokus
auf afrikanischen Amerikanern und von den Rennenrelationen im frühen 
20. Jahrhundert. Die Lektion hält Konten gegeneinander, die auf
beiden positiven Verbesserungen der schwarzen Gesellschaft und der 
Argumente gegen Zuführung in Verbindung stehen. Kombiniert, 
konnten diese Primärquellen und der angeschlossene Lektionplan als 
Dokument gegründete Frage (DBQ) in einer hochentwickelten US 
Geschichte oder afrikanischen amerikanischen in einem Geschichte Kurs 
verwendet werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les documents inclus dans cette leçon viennent de
la collection du nord d'expérience de la Caroline de documenter 
les Sud et spécifiquement le foyer américains sur les 
Américains africains et des relations inter-raciales en début du 
20ème siècle. La leçon juxtapose les comptes qui associent 
les aux deux les améliorations positives de la société et des 
arguments noirs contre l'avancement. Combinées, ces sources 
primaires et le plan d'accompagnement de leçon pourraient être 
utilisés comme question basée par document (DBQ) dans une histoire 
avançée des USA ou un cours américain africain d'histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os originais incluídos nesta lição vêm da 
coleção da experiência de North.carolina de documentar o sul e 
especificamente o foco americanos em americanos africanos e das 
relações de raça no 20o século adiantado. A lição 
juxtaposes os clientes que se relacionam a ambas as melhorias 
positivas da sociedade e de argumentos pretos de encontro ao avanço. 
Combinadas, estas fontes preliminares e a planta acompanhando da
lição poderiam ser usadas como uma pergunta baseada original (DBQ) 
em um history avançado dos E. U. ou em um curso americano africano do
history.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I documenti inclusi in questa lezione vengono 
dalla raccolta di esperienza del North.carolina di documentazione il 
sud e specificamente del fuoco americani sugli Americani africani e 
dai rapporti di corsa nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo. La lezione
juxtaposes i clienti che si riferiscono agli entrambi miglioramenti 
positivi della società e degli argomenti neri contro l'avanzamento. 
Unite, queste sorgenti primarie ed il programma accompagnante di
lezione potrebbero essere usati come domanda basata documento (DBQ) in
una storia avanzata degli Stati Uniti o in un corso americano africano
di storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα έγγραφα που περιλαμβάνονται σε αυτό το μάθημα 
προέρχονται από τη συλλογή εμπειρίας της βόρειας Καρολίνας της 
τεκμηρίωσης του αμερικανικού νότου και εστιάζουν συγκεκριμένα σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς και τις φυλετικές σχέσεις στις αρχές του
20ού αιώνα. Το μάθημα αντιπαραβαεται τους απολογισμούς που 
αφορούν και τις θετικές βελτιώσεις της μαύρης κοινωνίας και τα 
ορίσματα ενάντια στην πρόοδο. Συνδυασμένες, αυτές οι 
αρχικές πηγές και το συνοδευτικό σχέδιο μαθήματος θα μπορούσαν 
να χρησιμοποιηθούν ως βασισμένη στο έγγραφο ερώτηση (DBQ) σε 
μια προηγμένη αμερικανική ιστορία ή μια αφρικανική αμερικανική 
σειρά μαθημάτων ιστορίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los documentos incluidos en esta lección vienen 
de la colección de la experiencia de Carolina del Norte de documentar
el sur y específicamente el foco americanos en americanos africanos y
de relaciones de raza en el vigésimo siglo temprano. La 
lección juxtaposes las cuentas que se relacionan con ambas las 
mejoras positivas de la sociedad y de argumentos negros contra el 
adelanto. Combinadas, estas fuentes primarias y el plan de 
acompañamiento de la lección se podrían utilizar como pregunta 
basada documento (DBQ) en una historia avanzada de los E.E.U.U. o un 
curso americano africano de la historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MEGHAN MCGLINN
FN:MEGHAN MCGLINN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204645</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108401</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-african-american-experience-in-nc-after-reconstruction</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
