<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108308</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108308</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087372</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"All These Mean Dykes Standing Around:"Shelley Ettinger Describes the Lesbian and Gay Community of the 1970s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"alles beschreibt diese die Mittel-Dämme, die 
Around:"Shelley Ettinger stehen, die lesbische und homosexuelle 
Gemeinschaft der siebziger Jahre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"tout ceux-ci des digues de moyen tenant 
Around:"Shelley Ettinger décrit la Communauté lesbienne et gaie des 
années 70</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"todo o estes os dykes do meio que estão 
Around:"Shelley Ettinger descrevem a comunidade lesbian e gay dos 
1970s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tutto questi dykes di media che si levano in 
piedi Around:"Shelley Ettinger descrivono la lesbica e la Comunità di
Gay degli anni 70</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όλα αυτά σημαίνουν ότι τα αναχώματα που στέκονται 
Around:"Shelley Ettinger περιγράφουν τη λεσβιακή και 
ομοφυλοφιλική Κοινότητα της δεκαετίας του '70</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"todo el éstos los diques del medio que están 
parado Around:"Shelley Ettinger describen a comunidad lesbiana y 
Gay de los años 70</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The women's movement of the 1970's sent shock-waves through every corner of American life, transforming the way people thought about families, jobs, and every day interactions. By questioning traditional sex roles, feminism also encouraged the growth of the gay and lesbian rights movement. Previously, many gay men and lesbians had concealed their sexuality, but the 1970's witnessed the growth of assertive and visible gay and lesbian alternative cultures. As a college student at the University of Michigan and a union activist within the city bus company, Shelley Ettinger remembered living and participating in an active, assertive lesbian culture during the mid-1970's. Although gay men and lesbians still faced harassment and discrimination, they were no longer afraid to express their identities or to speak out against bias and discrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Bewegung der Frauen der siebziger Jahre 
sendete Shock-waves durch jede Ecke der amerikanischen Lebensdauer und
wandelte die Methode Leute um, die an Familien gedacht wurden, die 
Jobs und die jeden Tagesinteraktionen. Durch fragende 
traditionelle Geschlechtrollen regte der Feminismus auch das Wachstum 
der homosexuellen und Lesbierrechtbewegung an. Vorher hatten 
viele homosexuelle Männer und Lesbier ihre Sexualität verborgen, 
aber die siebziger Jahre zeugten das Wachstum der assertive und 
sichtbaren homosexuellen und lesbischen alternativen Kulturen. 
Als Student an der Universität von Michigan und 
Anschlußaktivist innerhalb der Stadtbusfirma, Shelley Ettinger 
erinnerten des Lebens und des Teilnehmens an einer aktiven, assertive 
lesbischen Kultur während der Mitte der 70-iger Jahre. Obgleich
homosexuell Männer und gegenübergestellte Belästigung und 
Unterscheidung der Lesbier noch, hatten sie nicht mehr Angst, ihre 
Identitäten auszudrücken oder heraus gegen Vorspannung und 
Unterscheidung zu sprechen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement des femmes des années 70 a envoyé 
des ondes de choc par chaque coin de vie américaine, transformant les
personnes de voie pensées aux familles, les travaux, et des 
interactions de chaque jour. Par des rôles traditionnels 
d'interrogation de sexe, le féminisme a également encouragé la 
croissance du mouvement gai et de lesbienne de droits. 
Précédemment, beaucoup d'hommes et lesbiennes gais avaient 
caché leur sexualité, mais les années 70 étaient témoin de la 
croissance des cultures alternatives gaies et lesbiennes autoritaires 
et visibles. En tant qu'un étudiant d'université à 
l'université du Michigan et activiste des syndicats dans la compagnie
de bus de ville, la vie retrouvée par Ettinger de Shelley et 
participer à une culture lesbienne active et autoritaire pendant le 
milieu des années 70. Bien que gai des hommes et harcèlement et 
discrimination toujours faits face de lesbiennes, il n'avait plus peur
pour exprimer leurs identités ou pour parler dehors contre la 
polarisation et la discrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento das mulheres dos 1970's emitiu 
shock-waves através de cada canto da vida americana, transformando os
povos da maneira pensados sobre famílias, trabalhos, e interações 
de cada dia. Por papéis tradicionais questionando do sexo, o 
feminismo incentivou também o crescimento do movimento gay e do 
lesbian das direitas. Previamente, muitos homens e lesbians gay 
tinham escondido seu sexuality, mas os 1970's testemunharam o 
crescimento de culturas alternativas gay e lesbian assertive e 
visíveis. Como um estudante de faculdade na universidade de 
Michigan e uma activista da união dentro da companhia de 
barra-ônibus da cidade, de viver recordado Ettinger de Shelley e de 
participar em uma cultura lesbian ativa, assertive durante os 
mid-1970's. Embora gay homens e harassment e discriminação 
ainda enfrentados dos lesbians, estavam uns receosos não mais longo 
expressar suas identidades ou falar para fora de encontro à 
polarização e à discriminação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento delle donne degli anni 70 ha 
trasmesso gli shock-waves attraverso ogni angolo di vita americana, 
trasformante la gente di modo pensata alle famiglie, i lavori e le 
interazioni di ogni giorno. Dai ruoli tradizionali interroganti 
del sesso, il feminism egualmente ha consigliato allo sviluppo del 
movimento di diritti della lesbica e di gay. 
Precedentemente, molti uomini di gay e lesbiche avevano 
celato il loro sexuality, ma gli anni 70 hanno testimoniato lo 
sviluppo delle colture assertive e visibili di alternativa della 
lesbica e di gay. Come un allievo di università 
all'università de Michigan e attivista del sindacato in seno 
all'azienda di bus della città, Shelley Ettinger si è ricordato di 
vivere e partecipare ad una coltura lesbica attiva e assertive durante
i mid-1970's. Anche se gli uomini di gay ed il 
harassment e la distinzione ancora affrontati delle lesbiche, non 
erano più impauriti esprimere le loro identità o parlare fuori 
contro polarizzazione e distinzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κίνημα των γυναικών της δεκαετίας του '70 έστειλε 
shock-waves μέσω κάθε γωνίας της αμερικανικής ζωής, που 
μετασχηματίζει τους ανθρώπους τρόπων σκεπτόμενους για τις 
οικογένειες, τις εργασίες, και τις αλληλεπιδράσεις κάθε ημέρας. 
Με την επερώτηση των παραδοσιακών ρόλων φύλων, ο φεμινισμός
ενθάρρυνε επίσης την αύξηση του ομοφυλοφιλικού και λεσβιακού 
κινήματος δικαιωμάτων. Προηγουμένως, πολλές ομοφυλοφιλικές 
άτομα και λεσβίες είχαν κρύψει τη σεξουαλικότητά τους, αλλά η 
δεκαετία του '70 βεβαίωσε την αύξηση των κατηγορηματικών και 
ορατών ομοφυλοφιλικών και λεσβιακών εναλλακτικών πολιτισμών. 
Σαν σπουδαστή κολλεγίων στο πανεπιστήμιο του Μίτσιγκαν και 
ένα ενεργό στέλεχος ένωσης μέσα στην επιχείρηση διαδρόμων 
πόλεων, Shelley Ettinger θυμήθηκε και σε έναν ενεργό, 
κατηγορηματικό λεσβιακό πολιτισμό κατά τη διάρκεια τα μέσα 
τησδεκαετίας του '70. Αν και τα ομοφυλοφιλικές άτομα και οι 
λεσβίες αντιμετώπισαν ακόμα την παρενόχληση και τη διάκριση, δεν 
ήταν πλέον φοβισμένα να εκφράσουν τις ταυτότητές τους ή να 
μιλήσουν έξω ενάντια στην πόλωση και τη διάκριση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento de las mujeres de los años 70 
envió ondas de choque a través de cada esquina de la vida americana,
transformando la gente de la manera pensada de las familias, trabajos,
e interacciones de cada día. Por papeles tradicionales del sexo
que preguntaban, el feminismo también animó el crecimiento del 
movimiento de las derechas del gay y de la lesbiana. 
Previamente, muchos hombres y lesbianas gays habían 
encubierto su sexualidad, pero los años 70 atestiguaron el 
crecimiento de las culturas asertivas y visibles del alternativa del 
gay y de la lesbiana. Como un estudiante de universidad 
en la universidad de Michigan y activista de la unión dentro de la 
compañía de megabus de la ciudad, de vivir recordado Ettinger de 
Shelley y de participar en una cultura lesbiana activa, asertiva 
durante los mediados de los años setenta. Aunque es gay 
los hombres y hostigamiento y discriminación todavía hechos frente 
de las lesbianas, estaban asustados no más largo expresar sus 
identidades o hablar hacia fuera contra diagonal y la discriminación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087372</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108308</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/all-these-mean-dykes-standing-around-shelley-ettinger-describes-the-lesbian-and-gay-community-of-the-1970s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
