<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104814</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104814</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202794</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lunsford Lane: A Slave in North Carolina Who Buys His Freedom</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lunsford Weg: Ein Sklave in Nord-Carolina, 
das seine Freiheit kauft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ruelle de Lunsford : Un Slave en 
Caroline du nord qui achète sa liberté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pista De Lunsford: Um escravo em 
North.carolina que compra sua liberdade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vicolo Di Lunsford: Uno schiavo in 
North.carolina che compra la sua libertà</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάροδος Lunsford: Ένας σκλάβος στη βόρεια 
Καρολίνα που αγοράζει την ελευθερία του</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Carril De Lunsford: Un esclavo en Carolina 
del Norte que compra su libertad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Lunsford Lane's story is about a slave who lives in Raleigh, North Carolina. Though his master owns as many as three plantations outside of Raleigh, Mr. Lane is not a plantation slave. Rather, he works for his master in the city-dwelling. His story provides an example of an ingenious, determined, and disciplined slave who's vision and creativity affords him the opportunity to earn money and eventually buy his freedom. This is an incredible story.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichte des Lunsford Wegs ist über einen 
Sklaven, der in Raleigh, Nord-Carolina wohnt. Obwohl sein 
Meister bis zu wie drei Plantagen außerhalb Raleigh besitzt, ist Herr
Lane nicht ein Plantagesklave. Eher arbeitet er für seinen 
Meister in der Stadt-Wohnung. Seine Geschichte liefert ein 
Beispiel von einem scharfsinnigen, entschlossen, und disziplinierter 
Sklave, der Anblick und Kreativität hat, leistet sich ihn die 
Gelegenheit, Geld zu erwerben und seine Freiheit schließlich zu 
kaufen. Dieses ist eine unglaubliche Geschichte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'histoire de la ruelle de Lunsford est au sujet 
d'un slave qui habite dans Raleigh, Caroline du nord. 
Bien que son maître possède l'autant d'en tant que trois 
plantations en dehors de de Raleigh, M. Lane n'est pas une plantation 
slave. Plutôt, il travaille pour son maître dans le 
ville-logement. Son histoire fournit un exemple d'un ingénieux,
déterminé, et qui a la vision et la créativité slaves 
disciplinées l'a les moyens l'occasion de gagner l'argent et 
d'acheter par la suite sa liberté. C'est une histoire 
incroyable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A história da pista de Lunsford é sobre um 
escravo que viva em Raleigh, North.carolina. Embora seu mestre 
possui o tanto como como três plantações fora de Raleigh, o Sr. 
Pista não é um escravo da plantação. Rather, trabalha para 
seu mestre na cidade-moradia. Sua história fornece um exemplo 
de um ingenious, determinado, e o escravo disciplinado que tem a 
visão e a creatividade tem-no recursos para a oportunidade de ganhar 
o dinheiro e de comprar eventualmente sua liberdade. Esta é uma
história incredible.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La storia del vicolo di Lunsford è circa uno 
schiavo che vive in Raleigh, North.carolina. Benchè il suo 
supervisore possieda l'altretanto come tre piantagioni fuori di 
Raleigh, il sig. Lane non è uno schiavo della piantagione. 
Piuttosto, lavora per il suo supervisore nella città-dimora. 
La sua storia fornisce un esempio di un ingenious, risoluto e lo
schiavo disciplinato che ha la visione e creatività se lo permette 
l'occasione guadagnare i soldi e finalmente comprare la sua libertà. 
Ciò è una storia incredibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιστορία της παρόδου Lunsford είναι για έναν 
σκλάβο που ζει σε Raleigh, βόρεια Καρολίνα. Αν και ο 
κύριός του είναι κύριος τουλάχιστον τρεις φυτείες έξω από 
Raleigh, ο κ. Lane δεν είναι σκλάβος φυτειών. Μάλλον, 
εργάζεται για τον κύριό του στην πόλη-κατοικία. Η ιστορία 
του παρέχει ένα παράδειγμα ενός έξυπνου, καθορισμένος, και 
πειθαρχημένος σκλάβος που το όραμα και η δημιουργικότητα αντέχουν
οικονομικά του στην ευκαιρία να κερδηθούν τα χρήματα και να 
αγοραστεί τελικά η ελευθερία του. Αυτό είναι μια απίστευτη
ιστορία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La historia del carril de Lunsford está sobre un 
esclavo que viva en Raleigh, Carolina del Norte. Aunque su amo 
posee tanto como tres plantaciones fuera de Raleigh, Sr. Lane no es un
esclavo de la plantación. Algo, él trabaja para su amo en la 
ciudad-vivienda. Su historia proporciona a un ejemplo de un 
ingenioso, resuelto, y el esclavo disciplinado que tiene la visión y 
creatividad lo produce la oportunidad de ganar el dinero y de comprar 
eventual su libertad. Esto es una historia increíble.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOHN SCHAEFER
FN:JOHN SCHAEFER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:VICTORIA SCHAEFER
FN:VICTORIA SCHAEFER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202794</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104814</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lunsford-lane-a-slave-in-north-carolina-who-buys-his-freedom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
