<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105886</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105886</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086987</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Meeting Continued All Night, Both by the White &amp; Black People": Georgia Camp Meeting, 1807</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Sitzung setzte alle Nacht, durch die weißen 
u. schwarzen Leute" fort: Georgia Lager-Sitzung, 1807</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la réunion s'est poursuivie toute la nuit, par 
les personnes blanches et noires" : Réunion de Camp de la 
Géorgie, 1807</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a reunião continuou toda a noite,  pelos povos 
brancos &amp; pretos": Reunião Do Acampamento De Geórgia, 1807</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la riunione ha continuato tutta la notte, sia 
dalla gente bianca &amp; nera": Riunione Dell'Accampamento Della 
Georgia, 1807</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η συνεδρίαση συνεχίστηκε όλη τη νύχτα, και από τους 
λευκούς &amp; μαύρους ανθρώπουσ": Συνεδρίαση των στρατόπεδων 
της Γεωργίας, 1807</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la reunión continuó toda la noche, por la gente
blanca y negra": Reunión Del Campo De Georgia, 1807</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Camp meetings such as this one, held near Sparta, Georgia, in 1807, were a manifestation of the nationwide Second Great Awakening of the early 19th century. The Second Great Awakening was an evangelical religious revival conducted by Baptists, Methodists, and other dissenting Protestant sects. Evangelical religion was often described as "enthusiastic," and people attending expressed their feelings through spontaneous movements and speech. Like the first Great Awakening of the 18th century, the Second Great Awakening was notably egalitarian, with men, women, blacks, and poor whites mingling together in worship.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lagersitzungen wie diese, angehalten nahe Sparta, 
Georgia, 1807, waren eine Äusserung des allgemein zweiten großen 
Weckens des frühen 19. Jahrhunderts. Das zweite große Wecken 
war eine evangelische fromme Wiederbelebung, die durch Baptists, 
Methodisten und andere nicht übereinstimmende protestierende sects 
geleitet wurde. Evangelische Religion wurde häufig beschrieben,
wie "enthusiastisch," und das Leutebeachten ihre Gefühle durch 
spontane Bewegungen und Rede ausdrückte. Wie das erste große 
Wecken des 18. Jahrhunderts, war das zweite große Wecken, mit 
Männern, die Frauen vornehmlich gleichmacherisch, Schwarze, und 
schlechtes Weiß zusammen vermischend in der Anbetung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les réunions de camp telles que celle-ci, tenu 
près de Sparta, la Géorgie, en 1807, étaient une manifestation du 
deuxième grand réveil dans tout le pays du 19ème siècle tôt. 
Le deuxième grand réveil était une renaissance religieuse 
évangélique conduite par Baptists, méthodistes, et d'autres sects 
protestants différants d'opinion. La religion évangélique a 
été souvent décrite comme "enthousiaste," et être présent de 
personnes a exprimé leurs sentiments par les mouvements et le 
discours spontanés. Comme le premier grand réveil du 18ème 
siècle, le deuxième grand réveil était notamment égalitaire, avec
les hommes, des femmes, noir, et blancs pâles se mélangeant ensemble
dans le culte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As reuniões do acampamento tais como esta, 
prendido perto de Sparta, Geórgia, em 1807, eram um manifestation do 
segundo awakening grande de âmbito nacional do 1ø século adiantado.
Segundo awakening grande era um revival religioso evangelical 
conduzido por Baptists, por methodists, e por outros sects protestant 
dissenting. A religião evangelical foi descrita frequentemente 
como "entusiástico," e atender dos povos expressou seus sentimentos 
com os movimentos e o discurso espontâneos. Como primeiro 
awakening grande do 18o século, segundo awakening grande era 
notàvelmente egalitarian, com homens, as mulheres, preto, e brancos 
deficientes mingling junto na adoração.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le riunioni dell'accampamento come questa, 
tenutasi vicino a Sparta, la Georgia, in 1807, erano una 
manifestazione del secondo risveglio grande nazionale del 
diciannovesimo secolo in anticipo. Il secondo risveglio grande 
era una rinascita religiosa evangelical condotta da battista, dai 
methodists e da altri sects protestanti dissenting. La religione
evangelical è stata descritta spesso come "entusiastico," ed 
assistere della gente ha espresso le loro sensibilità con i movimenti
ed il discorso spontanei. Come il primo risveglio grande del 
diciottesimo secolo, il secondo risveglio grande era considerevolmente
egalitario, con gli uomini, donne, neri ed i poveri bianchi 
mescolanti insieme nel culto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συνεδριάσεις των στρατόπεδων όπως αυτή, κράτησαν 
κοντά σε Sparta, Γεωργία, το 1807, ήταν μια εκδήλωση του σε 
εθνικό επίπεδο δεύτερου μεγάλου ξυπνήματος του πρόωρου 19$ου 
αιώνα. Το δεύτερο μεγάλο ξύπνημα ήταν μια εβαγγελική 
θρησκευτική αναγέννηση που διευθύνθηκε από Baptists, 
Methodists, και άλλα προτεσταντικά sects διαφωνίας. Η 
εβαγγελική θρησκεία περιγράφηκε συχνά όπως "ενθουσιώδης," και η 
παρουσία ανθρώπων εξέφρασε τα συναισθήματά τους μέσω των 
αυθόρμητων μετακινήσεων και της ομιλίας. Όπως το πρώτο 
μεγάλο ξύπνημα του 18$ου αιώνα, το δεύτερο μεγάλο ξύπνημα ήταν 
ειδικότερα egalitarian, με τους άνδρες, τις γυναίκες, τους 
Μαύρους, και τα φτωχά λευκά ανακατεύοντας μαζί στη λατρεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las reuniones del campo tales como ésta, 
sostenido cerca de Sparta, Georgia, en 1807, eran una manifestación 
de segundo gran despertar a nivel nacional del diecinueveavo siglo 
temprano. El segundo gran despertar era un renacimiento 
religioso evangélico conducido por Baptists, los methodists, y otros 
sects protestantes dissenting. La religión evangélica fue 
descrita a menudo como "entusiástico," y el atender de la gente 
expresó sus sensaciones con los movimientos y el discurso 
espontáneos. Como primer gran despertar del décimo octavo 
siglo, el segundo gran despertar era notablemente igualitario, con los
hombres, las mujeres, los negros, y los blancos pobres mezclando junto
en la adoración.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086987</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105886</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-meeting-continued-all-night-both-by-the-white-black-people-georgia-camp-meeting-1807</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
