<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107454</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107454</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206219</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Modeling for Understanding in Science and Technology Education (MUSE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Formung für das Verstehen in der Wissenschaft und
in der Technologie-Ausbildung (MUSE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Modeler pour l'Arrangement en la Science et 
éducation de technologie (MUSE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Modelar para compreender na ciência e na 
instrução da tecnologia (MUSE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modellando per capire nella scienza e 
nell'educazione di tecnologia (MUSE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαμόρφωση για την κατανόηση στην εκπαίδευση επιστήμης
και τεχνολογίας (ΜΟΥΣΑ)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El modelar para entender en la ciencia y la 
educación de la tecnología (MUSE)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers instructional units in earth-moon-sun dynamics and natural selection. These units were produced though a collaborative project involving university researchers, high school teachers, and students. Each unit contains extensive information and materials for use in middle or high school.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">anweisende Maßeinheiten der Angebote in der 
Masse-Mond-Sonne Dynamik und in der natürlichen Auswahl. Diesen
Maßeinheiten wurden zwar ein gemeinschaftliches Projekt produziert, 
das Universitätsforscher, High School Lehrer und Kursteilnehmer mit 
einbezieht. Jede Maßeinheit enthält umfangreiche Informationen
und Materialien für Gebrauch in der mittleren oder High School.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">unités d'instruction d'offres dans la dynamique 
du terre-lune-soleil et la sélection normale. Ces unités ont 
été produites cependant un projet de collaboration faisant 
participer des chercheurs d'université, des professeurs de lycée, et
des étudiants. Chaque unité contient l'information et les 
matériaux étendus pour l'usage dans le lycée moyen ou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">unidades instrutivas das ofertas na dinâmica do 
terra-lua-sol e na seleção natural. Estas unidades foram 
produzidas though um projeto collaborative que envolve investigadores 
da universidade, professores da High School, e estudantes. Cada 
unidade contem a informação e materiais extensivos para o uso na 
High School média ou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">unità didattiche di offerte nei dynamics del 
terra-luna-sole e nella selezione naturale. Queste unità sono 
state prodotte comunque un progetto di collaborazione che fa 
partecipare i ricercatori dell'università, gli insegnanti della High 
School e gli allievi. Ogni unità contiene le vasti informazioni
e materiali per uso in High School centrale o.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εκπαιδευτικές μονάδες προσφορών στη δυναμική 
γη-φεγγάρι-ήλιων και τη φυσική επιλογή. Αυτές οι μονάδες 
παρήχθησαν αν και ένα συνεργασίας πρόγραμμα που περιλαμβάνει τους
πανεπιστημιακούς ερευνητές, τους δασκάλους γυμνασίου, και τους 
σπουδαστές. Κάθε μονάδα περιέχει τις εκτενείς πληροφορίες 
και τα υλικά για τη χρήση στη μέση ή το γυμνάσιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">unidades educacionales de las ofertas en 
dinámicas del tierra-luna-sol y la selección natural. Estas 
unidades fueron producidas sin embargo un proyecto de colaboración 
que implicaba investigadores de la universidad, profesores de la High 
School secundaria, y a estudiantes. Cada unidad contiene la 
información y los materiales extensos para el uso en High School 
media o secundaria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206219</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107454</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/modeling-for-understanding-in-science-and-technology-education-muse</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
