<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105497</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105497</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206784</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Puerto Rico at the Dawn of the Modern Age, 1831-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Puerto Rico an der Dämmerung des modernen Alters,
1831-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Porto Rico à l'aube de l'âge moderne, 
1831-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Puerto Rico no alvorecer da idade moderna, 
1831-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Porto Rico all'alba dell'età moderna, 
1831-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πουέρτο Ρίκο στην αυγή της σύγχρονης ηλικίας, 
1831-1929</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Puerto Rico en el amanecer de la edad moderna, 
1831-1929</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">portrays the early history of the commonwealth of Puerto Rico through first-person accounts, political writings, and histories drawn from the Library of Congress's general collections. Among the topics it highlights are the land and its resources, relations with Spain, competition among political parties, reform efforts, and recollections by veterans of the Spanish-American War.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schildert die Frühgeschichte des Commonwealth von
Puerto Rico durch Erstperson Konten, politische Schreiben, und 
Geschichten gezeichnet von der Bibliothek der allgemeinen Ansammlungen
des Kongresses. Unter den Themen, die sie markiert, sind das 
Land und seine Betriebsmittel, Relationen mit Spanien, Konkurrenz 
unter politischen Parteien, Verbesserungbemühungen und 
Erinnerungen durch Veterane des Spanisch-Amerikanischen Krieges.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dépeint l'histoire des débuts du Commonwealth du
Porto Rico par des comptes de premier-personne, des écritures 
politiques, et des histoires tiré de la bibliothèque des collections
générales du congrès. Parmi les sujets qu'elle met en valeur 
sont la terre et ses ressources, relations avec l'Espagne, concurrence
parmi les parties, les efforts de réforme, et les souvenirs 
politiques par des vétérans de la guerre Espagnol-Américaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">portrays o history adiantado da comunidade de 
Puerto Rico com os clientes da primeiro-pessoa, as escritas 
políticas, e os histories desenhada da biblioteca de coleções 
gerais do congress. Entre os tópicos que destaca são a terra e
seus recursos, relações com Spain, competição entre partidos, 
esforços da reforma, e recollections políticos por veterans da 
guerra Espanhol-Americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ritrae la storia remota del commonwealth del Porto
Rico con i clienti della primo-persona, le scritture politiche ed i 
dati storici dissipato dalla libreria delle collezioni generali del 
congresso. Fra i soggetti che evidenzia sono la terra e le 
relative risorse, rapporti con la Spagna, concorrenza fra i partiti, 
gli sforzi di riforma ed i ricordi politici dai veterani della guerra 
Spagnolo-Americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">απεικονίζει την πρόωρη ιστορία της Κοινοπολιτείας του 
Πουέρτο Ρίκο μέσω των απολογισμών πρώτος-προσώπων, των 
πολιτικών γραφών, και των ιστοριών που προέρχονται από τις 
γενικές συλλογές βιβλιοθήκης του συνεδρίου. Μεταξύ των 
θεμάτων κυριώτερα σημεία είναι το έδαφος και τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς του, σχέσεις με την Ισπανία, ανταγωνισμός μεταξύ των
πολιτικών κομμάτων, των προσπαθειών μεταρρύθμισης, και των 
αναμνήσεων από τους παλαιμάχους του spanish-American πολέμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">retrata la historia temprana de la Commonwealth de
Puerto Rico con cuentas de la primero-persona, escrituras políticas, 
e historias trazado de la biblioteca de las colecciones generales del 
congreso. Entre los asuntos que destaca están la pista y sus 
recursos, relaciones con España, competición entre partidos, 
esfuerzos de la reforma, y recuerdos políticos de los veteranos de la
guerra Español-Americana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206784</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105497</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/puerto-rico-at-the-dawn-of-the-modern-age-1831-1929</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
