<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104382</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104382</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086381</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Kentucke, Which I Esteemed a Second Paradise:" Daniel Boone Crosses the Mountains and Visits Kentucky, 1769-71</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Kentucke, dem ich schätzte ein zweites Paradies:"
Daniel Boone kreuzt die Berge und besichtigt Kentucky, 1769-71</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Kentucke, que j'ai estimé un deuxième paradis :"
Daniel Boone croise les montagnes et visite le Kentucky, 
1769-71</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Kentucke, que eu esteemed um segundo paradise:" 
Daniel Boone cruza as montanhas e visita Kentucky, 1769-71</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Kentucke, che ho stimato un secondo paradise:" 
Daniel Boone attraversa le montagne e visita il Kentucky, 
1769-71</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Kentucke, το οποίο εκτίμησα έναν δεύτερο 
παράδεισο:" Ντάνιελ Boone Crosses τα βουνά και οι 
επισκέψεις Κεντάκυ, 1769-71</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Kentucke, que estimé un segundo paraíso:" 
Daniel Boone cruza las montañas y visita Kentucky, 1769-71</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As eighteenth-century colonists eyed the lands across the Appalachian Mountains for further settlement, they needed explorers and promoters. Daniel Boone was both. Born in Pennsylvania in 1734, he settled his family along the Yadkin River in North Carolina in 1757. A decade later he traveled across the Appalachians to explore and hunt in the rich area around the Kentucky River. Boone and his hunting partners actually shared many values with the local Indians, but the goals of natives and newcomers diverged when permanent settlement occurred. By 1775, Boone was leading settlers through the Cumberland Gap along the Wilderness Road to the stockaded settlement of Boonesborough. He described his most significant trip, which took place between 1769 and 1771, in this selection from his 1784 "autobiography." John Filson, a land speculator and author of  Discovery, Settlement and Present State of Kentucke , created Boone's legend as a frontier hero by appending a ghostwritten first person narrative by Boone to his promotional tract. Soon after, Boone abandoned Kentucky because of disputed land claims; he eventually died in Missouri in 1820.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während Achtzehntjahrhundert Kolonisten die 
Länder über den Appalachian Bergen für weitere Regelung musterten, 
benötigten sie Forscher und Förderer. Daniel Boone war beide. 
Getragen in Pennsylvania 1734, vereinbarte er seine Familie 
entlang dem Yadkin Fluß in Nord-Carolina 1757. Eine Dekade 
später reiste er über die Appalachians, um im reichen Bereich um den
Kentucky Fluß zu erforschen und zu jagen. Boone und seine 
Jagdpartner teilten wirklich viele Werte mit den lokalen Indern, aber 
die Ziele der Eingeborener und der Neulinge liefen auseinander, als 
permanente Regelung auftrat. Bis zum 1775 war Boone führende 
Siedleren durch den Cumberland Abstand entlang der Wildnis-Straße zu 
stockaded Regelung von Boonesborough. Er beschrieb seine 
bedeutendste Reise, die zwischen 1769 und 1771 stattfand, in dieser 
Auswahl von seinem 1784 "Autobiographie." John Filson, ein 
Landspekulant und Autor der Entdeckung, der Regelung und des aktuellen
Standes von Kentucke, erstellte Legende Boones als Grenzheld, indem er
eine ghostwritten erste Persondarstellung durch Boone zu seiner 
fördernden Fläche anfügte. Bald nach, verließ Boone Kentucky
wegen der diskutierten Landansprüche; er starb schließlich in 
Missouri 1820.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que les colons de dix-huitième-siècle 
observaient les terres à travers les montagnes appalachiennes pour 
davantage de règlement, ils ont eu besoin d'explorateurs et 
d'instigateurs. Daniel Boone était tous deux. Soutenu en 
Pennsylvanie en 1734, il a arrangé sa famille le long du fleuve de 
Yadkin en Caroline du nord en 1757. Une décennie plus tard 
il a voyagé à travers les Appalaches pour l'explorer et chasser dans
la zone riche autour du fleuve du Kentucky. Boone et ses 
associés de chasse ont partagé réellement beaucoup de valeurs avec 
les Indiens locaux, mais les buts des indigènes et des nouveaux venus
ont divergé quand le règlement permanent s'est produit. D'ici 
1775, Boone était de principaux colons par l'intervalle de Cumberland
le long de la route de désert au stockaded le règlement de 
Boonesborough. Il a décrit son voyage plus significatif, qui a 
eu lieu entre 1769 et 1771, dans cette sélection à partir de son 
1784 "autobiographie." John Filson, un spéculateur de terre et 
auteur de découverte, de règlement et d'état actuel de Kentucke, a 
créé la légende de Boone en tant que héros de frontière en 
ajoutant un premier récit écrit anonymement de personne par Boone à
sa région promotionnelle. Peu après, Boone a abandonné le 
Kentucky en raison des réclamations contestées de terre ; il 
est par la suite mort au Missouri en 1820.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto os colonos de décimo-século eyed as 
terras através das montanhas appalachian para um estabelecimento mais
adicional, necessitaram exploradores e promoters. Daniel Boone 
era ambos. Carregado em Pensilvânia em 1734, estabeleciu sua 
família ao longo do rio de Yadkin em North.carolina em 1757. 
Uma década mais tarde viajou através dos appalachians para 
explorar e caçar na área rica em torno do rio de Kentucky. 
Boone e seus sócios da caça compartilharam realmente de muitos
valores com os indians locais, mas os objetivos dos nativos e dos 
newcomers diverged quando o estabelecimento permanente ocorreu. 
Por 1775, Boone era settlers principais com a abertura de 
Cumberland ao longo da estrada da região selvagem ao stockaded o 
estabelecimento de Boonesborough. Descreveu seu desengate mais 
significativo, que ocorreu entre 1769 e 1771, nesta seleção do seu 
1784 "autobiography." John Filson, um speculator da terra e 
autor da descoberta, do estabelecimento e do estado atual de Kentucke,
criou a legenda de Boone como um herói da fronteira adicionando uma 
primeira narrativa escrita da pessoa por Boone a seu intervalo 
promotional. Logo após, Boone abandonou Kentucky por causa das 
reivindicações disputadas da terra; morreu eventualmente em 
Missouri em 1820.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre i colonizzatori di diciottesimo-secolo eyed 
le terre attraverso le montagne appalachian per ulteriore 
stabilimento, hanno avuto bisogno degli esploratori e dei promotori. 
Daniel Boone era entrambi. Sopportato in Pensilvania in 
1734, ha depositato la sua famiglia lungo il fiume di Yadkin in 
North.carolina in 1757. Una decade più successivamente ha 
viaggiato attraverso i appalachians per esplorare e cercare 
nella zona ricca intorno al fiume del Kentucky. Boone ed i suoi 
soci cercare realmente hanno ripartito molti valori con gli 
indiani locali, ma gli obiettivi dei nativi e dei nuovi venuti hanno 
diverso quando lo stabilimento permanente ha accaduto. Entro 
1775, Boone era settlers principali con lo spacco di Cumberland lungo 
la strada della selva al stockaded lo stabilimento di Boonesborough. 
Ha descritto il suo viaggio più significativo, che ha avvenuto 
fra 1769 e 1771, in questa selezione dal suo 1784 "autobiography." 
John Filson, uno speculatore della terra ed autore della 
scoperta, dello stabilimento e del presente Dichiara di 
Kentucke, leggenda del Boone creato come hero di frontiera collegando 
una prima descrizione scritta per conto d'altri della persona da Boone
al suo tratto promozionale. Presto dopo, Boone ha abbandonato il
Kentucky a causa dei reclami disputati della terra; finalmente 
è morto nel Missouri in 1820.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαν αποίκους δέκατος-αιώνα eyed τα εδάφη στα της 
όξινης απορροής βουνά για την περαιτέρω τακτοποίηση, χρειάστηκαν
τους εξερευνητές και τους υποστηρικτές. Ο Ντάνιελ Boone 
ήταν και οι δύο. Γεννημένος στην Πενσυλβανία το 1734, 
εγκατέστησε την οικογένειά του κατά μήκος του ποταμού Yadkin 
στη βόρεια Καρολίνα το 1757. Μια δεκαετία αργότερα 
μετακινήθηκε από την μιά άκρη στην άλλη του Appalachians για 
να εξερευνήσει και να κυνηγήσει στην πλούσια περιοχή γύρω από 
τον ποταμό του Κεντάκυ. Το Boone και οι κυνηγώντας 
συνεργάτες του μοιράστηκαν πραγματικά πολλές τιμές με τους 
τοπικούς Ινδούς, αλλά οι στόχοι των ντόπιων και των νεοφερμένων 
απόκλισαν όταν εμφανίστηκε η μόνιμη τακτοποίηση. Από 
1775, Boone οδηγούσε τους αποίκους μέσω του χάσματος του 
Cumberland κατά μήκος του δρόμου αγριοτήτων η τακτοποίηση 
Boonesborough. Περιέγραψε το σημαντικότερο ταξίδι του, που
πραγματοποιήθηκε μεταξύ 1769 και 1771, σε αυτήν την επιλογή 
από 1784 του "αυτοβιογραφία." Θ*Ιοχν Filson, ένας 
παίκτης χρηματιστηρίου εδάφους και ένας συντάκτης της 
ανακάλυψης, της τακτοποίησης και της παρούσας κατάστασης 
Kentucke, δημιούργησαν το μύθο Boone δεδομένου ότι ένας 
συνοριακός ήρωας με την επισύναψη του α το πρώτο αφήγημα 
προσώπων από Boone στο προωθητικό κομμάτι του. Σύντομα 
κατόπιν, Boone εγκατέλειψε το Κεντάκυ λόγω των συζητημένων 
αξιώσεων εδάφους  πέθανε τελικά στο Μισσούρι το 1820.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que los colonos del de'cimo octavo-siglo 
eyed las pistas a través de las montañas apalaches para el 
establecimiento adicional, necesitaron a exploradores y a promotores. 
Daniel Boone era ambos. Llevado en Pennsylvania en 1734, 
él colocó a su familia a lo largo del río de Yadkin en Carolina del
Norte en 1757. Una década él viajó más adelante a través de
los apalaches para explorar y para buscar en el área rica alrededor 
del río de Kentucky. Boone y sus socios de la caza compartieron
realmente muchos valores con los indios locales, pero las metas de 
naturales y de recién llegado divergieron cuando ocurrió el 
establecimiento permanente. Antes de 1775, Boone era colonos 
principales con el boquete de Cumberland a lo largo del camino del 
yermo a stockaded el establecimiento de Boonesborough. Él 
describió su viaje más significativo, que ocurrió entre 1769 y 
1771, en esta selección a partir de su 1784 "autobiografía." 
Juan Filson, especulador de la pista y autor del descubrimiento,
del establecimiento y del estado actual de Kentucke, creó la leyenda 
de Boone como héroe de la frontera añadiendo una primera narrativa 
escrita bajo la firma de otro de la persona al final del fichero de 
Boone a su zona promocional. Pronto después de, Boone abandonó
Kentucky debido a demandas disputadas de la pista; él murió 
eventual en Missouri en 1820.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086381</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104382</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/kentucke-which-i-esteemed-a-second-paradise-daniel-boone-crosses-the-mountains-and-visits-kentucky-1769-71</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
