<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103577</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103577</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974011</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">FatWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">FatWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">FatWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">FatWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">FatWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">FatWorld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">FatWorld</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">FATWORLD is a video game about the politics of nutrition. It explores the relationships between obesity, nutrition, and socioeconomics in the contemporary U.S. The game's goal is not to tell people what to eat or how to exercise, but to demonstrate the complex, interwoven relationships between nutrition and factors like budgets, the physical world, subsidies, and regulations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">FATWORLD ist ein videospiel über die Politik von 
Nahrung. Es erforscht die Verhältnisse zwischen Korpulenz, 
Nahrung und socioeconomics in den zeitgenössischen US. Das Ziel
des Spiels ist nicht, Leuten was zu essen oder wie man zu erklären 
trainiert, aber die komplizierten, verwobenen Verhältnisse zwischen 
Nahrung und die Faktoren mögen Etats, die körperliche Welt, die 
Beihilfe und die Regelungen demonstriert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">FATWORLD est un jeu vidéo au sujet de la 
politique de la nutrition. Il explore les rapports entre 
l'obésité, la nutrition, et le socioeconomics aux États-Unis 
contemporains. Le but du jeu n'est pas de dire aux gens quoi 
manger ou comment s'exercer, mais démontrer les rapports entre la 
nutrition et les facteurs complexes et entrelacés aiment les budgets,
le monde physique, des subventions, et des règlements.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">FATWORLD é um jogo video sobre a política do 
nutrition. Explora os relacionamentos entre o obesity, o 
nutrition, e o socioeconomics nos E. U. contemporary. O objetivo
do jogo não é dizer a povos o que comer ou como exercitar, mas 
demonstrar os relacionamentos entre o nutrition e os fatores 
complexos, interwoven gosta de orçamentos, do mundo físico, de 
subsídios, e de regulamentos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">FATWORLD è un video gioco circa la politica di 
nutrizione. Esplora i rapporti fra l'obesità, la nutrizione ed 
il socioeconomics negli Stati Uniti contemporanei. L'obiettivo 
del gioco non è di dire alla gente a che cosa mangiare o a come 
esercitarsi, ma dimostrare i rapporti fra nutrizione ed i fattori 
complessi e intrecciati gradisce i preventivi, il mondo fisico, le 
sovvenzioni e le regolazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">FATWORLD είναι ένα τηλεοπτικό παιχνίδι για την 
πολιτική της διατροφής. Ερευνά τις σχέσεις μεταξύ της 
παχυσαρκίας, της διατροφής, και του socioeconomics στις 
σύγχρονες ΗΠΑ Ο στόχος του παιχνιδιού δεν είναι να ειπωθεί 
στους ανθρώπους τι για να φάει ή πώς να ασκήσει, αλλά να 
καταδείξει τις σύνθετες, αναμειγμένες σχέσεις μεταξύ της 
διατροφής και των παραγόντων όπως τους προϋπολογισμούς, το 
φυσικούς κόσμο, τις επιχορηγήσεις, και τους κανονισμούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">FATWORLD es un juego video sobre la política de 
la nutrición. Explora los lazos entre la obesidad, la 
nutrición, y el socioeconomics en los E.E.U.U. contemporáneos. 
No es decir la meta del juego a gente cuál comer o cómo 
ejercitar, pero demostrar los lazos entre la nutrición y los factores
complejos, entretejidos tiene gusto de los presupuestos, del mundo 
físico, de subsidios, y de regulaciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:IAN BOGOST
FN:IAN BOGOST
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974011</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103577</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fatworld</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
