<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103114</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103114</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087045</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Secret Life of Shop Girls: O. Henry's Short Story "The Trimmed Lamp"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das geheime Leben der System-Mädchen: O. 
Kurze Geschichte Des Henrys "Die Getrimmte Lampe"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vie secrète des filles de système : O. 
l'Histoire Courte d'Henry "La Lampe Équilibrée"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A vida secreta de meninas da loja: O. 
História Curta Do Henry "A Lâmpada Aparada"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La vita segreta delle ragazze del negozio: 
O. Storia Corta Del Henry "La Lampada Assettata"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μυστική ζωή των κοριτσιών καταστημάτων: Ο. 
Σύντομη ιστορία Henry "ο τακτοποιημένος λαμπτήρασ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La vida secreta de las muchachas del departamento:
O. Historia Corta Del Henrio "La Lámpara Cortada"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Department stores not only became a major source of employment for young urban white women beginning in the late 19th century; they also offered a new focus for stories and novels about life in America's burgeoning cities. Writers as diverse as Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, and O. Henry often used the world of department stores and the shop girls who worked there to create a modern fiction (including a brand new form--the short story) that allowed readers to feel the texture of urban life. In "The Trimmed Lamp" (1906), O. Henry (William Sidney Porter) offered a sentimental and moralistic portrait of the after-hours lives of young New York working women. While Porter's stories often focused on shop girls' predicaments (he was considered, in the words of fellow writer Vachel Lindsay, "the little shop girls' knight"), they were typically bathed in a sentimental glow.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abteilung Speicher wurden nicht nur eine 
Hauptquelle der Beschäftigung für die jungen städtischen weißen 
Frauen, die im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert anfangen; 
sie boten auch einen neuen Fokus für Geschichten und Romane 
über das Leben in Amerikas sprießenden Städte an. Verfasser 
so verschieden, wie Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber und O. Henry häufig
die Welt der Abteilung Speicher und der Systemmädchen benutzten, die 
dort arbeiteten, um eine moderne Erfindung zu erstellen 
(einschließlich nagelneues Formular -- die kurze Geschichte) die 
Lesern erlaubte, der Beschaffenheit der städtischen Lebensdauer zu 
glauben. "in der getrimmten Lampe" (1906), bot O. Henry (William
Sidney Porter) ein sentimental und moralistic Portrait von nach den 
Stunden Leben der jungen New York Funktion Frauen an. Während 
Geschichten des Porters häufig auf Zwangslagen der Systemmädchen (er
wurde, in den Wörtern des Mitverfassers Vachel Lindsay, "des kleinen 
Ritters der Systemmädchen" betrachtet), konzentrierten, wurden sie 
gewöhnlich in einem sentimental Glühen gebadet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les grands magasins sont non seulement devenus une
source importante d'emploi pour de jeunes femmes blanches urbaines 
commençant vers la fin du 19ème siècle ; ils ont également 
offert un nouveau foyer pour des histoires et des romans au sujet de 
la vie dans les villes bourgeonnantes de l'Amérique. Auteurs 
aussi divers que Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, et O. Henry ont 
souvent utilisé le monde des grands magasins et des filles de 
système qui ont travaillé là pour créer une fiction moderne (forme
nouvelle y compris -- l'histoire courte) qui a permis à des lecteurs 
de sentir la texture de la vie urbaine. Dans "la lampe 
équilibrée" (1906), O. Henry (bagagiste de William Sidney) a offert 
une verticale sentimentale et moraliste de après les vies d'heures de 
jeunes travailleuses actives de New York. Tandis que les 
histoires du bagagiste se concentraient souvent sur les situations 
fâcheuses des filles de système (il a été considéré, dans les 
mots de l'auteur Vachel Lindsay de camarade, "des petites du chevalier
filles de système"), elles ont été typiquement baignées dans une 
lueur sentimentale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As lojas de departamento transformaram-se não 
somente uma fonte principal do emprego para as mulheres brancas 
urbanas novas que começam no 1ø século atrasado; ofereceram 
também um foco novo para histórias e novelas sobre a vida em cidades
burgeoning de América. Escritores tão diversos como Theodore 
Dreiser, Edna Ferber, e O. Henry usaram frequentemente o mundo das 
lojas de departamento e das meninas da loja que trabalharam lá para 
criar um fiction moderno (formulário brandnew including -- a 
história curta) que permitisse que os leitores sentissem a textura da
vida urbana. "na lâmpada aparada" (1906), O. Henry (porter de 
William Sidney) ofereceu um retrato sentimental e moralistic do após 
vidas das horas de mulheres de funcionamento novas de New York. 
Quando as histórias do porter focalizaram frequentemente em 
predicaments das meninas da loja (foi considerado, nas palavras do 
escritor Vachel Lindsay do companheiro, "do knight das meninas 
pequenas da loja"), foram banhadas tipicamente em um fulgor 
sentimental.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I grandi magazzini si sono transformati in non 
soltanto in una sorgente importante di occupazione per le donne 
bianche urbane giovani che cominciano verso la fine del diciannovesimo
secolo; egualmente hanno offerto un nuovo fuoco per le storia ed
i romanzi circa vita nelle città burgeoning dell'America. 
Produttori vari come Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber ed O. Henry 
hanno usato spesso il mondo dei grandi magazzini e delle ragazze del 
negozio che hanno lavorato là per creare un romanzo moderno (forma 
brandnew compresa -- la storia corta) che ha permesso che i lettori 
ritenessero la struttura di vita urbana. "nella lampada 
assettata" (1906), O. Henry (portatore del William Sidney) ha offerto 
un ritratto sentimental e moralistic del dopo le vite di ore delle
donne lavorarici giovani de New York. Mentre le storia del 
portatore hanno messo a fuoco spesso sui predicaments delle ragazze 
del negozio (è stato considerato, nelle parole del produttore Vachel 
Lindsay del collega, "del cavaliere delle ragazze piccole del 
negozio"), sono state bagnate tipicamente in un'incandescenza 
sentimental.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα καταστήματα τμήματος όχι μόνο έγιναν μια 
σημαντική πηγή απασχόλησης για τις νέες αστικές λευκές γυναίκες
που αρχίζουν προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα  πρόσφεραν 
επίσης μια νέα εστίαση για τις ιστορίες και τα μυθιστορήματα για 
τη ζωή να φυτρώσουν της Αμερικής στις πόλεις. Οι συγγραφείς
τόσο διαφορετικοί όσο Theodore Dreiser, Edna Ferber, 
και Ο. Henry χρησιμοποίησαν συχνά τον κόσμο των καταστημάτων 
τμημάτων και των κοριτσιών καταστημάτων που ελειτούργησε εκεί για
να δημιουργήσει μια σύγχρονη μυθιστοριογραφία (συμπεριλαμβανομένης
μιας ολοκαίνουργιας μορφής -- η σύντομη ιστορία) που επέτρεψε 
στους αναγνώστες για να αισθανθεί τη σύσταση της αστικής ζωής. 
"Στον τακτοποιημένο λαμπτήρα" (1906), Ο. Henry 
(William Sidney Porter) πρόσφερε ένα συναισθηματικό και 
ηθοπλαστικό πορτρέτο των ζωών μετά από-ωρών των νέων 
εργαζόμενων γυναικών της Νέας Υόρκης. Ενώ οι ιστορίες του 
αχθοφόρου εστίασαν συχνά στις δυσάρεστες καταστάσεις των 
κοριτσιών καταστημάτων (εξετάστηκε, στις λέξεις του συντροφικού 
συγγραφέα Vachel Lindsay, "του ιππότη των μικρών κοριτσιών 
καταστημάτων"), λούστηκαν χαρακτηριστικά σε μια συναισθηματική 
πυράκτωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los almacenes grandes se convirtieron en no 
solamente una fuente importante del empleo para las mujeres blancas 
urbanas jóvenes que comenzaban en la a fines del siglo XIX; 
también ofrecieron un nuevo foco para las historias y las 
novelas sobre vida en las ciudades burgeoning de América. 
Programas de escritura tan diversos como Theodore Dreiser, Edna 
Ferber, y O. Henry utilizaron a menudo el mundo de los almacenes 
grandes y de las muchachas del departamento que trabajaron allí para 
crear una ficción moderna (forma brandnew incluyendo -- la historia 
corta) que permitió que los programas de lectura sintieran la textura
de la vida urbana. En "la lámpara cortada" (1906), O. Henry 
(portero de Guillermo Sidney) ofreció un retrato sentimental y 
moralizador del después de vidas de las horas de las mujeres de 
funcionamiento jóvenes de Nueva York. Mientras que las 
historias del portero se centraron a menudo en los líos de las 
muchachas del departamento (lo consideraban, en las palabras del 
programa de escritura Vachel Lindsay del compañero, "del caballero de
las pequeñas muchachas del departamento"), fueron bañadas 
típicamente en un resplandor sentimental.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087045</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103114</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-secret-life-of-shop-girls-o-henrys-short-story-the-trimmed-lamp</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
