<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103662</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103662</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087199</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Need to Exterminate Them": A Marine Describes the Battle of Guam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir müssen sie abschaffen": Eine Marine 
beschreibt die Schlacht von Guam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous devons les exterminer" : Une marine 
décrit la bataille de la Guam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós necessitamos eliminá-los": Um 
fuzileiro naval descreve a batalha de Guam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"dobbiamo exterminate": Un fante di marina 
descrive la battaglia del Guam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πρέπει να τους εξολοθρεύσουμε": Ένα ναυτικό 
περιγράφει τη μάχη του Γκουάμ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"necesitamos exterminarlas": Un infante de 
marina describe la batalla de Guam</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Pacific theater was the most inhospitable environment in all of World War II, with all-out assaults that were unparalleled in their barbarity. The ferocity of the battles and the atrocities committed by both sides were further encouraged by the pervasive anti-Asian racism expressed by Americans toward the Japanese enemy. Fighting the war in the Pacific left indelible impressions on the men who served there. Because employees at the Library of Congress thought marines might have time to do ethnographic recordings of the music and culture of the native peoples they encountered in the South Pacific, several marine units were given metal disc recording machines to carry with them. Though they never managed to use the recorders for their intended purpose, several marines did have the presence of mind to record what happened during major battles at sea and on the islands. In one such recording, made on the island of Guam in 1944, an unidentified marine described his foxhole.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das pazifische Theater war die unwirtlichste 
Umgebung in den ganzen Zweiten Weltkrieg, mit all-out Angriffen, die 
in ihrem Barbarity unvergleichlich waren. Die Grausamkeit der 
Schlachten und die Grausamkeiten, die durch beide Seiten festgelegt 
wurden, wurden weiter durch den durchdringenden Anti-Asiatischen 
Rassismus angeregt, der von Americans in Richtung zum japanischen 
Feind ausgedrückt wurde. Den Krieg in den pazifischen linken 
unauslöschbaren Eindrücken auf den Männern kämpfen, die dort 
dienten. Weil Angestellte an der Bibliothek der Kongreßgedanke 
Marinen Zeit haben konnten, ethnographische Aufnahmen der Musik und 
der Kultur der gebürtigen Völker zu tun, die sie im Südpazifik 
antrafen, wurden einige Marinemaßeinheiten die Metalplatte 
Aufnahmemaschinen gegeben, zum mit ihnen zu tragen. Obwohl sie 
nie handhatten, die Schreiber für ihren beabsichtigten Zweck zu 
benutzen, hatten einige Marinen die Geistesgegenwart, zum zu 
speichern, was während der Hauptschlachten am Meer und auf den Inseln
geschah. In einer solchen Aufnahme gebildet auf der Insel von 
Guam 1944, beschrieb eine nicht identifizierte Marine sein foxhole.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le théâtre Pacifique était l'environnement le 
plus inhospitalier en tout de la deuxième guerre mondiale, avec les 
assauts globaux qui étaient inégalés dans leur barbarie. La 
férocité des batailles et les atrocités commises par les deux 
côtés ont été encore encouragées par le racisme anti-Asiatique 
dominant exprimé par Americans vers l'ennemi japonais. 
Combattant la guerre dans les impressions indélébiles gauches 
Pacifiques sur les hommes qui ont servi là. Puisque les 
employés à la bibliothèque des soldats de marine de pensée du 
congrès pourraient avoir le temps pour faire les enregistrements 
ethnographiques de la musique et de la culture des indigènes qu'ils 
ont rencontrés dans le Pacifique du sud, plusieurs unités 
marines ont été données des machines d'enregistrement de disque en 
métal à porter avec elles. Bien qu'elles ne soient jamais 
parvenues à utiliser les enregistreurs pour leur but destiné, 
plusieurs marines ont eu la présence de l'esprit pour enregistrer ce 
qui s'est produit pendant des batailles principales en mer et sur les 
îles. Dans un tel enregistrement, fait sur l'île de la Guam en
1944, une marine non identifiée a décrit son trou de tirailleur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O teatro pacífico era o ambiente o mais 
inhospitable em toda a segunda guerra mundial, com assaltos all-out 
que eram unparalleled em seu barbarity. O ferocity das batalhas 
e os atrocities cometidos por ambos os lados foram incentivados mais 
mais pelo racism anti-anti-Asian pervasive expressado por Americano 
para o inimigo japonês. Lutando a guerra nas impressões 
indelible esquerdas pacíficas nos homens que serviram lá. 
Porque os empregados na biblioteca de fuzileiros navais do 
pensamento do congress puderam ter o tempo para fazer gravações 
ethnographic da música e da cultura dos povos que nativos encontraram
no Pacífico sul, diversas unidades marinhas foram dadas as máquinas 
da gravação do disco do metal a carregar com elas. Embora 
nunca controlaram usar os registradores para sua finalidade 
pretendida, diversos fuzileiros navais tiveram a presença de mente 
para gravar o que aconteceu durante batalhas principais no mar e nos 
consoles. Em uma tal gravação, feita no console de Guam em 
1944, um fuzileiro naval não identificado descreveu seu foxhole.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il teatro pacifico era l'ambiente più 
inhospitable in tutto della seconda guerra mondiale, con gli assalti 
con tutti i mezzi a disposizione che erano senza pari nel loro barbarity. La ferocità
delle battaglie e le atrocità commesse da entrambi i lati più 
ulteriormente sono state consigliate a dal razzismo anti-Asiatico 
dominante espresso da Americans verso il nemico giapponese. 
Combattimento la guerra nelle impressioni indelebili di sinistra 
pacifiche con uomini che hanno servito là. Poiché gli 
impiegati alla libreria dei fanti di marina di pensiero del congresso 
potrebbero avere tempo di fare le registrazioni ethnographic della 
musica e della coltura delle popolazioni autoctone che hanno 
incontrato nel Pacifico del sud, parecchie unità marine sono state 
date le macchine della registrazione del disco del metallo da 
trasportare con loro. Benchè non riescano mai ad utilizzare i 
registratori per il loro scopo progettato, parecchi fanti di marina 
hanno avuti la presenza della mente per registrare che cosa è 
accaduto durante le battaglie importanti in mare e sulle isole. 
In una tale registrazione, fatta sull'isola del Guam in 1944, un
fante di marina non identificato ha descritto il suo foxhole.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ειρηνικό θέατρο ήταν το πιό αφιλόξενο περιβάλλον 
τον σε όλο παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ, με τις ενθουσιώδεις επιθέσεις που
ήταν ασύγκριτες στη βαρβαρότητά τους. Η αγριότητα των 
μαχών και οι αγριότητες που δεσμεύθηκαν και από τις δύο πλευρές 
ενθαρρύνθηκαν περαιτέρω από τον κυρίαρχο αντι-ασιατικό ρατσισμό 
που εκφράστηκε από Αμερικανούς προς τον ιαπωνικό εχθρό. 
Διεξάγοντας τον πόλεμο στις ειρηνικές αριστερές ανεξίτηλες 
εντυπώσεις στα άτομα που εξυπηρέτησαν εκεί. Επειδή οι 
υπάλληλοι στη βιβλιοθήκη του συνεδρίου σκέφτηκαν τα ναυτικά να 
έχουν το χρόνο να κάνουν τις εθνογραφικές καταγραφές της 
μουσικής και τον πολιτισμό των εγγενών λαών που αντιμετώπισαν στο
Νότιο Ειρηνικό, σε διάφορες θαλάσσιες μονάδες δόθηκαν οι 
μηχανές καταγραφής δίσκων μετάλλων που φέρνουν με τα. Αν 
και δεν κατόρθωσαν ποτέ να χρησιμοποιήσουν τα όργανα καταγραφής 
για τον προοριζόμενο σκοπό τους, διάφορα ναυτικά είχαν την 
παρουσία μυαλού για να καταγράψουν τι συνέβη κατά τη διάρκεια 
σημαντικών μαχών εν πλω και στα νησιά. Σε μια τέτοια 
καταγραφή, που έγινε στο νησί του Γκουάμ το 1944, ένα μη 
αναγνωρισμένο ναυτικό περιέγραψε το ατομικό όρυγμα μάχης του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El teatro pacífico era el ambiente más 
inhospitalario de toda la Segunda Guerra Mundial, con los asaltos 
totales que estaban sin par en su barbaridad. La ferocidad 
de las batallas y las atrocidades confiadas por ambas caras fueron 
animadas más a fondo por el racismo contra-Asia'tico penetrante 
expresado por americans hacia el enemigo japonés. Luchando la 
guerra en las impresiones indelebles izquierdas pacíficas en los 
hombres que sirvieron allí. Porque los empleados en la 
biblioteca de los infantes de marina del pensamiento del congreso 
pudieron tener tiempo para hacer las grabaciones etnográficas de la 
música y de la cultura de los indígenas que encontraron en el 
Pacífico del sur, varias unidades marinas fueron dadas las máquinas 
de la grabación del disco del metal a llevar con ellas. Aunque 
nunca manejaron utilizar los registradores para su propósito 
previsto, varios infantes de marina tenían la presencia de la mente 
para registrar qué sucedió durante batallas importantes en el mar y 
en las islas. En una tal grabación, hecha en la isla de Guam en
1944, un infante de marina no identificado describió su foxhole.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087199</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103662</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-need-to-exterminate-them-a-marine-describes-the-battle-of-guam</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
