<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105440</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105440</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086683</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ode to the Odious: A Poet Ridicules Laissez-Faire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ode zu Odious: Ein Dichter Lächerlich macht 
Laissez-Faire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ode à l'odieux : Ridicules Laissez-Faire 
D'un Poèt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ode ao odious: Um Poeta Ridicules 
Laissez-Faire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ode al odious: Un Poet Ridicules 
Laissez-Faire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ωδή στο μισητό: Ένας ποιητής γελοιοποιεί την 
ελεύθερη οικονομία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Oda al odioso: Irrisiones 
Laissez-Faire De un Poeta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the late 19th century, William Graham Sumner, an Episcopal minister turned academic sociologist, applied Darwin's scientific ideas of evolution to the social sphere to produce his theory of the economic survival of the fittest. Sumner's writings justified government inaction in the face of vast social dislocations caused by rapid industrialization and the periodic economic depressions that accompanied it. Critics of the new industrial order rejected the rigid "laws" propounded by Sumner and other conservative social scientists. They countered with their own laws of social development based on alternative readings of nature and science. Some labor thinkers proposed a sort of working-class social Darwinism, which challenged the ideas of conservatives. Other critics simply greeted the ideas of conservatives with derision. Phillips Thomson's 1878 poem, "The Political Economist and the Tramp," poked fun at the social Darwinism championed by conservatives who preferred to believe that the working class was fated to be perpetually bested by the "fitter" middle class.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert drehte
William Graham Sumner, ein episkopaler Minister akademischen 
Soziologen, angewandten Darwins wissenschaftliche Ideen von der 
Entwicklung zum Sozialbereich, seine Theorie des ökonomischen 
Überlebens vom passendsten zu produzieren. Schreiben Sumners 
schlossen Regierung Untätigkeit angesichts der beträchtlichen 
Sozialversetzungen aus, die durch schnelle Industrialisierung und die 
periodischen Wirtschaftskrisen, die, verursacht wurden sie 
begleiteten. Kritiker der neuen industriellen Ordnung wiesen die
steifen "Gesetze zurück", die von Sumner und von anderen 
konservativen Sozialwissenschaftlern vorgeschlagen wurden. Sie 
widersprachen mit ihren eigenen Gesetzen der Sozialentwicklung basiert
auf alternativen Messwerten der Natur und der Wissenschaft. 
Einige Arbeitsdenker schlugen eine Sortierung der Arbeiterklasse
Sozialdarwinism vor, die die Ideen der Konservativer herausforderte. 
Andere Kritiker grüßten einfach die Ideen der Konservativer 
mit Hohn. Kreuzkopfthomsons Gedicht 1878, "der politische 
Wirtschaftswissenschaftler und der Tramp," stießen den Spaß beim 
Sozialdarwinism verfochten von den Konservativen, die es vorzogen, zu 
glauben, daß die Funktion Kategorie fated war, unaufhörlich zu sein 
bested durch die "passendere" mittlere Kategorie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Au 19ème siècle en retard, William Graham 
Sumner, un ministre épiscopal a tourné le sociologue d'universitaire, 
les idées scientifiques de Darwin appliqué de l'évolution à la 
sphère sociale de produire sa théorie de la survie économique du 
plus convenable. Les écritures de Sumner ont justifié 
l'inaction de gouvernement face à de vastes dislocations sociales 
provoquées par l'industrialisation rapide et les dépressions 
économiques périodiques qui l'ont accompagnée. Les critiques 
de la nouvelle commande industrielle ont rejeté les "lois" rigides 
proposées par Sumner et d'autres sociologues conservateurs. Ils
ont paré avec leurs propres lois du développement social basées sur
les lectures alternatives de la nature et de la science. 
Quelques penseurs de travail ont proposé un tri de classe 
ouvrier Darwinism social, qui a défié les idées des conservateurs. 
D'autres critiques ont simplement salué les idées des 
conservateurs avec la dérision. La poésie 1878 de Thomson 
Phillips, "l'économiste politique et le vagabond," ont poussé 
l'amusement chez le Darwinism social soutenu par les conservateurs qui
ont préféré croire que la classe ouvrière était destinée pour 
être perpétuellement bested par la bourgeoisie "plus convenable".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 1ø século atrasado, William Graham Sumner, um
ministro episcopal girou o sociologist academic, idéias científicas 
de Darwin aplicado da evolução à esfera social produzir sua teoria 
da sobrevivência econômica do mais apto. As escritas de Sumner
justificaram o inaction do governo na cara dos dislocations sociais 
vastos causados pelo industrialization rápido e pelos depressions 
econômicos periódicos que a acompanharam. Os críticos da 
ordem industrial nova rejeitaram as "leis rígidas" propounded por 
Sumner e por outros cientistas sociais conservadores. 
Opuseram-se com suas próprias leis do desenvolvimento social 
baseadas em leituras alternativas da natureza e da ciência. 
Alguns thinkers labor propuseram uma sorte do working-class 
Darwinism social, que desafiasse as idéias dos conservadores. 
Outros críticos cumprimentaram simplesmente as idéias dos 
conservadores com derision. O poema 1878 de Thomson Phillips, "o
economista político e a caminhada," picaram o divertimento no 
Darwinism social championed pelos conservadores que preferiram 
acreditar que a classe de funcionamento era fated ser perpetually 
bested pela classe média "mais apta".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verso la fine del diciannovesimo secolo, William 
Graham Sumner, un ministro episcopal ha girato il sociologist 
accademico, idee scientifiche del Darwin applicato di sviluppo alla 
sfera sociale produrre la sua teoria della sopravvivenza economica 
dell'più adatto. Le scritture del Sumner hanno giustificato 
l'inerzia di governo di fronte alle dislocazioni sociali ampie causate
dall'industrializzazione veloce e dalle depressioni economiche 
periodiche che la hanno accompagnata. I critici di nuovo ordine 
industriale hanno rifiutato "le leggi" rigide proposte da Sumner e da 
altri sociologi conservatori. Hanno ricambiato con le loro proprie
leggi di evoluzione sociale basate sulle letture alternative della 
natura e della scienza. Alcuni thinkers di lavoro hanno 
proposto un ordinamento della classe operaia Darwinism sociale, che ha
sfidato le idee dei conservatori. Altri critici greeted 
semplicemente le idee dei conservatori con derision. Il poem 
1878 del Thomson "phillips", "l'economista politico ed il vagabondo," 
hanno colpito il divertimento al Darwinism sociale sostenuto dai 
conservatori che hanno preferito credere che il codice categoria di 
funzionamento fosse fated essere perpetuo bested dal codice categoria 
centrale "più adatto".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, William Graham 
Sumner, ένας επισκοπικός υπουργός γύρισε τον ακαδημαϊκό 
κοινωνιολόγο, εφαρμοσμένες επιστημονικές ιδέες Δαρβίνου της 
εξέλιξης στην κοινωνική σφαίρα για να παραγάγει τη θεωρία του της
οικονομικής επιβίωσης του καταλληλότερου. Οι γραφές του 
Sumner δικαιολόγησαν την κυβερνητική απραξία παρά τις 
απέραντες κοινωνικές εξαρθρώσεις που προκλήθηκαν από τη γρήγορη 
εκβιομηχάνιση και τις περιοδικές οικονομικές υφέσεις που την 
συνόδευσαν. Οι κριτικοί της νέας βιομηχανικής κατάταξης 
απέρριψαν τους άκαμπτους "νόμουσ" που προτάθηκαν από Sumner 
και άλλους συντηρητικούς κοινωνικούς επιστήμονες. 
Αντιμετώπισαν με τους νόμους κοινωνικής ανάπτυξής τους 
βασισμένους στις εναλλακτικές αναγνώσεις της φύσης και την 
επιστήμη. Μερικοί φιλόσοφοι εργασίας πρότειναν κάποια 
εργατική τάξη κοινωνικό Darwinism, η οποία προκάλεσε τις 
ιδέες των συντηρητικών. Αλλοι κριτικοί χαιρέτησαν απλά τις
ιδέες των συντηρητικών με το χλευασμό. Το ποίημα 1878 
Thomson Phillips, "ο πολιτικός οικονομολόγος και ο αγύρτης," 
έσπρωξε τη διασκέδαση στο κοινωνικό Darwinism που υπερασπίστηκε
από τα συντηρητικά που προτίμησαν να θεωρήσουν ότι η εργατική 
τάξη ήταν προδιαγεγραμμένη για να είναι μονίμως από τη 
"καταλληλότερη" μέση κλάση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la a fines del siglo XIX, Guillermo Graham 
Sumner, un ministro episcopal dio vuelta al sociólogo académico, 
ideas científicas de Darwin aplicado de la evolución a la esfera 
social de producir su teoría de la supervivencia económica del más 
apto. Las escrituras de Sumner alinearon la inacción del 
gobierno en la cara de las dislocaciones sociales extensas causadas 
por la industrialización rápida y las depresiones económicas 
periódicas que la acompañaron. Los críticos de la nueva orden
industrial rechazaron los "leyes rígidos" propuestos por Sumner y 
otros científicos sociales conservadores. Contradijeron con sus
propios leyes del desarrollo social basados en lecturas alternativas 
de la naturaleza y de la ciencia. Algunos pensadores de trabajo 
propusieron una clase de clase obrera Darwinism social, que desafió 
las ideas de conservadores. Otros críticos saludaron 
simplemente las ideas de conservadores con el derision. El poema
1878 de Thomson Phillips, "el economista político y el vagabundo," 
empujaron la diversión en el Darwinism social defendida por los 
conservadores que prefirieron creer que la clase obrera era 
predestinada estar perpetuo bested por la clase media "más apta".</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086683</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105440</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/ode-to-the-odious-a-poet-ridicules-laissez-faire</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
