<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105715</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105715</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206884</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Valley of the Shadow Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Senke des Schatten-Projektes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vallée du projet d'ombre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O vale do projeto da sombra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La valle del progetto dell'ombra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κοιλάδα του προγράμματος σκιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El valle del proyecto de la sombra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">follows two communities, one Northern and one Southern, through their experiences in the American Civil War. This hypermedia archive contains thousands of sources from before, during and after the Civil War in Virginia and Pennsylvania including newspapers, letters, diaries, photographs, maps, church records, population census and military records. Students can write their own histories, reconstructing the lives of those who lived during the period.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">folgt zwei Gemeinschaften, eine, die Nord sind und
südlicher einer, durch ihre Erfahrungen im amerikanischen 
Bürgerkrieg. Dieses hypermedia Archiv enthält Tausenden 
Quellen von vor, während und nach dem Bürgerkrieg in Virginia und in
Pennsylvania einschließlich Zeitungen, Zeichen, Tagebücher, 
Fotographien, Karten, Kirchesätze, Bevölkerung Zählung und 
Militärsätze. Kursteilnehmer können ihre eigenen Geschichten 
schreiben und die Leben von denen wieder aufbauen, die während der 
Periode lebten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">suit les deux communautés, une nordique et une 
méridionale, par leurs expériences de la guerre civile américaine. 
Ces archives de hypermedia contiennent des milliers de sources 
de avant, pendant et après la guerre civile la Virginie et en 
Pennsylvanie comprenant des journaux, des lettres, des agendas, des 
photographies, des cartes, des enregistrements d'église, le 
recensement de population et des enregistrements de militaires. 
Les étudiants peuvent écrire leurs propres histoires, 
reconstruisant les vies de ceux qui ont vécu pendant la période.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">segue duas comunidades, uma do norte e uma do sul,
com suas experiências na guerra civil americana. Este arquivo 
do hypermedia contem milhares das fontes de antes, durante e após da 
guerra civil em Virgínia e em Pensilvânia including jornais, letras,
diários, fotografias, mapas, registros da igreja, census da 
população e registros das forças armadas. Os estudantes podem
escrever seus próprios histories, reconstructing as vidas daqueles 
que viveram durante o período.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">segue due Comunità, una nordica ed una del sud, 
con le loro esperienze di guerra civile americana. Questo 
archivio di hypermedia contiene le migliaia delle sorgenti da prima, 
durante e dopo la guerra civile la Virginia ed in Pensilvania compreso
i giornali, le lettere, i diari, le fotografie, i programmi, i record 
della chiesa, il censimento della popolazione ed i record dei 
militari. Gli allievi possono scrivere i loro propri dati 
storici, ricostruenti le vite di coloro che ha vissuto durante il 
periodo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ακολουθεί δύο κοινότητες, μια βόρεια και μια νότια, 
μέσω της εμπειρίας τους στον αμερικανικό εμφύλιο πόλεμο. 
Αυτό το αρχείο υπερμεσών περιέχει χιλιάδες πηγές από πριν
από, κατά τη διάρκεια και μετά από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο στη 
Βιρτζίνια και την Πενσυλβανία συμπεριλαμβανομένων των εφημερίδων, 
των επιστολών, των ημερολογίων, των φωτογραφιών, των χαρτών, των 
αρχείων εκκλησιών, της απογραφής πληθυσμών και των στρατιωτικών 
αρχείων. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να γράψουν τις ιστορίες 
τους, αναδημιουργώντας τις ζωές εκείνοι που έζησαν κατά τη 
διάρκεια της περιόδου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sigue a dos comunidades, una norteña y una 
meridional, con sus experiencias en la guerra civil americana. 
Este archivo del hypermedia contiene millares de fuentes de 
antes, durante y después de la guerra civil en Virginia y 
Pennsylvania incluyendo los periódicos, las cartas, los diarios, las 
fotografías, las correspondencias, los expedientes de la iglesia, 
censo de la población y expedientes de los militares. Los 
estudiantes pueden escribir sus propias historias, reconstruyendo las 
vidas de los que vivieron durante el período.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206884</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105715</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-valley-of-the-shadow-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
