<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108146</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108146</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086975</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Jewish Daily Forward Reports the Triangle Tragedy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die jüdischen täglichen Vorwärtsreports die 
Dreieck-Tragödie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les états vers l'avant quotidiens juifs la 
tragédie de triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os relatórios para diante diários jewish a 
tragédia do triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I rapporti di andata quotidiani ebrei la tragedia 
del triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εβραϊκές καθημερινές μπροστινές εκθέσεις η 
τραγωδία τριγώνων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los informes delanteros diarios judíos la tragedia
del triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One of the greatest industrial tragedies in U.S. history occurred on March 25, 1911, when 146 workers, mostly young immigrant women, died in a fire at the Triangle Shirtwaist company in New York City. The victims had been trapped by blocked exit doors and faulty fire escapes. One of the worst industrial fires in U.S. history, the Triangle fire became a galvanizing symbol of industrial capitalism's excesses and the pressing need for reform. In its aftermath, a coalition of middle-class reformers and working people secured passage of landmark occupational health and safety laws. The Triangle fire received sensational coverage in all the New York newspapers. This article from the  Jewish Daily Forward , printed the day after the fire, emphasized the tragic loss to the Jewish community.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine der größten industriellen Tragödien in der 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte trat an März 25, 1911, als 146 
Arbeiter, meistens die jungen einwandernden Frauen auf, gestorben in 
einem Feuer bei der Dreieck Shirtwaist Firma in New York City. 
Die Opfer waren durch geblockte Ausgang Türen eingeschlossen 
worden und fehlerhaftes Feuer entgeht. Eins der falschsten 
industriellen Feuer in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte, das 
Dreieckfeuer wurde ein Galvanisierensymbol der Überflüsse des 
industriellen Kapitalismus und das dringende Bedürfnis an der 
Verbesserung. In seiner Nachmahd sicherten eine Koalition der 
MittelklasseReformer und Arbeitsleute Durchgang berufliche 
Gesundheit und Sicherheit des Grenzsteins der Gesetze. Das 
Dreieckfeuer empfing sensational Dichte in allen New York Zeitungen. 
Dieser Artikel vom jüdischen täglichen Vorwärts, gedruckt der
Tag nach dem Feuer, hervorgehoben dem tragischen Verlust zur 
jüdischen Gemeinschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une des plus grandes tragédies industrielles dans 
l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS s'est produite 25 mars 1911, quand 146 
ouvriers, la plupart du temps jeunes femmes immigrées, mortes dans un
feu à la compagnie de Chemisier de triangle à New York City. 
Les victimes avaient été emprisonnées par les portes 
bloquées de sortie et le feu défectueux s'échappe. Un des 
plus mauvais feux industriels dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS, le feu 
de triangle est devenu un symbole de galvanisation des excès du 
capitalisme industriel et la nécessité pressante de la réforme. 
Dans sa conséquence, une coalition des réformateurs de classe 
moyen et les personnes travaillantes ont fixé le passage des lois de 
salubrité professionnelle et de sûreté de borne limite. Le 
feu de triangle a reçu l'assurance sensationnelle dans tous les journaux
de New York. Cet article de l'vers l'avant quotidien juif, 
imprimé le jour après le feu, souligné la perte tragique à la 
communauté juive.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma das tragédias industriais as mais grandes no 
history de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocorreu março em 25, 1911, quando 146 
trabalhadores, na maior parte mulheres immigrant novas, morridas em um
fogo na companhia de Shirtwaist do triângulo em New York City. 
As vítimas tinham sido prendidas por portas obstruídas da 
saída e o fogo defeituoso escapa-se. Um dos fogos industriais 
os mais maus no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS, o fogo do triângulo 
transformou-se um símbolo galvanizing de excessos do capitalismo 
industrial e a necessidade pressionando para a reforma. Em seu 
aftermath, um coalition de reformers do middle-class e os povos 
trabalhando fixaram a passagem de leis da saúde ocupacional e da 
segurança do marco. O fogo do triângulo recebeu a cobertura do
sensational em todos os jornais de New York. Este artigo do para
diante diário jewish, impresso o dia após o fogo, emfatizado a perda
trágica à comunidade jewish.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una delle tragedie industriali più grandi nella 
storia degli STATI UNITI si è presentata il 25 marzo 1911, quando 146
operai, principalmente donne immigrate giovani, morte in un fuoco 
all'azienda di Shirtwaist del triangolo a New York City. Le 
vittime erano state bloccate dai portelli ostruiti dell'uscita ed il 
fuoco difettoso fuoriesce. Uno dei fuochi industriali più 
difettosi nella storia degli STATI UNITI, il fuoco del triangolo si è
transformato in in un simbolo di galvanizzazione degli eccessi del 
capitalismo industriale e nella necessità urgente della riforma. 
Nel relativo guaime, una coalizione dei reformers della classe 
media e la gente lavorante hanno assicurato il passaggio delle leggi 
professionale di sanità e sicurezza del limite. Il fuoco del 
triangolo ha ricevuto il riempimento di sensational in tutti i 
giornali de New York. Questo articolo dal di andata quotidiano 
ebreo, stampato il giorno dopo il fuoco, dato risalto a la perdita 
tragica alla Comunità ebrea.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια από τις μέγιστες βιομηχανικές τραγωδίες στην 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία εμφανίστηκε στις 25 Μαρτίου ..1911, όταν
πέθαναν 146 εργαζόμενοι, συνήθως νέες που έχουν μεταναστεύσει
γυναίκες, σε μια πυρκαγιά στην επιχείρηση μπλουζών τριγώνων στην 
πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης. Τα θύματα είχαν παγιδευτεί από τις 
παρεμποδισμένες πόρτες εξόδων και τις ελαττωματικές εξόδους 
κινδύνου. Μια από τις χειρότερες βιομηχανικές πυρκαγιές 
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία, το πυρ τριγώνων έγινε ένα γαλβανίζοντας
σύμβολο των υπερβολών της βιομηχανικής κεφαλαιοκρατίας και της 
επείγουσας ανάγκης για τη μεταρρύθμιση. Στη συνέπειά του, 
ένας συνασπισμός των μεταρρυθμιστών μεσαίων τάξεων και των 
εργαζόμενων ανθρώπων εξασφάλισε τη μετάβαση των νόμων υγιεινής 
και ασφάλειας της εργασίας ορόσημων. Το πυρ τριγώνων έλαβε 
τη συγκλονιστική κάλυψη σε όλες τις εφημερίδες της Νέας Υόρκης. 
Αυτό το άρθρο από εβραϊκή καθημερινή την μπροστινή, 
τύπωσε την ημέρα μετά από την πυρκαγιά, υπογράμμισε την τραγική
απώλεια στην εβραϊκή κοινότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una de las tragedias industriales más grandes de 
la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocurrió de marcha la 25 de 1911, cuando
146 trabajadores, sobre todo mujeres inmigrantes jóvenes, muertas en 
un fuego en la compañía de Shirtwaist del triángulo en New York 
City. Las puertas bloqueadas de la salida habían atrapado a las
víctimas y el fuego defectuoso se escapa. Uno de los fuegos 
industriales peores de la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS, el fuego del 
triángulo se convirtió en un símbolo de la galvanización de los 
excesos del capitalismo industrial y la necesidad acuciante de la 
reforma. En sus consecuencias, una coalición de los reformadores
de la clase media y la gente de trabajo aseguraron el paso de los 
leyes de la medicina del trabajo y de la seguridad de la señal. 
El fuego del triángulo recibió cobertura del sensational en 
todos los periódicos de Nueva York. Este artículo del 
delantero diario judío, impreso el día después del fuego, acentuado
la pérdida trágica a la comunidad judía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086975</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108146</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-jewish-daily-forward-reports-the-triangle-tragedy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
