<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105139</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105139</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1641023841</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Biology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Biologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Biologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Biologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η βιολογία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Biology course is a first-year course in biology at the high school level. The course emphasizes a multi-representational approach to algebra, with concepts, results, and problems being expressed graphically, analytically, and verbally. The course uses four themes to organize important concepts throughout the course: science, technology, and society; evolution; the relationship between structure and function; and science as a process.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Biologiekurs ist ein des ersten Jahres Kurs in
der Biologie auf der High School Stufe. Der Kurs hebt eine 
multi-representational Annäherung zur Algebra, mit Konzepten, zu den 
Resultaten und zu den Problemen graphisch, analytisch und, die 
mündlich ausgedrückt werden hervor. Der Kurs verwendet vier 
Themen, um wichtige Konzepte während des Kurses zu organisieren: 
Wissenschaft, Technologie und Gesellschaft; Entwicklung; 
das Verhältnis zwischen Struktur und Funktion; und 
Wissenschaft als Prozeß.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le cours de biologie est un cours de première 
année de biologie au niveau de lycée. Le cours souligne une 
approche de multi-représentatif à l'algèbre, avec des concepts, aux 
résultats, et aux problèmes étant exprimés graphiquement, 
analytiquement, et verbalement. Le cours emploie quatre thèmes 
pour organiser des concepts importants dans tout le cours : la 
science, technologie, et société ; évolution ; le 
rapport entre la structure et la fonction ; et la science comme 
processus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O curso da biologia é um curso first-year na 
biologia no nível da High School. O curso emfatiza uma 
aproximação do multi-representational à álgebra, com conceitos, 
aos resultados, e aos problemas que estão sendo expressados gràfica,
analìticamente, e verbal. O curso usa quatro temas organizar 
conceitos importantes durante todo o curso: ciência, 
tecnologia, e sociedade; evolução; o relacionamento 
entre a estrutura e a função; e ciência como um processo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il corso di biologia è un corso del primo anno 
nella biologia al livello della High School. Il corso dà 
risalto ad un metodo di multi-representational ad algebra, con i 
concetti, ai risultati ed ai problemi che sono espressi graficamente, 
analiticamente e verbalmente. Il corso usa quattro temi per 
organizzare i concetti importanti durante il corso: scienza, 
tecnologia e società; sviluppo; il rapporto fra la 
struttura e la funzione; e scienza come processo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σειρά μαθημάτων της βιολογίας είναι μια πρωτοετής 
σειρά μαθημάτων στη βιολογία στο επίπεδο γυμνασίου. Η 
σειρά μαθημάτων υπογραμμίζει μια πολυ-αντιπροσωπευτική προσέγγιση
στην άλγεβρα, με τις έννοιες, τα αποτελέσματα, και τα προβλήματα 
που εκφράζονται γραφικά, αναλυτικά, και προφορικά. Η σειρά 
μαθημάτων χρησιμοποιεί τέσσερα θέματα για να οργανώσει τις 
σημαντικές έννοιες σε όλη τη σειρά μαθημάτων: επιστήμη, 
τεχνολογία, και κοινωνία  εξέλιξη  η σχέση μεταξύ της
δομής και της λειτουργίας  και επιστήμη ως διαδικασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El curso de la biología es un curso del primer 
año en biología en el nivel de la High School secundaria. El 
curso acentúa un acercamiento del multi-representational a la 
álgebra, con conceptos, a los resultados, y a los problemas que son 
expresados gráficamente, analíticamente, y verbalmente. El 
curso utiliza cuatro temas para ordenar conceptos importantes a 
través del curso: ciencia, tecnología, y sociedad; 
evolución; el lazo entre la estructura y la función; 
y ciencia como proceso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNKNOWN
FN:UNKNOWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1641023841</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105139</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/biology-2</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
