<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086922</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Constant Reiteration of Horror and Violence": A Senate Report on Television and Juvenile Delinquency</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die konstante Wiederholung der Grausigkeit und 
der Gewalttätigkeit": Ein Senat-Bericht über Fernsehen und 
jugendliche Gesetzesverletzung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la réiteration constante de l'horreur et de la 
violence" : Un état de sénat à la télévision et à la 
délinquance juvénile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o reiteration constante do horror e da 
violência": Um relatório do senate na televisão e no 
delinquency juvenile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la reiterazione costante dell'orrore e della 
violenza": Un rapporto del senato sulla televisione e sulla 
delinquenza giovanile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η σταθερή επανάληψη της φρίκης και της βίασ": 
Μια έκθεση Συγκλήτου σχετικά με την τηλεόραση και τη 
νεανική εγκληματικότητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la reiteración constante del horror y de la 
violencia": Un informe del senado sobre la televisión y la 
delincuencia juvenil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While experimental television broadcasts were first transmitted in the 1920s, mass production of television sets did not occur until after World War II. By 1960 the number of sets in the U.S. had surpassed the number of homes. With this relatively swift introduction of television into domestic American life, concern was voiced over the harmful influence that watching television might have on the nation's children. Earlier in the century, anxieties by both Progressives and traditionalists about harmful effects of movies on youth had led to Congressional hearings regarding Federal censorship. Reformers, however, lacked convincing evidence to support their claims and the motion picture industry developed an effective self-censoring mechanism to maintain control over screen content. Similarly, after Congress held its first hearing in 1952 on the effect of television on children, they chose not to take any action to interfere with the industry, in part because that year the National Association of Radio and Television Broadcasters adopted a code to regulate broadcast content. A Senate report issued after hearings in 1954 and 1955 on the possible influence of television on juvenile delinquency summarized studies to determine the quantity of criminal and violent acts on television shows accessible for children to view. The report also presented a range of views on whether a "cumulative effect of crime-and-horror television programs" could be harmful to children. Excerpts from the report are followed by additional opinions submitted by the National Association for Better Radio and Television, an advocacy group organized in 1949.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während experimentelle Fernsehensendungen zuerst 
in die zwanziger Jahre übertragen wurden, trat Großserienfertigung 
der Fernseher nicht bis nach den Zweiten Weltkrieg auf. Durch 
1960 hatte die Zahl Sets in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN die Zahl Häusern 
übertroffen. Mit dieser verhältnismäßig schnellen Einleitung
des Fernsehens in inländische amerikanische Lebensdauer, wurde 
Interesse über dem schädlichen Einfluß geäußert, den 
überwachendes Fernsehen auf den Kindern der Nation haben konnte. 
Früh im Jahrhundert, hatten Ängste durch Progressisten und 
Traditionalisten um schädliche Effekte von Filmen auf Jugend zu die 
Kongreßhörfähigkeiten betreffend sind Bundeszensur geführt. 
Die Reformer jedoch ermangelt, Beweis überzeugend, um 
ihre Ansprüche und die Bewegung Abbildung Industrie zu unterstützen,
entwickelten eine wirkungsvolle Selbst-zensierende Einheit, um 
Steuerung über Bildschirminhalt beizubehalten. Ähnlich nachdem
Kongreß seine erste Hörfähigkeit 1952 auf dem Effekt des Fernsehens
auf Kindern anhielt, beschlossen sie, keine Maßnahmen zu ergreifen, 
um die Industrie, im Teil zu behinderen, weil dieses Jahr die 
nationale Verbindung der Radio-und Fernsehen-Rundfunkstationen einen 
Code annahm, um Sendung Inhalt zu regeln. Ein Senatreport gab 
nach Hörfähigkeiten 1954 heraus und 1955 auf dem möglichen Einfluß
des Fernsehens auf jugendliche Gesetzesverletzung faßte Studien 
zusammen, um die Quantität der kriminellen und heftigen Taten auf den
Fernsehenerscheinen festzustellen, die für Kinder zur Ansicht 
zugänglich sind. Der Report stellte auch eine Strecke der 
Ansichten an dar, ob ein "kumulativer Effekt der 
Verbrechen-und-Grausigkeit Fernsehenprogramme" zu den Kindern 
schädlich sein könnte. Excerpts vom Report werden von den 
zusätzlichen Meinungen gefolgt, die durch die nationale Verbindung 
für besseren Radio und Fernsehen, eine Befürwortung Gruppe 
eingegeben werden, die 1949 organisiert wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que des émissions expérimentales de 
télévision étaient transmises la première fois dans les années 
20, la production en série des téléviseurs ne s'est pas produite 
jusque 2'après la deuxième guerre mondiale. Par 1960 le nombre
de positionnements aux ETATS-UNIS avait surpassé le nombre de 
maisons. Avec cette introduction relativement rapide de 
télévision dans la vie américaine domestique, le souci a été 
exprimé au-dessus de l'influence nocive que la télévision 
d'observation pourrait avoir sur les enfants de la nation. Plus 
tôt en siècle, les inquiétudes par des progressifs et des 
traditionalistes au sujet des effets nocifs des films sur la jeunesse 
avaient mené aux auditions congressionnelles concernant la censure 
fédérale. Les réformateurs, cependant, manqués convainquant 
l'évidence pour supporter leurs réclamations et l'industrie de film 
cinématographique ont développé un mécanisme pertinent de 
art de l'auto-portrait-censoring pour mettre à jour le contrôle du contenu 
d'écran. De même, après que le congrès ait tenu sa première
audition en 1952 sur l'effet de la télévision sur des enfants, ils 
ont choisi de ne pas prendre n'importe quelle mesure pour gêner 
l'industrie, en partie parce que cette année l'association nationale 
des radiodiffuseurs de radio et de télévision a adopté un code pour
régler le contenu d'émission. Un état de sénat a émis 
après des auditions en 1954 et 1955 sur l'influence possible de la 
télévision sur la délinquance juvénile a récapitulé des études 
pour déterminer la quantité d'actes criminels et violents sur des 
expositions de télévision accessibles aux enfants à la vue. 
L'état également a présenté un intervalle des vues en 
fonction si "un effet cumulatif des émissions télévisées de 
crime-et-horreur" pourrait être nocif aux enfants. Des extraits
de l'état sont suivis des avis supplémentaires soumis par 
l'association nationale pour une meilleures radio et télévision, un 
groupe de recommandation organisé en 1949.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando as transmissões experimentais da 
televisão foram transmitidas primeiramente nos 1920s, a produção 
maciça de jogos de televisão não ocorreu até após a segunda 
guerra mundial. Por 1960 o número dos jogos nos ESTADOS UNIDOS 
surpassed o número das HOME. Com esta introdução 
relativamente rápida da televisão na vida americana doméstica, o 
interesse foi exprimido sobre a influência prejudicial que a 
televisão prestando atenção pôde ter nas crianças da nação. 
Mais cedo no século, as ansiedades  por progressistas e por 
tradicionalistas sobre efeitos prejudiciais dos filmes na juventude 
tinham conduzido aos hearings congressionais a respeito da censura 
federal. Reformers, entretanto, faltado convencendo a evidência
para suportar suas reivindicações e a indústria de retrato de 
movimento desenvolveu um mecanismo self-self-censoring eficaz para 
manter o controle sobre o índice da tela. Similarmente, depois 
que o congress prendeu seu primeiro hearing em 1952 no efeito da 
televisão em crianças, escolheram não fazer exame de nenhuma ação
para interferir com a indústria, na parte porque esse ano a 
associação nacional de radiodifusores do rádio e da televisão 
adotou um código para regular o índice da transmissão. Um 
relatório do senate emitiu após hearings em 1954 e 1955 na 
influência possível da televisão no delinquency juvenile sumariaram
estudos para determinar a quantidade de atos criminal e violentos nas 
mostras da televisão acessíveis para crianças à vista. O 
relatório apresentou também uma escala das vistas sobre se "um 
efeito cumulativo de programas da televisão do 
crime-e-crime-and-horror" poderia ser prejudicial às crianças. 
Os excerpts do relatório são seguidos pelas opiniões 
adicionais submetidas pela associação nacional para o rádio e a 
televisão melhores, um grupo do advocacy organizado em 1949.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre le radiodiffusioni sperimentali della 
televisione in primo luogo sono state trasmesse negli anni 20, la 
fabbricazione in serie dei televisori non si è presentata fino dopo 
alla seconda guerra mondiale. Da 1960 il numero di insiemi negli
STATI UNITI aveva sorpassato il numero di sedi. Con questa 
introduzione relativamente rapida della televisione in vita americana 
domestica, la preoccupazione è stata espressa sopra l'influenza 
nociva che la televisione guardante potrebbe avere sui bambini della 
nazione. Più presto nel secolo, le ansie sia dai progressives 
che dai tradizionalisti circa gli effetti nocivi dei film 
sulla gioventù avevano condotto alle udienze congressuali per quanto 
riguarda censura federale. Reformers, tuttavia, difettato di 
convincendo la prova per sostenere i loro reclami e l'industria 
cinematografica ha sviluppato un meccanismo dicensura efficace per 
effettuare il controllo sopra il soddisfare dello schermo. 
Similmente, dopo che il congresso tenesse la relativa prima 
udienza in 1952 sull'effetto della televisione sui bambini, hanno 
scelto non intraprendere alcun'azione per interferire con l'industria,
in parte perché quell'anno l'associazione nazionale dei distributori 
a spaglio della televisione e della radio ha adottato un codice per 
regolare il soddisfare di radiodiffusione. Un rapporto del 
senato ha pubblicato dopo le udienze in 1954 e 1955 sull'influenza 
possibile della televisione sulla delinquenza giovanile ha 
ricapitolato gli studi per determinare la quantità di atti criminali 
e violenti sulle esposizioni della televisione accessibili ai bambini 
alla vista. Il rapporto egualmente ha presentato una gamma di 
viste sopra se "un effetto cumulativo dei programmi televisivi di 
crimine-e-orrore" potrebbe essere nocivo ai bambini. I brani dal
rapporto sono seguiti dalle opinioni supplementari presentate 
dall'associazione nazionale per la radio e la televisione migliori, un
gruppo di avvocatura organizzato in 1949.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ οι πειραματικές τηλεοπτικές ραδιοφωνικές 
μεταδόσεις μεταδόθηκαν αρχικά στη δεκαετία του '20, η μαζική 
παραγωγή των τηλεοπτικών συνόλων δεν εμφανίστηκε μέχρι τον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Μέχρι το 1960 ο αριθμός συνόλων 
στις ΗΠΑ είχε ξεπεράσει τον αριθμό σπιτιών. Με αυτήν την 
σχετικά γρήγορη εισαγωγή της τηλεόρασης στην εσωτερική 
αμερικανική ζωή, η ανησυχία εκφράστηκε πέρα από την επιβλαβή 
επιρροή που η τηλεόραση προσοχής να έχει στα παιδιά του έθνους. 
Νωρίτερα στον αιώνα, οι ανησυχίες και από Progressives 
και από τα traditionalists για τα επιβλαβή αποτελέσματα των 
κινηματογράφων στη νεολαία είχαν οδηγήσει στις του Κογκρέσου 
ακροάσεις σχετικά με την ομοσπονδιακή λογοκρισία. Οι 
μεταρρυθμιστές, εντούτοις, στερήθηκαν τα πειστικά στοιχεία για να
υποστηρίξουν τις αξιώσεις τους και η βιομηχανία ταινιών ανέπτυξε 
έναν αποτελεσματικό μηχανισμό μόνος-λογοκρισίας για να 
διατηρήσει τον έλεγχο της περιεκτικότητας σε οθόνη. Ομοίως,
μετά από το συνέδριο που έγινε την πρώτη ακρόασή του το 1952
στην επίδραση της τηλεόρασης στα παιδιά, επέλεξαν να μην λάβουν 
οποιαδήποτε μέτρα να παρεμποδίσουν τη βιομηχανία, εν μέρει 
επειδή εκείνο το έτος η εθνική ένωση των εκφωνητών ραδιοφώνων 
και τηλεόρασης υιοθέτησε έναν κώδικα για να ρυθμίσει το 
περιεχόμενο ραδιοφωνικής μετάδοσης. Μια έκθεση Συγκλήτου 
που παρουσιάστηκε μετά από τις ακροάσεις το 1954 και το 1955
στην πιθανή επιρροή της τηλεόρασης στη νεανική εγκληματικότητα 
συνόψισε τις μελέτες για να καθοριστεί η ποσότητα εγκληματικών 
και βίαιων πράξεων στην τηλεόραση εμφανίζει προσιτό για τα 
παιδιά στην όψη. Η έκθεση παρουσίασε επίσης μια σειρά των 
όψεων σχετικά με εάν μια "αθροιστική επίδραση των τηλεοπτικών 
προγραμμάτων έγκλημα-και-φρίκησ" θα μπορούσε να είναι επιβλαβής 
στα παιδιά. Τα αποσπάσματα από την έκθεση ακολουθούνται 
από τις πρόσθετες απόψεις που υποβάλλονται από την εθνική ένωση
για το καλύτερο ραδιόφωνο και την τηλεόραση, μια ομάδα 
υπεράσπισης που οργανώνεται το 1949.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que las difusiones experimentales de la 
televisión primero fueron transmitidas en los años 20, la 
producción en masa de las televisiones no ocurrió hasta después de 
la Segunda Guerra Mundial. Por 1960 el número de conjuntos en 
los ESTADOS UNIDOS había sobrepasado el número de hogares. Con
esta introducción relativamente rápida de la televisión en vida 
americana doméstica, la preocupación fue expresada sobre la 
influencia dañosa que la televisión que miraba pudo tener en los 
niños de la nación. Anterior en el siglo, las ansiedades de 
los progresistas y de los tradicionalistas sobre efectos dañosos de 
películas en la juventud habían conducido a las audiencias del 
congreso con respecto a censura federal. Los reformadores, sin 
embargo, faltados convenciendo a evidencia que utilice sus demandas y 
la industria de película desarrollaron un mecanismo de uno 
mismo-censura eficaz para mantener control sobre contenido de la 
pantalla. Semejantemente, después de que el congreso llevara a 
cabo su primera audiencia en 1952 en el efecto de la televisión en 
niños, eligieron no tomar ninguna acción para interferir con la 
industria, en parte porque ese año la asociación nacional de los 
locutores de la radio y de la televisión adoptó un código para 
regular el contenido de la difusión. Un informe del senado 
publicó después de audiencias en 1954 y 1955 en la influencia 
posible de la televisión en delincuencia juvenil resumió estudios 
para determinar la cantidad de actos criminales y violentos en las 
demostraciones de la televisión accesibles para los niños a la 
visión. El informe también presentó un rango de opiniónes 
encendido si un "efecto acumulativo de los programas de la televisión
del crimen-y-horror" podría ser dañoso a los niños. Los 
extractos del informe son seguidos por las opiniones adicionales 
sometidas por la asociación nacional para una radio y una televisión
mejores, un grupo de la defensa ordenado en 1949.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086922</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105131</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-constant-reiteration-of-horror-and-violence-a-senate-report-on-television-and-juvenile-delinquency</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
