<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104632</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104632</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Friends in High Places: A Pro-Labor Governor Speaks Out</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freunde in den hohen Plätzen: 
Pro-Bearbeiten Sie Regler Spricht Heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Amis dans les endroits élevés : 
Pro-Travaillez Le Gouverneur Parle Dehors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Amigos em lugares elevados: Pro-Trabalhe O 
Regulador Fala Para fora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Amici negli alti posti: Un Regolatore Di 
Pro-lavoro Parla Fuori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φίλοι στις υψηλές θέσεις: Ένας κυβερνήτης 
υπέρ-εργασίας μιλά έξω</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Amigos en altos lugares: Favorable-Trabaje 
El Gobernador Habla Hacia fuera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Davis Waite, the Populist and pro-labor governor of Colorado, won national notoriety in the summer of 1893 after he declared that if change would not come peacefully, it was "better, infinitely better that blood should flow to the horses' bridles than our national liberties should be destroyed." A Republican-controlled lower house blocked many of Waite's initiatives, but he was nonetheless able to use his administrative powers to support workers. In the Cripple Creek strike of 1894, he brought in state troops on behalf of the striking miners--a rare use of state police power in an era when troops were routinely employed to break strikes. When opponents charged Waite's administration with partisanship, he replied defiantly: "Well, what if it is? Is it not the truth that for thirty years the two old parties have been legislating for the creditor class? It is true, and turn about is fair play." This same spirit was evident in his 1893Thanksgiving Day Proclamation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Davis Waite, der Populist und Pro-bearbeiten 
Regler von Kolorado, gewonnene nationale Allbekanntheit am Sommer von 
1893, nachdem er erklärte, daß, wenn Änderung nicht friedlich 
kommen würde, es "besser war, unendlich besser, daß Blut zu den 
Zäumen der Pferde, als fließen sollte unsere nationalen Freiheiten 
zerstört werden sollten." Ein Republikanisch-kontrolliertes 
Unterhaus blockte viele von Initiativen Waites, aber er konnte 
nichtsdestoweniger, seine administrativen Energien zu verwenden, 
Arbeiter zu unterstützen. Im Krüppel-Nebenflußschlag von 
1894, holte er in Zustandtruppen im Namen der auffallenden Bergmänner
-- ein seltener Gebrauch von Zustandpolizeienergie in einer Ära, als 
Truppen routinemäßig beschäftigt wurden, um Schläge zu brechen. 
Als Konkurrenten Leitung Waites mit Parteilichkeit aufluden, 
antwortete er defiantly: "gut, was, wenn es ist? Ist es 
nicht die Wahrheit, die für dreißig Jahre die zwei alten 
Parteien für die Gläubigerkategorie Gesetze gegeben haben? 
Es ist zutreffend und Umdrehung ist ungefähr angemessenes 
Spiel." Dieser gleiche Geist war in seiner proklamation des 
Tag1893Thanksgiving offensichtlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Davis Waite, le populiste et pro-travaillent le 
gouverneur du Colorado, notoriété nationale gagnée en été de 1893
après qu'il ait déclaré que si le changement ne viendrait pas 
paisiblement, il était "meilleur, infiniment mieux que le sang 
devrait couler dans les freins des chevaux que nos libertés 
nationales devraient être détruites." Une Chambre 
Républicain-commandée a bloqué plusieurs des initiatives de Waite, 
mais il pouvait néanmoins utiliser ses puissances administratives de 
supporter des ouvriers. Dans la grève de crique d'estropié de 
1894, il a apporté des troupes d'état au nom des mineurs saisissants
-- une utilisation rare de puissance de police d'état dans une ère 
où des troupes ont été par habitude employées pour casser des 
grèves. Quand les adversaires ont chargé la gestion de Waite 
de l'esprit de parti, il a répondu d'un air provoquant : "bien,
ce qui s'il est ? N'est-ce pas la vérité que pendant trente 
années les deux vieilles parties avaient légiférée pour la classe 
de créancier ? Il est vrai, et le tour est environ franc jeu." 
Cet même esprit était évident dans sa proclamation du jour 
1893Thanksgiving.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Davis Waite, populist e pro-trabalha o regulador 
de Colorado, notoriety nacional ganhado no verão de 1893 depois que 
declarou que se a mudança não vier pacificamente, era "melhor, 
infinita mais melhor que o sangue deve fluir aos breios dos cavalos do
que nossas liberdades nacionais devem ser destruídas." Uma casa
mais baixa Republicano-controlada obstruiu muitas de iniciativas de 
Waite, mas podia nonetheless  usar suas potências administrativas 
suportar trabalhadores. Na batida do creek do aleijado de 1894, 
trouxe em tropas do estado em nome dos mineiros impressionantes -- um 
uso raro da potência das polícias do estado em uma era em que as 
tropas fossem empregadas rotineiramente para quebrar batidas. 
Quando os oponentes carregaram a administração de Waite com o 
partisanship, respondeu defiantly: "bem, que se for? Não 
é a verdade que por trinta anos os dois partidos velhos legislating 
para a classe do credor? É verdadeiro, e a volta é 
aproximadamente jogo justo." Este mesmo espírito era evidente 
em seu proclamation do dia 1893Thanksgiving.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Davis Waite, il populist e regolatore di 
pro-lavoro di Colorado, notoriety nazionale vinto di estate di 1893 
dopo che dichiarasse che se il cambiamento non venisse pacificamente, 
era infinitamente più meglio "migliore, che l'anima dovrebbe fluire i
freni dei cavalli che le nostre libertà nazionali dovrebbero essere 
distrutte." Una Camera di repubblicano-controlled ha ostruito
molte delle iniziative del Waite, ma poteva ciò nonostante usare le 
sue potenzi amministrative sostenere gli operai. Nel colpo 
dell'insenatura del cripple di 1894, ha portato dentro dichiara
le truppe a nome dei minatori notevoli -- un uso raro di 
dichiara l'potenza della polizia in un'era in cui le truppe 
sono state impiegate ordinariamente per rompere i colpi. Quando 
gli avversari hanno caricato la gestione del Waite di partisanship, ha
risposto defiantly: "bene, che cosa se è? Non è la 
verità che per trenta anni i due vecchi partiti stiano legiferando 
per il codice categoria del creditore? È allineare e la girata 
circa è gioco giusto." Questo stesso spirito era evidente nella
sua proclamazione di giorno 1893Thanksgiving.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Νταίηβις Waite, ο λαϊκιστικός και κυβερνήτης 
υπέρ-εργασίας του Κολοράντο, κέρδισαν την εθνική κακή φήμη το 
καλοκαίρι 1893 αφότου δήλωσε ότι εάν η αλλαγή δεν θα ερχόταν
ειρηνικά, ήταν "καλύτερα, απείρως καλύτερα ότι το αίμα πρέπει 
να ρεύσει στα χαλινάρια των αλόγων από οι εθνικές ελευθερίες μας
πρέπει να καταστραφούν." Ένα δημοκρατικός-ελεγχόμενο 
χαμηλότερο σπίτι εμπόδισε πολλών από τις πρωτοβουλίες Waite, 
αλλά ήταν εν τούτοις ικανός να χρησιμοποιήσει τις διοικητικές 
δυνάμεις του να υποστηρίξει τους εργαζομένους. Στη Cripple
απεργία κολπίσκου 1894, έφερε στα κρατικά στρατεύματα εξ 
ονόματος των εντυπωσιακών ανθρακωρύχων -- μια σπάνια χρήση της 
δύναμης κρατικής αστυνομίας σε μια εποχή όταν απασχολήθηκαν 
συνήθως τα στρατεύματα για να σπάσουν τις απεργίες. Όταν οι
αντίπαλοι χρέωσαν την κυβέρνηση Waite με τον κομματισμό, 
απάντησε προκλητικά: "Καλά, τι εάν είναι; Δεν είναι 
η αλήθεια ότι για τριάντα έτη τα δύο παλαιά συμβαλλόμενα μέρη 
έχουν νομοθετήσει για την κλάση πιστωτών; Είναι αληθινό, 
και η στροφή είναι περίπου δίκαιο παιχνίδι." Αυτό το ίδιο
πνεύμα ήταν εμφανές στην προκήρυξη ημέρας 1893Thanksgiving 
του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Davis Waite, el populist y favorable-trabaja el 
gobernador de Colorado, notoriedad nacional ganada en el verano de 
1893 después de que él declarara que si no vendría el cambio 
pacífico, era "mejor, infinitamente mejor que la sangre debe fluir a 
los frenillos de los caballos que nuestras libertades nacionales se 
deben destruir." Más Bajo Republicano-controlado bloqueó 
muchas de las iniciativas de Waite, pero él podía no obstante  
utilizar sus potencias administrativas de apoyar a trabajadores. 
En la huelga del cala del lisiado de 1894, él trajo en tropas 
del estado a nombre de los mineros llamativos -- un uso raro de la 
potencia del policía del estado en una era en que emplearon a las 
tropas rutinariamente para romper huelgas. Cuando los opositores
cargaron la administración de Waite con partisanship, él contestó 
desafiantemente: ¿"bien, qué si es? ¿No es la verdad que 
por treinta años los dos viejos partidos han estado legislando para 
la clase del acreedor? Es verdad, y la vuelta es alrededor juego
justo." Este mismo alcohol era evidente en su proclamación del 
día 1893Thanksgiving.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104632</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/friends-in-high-places-a-pro-labor-governor-speaks-out</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
