<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103328</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103328</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087106</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"This Is No Joke: This Is War": A Live Radio Broadcast of the Attack on Pearl Harbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Dieses Ist Kein Witz: Dieses Ist Krieg ": 
Eine Phasenradiosendung des Angriffs auf Pearl Harbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ce N'est Aucune Plaisanterie : C'est Guerre
": Une émission par radio de phase de l'attaque sur le port de 
perle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Este Não é Nenhum Gracejo: Esta É Guerra
": Uma transmissão de rádio viva do ataque no porto de 
pérola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Questo È Scherzo: Ciò È Guerra ": 
Una radiodiffusione radiofonica in tensione dell'attacco al 
porto di perla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτό δεν είναι κανένα αστείο: Αυτό είναι 
πόλεμος ": Μια ζωντανή ραδιο ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση της 
επίθεσης στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ésta No es Ninguna Broma: Ésta Es Guerra 
": Una difusión de radio viva del ataque contra puerto de 
perla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, on December 7, 1941, stunned virtually everyone in the U.S. military. American intelligence, with the benefit of intercepted Japanese messages, had known for some time that Japan was planning an assault, but military leaders had no idea precisely when and where. Hawaii, they assumed, was so far away from Japan that the Japanese navy could never mount an effective attack. Japan's carrier-launched bombers found Pearl Harbor totally unprepared. A radio broadcast from station KTU in Honolulu the day of the attack captured the events as they unfolded over several hours. From the roof of a Honolulu office building, the radio reporter described significant damage. Apparently, he was calling New York City on the phone, while the New York station broadcast his call to the nation at large.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der japanische Angriff auf Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, 
an Dezember 7, 1941, betäubt praktisch jeder im VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Militär. Amerikanische Intelligenz, mit dem Nutzen der 
abgefangenen japanischen Meldungen, hatte während einiger Zeit 
gewußt, daß Japan einen Angriff plante, aber militärische Führer 
hatten keine Idee genau als und wo. Hawaii, nahmen sie an, waren
von Japan bis jetzt weg, daß die japanische Marine einen 
wirkungsvollen Angriff nie einhängen könnte. Japans 
Fördermaschine-ausgestoßene Bomber fanden Pearl Harbor total 
unvorbereitet. Eine Radiosendung von der Station KTU in Honolulu
der Tag des Angriffs erfaßte die Fälle, während sie über einigen 
Stunden ausbritten. Vom Dach eines Honolulu Bürohauses, 
beschrieb der Radioreporter bedeutende Beschädigung. 
Anscheinend benannte er New York City am Telefon, während die 
New York Stationsendung seins Aufruf zur Nation an großem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'attaque japonaise sur le port de perle, Hawaï, 
7 décembre 1941, assommé pratiquement chacun dans les militaires 
des ETATS-UNIS. L'intelligence américaine, avec l'avantage des 
messages japonais arrêtés, avait su pendant un certain temps que le 
Japon projetait un assaut, mais les amorces militaires n'ont eu aucune
idée avec précision quand et où. Hawaï, ils ont supposé, 
étaient jusqu'ici partis du Japon que la marine japonaise pourrait ne
jamais monter une attaque pertinente. Les bombardiers 
porteur-lancés du Japon ont trouvé le port de perle totalement non 
préparé. Une émission par radio de la station KTU à Honolulu
le jour de l'attaque a capturé les événements pendant qu'ils 
dévoilaient au-dessus de plusieurs heures. Du toit d'un 
bâtiment de bureau de Honolulu, le journaliste par radio a décrit 
des dommages significatifs. Apparemment, il appelait New York 
City au téléphone, alors que l'émission de station de New York sien
appel à la nation dans son ensemble.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ataque japonês no porto de pérola, Havaí, 
dezembro em 7, 1941, stunned virtualmente todos nas forças armadas de
ESTADOS UNIDOS. A inteligência americana, com o benefício de 
mensagens japonesas interceptadas, tinha sabido por alguma hora que 
Japão planeava um assalto, mas os líderes militares não tiveram 
nenhuma idéia precisamente quando e onde. Havaí, supuseram, 
foram assim distantes afastado de Japão que a marinha japonesa 
poderia nunca montar um ataque eficaz. Os bombardeiros 
portador-lançados de Japão encontraram o porto de pérola totalmente
unprepared. Uma transmissão de rádio da estação KTU em 
Honolulu o dia do ataque capturou os eventos enquanto unfolded sobre 
diversas horas. Do telhado de um edifício de escritório de 
Honolulu, o repórter de rádio descreveu os danos significativos. 
Aparentemente, chamava New York City no telefone, quando a 
transmissão da estação de New York his atendimento à nação em 
grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'attacco giapponese al porto di perla, Hawai, il 
7 dicembre 1941, stordito virtualmente tutto nei militari degli STATI 
UNITI. L'intelligenza americana, con il beneficio dei messaggi 
giapponesi intercettati, aveva saputo per un certo tempo che il 
Giappone stava progettando un assalto, ma i capi militari non 
hanno avuti precisamente idea quando e dove. L'Hawai, hanno 
presupposto, erano finora assenti dal Giappone che il blu marino 
giapponese potrebbe non montare mai un attacco efficace. I 
bombardieri elemento-lanciati del Giappone hanno trovato il porto di 
perla completamente non preparato. Una radiodiffusione 
radiofonica dalla stazione KTU a Honolulu il giorno dell'attacco ha 
bloccato gli eventi mentre hanno spiegato sopra parecchie ore. 
Dal tetto di una costruzione di ufficio de Honolulu, il 
reporter radiofonico ha descritto danni significativi. 
Apparentemente, stava chiamando New York City sul telefono, 
mentre la radiodiffusione della stazione de New York suo chiamata alla
nazione nel suo insieme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιαπωνική επίθεση στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, Χαβάη, 
στις 7 Δεκεμβρίου ..1941, ζάλισε ουσιαστικά της καθεμίας στις 
ΗΠΑ στρατιωτικές. Η αμερικανική νοημοσύνη, με το όφελος των 
παρεμποδισμένων ιαπωνικών μηνυμάτων, ήξερε για κάποιο χρόνο ότι
η Ιαπωνία προγραμμάτιζε μια επίθεση, αλλά οι στρατιωτικοί ηγέτες
δεν είχαν καμία ιδέα ακριβώς όταν και όπου. Η Χαβάη, 
υπέθεσαν, ήταν τόσο μακριά από την Ιαπωνία ότι το ιαπωνικό 
ναυτικό δεν θα μπορούσε ποτέ να επικολλήσει μια αποτελεσματική 
επίθεση. Τα μεταφορέας-προωθημένα βομβαρδιστικά αεροπλάνα 
της Ιαπωνίας βρήκαν το λιμάνι μαργαριταριών συνολικά 
απροετοίμαστο. Μια ραδιο ραδιοφωνική μετάδοση από το σταθμό
KTU στη Χονολουλού η ημέρα της επίθεσης συνέλαβε τα γεγονότα 
όπως ξετύλιξαν κατά τη διάρκεια αρκετών ωρών. Από τη 
στέγη ενός κτηρίου γραφείων της Χονολουλού, ο ραδιο 
δημοσιογράφος περιέγραψε τη σημαντική ζημία. Προφανώς, 
καλούσε την πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης στο τηλέφωνο, ενώ ο σταθμός 
της Νέας Υόρκης μετέδωσε ραδιοφωνικά την κλήση του στο έθνος 
κατά πολύ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ataque japonés contra el puerto de perla, 
Hawaii, 7 de diciembre de 1941, atontado virtualmente cada uno en 
los militares de ESTADOS UNIDOS. La inteligencia americana, con 
la ventaja de mensajes japoneses interceptados, había sabido por una 
cierta hora que Japón planeaba un asalto, pero los arranques de cinta
militares no tenían ninguna idea exacto cuando y donde. Hawaii,
asumieron, estaban hasta ahora ausentes de Japón que la marina de guerra 
japonesa podría nunca montar un ataque eficaz. Los bombarderos 
portador-lanzados de Japón encontraron el puerto de perla totalmente 
sin preparación. Una difusión de radio de la estación KTU en 
Honolulu el día del ataque capturó los acontecimientos mientras que 
revelaron sobre varias horas. De la azotea de un edificio de 
oficinas de Honolulu, el reportero de radio describió daño 
significativo. Al parecer, él llamaba New York City en el 
teléfono, mientras que la difusión de la estación de Nueva York el 
suyo llamada a la nación en grande.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087106</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103328</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/this-is-no-joke-this-is-war-a-live-radio-broadcast-of-the-attack-on-pearl-harbor</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
