<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104797</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104797</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212962</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Using an Earth History Approach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verwenden einer Masse Geschichte Annäherung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisation d'une approche d'histoire de la terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usando uma aproximação do history da terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Usando un metodo di storia della terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρησιμοποίηση μιας προσέγγισης γήινης ιστορίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usar un acercamiento de la historia de la tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Starting point module is written to assist geoscience faculty who are developing or modifying courses or units on Earth history/historical geology or on contemporary topics that benefit from a historical perspective. It provides information on what this approach is, why it is useful, how to make use of it and includes an annotated list of references and resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Vorlage geoscience Lehrkörper dieses 
Ausgangspunktmodul wird geschrieben, das sind, ändernd entwickelnd 
oder Kurse oder Maßeinheiten auf Masse history/historical Geologie 
oder auf zeitgenössischen Themen, die von einer historischen 
Perspektive profitieren. Es stellt Informationen auf zur 
Verfügung, was diese Annäherung ist, warum es nützlich ist, wie man
sie und einschließt eine angemerkte Liste von Referenzen und von 
Betriebsmitteln gebraucht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module de point de départ est écrit au corps 
enseignant de geoscience d'aide qui sont développant ou modifiant des
cours ou des unités sur la géologie de la terre history/historical 
ou sur les sujets contemporains qui tirent bénéfice d'une 
perspective historique. Il fournit des informations sur ce 
qu'est, pourquoi il est utile, comment se servir d'elles et inclut 
cette approche une liste annotée de références et de ressources.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo do ponto começar é escrito à 
faculdade do geoscience da assistência que é desenvolvendo ou 
modificando cursos ou unidades na geologia da terra history/historical
ou nos tópicos contemporary que se beneficiam de um perspective 
histórico. Fornece a informação em o que esta aproximação 
é, porque é útil, como a empregar e inclui uma lista anotada das 
referências e dos recursos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo del punto di partenza è scritto 
alla facoltà di geoscience di aiuto che è sviluppante o modificante 
i corsi o le unità sulla geologia della terra history/historical o 
sui soggetti contemporanei che traggono beneficio da una prospettiva 
storica. Fornisce le informazioni su che cosa questo metodo è, 
perchè è utile, come usarle ed include una lista annotata dei 
riferimenti e delle risorse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα αφετηρίας γράφεται για να βοηθήσει τη 
σχολή geoscience που αναπτύσσει ή τροποποιεί τις σειρές 
μαθημάτων ή τις μονάδες στη γήινη ιστορία/την ιστορική γεωλογία
ή στα σύγχρονα θέματα που ωφελούνται από μια ιστορική 
προοπτική. Παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για αυτό που αυτή η 
προσέγγιση είναι, γιατί είναι χρήσιμο, πώς να την 
χρησιμοποιήσει και περιλαμβάνει έναν σχολιασμένο κατάλογο 
αναφορών και στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo del punto de partida se escribe a la 
facultad del geoscience de la ayuda que es que desarrolla o de 
modificación de cursos o de unidades en la geología de la tierra 
history/historical o en los asuntos contemporáneos que benefician de 
una perspectiva histórica. Proporciona a la información en 
cuáles es, porqué es útil, cómo hacerla uso e incluye este 
acercamiento una lista anotada de referencias y de recursos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REBECCA TEED
FN:REBECCA TEED
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212962</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104797</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/using-an-earth-history-approach</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
