<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106221</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106221</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211260</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Park Service - Nature Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationalpark-Service - Natur-Netz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Service de Parc National - Filet de Nature</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Serviço Do Parque Nacional - Rede Da Natureza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Servizio Del Parco Nazionale - Rete Della Natura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική υπηρεσία πάρκων - δίκτυο φύσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Servicio Del Parque Nacional - Red De la 
Naturaleza</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Nature Net encompasses five web sites that cover air quality, biology, geology, social science and water resources within the National Park Service. Each category includes general information, descriptions of programs and policies, scientific information, publications, educational resources and photographs. This site is a good starting point for research or information about the natural resources of our National Parks. This resource is part of the Biocomplexity collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Natur-Netz gibt fünf Web-Sites um, die 
Luftqualität, Biologie, Geologie, Sozialwissenschaft und 
Wasserbetriebsmittel innerhalb des Nationalpark-Services umfassen. 
Jede Kategorie enthält allgemeine Informationen, Beschreibungen
von Programmen und von politischen Richtlinien, Fachinformation, 
Publikationen, pädagogische Betriebsmittel und Fotographien. 
Diese Site ist ein guter Ausgangspunkt zu Forschung oder 
Information über die Naturresourcen unserer Nationalparks. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der Biocomplexity Ansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le filet de nature entoure cinq sites de Web qui 
couvrent la qualité d'air, la biologie, la géologie, la science 
sociale et les ressources d'eau dans le service de parc national. 
Chaque catégorie inclut des informations générales, des 
descriptions des programmes et des politiques, l'information 
scientifique, des publications, des ressources éducatives et des 
photographies. Ce site est un bon point de départ pour la 
recherche ou les informations sur les ressources naturelles de nos 
parcs nationaux. Cette ressource fait partie de la collection 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A rede da natureza abrange cinco locais do Web que
cobrem a qualidade do ar, a biologia, a geologia, a ciência social e 
os recursos de água dentro do serviço do parque nacional. Cada
categoria inclui a informação geral, as descrições dos programas e
das políticas, a informação científica, as publicações, recursos
educacionais e fotografias. Este local é um ponto começar bom 
para a pesquisa ou a informação sobre os recursos naturais de nossos
parques nacionais. Este recurso é parte da coleção 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La rete della natura comprende cinque luoghi di 
Web che riguardano la qualità dell'aria, la biologia, la geologia, la
scienza sociale e le risorse idriche all'interno del servizio del 
parco nazionale. Ogni categoria include le generalità, le 
descrizioni dei programmi e delle politiche, l'informazione 
scientifica, le pubblicazioni, le risorse educative e le fotografie. 
Questo luogo è un buon punto di partenza per ricerca o le 
informazioni sulle risorse naturali dei nostri parchi nazionali. 
Questa risorsa fa parte dell'accumulazione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ di Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το δίκτυο φύσης καλύπτει πέντε ιστοχώρους που 
καλύπτουν την ατμοσφαιρική ποιότητα, τη βιολογία, τη γεωλογία, 
τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες και τους υδάτινους πόρους μέσα στην 
εθνική υπηρεσία πάρκων. Κάθε κατηγορία περιλαμβάνει τις 
γενικές πληροφορίες, τις περιγραφές των προγραμμάτων και των 
πολιτικών, τις επιστημονικές πληροφορίες, τις δημοσιεύσεις, τα 
εκπαιδευτικές στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και τις φωτογραφίες. 
Αυτή η περιοχή είναι μια καλή αφετηρία για την έρευνα ή 
πληροφορίες για τα φυσικά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς των εθνικών 
πάρκων μας. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος της 
Biocomplexity συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La red de la naturaleza abarca cinco sitios del 
Web que cubran calidad del aire, biología, la geología, la ciencia 
social y recursos de agua dentro del servicio del parque nacional. 
Cada categoría incluye la información de carácter general, 
descripciones de programas y de políticas, la información 
científica, las publicaciones, los recursos educativos y las 
fotografías. Este sitio es un buen punto de partida para la 
investigación o la información sobre los recursos naturales de 
nuestros parques nacionales. Este recurso es parte de la 
colección http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211260</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106221</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-park-service-nature-net</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
