<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106850</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106850</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087318</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A map of servitude.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Karte der Versklavung.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une carte de servitude.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um mapa do servitude.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un programma del servitude.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας χάρτης της δουλείας.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una correspondencia de la servidumbre.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The back of a Louisiana slave named Gordon, photographed in 1863 after he escaped to the Union forces. Whipping was the most common form of punishment on plantations, and slaveowners and overseers whipped slaves with frightening regularity. Slaves could be whipped for almost any pretext: for "not picking cotton," "or not picking as well as he can," for picking "very trashy cotton," and so forth. One overseer gave twelve lashes to eight women for "hoeing bad corn." While punishments were often work related, whipping was also used to humiliate slaves and instill deference, obedience, and servility. Slaves could be whipped for answering back to overseers or appearing in any way "insolent."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Rückseite von einem Louisiana benannter 
Sklavengordon, fotografiert 1863, nachdem er zu den Anschlußkräften 
entging. Das Peitschen war das geläufigste Formular der 
Bestrafung auf Plantagen, und slaveowners und Aufseher peitschten 
Sklaven mit erschreckender Gleichmässigkeit. Sklaven konnten 
für fast jeden möglichen Vorwand gepeitscht werden: für 
"Baumwolle nicht und so weiter auswählen," "oder nicht sowie ihn 
auswählen Dose," für trashy Baumwolle des Sammelns "sehr,". 
Ein Aufseher gab acht Frauen für "hackenden falschen Mais 
zwölf Peitschen." Während Bestrafungen häufig die in 
Verbindung gestandene Arbeit waren, wurde das Peitschen auch 
verwendet, um Sklaven zu demütigen und Achtung, Gehorsam und 
servility einzuflößen. Sklaven konnten für das Antworten 
zurück zu Aufsehern gepeitscht werden oder das Erscheinen in jeder 
unverschämter Hinsicht "."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le dos de la Louisiane Gordon nommé slave, 
photographié en 1863 après qu'il se soit échappé aux forces des 
syndicats. La fouettée était la forme la plus commune de la 
punition sur des plantations, et les slaveowners et les contrôleurs 
ont fouetté des esclaves avec la régularité effrayante. Des 
esclaves ont pu être fouettés pour presque n'importe quel prétexte 
: pour "ne pas sélectionner le coton," "ou ne pas sélectionner
comme lui bidon," pour le coton très sans valeur de cueillette "," et
ainsi de suite. Un contrôleur a donné douze mèches à huit 
femmes pour "le maïs gâté de houement." Tandis que les 
punitions étaient souvent travail associé, la fouettée a été 
également employée pour humilier des esclaves et pour instiller la 
déférence, l'obéissance, et la servilité. Des esclaves ont 
pu être fouettés pour répondre de nouveau aux contrôleurs ou 
apparaître de quelque façon "insolent."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A parte traseira de um Louisiana Gordon nomeado slave, 
fotografada em 1863 depois que se escapou às forças da união. 
Chicotear era o formulário o mais comum da punição em 
plantações, e os slaveowners e os overseers chicotearam escravos com
regularity frightening. Os escravos podiam ser chicoteados para 
quase todo o pretext: para "não escolher o algodão," "ou não 
o escolher assim como ele lata," para o algodão muito trashy da 
colheita "," e assim por diante. Um overseer deu doze chicotes a
oito mulheres para "o milho mau hoeing." Quando as punições 
eram frequentemente trabalho relacionado, chicotear foi usado também 
humilhar escravos e instill o deference, o obedience, e o servility. 
Os escravos podiam ser chicoteados respondendo para trás aos 
overseers ou aparecendo em toda a maneira "insolent."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La parte posteriore della Luisiana Gordon chiamato slave, 
fotografata in 1863 dopo che fuoriesca alle forze del sindacato. 
Sbattere era la forma più comune della punizione sulle 
piantagioni e gli slaveowners ed i overseers hanno sbattuto gli 
schiavi con regolarità spaventosa. Gli schiavi hanno potuto 
essere sbattuti per quasi tutto il pretesto: per "il 
selezionamento del cotone," "o il selezionamento come pure lui latta,"
per il cotone molto trashy di raccolto "," e così via. Un 
overseer ha dato dodici sferze ad otto donne per "cereale difettoso di
zappatura." Mentre le punizioni erano spesso lavoro riguardante,
sbattere egualmente è stato usato per umiliare gli schiavi ed 
infondere la deferenza, il obedience ed il servility. Gli 
schiavi hanno potuto essere sbattuti per la risposta di nuovo ai 
overseers o comparire in tutto il modo "insolent."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πλάτη ενός σκλάβου της Λουιζιάνας ονόμασε 
Gordon, που φωτογραφίστηκε το 1863 αφότου δραπέτευσε στις 
δυνάμεις ένωσης. Το κτύπημα ήταν η πιό κοινή μορφή της 
τιμωρίας στις φυτείες, και τα slaveowners και τα overseers 
κτύπησαν τους σκλάβους με τον εκφοβισμό της τακτικότητας. Οι
σκλάβοι θα μπορούσαν να κτυπηθούν για σχεδόν οποιαδήποτε 
πρόφαση: για "το βαμβάκι μη επιλογής," "ή μη επιλογή καθώς
επίσης και μπορεί," για το σκάρτο βαμβάκι επιλογής "πολύ," και 
ούτω καθ'εξής. Ένα overseer έδωσε δώδεκα μαστίγια σε 
οκτώ γυναίκες για "το κακό καλαμπόκι σκαψίματος με σκαπάνη." 
Ενώ οι τιμωρίες ήταν συχνά εργασία σχετική, το κτύπημα 
χρησιμοποιήθηκε επίσης για να ταπεινώσει τους σκλάβους και να 
ενσταλάξει το σεβασμό, την υπακοή, και τη δουλικότητα. Οι 
σκλάβοι θα μπορούσαν να κτυπηθούν για την απάντηση πίσω στα 
overseers ή την εμφάνιση από καμιά άποψη "θρασιοί."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La parte posteriora de una Luisiana Gordon nombrado 
auxiliar, fotografiada en 1863 después de que él se escapara a las 
fuerzas de la unión. El azotar era la forma más común de 
castigo en plantaciones, y los slaveowners y los overseers azotaron 
esclavos con regularidad espantosa. Los esclavos se podían 
azotar para casi cualquier pretexto: para "no escoger algodón,"
"o no escoger tan bien como él lata," para el algodón muy trashy de 
la cosecha "," y así sucesivamente. Un overseer dio doce 
latigazos a ocho mujeres para de "mal maíz azada." Mientras que
los castigos eran a menudo trabajo relacionado, el azotar también fue
utilizado para humillar esclavos y para inculcar respeto, obediencia, 
y servility. Los esclavos se podían azotar para contestar de 
nuevo a overseers o aparecer de cualquier manera "insolente."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087318</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106850</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-map-of-servitude</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
