<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108708</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108708</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086298</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Was a Cabinet-maker By Trade": A Working Man's Recollections of America, 1825-35</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich war ein Schrank-Hersteller durch Handel": 
Erinnerungen eines Funktion Mannes von Amerika, 1825-35</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'étais un Module-générateur par le commerce" 
: Les souvenirs d'un ouvrier de l'Amérique, 1825-35</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu era um Armário-fabricante pelo comércio": 
Recollections de homem de funcionamento de América, 1825-35</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ero un Armadietto-creatore tramite commercio": 
Ricordi dell'uomo di funzionamento dell'America, 1825-35</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"ήμουν επιπλοποιός από το εμπόριο": Ανθρώπινες 
αναμνήσεις μιας εργασίας της Αμερικής, 1825-35</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"era un Cabina-fabricante por comercio": 
Recuerdos de un hombre de funcionamiento de América, 1825-35</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Urban artisans experienced dramatic changes in the second quarter of the 19th century. New York and other cities were destinations of choice for many rural mechanics as well as those coming from overseas. Upon arrival they found workshops in great flux as traditional social relations among master, journeyman, and apprentice were being transformed into an employer-employee relationship. In some crafts, such as cabinetmaking, change came more slowly because of the complexities of fashioning large case furniture. In other trades, such as tailoring, tiny sweatshops started to dot the city streets. A new working class was coming into being, often with a variety of religions and backgrounds, and they organized to contest these and other changes in work conditions and compensation. This anonymous account from a British periodical in 1845 related the experience of a British cabinetmaker in New York in the 1830s; he eventually returned home.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Städtische Handwerker erfuhren drastische 
Änderungen im zweiten Viertel des 19. Jahrhunderts. New York 
und andere Städte waren Zieleinheiten der Wahl für viele 
landwirtschaftliche Mechaniker sowie die, die von übersee kommen. 
Nach Ankunft fanden sie Werkstätten im großen Fluß, während 
traditionelle Sozialrelationen unter Meister, Facharbeiter und 
Lehrling in ein Arbeitgeber-Arbeitnehmer-Verhältnis umgewandelt 
wurden. In einigen Fertigkeiten wie Cabinetmaking, kam Änderung
langsam wegen der Kompliziertheiten der Formgebung der großen 
Fallmöbel. In anderem Handel wie Herstellen, begannen kleine 
Fabriken mit schlechten Arbeitsbedingungen, die Stadtstraßen zu 
punktieren. Eine neue Funktion Kategorie kam in Sein, häufig 
mit einer Vielzahl von Religionen und von Hintergründen, und sie 
organisierten, um diese und andere Änderungen in dem Arbeit 
Zuständen und Ausgleich zu wetteifern. Dieses anonyme Konto von
einer britischen Zeitschrift in 1845 stand die Erfahrung eines 
britischen cabinetmaker in New York im 1830s in Verbindung; er 
kam schließlich nach Hause zurück.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les artisans urbains ont éprouvé les changements
excessifs du deuxième trimestre du 19ème siècle. New York et 
d'autres villes étaient des destinations de choix pour beaucoup de 
mécanique rurale aussi bien que ceux venant de outre-mer. Sur 
l'arrivée ils ont trouvé des ateliers dans le grand flux pendant que
des relations sociales traditionnelles parmi le maître, le compagnon,
et l'apprenti étaient transformées en rapport d'employeur à 
employé. Dans quelques métiers, tels que cabinetmaking, le 
changement est venu plus lentement en raison des complexités de 
façonner de grands meubles de cas. Dans d'autres commerces, 
tels que la mise sur pied, les bagnes minuscules ont commencé à 
pointiller les rues de ville. Une nouvelle classe ouvrière se 
produisait, souvent avec une variété de religions et de milieux, et 
ils ont organisé pour contester ces derniers et d'autres changements 
des états et de la compensation de travail. Ce compte anonyme 
d'un périodique britannique dans 1845 a associé l'expérience d'un 
ébéniste britannique à New York dans le 1830s ; il par la 
suite est retourné à la maison.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os artisans urbanos experimentaram mudanças 
dramáticas no segundo quarto do 1ø século. New York e outras 
cidades eram destinos da escolha para muitos mecânicos rurais 
as.well.as aquelas que vêm de no ultramar. Em cima da chegada 
encontraram oficinas no fluxo grande enquanto as relações sociais 
tradicionais entre o mestre, o journeyman, e o aprendiz eram 
transformadas em um relacionamento employer-employee. Em alguns 
ofícios, tais como cabinetmaking, a mudança veio mais lentamente por
causa das complexidades de formar o furniture grande do caso. Em
outros comércios, tais como costurar, os sweatshops minúsculos 
começaram pontilhar as ruas da cidade. Uma classe de 
funcionamento nova estava vindo em ser, frequentemente com uma 
variedade das religiões e dos fundos, e organizaram para contestar 
estes e outras mudanças em condições e em compensação do 
trabalho. Este cliente anonymous de um periodical britânico em 
1845 relacionou a experiência de um cabinetmaker britânico em New 
York no 1830s; retornou eventualmente para casa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli artigianale urbani hanno avvertito i 
cambiamenti drammatici nel secondo trimestre del diciannovesimo 
secolo. New York ed altre città erano destinazioni della scelta
per molti meccanici rurali così come quelle che vengono da oltremare.
Sull'arrivo hanno trovato i workshop nel cambiamento continuo 
grande mentre i rapporti sociali tradizionali fra il supervisore, 
l'operaio qualificato e l'apprendista stavano trasformandi in un 
rapporto employer-employee. In alcuni mestieri, come 
cabinetmaking, il cambiamento è venuto più lentamente a causa delle 
complessità di adattare la grande mobilia di caso. In altri 
commerci, come adattamento, le azienda che sfrutta la manodopera molto
piccole hanno cominciato punteggiare le vie della città. Un 
nuovo codice categoria di funzionamento stava producendo, spesso con 
una varietà di religioni e di ambiti di provenienza ed hanno 
organizzato per contestare questi ed altri cambiamenti negli stati e 
nella compensazione del lavoro. Questo cliente anonimo da un 
periodico britannico in 1845 ha collegato l'esperienza in un 
cabinetmaker britannico a New York nel 1830s; finalmente ha 
ritornato a casa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα αστικά artisans δοκίμασαν τις δραματικές αλλαγές
στο δεύτερο τέταρτο του 19$ου αιώνα. Η Νέα Υόρκη και άλλες
πόλεις ήταν προορισμοί της επιλογής για πολλούς αγροτικούς 
μηχανικούς καθώς επίσης και εκείνους που προέρχονται από στο 
εξωτερικό. Επάνω στην άφιξη βρήκαν τα εργαστήρια στη 
μεγάλη ροή δεδομένου ότι οι παραδοσιακές κοινωνικές σχέσεις 
μεταξύ του κυρίου, του τεχνίτη, και του μαθητευόμενου 
μετασχηματίζονταν σε μια σχέση εργοδότης-υπαλλήλων. Σε 
μερικές τέχνες, όπως, η αλλαγή ήρθε πιό αργά λόγω των 
περιπλοκών της διαμόρφωσης των μεγάλων επίπλων περίπτωσης. 
Σε άλλα εμπόρια, όπως η προσαρμογή, τα μικροσκοπικά 
σκλαβοπάζαρο άρχισαν να διαστίζουν τις οδούς πόλεων. Μια 
νέα εργατική τάξη δημιουργούταν, συχνά με ποικίλα θρησκείες και
υπόβαθρα, και οργάνωσαν για να αμφισβητήσουν αυτές και άλλες 
αλλαγές στους όρους και την αποζημίωση εργασίας. Αυτός ο 
ανώνυμος απολογισμός από ένα βρετανικό περιοδικό το 1845 
αφορούσε την εμπειρία ενός βρετανικού επιπλοποιού στη Νέα Υόρκη
στο 1830s  επέστρεψε τελικά το σπίτι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los artesanos urbanos experimentaron cambios 
dramáticos en el segundo trimestre del diecinueveavo siglo. 
Nueva York y otras ciudades eran destinaciones de la opción 
para muchos mecánicos rurales así como ésas que venían de en 
ultramar. Sobre llegada encontraron talleres en gran flux 
mientras que las relaciones sociales tradicionales entre amo, oficial,
y aprendiz eran transformadas en un lazo employer-employee. En 
algunos artes, tales como cabinetmaking, el cambio vino más 
lentamente debido a las complejidades de formar los muebles grandes 
del caso. En otros comercios, tales como adaptación, las 
fábricas de explotación minúsculas comenzaron a puntear las calles 
de la ciudad. Una nueva clase obrera venía en estar, a menudo 
con una variedad de religiones y de fondos, y ordenaron para disputar 
éstos y otros cambios en condiciones y la remuneración del trabajo. 
Esta cuenta anónima de un periódico británico en 1845 
relacionó la experiencia de un cabinetmaker británico en Nueva York 
en el 1830s; él volvió eventual a casa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086298</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108708</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-was-a-cabinet-maker-by-trade-a-working-mans-recollections-of-america-1825-35</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
