<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108239</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108239</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086763</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Protestant Paranoia: The American Protective Association Oath</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Protestierender Paranoia: Der Amerikanische 
Schützende Verbindung Eid</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Paranoïa Protestante : Le Serment 
Protecteur Américain d'Association</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Paranoia Protestant: O Juramento Protetor 
Americano Da Associação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Paranoia Protestante: Il Giuramento 
Protettivo Americano Di Associazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προτεσταντική παράνοια: Ο αμερικανικός 
προστατευτικός όρκος ένωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paranoia Protestante: El Juramento Protector
Americano De la Asociación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1887, Henry F. Bowers founded the nativist American Protective Association (APA) in Clinton, Iowa. Bowers was a Mason, and he drew from its fraternal ritual--elaborate regalia, initiation ceremonies, and a secret oath--in organizing the APA. He also drew many Masons, an organization that barred Catholics. The organization quickly acquired an anti-union cast. Among other things, the APA claimed that the Catholic leader of the Knights, Terence V. Powderly, was part of a larger conspiracy against American institutions. Even so, the APA successfully recruited significant numbers of disaffected trade unionists in an era of economic hard times and the collapse of the Knights of Labor. This secret oath taken by members of the American Protective Association in the 1890s revealed the depth of Protestant distrust and fear of Catholics holding public office.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1887 gründete Henry F. Bowers die nativist 
amerikanische schützende Verbindung (APA) in Clinton, Iowa. 
Bowers waren ein Maurer und er zeichnete von seinem 
brüderlichen Ritual -- durchdachtes regalia, Inbetriebnahmezeremonien
und ein geheimer Eid -- wenn er das APA organisierte. Er 
zeichnete auch viele Maurer, eine Organisation, die Katholische 
abhielt. Die Organisation erwarb schnell eine Anti-Anschluß 
Form. Unter anderem behauptete das APA, daß der katholische 
Führer der Ritter, Terence V. Powderly, ein Teil einer größeren 
Verschwörung gegen amerikanische Anstalten war. Allerdings 
disaffected die APA erfolgreich eingezogenen bedeutenden Zahlen von 
Gewerkschaftler in einer Ära der ökonomischen harten Zeiten und im 
Einsturz der Ritter der Arbeit. Dieser geheime Eid, der von den 
Bauteilen der amerikanischen schützenden Verbindung im 1890s 
geschworen wurde, deckte die Tiefe des protestierenden Mißtrauens und
Furcht vor den Katholischen auf, die öffentliche Dienststelle 
bekleiden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1887, Henry F. Bowers a fondé l'association 
protectrice américaine nativiste (APA) dans Clinton, Iowa. 
Les tonnelles étaient un maçon, et il a tiré de son rituel 
fraternel -- régalia raffiné, cérémonies de déclenchement, et 
un serment secret -- en organisant l'APA. Il a également 
dessiné beaucoup de maçons, une organisation qui a interdit à des 
catholiques. L'organisation a rapidement saisi une fonte 
d'anti-union. Entre autres, l'APA a réclamé que l'amorce 
catholique des chevaliers, Terence V. Powderly, faisait partie d'une 
plus grande conspiration contre les établissements américains. 
Néanmoins, l'APA a avec succès recruté des nombres 
significatifs des syndicalistes mécontents dans une ère des 
périodes difficiles économiques et l'effondrement des chevaliers du 
travail. Ce serment secret pris par des membres de l'association
protectrice américaine dans le 1890s a indiqué la profondeur de la 
méfiance protestante et la crainte des catholiques tenant le bureau 
public.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1887, o Henry F. Bowers fundou a associação 
protetora americana nativist (APA) em Clinton, Iowa. Os bowers 
eram um mason, e desenhou de seu ritual fraternal -- regalia 
elaborado, ceremonies da iniciação, e um juramento secreto -- em 
organizar o APA. Desenhou também muitos masons, uma 
organização que barrasse catholics. A organização adquiriu 
rapidamente um molde da anti-união. Entre outras coisas, o APA 
reivindicou que o líder catholic dos knights, Terence V. Powderly, 
era parte de um conspiracy maior de encontro às instituições 
americanas. Mesmo assim, os números significativos com sucesso 
recrutados de APA de disaffected os unionists de comércio em uma era 
de épocas duras econômicas e no colapso dos knights do trabalho. 
Este juramento secreto feito exame por membros da associação 
protetora americana no 1890s revelou a profundidade do distrust 
protestant e o medo dos catholics que prendem o escritório público.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1887, il henry F. Bowers ha fondato 
l'associazione protettiva americana nativist (APA) in Clinton, Iowa. 
I bowers erano un mason ed ha dissipato dal relativo rituale 
fraterno -- regalia elaborato, cerimonie di inizio e un giuramento 
segreto -- nell'organizzazione del APA. Egualmente ha dissipato 
molti masons, un'organizzazione che ha escluso i cattolici. 
L'organizzazione ha acquistato rapidamente un getto 
dell'anti-unione. Tra l'altro, il APA ha sostenuto che il 
capo cattolico dei cavalieri, Terence V. Powderly, faceva parte
di più grande cospirazione contro le istituzioni americane. 
Nondimeno, i numeri significativi con successo reclutati di APA 
di disaffected i sindacalisti in un'era dei periodi duri economici e 
nel crollo dei cavalieri del Lavoro. Questo giuramento 
segreto preso dai membri dell'associazione protettiva americana nel 
1890s ha rivelato la profondità della diffidenza protestante ed il 
timore dell'ufficio pubblico della tenuta dei cattolici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1887, Henry F. Bowers ίδρυσε την 
αμερικανική προστατευτική ένωση nativist (APA) σε Clinton,
Iowa. Οι κιόσκι ήταν κτίστης, και έσυρε από το αδελφικό
τελετουργικό του -- επιμελημένο βασιλικό έμβλημα, τελετές 
έναρξης, και ένας μυστικός όρκος -- στην οργάνωση του APA. 
Έσυρε επίσης πολλούς κτίστες, μια οργάνωση που έφραξε τους
Καθολικούς. Η οργάνωση απόκτησε γρήγορα μια αντι-ένωση 
χυτή. Μεταξύ άλλων, το APA υποστήριξε ότι ο καθολικός 
ηγέτης των ιπποτών, Terence Θ*Β. Powderly, ήταν μέρος μιας 
μεγαλύτερης συνωμοσίας ενάντια στα αμερικανικά όργανα. 
Ακόμα κι έτσι, το APA στρατολόγησε επιτυχώς τους 
σημαντικούς αριθμούς δυσαρεστημένων συνδικαλιστών σε μια εποχή 
των οικονομικών σκληρών χρόνων και την κατάρρευση των ιπποτών της
εργασίας. Αυτός ο μυστικός όρκος που λήφθηκε από τα μέλη 
της αμερικανικής προστατευτικής ένωσης στο 1890s αποκάλυψε το 
βάθος της προτεσταντικής δυσπιστίας και το φόβο των Καθολικών που
κρατούν το δημόσιο γραφείο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1887, el Henrio F. Bowers fundó la asociación
protectora americana nativista (APA) en Clinton, Iowa. Los 
bowers eran masón, y él trazó de su ritual fraternal -- regalía 
elaborada, ceremonias del lanzamiento, y un juramento secreto -- en la
ordenación del APA. Él también trazó a muchos masones, una 
organización que barró a católicos. La organización 
adquirió rápidamente un molde de la contra-unio'n. Entre otras
cosas, el APA demandó que el arranque de cinta católico de los 
caballeros, Terence V. Powderly, era parte de una conspiración más 
grande contra las instituciones americanas. Incluso así pues, 
los números significativos con éxito reclutados de APA de 
disaffected a unionistas comerciales en una era de épocas duras 
económicas y el derrumbamiento de los caballeros del trabajo. 
Este juramento secreto tomado por los miembros de la asociación
protectora americana en el 1890s reveló la profundidad de la 
desconfianza protestante y el miedo de los católicos que sostenían 
la oficina pública.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086763</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108239</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/protestant-paranoia-the-american-protective-association-oath</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
