<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108320</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108320</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087378</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Am I Not a Woman and a Sister?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sind ich nicht eine Frau und eine Schwester?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"suis moi pas une femme et une soeur?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"são eu não uma mulher e uma irmã?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sono io non una donna e una sorella?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είναι ι όχι μια γυναίκα και μια αδελφή;"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"son yo no una mujer y una hermana?"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">African-American women held as slaves were particularly vulnerable to abuse at the hands of their white owners. This engraving appeared in abolitionist George Bourne's  Slavery Illustrated in Its Effects upon Women , published in 1837. It highlighted the connections between the anti-slavery and women's rights movements, as some women abolitionists, such as Sarah and Angelina Grimke, used the anti-slavery cause to address their own plight as women. The connections they drew were highly controversial, and many anti-slavery organizations were split over the issue of women's rights.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Frauen, die als Sklaven 
angehalten wurden, waren zum Mißbrauch an den Händen ihrer weißen 
Inhaber besonders verletzbar. Dieser Stich erschien abolitionist
George Bournes in der Sklaverei, die in seinen Effekten nach den 
Frauen veranschaulicht wurde, veröffentlicht 1837. Er markierte
die Anschlüsse zwischen der Anti-Sklaverei und Rechtbewegungen der 
Frauen, wie einige Frauen abolitionists, wie Sarah und Angelina 
Grimke, die Anti-Sklaverei Ursache verwendeten, um ihre eigene Lage 
als Frauen zu adressieren. Die Anschlüsse, die sie zeichneten, 
waren in hohem Grade umstritten, und viele Anti-Sklaverei 
Organisationen wurden über der Ausgabe der Rechte der Frauen 
aufgespaltet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les femmes afro-américaines tenues comme esclaves étaient 
particulièrement vulnérables à l'abus aux mains de leurs 
propriétaires blancs. Cette gravure est apparue dans 
l'esclavage de George Bourne d'abolitionniste illustré dans ses 
effets sur des femmes, éditées en 1837. Elle a mis en valeur 
les connexions entre l'anti-esclavage et les mouvements des droits des
femmes, comme les abolitionnistes de quelques femmes, tels que Sarah et 
Angelina Grimke, avaient l'habitude la cause d'anti-esclavage pour 
adresser leur propre situation difficile comme femmes. Les 
connexions qu'elles ont dessinées étaient fortement controversées, 
et beaucoup d'organismes d'anti-esclavage ont été dédoublés 
au-dessus de la question des droits des femmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As mulheres Africano-Americanas prendidas como escravos 
eram particularmente vulneráveis ao abuso nas mãos de seus 
proprietários brancos. Este engraving apareceu no slavery de 
George Bourne do abolitionist ilustrado em seus efeitos em cima das 
mulheres, publicadas em 1837. Destacou as conexões entre o 
anti-anti-slavery e movimentos das direitas das mulheres, como os 
abolitionists de algumas mulheres, tais como Sarah e Angelina Grimke, 
usaram a causa do anti-anti-slavery se dirigir a seu próprio plight 
como mulheres. As conexões que desenharam eram altamente 
controversas, e muitas organizações do anti-anti-slavery foram 
rachadas sobre a introdução de direitas das mulheres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le donne Africano-Americane tenute come schiavi erano 
particolarmente vulnerabili ad abuso alle mani dei loro proprietari 
bianchi. Questa incisione è comparso nello slavery di George 
Bourne di abolitionist illustrato nei relativi effetti sulle donne, 
pubblicate in 1837. Ha evidenziato i collegamenti fra il 
anti-anti-slavery e movimenti di diritti delle donne, come 
abolitionists di alcune donne, quali Sarah ed Angelina Grimke, hanno 
usato la causa di anti-anti-slavery per richiamare la loro propria 
situazione difficile come donne. I collegamenti che hanno 
dissipato erano altamente discutibili e molte organizzazioni di 
anti-anti-slavery sono state spaccate sopra l'emissione dei diritti 
delle donne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά οι γυναίκες που κρατήθηκαν ως 
σκλάβοι ήταν ιδιαίτερα τρωτές στην κατάχρηση στα χέρια των 
λευκών ιδιοκτητών τους. Αυτή η χάραξη εμφανίστηκε στη 
σκλαβιά George Bourne's ρεφορμιστών που διευκρινίστηκε στα 
αποτελέσματά της επάνω στις γυναίκες, που δημοσιεύθηκαν το 
1837. Έδωσε έμφαση στις συνδέσεις μεταξύ των 
μετακινήσεων ενάντιων στη δουλεία και δικαιωμάτων των γυναικών, 
δεδομένου ότι μερικοί ρεφορμιστές γυναικών, όπως Sarah και 
Angelina Grimke, χρησιμοποίησαν την ενάντια στη δουλεία 
αιτία για να εξετάσουν τη δύσκολη θέση τους ως γυναίκες. Οι
συνδέσεις που έσυραν ήταν ιδιαίτερα αμφισβητούμενες, και πολλές 
ενάντιες στη δουλεία οργανώσεις χωρίστηκαν πέρα από το ζήτημα 
των δικαιωμάτων των γυναικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las mujeres Africano-Americanas sostenidas como esclavos 
eran determinado vulnerables al abuso en las manos de sus propietarios
blancos. Este grabado apareció en la esclavitud de George 
Bourne del abolitionist ilustrada en sus efectos sobre las mujeres, 
publicadas en 1837. Destacó las conexiones entre la 
contra-esclavitud y los movimientos de las derechas de las mujeres, 
como los abolitionists de algunas mujeres, tales como Sarah y Angelina
Grimke, utilizaron la causa de la contra-esclavitud para tratar su 
propio apuro como mujeres. Las conexiones que trazaron eran 
altamente polémicas, y muchas organizaciones de la contra-esclavitud 
estuvieron partidas sobre la aplicación las derechas de las mujeres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087378</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108320</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/am-i-not-a-woman-and-a-sister</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
