<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106261</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106261</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086691</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"One Country! One Language! One Flag!" The Invention of an American Tradition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ein Land! Eine Sprache! Eine 
Markierungsfahne!" Die Erfindung einer amerikanischen Tradition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Un Pays ! Un Langage ! Un 
Indicateur!" L'invention d'une tradition américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Um País! Uma Língua! Uma Bandeira!"
A invenção de uma tradição americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Un Paese! Un Linguaggio! Una 
Bandierina!" L'invenzione di una tradizione americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια χώρα! Μια γλώσσα! Μια σημαία!" Η
εφεύρεση μιας αμερικανικής παράδοσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡"Un País! ¡Un Lenguaje! Un 
Indicador!" La invención de una tradición americana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Most people assume that the pledge of allegiance is as old as the Republic. In fact, it was invented in 1892 by Francis Bellamy, director of youth activities for the magazine  Youth's Companion . Bellamy drew up the "pledge to the flag" (as it was then called) and publicized it as part of the activities surrounding the 400th anniversary of Columbus's arrival in America. On Columbus Day in 1892, ten million children recited Bellamy's pledge and it soon became a daily ritual in American schoolrooms. Its widespread adoption reflected both the anxieties about insuring an "American" identity in the midst of a renewed wave of European immigration and a growing nationalistic feeling that would soon help foster American expansionism overseas. The salute to the flag, described below, was dropped in 1942 because of its similarity to Hitler's fascist salute, and replaced with the "modern" salute (right hand over heart). In 1954--in the midst of another wave of American anxiety (this time about domestic and foreign Communism)--the words "under God" were added to the pledge in an effort to distinguish true Americans from "Godless Communists."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die meisten Leute nehmen an, daß versprochene der 
Untertanentreue so alt wie die Republik ist. Tatsächlich wurde 
es 1892 von Francis Bellamy, Direktor der Jugendaktivitäten für den 
Begleiter der Zeitschrift Jugend erfunden. Bellamy arbeitte 
"versprechen zur Markierungsfahne" (während es dann benannt 
wurde) und publizierten es als Teil der Aktivitäten aus, die den 400.
Jahrestag von Ankunft Columbus in Amerika umgeben. Am Columbus 
Tag 1892, recited 10 Million Kinder Bellamys versprechen und es 
wurde bald ein tägliches Ritual in den amerikanischen Klassenzimmern.
Seine weitverbreitete Annahme reflektierte beide Ängste um das 
Versichern einer "amerikanischen" Identität in der Mitte einer 
erneuerten Welle der europäischen Immigration und des wachsenden 
nationalistischen Gefühls, die bald amerikanischem Pflegeexpansionism
übersee helfen würde. Der Gruß zur Markierungsfahne, unten 
beschrieben, wurde 1942 wegen seiner Ähnlichkeit Hitlers zum 
faschistischen Gruß fallengelassen und ersetzt mit dem "modernen" 
Gruß (rechte Hand über Innerem). faßt 1954 -- in der Mitte 
einer anderen Welle der amerikanischen Angst (dieses mal über 
inländischen und fremden Kommunismus -- the "unter Gott" wurden 
hinzugefügt versprochene in einer Bemühung, zutreffende Amerikaner 
"von den gottlosen Kommunisten zu unterscheiden." ab</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La plupart des personnes supposent que 
l'engagement de l'allégeance est aussi vieux que la République. 
En fait, il a été inventé en 1892 par Francis Bellamy, 
directeur des activités de la jeunesse pour le compagnon de la 
jeunesse de magasin. Bellamy a élaboré l'"engagement à 
l'indicateur" (pendant qu'il s'appelait alors) et lui a donné de la 
publicité en tant qu'élément des activités entourant le 400th 
anniversaire de l'arrivée de Columbus en Amérique. Le jour de 
Columbus en 1892, dix millions d'enfants ont exposé 
l'engagement de Bellamy et c'est bientôt devenu un rituel quotidien 
dans les classes américaines. Sa adoption répandue a reflété
les les deux les inquiétudes au sujet d'assurer une identité 
"américaine" au milieu d'une vague remplacée de l'immigration 
européenne et d'un sentiment nationaliste croissant qui aiderait 
bientôt l'expansionism américain adoptif outre-mer. Le salut 
à l'indicateur, décrit ci-dessous, a été abandonné en 1942 en 
raison de sa similitude au salut fasciste de Hitler, et substitué 
avec le salut "moderne" (main droite au-dessus de coeur). En 
1954 -- au milieu d'une autre vague de l'inquiétude américaine 
(cette fois au sujet de Communism) domestique et étranger -- les mots
"sous Dieu" ont été ajoutés à l'engagement dans un effort de 
distinguer les Américains vrais "des communistes athée."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A maioria de povos supõem que o pledge do 
allegiance é tão velho quanto a república. No fato, foi 
inventado em 1892 por Francis Bellamy, diretor de atividades da 
juventude para o companheiro da juventude do compartimento. 
Bellamy desenhou acima do "pledge à bandeira" (enquanto foi 
chamado então) e publicized o como a parte das atividades que cercam 
o 400th anniversary da chegada de Columbo em América. No dia de
Columbo em 1892, dez milhão crianças recited o pledge de Bellamy e 
transformou-se logo um ritual diário em schoolrooms americanos. 
Seu adoption difundido refletiu ambas as ansiedades sobre 
segurar uma identidade "americana" no meio de uma onda renovada do 
immigration europeu e de um sentimento nationalistic crescente que 
ajudasse logo ao expansionism americano foster no ultramar. A 
saudação à bandeira, descrita abaixo, foi deixada cair em 1942 por 
causa de sua similaridade à saudação fascist de Hitler, e 
substituída com a saudação "moderna" (mão direita sobre o 
coração). Em 1954 -- no meio de uma outra onda da ansiedade 
americana (esta vez sobre Communism) doméstico e extrangeiro -- as 
palavras "sob o deus" foram adicionadas ao pledge em um esforço 
distinguir americanos verdadeiros "dos comunistas godless."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La maggior parte della gente suppone che l'impegno
di allegiance è vecchio quanto la Repubblica. Infatti, è stato
inventato in 1892 da Francis Bellamy, direttore delle attività della 
gioventù per il compagno della gioventù dello scomparto. 
Bellamy ha elaborato "l'impegno alla bandierina" (mentre allora 
è stato chiamato) e divulg esso come componente delle attività che 
circondano il 400th anniversario dell'arrivo de Columbus in America. 
Il giorno di Columbus in 1892, dieci milione bambini recited 
l'impegno del Bellamy e presto si è transformato in in un rituale 
quotidiano in aule scolastiche americane. La relativa 
approvazione diffusa ha riflesso le entrambe ansie circa 
l'assicurazione dell'identità "americana" in mezzo a un'onda 
rinnovata dell'immigrazione europea e di una sensibilità 
nazionalistica crescente che presto aiuterebbe il expansionism 
americano adottivo oltremare. Il saluto alla bandierina, 
descritta qui sotto, è stato caduto in 1942 a causa della relativa 
somiglianza al saluto fascista del Hitler ed è stato sostituito 
con il saluto "moderno" (mano destra sopra cuore). In 1954 -- 
in mezzo a un'altra onda di ansia americana (questo volta circa 
Communism) domestico e straniero -- le parole "sotto il dio" sono 
state aggiunte all'impegno in uno sforzo distinguere gli Americani 
allineare "dai comunisti godless."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι περισσότεροι άνθρωποι υποθέτουν ότι η υποχρέωση 
της υποταγής είναι τόσο παλαιά όσο η Δημοκρατία. Στην 
πραγματικότητα, εφευρέθηκε το 1892 από το Francis Bellamy,
σκηνοθέτης των δραστηριοτήτων νεολαίας για το σύντροφο της 
νεολαίας περιοδικών. Το Bellamy κατάρτισε τη "υποχρέωση 
στη σημαία" (όπως κλήθηκε έπειτα) και την κοινοποίησε ως τμήμα 
των δραστηριοτήτων που περιβάλλουν τη 400th επέτειο της άφιξης 
του Columbus στην Αμερική. την ημέρα του Columbus το 
1892, δέκα εκατομμύριο παιδιά εξέθεσαν την υποχρέωση 
Bellamy και έγινε σύντομα ένα καθημερινό τελετουργικό στις 
αμερικανικές αίθουσες διδασκαλίας. Η διαδεδομένη υιοθέτησή
της απεικόνισε και τις ανησυχίες για την ασφάλιση μιας 
"αμερικανικήσ" ταυτότητας στη μέση ενός ανανεωμένου κύματος της 
ευρωπαϊκής μετανάστευσης και ενός αυξανόμενου εθνικιστικού 
συναισθήματος που θα βοηθούσαν σύντομα να ενθαρρύνουν το 
αμερικανικό expansionism στο εξωτερικό. Το χαιρετισμό στη 
σημαία, που περιγράφηκε κατωτέρω, έπεσαν το 1942 λόγω της 
ομοιότητάς του hitler στο φασιστικό χαιρετισμό, και 
αντικατέστησε με το "σύγχρονο" χαιρετισμό (δεξή πέρα από την 
καρδιά). Το 1954 -- στη μέση ενός άλλου κύματος της 
αμερικανικής ανησυχίας (αυτή τη φορά για εσωτερικό και ξένο 
Communism) -- οι λέξεις "κάτω από το Θεό" προστέθηκαν στην 
υποχρέωση σε μια προσπάθεια να διακριθούν αληθινοί Αμερικανοί 
από τους "άθεους κομμουνιστές."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La mayoría de la gente asume que el compromiso de
la lealtad es tan viejo como la república. En hecho, fue 
inventado en 1892 por Francis Bellamy, director de las actividades de 
la juventud para el compañero de la juventud del compartimiento. 
Bellamy elaboró el "compromiso al indicador" (mientras que 
entonces fue llamado) y lo publicó como parte de las actividades que 
rodeaban el 400o aniversario de la llegada de Columbus en América. 
El el día de Columbus en 1892, diez millones de niños 
recitaron el compromiso de Bellamy y pronto se convirtió en un
ritual diario en aulas americanos. Su adopción extensa reflejó
ambas las ansiedades sobre asegurar una identidad "americana" en el 
medio de una onda renovada de la inmigración europea y de una 
sensación nacionalista cada vez mayor que pronto ayudaría a 
expansionism americano foster en ultramar. El saludo al 
indicador, descrito abajo, fue caído en 1942 debido a su semejanza al
saludo fascista de Hitler, y substituido por el saludo "moderno" (mano
derecha sobre corazón). En 1954 -- en el medio de otra onda de 
la ansiedad americana (este vez sobre Communism) doméstico y no 
nativo -- las palabras "bajo dios" fueron agregadas al compromiso en 
un esfuerzo de distinguir a americanos verdaderos de "comunistas 
ateos."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086691</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106261</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/one-country-one-language-one-flag-the-invention-of-an-american-tradition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
