<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107060</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107060</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207002</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kid's Korner at Tumac?cori National Historical Park</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Korner des Zickleins Tumac?cori am nationalen 
historischen Park</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Korner du gosse au parc historique national de 
Tumac?cori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Korner do miúdo no parque histórico nacional de 
Tumac?cori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Korner del capretto al parco storico nazionale di 
Tumac?cori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Korner κατσικιού στο εθνικό ιστορικό πάρκο 
Tumac?cori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Korner del cabrito en el parque histórico nacional
de Tumac?cori</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a site where children can learn about customs and games of the first Europeans who came to southern Arizona and the native people who lived there in the 1600s. The site includes instructions for making adobe bricks, constructing a pump drill, creating a Native American calendar, and other activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Site, in der Kinder über Gewohnheiten und
Spiele der ersten Europäer erlernen können, die zum südlichen 
Arizona und zu den gebürtigen Leuten kamen, die dort im 1600s lebten.
Die Site schließt Anweisungen für das Bilden der 
Ziegelsteinziegelsteine ein und konstruiert ein Pumpe Bohrgerät und 
erstellt einen gebürtigen amerikanischen Kalender und andere 
Aktivitäten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un site où les enfants peuvent se renseigner 
sur des coutumes et des jeux des premiers Européens qui sont venu 
chez l'Arizona méridional et les indigènes qui ont vécu là dans le
1600s. Le site inclut des instructions pour faire des briques 
d'adobe, construisant un foret de pompe, créant un calendrier 
américain indigène, et d'autres activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um local onde as crianças possam aprender sobre
costumes e jogos dos primeiros Europeus que vieram ao arizona do sul e
aos povos nativos que viveram lá no 1600s. O local inclui 
instruções para fazer tijolos do adôbe, construindo uma broca da 
bomba, criando um calendário americano nativo, e outras atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un luogo in cui i bambini possono imparare circa
le abitudini ed i giochi dei primi Europei che sono venuto in Arizona 
del sud e le popolazioni autoctone che hanno vissuto là nel 1600s. 
Il luogo include le istruzioni per fare i mattoni dell'adobe, 
costruendo un trivello della pompa, creando un calendario americano 
natale ed altre attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια περιοχή όπου τα παιδιά μπορούν να μάθουν 
για το τελωνείο και τα παιχνίδια των πρώτων Ευρωπαίων που ήρθαν 
στη νότια Αριζόνα και τους εγγενείς ανθρώπους που έζησαν εκεί 
στο 1600s. Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τις οδηγίες για την 
κατασκευή των τούβλων πλίθας, την κατασκευή ενός τρυπανιού 
αντλιών, τη δημιουργία ενός εγγενούς αμερικανικού ημερολογίου, 
και άλλες δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un sitio en donde los niños pueden aprender 
sobre costumbres y juegos de los primeros europeos que vinieron al 
Arizona meridional y a los indígenas que vivieron allí en el 1600s. 
El sitio incluye las instrucciones para hacer ladrillos del 
adobe, construyendo un taladro de la bomba, creando un calendario 
americano nativo, y otras actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207002</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107060</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/kids-korner-at-tumac-cori-national-historical-park</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
