<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103831</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103831</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087413</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Attorney General A. Mitchell Palmer Makes "The Case against the Reds"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Generalstaatsanwalt A. Mitchell Palmer Marken "das
Argument gegen die Rottöne"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Marques Général de A. Mitchell Palmer de 
mandataire "le point de droit contre les rouges"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Makes gerais de A. Mitchell Palmer do advogado "o 
argumento de encontro aos vermelhos"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Marche generali del A. Mitchell Palmer 
dell'avvocato "l'argomento contro i colori rossi"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο γενικός εισαγγελέας Α. Mitchell Palmer δίνει 
"τα επιχειρήματα ενάντια στα κόκκινα"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Marcas generales de A. Mitchell Palmer del abogado
"el caso en contra de los rojos"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The climate of repression established in the name of wartime security during World War I continued after the war as the U.S. government focused on communists, Bolsheviks, and "reds." This anticommunist crusade climaxed during the "Palmer raids" of 1919-1921, when Attorney General A. Mitchell Palmer's men, striking without warning and without warrants, smashed union offices and the headquarters of Communist and Socialist organizations. Palmer believed that communism was "eating its way into the homes of the American workman." Palmer charged in this 1920 essay that communism was an imminent threat and explained why Bolsheviks had to be deported.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Klima der Unterdrückung hergestellt im Namen 
der Kriegsicherheit während des Ersten Weltkrieges fuhr nach dem 
Krieg als die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung fort, die gerichtet wurde 
auf Kommunisten, Bolschewike und "Rottöne." Dieser 
anticommunist Kreuzzug steigerte sich während des "Palmer 
überfällt" von 1919-1921, als Generalstaatsanwalt A. Mitchell 
Palmers Männer, anschlagend ohne WARNING und ohne Ermächtigungen, 
Anschlußbüros und die Hauptsitze der kommunistischen und 
sozialistischen Organisationen zertrümmerten. Palmer glaubte, 
daß Kommunismus "aß seine Methode in die Häuser des 
amerikanischen Arbeiters." Palmer lud in diesem Versuch 1920 
auf, daß Kommunismus eine unmittelbar drohende Drohung und 
erklärt war, warum Bolschewike verbannt werden mußten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le climat de la répression établi au nom de la 
sécurité de temps de guerre pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale a 
continué après la guerre comme gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS 
concentré sur des communistes, des bolchéviques, et des "rouges." 
Cette croisade d'anticommunist a culminé pendant le "Palmer 
pille" de 1919-1921, quand les hommes de A. Mitchell Palmer's 
Général de mandataire, frappant sans avertissement et sans 
garanties, ont cassé des bureaux des syndicats et les sièges sociaux
des organismes communistes et socialistes. Palmer a cru que le 
communisme "mangeait sa voie dans les maisons de l'ouvrier 
américain." Palmer a chargé dans cet essai 1920 que le 
communisme était une menace imminente et expliqué pourquoi des 
bolchéviques ont dû être expulsés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O clima do repression estabelecido no nome da 
segurança do wartime durante o world.war.i continuou após a guerra 
como o governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS focalizado em comunistas, em 
bolsheviks, e em "vermelhos." Este crusade do anticommunist 
climaxed durante o "Palmer invade" de 1919-1921, quando de advogado os
homens de A. Mitchell Palmer geral, golpeando sem aviso e sem 
autorizações, despedaçaram escritórios da união e as matrizes de 
organizações comunistas e socialist. Palmer acreditou que o 
communism "comia sua maneira nas HOME do trabalhador americano." 
Palmer carregou neste essay 1920 que o communism era uma ameaça
imminent e explicado porque os bolsheviks tiveram que deported.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il clima di repressione stabilito in nome di 
sicurezza di wartime durante il world.war.i è continuato dopo la 
guerra come il governo degli STATI UNITI messo a fuoco sui comunisti, 
sui bolsheviks e "sui colori rossi." Questo crusade di 
anticommunist ha raggiunto il punto culminante durante "il Palmer 
raids" di 1919-1921, quando di avvocato gli uomini del A. Mitchell 
Palmer generale, colpendo senza avvertimento e senza garanzie, hanno 
fracassato gli uffici del sindacato e le sedi delle organizzazioni 
comuniste e socialiste. Palmer ha creduto che il comunismo 
"stesse mangiando il relativo modo nelle sedi dell'operaio americano."
Palmer si è caricato in questo saggio 1920 che il comunismo era
una minaccia imminente e spiegato perchè i bolsheviks hanno dovuto 
deported.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κλίμα της καταστολής που καθιερώθηκε στο όνομα της 
εν καιρώ πολέμου ασφάλειας κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου συνεχίστηκα μετά από τον πόλεμο όπως η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ 
κυβέρνηση εστίασε στους κομμουνιστές, Bolsheviks, και "τα 
κόκκινα." Αυτή η αντικομμουνιστής σταυροφορία κατά τη 
διάρκεια των "επιδρομών Palmer" του 1919-1921, όταν 
συνέθλιψαν τα άτομα Α. Mitchell Palmer's γενικών 
εισαγγελέων, που χτυπούν χωρίς προειδοποίηση και χωρίς 
εντάλματα, τα γραφεία ένωσης και την έδρα των κομμουνιστικών και 
σοσιαλιστικών οργανώσεων. Το Palmer εθεώρησε ότι ο 
κομμουνισμός "έτρωγε τον τρόπο του στα σπίτια του αμερικανικού 
εργάτη." Το Palmer χρέωσε σε αυτό το δοκίμιο του 1920 
ότι ο κομμουνισμός ήταν μια επικείμενη απειλή και εξήγησε γιατί
Bolsheviks έπρεπε να.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El clima de la represión establecido en el nombre
de la seguridad del tiempo de guerra durante Primera Guerra Mundial 
continuó después de la guerra como el gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
centrado en comunistas, bolsheviks, y "rojos." Esta cruzada 
del anticommunist culminó durante el "Palmer ataca" de 1919-1921, 
cuando de abogado los hombres de A. Mitchell Palmer general, pulso sin
la alerta y sin autorizaciones, rompieron oficinas de la unión y las 
jefaturas de organizaciones comunistas y socialistas. Palmer 
creyó que el comunismo "comía su manera en los hogares del 
trabajador americano." Palmer cargó en este ensayo 1920 que el 
comunismo fuera una amenaza inminente y explicado porqué los 
bolsheviks tuvieron que estar deportados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087413</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103831</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/attorney-general-a-mitchell-palmer-makes-the-case-against-the-reds</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
