<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104048</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104048</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205551</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Latin Vocabulary I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lateinischer Wortschatz I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vocabulaire Latin I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vocabulário Latin I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vocabolario Latino I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λατινικό λεξιλόγιο Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vocabulario Latino I</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A vocabulary trainer for Latin learners, aimed at complete beginners. It contains a variety of question types: multiple choice, typed response, matching pairs, and a mystery word game. The module demonstrates the use of the Qedoc quiz software for training vocabulary in a manner that minimizes the time of the educator. The module uses a 43-item vocabulary table and 6 basic question templates. From this the programme generates 129 single response questions, about 3 million multiple choice combinations and uncountable variations of the memory games. The results are then sorted into 6 different levels based on a specific question type, each level with randomised content. The result is a highly efficient production of a methodologically varied and valuable learning environment with huge replayability. The learner's progress can be tracked and numerous rewards mark different stages of attainment. Colourful icons, backgrounds and sound effects add to the enjoyability of the learning experience.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Wortschatzkursleiter für lateinische 
Anfänger, angestrebte komplette Anfänger. Er enthält eine 
Vielzahl der Frage Typen: mehrfache Wahl, Antwort geschrieben, 
zusammenpassende Paare und ein Geheimniswortspiel. Das Modul 
zeigt den Gebrauch von der Qedoc Quizsoftware für Training Wortschatz
in gewissem Sinne, der die Zeit des Erziehers herabsetzt. Das 
Modul benutzt eine 43-Einzelteile Wortschatztabelle und 6 grundlegende
Frage Schablonen. Von diesem legt das Programm 129 einzelne 
Wartefragen, ungefähr 3 Million mehrfache auserlesene Kombinationen 
und uncountable Varianten der Speicherspiele fest. Die Resultate
werden dann in 6 unterschiedliche Stufen sortiert, die auf einem 
spezifischen Frage Typen, jede Stufe mit randomisiertem Inhalt 
basieren. Das Resultat ist eine in hohem Grade leistungsfähige 
Produktion einer methodologisch veränderten und wertvollen 
erlernenumgebung mit sehr großem replayability. Der Fortschritt
des Anfängers kann aufgespürt werden und zahlreiche Belohnungen 
kennzeichnen unterschiedliche Stadien der Erreichung. Bunte 
Ikonen, Hintergründe und stichhaltige Effekte fügen dem enjoyability
der Lernenerfahrung hinzu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un entraîneur de vocabulaire pour les étudiants 
latins, débutants complets visés. Il contient une variété de
types de question : choix multiple, tapé la réponse, paires 
assorties, et un jeu de mots de mystère. Le module démontre 
l'utilisation du logiciel de jeu de Qedoc pour le vocabulaire de 
formation en quelque sorte qui réduit au minimum la période de 
l'éducateur. Le module utilise une table de vocabulaire de 
43-éléments et 6 descripteurs de base de question. De ceci le 
programme produit de 129 questions simples de réponse, d'environ 3 
millions de combinaisons bien choisies multiples et de variations 
incomptables des jeux de mémoire. Les résultats sont alors 
triés dans 6 niveaux différents basés sur un type spécifique de 
question, chaque niveau avec le contenu randomisé. Le résultat
est une production fortement efficace d'un environnement d'étude 
méthodologiquement changé et valable avec le replayability énorme. 
Le progrès de l'étudiant peut être dépisté et les 
nombreuses récompenses marquent différentes étapes 
d'accomplissement. Les graphismes colorés, les milieux et les 
effets sains ajoutent à l'enjoyability de l'expérience d'étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um instrutor do vocabulário para os learners 
latin, novatos completos visados. Contem uma variedade de tipos 
da pergunta: escolha múltipla, datilografada a resposta, pares 
combinando, e um jogo de palavra do mistério. O módulo 
demonstra o uso do software do quiz de Qedoc para o vocabulário do 
treinamento em uma maneira que minimize a época do educador. O 
módulo usa uma tabela do vocabulário dos 43-artigos e 6 moldes 
básicos da pergunta. Desta o programa gera 129 únicas 
perguntas da resposta, aproximadamente 3 milhão combinações bem 
escolhidas múltiplas e variações uncountable dos jogos da memória.
Os resultados são classificados então em 6 níveis diferentes 
baseados em um tipo específico da pergunta, cada nível com índice 
randomised. O resultado é uma produção altamente eficiente de
um ambiente de aprendizagem methodologically variado e valioso com 
replayability enorme. O progresso do learner pode ser seguido e 
as recompensas numerosas marcam estágios diferentes da realização. 
Os ícones coloridos, os fundos e os efeitos sadios adicionam ao
enjoyability da experiência de aprendizagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un addestratore di vocabolario per i principianti 
latini, principianti completi puntati su. Contiene una varietà 
di tipi di domanda: scelta multipla, digitata risposta, 
accoppiamenti di corrispondenza e un gioco di parola di mistero. 
Il modulo dimostra l'uso del software di quiz di Qedoc per 
vocabolario di addestramento in un modo che minimizza il periodo 
dell'educatore. Il modulo usa una tabella di vocabolario degli 
43-articoli e 6 mascherine di base di domanda. Da questa il 
programma genera 129 singole domande di risposta, circa 3 milione 
combinazioni choice multiple e le variazioni uncountable dei giochi di
memoria. I risultati allora sono ordinati in 6 livelli 
differenti basati su un tipo specifico di domanda, ogni livello con 
il soddisfare ripartito con scelta casuale. Il risultato è una 
produzione altamente efficiente di un ambiente imparante 
metodologicamente variato ed importante con il replayability enorme. 
Il progresso del principiante può essere rintracciato e le 
ricompense numerose contrassegnano le fasi differenti del 
raggiungimento. Le icone colourful, gli ambiti di provenienza e 
gli effetti sani aggiungono al enjoyability dell'esperienza di 
apprendimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας εκπαιδευτής λεξιλογίου για τους λατινικούς 
αρχαρίους, στόχευσε στους πλήρεις αρχαρίους. Περιέχει 
ποικίλους τύπους ερώτησης: πολλαπλή επιλογή, 
δακτυλογραφημένη απάντηση, ταιριάζοντας με ζευγάρια, και ένα 
παιχνίδι λέξης μυστηρίου. Η ενότητα καταδεικνύει τη χρήση 
του λογισμικού διαγωνισμοου γνώσεων Qedoc για το λεξιλόγιο 
κατάρτισης με έναν τρόπο που ελαχιστοποιεί το χρόνο του 
εκπαιδευτικού. Η ενότητα χρησιμοποιεί πίνακα λεξιλογίου 
4νtem και 6 βασικά πρότυπα ερώτησης. Από αυτό το 
πρόγραμμα παράγει 129 ενιαίες ερωτήσεις απάντησης, περίπου 3 
εκατομμύριο πολλαπλάσιους συνδυασμούς επιλογής και τις 
uncountable παραλλαγές των παιχνιδιών μνήμης. Τα 
αποτελέσματα ταξινομούνται έπειτα σε 6 διαφορετικά επίπεδα 
βασισμένα σε έναν συγκεκριμένο τύπο ερώτησης, κάθε επίπεδο με 
το τυχαίο περιεχόμενο. Το αποτέλεσμα είναι μια ιδιαίτερα 
αποδοτική παραγωγή ενός μεθοδολογικά ποικίλου και πολύτιμου 
μαθησιακού περιβάλλοντος με το τεράστιο replayability. Η 
πρόοδος του αρχαρίου μπορεί να ακολουθηθεί και οι πολυάριθμες 
ανταμοιβές χαρακτηρίζουν τα διαφορετικά στάδια της επίτευξης. 
Τα ζωηρόχρωμα εικονίδια, τα υπόβαθρα και τα υγιή 
αποτελέσματα προσθέτουν στο enjoyability της εμπειρίας 
εκμάθησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un amaestrador del vocabulario para los 
principiantes latinos, principiantes completos dirigidos. 
Contiene una variedad de tipos de la pregunta: opción 
múltiple, pulsada respuesta, pares que corresponden con, y un juego 
de palabra del misterio. El módulo demuestra el uso del 
software del concurso de Qedoc para el vocabulario del entrenamiento 
de una manera que reduzca al mínimo la época del educador. El 
módulo utiliza un vector del vocabulario de los 43-items y 6 modelos 
básicos de la pregunta. De esto el programa genera 129 solas 
preguntas de la respuesta, cerca de 3 millones de combinaciones bien 
escogidas múltiples y las variaciones uncountable de los juegos de la
memoria. Los resultados entonces se clasifican en 6 diversos 
niveles basados en un tipo específico de la pregunta, cada nivel con 
el contenido seleccionado al azar. El resultado es una 
producción altamente eficiente de un ambiente que aprende 
metodológico variado y valioso con replayability enorme. El 
progreso del principiante puede ser seguido y las recompensas 
numerosas marcan diversas etapas del logro. Los iconos 
coloridos, los fondos y los efectos sonoros agregan al enjoyability de
la experiencia de aprendizaje.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:QEDOC EDUCATIONAL TEAM
FN:QEDOC EDUCATIONAL TEAM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205551</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104048</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/latin-vocabulary-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
