<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104705</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104705</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202708</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Atomic spectra and the Bohr model</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Atomspektren und das Bohr Modell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Spectres atomiques et le modèle de Bohr</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Spectra atômicos e o modelo de Bohr</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Spettri atomici ed il modello di Bohr</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ατομικά φάσματα και το μοντέλο Bohr</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Espectros atómicos y el modelo de Bohr</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students view continuous spectra from incandescent and fluorescent lights and line spectra of selected elements. Students relate energy to frequency of light seen in the spectra. The presence of only certain lines in atomic spectra is related to Bohr's model of the atom. In a second experiment, students determine electron energies in the hydrogen atom.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer sehen ununterbrochene Spektren von 
den weißglühenden und Leuchtstofflichtern an und zeichnen Spektren 
der ausgewählten Elemente. Kursteilnehmer stehen Energie auf 
der Frequenz des Lichtes gesehen in die Spektren in Verbindung. 
Das Vorhandensein nur bestimmter Zeilen in den Atomspektren 
hängt mit Modell Bohrs des Atoms zusammen. In einem zweiten 
Experiment stellen Kursteilnehmer Elektronenergie im Wasserstoffatom 
fest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants visualisent des spectres continus 
des lumières incandescentes et fluorescentes et rayent des éventails
les éléments choisis. Les étudiants rapportent l'énergie à 
la fréquence de la lumière vue dans les spectres. La présence
de certaines lignes seulement dans des spectres atomiques est liée au
modèle de Bohr de l'atome. Dans une deuxième expérience, les 
étudiants déterminent des énergies d'électron dans l'atome 
d'hydrogène.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes vêem spectra contínuos das luzes 
incandescent e fluorescentes e alinham spectra de elementos 
selecionados. Os estudantes relacionam a energia à freqüência
da luz vista nos spectra. A presença somente de determinadas 
linhas em spectra atômicos é relacionada ao modelo de Bohr do 
átomo. Em uma segunda experiência, os estudantes determinam 
energias do elétron no átomo do hidrogênio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi osservano gli spettri continui dalle 
luci incandescenti e fluorescenti ed allineano le gamme di elementi 
selezionati. Gli allievi riferiscono l'energia a frequenza di 
luce vista negli spettri. La presenza soltanto di determinate 
righe negli spettri atomici è collegata con il modello del Bohr 
dell'atomo. In un secondo esperimento, gli allievi determinano 
le energie dell'elettrone nell'atomo dell'idrogeno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές εμφανίζουν τα συνεχή φάσματα από τα 
πυρακτωμένα και φθορισμού φώτα και τα φάσματα γραμμών των 
επιλεγμένων στοιχείων. Οι σπουδαστές αφορούν την ενέργεια 
τη συχνότητα του φωτός που βλέπει στα φάσματα. Η 
παρουσία μόνο ορισμένων γραμμών στα ατομικά φάσματα 
συσχετίζεται με το μοντέλο Bohr του ατόμου. Σε ένα 
δεύτερο πείραμα, οι σπουδαστές καθορίζουν τις ενέργειες 
ηλεκτρονίων στο άτομο υδρογόνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes opinión espectros continuos de 
luces incandescentes y fluorescentes y alinean espectros de elementos 
seleccionados. Los estudiantes relacionan energía con la 
frecuencia de la luz vista en los espectros. La presencia 
solamente de ciertas líneas en espectros atómicos se relaciona con 
el modelo de Bohr del átomo. En un segundo experimento, los 
estudiantes determinan energías del electrón en el átomo del 
hidrógeno.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LISA BACON
FN:LISA BACON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202708</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104705</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/atomic-spectra-and-the-bohr-model</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
