<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103395</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103395</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203221</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hunting Bears with a Microscope</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jagd-Bären mit einem Mikroskop</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ours de chasse avec un microscope</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ursos da caça com um microscópio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cercare gli orsi con un microscopio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κυνήγι αντέχει με ένα μικροσκόπιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Osos de la caza con un microscopio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this online activity, students use lichens and tardigrades (water bears) to investigate their use as bioindicators of key air pollutants. When lichens are exposed to some kinds of air pollutants, especially to sulfur dioxide, the lichens are injured and die. The lichen coverage in a specified area should be a good indicator of the level of air quality. The diversity of the tardigrade species on the lichens will be used to develop another level for bioindication of air quality. Sections of this activity include: introduction, sulfur dioxide and lichens, sampling procedure for lichen coverage, tardigrade sampling, sampling procedure for tardigrades, calculating diversity using the Simpson Diversity Index, interpretation of results, and references.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Online-Dienst benutzen Kursteilnehmer 
Flechten und tardigrades (Wasserbären) um ihren Gebrauch 
nachzuforschen wie bioindicators der 
Schlüsselluftverschmutzungsstoffe. Wenn Flechten einigen Arten 
Luftverschmutzungsstoffe, besonders zum Schwefeldioxid, die Flechten 
ausgesetzt werden, werden verletzt und sterben. Die 
Flechtedichte in einem spezifizierten Bereich sollte eine gute Anzeige
der Stufe der Luftqualität sein. Die Verschiedenartigkeit der 
tardigrade Sorte auf den Flechten wird verwendet, um eine andere Stufe
für bioindication der Luftqualität zu entwickeln. Kapitel 
dieser Aktivität schließen ein: Einleitung, Schwefeldioxid und
Flechten, Musterstückprozedur für Flechtedichte, tardigrade 
Musterstück, Musterstückprozedur für tardigrades, 
Rechenverschiedenartigkeit mit dem Simpson Verschiedenartigkeit-Index,
Deutung von Resultaten und Referenzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité en ligne, les étudiants 
emploient des lichens et des tardigrades (ours de l'eau) pour étudier
leur utilisation comme des bioindicators des polluants principaux 
d'air. Quand des lichens sont exposés à quelques genres de 
polluants d'air, particulièrement à l'anhydride sulfureux, les 
lichens sont blessés et meurent. L'assurance de lichen dans une
zone indiquée devrait être un bon indicateur du niveau de la 
qualité d'air. La diversité des espèces de tardigrade sur
les lichens sera employée pour développer un autre niveau pour le 
bioindication de la qualité d'air. Les sections de cette 
activité incluent : anhydride et lichens d'introduction et 
sulfureux, procédé de prélèvement pour l'assurance de lichen, 
prélèvement de tardigrade, procédé de prélèvement pour des 
tardigrades, diversité calculatrice en utilisant l'incrément de 
diversité de Simpson, traduction des résultats, et références.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade em linha, os estudantes usam 
lichens e tardigrades (ursos da água) investigar seu uso como 
bioindicators dos pollutants chaves do ar. Quando os lichens 
são expostos a alguns tipos de pollutants do ar, especial ao dióxido
de enxôfre, os lichens são feridos e morrem. A cobertura do 
lichen em uma área especificada deve ser um indicador bom do nível 
da qualidade do ar. A diversidade da espécie do tardigrade nos 
lichens será usada desenvolver um outro nível para o bioindication 
da qualidade do ar. As seções desta atividade incluem: 
introdução, dióxido e lichens de enxôfre, procedimento de 
amostragem para a cobertura do lichen, amostragem do tardigrade, 
procedimento de amostragem para tardigrades, diversidade calculadora 
usando o deslocamento predeterminado da diversidade de Simpson, 
interpretação dos resultados, e referências.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività in linea, gli allievi usano i 
licheni ed i tardigrades (orsi dell'acqua) per studiare il loro uso 
come bioindicators delle sostanze inquinanti chiave dell'aria. 
Quando i licheni sono esposti ad alcuni generi di sostanze 
inquinanti dell'aria, particolarmente all'anidride solforosa, i 
licheni sono danneggiati e muoiono. Il riempimento del lichene 
in una zona specificata dovrebbe essere un buon indicatore del livello
di qualità dell'aria. La diversità della specie del tardigrade
sui licheni sarà usata per sviluppare un altro livello per il 
bioindication di qualità dell'aria. Le sezioni di questa 
attività includono: introduzione, anidride solforosa e licheni,
procedura di campionamento per riempimento del lichene, campione del 
tardigrade, procedura di campionamento per i tardigrades, diversità 
calcolatrice usando l'indice di diversità di Simpson, interpretazione
dei risultati e riferimenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την σε απευθείας σύνδεση δραστηριότητα, οι 
σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν τις λειχήνες και tardigrades (το ύδωρ 
αντέχει) για να ερευνήσουν τη χρήση τους ως βιοενδείκτες των 
βασικών ατμοσφαιρικών ρύπων. Όταν οι λειχήνες εκτίθενται 
σε μερικά είδη ατμοσφαιρικών ρύπων, ειδικά στο διοξείδιο θείου,
οι λειχήνες τραυματίζονται και κύβος. Η κάλυψη λειχήνων σε 
μια προσδιορισμένη περιοχή πρέπει να είναι ένας καλός δείκτης 
του επιπέδου ατμοσφαιρικής ποιότητας. Η ποικιλομορφία των 
tardigrade ειδών στις λειχήνες θα χρησιμοποιηθεί για να 
αναπτύξει ένα άλλο επίπεδο για το bioindication της 
ατμοσφαιρικής ποιότητας. Τα τμήματα αυτής της 
δραστηριότητας περιλαμβάνουν: εισαγωγή, διοξείδιο θείου και
λειχήνες, διαδικασία δειγματοληψίας για την κάλυψη λειχήνων, 
tardigrade δειγματοληψία, διαδικασία δειγματοληψίας για τα 
tardigrades, ποικιλομορφία υπολογισμού που χρησιμοποιεί το 
ευρετήριο ποικιλομορφίας Simpson, ερμηνεία των αποτελεσμάτων, 
και των αναφορών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad en línea, los estudiantes 
utilizan los liquenes y los tardigrades (osos del agua) para 
investigar su uso como los bioindicators de los agentes contaminadores
dominantes del aire. Cuando los liquenes se exponen a algunas 
clases de agentes contaminadores del aire, especialmente al dióxido 
de sulfuro, los liquenes se dañan y mueren. La cobertura del 
liquen en un área especificada debe ser un buen indicador del nivel 
de la calidad del aire. La diversidad de la especie del 
tardigrade en los liquenes será utilizada para desarrollar otro nivel
para el bioindication de la calidad del aire. Las secciones de 
esta actividad incluyen: introducción, dióxido y liquenes de 
sulfuro, procedimiento de muestreo para la cobertura del liquen, 
muestreo del tardigrade, procedimiento de muestreo para los 
tardigrades, diversidad calculadora usando el índice de la diversidad
de Simpson, interpretación de resultados, y referencias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:STEVE CASE
FN:STEVE CASE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:THE NATIONAL HEALTH MUSEUM: ACCESS EXCELLENCE
FN:THE NATIONAL HEALTH MUSEUM: ACCESS EXCELLENCE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203221</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103395</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hunting-bears-with-a-microscope</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
