<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/162285444</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>162285444</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212810</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tides and Water Levels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gezeiten und Wasser-Stufen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Marées et niveaux d'eau</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Marés e níveis de água</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Maree e livelli d'acqua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παλίρροιες και στάθμες ύδατος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mareas y niveles del agua</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Tides and Waters Levels Tutorial, presented by NOAA's National Ocean Service (NOS), is an overview of the complex systems that govern the movement of tides and water levels. The tutorial is made up of 11 chapters that can be read in or out sequence and include many illustrative and interactive graphics to visually enhance the learning process. To complement the information highlighted in the tutorial, the site also features a Roadmap to Resources page which provides links to additional tutorials and specific tidal and current data offered by NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Gezeiten-und Wasser-Stufen der Tutorial, 
dargestellt durch Ozean-Service National NOAAs (Nr.), ist ein 
Überblick über die komplexen Systeme, die die Bewegung von 
Gezeiten und von Wasserstufen regeln. Der Tutorial 
besteht 11 Kapitel, die innen gelesen werden können oder aus 
Reihenfolge und enthält viele illustrative und interaktive Graphiken,
um den Lernprozeß sichtlich zu erhöhen. Die Informationen 
ergäzunzen markierte im Tutorial, kennzeichnet die Site auch einen 
Schaltplan zur Betriebsmittelseite die Links zu den zusätzlichen 
Tutorials und spezifischen Gezeiten- und aktuellen zu den Daten zur 
Verfügung stellt, die von NOAA angeboten werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les niveaux cours d'instruction de marées et 
d'eaux, présenté par le service d'océan de National de NOAA's 
(numéros), est une vue d'ensemble des systèmes complexes qui 
régissent le mouvement des marées et des niveaux d'eau. Le 
cours d'instruction se compose de 11 chapitres qui peuvent être lus 
dedans ou hors de l'ordre et inclut beaucoup de graphiques 
d'illustration et interactifs pour mettre en valeur visuellement 
l'apprentissage. Compléter l'information a mis en valeur dans 
le cours d'instruction, le site comporte également une carte 
routière à la page de ressources qui fournit des liens aux cours 
d'instruction supplémentaires et aux données de marée et actuelles 
spécifiques offerts par NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os níveis tutorial das marés e de águas, 
apresentado pelo serviço do oceano de Nacional de NOAA (no.), são 
uma vista geral dos sistemas complexos que governam o movimento das 
marés e dos níveis de água. O tutorial é composto de 11 
capítulos que podem ser lidos dentro ou para fora da seqüência e 
inclui muitos gráficos ilustrativos e interativos para realçar 
visualmente o processo de aprendizagem. Complementar a 
informação destacou no tutorial, o local caracteriza também um mapa
rodoviário à página dos recursos que fornece as ligações aos 
tutorials adicionais e aos dados tidal e atuais específicos 
oferecidos por NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I livelli d'acqua lezione privata e di maree, 
presentata da servizio dell'oceano del National del NOAA (no.), è una
descrizione dei sistemi complessi che governano il movimento delle 
maree e dei livelli d'acqua. La lezione privata si compone di 11
capitolo che possono essere letti dentro o verso l'esterno la sequenza
ed include molti grafici illustrativi ed interattivi per aumentare 
visivamente l'apprendimento. Complementare le informazioni ha 
evidenziato nella lezione privata, il luogo egualmente caratterizza 
una carta stradale alla pagina delle risorse che fornisce i 
collegamenti alle lezioni private supplementari ed ai dati di marea e 
correnti specifici offerti da NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σεμινάριο παλιρροιών και σταθμών ύδατος, που 
παρουσιάζεται από την εθνική ωκεάνια υπηρεσία NOAA (αριθ.), 
είναι μια επισκόπηση των σύνθετων συστημάτων που κυβερνούν τη 
μετακίνηση των παλιρροιών και των σταθμών ύδατος. Το 
σεμινάριο αποτελείται από 11 κεφάλαια που μπορούν να 
διαβαστούν μέσα ή έξω ακολουθία και να περιλάβουν πολλά 
επεξηγηματική και διαλογική γραφική παράσταση για να ενισχύσουν 
οπτικά τη διαδικασία εκμάθησης. Για να συμπληρώσει τις 
πληροφορίες που τονίζονται στο σεμινάριο, η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει 
επίσης ένα Roadmap στη σελίδα των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς που 
παρέχει τις συνδέσεις με τα πρόσθετα σεμινάρια και τα 
συγκεκριμένα παλιρροιακά και παρόντα στοιχεία που προσφέρονται 
από NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los niveles guía de las mareas y de las aguas, 
presentada por el servicio del océano National de NOAA (No.), son una
descripción de los sistemas complejos que gobiernan el movimiento de 
mareas y de niveles del agua. La guía se compone de 11 
capítulos que puedan ser leídos adentro o fuera de secuencia e 
incluye muchos gráficos ilustrativos e interactivos para realzar 
visualmente el proceso de aprendizaje. Complementar la 
información destacó en la guía, el sitio también ofrece un mapa 
itinerario a la paginación de los recursos que proporciona a 
conexiones a las guías adicionales y a los datos de marea y actuales 
específicos ofrecidos por NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212810</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>162285444</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tides-and-water-levels</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
