<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105564</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105564</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086292</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Saw The Walking Dead": A Black Sergeant Remembers Buchenwald</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Sah Absolut Gehen": Ein Schwarzer 
Sergeant Erinnert Sich an Buchenwald</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"J'ai vu La Marche Complètement" : Un 
Sergent Noir Se rappelle Buchenwald</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Vi Andar Absolutamente": Um Sergeant 
Preto Recordar Buchenwald</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ho visto Camminare Completamente": Un 
Sergeant Nero Remembers Buchenwald</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εβλέίδα το περπάτημα απολύτωσ": Ένας 
μαύρος λοχίας θυμάται Buchenwald</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Vi Recorrer Absolutamente": Un Sargento 
Negro Remembers Buchenwald</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The American soldiers who liberated the Buchenwald Nazi concentration camp had powerful reactions to what they saw, often shaped by their own backgrounds. Leon Bass was a nineteen-year-old African-American sergeant serving in a segregated army unit when he encountered the "walking dead" of Buchenwald. Like many others, he tried to repress his memories of the horrors that he saw there and "never talked about it all." But in the 1960s, while involved in the Civil Rights movement and teaching, he met a Holocaust survivor and felt moved to declare to his students that "I was there, I saw." In this interview with Pam Sporn and her students, he linked the oppression of the Jews and other Nazi victims with the segregation and discrimination faced by African Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die amerikanischen Soldaten, die das Buchenwald 
Nazi Konzentration Lager befreiten, hatten leistungsfähige Reaktionen
auf was sie sahen, häufig geformt durch ihre eigenen Hintergründe. 
Leon Baß war eine neunzehn-Jahr-alte Afrikanisch-Amerikanische 
Sergeantumhüllung in einer getrennten Armeemaßeinheit, als er von 
Buchenwald "absolut" gehen antraf. Wie viele andere versuchte 
er, seine Speicher der Grausigkeiten zu unterdrücken, die er dort sah
und "befaßte mit ihm sich allem nie." Aber in den sechziger 
Jahren, während es in die Zivilrechtbewegung und -unterricht mit 
einbezogen wird, traf er einen Holocaust Überlebenden und der Filz, 
der verschoben wurde, um zu seinen Kursteilnehmern zu erklären, die 
"ich war dort, sah ich." In diesem Interview mit PAM Sporn und 
ihre Kursteilnehmer, band er die Unterdrückung der Juden und anderer 
Nazi Opfer mit der Abtrennung und die Unterscheidung, die von African 
Americans gegenübergestellt wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les soldats américains qui ont libéré le camp 
de concentration Nazi de Buchenwald ont eu les réactions 
puissantes à ce qu'ils ont vu, souvent formé par leurs propres 
milieux. La basse de Leon était une dix-neuf-année-vieille 
portion afro-américaine de sergent dans une unité d'armée isolée 
quand il a rencontré la "marche complètement" de Buchenwald. 
Comme beaucoup d'autres, il a essayé de réprimer ses mémoires
des horreurs qu'il a vues là et "n'a jamais parlé d'elle toute." 
Mais dans les années 60, tandis qu'impliqué dans le mouvement 
et l'enseignement de droits civiques, il a rencontré Holocauste un 
survivant et feutre déplacé pour déclarer à ses étudiants qui 
"j'étais là, j'ai vu." Dans cette entrevue avec la PAM Sporn 
et ses étudiants, il a joint l'oppression des juifs et d'autres 
victimes Nazies avec la ségrégation et la discrimination 
faite face par African Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os soldados americanos que liberated o campo de 
concentração nazi de Buchenwald tiveram as reações poderosas a o 
que viram, dado forma frequentemente por seus próprios fundos. 
O baixo de Leon era um serving Africano-Americano 
dezenove-ano-velho do sergeant em uma unidade de exército segregada 
quando encontrou "andar absolutamente" de Buchenwald. Como 
muitas outras, tentou repress suas memórias dos horrors que viu lá e
"nunca falou sobre ele todo." Mas nos 1960s, quando envolvido no
movimento e no ensino das direitas civis, encontrou-se com um 
sobrevivente de Holocaust e feltro movido para declarar a seus 
estudantes que "eu era lá, eu vi." Nesta entrevista com Pam 
Sporn e seus estudantes, ligou o oppression dos jews e de outras 
vítimas nazi com o segregation e a discriminação enfrentada por 
Africano Americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I soldati americani che hanno liberato 
l'accampamento di concentrazione Nazista di Buchenwald hanno avuti 
reazioni potenti a che cosa hanno visto, a forma di spesso dai loro 
propri ambiti di provenienza. La spigola di Leon era un 
diciannove-anno-vecchio serving Africano-Americano del sergeant in 
un'unità di esercito segregata quando ha incontrato "camminare 
completamente" di Buchenwald. Come molti altre, ha provato a 
reprimere le sue memorie degli orrori che ha visto là e "non la ha 
parlata mai tutta." Ma negli anni 60, mentre coinvolto nel 
movimento e nell'insegnamento di diritti civili, ha venuto a contatto 
di un superstite di Holocaust e feltro spostato per dichiarare ai suoi
allievi che "ero là, ho visto." In questa intervista con il PAM
Sporn ed i suoi allievi, ha collegato il oppression degli ebrei e di 
altre vittime Naziste con la segregazione e la distinzione 
affrontata dall'African Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αμερικανικοί στρατιώτες που ελευθέρωσαν το 
ναζιστικό στρατόπεδο συγκέντρωσης Buchenwald είχαν τις ισχυρές
αντιδράσεις σε αυτό που εβλέίδαν, συχνά διαμορφωμένος από
τα υπόβαθρά τους. Η πέρκα Leon ήταν ένας 
δεκαεννέα-χρονών αφρικανικός-αμερικανικός λοχίας που σε
μια διαχωρισμένη μονάδα στρατού όταν αντιμετώπισε το "περπάτημα 
απολύτωσ" Buchenwald. Όπως πολλούς άλλους, προσπάθησε να
καταστείλει τις μνήμες του των φρικών που εβλέίδε εκεί 
και "δεν μίλησε ποτέ για τον όλοι." Αλλά στη δεκαετία του 
'60, ενώ περιλαμβάνεται στη μετακίνηση και τη διδασκαλία αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων, συνάντησε έναν επιζόντα ολοκαυτώματος και 
αισθάνθηκε κινημένος για να δηλώσει στους σπουδαστές του ότι 
"ήμουν εκεί, εβλέίδα." Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη με 
Pam Sporn και τους σπουδαστές της, σύνδεσε την κατοχή των 
Εβραίων και άλλων ναζιστικών θυμάτων με το διαχωρισμό και τη 
διάκριση που αντιμετωπίστηκαν από αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los soldados americanos que liberaron el campo de 
concentración nazi de Buchenwald tenían reacciones de gran alcance a
lo que vieron, formado a menudo por sus propios fondos. El bajo 
de Leon era una diecinueve-año-vieja porción Africano-Americana del 
sargento en una unidad de ejército segregada cuando él encontró 
"recorrer absolutamente" de Buchenwald. Como muchos otras, él 
intentó reprimir sus memorias de los horrores que él vio allí y 
"nunca habló de él todo." Pero en los años 60, mientras que 
estaba implicado en el movimiento y la enseñanza de las derechas 
civiles, él satisfizo a sobreviviente de Holocaust y fieltro movido 
para declarar a sus estudiantes que "era allí, vi." En esta 
entrevista con PAM Sporn y sus estudiantes, él conectó la opresión 
de los judíos y de otras víctimas nazis a la segregación y la 
discriminación hecha frente por african americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086292</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105564</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-saw-the-walking-dead-a-black-sergeant-remembers-buchenwald</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
