<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108184</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108184</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206281</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">EPA: Wastes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">EPA: Vergeudungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">EPA : Pertes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">EPA: Desperdícios</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">EPA: Sprechi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">EPA: Απόβλητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">EPA: Basuras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a place where students and teachers can order educational materials, activity books and games that help raise awareness about solid waste issues, learn how to gain hands-on awareness of waste reduction, recycling, and composting, through solid waste service-learning projects, and learn about careers in solid waste management.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Platz, in dem Kursteilnehmer und Lehrer 
pädagogische Materialien bestellen können, Aktivität anmeldet und 
Spiele, die helfen, Bewußtsein über Feststoffausgaben aufzuwerfen, 
erlernen, wie man das Blindeinschub Bewußtsein der überschüssigen 
Verkleinerung gewinnt und aufbereitet, und Düngen, durch 
Service-erlernenprojekte des Feststoffs und erlernt über Karrieren im
Feststoffmanagement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un endroit où les étudiants et les 
professeurs peuvent commander les matériaux éducatifs, activité 
réserve et les jeux qui aident à soulever la conscience au sujet des
issues de déchets solides, apprennent comment gagner la conscience à
commande manuelle de la réduction de rebut, réutilisant, et 
terreautage, par des projets d'service-étude de déchets solides, et 
se renseigne sur des carrières dans la gestion de déchets solides.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um lugar onde os estudantes e os professores 
possam requisitar materiais educacionais, atividade registra e os 
jogos que ajudam levantar a consciência sobre edições do 
desperdício contínuo, aprendem como ganhar a consciência hands-on 
da redução waste, recycling, e composting, com os projetos 
deaprendizagem do desperdício contínuo, e aprende sobre carreiras na
gerência waste contínua.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un posto in cui gli allievi e gli insegnanti 
possono ordinare i materiali educativi, attività prenota e giochi che
contribuiscono a sollevare la consapevolezza circa le edizioni dei 
rifiuti solidi, imparano come guadagnare la consapevolezza hands-on di
riduzione residua, riciclante e concimare con la composta, con i 
progetti servizio-imparanti dei rifiuti solidi ed impara circa le 
carriere nella gestione dei rifiuti solidi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια θέση όπου οι σπουδαστές και οι δάσκαλοι 
μπορούν να διατάξουν τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, βιβλία 
δραστηριότητας και τα παιχνίδια που βοηθούν να βελτιώσουν την 
πληροφόρηση για τα ζητήματα στερεών αποβλήτων, μαθαίνουν πώς να 
κερδίσουν την εμπράγματη συνειδητοποίηση της μείωσης αποβλήτων, 
ανακυκλώνοντας, και η λιπασματοποίηση, μέσω των προγραμμάτων 
υπηρεσία-εκμάθησης στερεών αποβλήτων, και μαθαίνουν για τις 
σταδιοδρομίες στη διαχείριση των στερεών αποβλήτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un lugar en donde los estudiantes y los 
profesores pueden pedir los materiales educativos, actividad reserva y
los juegos que ayudan a levantar conocimiento sobre ediciones de la 
basura sólida, aprenden cómo ganar el conocimiento con manos de la 
reducción inútil, reciclando, y abonamiento, con proyectos 
servicio-que aprenden de la basura sólida, y aprende sobre carreras 
en la gestión de desechos sólida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206281</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108184</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/epa-wastes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
