<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108639</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108639</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211173</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Online Science-athon: Catching Sunshine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Onlinewissenschaft-athon: Anziehender 
Sonnenschein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science-athon En ligne : Soleil 
Contagieux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência-athon Em linha: Luz do sol 
Catching</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza-athon In linea: Sole Catching</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε απευθείας σύνδεση επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον: 
Σύλληψη της ηλιοφάνειας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia-athon En línea: Sol Catching</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Online Science-athon offers elementary and middle-grade students opportunities to discover the science in their daily lives. Presented as challenges, the Science-athon asks students to investigate their world in ways that are engaging and fun, easy for teachers to incorporate into their teaching, and instructive. Students doing Catching Sunshine decide on a container -- tin can, cardboard box, plastic bucket, paper bag, or similar object -- to use as a solar collector. Then they determine how to maximize the amount of sunshine the collector catches by figuring out how to point it, what colors and textures to use on the inside surfaces, and how to insulate it. Reviewing scientific information helps students improve the effectiveness of their collector designs and make predictions about the ones they think will catch the most sunshine. On Catching Sunshine Day, students collect and record data to share with other students doing the challenge. Analysis of their data and data collected by others allows participants to formulate explanations, to check these explanations against scientific knowledge and the explanations and experiences of others, and to put their ideas to practical use.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Onlinewissenschaft-athon bietet die 
grundlegende und Mittlergrad Kursteilnehmer Gelegenheiten, die 
Wissenschaft in ihren täglichen Lebensdauern zu entdecken an. 
Dargestellt als Herausforderungen, bittet die Wissenschaft-athon
Kursteilnehmer, ihre Welt in den Methoden, die und sich engagieren, im
Spaß nachzuforschen, einfach, damit Lehrer in ihren Unterricht 
verbinden, und lehrreich. Die Kursteilnehmer, die anziehenden 
Sonnenschein tun, entscheiden auf einem Behälter -- Blechdose, 
Sammelpack, Plastikwanne, Papierbeutel oder ähnliche Nachricht -- als
Sonnenkollektor zu verwenden. Dann stellen sie fest, wie man die
Menge des Sonnenscheins maximiert, den der Kollektor abfängt, indem 
er darstellt aus, wie man ihn zeigt, welche Farben und auf den 
Innenflächen zu verwenden Beschaffenheiten, und wie man ihn isoliert.
Fachinformation Hilfen Kursteilnehmer wiederholend, verbessern 
Sie die Wirksamkeit ihrer Kollektordesigns und bilden Sie Vorhersagen 
über die, die sie abfangen den meisten Sonnenschein denken. An 
anziehendem Sonnenschein-Tag sammeln Kursteilnehmer und speichern 
Daten, um mit anderen Kursteilnehmern zu teilen, welche die 
Herausforderung tun. Analyse ihrer Daten und der Daten, die 
durch andere gesammelt werden, erlaubt Teilnehmern, Erklärungen zu 
formulieren, diese Erklärungen gegen wissenschaftliches Wissen und 
die Erklärungen und die Erfahrungen von anderen zu überprüfen, und 
ihre Ideen zum praktischen Gebrauch zu setzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science-athon en ligne offre les étudiants 
élémentaires et de moyen-catégorie des occasions de découvrir la 
science dans leurs vies quotidiennes. Présenté en tant que 
défis, la Science-athon demande à des étudiants d'étudier leur 
monde des voies qui s'engagent et de l'amusement, facile pour des 
professeurs d'incorporer à leur enseignement, et instructif. 
Les étudiants faisant le soleil contagieux décident d'un 
récipient -- boîte en fer blanc, cadre de carton, position en 
plastique, sac de papier, ou objet semblable -- pour utiliser comme 
capteur solaire. Alors ils déterminent comment maximiser la 
quantité de soleil que le collecteur attrape en figurant hors de la 
façon le diriger, quels couleurs et textures à utiliser sur les 
surfaces intérieures, et comment l'isoler. En passant en revue 
des étudiants d'aides d'information scientifique améliorez 
l'efficacité de leurs conceptions de collecteur et faites les 
prévisions au sujet de celles qu'ils pensent attraperont la plupart 
de soleil. Le jour contagieux de soleil, les étudiants 
rassemblent et enregistrent des données pour partager avec d'autres 
étudiants faisant le défi. L'analyse de leurs données et de 
données rassemblées par d'autres permet à des participants de 
formuler des explications, de contrôler ces explications contre la 
connaissance scientifique et les explications et des expériences de 
d'autres, et de mettre leurs idées à l'utilisation pratique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Ciência-athon em linha oferece estudantes 
elementares e da médio-classe oportunidades de descobrir a ciência 
em suas vidas diárias. Apresentado como desafios, a 
Ciência-athon pede que os estudantes investiguem seu mundo nas 
maneiras que estão acoplando e no divertimento, fácil para que os 
professores incorporem em seu ensino, e instructive. Os 
estudantes que fazem luz do sol catching decidem-se em um recipiente 
-- lata de lata, caixa de cartão, cubeta plástica, saco de papel, ou
objeto similar -- usar-se como um coletor solar. Então 
determinam como maximize a quantidade de luz do sol que o coletor 
trava figurando para fora de como o apontar, que cores e texturas a se
usar nas superfícies interiores, e como o isolar. Revendo 
estudantes das ajudas da informação científica melhore a eficácia 
de seus projetos do coletor e faça predições sobre essas que pensam
travarão a maioria de luz do sol. Em dia catching da luz do 
sol, os estudantes coletam e gravam dados para compartilhar com outros
estudantes que fazem o desafio. A análise de seus dados e de 
dados coletados por outros permite que os participants formulem 
explanações, verifiquem estas explanações de encontro ao 
conhecimento científico e as explanações e experiências de outras,
e ponham suas idéias ao uso prático.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Scienza-athon in linea offre gli allievi del 
centrale-grado ed elementari occasioni scoprire la scienza nelle loro 
vite quotidiane. Presentato come sfide, la Scienza-athon chiede 
agli allievi di studiare il loro mondo nei modi che stanno 
agganciandosi e nel divertimento, facile affinchè gli insegnanti 
incorpori nel loro insegnamento ed istruttivo. Gli allievi che 
fanno il sole catching decidono di un contenitore -- barattolo di 
latta, contenitore di cartone, sacco di carta di plastica, del benna, 
o oggetto simile -- usare come collettore solare. Allora 
determinano come elevare la quantità di sole che il collettore 
interferisce calcolando verso l'esterno come indicarlo, che colori e 
strutture da usare sulle superfici interne e come isolarlo. 
Rivedendo gli allievi di aiuti di informazione scientifica 
migliori l'efficacia dei loro disegni del collettore e faccia le 
previsioni circa quelle che pensino interferiscano la maggior parte 
del sole. Il giorno catching del sole, gli allievi raccolgono e 
registrano i dati per ripartirsi con altri allievi che fanno la sfida.
L'analisi dei loro dati e dei dati raccolti da altri permette 
che i partecipanti formulino le spiegazioni, controllino queste 
spiegazioni contro conoscenza scientifica e le spiegazioni e le 
esperienze in altre e mettano le loro idee ad uso pratico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σε απευθείας σύνδεση επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον 
προσφέρει τις στοιχειώδεις και μέσες ευκαιρίες σπουδαστών να 
ανακαλύψουν την επιστήμη στις καθημερινές ζωές τους. 
Παρουσιασμένη ως προκλήσεις, η επιστήμη -επιστήμη-ατχον 
ζητά από τους σπουδαστές για να ερευνήσει τον κόσμο τους στους 
τρόπους που δεσμεύουν και διασκέδαση, εύκολη για τους δασκάλους 
να ενσωματώσουν στη διδασκαλία τους, και διδακτική. Οι 
σπουδαστές που κάνουν πιάνοντας την ηλιοφάνεια αποφασίζουν 
σχετικά με ένα εμπορευματοκιβώτιο -- δοχείο κασσίτερου, κιβώτιο 
χαρτονιού, πλαστικός κάδος, τσάντα εγγράφου, ή παρόμοιο 
αντικείμενο -- στη χρήση ως ηλιακός συσσωρευτής. Κατόπιν 
καθορίζουν πώς να μεγιστοποιήσουν το ποσό ηλιοφάνειας που ο 
συλλέκτης πιάνει με τον υπολογισμό πώς να την δείξει, τί 
χρώματα και συστάσεις στη χρήση στις εσωτερικές επιφάνειες, και 
πώς να την μονώσει. Η αναθεώρηση των επιστημονικών 
πληροφοριών βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να βελτιώσουν την 
αποτελεσματικότητα των σχεδίων συλλεκτών τους και να κάνουν τις 
προβλέψεις για αυτές που σκέφτονται θα πιάσουν την περισσότερη 
ηλιοφάνεια. Στη σύλληψη της ημέρας ηλιοφάνειας, οι 
σπουδαστές συλλέγουν και τα στοιχεία αρχείων που μοιράζονται με 
άλλους σπουδαστές που κάνουν την πρόκληση. Η ανάλυση των 
στοιχείων τους και των στοιχείων που συλλέγονται από άλλα 
επιτρέπει στους συμμετέχοντες για να διατυπώσει τις εξηγήσεις, για
να ελέγξει αυτές τις εξηγήσεις σε σχέση με την επιστημονική 
γνώση και τις εξηγήσεις και την εμπειρία άλλες, και για να βάλει 
τις ιδέες τους στην πρακτική χρήση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Ciencia-athon en línea ofrece a estudiantes 
elementales y del medio-grado las oportunidades de descubrir la 
ciencia en sus vidas diarias. Presentado como desafíos, la 
Ciencia-athon pide que los estudiantes investiguen su mundo de las 
maneras que están enganchando y de la diversión, fácil para que los
profesores incorporen en su enseñanza, e instructivo. Los 
estudiantes que hacen la sol catching deciden sobre un envase -- lata 
de lata, caja de cartón, compartimiento plástico, bolsa de papel, u 
objeto similar -- utilizar como colector solar. Entonces se 
determinan cómo maximizar la cantidad de sol que el colector coge 
calculando fuera de cómo señalarlo, qué colores y texturas a 
utilizar en las superficies interiores, y cómo aislarlo. 
Repasando a estudiantes de las ayudas de la información 
científica mejore la eficacia de sus diseños del colector y haga las
predicciones sobre las que piensan cogerán la mayoría de la sol. 
En día catching de la sol, los estudiantes recogen y registran 
datos para compartir con otros estudiantes que hacen el desafío. 
El análisis de sus datos y de los datos recogidos por otros 
permite que los participantes formulen explicaciones, que controlen 
estas explicaciones contra conocimiento científico y las 
explicaciones y las experiencias de otras, y que pongan sus ideas al 
uso práctico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211173</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108639</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/catching-sunshine</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
