<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103483</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103483</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213094</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Wave Superposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Welle Superposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Superposition de Vague</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Superposition Da Onda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Superposition Dell'Onda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κύμα Superposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Superposición De la Onda</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Wave Superposition exercise is an interactive JAVA environment that allows the user to look at the linear superposition of up to four ocean waves of different amplitudes and period. Direction of travel (right or left) and the local depth of water can be specified. Students can learn definitions of wavelength, wave speed, wave amplitude, and wave period and gain an overall understanding of the superposition of waves. Waves reflection and standing waves can also be explored. Although this is an oceanography activity it could be used in any course that has some discussion of waves (electromagnetic waves, sound waves, seismic waves, and water waves). This site also provides teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment idea and additional resources on wave superposition. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Welle Superpositionübung ist eine interaktive 
JAVA Umgebung, die dem Benutzer erlaubt, den linearen Superposition 
von bis vier Ozeanwellen der unterschiedlichen Umfänge und der 
Periode zu betrachten. Richtung des Spielraums (recht oder link)
und die lokale Tiefe des Wassers können spezifiziert werden. 
Kursteilnehmer können Definitionen der Wellenlänge erlernen, 
Geschwindigkeit wellenartig bewegen, Umfang wellenartig bewegen und 
Periode wellenartig bewegen und ein gesamtes Verständnis des 
Superposition der Wellen gewinnen. Wellen Reflexion und 
Stellungwellen können auch erforscht werden. Obgleich dieses 
eine Ozeanographieaktivität ist, könnte es in jedem möglichem Kurs 
verwendet werden, der irgendeine Diskussion über Wellen hat 
(elektromagnetische Wellen, Schallwellen, seismische Wellen und 
Wasserwellen). Diese Site stellt auch unterrichtende Anmerkungen
und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Idee und zusätzliche 
Betriebsmittel auf Welle Superposition zur Verfügung. Diese 
Aktivität ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'exercice de superposition de vague est un 
environnement interactif de JAVA qui permet à l'utilisateur de 
regarder la superposition linéaire de jusqu'à quatre vagues d'océan
des amplitudes et de la période différentes. La direction du 
voyage (droit ou gauche) et la profondeur locale de l'eau peuvent 
être indiquées. Les étudiants peuvent apprendre des 
définitions de longueur d'onde, onduler la vitesse, onduler 
l'amplitude, et onduler la période et gagner un arrangement global de
la superposition des vagues. Des vagues de réflexion et de 
position de vagues peuvent également être explorées. Bien que
ce soit une activité d'océanographie il pourrait être utilisé dans
n'importe quel cours qui a une certaine discussion des vagues (ondes 
électromagnétiques, vagues saines, vagues séismiques, et vagues de 
l'eau). Ce site fournit également les notes et les extrémités
d'enseignement, le matériel didactique, l'idée d'évaluation et les 
ressources supplémentaires sur la superposition de vague. Cette
activité fait partie de la collection de point de départ : 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O exercício do superposition da onda é um 
ambiente interativo de JAVA que permita que o usuário olhe o 
superposition linear de até quatro ondas do oceano de amplitudes e do
período diferentes. O sentido do curso (direito ou esquerdo) e 
a profundidade local da água podem ser especificados. Os 
estudantes podem aprender definições do wavelength, acenar a 
velocidade, acenar a amplitude, e acenar o período e ganhar uma 
compreensão total do superposition das ondas. As ondas da 
reflexão e da posição das ondas podem também ser exploradas. 
Embora esta fosse uma atividade do oceanography poderia ser 
usado em todo o curso que tiver alguma discussão das ondas (ondas 
eletromagnéticas, ondas sadias, ondas seismic, e ondas da água). 
Este local fornece também notas e pontas ensinando, materiais 
de ensino, idéia da avaliação e recursos adicionais no 
superposition da onda. Esta atividade é parte da coleção do 
ponto começar: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'esercitazione di superposition dell'onda è un 
ambiente interattivo del JAVA che permette che l'utente guardi il 
superposition lineare di fino a quattro onde dell'oceano delle 
ampiezze e del periodo differenti. Il senso della corsa (di 
destra o di sinistra) e la profondità locale di acqua possono essere 
specificati. Gli allievi possono imparare le definizioni della 
lunghezza d'onda, fluttuare la velocità, fluttuare l'ampiezza e 
fluttuare il periodo e guadagnare una comprensione generale del 
superposition delle onde. Le onde di riflessione e di condizione
delle onde possono anche essere esplorate. Anche se questa è 
un'attività di oceanografia potrebbe essere usato in tutto il corso 
che ha certa discussione sulle onde (onde elettromagnetiche, onde 
sonore, onde sismiche ed onde dell'acqua). Questo luogo 
egualmente fornisce le note e punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici,
idea di valutazione e risorse supplementari sul superposition 
dell'onda. Questa attività fa parte dell'accumulazione del 
punto di partenza: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η άσκηση Superposition κυμάτων είναι ένα διαλογικό
περιβάλλον της ΙΑΒΑΣ που επιτρέπει στο χρήστη για να εξετάσει το 
γραμμικό superposition μέχρι τεσσάρων ωκεάνιων κυμάτων των 
διαφορετικών ευρών και της περιόδου. Η κατεύθυνση του 
ταξιδιού (δεξιού ή αριστερού) και το τοπικό βάθος του ύδατος 
μπορούν να προσδιοριστούν. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να μάθουν 
τους ορισμούς του μήκους κύματος, της ταχύτητας κυμάτων, του 
εύρους κυμάτων, και της περιόδου κυμάτων και να κερδίσουν μια 
γενική κατανόηση του superposition των κυμάτων. Η 
αντανάκλαση κυμάτων και τα μόνιμα κύματα μπορούν επίσης να 
εξερευνηθούν. Αν και αυτό είναι μια δραστηριότητα 
ωκεανογραφίας θα μπορούσε να χρησιμοποιηθεί σε οποιαδήποτε σειρά 
μαθημάτων που διοργανώνει κάποια συζήτηση των κυμάτων 
(ηλεκτρομαγνητικά κύματα, υγιή κύματα, σεισμικά κύματα, και 
κύματα ύδατος). Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει επίσης τις 
σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, την 
ιδέα αξιολόγησης και τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς στο 
superposition κυμάτων. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος 
της συλλογής αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ejercicio de la superposición de la onda es un 
ambiente interactivo de JAVA que permite que el utilizador mire la 
superposición linear de hasta cuatro ondas del océano de diversos 
amplitudes y período. La dirección del recorrido (derecho o 
izquierdo) y la profundidad local del agua pueden ser especificadas. 
Los estudiantes pueden aprender definiciones de la longitud de 
onda, agitar velocidad, agitar amplitud, y agitar período y ganar una
comprensión total de la superposición de ondas. Las ondas de 
la reflexión y de la situación de las ondas pueden también ser 
exploradas. Aunque esto es una actividad de la oceanografía 
podría ser utilizada en cualquier curso que tenga cierta discusión 
de las ondas (ondas electromagnéticas, ondas acústicas, ondas 
sísmicas, y ondas del agua). Este sitio también proporciona a 
notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales didácticos, 
idea del gravamen y los recursos adicionales en la superposición de 
la onda. Esta actividad es parte de la colección del punto de 
partida: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213094</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103483</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/wave-superposition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
