<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108792</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108792</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086067</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Defending Greenwood": A Survivor Recalls the Tulsa Race Riot of 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Verteidigender Wald": Ein Überlebender 
erinnert an den Tulsa Rennen-Aufstand von 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Greenwood Défendant" : Un survivant 
rappelle l'émeute de course de Tulsa de 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Greenwood Defendendo": Um sobrevivente 
recorda o motim da raça de Tulsa de 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Greenwood Difendente": Un superstite 
ricorda il tumulto della corsa de Tulsa di 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Υπεράσπιση greenwood": Ένας επιζών 
υπενθυμίζει τη φυλετική ταραχή Tulsa του 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Bosque verde Que defiende": Un 
sobreviviente recuerda el alboroto de la raza de Tulsa de 1921</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The post-World War I period in the United States saw devastating race riots around the nation: in small cities and in larger ones. But the Tulsa race riot in 1921 was perhaps the worst. Sparked by the supposed sexual assault of a white woman by a young black man, white Tulsa residents went on a twenty-four-hour rampage which resulted in the death of anywhere from 75 to 250 people and the burning of more than 1,000 black homes and businesses. Yet the African-Americans of Tulsa were not passive victims: when armed whites congregated at the Tulsa courthouse planning to lynch the young black imprisoned for the rape they were met by a crowd of equally angry blacks determined to prevent the lynching. In this interview with historian Scott Ellsworth, W. D. Williams proudly remembered the self-assertiveness of local black citizens, including his father, who took up arms to defend home and community.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Periode des Pfosten-Weltkrieges I in den 
Vereinigten Staaten sah verheerende Rennenaufstände um die Nation: 
in den kleinen Städte und in den größeren. Aber der 
Tulsa Rennenaufstand 1921 war möglicherweise das falschste. 
Gefunkt durch den angenommenen sexuellen Angriff einer weißen 
Frau durch einen jungen schwarzen Mann, gingen weiße Tulsa Bewohner 
auf eine Zwanzig-vier-Stunde randalieren, die den Tod von 
überall von 75 bis 250 Leuten und das Brennen von mehr als 1.000 
schwarzen Häusern und von Geschäften ergab. Noch waren die 
Afrikanisch-Amerikaner von Tulsa nicht passive Opfer: als 
bewaffnet das Weiß, das an der Tulsa Gerichtplanung versammelt wurde,
um das junge Schwarze zu lynchen eingesperrt wurde für den Raub, 
wurden sie, von einer Masse der gleichmäßig verärgerten Schwarzen 
getroffen, die festgestellt wurden, um das Lynchen zu verhindern. 
In diesem Interview mit Historiker Scott Ellsworth, W. D. 
Williams erinnerte stolz sich das an self-Selbstsicherheit der lokalen 
schwarzen Bürger, einschließlich seinen Vater, der Arme aufnahm, um 
Haus und Gemeinschaft zu verteidigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La période de la guerre I de poteau-Monde aux 
Etats-Unis a vu des émeutes dévastatrices de course dans la nation :
dans de petites villes et dans les plus grandes. Mais 
l'émeute de course de Tulsa en 1921 était peut-être la plus 
mauvaise. Étincelé par l'assaut sexuel supposé d'une femme 
blanche par un jeune homme noir, les résidants blancs de Tulsa sont 
allés sur un saccage de vingt-quatre-heure qui a eu comme 
conséquence la mort n'importe où de de 75 à 250 personnes et la 
brûlure de plus de 1.000 maisons et entreprises noires. 
Pourtant les Afro-Américains de Tulsa n'étaient pas les victimes 
passives : si armés des blancs rassemblés à la planification 
de tribunal de Tulsa pour lyncher le jeune noir emprisonné pour le 
viol ils ont été rencontrés par une foule des noirs également 
fâchés déterminés pour empêcher lyncher. Dans cette 
entrevue avec l'historien Scott Ellsworth, W. D. Williams s'est 
fièrement rappelé le art de l'auto-portrait-assertiveness des citoyens noirs 
locaux, y compris son père, qui a pris des bras pour défendre la 
maison et la communauté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O período da guerra I do borne-Mundo nos estados 
unidos viu motins devastating da raça em torno da nação: em 
cidades pequenas e nas maiores. Mas o motim da raça de Tulsa em
1921 era talvez o mais mau. Acendido pelo assalto sexual suposto
de uma mulher branca por um homem preto novo, os residentes brancos de
Tulsa foram em um rampage de vinte-quatro-hora que resultasse na morte
em qualquer lugar  de 75 a 250 povos e da queimadura de mais de 1.000 
HOME e negócios pretos. Contudo os Africano-Americanos de Tulsa
não eram vítimas passivas: quando armados os brancos 
congregated no planeamento do tribunal de Tulsa para lynch o preto 
novo imprisoned para a violação foram encontrados com por uma 
multidão dos pretos ingualmente irritados determinados impedir 
lynching. Nesta entrevista com historian Scott Ellsworth, W. D. 
Williams recordou orgulhosamente o self-self-assertiveness de 
cidadãos pretos locais, including seu pai, que fêz exame acima dos 
braços para defender a HOME e a comunidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il periodo di guerra I del alberino-Mondo in unito
Dichiara i tumulti devastating della corsa della sega intorno 
alla nazione: in piccole città ed in quelle più grandi. 
Ma il tumulto della corsa de Tulsa in 1921 era forse il più 
difettoso. Scintillato tramite l'assalto sessuale presunto di 
una donna bianca dall'uomo nero giovane, i residenti bianchi de Tulsa 
sono andato su un rampage di venti-quattro-ora che ha provocato la 
morte dovunque di 75 - 250 genti e bruciarsi di più di 1.000 sedi e 
commercio neri. Tuttavia gli Africano-Americani di Tulsa non 
erano vittime passive: una volta munite i bianchi congregated 
alla pianificazione del courthouse de Tulsa per lynch l'incarcerato 
nero giovane per la violenza sono stati venuti a contatto di da una 
folla dei neri ugualmente arrabbiati determinati per impedire 
lynching. In questa intervista con lo storico Scott Ellsworth, 
W. D. Williams si è ricordato fiero del auto-self-assertiveness dei 
cittadini neri locali, compreso il suo padre, che ha preso 
l'armi per difendere la sede e la Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετα-παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι περίοδος στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες εβλέίδε τις καταστρεπτικές φυλετικές ταραχές 
γύρω από το έθνος: στις μικρές πόλεις και μεγαλύτερες. 
Αλλά η φυλετική ταραχή Tulsa το 1921 ήταν ίσως η 
χειρότερη. Σπινθηρισμένοι από την υποτιθέμενη σεξουαλική 
επίθεση μιας λευκιάς γυναίκας από έναν νέο μαύρο άνδρα, οι 
λευκοί κάτοικοι Tulsa πήγαν σε μια έξαλλη συμπεριφορά 
είκοσι-τέσσερις-ώρας που οδήγησε στο θάνατο οπουδήποτε από 
75 έως 250 ανθρώπους και το κάψιμο περισσότερων από 
1.000 μαύρων σπιτιών και επιχειρήσεων. Ακόμα οι 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανοί Tulsa δεν ήταν παθητικά θύματα: 
όταν τα οπλισμένα λευκά συναθροίστηκαν στο δικαστήριο 
Tulsa προγραμματίζοντας να λυντσάρουν το νέο Μαύρο που 
φυλακίστηκε για το βιασμό καλύφτηκαν από ένα πλήθος των 
εξίσουων ν Μαύρων αποφάσισαν να αποτρέψουν το λυντσάρισμα. 
Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη με τον ιστορικό Scott 
Ellsworth, Θ*Ω. Δ. Ουίλιαμς θυμήθηκε υπερήφανα τη 
μόνος-ασφάλεια των τοπικών μαύρων πολιτών, συμπεριλαμβανομένου 
του πατέρα του, ο οποίος πήρε τα όπλα για να υπερασπίσει το 
σπίτι και την κοινότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El período de la guerra I del poste-Mundo en los 
Estados Unidos consideró alborotos devastadores de la raza alrededor 
de la nación: en ciudades pequeñas y en las más grandes. 
Pero el alboroto de la raza de Tulsa en 1921 era quizás el 
peor. Chispeado por el asalto sexual supuesto de una mujer 
blanca por un hombre negro joven, los residentes blancos de Tulsa 
fueron en un alboroto de la veinte-cuatro-hora que dio lugar a la 
muerte dondequiera a partir de 75 a 250 personas y quemarse de más de
1.000 hogares y negocios negros. Con todo los 
Africano-Americanos de Tulsa no eran víctimas pasivas: cuando 
son armada los blancos juntados en las hojas de operación (planning) 
del palacio de justicia de Tulsa para lynch el negro joven encarcelado
para la violación a una muchedumbre de los negros igualmente enojados
los satisficieron determinados para prevenir lynching. En esta 
entrevista con el historiador Scott Ellsworth, W. D. Williams recordó
orgulloso la uno mismo-asertividad de ciudadanos negros locales, 
incluyendo su padre, que tomó los brazos para defender el hogar y a 
comunidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086067</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108792</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/defending-greenwood-a-survivor-recalls-the-tulsa-race-riot-of-1921</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
