<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105531</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105531</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212123</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Simplified MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vereinfachtes MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">MRI Simplifié</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">MRI Simplificado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">MRI Semplificato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Απλουστευμένο MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">MRI Simplificado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Is it a tumor? Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) can tell. Your head is full of tiny radio transmitters (the nuclear spins of the hydrogen nuclei of your water molecules). In an MRI unit, these little radios can be made to broadcast their positions, giving a detailed picture of the inside of your head.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>es</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ist es ein Tumor? Kerspintomographie (MRI) 
kann sagen. Ihr Kopf ist von den kleinen Radioübermittlern voll
(die Kerndrehbeschleunigungen der Wasserstoffkerne Ihrer 
Wassermoleküle). In einer MRI Maßeinheit können diese kleinen
Radios gebildet werden, um ihre Positionen zu übertragen und eine 
ausführliche Abbildung des Inneres Ihres Kopfes geben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Est-ce une tumeur ? La formation image de 
résonance magnétique (MRI) peut indiquer. Votre tête est 
pleine des émetteurs par radio minuscules (les rotations nucléaires 
des noyaux d'hydrogène de vos molécules d'eau). Dans une 
unité de MRI, ces petites radios peuvent être faites pour annoncer 
leurs positions, donnant une image détaillée de l'intérieur de 
votre tête.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">É um tumor? A imagem latente de resonance 
magnético (MRI) pode dizer. Sua cabeça está cheia dos 
transmissores de rádio minúsculos (as rotações nucleares dos 
núcleos do hidrogênio de suas moléculas de água). Em uma 
unidade de MRI, estes rádios pequenos podem ser feitos para 
transmitir suas posições, dando um retrato detalhado do interior de 
sua cabeça.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">È un tumore? La formazione immagine di 
risonanza magnetica (MRI) può dire a. La vostra testa è piena 
delle radiotrasmittenti molto piccole (rotazioni nucleari dei nuclei 
dell'idrogeno delle vostre molecole di acqua). In un'unità di 
MRI, queste radio piccole possono essere fatte per trasmettere per 
radio le loro posizioni, danti un'immagine dettagliata della parte 
interna della vostra testa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Είναι ένας όγκος; Η απεικόνιση μαγνητικής 
αντήχησης (MRI) μπορεί να πει. Το κεφάλι σας είναι 
πλήρες των μικροσκοπικών ραδιο συσκευών αποστολής σημάτων (οι 
πυρηνικές περιστροφές των πυρήνων υδρογόνου των μορίων ύδατός 
σας). Σε μια μονάδα MRI, αυτά τα μικρά ραδιόφωνα μπορούν
να γίνουν για να μεταδώσουν ραδιοφωνικά τις θέσεις τους, που 
δίνουν μια λεπτομερή εικόνα του εσωτερικού του κεφαλιού σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Es un tumor? La proyección de imagen de 
resonancia magnética (MRI) puede decir. Su cabeza es llena de 
los radiotransmisores minúsculos (las vueltas nucleares de los 
núcleos del hidrógeno de sus moléculas de agua). En una 
unidad de MRI, estas pequeñas radios se pueden hacer para difundir 
sus posiciones, dando un cuadro detallado del interior de su cabeza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212123</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105531</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/simplified-mri</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
