<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108188</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108188</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086134</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Evicted.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gewaltsam vertrieben.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expulsé.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Evicted.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Evicted.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκδιωγμένος.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Desahuciado.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the Great Depression, the New Deal's Agricultural Adjustment Act attempted to raise disastrously low commodity prices by authorizing the federal government to pay farmers to raise fewer crops. These crop reduction subsidies enabled landlords to dispossess so many African-American tenants and share-croppers that the bill was often referred to sardonically as the Negro Removal Act." Despite such unintended consequences and other exclusions from New Deal programs</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des großen Tiefstands versuchte die 
landwirtschaftliche Justage-Tat des neuen Abkommens, verhängnisvoll 
niedrige Rohstoffpreise aufzuwerfen, indem sie die Bundesregierung 
autorisierte, um Landwirte zu zahlen, um wenige Getreide anzuheben. 
Diese ernten Verkleinerung Beihilfe aktivierte Hauswirte, um so 
viele Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Pächter und Anteil-Abschneider zu 
enteignen, daß die Rechnung wurde häufig angesprochen sardonically 
als die Schwarze-Abbau-Tat." Trotz solcher unbeabsichtigter 
Konsequenzen und anderer Ausschlüsse von den Programmen des neuen 
Abkommens</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la grande dépression, l'acte agricole du réglage
de nouvelle affaire a essayé d'augmenter des cours désastreusement 
bas de matières premières en autorisant le gouvernement fédéral 
pour payer des fermiers pour élever peu de collectes. Celles-ci
cultivent les propriétaires permis par subventions de réduction pour
déposséder tant de locataires et de part-tondeurs afro-américains que 
la facture désigné souvent sardonically sous le nom de la Loi de 
déplacement de nègre." En dépit de telles conséquences 
fortuites et d'autres exclusions des programmes de nouvelle affaire</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o depression grande, o ato agricultural do ajuste 
de negócio novo tentou levantar preços de producto desastrosamente 
baixos autorizando o governo federal para pagar fazendeiros para 
levantar poucas colheitas. Estes colhem landlords permitidos 
subsídios da redução para dispossess assim muitos tenants e 
parte-cultivadores Africano-Americanos que a conta estêve consultada 
frequentemente a sardonically como o ato da remoção do negro." 
Apesar de tais conseqüências unintended e de outras exclusões
dos programas do negócio novo</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la depressione grande, la Legge agricola di 
registrazione del nuovo affare ha tentato di aumentare i prezzi 
disastroso bassi dei prodotti autorizzando il governo federale per 
pagare i coltivatori per alzare i pochi raccolti. Questi potano 
i proprietari permessi sovvenzioni di riduzione per dispossess tanti 
inquilini e parte-coltivatori Africano-Americani che la fattura si è 
riferita a spesso sardonically come la Legge di rimozione del negro." 
Malgrado tali conseguenze non intenzionali ed altre esclusioni 
dai programmi di nuovo affare</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης, ο 
γεωργικός νόμος ρύθμισης της νέας διαπραγμάτευσης προσπάθησε να 
αυξήσει καταστροφικά τις χαμηλές τιμές προϊόντων με να 
επιτρέψει στην ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση για να πληρώσει τους 
αγρότες για να αυξήσει λιγότερες συγκομιδές. Αυτοί 
καλλιεργούν τους επιχορηγήσεις ιδιοκτήτες μείωσης για να 
απαλλοτριώσουν τόσους πολλούς αφρικανικός-αμερικανικούς μισθωτές
και επίμορτους καλλιεργητές στους οποίους ο λογαριασμός 
αναφέρθηκε συχνά σαρδόνια ως νόμος αφαίρεσης νέγρων." 
Παρά τέτοιες απρομελέτητες συνέπειες και άλλους 
αποκλεισμούς από τα νέα προγράμματα διαπραγμάτευσης</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la gran depresión, el acto agrícola del ajuste 
del nuevo reparto procuró subir precios desastroso bajos de materia 
autorizando el gobierno federal para pagar a granjeros para levantar 
pocas cosechas. Éstos cosechan a propietarios permitidos los 
subsidios de la reducción para dispossess a tan muchos arrendatarios 
y parte-cosechadores Africano-Americanos que la cuenta fue referida a 
menudo sardonically como el acto del retiro del negro." A pesar 
de tales consecuencias involuntarias y otras exclusiones de programas 
del nuevo reparto</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086134</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108188</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/evicted</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
