<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105090</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105090</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209929</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Area of a square. Definition and formula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bereich eines Quadrats. Definition und 
Formel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zone d'une place. Définition et formule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Área de um quadrado. Definição e 
fórmula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Zona di un quadrato. Definizione e formula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τομέας ενός τετραγώνου. Καθορισμός και τύπος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Área de un cuadrado. Definición y 
fórmula</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the area of a square. The applet shows a square with all vertices draggable. As you drag any one, the area id continuously calculated and shown on the applet. The square is filled with a unit grid to allow class estimation of area. The displayed calculation can be turned off. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die den Bereich eines Quadrats zeigen. Der applet 
zeigt ein Quadrat mit allen draggable Gipfeln. Wie Sie irgendein
schleppen, die Bereichsbezeichnung ununterbrochen errechnet und auf 
dem applet gezeigt. Das Quadrat wird mit einem Maßeinheit 
Rasterfeld gefüllt, um Kategorie Schätzung des Bereiches zu 
erlauben. Die angezeigte Berechnung kann abgestellt werden. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent la zone d'une place. L'applet montre une place 
avec tous les sommets draggable. Comme vous traînez n'importe 
quel, l'identification de zone sans interruption calculée et montrée
sur l'applet. La place est remplie de grille d'unité pour 
permettre l'évaluation de classe de la zone. Le calcul affiché
peut être arrêté. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de
plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. 
Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut 
lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison 
ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem a área de um quadrado. O applet mostra um quadrado 
com todos os vertices draggable. Como você arrasta qualquer, a 
identificação de área continuamente calculada e mostrada no applet.
O quadrado é enchido com uma grade da unidade para permitir o 
estimation da classe da área. O cálculo indicado pode ser 
desligado. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano la zona di un quadrato. Il applet mostra un quadrato 
con tutti i vertici draggable. Come trascinate qualunque, 
l'identificazione di zona calcolata ed indicata continuamente sul 
applet. Il quadrato è riempito di griglia dell'unità per 
permettere la valutazione del codice categoria di zona. Il 
calcolo visualizzato può essere spento. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τον τομέα ενός τετραγώνου. Το applet 
εμφανίζει ένα τετράγωνο με όλα vertices draggable. 
Δεδομένου ότι σέρνετε οποιου δήποτε, την ταυτότητα 
περιοχής που υπολογίζεται συνεχώς και που εμφανίζεται στο 
applet. Το τετράγωνο γεμίζουν με ένα πλέγμα μονάδων για 
να επιτρέψει την εκτίμηση κλάσης της περιοχής. Ο 
επιδειχθείς υπολογισμός μπορεί να κλειθεί. Το Applet 
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el área de un cuadrado. El applet muestra un 
cuadrado con todas las cimas draggable. Como usted arrastra, la 
identificación de área calculada y mostrada continuamente en el 
applet. El cuadrado se llena de una rejilla de la unidad para 
permitir la valoración de la clase del área. El cálculo 
visualizado se puede dar vuelta apagado. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209929</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105090</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/area-of-a-square-definition-and-formula</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
