<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104706</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104706</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206750</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">First American West: The Ohio River Valley, 1750-1820</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erster Amerikanischer Westen: Das Ohio River 
Valley, 1750-1820</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Premier Ouest Américain : l'Ohio River 
Valley, 1750-1820</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Primeiro Oeste Americano: O Ohio River 
Valley, 1750-1820</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Primo Ovest Americano: L'Ohio River Valley, 
1750-1820</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρώτη αμερικανική δύση: Η κοιλάδα ποταμών του 
Οχάιου, 1750-1820</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Primer Oeste Americano: El Ohio River Valley,
1750-1820</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">consists of letters, journals, books, newspapers, maps, and images documenting the land, peoples, and exploration of the trans-Appalachian West. The first European travelers, their relations with Native Americans, new settlers' migration and acquisition of land, navigation down the Ohio River, planting of crops, trade in tobacco and horses, and the roles of African Americans, women, churches, and schools are documented.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">aus Zeichen, Journalen, Büchern, Zeitungen, Karten
und Bildern besteht das Dokumentieren des Landes, der Völker und der 
Erforschung des Transport-Trans-Appalachianwestens. Die ersten 
europäischen Reisenden, ihre Relationen mit gebürtigen Amerikanern, 
Migration der neuen Siedleren und Datenerfassung des Landes, 
Navigation hinunter den Ohio Fluß, das Errichten der Getreide, der 
Handel im Tabak und in den Pferden und die Rollen der afrikanischen 
Amerikaner, der Frauen, der Kirchen und der Schulen werden 
dokumentiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">se compose des lettres, des journaux, des livres, 
des journaux, des cartes, et des images documentant la terre, les 
peuples, et l'exploration de l'ouest de transport-Appalache. Les
premiers voyageurs européens, leurs relations avec les Américains 
indigènes, transfert des nouveaux colons et saisie de terre, 
navigation en bas du fleuve de l'Ohio, la plantation des collectes, 
échanges de tabac et des chevaux, et les rôles des Américains, des 
femmes, des églises, et des écoles africains sont documentés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">consiste em letras, em jornais, em livros, em 
jornais, em mapas, e em imagens que documentam a terra, os povos, e a 
exploração do oeste do transporte-trans-Appalachian. Os 
primeiros viajantes europeus, suas relações com americanos nativos, 
a migração dos settlers' novos e a aquisição da terra, a 
navegação abaixo o rio de Ohio, plantar das colheitas, o comércio 
no tabaco e nos cavalos, e os papéis de americanos, de mulheres, de 
igrejas, e de escolas africanos são documentados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiste delle lettere, delle pubblicazioni, dei 
libri, dei giornali, dei programmi e delle immagini che documentano la
terra, la gente e l'esplorazione dell'ovest del 
trasporto-trans-Appalachian. I primi viaggiatori europei, i loro
rapporti con gli Americani natali, l'espansione dei nuovi settlers e 
l'aquisizione di terra, il percorso giù il fiume dell'Ohio, la 
piantatura dei raccolti, il commercio di tabacco e di cavalli ed i 
ruoli degli Americani, delle donne, delle chiese e delle scuole 
africani sono documentati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποτελείται από τις επιστολές, τα περιοδικά, τα 
βιβλία, τις εφημερίδες, τους χάρτες, και τις εικόνες 
τεκμηριώνοντας το έδαφος, τους λαούς, και την εξερεύνηση της 
δια-της όξινης απορροής δύσης. Οι πρώτοι ευρωπαϊκοί 
ταξιδιώτες, οι σχέσεις τους με εγγενείς Αμερικανούς, η 
μετανάστευση των νέων αποίκων και η απόκτηση του εδάφους, η 
ναυσιπλοϊ'α κάτω από τον ποταμό του Οχάιου, η φύτευση των 
συγκομιδών, το εμπόριο στον καπνό και τα άλογα, και οι ρόλοι 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών, των γυναικών, των εκκλησιών, και των 
σχολείων είναι τεκμηριωμένοι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">consiste en cartas, los diarios, los libros, los 
periódicos, las correspondencias, y las imágenes que documentan la 
pista, la gente, y la exploración del oeste del transporte-Apalache. 
Documentan a las primeras hojas de ruta (traveler) europeas, sus
relaciones con los americanos nativos, la migración de los nuevos 
colonos y la adquisición de la pista, la navegación rio abajo de 
Ohio, el plantar de cosechas, el comercio en tabaco y caballos, y el 
papeles de americanos, de mujeres, de iglesias, y de escuelas 
africanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206750</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104706</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/first-american-west-the-ohio-river-valley-1750-1820</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
