<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103625</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103625</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212948</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">USGS Biological Resources: National Activities</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">USGS Biologische Betriebsmittel: Nationale 
Aktivitäten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ressources Biologiques d'USGS : Activités 
Nationales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recursos Biológicos de USGS: Atividades 
Nacionais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risorse Biologiche di USGS: Attività 
Nazionali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βιολογικά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς USGS: Εθνικές
δραστηριότητες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recursos Biológicos de USGS: Actividades 
Nacionales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The mission of the United States Geological Survey's Biological Resources Discipline involves working with others to provide the scientific understanding and technologies needed to support the sound management and conservation of our Nation's biological resources. This website contains a comprehensive listing of biological research taking place within the USGS biology branch. This portal provides access to the National Bird Banding Project, the National Park Service flora and fauna database, the National Water Quality Assessment Program, the Global Change Research Program, the Land Use History of North America and many more. It is an excellent starting place for information and data from research projects within the USGS Biological Resources branch. This resource is a part of the Biocomplexity collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Mission der Vereinigte Staaten geologischen 
biologischen Betriebsmittel-der Disziplin Übersicht bezieht mit ein 
zu arbeiten in andere, um das Wissenschaftsverständnis und die 
Technologien zur Verfügung zu stellen, die benötigt werden, um das 
stichhaltige Management und die Erhaltung der biologischen 
Betriebsmittel unserer Nation zu unterstützen. Diese Web site 
enthält komplette Listen der biologischen Forschung stattfinden 
innerhalb des USGS Biologiezweigs. Dieses Portal liefert Zugriff
zum nationalen Vogel, den Streifenbildungen sich projizieren, die 
Nationalpark-Service-Flora und die Faunadatenbank, das nationale 
Wasserqualität-Einschätzung Programm, das globale Änderung 
Forschung Programm, die Flächennutzung-Geschichte von Nordamerika und
viel mehr. Es ist ein ausgezeichneter beginnender Platz zu 
Information und Daten von den Forschung Projekten innerhalb der USGS 
biologischen Betriebsmittel breiten sich aus. Dieses Hilfsmittel
ist ein Teil der Biocomplexity Ansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La mission de la discipline biologique des 
ressources de l'enquête géologique des Etats-Unis implique de 
travailler de d'autres pour fournir l'arrangement et les technologies 
scientifiques requis pour supporter la gestion et l'économie saines 
des ressources biologiques de notre nation. Ce site Web contient
une liste complète de recherche biologique ayant lieu dans le 
branchement de biologie d'USGS. Ce portail permet d'accéder à 
l'oiseau national que les bandes projettent, la flore de service de 
parc national et la base de données de faune, le programme national 
d'évaluation de qualité de l'eau, le programme de recherche global 
de changement, l'histoire d'utilisation de la terre de l'Amérique 
du nord et beaucoup plus. C'est un excellent endroit 
commençant pour information et les données des projets de recherche 
dans les ressources biologiques d'USGS s'embranchent. Cette 
ressource est une partie de la collection 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity de Biocomplexity.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A missão da disciplina biológica dos recursos do
exame geological unido dos estados envolve trabalhar com a outra para 
fornecer a compreensão científica e as tecnologias necessitadas 
suportar a gerência e o conservation sadios de recursos biológicos 
da nossa nação. Este Web site contem uma lista detalhada da 
pesquisa biológica que ocorre dentro da filial da biologia de USGS. 
Este portal fornece o acesso ao pássaro que nacional as bordas 
se projetam, o flora do serviço do parque nacional e a base de dados 
do fauna, o programa nacional da avaliação da qualidade de água, o 
programa de pesquisa global da mudança, o history do uso de terra de 
America do Norte e muito mais. É um lugar começando excelente 
para a informação e os dados dos projetos de pesquisa dentro dos 
recursos biológicos de USGS ramificam. Este recurso é uma 
parte da coleção http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity de 
Biocomplexity.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La missione del unito Dichiara le risorse 
che biologiche dell'indagine geologica la disciplina coinvolge 
lavorare con altre per fornire la conoscenza scientifica e le 
tecnologie state necessaria per sostenere la gestione e la 
conservazione sane delle risorse biologiche della nostra nazione. 
Questo Web site contiene un elenco completo della ricerca 
biologica che avviene all'interno del ramo di biologia di USGS. 
Questo portal fornisce l'accesso all'uccello che nazionale le 
fasce si proiettano, la flora di servizio del parco nazionale e la 
base di dati di fauna, il programma nazionale di valutazione di 
qualità dell'acqua, il programma di ricerca globale del cambiamento, 
la storia di utilizzazione delle terre dell'America del Nord e molto. 
È un posto cominciante eccellente per informazione ed i dati 
dai progetti di ricerca all'interno delle risorse biologiche di USGS 
si ramificano. Questa risorsa è una parte dell'accumulazione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity di Biocomplexity.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αποστολή της πειθαρχίας των βιολογικών στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς της Ηνωμένης γεωλογικής έρευνας περιλαμβάνει την 
εργασία με άλλα για να παρέχει την επιστημονική κατανόηση και τις
τεχνολογίες που απαιτούνται για να υποστηρίξουν την υγιείς 
διαχείριση και συντήρηση των βιολογικών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς 
του έθνους μας. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει μια περιεκτική 
λίστα της βιολογικής έρευνας που πραγματοποιείται μέσα στον 
κλάδο της βιολογίας USGS. Αυτή η πύλη παρέχει την 
πρόσβαση στο εθνικό έργο ζώνης πουλιών, την εθνική βάση 
δεδομένων χλωρίδας και πανίδας υπηρεσιών πάρκων, το εθνικό 
πρόγραμμα αξιολόγησης της ποιότητας νερού, το σφαιρικό 
ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα αλλαγής, την ιστορία χρήσης εδάφους της 
Βόρειας Αμερικής και πολύ περισσότερους. Είναι μια άριστη 
αρχική θέση για τις πληροφορίες και στοιχείο από τα ερευνητικά 
προγράμματα μέσα στον κλάδο των βιολογικών στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς USGS. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι 
ένα μέρος της Biocomplexity συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La misión de la disciplina biológica de los 
recursos de la encuesta sobre geológica Estados Unidos implica el 
trabajar con otras para proporcionar a la comprensión científica y a
las tecnologías necesitadas para utilizar la gerencia y la 
conservación sanas de los recursos biológicos de nuestra nación. 
Este Web site contiene un listado comprensivo de la 
investigación biológica que ocurre dentro de la ramificación de la 
biología de USGS. Este portal proporciona al acceso al pájaro 
nacional que las bandas proyectan, la flora del servicio del parque 
nacional y la base de datos de la fauna, el programa nacional del 
gravamen de la calidad del agua, el programa de investigación global 
del cambio, la historia de la utilización del suelo de Norteamérica 
y muchos más. Es un lugar que comienza excelente para la 
información y los datos de proyectos de investigación dentro de los 
recursos biológicos de USGS ramifican. Este recurso es una 
parte de la colección http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity de 
Biocomplexity.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212948</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103625</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/usgs-biological-resources-national-activities</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
