<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106314</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106314</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086887</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Amazonian Convention."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Amazonische Versammlung."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"La Convention Amazonienne."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"A Convenção Amazonian."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Convenzione Amazonian."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η αμαζόνεια Συνθήκη."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"La Convención Amazonian."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An organized movement led by women and dedicated to winning equality took formal shape at the first women's rights convention, held in Seneca Falls, New York in 1848. Many of the women who took part had been active in other social causes, such as the abolition of slavery, before joining the struggle for women's rights. In this 1859 cartoon published in  Harper's Weekly , hecklers disrupted the proceedings of a women's-rights meeting.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine organisierte Bewegung, die von den Frauen geführt 
wurde und gewinnender Gleichheit eingesetzt war, nahm formale Form an 
der ersten Rechtversammlung der Frauen, angehalten in den 
Seneca-Fällen, New York 1848. Viele der Frauen, die teilnahmen,
waren in anderen Sozialursachen, wie der Aufhebung der Sklaverei aktiv
gewesen, bevor sie den Kampf für Rechte der Frauen verbanden. 
Veröffentlichte diese 1859 Karikatur in der Wochenzeitung 
Harpers, Hecklers störte die Verfahren eines Frau-Rechte Treffens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un mouvement organisé mené par des femmes et consacré 
à l'égalité de gain a pris la forme formelle des premières à la 
convention des droits femmes, tenue en quelques automnes de 
Seneca, New York en 1848. Plusieurs des femmes qui ont 
participé avaient été en activité dans d'autres causes sociales, 
telles que l'abolition de l'esclavage, avant de joindre la lutte pour 
les droits des femmes. Dans ce 1859 dessin animé a édité en 
hebdomadaire de Harper, éléments perturbateurs a perturbé les 
démarches de se réunir de femme-droits.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um movimento organizado conduzido por mulheres e dedicado 
à igualdade ganhando fêz exame da forma formal na convenção das 
direitas das primeiras mulheres, prendida nas quedas do seneca, New 
York em 1848. Muitas das mulheres que fizeram exame da parte 
tinham sido ativas em outras causas sociais, tais como o abolition do 
slavery, antes de juntar o esforço para direitas das mulheres. 
Este em 1859 cartoon publicou no semanário de Harper, hecklers 
disrupted as continuações de um encontro das mulher-direitas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un movimento organizzato condotto dalle donne e dedicato 
ad uguaglianza di vincita ha preso la figura convenzionale alla 
convenzione di diritti delle prime donne, tenuta nelle cadute del 
seneca, New York in 1848. Molte delle donne che hanno 
partecipato erano state attive in altre cause sociali, quale 
l'abolizione di slavery, prima di unire la lotta per i diritti delle 
donne. In questo fumetto 1859 pubblicato in settimanale del 
Harper, i hecklers hanno interrotto gli atti di un venire a contatto 
di donna-parti di destra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια οργανωμένη μετακίνηση που οδηγήθηκε από τις 
γυναίκες και που αφιερώθηκε στη νίκη της ισότητας πήρε την 
επίσημη μορφή στη σύμβαση δικαιωμάτων των πρώτων γυναικών, που 
έγινε σε Σενέκα Falls, Νέα Υόρκη σε 1848, Πολλές από
τις γυναίκες που συμμετείχαν είχαν δραστηριοποιηθεί σε άλλες 
κοινωνικές αιτίες, όπως η κατάργηση της σκλαβιάς, πρίν ενώνουν 
την προσπάθεια για τα δικαιώματα των γυναικών. Σε αυτά τα 
κινούμενα σχέδια 1859 που δημοσιεύθηκαν στην εβδομαδιαία 
έκδοση Harper, τα hecklers αναστάτωσαν τα πρακτικά μιας 
συνεδρίασης των γυναικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un movimiento ordenado conducido por las mujeres y 
dedicado a la igualdad que ganaba tomó dimensión de una variable 
formal en la convención de las derechas de las primeras mujeres, 
llevada a cabo en las caídas del seneca, Nueva York en 1848. 
Muchas de las mujeres que participaron habían sido activas en 
otras causas sociales, tales como la abolición de la esclavitud, 
antes de ensamblar la lucha para las derechas de las mujeres. En
esta 1859 historieta publicó en el semanario de Harper, personas que 
interrumpe interrumpió los procedimientos de satisfacer de los 
mujer-derechos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086887</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106314</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-amazonian-convention</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
