<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106001</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106001</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Daisyworld Interactive Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Daisyworld Interaktive Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité Interactive de Daisyworld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Interativa De Daisyworld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Interattiva Di Daisyworld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαλογική δραστηριότητα Daisyworld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad Interactiva De Daisyworld</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students use a JAVA interface design to explore the Daisy World model. The model is intended to illustrate a mechanism by which biota might optimize their abiotic environment by means of negative feedback. The model does not attempt to describe all of the possible mechanisms and feedbacks which might influence the ways in which the plants and climate develop. Instead, it is an heuristic model, that seeks to describe the ways in which this mechanism might work. The original model was developed by Watson and Lovelock(1983). The JAVA interface comes with a link to a student activity page in PDF format. The activity is designed to take about 4 hours and is intended for introductory geoscience courses with an Earth Systems approach. This activity is appropriate for course with minimal mathematics or science prerequisites. Students should have some experience with either Excel, another graphing program, or making graphs by hand. Since the graphical analysis is introductory and fairly qualitative, the activity is appropriate as a beginning graphing exercise. This site also includes teaching notes and tips, necessary teaching materials, assessment ideas and additional resources. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer verwenden ein JAVA Schnittstelle 
Design, um das Gänseblümchen-Weltmodell zu erforschen. Das 
Modell soll eine Einheit veranschaulichen, durch die Flora und Fauna 
ihre abiotic Umgebung mittels des negativen Feedbacks optimieren 
konnte. Das Modell versucht nicht, alle möglichen von und von 
Feedbacks zu beschreiben, die die Methoden beeinflussen konnten, in 
denen die Betriebe und das Klima sich entwickeln. Stattdessen 
ist es ein heuristisches Modell, dieses die Suchvorgänge, zum der 
Methoden zu beschreiben, in denen diese Einheit arbeiten konnte. 
Das ursprüngliche Modell wurde durch Watson und Lovelock(1983) 
entwickelt. Die JAVA Schnittstelle kommt mit einem Link zu einer
Kursteilnehmeraktivität Seite im pdf Format. Die Aktivität ist
konzipiert, um ungefähr 4 Stunden zu dauern und ist für einleitende 
geoscience Kurse mit einer Masse Systeme Annäherung bestimmt. 
Diese Aktivität ist für Kurs mit minimalen Mathematik- oder 
Wissenschaftsvorbedingungen angebracht. Kursteilnehmer sollten 
etwas Erfahrung entweder mit übertreffen lassen, ein anderes 
graphisch darstellenprogramm oder Diagramme eigenhändig bilden. 
Da die graphische Analyse einleitend und ziemlich qualitativ 
ist, ist die Aktivität als anfangengraphisch darstellenübung 
angebracht. Diese Site schließt auch unterrichtende Anmerkungen
und Spitzen, notwendige Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen und 
zusätzliche Betriebsmittel ein. Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil 
der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants emploient une conception d'interface
de JAVA pour explorer le modèle du monde de marguerite. Le 
modèle est destiné pour illustrer un mécanisme par lequel le biota 
pourrait optimaliser leur environnement abiotique au moyen de feedback
négatif. Le modèle n'essaye pas de décrire tous les 
mécanismes et feedbacks possibles qui pourraient influencer les voies
dont les usines et le climat se développent. Au lieu de cela, 
c'est un modèle heuristique, ce des recherches pour décrire les 
voies dont ce mécanisme pourrait fonctionner. Le modèle 
initial a été développé par Watson et Lovelock(1983). 
L'interface de JAVA vient avec un lien à une page d'activité 
d'étudiant dans le format de pdf. L'activité est conçue pour 
prendre environ 4 heures et est destinée pour des cours 
préliminaires de geoscience avec une approche systématisée de la 
terre. Cette activité est appropriée pour le cours avec des 
choses nécessaires minimales de mathématiques ou de science. 
Les étudiants devraient faire exceler une certaine expérience 
avec, un programme de graphique différent, ou faire des graphiques à
la main. Puisque l'analyse graphique est préliminaire et assez 
qualitative, l'activité est appropriée comme exercice de graphique 
commençant. Ce site inclut également les notes et les 
extrémités d'enseignement, le matériel didactique nécessaire, les 
idées d'évaluation et les ressources supplémentaires. Cette 
activité fait partie de la collection de point de départ : 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes usam um projeto da relação de JAVA 
explorar o modelo do mundo do daisy. O modelo é pretendido 
ilustrar um mecanismo por que o biota pôde optimize seu ambiente 
abiotic por meio do feedback negativo. O modelo não tenta 
descrever todos os mecanismos e feedbacs possíveis que puderam 
influenciar as maneiras em que as plantas e o clima se tornam. 
Instead, é um modelo heurístico, esse as buscas para descrever
as maneiras em que este mecanismo pôde trabalhar. O modelo 
original foi desenvolvido por Watson e por Lovelock(1983). A 
relação de JAVA vem com uma ligação a uma página da atividade do 
estudante no formato do pdf. A atividade é projetada fazer 
exame de aproximadamente 4 horas e pretendida para cursos 
introdutórios do geoscience com uma aproximação de sistemas da 
terra. Esta atividade é apropriada para o curso com 
pré-requisitos mínimos da matemática ou da ciência. Os 
estudantes devem mandar alguma experiência com excel, um outro 
programa representando graficamente, ou fazer gráficos pela mão. 
Desde que a análise gráfica é introdutória e razoavelmente 
qualitative, a atividade é apropriada como um exercício 
representando graficamente de começo. Este local inclui também
notas e pontas ensinando, materiais de ensino necessários, idéias da
avaliação e recursos adicionais. Esta atividade é parte da 
coleção do ponto começar: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi usano un disegno dell'interfaccia del 
JAVA per esplorare il modello del mondo della margherita. Il 
modello è inteso per illustrare un meccanismo da cui la biota 
potrebbe ottimizzare il loro ambiente abiotic per mezzo di risposte 
negative. Il modello non tenta di descrivere tutte le meccanismi
e risposte possibili che potrebbero influenzare i modi in cui le 
piante ed il clima si sviluppano. Invece, è un modello 
euristico, quel ricerche per descrivere i modi in cui questo 
meccanismo potrebbe funzionare. Il modello originale è stato 
sviluppato da Watson e da Lovelock(1983). L'interfaccia del JAVA
viene con un collegamento ad una pagina di attività dell'allievo nel 
formato del pdf. L'attività è destinata per occorrere circa 4 
ore ed è intesa per i corsi introduttivi di geoscience con un 
approccio sistematico della terra. Questa attività è adatta 
per il corso con i requisiti preliminari minimi di scienza o di 
matematica. Gli allievi dovrebbero fare una certa esperienza 
con, un altro programma rappresentante graficamente, o eccellere fare 
i grafici a mano. Poiché l'analisi grafica è introduttiva e 
ragionevolmente qualitativa, l'attività è adatta come esercitazione 
rappresentante graficamente d'inizio. Questo luogo egualmente 
include le note e punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici necessari, 
idee di valutazione e risorse supplementari. Questa attività fa
parte dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν ένα σχέδιο διαπροσωπειών 
της ΙΑΒΑΣ για να ερευνήσουν το παγκόσμιο μοντέλο μαργαριτών. 
Το μοντέλο προορίζεται να επεξηγήσει έναν μηχανισμό από 
τον οποίο ο βιόκοσμος να βελτιστοποιήσει το αβιοτικό περιβάλλον 
τους με τη βοήθεια της αρνητικής ανατροφοδότησης. Το μοντέλο
δεν προσπαθεί να περιγράψει όλους τους πιθανούς μηχανισμούς και 
ανατροφοδοτήσεις που να επηρεάσουν τους τρόπους με τους οποίους οι
εγκαταστάσεις και το κλίμα αναπτύσσονται. Αντ' αυτού, είναι
ένα ευρετικό μοντέλο, αυτός επιδιώκει να περιγράψει τους 
τρόπους με τους οποίους αυτός ο μηχανισμός να λειτουργήσει. 
Το αρχικό μοντέλο αναπτύχθηκε από Watson και Lovelock 
(1983). Η διαπροσωπεία της ΙΑΒΑΣ έρχεται με μια σύνδεση με
μια σελίδα δραστηριότητας σπουδαστών με τη μορφή PDF. Η 
δραστηριότητα έχει ως σκοπό να πάρει περίπου 4 ώρες και 
προορίζεται για τις εισαγωγικές σειρές μαθημάτων geoscience με 
μια προσέγγιση γήινων συστημάτων. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα 
είναι κατάλληλη για τη σειρά μαθημάτων με τις ελάχιστες 
προϋποθέσεις μαθηματικών ή επιστήμης. Οι σπουδαστές 
πρέπει να έχουν κάποια εμπειρία με είτε Excel, άλλο που 
δίνει με γραφική παράσταση το πρόγραμμα, είτε που κάνει τις 
γραφικές παραστάσεις με το χέρι. Δεδομένου ότι η γραφική 
ανάλυση είναι εισαγωγική και αρκετά ποιοτική, η δραστηριότητα 
είναι κατάλληλη ως αρχή δίνοντας με γραφική παράσταση την 
άσκηση. Αυτή η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις σημειώσεις 
και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα απαραίτητα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις 
ιδέες αξιολόγησης και τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς. 
Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes utilizan un diseño del interfaz de
JAVA para explorar el modelo del mundo de la margarita. El 
modelo se piensa para ilustrar un mecanismo por el cual el biota pudo 
optimizar su ambiente abiotic por medio de feedback negativo. El
modelo no procura describir todos los mecanismos y feedbacces posibles
que pudieron influenciar las maneras de las cuales las plantas y el 
clima se convierten. En lugar, es un modelo heurístico, ese las
búsquedas para describir las maneras de las cuales este mecanismo 
pudo trabajar. El modelo original fue desarrollado por Watson y 
Lovelock(1983). El interfaz de JAVA viene con una conexión a 
una paginación de la actividad del estudiante en formato del pdf. 
La actividad se diseña para tomar cerca de 4 horas y se piensa 
para los cursos introductorios del geoscience con un acercamiento de 
sistemas de la tierra. Esta actividad es apropiada para el curso
con requisitos previos mínimos de las matemáticas o de la ciencia. 
Los estudiantes deben hacer que una cierta experiencia con 
sobresalgan, otro programa de representación gráfico gra'ficamente, 
o la fabricación de gráficos a mano. Puesto que el análisis 
gráfico es introductorio y bastante cualitativo, la actividad es 
apropiada como ejercicio de representación gráfico gra'ficamente que
comienza. Este sitio también incluye notas y las extremidades 
de enseñanza, los materiales didácticos necesarios, las ideas del 
gravamen y los recursos adicionales. Esta actividad es parte de 
la colección del punto de partida: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MACKAY
FN:ROBERT MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106001</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/daisyworld-interactive-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
