<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087599</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Brewster Kahle's modest mission: Archiving everything</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Brewster Kahles bescheidene Mission: 
Archivieren alles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mission modeste de Brewster Kahle : 
Archivage de tout</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Missão modesta de Brewster Kahle: Archiving
tudo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Missione modesta di Brewster Kahle: 
Archiviatura del tutto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέτρια αποστολή Kahle Brewster: 
Αρχειοθέτηση όλων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Misión modesta de Brewster Kahle: Archivar 
todo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Brewster Kahle is on a mission. He wants the whole planet to have access to human knowledge. All human knowledge. And he's striving to make that possible--one byte at a time.

Ten years ago, Kahle founded the nonprofit Internet Archive, with the goal of preserving the hitherto ephemeral pleasures of the Net for posterity. But, unsatisfied with limiting himself to the saving of Web sites, Kahle decided to broaden his scope and include existing collections of books, television programs, movies and music in the archive's massive digital repository.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Brewster Kahle ist auf einer Mission. Er 
wünscht den vollständigen Planeten Zugriff zum menschlichen Wissen 
haben. Alles menschliche Wissen. Vor und er bemüht zu 
bilden, daß möglich -- ein Byte an einem time.Ten Jahren, Kahle 
gründete das gemeinnützige Internet-Archiv, mit dem Ziel des 
Konservierens der bisher ephemeren Vergnügen des Netzes für 
Nachwelt. Aber, unsatisfied mit dem Begrenzen zur Einsparung der
Web-Sites, Kahle entschieden, um seinen Bereich zu erweitern und 
vorhandene Ansammlungen Bücher, Fernsehenprogramme, Filme und Musik 
im massiven digitalen Behälter des Archivs einzuschließen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Brewster Kahle est sur une mission. Il veut 
que la planète entière ait accès à la connaissance humaine. 
Toute la connaissance humaine. Et il tâche de faire que 
possible -- un octet à un time.Ten il y a des années, Kahle a fondé
les archives sans but lucratif d'Internet, avec le but de préserver 
les plaisirs jusqu'ici éphémères du filet pour la postérité. 
Mais, mécontent de se limiter à l'économie des sites de 
Web, Kahle décidé pour élargir sa portée et pour inclure 
les collections existantes de livres, d'émissions télévisées, de 
films et de musique dans le dépôt digital massif des archives.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Brewster Kahle está em uma missão. Quer o 
planeta inteiro ter o acesso ao conhecimento humano. Todo o 
conhecimento humano. E striving fazer que possível -- um byte 
em um time.Ten anos há, Kahle fundou o arquivo nonprofit do Internet,
com o objetivo de preservar os prazeres hitherto ephemeral da rede 
para a posteridade. Mas, unsatisfied com limitar-se ao saving de
locais do Web, Kahle decidido broaden seu espaço e incluir coleções
existentes dos livros, dos programas da televisão, dos filmes e da 
música no repositório digital maciço do arquivo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Brewster Kahle è su una missione. Desidera 
il pianeta intero avere accesso a conoscenza umana. Tutta la 
conoscenza umana. E sta sforzandosi fare che possibile -- un 
byte ad un time.Ten gli anni fa, Kahle ha fondato l'archivio senza 
scopo di lucro del Internet, con l'obiettivo di conservazione dei 
piaceri fino ad ora effimeri della rete per la posterità. Ma, 
unsatisfied con limitarsi al saving dei luoghi di Web, Kahle deciso 
per estendere la sua portata e per includere le collezioni attuali di 
libri, di programmi televisivi, di film e di musica nel 
deposito digitale voluminoso dell'archivio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Brewster Kahle είναι σε μια αποστολή. 
Θέλει ολόκληρο τον πλανήτη για να έχει πρόσβαση στην 
ανθρώπινη γνώση. Όλη η ανθρώπινη γνώση. Και του που 
προσπαθεί να κάνει ότι πιθανός -- μια οκτάδα τη φορά Δέκα
έτη πριν, Kahle ίδρυσε το μη κερδοσκοπικό αρχείο Διαδικτύου, 
με το στόχο την έως τώρα εφήμερη ευχαρίστηση του δικτύου για το 
μέλλον. Αλλά, ανικανοποίητος με τον περιορισμό στην 
αποταμίευση των ιστοχώρων, Kahle αποφάσισε να διευρύνει το 
πεδίο του και να περιλάβει τις υπάρχουσες συλλογές των βιβλίων, 
των τηλεοπτικών προγραμμάτων, των κινηματογράφων και της μουσικής 
στην ογκώδη ψηφιακή αποθήκη του αρχείου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Brewster Kahle está en una misión. Él 
quisiera que el planeta entero tuviera acceso al conocimiento humano. 
Todo el conocimiento humano. Y él se está esforzando 
hacer que posible -- un octeto en un time.Ten hace años, Kahle fundó
el archivo no lucrativo del Internet, con la meta de preservar los 
placeres hasta ahora efímeros de la red para la posteridad. 
Pero, insatisfecho con la limitación al ahorro de los sitios 
del Web, Kahle decidido para ensanchar su alcance y para 
incluir colecciones existentes de libros, de programas de la 
televisión, de películas y de música en el depósito digital masivo
del archivo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELINOR MILLS
FN:ELINOR MILLS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087599</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Copyright</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105755</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/brewster-kahles-modest-mission-archiving-everything</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
