<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106887</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106887</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086886</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Air is Sweet and Clear, the Heavens Serene, like the South Parts of France: William Penn Advertises for Colonists for Pennsylvania, 1683.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Luft ist süß und, die Himmel Serene, wie die
Südteile von Frankreich frei: William Penn macht für 
Kolonisten für Pennsylvania, 1683 bekannt.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'air est doux et clair, les cieux Sereins, 
comme les régions du sud de la France : William Penn 
annonce pour des colons pour la Pennsylvanie, 1683.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ar está doce e desobstruído, os heavens 
Serene, como as partes sul de France: William Penn anuncia para 
colonos para Pensilvânia, 1683.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'aria è dolce e chiara, il cielo Serene, come le
zone del sud della Francia: William Penn fa pubblicità a per i 
colonizzatori per la Pensilvania, 1683.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αέρας είναι γλυκός και σαφής, οι ουρανοί γαλήνιοι,
όπως τα νότια μέρη της Γαλλίας: Θ*Ωηλληαμ Penn 
Advertises για τους αποίκους για την Πενσυλβανία, 1683.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El aire está dulce y claro, los cielos Serene, 
como las partes del sur de Francia: Guillermo Penn anuncia para 
los colonos para Pennsylvania, 1683.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">William Penn, a well placed English gentlemen and a Quaker, turned an old debt into a charter for the proprietary colony called _Pennsylvania,? (all the land between New Jersey and Maryland) Penn took great pains in setting up his colony; twenty drafts survive of his First Frame of Government, the colony's 1682 constitution. Penn was determined to deal fairly and maintain friendly relations with the Lenni Lenape or Delaware Indians. He laid out in great detail the city of Philadelphia as well as organized other settlements and established the Free Society of Traders to control commerce with England. He sent back glowing accounts of the colony to his English friends and patrons. This  Letter to the Free Society of Traders,  published in 1683, has been recognized as the most effective of his promotional tracts. And it proved successful; by 1700 Pennsylvania's population reached 21,000.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">William Penn, eine Vertiefung plazierte englische Herren 
und ein Quäker, machte eine alte Schuld zu eine Charter für die 
eigene Kolonie, die _ Pennsylvania angerufen wurde? (das ganzes Land 
zwischen Neu-Jersey und Maryland) Penn nahm die großen Schmerz, wenn 
er seine Kolonie aufstellte; Zwanzig Entwürfe überleben von 
seinem ersten Feld der Regierung, die Beschaffenheit 1682 der Kolonie.
Penn wurde festgestellt, um ziemlich zu behandeln und 
freundliche Relationen mit dem Lenni Lenape oder den Delaware Indern 
beizubehalten. Er britt ausführlich großes, welches die Stadt 
von Philadelphia sowie andere Regelungen organisierte aus und stellte 
die freie Gesellschaft der Händler her, um Handel mit England zu 
steuern. Er schickte seinen englischen Freunden und Gönnern 
glühende Konten der Kolonie zurück. Dieses Zeichen zur freien 
Gesellschaft der Händler, veröffentlicht 1683, ist als das 
wirkungsvollste seiner fördernden Flächen erkannt worden. Und 
es prüfte erfolgreiches; durch Pennsylvania erreichte 
Bevölkerung 1700 21.000.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">William Penn, messieurs anglais placés par bien et un 
quaker, a transformé une vieille dette en charte pour la colonie de 
propriété industrielle appelée _ la Pennsylvanie ? (toute la terre 
entre New Jersey et le Maryland) Penn a pris de grandes douleurs en 
installant sa colonie ; vingt ébauches survivent de sa 
première vue de gouvernement, la constitution 1682 de la colonie. 
Penn a été déterminé pour s'occuper assez et pour mettre à 
jour des relations amicales avec le Lenni Lenape ou des Indiens du 
Delaware. Il a présenté dans le grand détail que la ville de 
Philadelphie aussi bien qu'a organisé d'autres règlements et a 
établi la société libre des commerçants pour contrôler le 
commerce avec l'Angleterre. Il a envoyé des comptes rougeoyants
en arrière de la colonie à ses amis et patrons anglais. Cette 
lettre à la société libre des commerçants, éditée en 1683, a 
été identifiée en tant que plus pertinent de ses régions 
promotionnelles. Et elle a été couronnée de succès ; 
d'ici la Pennsylvanie la population 1700 a atteint 21.000.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">William Penn, gentlemen ingleses colocados um poço e um 
quaker, girou um débito velho em uma carta patente para a colônia 
proprietária chamada _ Pensilvânia? (toda a terra entre Novo-Jersey 
e Maryland) Penn fêz exame de dores grandes em ajustar acima sua 
colônia; vinte esboços sobrevivem de seu primeiro quadro do 
governo, o constitution 1682 da colônia. Penn foi determinado 
negociar razoavelmente e manter relações amigáveis com o Lenni 
Lenape ou os indians de Delaware. Colocou para fora no detalhe 
que grande a cidade de Filadélfia as.well.as organizou outros 
estabelecimentos e estabeleceu a sociedade livre dos comerciantes para
controlar o comércio com Inglaterra. Emitiu clientes para trás
incandescendo da colônia a seus amigos e patrons ingleses. Esta
letra à sociedade livre dos comerciantes, publicada em 1683, foi 
reconhecida como o mais eficaz de seus intervalos promotional. E
provou bem sucedido; por Pensilvânia a população 1700 
alcançou 21.000.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">William Penn, signori inglesi disposti un pozzo e un 
quaker, ha trasformato in un vecchio debito una lettera per la colonia
riservata chiamata _ la Pensilvania? (tutta la terra fra la 
Nuovo-Jersey e Maryland) Penn ha preso i dolori grandi 
nell'installazione della sua colonia; venti brutte copie 
sopravvivono del suo primo telaio del governo, la costituzione 1682 
della colonia. Penn è stato determinato per trattare 
ragionevolmente ed effettuare i rapporti amichevoli con il Lenni 
Lenape o gli indiani del Delaware. Ha presentato in dettaglio 
che grande la città di Filadelfia così come ha organizzato altri 
stabilimenti ed ha stabilito la società libera dei commercianti per 
gestire il commercio con l'Inghilterra. Ha trasmesso i clienti 
indietro emettenti luce della colonia ai suoi amici e patroni inglesi.
Questa lettera alla società libera dei commercianti, pubblicata
in 1683, è stata riconosciuta come l'più efficace dei suoi tratti 
promozionali. Ed ha dimostrato riuscito; dalla Pensilvania
la popolazione 1700 ha raggiunto 21.000.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ωηλληαμ Penn, καλά τοποθετημένοι αγγλικοί κύριοι 
και ένας κουάκερος, μετέτρεψε ένα παλαιό χρέος σε χάρτη για την
ιδιόκτητη αποικία αποκαλούμενη _ Πενσυλβανία,; (όλο το έδαφος 
μεταξύ του Νιου Τζέρσευ! και της Μέρυλαντ) Penn κατέβαλε τις 
μεγάλες προσπάθειες στη σύσταση της αποικίας του  είκοσι 
σχέδια επιζούν του πρώτου πλαισίου κυβέρνησής του, το σύνταγμα 
1682 της αποικίας. Το Penn καθορίστηκε για να ασχοληθεί
αρκετά και να διατηρήσει τις φιλικές σχέσεις με το Lenni 
Lenape ή το Delaware Ινδοί. Σχεδίασε με μεγάλη 
λεπτομέρεια την πόλη της Φιλαδέλφειας καθώς επίσης και οργάνωσε 
άλλες τακτοποιήσεις και καθιέρωσε την ελεύθερη κοινωνία των 
εμπόρων για να ελέγξει το εμπόριο με την Αγγλία. Έστειλε 
τους απολογισμούς πυράκτωσης της αποικίας στους αγγλικούς φίλους 
και στους προστάτες του. Αυτή η επιστολή στην ελεύθερη 
κοινωνία των εμπόρων, που δημοσιεύεται το 1683, έχει 
αναγνωριστεί ως αποτελεσματικότερη των προωθητικών κομματιών του. 
Και αποδείχθηκε επιτυχές  από 1700 πληθυσμό της 
Πενσυλβανίας που επιτυγχάνεται 21.000.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guillermo Penn, caballeros ingleses colocados un receptor 
de papel y quaker, dio vuelta a una vieja deuda en una carta para la 
colonia propietaria llamada _ Pennsylvania? (toda la pista entre 
Nuevo-Jersey y Maryland) Penn tomó grandes dolores en setting-up a su
colonia; veinte bosquejos sobreviven de su primer bastidor del 
gobierno, la constitución 1682 de la colonia. Penn fue 
determinado para repartir bastante y para mantener relaciones cómodas
con el Lenni Lenape o los indios de Delaware. Él presentó en 
gran detalle que la ciudad de Philadelphia así como ordenó otros 
establecimientos y estableció a sociedad libre de comerciantes para 
controlar comercio con Inglaterra. Él envió las cuentas 
detrás que brillaban intensamente de la colonia a sus amigos y 
patrón ingleses. Esta carta a la sociedad libre de 
comerciantes, publicada en 1683, se ha reconocido como el más eficaz 
de sus zonas promocionales. Y probó acertado; antes de 
Pennsylvania la población 1700 alcanzó 21.000.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086886</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106887</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-air-is-sweet-and-clear-the-heavens-serene-like-the-south-parts-of-france-william-penn-advertises-for-colonists-for-pennsylvania-1683</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
