<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104114</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104114</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204025</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mitochondrial Control Region</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mitochondrische Steuerregion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Région Mitochondrique de Commande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Região Mitochondrial Do Controle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Regione Mitocondriale Di Controllo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μιτοχονδριακή περιοχή ελέγχου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Región Mitochondrial Del Control</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Every human cell has a "second" genome, found in the cell's energy-generating organelle, the mitochondrion. In fact, each mitochondrion has several copies of its own genome, and there are several hundred to several thousand mitochondria per cell. This means that the mitochondrial (mt) genome is highly amplified. While each cell contains only two copies of a given nuclear gene (one on each of the paired chromosomes), there are thousands of copies of a given mt gene per cell. Because of this high copy number, it is possible to obtain a mt DNA type from the equivalent of a single cell's worth of mt DNA. Thus, mt DNA is the genetic system of choice in cases where tissue samples are very old, very small, or badly degraded by heat and humidity. Under good circumstances - working from fresh cell samples - mt DNA is the easiest human DNA to amplify by PCR. This experiment examines a 440-nucleotide sequence from the noncoding region of mt genome. Hand cycling is a realistic alternative to automated thermal cyclers, and the high yield of amplified product can be visualized in an agarose gel with a variety of stains. Because each student is amplifying the same region, the gel electrophoresis results will also be the same for each. However, amplified student samples may be submitted to our Sequencing Service, which will generate student mt DNA sequences and post the results on our Sequence Server. Comparison of control region sequences reveals that most people have a unique pattern of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs). These sequence differences, in turn, are the basis for far-ranging investigations on human DNA diversity and the evolution of hominids. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jede menschliche Zelle hat ein "an zweiter Stelle"
Genom, fand im Energie-festlegenden Organell der Zelle, der 
Mitochondrion. Tatsächlich hat jeder Mitochondrion einige 
Exemplare seines eigenen Genoms, und es gibt mehreree hundert zu 
einiges tausend Mitochondrien pro Zelle. Dies heißt, daß das 
mitochondrische Genom (Millitorr) in hohem Grade verstärkt wird. 
Während jede Zelle nur zwei Exemplare eines gegebenen Kerngens 
(eins auf jedem der zusammengepaßten Chromosomen) enthält, gibt es 
Tausenden Exemplare eines gegebenen Millitorr Gens pro Zelle. 
Wegen dieser hohen Exemplarzahl ist es möglich, einen Millitorr
DNA Typen vom Äquivalent des Wertes einer Einzelzelle von Millitorr 
DNA zu erhalten. So ist Millitorr DNA das genetische System der 
Wahl, in den Fällen wo Gewebeproben sehr alt sehr klein sind, oder 
falsch vermindert durch Hitze und Feuchtigkeit. Unter guten 
Umständen - arbeitend von den frischen Zelle Proben - Millitorr DNA 
ist die einfachste Mensch DNA, zum durch PCR zu verstärken. 
Dieses Experiment überprüft eine Reihenfolge 440-nucleotide 
von der noncoding Region des Millitorr Genoms. Das Handradfahren
ist- eine realistische Alternative zu automatisierten thermischen 
cyclers, und das hohe Ergebnis des verstärkten Produktes kann in 
einem Agarosegel mit einer Vielzahl der Flecke sichtbar gemacht 
werden. Weil jeder Kursteilnehmer die gleiche Region verstärkt,
sind die Gelelektrophoreseresultate auch dieselben für jedes. 
Jedoch können verstärkte Kursteilnehmerproben bei unserem 
sequentiell ordnenden Service eingegeben werden, der 
Kursteilnehmermillitorr DNA Reihenfolgen festlegt und die Auswirkungen
auf unseren Reihenfolge Server bekanntgibt. Vergleich der 
Steuerregionreihenfolgen deckt auf, daß die meisten Leute ein 
eindeutiges Muster der einzelnen Nukleotidpolymorphien (SNPs) haben. 
Diese ordnen Unterschiede sind der Reihe nach die Grundlage für
weit-erstreckenuntersuchungen auf menschlicher DNA 
Verschiedenartigkeit und die Entwicklung von hominids sequentiell.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chaque cellule humaine a "en second lieu" un 
génome, a trouvé dans l'organelle énergie-produisante des cellules,
le mitochondrion. En fait, chaque mitochondrion a plusieurs 
copies de son propre génome, et il y a plusieurs centaines à 
plusieurs mille mitochondries par cellule. Ceci signifie que le 
génome (millitorr) mitochondrique est fortement amplifié. 
Tandis que chaque cellule contient seulement deux copies d'un 
gène nucléaire donné (un sur chacun des chromosomes appareillés), 
il y a des milliers de copies d'un gène donné de millitorr par 
cellule. En raison de ce nombre élevé de copie, il est 
possible d'obtenir un type d'ADN de millitorr de l'équivalent de la 
valeur d'une cellule de l'ADN de millitorr. Ainsi, l'ADN de 
millitorr est le système génétique du choix dans les cas où les 
échantillons de tissu sont très vieux, très petits, ou mal 
dégradé par la chaleur et humidité. Dans de bonnes 
circonstances - travaillant des échantillons frais de cellules - 
l'ADN de millitorr est l'ADN d'humain la plus facile à amplifier par 
PCR. Cette expérience examine un ordre 440-nucleotide de la 
région noncoding du génome de millitorr. Le cycle de main est 
une alternative réaliste aux cyclers thermiques automatisés, et le 
rendement élevé du produit amplifié peut être visualisé dans un 
gel d'agarose avec une variété de taches. Puisque chaque 
étudiant amplifie la même région, les résultats d'électrophorèse
de gel seront également les mêmes pour chacun. Cependant, des 
échantillons amplifiés d'étudiant peuvent être soumis à notre 
service d'ordonnancement, qui produira des ordres d'ADN de millitorr 
d'étudiant et signalera les résultats sur notre serveur d'ordre. 
La comparaison des ordres de région de commande indique que la 
plupart des personnes ont une seule configuration des polymorphismes 
simples de nucléotide (SNPs). Ceux-ci ordonnancent des 
différences, à leur tour, sont la base pour des investigations 
loin-s'étendantes sur la diversité humaine d'ADN et l'évolution des
hominids.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cada pilha humana tem "em segundo" um genome, 
encontrou no organelle energia-gerando da pilha, o mitochondrion. 
No fato, cada mitochondrion tem diversas cópias de seu próprio
genome, e há diversos cem a diverso mil mitochondria por a pilha. 
Isto significa que o genome (mt) mitochondrial está amplificado
altamente. Quando cada pilha contiver somente duas cópias de um
gene nuclear dado (um em cada um dos chromosomes emparelhados), há 
uns milhares das cópias de um gene dado do mt por a pilha. Por 
causa deste número elevado da cópia, é possível obter um tipo do 
DNA do mt do equivalente do valor de uma única pilha do DNA do mt. 
Assim, o DNA do mt é o sistema genetic da escolha nos casos 
onde as amostras do tecido são muito velhas, muito pequenas, ou 
degradado mal pelo calor e pela umidade. Sob circunstâncias 
boas - trabalhando das amostras frescas da pilha - o DNA do mt é o 
DNA o mais fácil do ser humano a amplificar por PCR. Esta 
experiência examina uma seqüência 440-nucleotide da região 
noncoding do genome do mt. Dar um ciclo da mão é uma 
alternativa realística aos cyclers térmicos automatizados, e o 
rendimento elevado do produto amplificado pode ser visualizado em um 
gel do agarose com uma variedade das manchas. Porque cada 
estudante está amplificando a mesma região, os resultados do 
electrophoresis do gel serão também os mesmos para cada um. 
Entretanto, as amostras amplificadas do estudante podem ser 
submetidas a nosso serviço arranjando em seqüência, que gerará 
seqüências do DNA do mt do estudante e afixará os resultados em 
nosso server da seqüência. A comparação de seqüências da 
região do controle revela que a maioria de povos têm um teste 
padrão original de únicos polymorphisms do nucleotide (SNPs). 
Estes arranjam em seqüência diferenças, por sua vez, são a 
base para investigações distante-variando na diversidade humana do 
DNA e a evolução dos hominids.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ogni cellula umana ha "in secondo luogo" un 
genome, ha trovato nell'organello digenerazione delle cellule, il 
mitochondrion. Infatti, ogni mitochondrion ha parecchie copie 
del relativo proprio genome e ci è diverse centinaia a parecchio 
mille mitocondri per la cellula. Ciò significa che il genome 
mitocondriale (mt) altamente è amplificato. Mentre ogni cellula
contiene soltanto due copie di dato gene nucleare (uno su ciascuno dei
cromosomi accoppiati), ci sono migliaia delle copie di dato gene di mt
per la cellula. A causa di questo alto numero della copia, è 
possibile ottenere un tipo del DNA di mt dall'equivalente di valore 
della cellula del DNA di mt. Quindi, il DNA di mt è il sistema 
genetico della scelta nei casi in cui i campioni del tessuto sono 
molto vecchi, molto piccoli, o degradato male da calore e da umidità.
In buone circostanze - funzionando dai campioni freschi delle 
cellule - il DNA di mt è il DNA dell'essere umano più facile da 
amplificare da PCR. Questo esperimento esamina una sequenza 
440-nucleotide dalla regione noncoding del genome di mt. Ciclare
della mano è un'alternativa realistica ai cyclers termici 
automatizzati e l'alto rendimento del prodotto amplificato può essere
visualizzato in un gel dell'agarosi con una varietà di macchie. 
Poiché ogni allievo sta amplificando la stessa regione, i 
risultati di elettroforesi del gel egualmente saranno gli stessi per 
ciascuno. Tuttavia, i campioni amplificati dell'allievo possono 
essere presentati al nostro servizio ordinante, che genererà le 
sequenze del DNA di mt dell'allievo ed invierà i risultati sul nostro
server di sequenza. Il confronto delle sequenze di regione di 
controllo rivela che la maggior parte della gente ha un modello unico 
di singoli polimorfismi del nucleotide (SNPs). Questi ordinano 
le differenze in serie, a loro volta, sono la base per le indagini 
digamma sulla diversità umana del DNA e lo sviluppo dei hominids.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάθε ανθρώπινο κύτταρο έχει ένα "δεύτερο" 
γονιδίωμα, που βρίσκονται παράγον ενέργεια organelle του 
κυττάρου, το mitochondrion. Στην πραγματικότητα, κάθε 
mitochondrion έχει διάφορα αντίγραφα του γονιδιώματός του, και
υπάρχουν αρκετές σε αρκετές χιλιάες μιτοχόνδρια ανά κύτταρο. 
Αυτό σημαίνει ότι το μιτοχονδριακό γονιδίωμα (mt) 
ενισχύεται ιδιαίτερα. Ενώ κάθε κύτταρο περιέχει μόνο δύο
αντίγραφα ενός δεδομένου πυρηνικού γονιδίου (ένα σε κάθε ένα 
από τα ταξινομημένα κατά ζεύγος χρωμοσώματα), υπάρχουν χιλιάδες
αντίγραφα ενός δεδομένου γονιδίου ΑΜ ανά κύτταρο. Λόγω 
αυτού του υψηλού αριθμού αντιγράφων, είναι δυνατό να ληφθεί 
ένας τύπος DNA ΑΜ από το αντίτιμο της αξίας ενός μονού 
κυττάρου του DNA ΑΜ. Κατά συνέπεια, το DNA ΑΜ είναι το
γενετικό σύστημα της επιλογής σε περιπτώσεις όπου τα δείγματα 
ιστού είναι πολύ παλαιά, πολύ μικρά, ή άσχημα υποβιβασμένος 
από τη θερμότητα και την υγρασία. Κάτω από το αγαθό οι 
περιστάσεις - που λειτουργούν από τα φρέσκα δείγματα κυττάρων - 
DNA ΑΜ είναι το ευκολότερο ανθρώπινο DNA για να ενισχύσουν 
από pcr. Αυτό το πείραμα εξετάζει μια ακολουθία 
440-νουκλεοτίδας από τη noncoding περιοχή του γονιδιώματος ΑΜ. 
Η ανακύκλωση χεριών είναι μια ρεαλιστική εναλλακτική λύση 
στα αυτοματοποιημένα θερμικά cyclers, και η υψηλή παραγωγή του 
ενισχυμένου προϊόντος μπορεί να απεικονιστεί σε ένα πήκτωμα 
αγαρόζης με ποικίλους λεκέδες. Επειδή κάθε σπουδαστής 
ενισχύει την ίδια περιοχή, τα αποτελέσματα ηλεκτροφόρησης 
πηκτωμάτων θα είναι επίσης τα ίδια για κάθε ένα. 
Εντούτοις, τα ενισχυμένα δείγματα σπουδαστών μπορούν να 
υποβληθούν στην τοποθετώντας διαδοχικά υπηρεσία μας, η οποία θα 
παραγάγει τις ακολουθίες DNA ΑΜ σπουδαστών και θα ταχυδρομήσει 
τα αποτελέσματα για τον κεντρικό υπολογιστή ακολουθίας μας. 
Η σύγκριση των ακολουθιών περιοχών ελέγχου αποκαλύπτει ότι
οι περισσότεροι άνθρωποι έχουν ένα μοναδικό πρότυπο των ενιαίων
πολυμορφισμών νουκλεοτίδας (SNPs). Αυτές οι διαφορές 
ακολουθίας, στη συνέχεια, είναι η βάση για τις far-ranging 
έρευνες στην ανθρώπινη ποικιλομορφία DNA και η εξέλιξη των 
ανθρωποειδών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cada célula humana tiene "en segundo lugar" un 
genoma, encontró en el organelle de energi'a-generacio'n de la 
célula, el mitochondrion. En hecho, cada mitochondrion tiene 
varias copias de su propio genoma, y hay varios cientos a vario 
mil mitochondria por la célula. Esto significa que el 
genoma mitochondrial (mt) está amplificado altamente. 
Mientras que cada célula contiene solamente dos copias de un 
gene nuclear dado (uno en cada uno de los cromosomas emparejados), hay
millares de copias de un gene dado del mt por la célula. Debido
a este alto número de la copia, es posible obtener un tipo de la DNA 
del mt del equivalente del valor de una célula de la DNA del mt. 
Así, la DNA del mt es el sistema genético de la opción en 
casos donde están muy viejas, muy pequeñas las muestras del tejido 
fino, o degradado gravemente por el calor y la humedad. Bajo 
buenas circunstancias - trabajando de muestras frescas de la célula -
la DNA del mt es la DNA más fácil del ser humano a amplificar por 
PCR. Este experimento examina una secuencia 440-nucleotide de la
región noncoding del genoma del mt. El completar un ciclo 
de la mano es un alternativa realista a los cyclers termales 
automatizados, y la alta producción del producto amplificado se puede
visualizar en un gel del agarose con una variedad de manchas. 
Porque cada estudiante está amplificando la misma región, los 
resultados del electrophoresis del gel también serán iguales para 
cada uno. Sin embargo, las muestras amplificadas del estudiante 
se pueden someter a nuestro servicio que ordena, que generará 
secuencias de la DNA del mt del estudiante y fijará los resultados en
nuestro servidor de la secuencia. La comparación de las 
secuencias de la región del control revela que la mayoría de la 
gente tiene un modelo único de los solos polimorfismos del nucleotide
(SNPs). Éstos ordenan diferencias, alternadamente, son la base 
para las investigaciones lejos-que se extienden en diversidad humana 
de la DNA y la evolución de hominids.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DOLAN DNA LEARNING CENTER, COLD SPRING HARBOR LABORATORY
FN:DOLAN DNA LEARNING CENTER, COLD SPRING HARBOR LABORATORY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204025</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104114</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mitochondrial-control-region</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
