<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103106</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103106</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087095</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"There's Been No Real Creative Response:" Ted Houghton on Homelessness in New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Es Hat Gegeben Keine Reale Kreative Antwort:" 
Ted Houghton auf Heimatlosigkeit in New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Il N'y a eu Aucune Vraie Réponse Créatrice :" 
Ted Houghton sur le Phénomène des sans-abri à New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Não houve Nenhuma Resposta Creativa Real:" 
Ted Houghton em Homelessness em New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non Ci È stato Risposta Creativa Reale:" 
Ted Houghton su Homelessness a New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εκεί όντας καμία πραγματική δημιουργική απάντηση:" 
TED Houghton στην έλλειψη στέγης στην πόλη της Νέας 
Υόρκης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No ha habido Respuesta Creativa Verdadera:" 
Ted Houghton en Falta de vivienda en New York City</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As the federal government drastically reduced funding for low-income housing during the 1980's and 1990's, homelessness emerged as a new and serious issue in many urban areas. Between one and three million Americans became homeless during the 1980's as the minimum wage fell in value and the creation of affordable housing came to a virtual standstill. By the end of the decade one-third of homeless Americans were children. As the homeless population grew, so did the number of organizations created to serve and organize the men, women, and families living in the streets or in over-crowded shelters. Ted Houghton was an organizer for Coalition for the Homeless, an advocacy group founded in 1981 and dedicated to the principle that decent shelter, sufficient food, affordable housing, and the chance to work for a living wage are fundamental rights in a civilized society.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während die Bundesregierung sich drastisch 
verringerte, für mit niedrigem Einkommengehäuse während der 
achtziger Jahre und der neunziger Jahre zu finanzieren, tauchte 
Heimatlosigkeit als neue und ernste Ausgabe in vielen städtischen 
Bereichen auf. Zwischen wurden einem und drei Million Amerikaner
während der achtziger Jahre heimatlos, während der minimale Lohn in 
Wert fiel und die Kreation des erschwinglichen Gehäuses zu einem 
virtuellen Stillstand kam. Ende der Dekade war Drittel von 
heimatlosen Amerikanern Kinder. Wie die heimatlose Bevölkerung 
wuchs, also die Zahl den Organisationen tat, die erstellt wurden, um 
die Männer, die Frauen und die Familien zu dienen und zu organisieren
leben in den Straßen oder in überfüllten Schutz. Ted Houghton
war ein Organisator für Koalition für den Homeless, eine 
Befürwortung Gruppe, die 1981 gegründet wurde und der Grundregel 
eingesetzt war, die annehmbarer Schutz, genügende Nahrung, 
erschwingliches Gehäuse und die Wahrscheinlichkeit, für einen 
lebenden Lohn zu arbeiten grundlegende Rechte in einer zivilisierten 
Gesellschaft sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que le gouvernement fédéral réduisait 
rigoureusement placer pour le logement de faible revenu pendant les 
années 80 et les années 90, le phénomène des sans-abri a émergé comme nouvelle 
et sérieuse issue dans beaucoup de zones urbaines. Entre un et 
trois millions d'Américains sont devenus sans foyer pendant les 
années 80 pendant que le salaire minimum diminuait de valeur et la 
création du logement accessible venait à un arrêt virtuel. 
Vers la fin de la décennie un tiers d'Américains sans foyer 
étaient des enfants. Comme la population sans foyer s'est 
développée, ainsi a fait le nombre d'organismes créés pour servir 
et organiser les hommes, les femmes, et les familles vivant dans les 
rues ou dans les abris surchargés. Ted Houghton était un 
organisateur pour la coalition pour le sans-abri, un groupe de 
recommandation fondé en 1981 et consacré au principe que l'abri 
décent, la suffisamment de nourriture, le logement accessible, et la 
chance de travailler pour un salaire vivant sont des justex 
fondamentaux dans une société civilisée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto o governo federal se reduziu dràstica 
financiar para a carcaça low-income durante os 1980's e os 1990's, o 
homelessness emergiu como uma edição nova e séria em muitas áreas 
urbanas. Entre um e três milhão americanos tornaram-se 
desabrigados durante os 1980's enquanto o salário mínimo caiu no 
valor e a criação da carcaça affordable veio a uma paralisação 
virtual. Para o fim da década um terço de americanos 
desabrigados eram crianças. Como a população desabrigada 
cresceu, assim que fêz o número das organizações criadas para 
servir e organizar aos homens, às mulheres, e às famílias que vivem
nas ruas ou em abrigos over-crowded. Ted Houghton era um 
organizer para o coalition para o desabrigado, um grupo do advocacy 
fundado em 1981 e dedicado ao princípio que o abrigo decent, o 
alimento suficiente, a carcaça affordable, e a possibilidade 
trabalhar para um salário vivo são direitas fundamentais em uma 
sociedade civilized.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre il governo federale drasticamente ha ridotto
costituire un fondo per per l'alloggiamento low-income durante gli 
anni 80 e gli anni 90, il homelessness è emerso come nuova ed 
edizione seria in molte aree urbane. Fra un e tre milione 
Americani sono diventato senza casa durante gli anni 80 mentre lo 
stipendio minimo ha diminuito di valore e la creazione di 
alloggiamento acquistabile è venuto ad una fermata virtuale. 
Per la fine della decade un terzo degli Americani senza casa era
bambini. Come la popolazione senza casa si è sviluppata, in 
modo da ha fatto il numero di organizzazioni create per servire ed 
organizzare gli uomini, le donne e le famiglie che vivono nelle vie o 
nei ripari sovraccaricati. Ted Houghton era un organizzatore per
coalizione per il nomade, un gruppo di avvocatura fondato in 1981 e 
dedicato al principio che il riparo decent, l'alimento sufficiente, 
l'alloggiamento acquistabile e la probabilità funzionare per uno 
stipendio vivente sono diritti fondamentali in una società 
civilizzata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση μείωσε 
δραστικά τη χρηματοδότηση για τη χαμηλού εισοδήματος κατοικία 
κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '80 και της δεκαετίας του '90, 
η έλλειψη στέγης προέκυψε ως νέο και σοβαρό ζήτημα σε πολλές 
αστικές περιοχές. Μεταξύ ένα και τρία εκατομμύριο 
Αμερικανών έγινε άστεγος κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '80 
καθώς ο βασικός μισθός ενέπεσε στην αξία και η δημιουργία της 
προσιτής κατοικίας ήρθε σε ένα εικονικό σταμάτημα. Μέχρι 
το τέλος της δεκαετίας το ένα τρίτο άστεγων Αμερικανών ήταν 
παιδιά. Δεδομένου ότι ο άστεγος πληθυσμός αυξήθηκε, έτσι 
έκανε τον αριθμό οργανώσεων που δημιουργήθηκαν για να 
εξυπηρετήσουν και να οργανώσουν τους άνδρες, τις γυναίκες, και τις
οικογένειες που ζουν στις οδούς ή στα επιβαρυνμένα καταφύγια. 
Το TED Houghton ήταν διοργανωτής για το συνασπισμό για 
τους αστέγους, μια ομάδα υπεράσπισης που ιδρύθηκε το 1981 και 
που αφιερώθηκε στην αρχή ότι η κόσμιη στέγη, τα ικανοποιητικά 
τρόφιμα, η προσιτή κατοικία, και η πιθανότητα να εργαστούν για 
μια αμοιβή διαβίωσης είναι θεμελιώδη δικαιώματα σε μια 
εκπολιτισμένη κοινωνία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que el gobierno federal redujo drástico 
el financiar para la cubierta de ingreso bajo durante los años 80 y 
los años 90, la falta de vivienda emergió como nueva y seria edición en 
muchas áreas urbanas. Entre un y tres millones de americanos 
hicieron sin hogar durante los años 80 mientras que el salario 
mínimo cayó en valor y la creación de la cubierta comprable vino a 
una parada virtual. Para el final de la década una mitad de 
americanos sin hogar era niños. Como la población sin hogar 
creció, así que hizo el número de las organizaciones creadas para 
servir y para ordenar a los hombres, a las mujeres, y a las familias 
que vivían en las calles o en abrigos atestados. Ted Houghton 
era un organizador para la coalición para el nómada, grupo de la 
defensa fundado en 1981 y dedicado al principio que el abrigo decente,
el suficiente alimento, la cubierta comprable, y la ocasión de 
trabajar para un salario vivo correcto fundamentales en una sociedad 
civilizada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087095</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103106</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/theres-been-no-real-creative-response-ted-houghton-on-homelessness-in-new-york-city</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
