<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086771</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Quittin' Time: A Visit to Chicago's Saloons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Quittin ' Zeit: Ein Besuch zu den Saloons 
Chicagos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Temps de Quittin ': Une visite aux salles de 
Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tempo De Quittin ': Uma visita aos saloons de
Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tempo Di Quittin ': Una chiamata ai saloni 
del Chicago</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρόνος Quittin ": Μια επίσκεψη στις αίθουσες 
του Σικάγου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tiempo De Quittin ': Una visita a los salones
de Chicago</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the mid-19th century, moral reformers viewed the saloon with unmitigated outrage. By the turn of the 20th century, though, anti-liquor groups such as the "Committee of Fifty" attempted to take a more dispassionate look at the saloon and its appeal to workingmen. Their goal was to displace the saloon by sponsoring non-liquor centered "substitutes." These efforts largely failed, but reformers' inquiries produced highly informative descriptions of saloon life at the end of the 19th century. The following article by sociologist Royal Melendy on "The Saloon in Chicago," published in 1900, conveyed a sense of how the saloon met a range of urban workers' social, economic, and cultural needs. Melendy's use of the term "workingman" emphasized the male character of the saloon. This should not be taken to mean that working-class women did not drink, but that drinking frequently took place at home. Some women, however, especially German and English immigrants, did drink in saloons and beer gardens.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im mid-19th Jahrhundert sahen moralische 
Reformer den Saloon mit unmitigated Verbrechen an. Durch 
die Jahrhundertwende 20., obwohl, Anti-Alkohol Gruppen wie der 
"Ausschuß von fünfzig" versuchten, einen sachlicheren Blick am 
Saloon und seinen Anklang zu nehmen zu den Workingmen. Ihr Ziel 
war, den Saloon zu verlegen, indem es förderte Nichtalkohol 
zentrierten "Ersatz." Diese Bemühungen fielen groß aus, aber 
Reformer' Anfragen produzierten in hohem Grade informative 
Beschreibungen des Saloonlebens am Ende des 19. Jahrhunderts. 
Der folgende Artikel durch Soziologen königliches Melendy 
auf "dem Saloon in Chicago," veröffentlichte 1900, übermittelt einer
Richtung von, wie der Saloon eine Strecke der städtischen 
ökonomischer und kultureller Notwendigkeiten der Sozial Arbeiter, 
traf. Gebrauch Melendys von der Bezeichnung "Workingman" hob das
männliche Zeichen des Saloon hervor. Dieses sollte nicht 
genommen werden, um zu bedeuten, daß Arbeiterklassefrauen nicht 
tranken, aber daß das Trinken häufig zu Hause stattfand. 
Einige Frauen jedoch besonders deutsch und englische 
Immigranten, tranken in den Saloons und in den Biergärten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En siècle de mid-19th, les réformateurs moraux ont 
visualisé la salle avec l'outrage non mitigé. Au tournant du 
20ème siècle, bien que, les groupes d'anti-boisson alcoolisée tels 
que le "Comité de cinquante" aient essayé de prendre un regard plus 
impartial à la salle et son appel aux ouvriers. Leur but était
de déplacer la salle en commanditant les "produits de remplacement 
centrés parboisson alcoolisée." Ces efforts ont en grande 
partie échoué, mais enquêtes de réformateurs les 'ont produit des 
descriptions fortement instructives de la vie de salle à la fin du 
19ème siècle. L'article suivant par le sociologue Melendy 
royal sur "la salle Chicago," a édité en 1900, transporté un sens 
de la façon dont la salle a rencontré un intervalle des besoins des 
ouvriers sociaux, économiques, et culturels urbains. 
L'utilisation de Melendy du terme "ouvrier" a souligné le 
caractère mâle de la salle. Ceci ne devrait pas être pris 
pour signifier que les femmes de classe ouvrière n'ont pas bu, mais 
que le boire fréquemment a eu lieu à la maison. Quelques 
femmes, cependant, particulièrement allemandes et immigrés anglais, 
ont bu dans les salles et les jardins de bière.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No século de mid-19th, os reformers morais viram o
saloon com unmitigated o ultraje. Pela volta do 20o século, 
embora, os grupos do anti-licor tais como o "comitê de cinqüênta" 
tentaram fazer exame de um olhar mais dispassionate no saloon e de sua
apelação aos workingmen. Seu objetivo era deslocar o saloon 
patrocinando "substitutos centrados non-licor." Estes esforços 
falharam pela maior parte, mas os inquéritos dos reformers' 
produziram descrições altamente informative da vida do saloon no fim
do 1ø século. O seguinte artigo pelo sociologist Melendy real 
"no saloon em Chicago," publicou em 1900, feito saber um sentido de 
como o saloon se encontrou com uma escala de necessidades urbanas dos 
trabalhadores sociais, as econômicas, e as cultural. O uso de 
Melendy do termo "workingman" emfatizou o caráter masculino do 
saloon. Isto não deve ser feito exame para significar que as 
mulheres do working-class não beberam, mas que beber ocorreu 
freqüentemente na HOME. Algumas mulheres, entretanto, especial 
alemãs e os immigrants ingleses, beberam nos saloons e nos jardins da
cerveja.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel secolo di mid-19th, i reformers morali hanno 
osservato il salone con unmitigated l'oltraggio. Dalla girata 
del ventesimo secolo, benchè, i gruppi del anti-liquore quale "il 
comitato di cinquanta" tentino di prendere uno sguardo più 
spassionato al salone ed il relativo appello ai workingmen. Il 
loro obiettivo era di spostare il salone patrocinando "i sostituti 
concentrati non-liquore." Questi sforzi in gran parte sono 
venuto a mancare, ma le inchieste dei reformers hanno prodotto le 
descrizioni altamente informative di vita del salone alla conclusione 
del diciannovesimo secolo. Il seguente articolo dal sociologist 
Melendy reale "sul salone in Chicago," ha pubblicato in 1900, 
trasportato un senso di come il salone ha andare incontro ad una gamma
di bisogni economici e e culturali urbani degli operai sociali. 
L'uso del Melendy del termine "workingman" ha dato risalto al 
carattere maschio del salone. Ciò non dovrebbe essere presa per
significare che le donne della classe operaia non hanno bevuto, ma che
bere ha avvenuto frequentemente nel paese. Alcune donne, 
tuttavia, particolarmente tedesche e gli immigranti inglesi, hanno 
bevuto in saloni e nei giardini della birra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο μέσος-19$ο αιώνα, οι ηθικοί μεταρρυθμιστές 
εμφάνισαν την αίθουσα με την αμετρίαστη προσβολή. Από τη 
στροφή του 20ού αιώνα, εν τούτοις, οι ομάδες αντι-ποτού όπως η 
"Επιτροπή πενήντα" που προσπαθούνται για να πάρουν έναν πιό 
αμερόληπτο εξετάζουν την αίθουσα και η έκκλησή της. Ο 
στόχος τους ήταν να μετατοπίσουν την αίθουσα με την υποστήριξη 
των μη κεντροθετημένων "υποκατάστατων." Αυτές οι προσπάθειες
απέτυχαν κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος, αλλά οι έρευνες των 
μεταρρυθμιστών παρήγαγαν τις ιδιαίτερα πληροφοριακές περιγραφές 
της ζωής αιθουσών στο τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα. Το ακόλουθο 
άρθρο από τον κοινωνιολόγο βασιλικό Melendy "στην αίθουσα στο 
Σικάγο," δημοσιευμένος το 1900, μεταβίβασε μια αίσθηση για το 
πώς η αίθουσα ικανοποίησε ένα φάσμα κοινωνικών, οικονομικών, 
και πολιτιστικών αναγκών των αστικών εργαζομένων. Η χρήση 
του Melendy του όρου "workingman" υπογράμμισε τον αρσενικό 
χαρακτήρα της αίθουσας. Αυτό δεν πρέπει να ληφθεί για να 
σημάνει ότι οι γυναίκες εργατικών τάξεων δεν ήπιαν, αλλά ότι η
κατανάλωση πραγματοποιήθηκε συχνά στο σπίτι. Μερικές 
γυναίκες, εντούτοις, ειδικά γερμανικοί και αγγλικοί μετανάστες, 
ήπιαν στις αίθουσες και τους κήπους μπύρας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el siglo de mid-19th, los reformadores morales 
vieron el salón con unmitigated ultraje. Por la vuelta del 
vigésimo siglo, aunque, los grupos del contra-licor tales como el 
"comité de cincuenta" procuraron tomar una mirada más desapasionada 
en el salón y su súplica a los workingmen. Su meta era 
desplazar el salón patrocinando "substitutos centrados no-licor." 
Estos esfuerzos fallaron en gran parte, pero preguntas de los 
reformadores las ' produjeron descripciones altamente informativas de 
la vida del salón en el final del diecinueveavo siglo. El 
artículo siguiente del sociólogo Melendy real en "el salón en 
Chicago," publicó en 1900, transportado un sentido de cómo el salón
resolvió un rango de las necesidades urbanas de los trabajadores 
sociales, económicas, y culturales. El uso de Melendy del 
término "workingman" acentuó el carácter masculino del salón. 
Esto no se debe tomar para significar que las mujeres de la 
clase obrera no bebieron, pero que ocurrió el beber con frecuencia en
el país. Algunas mujeres, sin embargo, especialmente alemanas y
los inmigrantes ingleses, bebieron en salones y jardines de la 
cerveza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086771</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104890</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/quittin-time-a-visit-to-chicagos-saloons</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
