<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105674</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105674</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087040</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Rights of All Must Be Secured or the Rights of None Will Be Secure": Arguments for Federal Civil Rights Legislation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Rechte von ganz müssen gesichert werden, 
oder die Rechte von keinen sind" sicher: Argumente für 
Bundeszivilrecht-Gesetzgebung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les droites de tout doivent être fixées ou les 
droites d'aucun seront bloquées" : Arguments pour la 
législation fédérale de droits civiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"as direitas de toda devem ser fixadas ou as 
direitas de nenhuns serão seguras": Argumentos para a 
legislação federal das direitas civis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i diritti di interamente devono essere assicurati
o i diritti di nessun saranno sicuri": Argomenti per 
legislazione federale di diritti civili</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τα δικαιώματα όλα πρέπει να εξασφαλιστούν ή τα 
δικαιώματα κανένα θα είναι ασφαλή": Ορίσματα για την 
ομοσπονδιακή νομοθεσία αστικών δικαιωμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"las derechas de todo deben ser aseguradas o las 
derechas de ningunos serán seguras": Argumentos para la 
legislación federal de las derechas civiles</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In a message to Congress in February 1948, President Harry S. Truman asked for Federal civil rights legislation, including antilynching laws. The last such bill to be signed into law, the 1875 Civil Rights Act, had been declared unconstitutional by the Supreme Court in 1883, during a period in which the number of lynchings of African Americans in the South increased sharply. The history of failed attempts to pass Federal antilyching legislation goes back to 1894, when a House bill to create a committee to investigate lynchings failed. In 1922, the House passed a bill by a two-to-one margin to make lynching a Federal crime, but despite President Warren G. Harding's support, Southern senators filibustered and defeated it. In 1933, President Franklin D. Roosevelt failed to support an antilynching bill proposed by the NAACP, fearing that key Southern lawmakers would retaliate and interfere with his New Deal agenda. In the following testimony to a House subcommittee in 1949, representatives of a Japanese American antidiscrimination league and the NAACP argued the need for Federal civil rights action. None of the bills under consideration by the subcommittee passed. President Dwight D. Eisenhower signed into law the first civil rights legislation since Reconstruction in 1957, but only the 1964 Civil Rights Act began to implement Federal laws and enforcement powers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In einer Meldung zum Kongreß im Februar 1948, bat
Präsident Harry S. Truman um Bundeszivilrechtgesetzgebung, 
einschließlich antilynching Gesetze. Das Letzte solche in 
Gesetz unterzeichnet zu werden Rechnung, die 1875 Zivilrechte 
fungieren, war gewesen erklärtes verfassungswidriges durch das Höchste 
Gericht 1883, während einer Periode, deren die Zahl lynchings der 
afrikanischen Amerikaner im Süden sich scharf erhöhte. Die 
Geschichte der verlassenen Versuche, antilyching Bundesgesetzgebung zu
führen geht zurück zu 1894, als eine Hausrechnung, zum eines 
Ausschusses zu erstellen, um lynchings nachzuforschen ausfiel. 
1922 verabschiedete das Haus einen Gesetz durch a zwei--ein zum 
Seitenrand, um das Lynchen eines Bundesverbrechens zu bilden, aber 
trotz Präsident Warren G. Hardings des Supports, die südlichen 
obstruierten Senatoren und besiegte ihn. 1933 konnte Präsident 
Franklin D. Roosevelt eine antilynching Rechnung unterstützen, die 
durch das NAACP vorgeschlagen wurde nicht und fürchtete, daß 
südliche Gesetzgeber der Taste seine Tagesordnung des neuen Abkommens
sich revanchieren und behinderen würden. Im folgenden Zeugnis 
zu einer Hausunterausschuß 1949, argumentierten Repräsentanten einer
japanischen amerikanischen antidiscrimination Liga und das NAACP die 
Notwendigkeit an der Bundesguten höflichtat. Keine der 
Rechnungen in Erwägung durch die Unterausschuß überschritten. 
Präsident Dwight D. Eisenhower unterzeichnete in Gesetz die 
erste Zivilrechtgesetzgebung seit Rekonstruktion 1957, aber nur die 
1964 Zivilrecht-Tat fing an, Bundesgesetze und Durchführungenergien 
einzuführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans un message au congrès en février 1948, le 
Président Harry S. Truman a demandé la législation fédérale de 
droits civiques, y compris des lois antilynching. Le bout une 
telle facture à signer dans la loi, les 1875 droits civiques 
agissent, avait été inconstitutionnel avoué par la cour suprême en
1883, pendant une période l'où le nombre de lynchings des 
Américains africains dans les Sud a augmenté brusquement. 
L'histoire des tentatives échouées de passer la législation 
antilyching fédérale va de nouveau à 1894, quand une facture de 
Chambre pour créer un comité pour étudier des lynchings a échoué.
En 1922, la Chambre a passé une facture par a deux--un à la 
marge pour faire lyncher un crime fédéral, mais en dépit de support
du Président Warren G. Harding's, sénateurs méridionaux flibustés 
et l'a défaite. En 1933, le Président Franklin D. Roosevelt 
n'a pas supporté une facture antilynching proposée par le NAACP, 
craignant que les législateurs méridionaux de clé exercent des 
représailles et gêneraient son ordre du jour de nouvelle affaire. 
Dans le témoignage suivant à un sous-comité de Chambre en 
1949, les représentants d'une ligue américaine japonaise 
d'antidiscrimination et le NAACP ont discuté le besoin d'action 
fédérale de droits civiques. Aucune des factures à l'étude 
par le sous-comité n'a passé. Le Président Dwight D. 
Eisenhower a signé dans la loi la première législation de droits 
civiques depuis la reconstruction en 1957, mais seulement la Loi de 
1964 droits civiques a commencé à mettre en application des lois et 
des puissances fédérales d'application.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em uma mensagem ao congress em fevereiro 1948, o 
presidente Harry S. Truman pediu legislação federal das direitas 
civis, including leis antilynching. O último tal conta a ser 
assinada na lei, as 1875 direitas civis age, tinha sido 
unconstitutional declarado pela corte suprema em 1883, durante um 
período em que o número dos lynchings de americanos africanos no sul
aumentou agudamente. O history de tentativas falhadas de passar 
a legislação antilyching federal vai para trás a 1894, quando uma 
conta da casa para criar um comitê para investigar lynchings falhou. 
Em 1922, a casa passou uma conta por a dois--um à margem para 
fazer lynching um crime federal, mas apesar da sustentação do 
presidente Warren G. Harding, senators do sul filibustered e 
derrotou-a. Em 1933, o presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt não 
suportou uma conta antilynching proposta pelo NAACP, temendo que os 
lawmakers do sul da chave retaliate e interfeririam com sua agenda do 
negócio novo. No seguinte testimony a uma subcomissão da casa 
em 1949, os representantes de uma liga americana japonesa do 
antidiscrimination e o NAACP discutiram a necessidade para a ação de
direitas civis federal. Nenhumas das contas sob a consideração
pela subcomissão passaram. O presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower 
assinou na lei a primeira legislação das direitas civis desde o 
reconstruction em 1957, mas somente o ato de 1964 direitas civis 
começou a executar leis e potências federais do enforcement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In un messaggio al congresso nel mese di febbraio 
del 1948, il presidente Harry S. Truman ha chiesto legislazione 
federale di diritti civili, compreso le leggi antilynching. 
L'ultimo tale fattura da firmare in legge, i 1875 diritti civili
si comporta, era stato inconstituzionale dichiarato dalla Corte 
suprema in 1883, durante il periodo di où il numero di lynchings 
degli Americani africani nel sud è aumentato acutamente. La 
storia dei tentativi guastati di passare la legislazione antilyching 
federale va di nuovo a 1894, quando una fattura della Camera per 
creare un comitato per studiare i lynchings è venuto a mancare. 
In 1922, la Camera ha passato una fattura dalla a due--u'a 
margine per fare lynching un crimine federale, ma malgrado il supporto
del presidente Warren G. Harding, senatori del sud filibustered e la 
ha sconfitta. In 1933, il presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt non 
è riuscito a sostenere una fattura antilynching proposta dal NAACP, 
temente che i legislatori del sud di tasto retaliate ed interferissero
con il suo ordine del giorno di nuovo affare. Nella seguente 
testimonianza ad un sottocomitato della Camera in 1949, i 
rappresentanti di una lega americana giapponese di antidiscrimination 
ed il NAACP hanno discusso l'esigenza di azione corretta civile 
federale. Nessun delle fatture allo studio dal sottocomitato 
hanno passato. Il presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower ha firmato in 
legge la prima legislazione di diritti civili da ricostruzione in 
1957, ma soltanto la Legge di 1964 diritti civili ha cominciato ad 
effettuare le leggi e le potenzi federali di applicazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε ένα μήνυμα στο συνέδριο τον Φεβρουάριο του 1948,
ο Πρόεδρος Harry S. Truman ζήτησε την ομοσπονδιακή 
νομοθεσία αστικών δικαιωμάτων, συμπεριλαμβανομένου οι νόμοι. 
Ο τελευταίος τέτοιος λογαριασμός που υπογράφεται στο νόμο, 
ο νόμος 1875 αστικών δικαιωμάτων, ήταν κηρυγμένος 
αντισυνταγματικός από το ανώτατο δικαστήριο το 1883, κατά τη 
διάρκεια μιας περιόδου στην οποία ο αριθμός λυντσαρισμάτων 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών στο νότο αυξήθηκε αισθητά. Η 
ιστορία των αποτυχημένων προσπαθειών να περαστεί η ομοσπονδιακή 
antilyching νομοθεσία επιστρέφει σε 1894, όταν απέτυχε ένας
λογαριασμός σπιτιών για να δημιουργήσει μια επιτροπή για να 
ερευνήσει τα λυντσαρίσματα. Το 1922, η Βουλή ψήφισε ένα 
νομοσχέδιο από ένα δύο-$$$-ΈΝΑ περιθώριο για να κάνει το 
λυντσάρισμα ενός ομοσπονδιακού εγκλήματος, αλλά παρά την 
υποστήριξη Προέδρου Warren G. Harding's, οι νότιοι 
γερουσιαστές και αυτό νίκησαν. Το 1933, ο Πρόεδρος 
Franklin D. Roosevelt απέτυχε να υποστηρίξει έναν 
antilynching λογαριασμό που προτάθηκε από το NAACP, φοσμένος
ότι οι βασικοί νότιοι νομοθέτες θα εκδικούνταν και θα 
παρεμπόδιζαν τη νέα ημερήσια διάταξη διαπραγμάτευσής του. 
Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση σε μια υποεπιτροπή σπιτιών το 
1949, οι αντιπρόσωποι μιας ιαπωνικής αμερικανικής ένωσης 
antidiscrimination και του NAACP υποστήριξαν την ανάγκη για 
την ομοσπονδιακή ενέργεια αστικών δικαιωμάτων. Κανένας από
τους λογαριασμούς υπό εξέταση από την υποεπιτροπή δεν πέρασε. 
Ο Πρόεδρος Dwight D. Eisenhower υπέγραψε στο νόμο 
την πρώτη νομοθεσία αστικών δικαιωμάτων από την αναδημιουργία το
1957, αλλά μόνο ο νόμος αστικών δικαιωμάτων του 1964 
άρχισε να εφαρμόζει τους ομοσπονδιακούς νόμους και τις δυνάμεις 
επιβολής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En un mensaje al congreso en febrero de 1948, 
presidente Harry S. Truman pidió la legislación federal de las 
derechas civiles, incluyendo leyes antilynching. El último tal 
cuenta que se firmará en ley, las 1875 derechas civiles actúa, 
había sido inconstitucional declarado por el Tribunal Supremo en 
1883, durante un período de el cual el número de lynchings de 
americanos africanos en el sur aumentó sostenidamente. La 
historia de tentativas falladas de aprobar la legislación antilyching
federal va de nuevo a 1894, cuando una cuenta de la casa para crear a 
un comité para investigar lynchings falló. En 1922, la casa 
aprobó una cuenta por a dos--uno a margen para hacer lynching un 
crimen federal, pero a pesar de la ayuda de presidente Warren G. 
Harding, senadores meridionales filibustered y la derrotó. En 
1933, presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt no pudo utilizar una cuenta 
antilynching propuesta por el NAACP, temiendo que los legisladores 
meridionales del clave tomarían represalias e interferirían con su 
agenda del nuevo reparto. En el testimonio siguiente a un 
subcomité de la casa en 1949, los representantes de una liga 
americana japonesa del antidiscrimination y el NAACP discutieron la 
necesidad de la acción federal de las derechas civiles. 
Ningunas de las cuentas bajo consideración del subcomité 
pasaron. Presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower firmó en ley la 
primera legislación de las derechas civiles desde la reconstrucción 
en 1957, pero solamente el acto de las 1964 derechas civiles comenzó 
a poner leyes y potencias federales de la aplicación en ejecucio'n.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087040</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105674</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-rights-of-all-must-be-secured-or-the-rights-of-none-will-be-secure-arguments-for-federal-civil-rights-legislation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
