<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103974</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103974</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200630</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Beginner Modeling Exercises</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anfänger, der Übungen Formt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Débutant Modelant des Exercices</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Novato Que Modela Exercícios</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Principiante Che Modella Le Esercitazioni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ασκήσεις διαμόρφωσης αρχαρίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Principiante Que modela Ejercicios</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The goal of this paper written as part of the MIT Systems Dynamics in Education Project is to teach the reader how to distinguish between stocks and flows. A stock is an accumulation that is changed over time by inflows and outflows. The reader will gain intuition about stocks and flow through and extensive list of different examples and will practice modeling simple systems with constant flows. STELLA modeling examples include, but are not restricted to, skunks populations, landfills, a bank account and nuclear weapons.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel dieses Papiers, das als Teil der MIT 
Systeme Dynamik in Ausbildung Projekt geschrieben wird, ist, dem Leser
beizubringen, wie man zwischen Aktien unterscheidet und fließt. 
Ein Vorrat ist eine Aufspeicherung, die über Zeit durch 
Zuströme und Ausflüsse geändert wird. Der Leser gewinnt 
Intuition über Aktien und fließt und umfangreiche Liste der 
unterschiedlichen Beispiele und übt, einfache Systeme mit konstanten 
Flüssen zu formen durch. STELLA, die Beispiele formen, 
schließen ein, aber werden nicht auf, Stinktierbevölkerungen, 
Aufschüttungen, ein Bankkonto und Kernwaffen eingeschränkt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cet article écrit en tant qu'élément 
de la dynamique de systèmes de MIT dans le projet d'éducation est 
d'enseigner au lecteur comment distinguer les stocks et coule. 
Des actions sont une accumulation qui est changée avec le temps
par des apports et des sorties. Le lecteur gagnera l'intuition 
au sujet des stocks et les traversera et la liste étendue de 
différents exemples et pratiquera modeler les systèmes simples avec 
des écoulements constants. STELLA modelant des exemples 
incluent, mais ne sont pas limités à, des populations de 
mouffettes, des remblais, un compte bancaire et les armes 
nucléaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objetivo deste papel escrito como a parte da 
dinâmica dos sistemas do MIT no projeto da instrução é ensinar ao 
leitor como distinguir entre o estoque e flui. Um estoque é uma
acumulação que seja mudada sobre o tempo por inflows e por outflows.
O leitor ganhará o intuition sobre o estoque e corrê-los-á 
através e a lista extensiva de exemplos diferentes e praticá-los-á 
modelar sistemas simples com fluxos constantes. STELLA que 
modelam exemplos incluem, mas não são restringidos a, populações 
dos skunks, landfills, um cliente de banco e armas nucleares.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'obiettivo di questa carta scritta come 
componente del dynamics dei sistemi del MIT nel progetto di formazione
è di insegnare al lettore come distinguersi fra gli stock e fluisce. 
Lle azione sono un'accumulazione che è cambiata col tempo dalle
affluenze e dalle uscite. Il lettore guadagnerà l'intuizione 
circa gli stock ed attraverserà e la vasta lista degli esempi 
differenti e si eserciterà in modellare i sistemi semplici con i 
flussi costanti. STELLA che modellano gli esempi includono, ma 
non si limitano a, popolazioni degli skunks, materiali di riporto, un 
cliente della banca ed armi nucleari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του εγγράφου που γράφεται ως τμήμα της
δυναμικής συστημάτων MIT στο πρόγραμμα εκπαίδευσης είναι να 
διδαχθεί ο αναγνώστης πώς να διακρίνει μεταξύ των αποθεμάτων και
των ροών. Ένα απόθεμα είναι μια συσσώρευση που κατά τη 
διάρκεια του χρόνου από τις εισροές και οι εκροές αλλάζει. 
Ο αναγνώστης θα κερδίσει τη διαίσθηση για τα αποθέματα και 
να διατρέξει και τον εκτενή κατάλογο διαφορετικών παραδειγμάτων 
και θα ασκήσει τα απλά συστήματα με τις σταθερές ροές. Τα 
παραδείγματα διαμόρφωσης της ΣΤΕΛΛΑ περιλαμβάνουν, αλλά δεν είναι
περιορισμένα, πληθυσμοί μεφιτίδων, υλικά οδόστρωσης, ένας 
τραπεζικός λογαριασμός και πυρηνικά όπλα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La meta de este papel escrito como parte de la 
dinámica de los sistemas del MIT en proyecto de la educación es 
enseñar al programa de lectura cómo distinguir entre la acción y 
fluye. Una acción es una acumulación que es cambiada en un 
cierto plazo por afluencias y salidas. El programa de lectura 
ganará la intuición sobre la acción y los atravesará y la lista 
extensa de diversos ejemplos y practicará el modelar de sistemas 
simples con flujos constantes. STELLA que modelan ejemplos 
incluyen, pero no se restringen a, las poblaciones de las mofetas,
los terraplenes, una cuenta bancaria y las armas nucleares.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JAY FORRESTER
FN:JAY FORRESTER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200630</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103974</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/beginner-modeling-exercises</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
