<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104666</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104666</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086903</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Body Count: Lynching in Arkansas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Zählung der Toten: Lynchen in Arkansas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Compte de Corps : Lyncher en Arkansas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Contagem De Corpo: Lynching em Arkansas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Conteggio Di Corpo: Lynching 
nell'Arkansas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αρίθμηση σώματος: Λυντσάρισμα στο Αρκάνσας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Cuenta De Cuerpo: El lynching en 
Arkansas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the eighteenth to the mid-nineteenth centuries, the term "lynching" did not have any racial implications. Starting in the 1880s, however, mob violence was increasingly directed at African Americans. The 1890s witnessed the worst period of lynching in U.S. history. The grim statistical record almost certainly understates the story. Many lynchings were not recorded outside their immediate locality, and pure numbers do not convey the brutality of lynching.In this 1892 report printed in Philadelphia's  Christian Recorder , Reverend E. Malcolm Argyle recounted events in Arkansas and described the efforts of his fellow black ministers to secure passage of anti-lynching legislation. In response to the rising tide of lynchings of African-Americans across the South during the 1890s, Memphis, Tennessee, newspaper editor Ida Wells-Barnett launched a national anti-lynching crusade. Despite decades of determined effort, the anti-lynching movement never succeeded in securing federal passage of an anti-lynching law. Although Congress never passed even a moderate anti-lynching statute brought before it for more than forty years, parts of the 1968 Civil Rights Act provided for federal intervention on behalf of individuals injured in the exercise of their civil rights.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von den achtzehnten bis mittler-19.jahrhunderten 
hatte die "lynchende" Bezeichnung keine rassischen Implikationen. 
Beginnend im 1880s jedoch wurde Pöbelgewalttätigkeit in 
zunehmendem Maße an den afrikanischen Amerikanern verwiesen. 
Das 1890s zeugte die falschste Periode des Lynchens in der 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte. Der grimmige statistische Satz 
understates fast zweifellos die Geschichte. Viele lynchings 
wurden nicht außerhalb ihrer sofortigen Stelle gespeichert, und reine
Zahlen übermitteln nicht die Brutalitäten von lynching.In diese 
1892, die Report Philadelphias im christlichen Schreiber druckte, 
Reverend E. Malcolm Argyle nachgezählte Fälle in Arkansas und 
beschrieben die Bemühungen seiner Mitschwarzminister, Durchgang der 
Anti-lynchenden Gesetzgebung zu sichern. In der Antwort zu den 
steigenden Gezeiten von lynchings der Afrikanisch-Amerikaner 
über dem Süden während des 1890s, stieß Memphis, Tennessee, 
Zeitungsverleger Ida Vertiefungen-Barnett einen nationalen 
Anti-lynchenden Kreuzzug aus. Trotz der Dekaden der 
entschlossenen Bemühung, folgte die Anti-lynchende Bewegung nie, mit,
Bundesdurchgang eines Anti-lynchenden Gesetzes zu sichern. 
Obgleich Kongreß nie sogar ein gemäßigtes Anti-lynchendes 
Gesetz führte, das vor ihm für mehr als vierzig Jahre geholt wurde, 
fungieren die Teile der 1968 Zivilrechte für Bundesintervention im 
Namen der Einzelpersonen zur Verfügung gestellt, die in der Übung 
ihrer Zivilrechte verletzt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des dix-huitième à mi-dix-neuvième siècles, le
terme "lynchant" n'a eu aucune implication raciale. Commençant 
dans le 1880s, cependant, la violence de foule a été de plus en plus
dirigée aux Américains africains. Le 1890s était témoin de 
la plus mauvaise période de lyncher dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS. 
L'enregistrement statistique sinistre minimise presque 
certainement l'histoire. Beaucoup de lynchings n'ont pas été 
enregistrés en dehors de leur localité immédiate, et les nombres 
purs ne donnent pas la brutalité de lynching.In ces 1892 que l'état 
a imprimés dans l'enregistreur chrétien de Philadelphie, 
événements racontés Argyle de E. Malcolm de Révérend en Arkansas 
et n'ont pas décrit les efforts de ses ministres de noir de camarade 
de fixer le passage de la législation anti-lynchante. En 
réponse à la marée se levante des lynchings des Afro-Américains à 
travers les Sud pendant le 1890s, Memphis, Tennessee, 
Puits-Barnett d'Ida d'éditeur de journal a lancé une croisade 
anti-lynchante nationale. En dépit des décennies d'effort 
déterminé, le mouvement anti-lynchant n'a jamais réussi à fixer le
passage fédéral d'une loi anti-lynchante. Bien que le congrès
n'ait jamais passé même un statut anti-lynchant modéré apporté 
avant lui pendant plus de quarante années, les parties des 1968 
droits civiques agissent prévues l'intervention fédérale au nom des 
individus blessés dans l'exercice de leurs droits civiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dos décimos oitavos a mid-décimos nonos 
séculos, o termo "que lynching" não teve nenhumas implicações 
raciais. Começando no 1880s, entretanto, a violência do mob 
foi dirigida cada vez mais em americanos africanos. O 1890s 
testemunhou o período o mais mau de lynching no history de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. O registro estatístico grim suaviza quase certamente a 
história. Muitos lynchings não foram gravados fora de seu 
locality imediato, e os números puros não fazem saber ao brutality 
de lynching.In estes 1892 que o relatório imprimiu no registrador 
christian de Filadélfia, eventos recounted Argyle de Reverend E. 
Malcolm em Arkansas e não descreveram os esforços de seus ministros 
do preto do companheiro fixar a passagem da legislação 
anti-anti-lynching. Em resposta à maré levantando-se dos 
lynchings dos Africano-Americanos através do sul durante o 1890s, 
Memphis, Tennessee, Poços-Barnett de Ida do editor de jornal lançou 
um crusade anti-anti-lynching nacional. Apesar das décadas de 
esforço determinado, o movimento anti-anti-lynching nunca sucedeu em 
fixar a passagem federal de uma lei anti-anti-lynching. Embora o
congress nunca passe mesmo um statute anti-anti-lynching moderado 
trazido antes dele por mais de quarenta anos, as partes das 1968 
direitas civis agem fornecidas para a intervenção federal em nome 
dos indivíduos feridos no exercício de suas direitas civis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dai diciottesimi - metà di-diciannovesimi secoli,
il termine "che lynching" non ha avuto alcune implicazioni razziali. 
Cominciando nel 1880s, tuttavia, la violenza del mob sempre più
è stata diretta agli Americani africani. Il 1890s ha 
testimoniato il periodo più difettoso di lynching nella storia degli 
STATI UNITI. Il record statistico torvo quasi certamente 
minimizza la storia. Molti lynchings non sono stati registrati 
fuori della loro località immediata ed i numeri puri non trasportano 
il brutality di lynching.In questi 1892 che rapporto ha stampato in 
registratore cristiano de Filadelfia, eventi raccontati Argyle di 
Reverend E. Malcolm nell'Arkansas e non hanno descritto gli sforzi dei
suoi ministri di nero del collega al passaggio sicuro di 
legislazione anti-anti-lynching. In risposta alla marea 
aumentante dei lynchings degli Africano-Americani attraverso il sud 
durante il 1890s, Memphis, Tennessee, Pozzi-Barnett di Ida 
dell'editore di giornale ha lanciato un crusade anti-anti-lynching 
nazionale. Malgrado le decadi di sforzo risoluto, il movimento 
anti-anti-lynching non è riuscito mai a assicurare il passaggio 
federale di una legge anti-anti-lynching. Anche se il congresso 
non ha passato mai persino uno statuto anti-anti-lynching moderato 
portato prima di esso per più di quaranta anni facente parte i 1968 
diritti civili si comportano provveduti ad intervento federale a nome 
degli individui danneggiati nell'esercitazione dei loro diritti 
civili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το δέκατο όγδοο στους μέσος-δέκατους έννατους 
αιώνες, ο όρος "που λυντσάρει" δεν είχε οποιεσδήποτε φυλετικές 
επιπτώσεις. Αρχική στο 1880s, εντούτοις, η βία όχλου 
κατευθύνθηκε όλο και περισσότερο σε αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. 
Το 1890s βεβαίωσε τη χειρότερη περίοδο λυντσαρίσματος 
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉ ιστορία. Το απαίσιο στατιστικό αρχείο 
σχεδόν βεβαίως μειώνει την ιστορία. Πολλά λυντσαρίσματα 
δεν καταγράφηκαν έξω από την άμεση τοποθεσία τους, και οι 
καθαροί αριθμοί δεν μεταβιβάζουν τη βιαιότητα του λυντσαρίσματος 
Σε αυτήν την έκθεση 1892 που τυπώθηκε στο χριστιανικό 
όργανο καταγραφής της Φιλαδέλφειας, Αιδεσιμότατος Ε. ο Malcolm 
Argyle εξιστόρησε τα γεγονότα στο Αρκάνσας και περιέγραψε τις 
προσπάθειες των συντροφικών μαύρων υπουργών του να εξασφαλίσει τη
μετάβαση της νομοθεσίας αντι-λυντσαρίσματος. Σε απάντηση 
στην αυξανόμενη παλίρροια των λυντσαρισμάτων 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανών πέρα από το νότο κατά τη διάρκεια του 
1890s, Μέμφιδα, Tennessee, ο επεξεργαστής IDA φρεάτιο- 
Barnett εφημερίδων προώθησε μια εθνική σταυροφορία 
αντι-λυντσαρίσματος. Παρά τις δεκαετίες αποφασιστικής 
προσπάθειας, η μετακίνηση αντι-λυντσαρίσματος δεν πέτυχε ποτέ 
στην εξασφάλιση της ομοσπονδιακής μετάβασης ενός νόμου 
αντι-λυντσαρίσματος. Αν και το συνέδριο που πέρασαν ποτέ 
ακόμη και ένα μέτριο καταστατικό αντι-λυντσαρίσματος που 
παρουσιάστηκε πριν από τον για περισσότερο από σαράντα έτη, 
μέρη του νόμου αστικών δικαιωμάτων του 1968 πρόβλεψε την 
ομοσπονδιακή επέμβαση εξ ονόματος των ατόμων που τραυματίστηκαν 
στην άσκηση των αστικών δικαιωμάτων τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A partir de los décimo octavos a mediados 
de-diecinueveavo siglos, el término "lynching" no tenía ninguna 
implicaciones racial. Comenzando en el 1880s, sin embargo, la 
violencia de la multitud fue dirigida cada vez más en los americanos 
africanos. El 1890s atestiguó el período peor de lynching en 
la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS. El expediente estadístico severo
minimisa casi ciertamente la historia. Muchos lynchings no 
fueron registrados fuera de su lugar inmediato, y los números puros 
no transportan la brutalidad de lynching.In estos 1892 que el informe 
imprimió en el registrador cristiano de Philadelphia, acontecimientos
contados de nuevo Argyle de Reverend E. Malcolm en Arkansas y no 
describieron los esfuerzos de sus ministros del negro del compañero 
de asegurar el paso de la legislación contra-anti-lynching. En 
respuesta a la marea de levantamiento de lynchings de 
Africano-Americanos a través del sur durante el 1890s, Memphis, 
Tennessee, Receptores de papel-Barnett de Ida del redactor lanzó una 
cruzada contra-anti-lynching nacional. A pesar de décadas 
del esfuerzo resuelto, el movimiento contra-anti-lynching nunca tuvo 
éxito en asegurar el paso federal de una ley contra-anti-lynching. 
Aunque el congreso nunca pasó incluso un estatuto 
contra-anti-lynching moderado traído antes de él por más de 
cuarenta años, las partes de las 1968 derechas civiles actúan 
previstas la intervención federal a nombre de los individuos dañados
en el ejercicio de las sus derechas civiles.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086903</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104666</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-body-count-lynching-in-arkansas</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
