<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104336</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104336</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Culturally Engaged Instruction (CEI): Putting theory into practice</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kulturell Engagierte Anweisung (CEI): Setzen
von von Theorie in Praxis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Instruction Culturelement Engagée (CEI) : 
Mise de la théorie en pratique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Instrução Culturally Acoplada (CEI): Pondo
a teoria na prática</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Istruzione Culturalmente Agganciata (CEI): 
Mettendo teoria in pratica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολιτιστικά δεσμευμένη οδηγία (CEI): 
Τοποθέτηση της θεωρίας σε εφαρμογή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Instrucción Cultural Contratada (CEI): 
Poner teoría en práctica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As an English teacher at a rural all-Black high school in the Mississippi Delta, Renee Moore enjoyed a genuine fellowship with her students, many of whom she worked with outside of school in church and community activities. Lessons in literature and writing went reasonably well (for a beginning teacher), but when she started to teach grammar, her students seemed to 'hit a brick wall.' She had two simultaneous responses to the wall. She immediately started searching for and experimenting with more effective grammar instructional methodologies, and she began what would become a career long action-research study on the issues surrounding the teaching of standard American English to African American students.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als englischer Lehrer an einer 
landwirtschaftlichen all-Schwarzen High School im Mississippi Dreieck,
genoß Renee Moore ein echtes Stipendium mit ihren Kursteilnehmern, 
viele von, wem bearbeitete sie mit außerhalb Schule in den Kirche- 
und Gemeinschaftsaktivitäten. Lektionen in der Literatur und im
Schreiben gingen angemessen Vertiefung (für einen anfangenlehrer), 
aber, als sie begann, Grammatik zu unterrichten, schienen ihre 
Kursteilnehmer, ' eine Ziegelsteinwand zu schlagen.' Sie hatte 
zwei simultane Antworten zur Wand. Sie fing sofort, nach zu 
suchen an und mit anweisenden Methodenlehren der wirkungsvolleren 
Grammatik zu experimentieren, und sie fing an, was eine Karriere lang 
Tätigkeit-Forschung Untersuchung über die Ausgaben werden würde, 
die den Unterricht amerikanischen Standardenglisch zu den 
afrikanischen amerikanischen Kursteilnehmern umgeben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En tant que professeur anglais à un lycée 
tout-Noir rural dans le delta du Mississippi, Renee Moore a apprécié
une camaraderie véritable avec ses étudiants, beaucoup de qui elle a
travaillé avec en dehors de de l'école dans des activités d'église
et de communauté. Les leçons dans la littérature et 
l'écriture sont allées raisonnablement bien (pour un professeur 
commençant), mais quand elle a commencé à enseigner la grammaire, 
ses étudiants ont semblé 'frapper un mur de brique.' Elle a eu
deux réponses simultanées au mur. Elle a immédiatement 
commencé à rechercher et expérimenter avec des méthodologies 
d'instruction de grammaire plus pertinente, et elle a commencé ce qui
deviendrait une étude d'action-recherche de carrière longtemps sur 
les questions entourant l'enseignement de l'anglais américain 
standard aux étudiants américains africains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como um professor inglês em uma High School 
todo-Preta rural no delta de Mississippi, Renee Moore apreciou um 
fellowship genuíno com seus estudantes, muitos de quem trabalhou com 
fora da escola em atividades da igreja e da comunidade. As 
lições na literatura e na escrita foram razoavelmente poço (para um
professor de começo), mas quando começou ensinar a gramática, seus 
estudantes pareceram ' bater uma parede do tijolo.' Teve duas 
respostas simultâneas à parede. Começou imediatamente 
procurarar por e experimentar com as metodologias instrutivas de uma 
gramática mais eficaz, e começou o que se transformaria um estudo da
ação-pesquisa da carreira por muito tempo nas edições que cercam o
ensino do inglês americano padrão aos estudantes americanos 
africanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come insegnante inglese ad una High School 
tutto-Nera rurale nel delta del Mississippi, Renee Moore ha goduto un 
fellowship genuino con i suoi allievi, molti di chi ha lavorato con 
fuori della scuola nelle attività della Comunità e della chiesa. 
Le lezioni nella letteratura e nella scrittura sono andato 
ragionevolmente pozzo (per un insegnante d'inizio), ma quando ha 
cominciato insegnare la grammatica, i suoi allievi hanno sembrato 
'colpire una parete del mattone.' Ha avuta due risposte 
simultanee alla parete. Immediatamente ha cominciato cercare e 
sperimentare con le metodologie didattiche di grammatica più efficace
ed ha cominciato che cosa si transformerebbe in lungamente in uno 
studio di azione-ricerca di carriera sulle edizioni che circondano 
l'insegnamento dell'inglese americano standard agli allievi americani 
africani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαν αγγλικό δάσκαλο σε ένα αγροτικό όλος-μαύρο 
γυμνάσιο στο δέλτα του Μισισιπή, Renee Moore απόλαυσε μια 
γνήσια υποτροφία με τους σπουδαστές της, πολλών από τους οποίους
συνεργάστηκε με έξω από το σχολείο στην εκκλησία και τις 
κοινοτικές δραστηριότητες. Τα μαθήματα στη λογοτεχνία και το
γράψιμο πήγαν εύλογα καλά (για έναν δάσκαλο αρχής), αλλά όταν
άρχισε να διδάσκει τη γραμματική, οι σπουδαστές της φάνηκαν "να 
χτυπούν έναν τοίχο τούβλου." Είχε δύο ταυτόχρονες 
απαντήσεις στον τοίχο. Αρχισε αμέσως για και με την 
αποτελεσματικότερη γραμματική εκπαιδευτικές μεθοδολογίες, και 
άρχισε αυτό που θα γινόταν μια μακροχρόνια ενέργεια-ερευνητική 
μελέτη σταδιοδρομίας για τα ζητήματα που περιβάλλουν τη 
διδασκαλία των πρότυπων αμερικανικών αγγλικών στους αφρικανικούς 
αμερικανικούς σπουδαστές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Como profesor inglés en una High School 
secundaria todo-Negra rural en el delta de Mississippi, Renee Moore 
gozó de una beca genuina con sus estudiantes, muchas de quién ella 
trabajó con fuera de la escuela en actividades de la iglesia y de la 
comunidad. Las lecciones en literatura y la escritura fueron 
razonablemente receptor de papel (para un profesor que comienza), pero
cuando ella comenzó a enseñar la gramática, sus estudiantes se 
parecían ' golpear una pared del ladrillo.' Ella tenía dos 
respuestas simultáneas a la pared. Ella comenzó inmediatamente
a buscar para y a experimentar con metodologías educacionales de una 
gramática más eficaz, y ella comenzó qué se convirtió en un 
estudio de la accio'n-investigacio'n de la carrera de largo en las 
ediciones que rodean la enseñanza del inglés americano estándar a 
los estudiantes americanos africanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RENEE MOORE
FN:RENEE MOORE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104336</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/culturally-engaged-instruction-cei-putting-theory-into-practice-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
