<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103593</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103593</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206318</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The War Relocation Camps of World War II: When Fear Was Stronger than Justice</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Krieg-Verschiebung Lager des Zweiten 
Weltkrieges: Als Furcht stärker als Gerechtigkeit war</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les camps de réadressage de guerre de la 
deuxième guerre mondiale : Quand la crainte était plus forte 
que la justice</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os acampamentos do relocation da guerra da segunda
guerra mundial: Quando o medo era mais forte do que a justiça</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli accampamenti di rilocazione di guerra della 
seconda guerra mondiale: Quando il timore era più forte della 
giustizia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα στρατόπεδα πολεμικής επαναμετάθεσης του παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου ΙΙ: Όταν ο φόβος ήταν ισχυρότερος από τη 
δικαιοσύνη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los campos de la realocación de la guerra de la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial: Cuando el miedo era más fuerte que 
justicia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the causes and effects of President Franklin Roosevelt's executive order, signed two months after the attack on Pearl Harbor, that moved nearly 120,000 Japanese and Japanese Americans into relocation centers. An excerpt is provided from the executive order as well as headlines from newspapers, a 1942 notice of instructions to all persons of Japanese ancestry, a description of life in the relocation centers, maps, and photos of a typical barracks room, mess hall, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft die Ursachen und die Effekte 
Präsident Franklin Roosevelts der Ausführungsverordnung, 
unterzeichnet zwei Monate nach dem Angriff auf Pearl Harbor, das fast 
120.000 japanisch und japanische Amerikaner in Verschiebung Mitten 
verschob. Ein Excerpt wird von der Ausführungsverordnung sowie 
Schlagzeilen von den Zeitungen, ein Begriff 1942 von Anweisungen zu 
allen Personen des japanischen Geschlechtes, eine Beschreibung des 
Lebens in der Verschiebung zentriert, Karten und Fotos eines typischen
Kaserneraumes, der Verwirrunghalle und mehr zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine les causes et les effets de la commande 
exécutive du Président Franklin Roosevelt's, signés deux mois 
après l'attaque sur le port de perle, qui a déplacé presque 120.000
japonais et Américains japonais dans des centres de réadressage. 
Un extrait est fourni de la commande exécutive aussi bien que 
des titres des journaux, une notification 1942 des instructions à 
toutes les personnes de l'ascendance japonaise, une description de la 
vie dans le réadressage centre, des cartes, et des photos d'une salle
de casernes, d'un hall de désordre, et d'un plus typiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina as causas e os efeitos da ordem executiva 
do presidente Franklin Roosevelt, assinados dois meses após o ataque 
no porto de pérola, que moveu quase 120.000 japoneses e americanos 
japoneses em centros do relocation. Um excerpt é fornecido da 
ordem executiva as.well.as headlines dos jornais, uma observação 
1942 das instruções a todas as pessoas do ancestry japonês, uma 
descrição da vida no relocation centra-se, mapas, e fotos de um 
quarto dos barracks, de um salão do mess, e de um mais típicos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina le cause e gli effetti di ordine esecutivo
del presidente Franklin Roosevelt, firmati due mesi dopo l'attacco al 
porto di perla, che ha spostato quasi 120.000 giapponesi e gli 
Americani giapponesi nei centri di rilocazione. Un brano è 
fornito dall'ordine esecutivo così come i titoli dai giornali, un 
avviso 1942 delle istruzioni a tutte le persone dell'ascendenza 
giapponese, una descrizione di vita nella rilocazione concentra, 
programmi e foto di una stanza dei barracks, di un corridoio di mess e
di un più tipici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τα αίτια και τα αιτιατά της εκτελεστικής 
κατάταξης Προέδρου Franklin Roosevelt's, που υπογράφονται 
δύο μήνες μετά από την επίθεση στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, το 
οποίο κίνησε σχεδόν 120.000 ιαπωνικούς και ιαπωνικούς 
Αμερικανούς στα κέντρα επαναμετάθεσης. Ένα απόσπασμα 
παρέχεται από την εκτελεστική κατάταξη καθώς επίσης και τους 
τίτλους από τις εφημερίδες, μια ειδοποίηση του 1942 των 
οδηγιών σε όλα τα πρόσωπα της ιαπωνικής καταγωγής, μια περιγραφή
της ζωής στα κέντρα επαναμετάθεσης, χάρτες, και οι φωτογραφίες 
ενός χαρακτηριστικού δωματίου αποδοκιμασιών, βρωμίζουν την 
αίθουσα, και περισσότερων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina las causas y los efectos de la orden 
ejecutiva de presidente Franklin Roosevelt, firmados dos meses 
después del ataque contra el puerto de perla, que movió a casi 
120.000 japoneses y a americanos japoneses en centros de la 
realocación. Un extracto se proporciona de la pedido ejecutiva 
así como títulos de los periódicos, un aviso 1942 de instrucciones 
a todas las personas de la ascendencia japonesa, una descripción de 
la vida en la realocación se centra, las correspondencias, y las 
fotos de un cuarto de los cuarteles, de un pasillo del lío, y más 
típicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206318</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103593</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-war-relocation-camps-of-world-war-ii-when-fear-was-stronger-than-justice</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
