<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102954</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102954</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207122</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Southwest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanischer Südwesten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sud-ouest Américain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sudoeste Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sud-ovest Americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικό νοτιοδυτικό σημείο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sudoeste Americano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents a travel itinerary of 58 historic places across Arizona, Colorado, and New Mexico. It includes forts built to protect mail routes and settlers, missions and churches, prehistoric cliff dwellings, trading posts, petroglyphs (from the petrified forest), pit house villages, and Indian villages home to the Anasazi, Sinagua, Zuni, and other Native American tribes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt einen Spielraumreiseweg von 58 historischen
Plätzen über Arizona, Kolorado und New-Mexico dar. Er enthält
die Forts, die aufgebaut werden, um Postwege und -siedleren, Missionen
und Kirchen, prähistorische Klippe Wohnungen, handelnde Pfosten, 
Petroglyphs (vom versteinerten Wald), Grubehausdörfer und indische 
Dörfer nach Hause zum Anasazi, zu Sinagua, zu Zuni und zu anderen 
gebürtigen amerikanischen Stämmen zu schützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente un itinéraire de voyage de 58 endroits 
historiques à travers l'Arizona, le Colorado, et le Nouveau-Mexique. 
Il inclut des forts construits pour protéger des itinéraires 
et des colons de courrier, des missions et des églises, des logements
préhistoriques de falaise, des comptoirs commerciaux, des 
pétroglyphes (de la forêt petrified), des villages de maison de 
mine, et des villages indiens à la maison à l'Anasazi, à Sinagua, 
à Zuni, et à d'autres tribus américaines indigènes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta um itinerary do curso de 58 lugares 
historic através do arizona, do Colorado, e da Novo México. 
Inclui os forts construídos para proteger rotas e settlers do 
correio, missões e igrejas, moradias pré-históricas do penhasco, 
bornes negociando, petroglyphs (da floresta petrified), vilas da casa 
do poço, e vilas indian para casa ao Anasazi, a Sinagua, a Zuni, e a 
outros tribes americanos nativos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta un itinerario di corsa di 58 posti 
storici attraverso l'Arizona, Colorado ed il Nuovo Messico. 
Include i forts costruiti per proteggere gli itinerari e 
settlers della posta, missioni e chiese, dimore prehistoric della 
scogliera, alberini di commercio, petroglyphs (dalla foresta 
petrified), villaggi della casa del pozzo e villaggi indiani a casa al
Anasazi, a Sinagua, a Zuni e ad altre tribù americane natali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει μια περιήγηση ταξιδιού 58 ιστορικών 
θέσεων πέρα από την Αριζόνα, το Κολοράντο, και το New 
Mexico. Περιλαμβάνει τα οχυρά που χτίζονται για να 
προστατεύσουν τις διαδρομές και τους αποίκους ταχυδρομείου, τις 
αποστολές και τις εκκλησίες, τις προϊστορικές κατοικίες απότομων
βράχων, τις θέσεις εμπορικών συναλλαγών, petroglyphs (από το 
δάσος), τα χωριά σπιτιών κοιλωμάτων, και το ινδικό του χωριού 
σπίτι στο Anasazi, Sinagua, Zuni, και άλλες εγγενείς 
αμερικανικές φυλές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta un itinerario del recorrido de 58 lugares
históricos a través del Arizona, de Colorado, y de New México. 
Incluye las fortalezas construidas para proteger las rutas y los
colonos del correo, las misiones y las iglesias, las viviendas 
prehistóricas del acantilado, los postes que negocian, los 
petroglyphs (del bosque aterrorizado), las aldeas de la casa del 
hueco, y las aldeas indias a casa al Anasazi, a Sinagua, a Zuni, y a 
otras tribus americanas nativas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207122</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102954</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-southwest</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
