<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104235</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104235</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213216</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">World Population</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weltbevölkerung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Population du Monde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">População Do Mundo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Popolazione Del Mondo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παγκόσμιος πληθυσμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Población Del Mundo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, students access and visualize world population data using the user friendly MyWorld GIS software. Data includes total population, population density, projected population, male and female population, and age specific population, etc. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität greifen Kursteilnehmer zu und
machen auf Weltbevölkerung Daten mit der benutzerfreundlichen MyWorld
GIS-Software sichtbar. Daten enthalten Gesamtbevölkerung, 
Bevölkerung Dichte, projizierte Bevölkerung, Mann und 
Fraubevölkerung und altern spezifische Bevölkerung, usw.. Auf 
dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen über die
erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les étudiants accèdent et 
visualisent à des données de population du monde en utilisant le 
logiciel convivial de GIs de MyWorld. Les données 
incluent la population totale, la densité de population, la 
population projetée, le mâle et la population de femelle, et 
vieillissent la population spécifique, etc... À cette page de 
point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations 
sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités 
d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, 
les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os estudantes alcançam e 
visualizam dados da população do mundo usando o software amigável 
dos SOLDADOS de MyWorld do usuário. Os dados incluem a 
população total, a densidade de população, a população 
projetada, o macho e a população da fêmea, e envelhecem a 
população específica, etc.. Nesta página do ponto começar, 
os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de 
aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as
notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as 
referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli allievi accedono e 
prevedono ai dati della popolazione del mondo usando il software 
facile da usare di GIS di MyWorld. I dati includono la 
popolazione totale, la densità demografica, la popolazione 
proiettata, il maschio e la popolazione della femmina ed invecchiano 
la popolazione specifica, ecc. A questa pagina del punto di 
partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sugli 
obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di 
istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le idee di 
valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές έχουν 
πρόσβαση και απεικονίζουν στα στοιχεία παγκόσμιων πληθυσμών 
χρησιμοποιώντας το φιλικό προς το χρήστη λογισμικό MyWorld 
GIS. Το στοιχείο περιλαμβάνει το συνολικό πληθυσμό, την 
πυκνότητα πληθυσμών, τον προβαλλόμενο πληθυσμό, τον ανδρικό και 
γυναικείο πληθυσμό, και το συγκεκριμένο πληθυσμό ηλικίας, 
κ.λπ.... Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν 
να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της
άσκησης, πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες 
διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις 
αναφορές και τα θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los estudiantes tienen acceso y
visualizan a datos de la población del mundo usando el software 
convivial de los SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN EL EJÉRCITO de MyWorld. 
Los datos incluyen a la población total, a la densidad 
demogr'afica, a la población proyectada, al varón y a población de 
la hembra, y envejecen la población específica, el etc. En 
esta paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener 
acceso a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, 
contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, 
los materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y 
los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213216</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104235</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/world-population</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
