<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103720</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103720</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086489</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Mr. Local Custom Must Die": An Analysis of the Racial Situation in the South in 1960 as Civil Rights Activism Increased</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Herr Lokale Gewohnheit Muß Sterben": Eine 
Analyse der rassischen Situation im Süden in 1960, wie 
Zivilrecht-Aktivismus sich erhöhte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"M. Coutume Locale Doit Mourir" : Une 
analyse de la situation raciale dans les Sud dans 1960 à 
mesure que l'activisme de droits civiques augmentait</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O "Sr. Costume Local Deve Morrer": Uma 
análise da situação racial no sul em 1960 como o activism das 
direitas civis aumentou</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Sig. Abitudine Locale Deve Morire": 
Un'analisi della situazione razziale nel sud in 1960 come il 
activism di diritti civili è aumentato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο κ. τοπική συνήθεια πρέπει να πεθάνει": Μια 
ανάλυση της φυλετικής κατάστασης στο νότο το 1960 ως ακτιβισμό
αστικών δικαιωμάτων αυξήθηκε</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Sr. Costumbre Local Debe Morir": Un 
análisis de la situación racial en el sur en 1960 como el activismo 
de las derechas civiles aumentó</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1960, following student sit-ins at segregated lunch counters throughout the South, George E. McMillan, a reporter from Knoxville, Tennessee, traveled the region and analyzed its "current raw, ugly temper." Six years after the Supreme Court unanimously ruled in  Brown v. Board of Education  that segregated public schools were unconstitutional, and five years after the Court declared that desegregation should proceed "with all deliberate speed," only a small percentage of Southern schools had been affected. African Americans faced disenfranchisement, severely limited economic opportunities, prejudicial treatment in the criminal justice system, and attacks from mobs and police. McMillan contrasted black outrage at the philosophy of "gradual" change with white insistence on retaining the status quo, and also looked at the role of the military and business communities in fostering change. The Raleigh, North Carolina, meeting McMillan mentioned in passing marked the creation of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), a prominent activist group intent on achieving racial equality.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1960 reiste folgender Kursteilnehmer 
sitzen-sit-ins an getrennten Mittagessenkostenzählern während des 
Südens, George E. McMillan, ein Reporter von Knoxville, Tennessee, 
die Region und analysierte seinen "aktuellen rohen, häßlichen 
Temper." Sechs Jahre nach dem Höchsten Gericht ordneten 
einmütig im braunen v. Brett der Ausbildung an, das allgemeine 
Schulen waren verfassungswidrig trennte und fünf Jahre nach dem Gericht, 
daß desegregation "mit allen fortfahren sollte überlegte 
Geschwindigkeit," nur einen kleinen Prozentsatz der südlichen Schulen
waren beeinflußt worden erklärten. Afrikanische Amerikaner 
gegenübergestelltes disenfranchisement, streng begrenzte ökonomische
Gelegenheiten, nachteilige Behandlung im kriminellen 
Gerechtigkeitsystem und Angriffe vom Pöbel und von der Polizei. 
McMillan kontrastierte schwarzes Verbrechen an der Philosophie 
"der stufenweisen" Änderung mit weißer Beharrlichkeit auf dem 
Beibehalten des Status Quo und betrachtete auch die Rolle der 
Militär- und Geschäftsgemeinschaften, wenn er Änderung förderte. 
Das Raleigh, Nord-Carolina, McMillan treffend, das erwähnt 
wurde, beim Überschreiten kennzeichnete die Kreation des 
Kursteilnehmer-Gewaltlosen Koordinationsausschusses (SNCC), eine 
vorstehende Aktivist Gruppe Absicht auf dem Erzielen der rassischen 
Gleichheit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1960, reposer-Institut central des statistiques
suivant d'étudiant aux compteurs isolés de déjeuner dans tous les 
Sud, George E. McMillan, un journaliste de Knoxville, 
Tennessee, a voyagé la région et a analysé son "trempe cru et laid 
actuel." Six ans après la cour suprême ont unanimement régné
dans le panneau brun de v. de l'éducation qui a isolé des écoles 
d'Etat étaient inconstitutionnel, et cinq ans après la cour ont 
déclaré que la déségrégation devrait se poursuivre "par tous vitesse 
délibérée," seulement un petit pourcentage des écoles 
méridionales avaient été affectés. Disenfranchisement fait 
face par Américains africains, occasions économiques sévèrement 
limitées, traitement préjudiciel dans le système criminel de 
justice, et attaques à partir des foules et de la police. 
McMillan a contrasté l'outrage noir à la philosophie du 
changement "progressif" avec l'insistance blanche sur maintenir le 
statu quo, et a également regardé le rôle des militaires et des 
milieux d'affaires en stimulant le changement. Le Raleigh, 
Caroline du nord, rencontrant McMillan mentionné dans le 
dépassement a marqué la création du Comité de coordination 
Non-violent d'étudiant (SNCC), une intention en avant de groupe 
d'activiste sur réaliser l'égalité raciale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1960, o sent-sit-ins seguindo do estudante em 
contadores segregados do lunch durante todo o sul, George E. McMillan,
um repórter de Knoxville, Tennessee, viajou a região e analisou sua 
"têmpera crua, feia atual." Seis anos após a corte suprema 
governaram unânimemente na placa marrom do v. da instrução que 
segregou escolas públicas era unconstitutional, e cinco anos após a 
corte declararam que o desegregation deve proseguir "com tudo 
velocidade deliberada," somente uma porcentagem pequena de escolas do 
sul tinham sido afetados. Americanos africanos 
disenfranchisement enfrentado, oportunidades econômicas severamente 
limitadas, tratamento prejudicial no sistema criminal da justiça, e 
ataques dos mobs e das polícias. McMillan contrastou o ultraje 
preto na filosofia da mudança "gradual" com insistence branco em 
reter o quo do status, e olhou também o papel das comunidades das 
forças armadas e de negócio em promover a mudança. O Raleigh,
North.carolina, encontrando-se com McMillan mencionado na passagem 
marcou a criação do comitê de coordenação de Nonviolent do 
estudante (SNCC), uma intenção proeminente do grupo da activista em 
conseguir a igualdade racial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1960, l'sed-Istituto centrale di statistica 
seguente dell'allievo ai contatori segregati del pranzo durante il 
sud, George E. McMillan, un reporter da Knoxville, Tennessee, ha 
viaggiato la regione ed ha analizzato il relativo "temperamento grezzo
e ugly corrente." Sei anni dopo la Corte suprema hanno regolato 
all'unanimità nel Bordo marrone del v. di formazione che ha 
segregato le "public school" era inconstituzionale e cinque anni dopo 
la corte hanno dichiarato che il desegregation dovrebbe procedere "a 
tutti velocità intenzionale," soltanto una piccola percentuale delle 
scuole del sud erano stati influenzati. Disenfranchisement 
affrontato Americani africani, occasioni economiche severamente 
limitate, trattamento pregiudizievole nel sistema criminale della 
giustizia ed attacchi dai mobs e dalla polizia. McMillan ha 
contrapposto l'oltraggio nero alla filosofia di cambiamento "graduale"
con l'insistenza bianca sul ritegno dello status quo ed egualmente ha 
guardato il ruolo delle Comunità di affari e dei militari nella 
promozione del cambiamento. Il Raleigh, North.carolina, venente 
a contatto di McMillan accennato nel passare ha contrassegnato la 
creazione del comitato di coordinazione di Nonviolent dell'allievo 
(SNCC), un'intenzione prominente del gruppo dell'attivista sul 
realizzare l'uguaglianza razziale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1960, μετά από το κάθομαι-INS σπουδαστών 
στους διαχωρισμένους μετρητές μεσημεριανού γεύματος σε όλο το 
νότο, George E. McMillan, ένας δημοσιογράφος από 
Knoxville, Tennessee, ταξίδεψε την περιοχή και ανέλυσε τη 
"παρούσα ακατέργαστη, άσχημη ιδιοσυγκρασία του." Έξι έτη 
αφότου διέταξε ομόφωνα το ανώτατο δικαστήριο Brown V. 
Board της εκπαίδευσης που διαχώρισε τα δημόσια σχολεία ήταν 
αντισυνταγματικά, και πέντε έτη αφότου δήλωσε το δικαστήριο ότι
ο διαχωρισμός πρέπει να συνεχίσει "με όλη τη σκόπιμη ταχύτητα," 
μόνο ένα μικρό ποσοστό των νότιων σχολείων επηρεαζόταν. 
Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί αντιμετώπισαν το 
disenfranchisement, σοβαρά περιορισμένες οικονομικές ευκαιρίες,
επιβλαβής επεξεργασία στο ποινικό δικαστικό σύστημα, και 
επιθέσεις από τους όχλους και την αστυνομία. Τα McMillan 
αντιπαρέβαλαν τη μαύρη προσβολή στη φιλοσοφία της "βαθμιαίασ" 
αλλαγής με την άσπρη επιμονή στη διατήρηση του καθεστώτος, και 
εξέτασαν επίσης το ρόλο των στρατιωτικών και επιχειρησιακών 
κοινοτήτων στην ενθάρρυνση της αλλαγής. Το Raleigh, 
βόρεια Καρολίνα, συνάντηση McMillan που αναφέρθηκε στη διάβαση
χαρακτήρισε τη δημιουργία της μη βίαιας συντονιστικής επιτροπής 
σπουδαστών (SNCC), μια προεξέχουσα ομάδα ενεργών στελεχών 
προσηλωμένη στην επίτευξη της φυλετικής ισότητας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1960, el sentar-sit-ins de siguiente del 
estudiante en los contadores segregados del almuerzo a través del 
sur, George E. McMillan, reportero de Knoxville, Tennessee, viajó la 
región y analizaba su "genio sin procesar, feo actual." Seis 
años después del Tribunal Supremo gobernaron unánimemente en la 
tarjeta marrón del v. de la educación que segregó escuelas 
públicas era inconstitucional, y cinco años después de la corte 
declararon que el desegregation debe proceder "con todos velocidad 
deliberada," solamente un porcentaje pequeño de escuelas meridionales
habían sido afectados. Disenfranchisement hecho frente 
americanos africanos, oportunidades económicas seriamente limitadas, 
tratamiento perjudicial en el sistema criminal de la justicia, y 
ataques de las multitudes y del policía. McMillan puso en 
contraste ultraje negro en la filosofía del cambio "gradual" con la 
insistencia blanca respecto a conservar el status quo, y también 
miraba el papel de las comunidades de los militares y de negocio en 
fomentar el cambio. El Raleigh, Carolina del Norte, resolviendo 
McMillan mencionado en pasar marcó la creación del comité que 
coordinaba de Nonviolent del estudiante (SNCC), un intento prominente 
del grupo del activista en la realización de igualdad racial.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086489</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103720</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/mr-local-custom-must-die-an-analysis-of-the-racial-situation-in-the-south-in-1960-as-civil-rights-activism-increased</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
