<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104763</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104763</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mars Exploration Rovers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mars Erforschung-Vagabunden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vagabonds d'Exploration de Mars</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vagabundos Da Exploração De Marte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vagabondi Di Esplorazione Del Marte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πλάνες εξερεύνησης του Αρη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rovers De la Exploración De Marte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of Spirit and Opportunity, two rovers that are investigating the hills and craters of Mars. See an animation of Spirit's journey from launch pad to Mars. Learn about its instruments. See a slide show of the most detailed images of Mars' surface ever captured. A lesson on the distance and relative size of other planets is included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte des Geistes und der 
Gelegenheit, zwei Vagabunden, die die Hügel und die Krater von 
Mars nachforschen. Sehen Sie eine Animation der Reise des 
Geistes von der Produkteinführung Auflage zu Mars. Erlernen Sie
über seine Instrumente. Sehen Sie eine Diavorführung der 
ausführlichsten Bilder der Oberfläche Mars überhaupt erfaßt. 
Eine Lektion auf dem Abstand und der relativen Größe anderer 
Planeten ist enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire de l'esprit et de l'occasion, deux 
vagabonds qui étudient les collines et les cratères de Mars. 
Voir l'animation du voyage de l'esprit de la garniture de 
lancement à Mars. Renseignez-vous sur ses instruments. 
Voir la projection de diapositives des images les plus 
détaillées de la surface de Mars jamais capturées. Une leçon
sur la distance et la taille relative d'autres planètes est incluse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história do espírito e da oportunidade, 
dois vagabundos que estão investigando os montes e as crateras de 
Marte. Veja um animation da viagem do espírito da almofada do 
lançamento a Marte. Aprenda sobre seus instrumentos. Veja
uma mostra de corrediça das imagens as mais detalhadas da superfície
de Marte capturadas sempre. Uma lição na distância e no 
tamanho relativo de outros planetas é incluída.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia dello spirito e dell'occasione, 
due vagabondi che stanno studiando le colline ed i crateri di Marte. 
Veda una animazione del viaggio dello spirito dal rilievo del 
lancio a Marte. Impari circa i relativi strumenti. Veda 
una proiezione di diapositive delle immagini più dettagliate della 
superficie del Marte bloccate mai. Una lezione sulla distanza e 
sul formato relativo di altri pianeti è inclusa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία του πνεύματος και της ευκαιρίας, δύο
πλάνες που ερευνούν τους λόφους και τους κρατήρες του Αρη. 
Δείτε μια ζωτικότητα του ταξιδιού του πνεύματος 
από το μαξιλάρι έναρξης στον Αρη. Μάθετε για τα όργανά 
του. Δείτε μια επίδειξη φωτογραφικών διαφανειών 
των πιό λεπτομερών εικόνων της επιφάνειας του Αρη που 
συλλαμβάνονται πάντα. Ένα μάθημα στην απόσταση και το 
σχετικό μέγεθος άλλων πλανητών συμπεριλαμβάνεται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia del alcohol y de la 
oportunidad, dos rovers que estén investigando las colinas y los 
cráteres de Marte. Vea una animación del viaje del alcohol de 
la pista del lanzamiento a Marte. Aprenda sobre sus 
instrumentos. Vea una demostración de diapositiva de las 
imágenes más detalladas de la superficie de Marte capturadas 
siempre. Una lección en la distancia y la talla relativa de 
otros planetas es incluida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104763</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mars-exploration-rovers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
