<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103287</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103287</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086858</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Stranger Than Fiction?: The Reading Habits of Early Twentieth-Century Working Women</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fremder Als Erfindung?: Die Lesegewohnheiten
der frühen Zwanzigst-Jahrhundert Funktion Frauen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étranger Que La Fiction ? : Les habitudes 
de lecture de premiers travailleuses actives de Vingtième-Siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Desconhecido Do que O Fiction?: Os hábitos 
de leitura de mulheres de funcionamento adiantadas de 
Vigésimo-Século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sconosciuto Che Romanzo?: Le abitudini di 
lettura delle donne lavorarici in anticipo di Ventesimo-Secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ξένος από τη μυθιστοριογραφία;: Οι συνήθειες 
ανάγνωσης των πρώτων εργαζόμενων γυναικών εικοστός-αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Extranjero Que La Ficción?: Los hábitos de
lectura de las mujeres de funcionamiento tempranas del 
Vige'simo-Siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although middle- and upper-class observers viewed the leisure habits of working-class women with condescension, few of them actually knew much about what working women did with their spare time. One exception was Dorothy Richardson, a woman from a middle-class Iowa family who had to work in a factory to support herself. In 1905, she published a fictionalized version of her experiences under the title,  The Long Day . In this excerpt, she described a discussion among her fellow workers about their favorite novels and music. Despite her disdainful view of their interest in "ungrammatical, crude, and utterly banal . . . cheap story books," her account demonstrated the importance of popular culture in the everyday lives of women factory workers. The novel that the women discussed,  Little Rosebud's Lovers , was written in 1886 by Laura Jean Libbey, a bestselling author of popular fiction. Libbey was particularly known for placing working-girl heroines within sensational and melodramatic plots.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich mittlere und der Oberklasse Beobachter 
die Freizeitgewohnheiten der Arbeiterklassefrauen mit Herablassung 
ansahen, wußten wenige von ihnen wirklich viel über, welche Funktion
Frauen mit ihrer Ersatzzeit taten. Eine Ausnahme war Dorothy 
Richardson, eine Frau von einer Mittelklasseiowa Familie, die in einer
Fabrik arbeiten mußte, um sich zu unterstützen. 1905 
veröffentlichte sie eine erfundene Version von ihr Erfahrungen unter 
dem Namen, der lange Tag. In diesem Excerpt beschrieb sie eine 
Diskussion unter ihren Mitarbeitern über ihre Lieblingsromane und 
Musik. Trotz ihrer disdainful Ansicht ihres Interesses "an 
ungrammatical, an grobem und an äußerst banalem. . . 
preiswerte Geschichte meldet, "ihr Konto demonstrierte den Wert 
der populären Kultur in den täglichen Leben der Frauarbeiter an. 
Der Roman, den den behandelten Frauen, Geliebten wenigen 
Rosebuds, 1886 von Laura Jean Libbey geschrieben wurden, ein 
bestselling Autor der populären Erfindung. Libbey bekannt 
besonders für das Plazieren der Arbeitenmädchen Heldinnen innerhalb 
des sensational und der melodramatischen Plots.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que les observateurs moyen- et de la 
bourgeoisie aient visualisé les habitudes de loisirs des femmes de 
classe ouvrier avec la condescendance, peu d'elles ont su réellement 
beaucoup au sujet de quels travailleuses actives ont fait avec du leur
temps disponible. Une exception était Dorothy Richardson, une 
femme d'une famille de l'Iowa de classe moyenne qui a dû travailler 
dans une usine pour se supporter. En 1905, elle a édité une 
version romancée d'elle des expériences sous le titre, la longue 
journée. Dans cet extrait, elle a décrit une discussion parmi 
ses ouvriers de camarade au sujet de leurs romans et musique 
préférés. En dépit de sa vue dédaigneuse de leur intérêt 
dans "non grammatical, brut, et tout à fait banal. . . 
l'histoire bon marché réserve, "son compte a démontré 
l'importance de la culture populaire dans les vies journalières des 
ouvriers d'usine de femmes. Le roman que les femmes discutées, 
les petits amoureux de Rosebud, ont été écrit en 1886 par Laura
Jean Libbey, un auteur bestselling de la fiction populaire. 
Libbey a été en particulier connu pour placer des héroïnes 
de travailler-fille dans les traçages sensationnels et 
mélodramatiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora os observadores médios e upper-class 
vissem os hábitos do lazer de mulheres do working-class com 
condescension, poucas delas souberam realmente muito sobre que 
mulheres de funcionamento fizeram com seu tempo de reposição. 
Uma exceção era Dorothy Richardson, uma mulher de uma família
de Iowa do middle-class que tivesse que trabalhar em uma fábrica para
se suportar. Em 1905, publicou uma versão fictionalized dela 
experiências sob o título, o dia longo. Neste excerpt, 
descreveu uma discussão entre seus trabalhadores de companheiro sobre
suas novelas e música favoritas. Apesar de sua vista disdainful
de seu interesse em "ungrammatical, em cru, e em totalmente banal. 
. . a história barata registra, "seu cliente 
demonstrou a importância da cultura popular nas vidas diárias de 
trabalhadores de fábrica das mulheres. A novela que as mulheres
discutidas, amantes de pouco Rosebud, foram escritas em 1886 por Laura
Jean Libbey, um autor bestselling do fiction popular. Libbey foi
conhecido particularmente colocando heroines da trabalh-menina dentro 
do sensational e dos lotes melodramatic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se gli osservatori centrali e d'alto ceto 
hanno osservato le abitudini di svago delle donne della classe operaia
con condescension, poche di loro realmente hanno conosciuto molto 
circa che donne lavorarici hanno fatto con il loro tempo di ricambio. 
Un'eccezione era Dorothy Richardson, una donna da una famiglia 
dello Iowa della classe media che ha dovuto lavorare in una fabbrica 
per sostenersi. In 1905, ha pubblicato una versione 
fictionalized di lei esperienze sotto il titolo, il giorno lungo. 
In questo brano, ha descritto una discussione fra i suoi 
compagni di lavoro circa i loro romanzi e musica favoriti. 
Malgrado il suo punto di vista disdainful del loro interesse "in
ungrammatical, in grezzo ed in assolutamente banale. . . 
la storia poco costosa prenota, "il suo cliente ha dimostrato 
l'importanza di coltura popolare nelle vite giornalieri degli operai 
di fabbrica delle donne. Il romanzo che le donne discusse, 
Amanti di poco Rosebud, sono state scritte in 1886 da Laura Jean 
Libbey, un autore bestselling di romanzo popolare. Libbey è 
stato conosciuto specialmente per la disposizione dei heroines della 
funzion-ragazza all'interno del sensational e dei diagrammi 
melodramatic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και μέση - και οι αριστοκρατικοί παρατηρητές 
εμφάνισαν τις συνήθειες ελεύθερου χρόνου των γυναικών εργατικών 
τάξεων με τη συγκατάβαση, λίγες από τις ήξεραν πραγματικά πολύ 
για αυτό που οι εργαζόμενες γυναίκες έκαναν με τον ελεύθερο 
χρόνο τους. Μια εξαίρεση ήταν Dorothy Richardson, μια 
γυναίκα από μια οικογένεια του Iowa μεσαίων τάξεων που έπρεπε
να εργαστεί σε ένα εργοστάσιο για να υποστηριχθεί. Το 
1905, δημοσίευσε το α η έκδοση της εμπειρίας της υπό τον 
τίτλο, η μακριά ημέρα. Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα, περιέγραψε 
μια συζήτηση μεταξύ των συντροφικών εργαζομένων της για τα 
αγαπημένες μυθιστορήματα και τη μουσική τους. Παρά την 
disdainful όψη ενδιαφέροντός τους της για "ungrammatical, 
ακατέργαστος, και εντελώς κοινότοπος. .. τα φτηνά 
βιβλία ιστορίας, "ο απολογισμός της κατέδειξαν τη σημασία του 
δημοφιλούς πολιτισμού στις καθημερινές ζωές των εργαζομένων 
εργοστασίων γυναικών. Το μυθιστόρημα που οι γυναίκες 
συζήτησαν, εραστές λίγου μπουμπουκιού τριαντάφυλλου, γράφτηκε το
1886 από τη Laura Jean Libbey, ένας με εμπορική 
επιτυχία συντάκτης της δημοφιλούς μυθιστοριογραφίας. Το 
Libbey ήταν γνωστό ιδιαίτερα για την τοποθέτηση των ηρωϊ'δων 
εργάζομαι-κοριτσιών μέσα στις συγκλονιστικές και μελοδραματικές 
πλοκές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque los observadores medios y de la clase alta 
vieron los hábitos del ocio de las mujeres de la clase obrera con el 
condescension, pocas de ellas sabían realmente mucho sobre qué 
mujeres de funcionamiento hicieron con su tiempo de repuesto. 
Una anomalía era Dorothy Richardson, mujer de una familia de 
Iowa de la clase media que tuvo que trabajar en una fábrica para 
apoyarse. En 1905, ella publicó una versión fictionalized de 
ella las experiencias bajo título, el día largo. En este 
extracto, ella describió una discusión entre sus trabajadores de 
compañero sobre sus novelas y música preferidas. A pesar de su
opinión desdeñosa de su interés en "ungrammatical, crudo, y 
completamente banal. . . la historia barata reserva,
"su cuenta demostró la importancia de la cultura popular en las vidas
diarias de los trabajadores de fábrica de las mujeres. La 
novela que Laura Jean Libbey escribieron las mujeres discutidas, 
amantes de poco Rosebud, en 1886, autor bestselling de la ficción 
popular. Libbey era conocido determinado para colocar a 
heroínas de la trabajar-muchacha dentro del sensational y de 
diagramas melodramatic.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086858</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103287</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/stranger-than-fiction-the-reading-habits-of-early-twentieth-century-working-women</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
