<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106166</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106166</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086228</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hear Wilson's Speech "On Labor"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hören Sie Rede Wilsons "Auf Arbeit"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entendez Le Discours de Wilson "Sur Le Travail"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ouça O Discurso De Wilson "No Trabalho"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Senta Il Discorso Del Wilson "Sul Lavoro"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακούστε την ομιλία Wilson "στην εργασία"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Oiga El Discurso De Wilson "En Trabajo"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The 1912 presidential election featured four candidates: Republican incumbent William Howard Taft, Democratic Governor Woodrow Wilson, former President Theodore Roosevelt representing the breakaway Bull Moose party, and Socialist Party candidate Eugene Debs, who was making his fourth run for President. All four presidential candidates appealed directly to working-class voters, who proved pivotal to the outcome. Voter interest, already piqued by the unusual campaign and the candidates' slashing attacks on one another, was further heightened by the availability of sound recordings of campaign addresses and, for the first time, film footage of the candidates on the campaign trail. In this campaign speech, Wilson argued against a minimum wage for women workers and called for the end of business monopolies. Wilson was the eventual winner, with over six million popular and 435 electoral votes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Präsidentenwahl 1912 kennzeichnete vier 
Anwärter: Republikanischer Amtsinhaber William Howard Taft, 
demokratischer Regler Woodrow Wilson, ehemaliger Präsident Theodore 
Roosevelt, welches die abgespaltene Bull ElchPartei und 
sozialistischen Parteianwärter Eugene Debs darstellt, der seinen 
vierten Durchlauf für Präsidenten bildete. Alle vier 
Präsidentenanwärter gefallen direkt Arbeiterklassewählern, die 
Angel zum Resultat prüften. Wählerinteresse, piqued bereits 
durch die ungewöhnliche Kampagne und die schneidenden Angriffe auf 
einem andere der Anwärter, wurden weiter durch die Verwendbarkeit der
Tonaufnahmen der Kampagne Adressen und zum ersten Mal der 
Filmgesamtlänge der Anwärter auf der Kampagne Spur erhöht. In
dieser Wahlrede Wilson argumentiert gegen einen minimalen Lohn für 
Frauarbeiter und das Ende der Geschäft Monopole verlangt. 
Wilson war der etwaige Sieger, mit über sechs Million 
populären und 435 Wahlstimmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élection 1912 présidentielle a comporté 
quatre candidats : Candidat sortant républicain William 
Howard Taft, Gouverneur démocratique Woodrow Wilson, l'ancien 
Président Theodore Roosevelt représentant la partie détachée 
d'orignaux de Bull, et le candidat Eugene Debs de parti socialiste, 
qui faisait son quatrième passage pour le président. Chacun 
des quatre candidats présidentiels faits directement appel aux 
électeurs de classe ouvrière, qui ont prouvé pivotal aux 
résultats. L'intérêt d'électeur, piqued déjà par la 
campagne peu commune et les attaques de réduction sur une des autres 
des candidats, ont été encore intensifiées par la disponibilité 
des enregistrements sonores des adresses de campagne et, pour la 
première fois, de la longueur de film des candidats sur la traînée 
de campagne. Dans ce discours de campagne, Wilson discuté 
contre un salaire minimum pour des ouvrières de femmes et nécessité
la fin des monopoles d'affaires. Wilson était le gagnant 
certain, avec plus de six millions de voix populaires et 435 
électorales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A eleição 1912 presidencial caracterizou quatro 
candidatos: Encarregado republicano William Howard Taft, 
regulador democrático Woodrow Wilson, presidente anterior Theodore 
Roosevelt que representa o partido breakaway dos alces de Bull, e o 
candidato Eugene Debs do partido socialist, que fazia seu quarto 
funcionamento para o presidente. Todos os quatro candidatos 
presidenciais apelados diretamente aos eleitores do working-class, que
provaram pivotal ao resultado. O interesse do eleitor, piqued 
já pela campanha incomun e os ataques slashing em um outros dos 
candidatos, heightened mais mais pela disponibilidade de gravações 
sadias de endereços da campanha e, para a primeira vez, de footage da
película dos candidatos na fuga da campanha. Neste discurso de 
campanha, Wilson discutido de encontro a um salário mínimo para 
trabalhadores das mulheres e chamado para o fim de monopólios do 
negócio. Wilson era o vencedor eventual, com sobre seis milhão
votos populares e 435 electoral.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'elezione presidenziale 1912 ha caratterizzato 
quattro candidati: Il incumbent repubblicano William Howard Taft, 
il regolatore democratico Woodrow Wilson, l'ex presidente Theodore 
Roosevelt che rappresenta il partito staccato delle alci del Bull ed 
il candidato Eugene Debs, che del partito socialista stava facendo il 
suo quarto funziona per il presidente. Tutti e quattro i 
candidati presidenziali hanno fatto appello direttamente agli elettori
della classe operaia, che hanno dimostrato chiave al risultato. 
L'interesse dell'elettore, già piqued dalla campagna insolita e
gli attacchi riducenti ad uno un altro dei candidati, più 
ulteriormente sono stati intensificati dalla disponibilità delle 
registrazioni del suono degli indirizzi di campagna e, per la prima 
volta, del metraggio della pellicola dei candidati alla traccia di 
campagna. In questo discorso di campagna, Wilson discusso contro
uno stipendio minimo per gli operai delle donne e richiesto la 
conclusione dei monopolii di affari. Wilson era il vincitore 
finale, con oltre sei milione voti popolari e 435 elettorali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προεδρική εκλογή του 1912 χαρακτήρισε τέσσερις 
υποψηφίους: Δημοκρατικός επιβεβλημένος William Howard 
Taft, δημοκρατικός κυβερνήτης Woodrow Wilson, προηγούμενος
Πρόεδρος Theodore Roosevelt που αντιπροσωπεύει το αποσπασθέν 
συμβαλλόμενο μέρος αλκών του Bull, και το σοσιαλιστικό 
υποψήφιο Eugene Debs συμβαλλόμενου μέρους, που έκανε το 
τέταρτό του τρέχει για τον Πρόεδρο. Και οι τέσσερις 
προεδρικοί υποψήφιοι απευθύνθηκαν άμεσα στους ψηφοφόρους 
εργατικών τάξεων, οι οποίοι αποδείχθηκαν κεντρικοί στην έκβαση. 
Το ενδιαφέρον ψηφοφόρων, ήδη από την ασυνήθιστη εκστρατεία
και οι επιθέσεις κοψίματος των υποψηφίων στο ένα άλλη, υψώθηκαν 
περαιτέρω από τη διαθεσιμότητα των υγιών καταγραφών των 
διευθύνσεων εκστρατείας και, για πρώτη φορά, του μήκους σε πόδηα
ταινιών των υποψηφίων στο ίχνος εκστρατείας. Σε αυτήν την 
ομιλία εκστρατείας, Wilson μίλησε ενάντια σε έναν βασικό 
μισθό για τους εργαζομένους γυναικών και απαιτήθηκε το τέλος των 
επιχειρησιακών μονοπωλίων. Θ*Ωηλσον ήταν ο ενδεχόμενος 
νικητής, με πάνω από έξι εκατομμύρια δημοφιλείς και 435 
εκλογικές ψήφους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La elección presidencial 1912 ofreció a cuatro 
candidatos: Titular republicano Guillermo Howard Taft, 
gobernador democrático Woodrow Wilson, presidente anterior Theodore 
Roosevelt que representa al partido disidente de los alces de Bull, y 
al candidato Eugene Debs del partido socialista, que hacía su cuarto 
funcionamiento para el presidente. Los cuatro candidatos 
presidenciales abrogados directamente a los votantes de la clase 
obrera, que probaron giratorio al resultado. El interés del 
votante, piqued ya por la campaña inusual y los ataques de reducción
radical contra uno otros de los candidatos, fueron aumentados más a 
fondo por la disponibilidad de las grabaciones de sonidos de los 
direccionamientos de la campaña y, para la primera vez, de la 
cantidad de la película de los candidatos contra el rastro de la 
campaña. En este discurso de campaña, Wilson discutido contra 
un salario mínimo para los trabajadores de las mujeres y llamado para
el final de los monopolios del negocio. Wilson era el ganador 
eventual, con sobre seis millones de votos populares y 435 
electorales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086228</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106166</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hear-wilsons-speech-on-labor</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
