<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104325</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104325</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206389</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Battle of Oriskany: Blood Shed a Stream Running Down</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schlacht von Oriskany: Blut-Halle ein 
Strom, der unten läuft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La bataille d'Oriskany : Hangar de sang un 
jet se déchargeant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A batalha de Oriskany: Vertente do sangue um
córrego que funciona para baixo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La battaglia di Oriskany: Tettoia di anima 
un flusso che funziona giù</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μάχη Oriskany: Το αίμα έριξε έναν 
περιορισμό ρευμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La batalla de Oriskany: Vertiente de la 
sangre una secuencia que se ejecuta abajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells how long-standing prejudices and the Revolutionary War unleashed massive bloodshed among inhabitants of New York's Mohawk Valley. Located in rich farmland and at a strategic point in a fur trade route, the valley had been settled by European immigrants who had prospered from productive farms and lucrative trade. As war broke out, everyone had to choose sides: Rebel or Tory. It was not easy for many. Five hundred years of unity among the Six Nations was broken.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt, wie althergebrachte Vorurteile und der 
revolutionäre Krieg massives Blutvergießen unter Einwohnern von New 
York mohikanischer Senke unleashed. Gefunden im reichen 
Ackerland und an einem strategischen Punkt in einem Pelzhandel Weg, 
war die Senke von den European Immigranten vereinbart worden, die sich
von den produktiven Bauernhöfen und vom lukrativen Handel erweitert 
hatten. Während Krieg ausbrach, mußte jeder Seiten wählen: 
Aufrührer oder Tory. Es war nicht für viele einfach. 
Fünfhundert Jahre Einheit unter den sechs Nationen waren 
unterbrochen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit comment les préjudices de longue date et la 
guerre révolutionnaire ont lâché le carnage massif parmi des 
habitants de la vallée mohicanne de New York. Situé dans les 
champs riches et à un point stratégique dans un itinéraire du 
commerce de fourrure, la vallée avait été arrangée par les 
immigrés d'European qui avaient prospéré des fermes productives et 
du commerce lucratif. Pendant que la guerre éclatait, chacun a 
dû choisir des côtés : Rebelle ou Conservateur. Il 
n'était pas facile pour beaucoup. Cinq cents ans d'unité parmi
les six nations étaient cassés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz como os preconceitos long-standing e a guerra 
revolucionária desencadearam o bloodshed maciço entre habitantes do 
vale mohawk de New York. Localizado na terra rica e em um ponto 
estratégico em uma rota do comércio da pele, o vale tinha sido 
estabelecido pelos immigrants de Europeu que prospered das fazendas 
produtivas e do comércio lucrative. Enquanto a guerra quebrou 
para fora, todos teve que escolher lados: Rebel ou tory. 
Não era fácil para muitos. Cinco cem anos da unidade 
entre as seis nações eram quebrados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a come i pregiudizi di vecchia data e la 
guerra rivoluzionaria hanno liberato il massacro voluminoso fra gli 
abitanti della valle mohawk de New York. Individuato in terreno 
coltivabile ricco e ad un punto strategico in un itinerario di 
commercio della pelliccia, la valle era stata depositata dagli 
immigranti della European che avevano fatto prosperare dai poderi 
produttivi e dal commercio lucrativo. Mentre la guerra ha 
scoppiato, tutta ha dovuto scegliere i lati: Ribelle o 
tory. Non era facile per molti. Cinquecento anni di unità
fra le sei nazioni erano rotti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει πώς οι από μακρού υφιστάμενες προκαταλήψεις και
ο επαναστατικός πόλεμος εξαπέλυσαν την ογκώδη αιματοχυσία μεταξύ
των κατοίκων της κοιλάδας Mohawk της Νέας Υόρκης. 
Τοποθετημένη στο πλούσιο καλλιεργήσιμο έδαφος και σε ένα 
στρατηγικό σημείο σε έναν εμπορικό δρόμο γουνών, η κοιλάδα 
ήταν εγκατεστημένη από τους ευρωπαϊκούς μετανάστες που είχαν 
ευημερήσει από τα παραγωγικά αγροκτήματα και το προσοδοφόρο 
εμπόριο. Δεδομένου ότι ο πόλεμος ξέσπησε, ο καθένας 
έπρεπε να επιλέξει τις πλευρές: Επαναστάτης ή tory. 
Δεν ήταν εύκολο για πολλούς. Πεντακόσια έτη ενότητας
μεταξύ των έξι εθνών ήταν σπασμένα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice cómo los prejudicar de muchos años y la 
guerra revolucionaria destraillaron matanza masiva entre habitantes 
del valle mohawk de Nueva York. Localizado en tierras de 
labrantío ricas y en una punta estratégica en una ruta del comercio 
de la piel, el valle había sido colocado por los inmigrantes european
que habían prosperado de granjas productivas y de comercio lucrativo.
Mientras que explotó la guerra, cada una tuvo que elegir caras:
Rebelde o tory. No era fácil para muchos. Cinco 
cientos años de unidad entre las seis naciones estaban quebrados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206389</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104325</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-battle-of-oriskany-blood-shed-a-stream-running-down</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
