<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103491</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103491</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086768</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Pure and Simple": Making the Case for Unionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"rein und einfach": Bilden des Arguments 
für Unionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"pur et simple" : Fabrication du point de 
droit pour le Syndicalisme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"puro e simples": Fazendo o argumento para 
Unionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"puro e semplice": Dimostrare il fondatezza 
di Unionism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Καθαρός και απλόσ": Υποστήριξη των 
επιχειρημάτων για το συνδικαλισμό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"puro y simple": Fabricación del caso para 
Unionism</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Whereas the Knights of Labor had advocated "abolition of the wages system," union leaders who coalesced behind Samuel Gompers and the new American Federation of Labor in 1886 were more likely to accept the terms of the existing capitalist system. Gompers and his closest associates rejected any interest in creating a new society. Instead, they called for a better life for working people. Adolph Strasser, a leader of the cigarmakers' union, clearly articulated this emerging philosophy of "pure and simple unionism" in his 1883 testimony before the U.S. Senate Committee on Education and Labor, which was investigating the "relations between capital and labor." Strasser had emigrated to America around 1871. In the early 1880s--around the time of this testimony--he allied with Gompers in refusing to turn over New York's United Cigarmakers union to socialists who had been democratically elected. Instead, he and Gompers expelled the leader of the socialists and caused a serious split in the union. Strasser remained an AFL leader and organizer until his death in 1910.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während die Ritter der Arbeit "Aufhebung des 
Lohnsystems befürwortet hatten," waren Anschlußführer, die hinter 
Samuel Gompers und die neue amerikanische Vereinigung von der Arbeit 
in 1886 verschmolzen, wahrscheinlicher, die Bedingungen des 
vorhandenen Kapitalistsystems zu akzeptieren. Gompers und seine 
nähsten Teilnehmer wiesen jedes mögliches Interesse zurück, an, 
eine neue Gesellschaft zu erstellen. Stattdessen verlangten sie 
eine bessere Lebensdauer für Arbeitsleute. Adolph Strasser, ein
Führer des Anschlußes der cigarmakers', artikulierte offenbar diese 
auftauchende Philosophie "des reinen und einfachen unionism" in seinem
Zeugnis 1883, bevor der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senat-Ausschuß für 
Ausbildung und Arbeit, die nachforschte die "Relationen zwischen 
Haupt- und Arbeits." Strasser war nach Amerika um 1871 
ausgewandert. Im frühen 1880s -- um die Zeit dieses Zeugnisses 
-- er verband mit Gompers beim Ablehnen, vereinigten Anschluß 
Cigarmakers New York zu den Sozialisten umzudrehen, die demokratisch 
gewählt worden waren. Stattdessen trieben er und Gompers den 
Führer der Sozialisten weg und verursachten eine ernste Spalte im 
Anschluß. Strasser blieb ein AFL Führer und Organisator bis 
seinen Tod 1910.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Considérant que les chevaliers du travail avaient
préconisé l'"abolition du système de salaires," les amorces des 
syndicats qui ont fusionné derrière Samuel Gompers et la nouvelle 
fédération américaine du travail dans 1886 étaient pour recevoir 
les limites du système existant de capitaliste. Gompers et ses 
associés plus étroits ont rejeté n'importe quel intérêt en 
créant une nouvelle société. Au lieu de cela, ils ont 
nécessité une meilleure vie pour les personnes travaillantes. 
Adolph Strasser, une amorce de l'union des cigarmakers, a 
clairement articulé cette philosophie naissante "de syndicalisme pur et
simple" dans son témoignage 1883 avant que le comité de sénat des 
ETATS-UNIS de l'éducation et du travail, qui étudiait les "relations
entre capital et de travail." Strasser avait émigré en 
Amérique autour de 1871. Dans le 1880s tôt -- autour de la 
période de ce témoignage -- il s'est allié avec Gompers en refusant
de retourner l'union unie de Cigarmakers de New York aux socialistes 
qui avaient été démocratiquement élus. Au lieu de cela, lui 
et Gompers ont expulsé l'amorce des socialistes et ont causé un 
fractionnement sérieux dans l'union. Strasser est resté une 
amorce et organisateur d'AFL jusqu'à sa mort en 1910.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Visto que os knights do trabalho tinham advogado o
"abolition do sistema dos salários," os líderes da união que 
coalesceram atrás de Samuel Gompers e o federation americano novo do 
trabalho em 1886 eram mais prováveis aceitar os termos do sistema 
existente do capitalista. Gompers e seus associados mais 
próximos rejeitaram todo o interesse em criar uma sociedade nova. 
Instead, chamaram-se por uma vida melhor para povos trabalhando.
Adolph Strasser, um líder da união dos cigarmakers', articulou
claramente esta filosofia emergente "do unionism puro e simples" em 
seu testimony 1883 antes que o comitê do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na 
instrução e no trabalho, que investigava as "relações entre 
importante e labor." Strasser emigrated a América em torno de 
1871. No 1880s adiantado -- em torno da época deste testimony 
-- aliou-se com o Gompers em recusar virar a união unida de 
Cigarmakers de New York para os socialists que tinham sido elegidos 
democràtica. Instead, e Gompers expeliram o líder dos 
socialists e causaram um split sério na união. Strasser 
remanesceu um líder e organizer de AFL até sua morte em 1910.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Considerando che i cavalieri del Lavoro 
avevano sostenuto "l'abolizione del sistema degli stipendi," i 
capi del sindacato che si sono uniti dietro Samuel Gompers e la
nuova federazione americana del Lavoro in 1886 erano più 
probabili accettare i termini del sistema attuale del capitalista. 
Gompers ed i suoi soci più vicini hanno rifiutato tutto 
l'interesse nella creazione della società nuova. Invece, hanno 
richiesto una vita migliore per la gente lavorante. Adolph 
Strasser, un capo dell'unione dei cigarmakers, ha articolato 
chiaramente questa filosofia d'emersione "del unionism puro e 
semplice" nella sua testimonianza 1883 prima del comitato del senato 
degli STATI UNITI di formazione e del Lavoro, che stava studiando
"i rapporti fra capitale ed il lavoro." Strasser aveva 
emigrato in America verso 1871. Nel 1880s iniziale -- intorno al
periodo di questa testimonianza -- si è alleato con Gompers nel 
rifiuto girare l'unione unita di Cigarmakers de New York ai socialisti
che democratico erano stati scelti. Invece, lui e Gompers hanno 
espulso il capo dei socialisti ed hanno causato una spaccatura 
seria nell'unione. Strasser è rimasto un capo ed 
organizzatore di AFL fino alla sua morte in 1910.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκτιμώντας ότι οι ιππότες της εργασίας είχαν 
υποστηρίξει "την κατάργηση του συστήματος αμοιβών," οι ηγέτες 
ένωσης που συγχωνεύτηκαν πίσω από το Samuel Gompers και τη 
νέα αμερικανική ομοσπονδία της εργασίας το 1886 ήταν 
πιθανότερο να αποδεχθούν τους όρους του υπάρχοντος 
κεφαλαιοκρατικού συστήματος. Το Gompers και οι πιό στενοί
συνεταίροι του απέρριψαν οποιοδήποτε ενδιαφέρον για τη δημιουργία
μιας νέας κοινωνίας. Αντ' αυτού, απαίτησαν μια καλύτερη 
ζωή για τους εργαζόμενους ανθρώπους. Το Adolph 
Strasser, ένας ηγέτης της ένωσης των cigarmakers, άρθρωσε 
σαφώς αυτήν την αναδυόμενη φιλοσοφία του "καθαρού και απλού 
συνδικαλισμού" στην κατάθεση 1883 του ενώπιον της Επιτροπής 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου της εκπαίδευσης και της εργασίας, η οποία 
ερευνούσε τις "σχέσεις μεταξύ του κεφαλαίου και της εργασίας." 
Το Strasser είχε μεταναστεύσει στην Αμερική περίπου 
1871. Στο πρόωρο 1880s -- γύρω από το χρόνο αυτής της
κατάθεσης -- σύνδεσε με Gompers στην άρνηση να αναποδογυριστεί 
η ενωμένη ένωση Cigarmakers της Νέας Υόρκης στους σοσιαλιστές 
που ήταν εκλεγμένων δημοκρατικά. Αντ' αυτού, αυτός και 
Gompers απέβαλαν τον ηγέτη των σοσιαλιστών και προκάλεσαν μια 
σοβαρή διάσπαση στην ένωση. Το Strasser παρέμεινε ηγέτης
AFL και διοργανωτής μέχρι το θάνατό του το 1910.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que los caballeros del trabajo habían 
abogado la "abolición del sistema de los salarios," los arranques de 
cinta de la unión que se unieron detrás de Samuel Gompers y la nueva
federación americana de trabajo en 1886 eran más probables validar 
los términos del sistema existente del capitalista. Gompers y 
sus asociados más cercanos rechazaron cualquier interés en crear a 
una nueva sociedad. En lugar, llamaron por una vida mejor para 
la gente de trabajo. Adolph Strasser, arranque de cinta de la 
unión de los cigarmakers, articuló claramente esta filosofía que 
emergía "del unionism puro y simple" en su testimonio 1883 antes de 
que el comité del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre la educación y el 
trabajo, que investigaba las "relaciones entre capital y de trabajo." 
Strasser había emigrado a América alrededor de 1871. 
En el 1880s temprano -- alrededor de la época de este 
testimonio -- él se alió con Gompers en el rechazo volcar la unión 
unida de Cigarmakers de Nueva York a los socialistas que democrático 
habían sido elegidos. En lugar, él y Gompers expelieron a 
arranque de cinta de los socialistas y causaron una fractura seria en 
la unión. Strasser seguía siendo un arranque de cinta y 
organizador de AFL hasta su muerte en 1910.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086768</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103491</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/pure-and-simple-making-the-case-for-unionism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
