<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103867</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103867</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201831</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Numbers Behind Hunger: Calorie Counting </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Zahlen Hinter Hunger: Kalorie-Zählen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Nombres Derrière La Faim : Compte de 
Calorie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Números Atrás Da Fome: Contagem Do 
Calorie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I Numeri Dietro Fame: Conteggio Di Caloria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αριθμοί πίσω από την πείνα: Υπολογισμός 
θερμίδας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Números Detrás Del Hambre: Cuenta De 
la Caloría</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Following are a series of activities in which students apply various math skills to better understand the problems of world hunger and what steps are being taken to reduce the number of people without enough to eat. This activity makes use of basic math skills to learn more about the energy value of food. A link to the US Dept. of Agriculture National Nutrient Database is listed here. Teachers may want to browse through the database first and determine the best way to present it to students: let them explore the entire database or make a condensed chart for students to reference. This activity is #5 of 5 in this lesson. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Folgen sind eine Reihe Aktivitäten, in denen 
Kursteilnehmer verschiedene Mathefähigkeiten anwenden, um die 
Probleme Welthunger besser zu verstehen und in welchen Jobsteps 
unternommen werden, um die Zahl Leuten ohne genug zu verringern, um zu
essen. Diese Aktivität gebraucht grundlegende 
Mathefähigkeiten, um mehr über den Energiewert der Nahrung zu 
erlernen. Ein Link zur US Abt. Landwirtschaft der nationalen 
Nährdatenbank wird hier ausgedruckt. Lehrer können durch die 
Datenbank zuerst durchstöbern und die beste Methode feststellen 
wünschen, sie Kursteilnehmern darzustellen: lassen Sie sie die 
gesamte Datenbank erforschen oder ein verkürztes Diagramm lassen, 
damit Kursteilnehmer ansprechen. Diese Aktivität ist #5 von 5 
in dieser Lektion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Suivre une série d'activités dans lesquelles les
étudiants appliquent de diverses qualifications de maths pour 
comprendre mieux les problèmes de la faim du monde et quelles mesures
sont prises pour réduire le nombre de personnes sans assez pour 
manger. Cette activité se sert des qualifications de base de 
maths pour apprendre plus au sujet de la valeur d'énergie de la 
nourriture. Un lien au service des USA de la base de données 
nutritive nationale d'agriculture est énuméré ici. Les 
professeurs peuvent vouloir parcourir par la base de données d'abord 
et déterminer la meilleure voie de la présenter aux étudiants : 
laissez-les explorer la base de données entière ou faire un 
diagramme condensé pour que les étudiants mettent en référence. 
Cette activité est #5 de 5 dans cette leçon.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Seguir é uma série das atividades em que os 
estudantes aplicam várias habilidades do math para compreender mais 
melhor os problemas da fome do mundo e no que etapas estão sendo 
feitas exame para reduzir o número dos povos sem bastantes para 
comer. Esta atividade emprega habilidades básicas do math para 
aprender mais sobre o valor da energia do alimento. Uma 
ligação ao dept. dos E. U. da base de dados nutriente nacional da 
agricultura é alistada aqui. Os professores podem querer browse
primeiramente através da base de dados e determinar a mais melhor 
maneira apresentá-la aos estudantes: deixe-os explorar a base 
de dados inteira ou fazer uma carta condensada para que os estudantes 
reference. Esta atividade é #5 de 5 nesta lição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Segue una serie di attività in cui gli allievi 
applicano le varie abilità di per la matematica per capire più 
meglio i problemi di fame del mondo ed in che misure stanno prendende 
per ridurre il numero di gente senza abbastanza per mangiare. 
Questa attività usa le abilità di base di per la matematica 
per imparare più circa il valore di energia di alimento. Un 
collegamento al servizio degli Stati Uniti della base di dati 
nutriente nazionale di agricoltura è elencato qui. Gli 
insegnanti possono desiderare passare in rassegna attraverso la base 
di dati in primo luogo e determinare il modo migliore presentarlo agli
allievi: lascilo esplorare l'intera base di dati o fare una 
tabella condensata affinchè gli allievi si riferiscano. Questa 
attività è #5 di 5 in questa lezione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρακάτω είναι μια σειρά δραστηριοτήτων στην οποία οι
σπουδαστές εφαρμόζουν τις διάφορες δεξιότητες math για να 
καταλάβουν καλύτερα τα προβλήματα της παγκόσμιας πείνας και ποια 
μέτρα λαμβάνονται για να μειώσουν τον αριθμό ανθρώπων χωρίς 
αρκετούς να φάνε. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα χρησιμοποιεί τις 
βασικές δεξιότητες math για να μάθει περισσότερους για την 
ενεργειακή αξία των τροφίμων. Μια σύνδεση με το αμερικανικό
τμήμα της εθνικής θρεπτικής βάσης δεδομένων γεωργίας 
παρατίθεται εδώ. Οι δάσκαλοι μπορούν να θελήσουν να 
περιοδεύσουν μέσω της βάσης δεδομένων πρώτα και να καθορίσουν 
τον καλύτερο τρόπο να το παρουσιάσουν στους σπουδαστές: τους
αφήστε να εξερευνήσουν την ολόκληρη βάση δεδομένων ή να κάνουν 
ένα συμπυκνωμένο διάγραμμα για τους σπουδαστές στην αναφορά. 
Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι #5 5 σε αυτό το μάθημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los siguientes son una serie de actividades en las
cuales los estudiantes apliquen varias habilidades de la matemáticas 
para entender mejor los problemas del hambre del mundo y qué medidas 
se están tomando para reducir el número de la gente sin bastantes 
para comer. Esta actividad hace uso habilidades básicas de la 
matemáticas para aprender más sobre el valor de la energía del 
alimento. Una conexión al departamento de los E.E.U.U. de la 
base de datos nutriente nacional de la agricultura se enumera aquí. 
Los profesores pueden desear hojear a través de la base de 
datos primero y determinar la mejor manera de presentarla a los 
estudiantes: déjelos explorar la base de datos entera o hacer 
una carta condensada para que los estudiantes se refieran. Esta 
actividad es #5 de 5 en esta lección.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201831</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103867</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-numbers-behind-hunger-calorie-counting</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
