<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108392</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108392</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086394</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Landon in a Landslide: The Poll That Changed Polling</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Landon in einem Erdrutsch: Die 
Abstimmung, Die Wahl Änderte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Landon dans un éboulement : Le Balayage Qui
A changé l'Interrogation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Landon em um landslide: A Votação Que 
Mudou A Votação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Landon in un landslide: Lo Scrutinio Che Ha 
cambiato La Votazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Landon σε μια καθίζηση εδάφους: Η ψηφοφορία 
που άλλαξε την ψηφοφορία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Landon en un derrumbamiento: La Encuesta Que
Cambió La Interrogación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The 1936 presidential election proved a decisive battle, not only in shaping the nation's political future but for the future of opinion polling. The  Literary Digest,  the venerable magazine founded in 1890, had correctly predicted the outcomes of the 1916, 1920, 1924, 1928, and 1932 elections by conducting polls. These polls were a lucrative venture for the magazine: readers liked them; newspapers played them up; and each "ballot" included a subscription blank. The 1936 postal card poll claimed to have asked one forth of the nation's voters which candidate they intended to vote for. In  Literary Digest 's October 31 issue, based on more than 2,000,000 returned post cards, it issued its prediction: Republican presidential candidate Alfred Landon would win 57 percent of the popular vote and 370 electoral votes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Präsidentenwahl 1936 prüfte eine 
entscheidende Schlacht, nicht nur im Formen der politischen Zukunft 
der Nation aber während der Zukunft der Meinung Wahl. 
Die literarische Auswahl, die venerable Zeitschrift, die 1890 
gegründet wurde, hatte richtig die Resultate der 1916, 1920, 1924, 
1928 und 1932 Wahlen vorausgesagt, indem sie Abstimmungen leitete. 
Diese Abstimmungen waren ein lukratives Wagnis für die 
Zeitschrift: Leser mochten sie; Zeitungen spielten sie 
oben; und jeder "Stimmzettel" schloß ein Zeichnungsformular 
ein. Die Postkarte 1936 Abstimmung behauptete, weiter gefragt zu
haben einen von die Wähler, sie, für der Nation beabsichtigten 
welchen Anwärter zu wählen. In der literarischen Auswahl ' s 
Oktober 31 die Ausgabe, basiert auf mehr als 2.000.000 
zurückgebrachten Pfostenkarten, gab sie seine Vorhersage heraus: 
Republikanischer Präsidentenanwärter Alfred Landon würde 57 
Prozent der populären Stimme und 370 Wahlstimmen gewinnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élection 1936 présidentielle a prouvé une 
bataille décisive, non seulement en formant le futur politique de la 
nation mais pour le futur de l'interrogation d'opinion. Le 
sommaire littéraire, le magasin vénérable fondé en 1890, avait 
correctement prévu les résultats des 1916, 1920, 1924, 1928, et 1932
élections en conduisant des balayages. Ces balayages étaient 
une entreprise lucrative pour le magasin : les lecteurs les ont 
aimés ; les journaux les ont joués vers le haut ; et 
chaque "vote" a inclus un blanc d'abonnement. Le balayage postal
de la carte 1936 a prétendu avoir demandé un en avant derrière les 
électeurs de la nation pour quel candidat ils ont eu l'intention de 
voter. Issue de s octobre 31 en sommaire littéraire ', basée 
sur plus de 2.000.000 cartes retournées de poteau, il a émis sa 
prévision : Le candidat présidentiel républicain Alfred 
Landon gagnerait 57 pour cent de la voix populaire et de 370 voix 
électorales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A eleição 1936 presidencial provou uma batalha 
decisive, não somente em dar forma ao futuro político da nação mas
para o futuro da votação da opinião. O sumário literário, o
compartimento venerable fundado em 1890, tinha predito corretamente os
resultados das 1916, 1920, 1924, 1928, e 1932 eleições conduzindo 
votações. Estas votações eram um risco lucrative para o 
compartimento: os leitores gostaram d; os jornais 
jogaram-nos acima; e cada "cédula" incluiu um espaço em branco
de subscrição. A votação postala do cartão 1936 reivindicou
ter perguntado adiante um dos eleitores da nação que candidato 
pretenderam votar para. Edição de s outubro 31 no sumário 
literário ', baseada em mais de 2.000.000 cartões retornados do 
borne, emitiu sua predição: O candidato presidencial 
republicano Alfred Landon ganharia 57 por cento do voto popular e de 
370 votos electoral.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'elezione presidenziale 1936 ha dimostrato una 
battaglia decisiva, non soltanto nella modellatura del futuro politico
della nazione ma per il futuro di votazione di opinione. La 
raccolta letteraria, lo scomparto venerable fondato in 1890, aveva 
predetto correttamente i risultati delle 1916, 1920, 1924, 1928 e 1932
elezioni conducendo lo scrutinio. Questo scrutinio era 
un'impresa lucrativa per lo scomparto: i lettori lo hanno 
gradito; i giornali lo hanno giocati in su; ed ogni 
"scheda elettorale" ha incluso uno spazio in bianco di abbonamento. 
Lo scrutinio postale della scheda 1936 ha sostenuto chiedere uno
avanti adegli elettori della nazione quale candidato hanno inteso 
votare per. In edizione di s il 31 di raccolta letteraria 
'ottobre, basata su più di 2.000.000 schedi restituite dell'alberino,
ha pubblicato la relativa previsione: Il candidato presidenziale
repubblicano Alfred Landon vincerebbe 57 per cento del voto popolare e 
di 370 voti elettorali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προεδρική εκλογή του 1936 απέδειξε μια 
αποφασιστική μάχη, όχι μόνο στη διαμόρφωση του πολιτικού 
μέλλοντος του έθνους αλλά για το μέλλον της ψηφοφορίας άποψης. 
Η λογοτεχνική αφομοίωση, το σεβάσμιο περιοδικό που ιδρύθηκε
το 1890, είχε προβλέψει σωστά τις εκβάσεις το 1916 ..1920
..1924 ..1928, και τις εκλογές του 1932 με τη διεύθυνση των
ψηφοφοριών. Αυτές οι ψηφοφορίες ήταν μια προσοδοφόρα 
επιχείρηση για το περιοδικό: οι αναγνώστες τους συμπάθησαν  
οι εφημερίδες τους έπαιξαν επάνω  και κάθε "ψήφοσ" 
περιέλαβε ένα κενό συνδρομής. Η ψηφοφορία καρτών του 
1936 ταχυδρομική υποστήριξε ότι έχει ρωτήσει τον έναν εμπρός
από τους ψηφοφόρους του έθνους για τον οποίο ο υποψήφιος αυτοί 
σκόπευε να ψηφίσει. Στη λογοτεχνική αφομοίωση "s 31 
Οκτωβρίου το ζήτημα, βασισμένο σε περισσότερες από 2.000.000 
επιστρεφόμενες μετα κάρτες, αυτό εξέδωσε την πρόβλεψή του: 
Ο δημοκρατικός προεδρικός υποψήφιος Alfred Landon θα 
κέρδιζε 57 τοις εκατό δημοφιλούς ψηφοφορίας και 370 
εκλογικών ψήφων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La elección presidencial 1936 probó una batalla 
decisiva, no solamente en formar el futuro político de la nación 
pero para el futuro de la interrogación de la opinión. El 
resumen literario, el compartimiento venerable fundado en 1890, había
predicho correctamente los resultados de las 1916, 1920, 1924, 1928, y
1932 elecciones conduciendo encuestas. Estas encuestas eran una 
empresa lucrativa para el compartimiento: los programas de 
lectura tuvieron gusto de ellas; los periódicos los jugaron 
para arriba; y cada "balota" incluyó un espacio en blanco de 
suscripción. La encuesta postal de la tarjeta 1936 demandó 
haber preguntado uno adelante a los votantes de la nación por qué 
candidato se prepusieron votar. En edición de s de octubre el 
31 del resumen literario ', basada en más de 2.000.000 tarjetas 
vueltas del poste, publicó su predicción: El candidato 
presidencial republicano Alfred Landon ganaría 57 por ciento del voto
popular y de 370 votos electorales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086394</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108392</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/landon-in-a-landslide-the-poll-that-changed-polling</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
