<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105243</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105243</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087038</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Right to Housing Is a Civil Right Due Without Discrimination": Racial Bias in Public and Private Housing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das Recht zum Gehäuse ist ein Zivilrecht, das 
ohne Unterscheidung" passend ist: Rassische Vorspannung im 
allgemeinen und privaten Gehäuse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la droite au logement est un droit civique dû 
sans discrimination" : Polarisation raciale dans le logement 
public et privé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a direita à carcaça é uma direita civil devida
sem discriminação": Polarização racial na carcaça pública 
e confidencial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la destra ad alloggiamento è una destra civile 
dovuta senza distinzione": Polarizzazione razziale in edilizia 
pubblica e privata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το δικαίωμα στην κατοικία είναι ένα αστικό δικαίωμα
που οφείλεται χωρίς διάκριση": Φυλετική πόλωση στη δημόσια
και ιδιωτική κατοικία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la derecha a la cubierta un correcto civil debido
sin la discriminación": Diagonal racial en la cubierta pública
y privada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The New Deal Public Works Administration, created in 1933, built public institutions, but failed to ease the severe housing shortage by constructing homes. In 1934, Congress created the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) to insure home mortgages and loans for home repairs at low-interest, long-term rates. While the FHA helped middle-income homeowners, it refused to insure mortgages in poorer inner-city areas where the risks of default were seen as greater than in the suburbs. FHA guidelines also by supporting racial covenants that prevented African Americans from moving into _white? neighborhoods. The following statement by a Newark, New Jersey, African-American newspaper to a joint Congressional committee on housing--created by anti-housing reform legislators to stall passage of a public housing bill--charged that policies of racial discrimination denied access to people of color for housing in both private and public facilities. The Supreme Court ruled in 1948 that restrictive covenants were not legally enforceable and FHA subsequently banned restrictive covenant clauses in contracts. Racial discrimination in housing continued, however, in sales of existing houses and through unwritten "gentlemen's agreements" between realtors and buyers. The Civil Rights Act of 1964 barred discrimination in public accommodations, but de facto segregation continued in many parts of the U.S.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die neues Abkommen-Arbeiten die Leitung, erstellt 
1933, bauten allgemeine Anstalten auf, aber konnten den strengen 
Gehäusemangel erleichtern, indem sie nicht Häuser konstruierten. 
1934 erstellte Kongreß die Bundesgehäuse-Leitung (FHA) um 
Haushypotheken und Darlehen für Hauptreparaturen mit den 
niedrigverzinslichen, langfristigen Kinetik zu versichern. 
Während das FHA mittleren Einkommeneigenheimbesitzern half, 
lehnte es ab, Hypotheken in den schlechteren Innerstadt Bereichen zu 
versichern, in denen die Verzugsrisiken gesehen wurden, wie grösser 
als in den Vororten. FHA Korrekturlinien auch durch das 
Unterstützen der rassischen Vereinbarungen, die afrikanische 
Amerikaner am Bewegen in _ Weiß hinderten? Nachbarschaften. 
Die folgende Anweisung durch ein Newark, Neu-Jersey, 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Zeitung zu einem gemeinsamen 
Kongreßausschuß für das Gehäuse -- hergestellt von den 
Anti-Gehäuse Verbesserunggesetzgebern, um Durchgang einer Rechnung 
des allgemeinen Gehäuses festzuklemmen -- aufgeladen, daß die 
Politik der rassischen Unterscheidung verweigert zu den Leuten der 
Farbe für die Unterbringung in den privaten und allgemeinen 
Teildiensten zugreift. Das Höchste Gericht ordnete 1948 an, 
daß einschränkende Vereinbarungen nicht erlaubterweise durchsetzbar 
waren und FHA nachher einschränkende Vereinbarungklauseln in den 
Verträgen verbot. Rassische Unterscheidung im Gehäuse fuhr, 
jedoch, in den Verkäufen der vorhandenen Häuser und durch 
Vereinbarungen der ungeschriebenen "Herren" zwischen Realtors und 
Kunden fort. Die Zivilrecht-Tat von 1964 hielt Unterscheidung in
den allgemeinen Anpassungen, aber de Facto die Abtrennung, die in 
vielen Teilen der US fortgesetzt wurde ab.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les travaux publics gestion de nouvelle affaire, 
créée en 1933, ont établi les établissements publics, mais n'ont 
pas soulagé le manque de logement grave en construisant des maisons. 
En 1934, le congrès a créé la gestion de logement fédéral 
(FHA) pour assurer les prêts hypothécaires à l'habitation et les 
prêts pour les réparations à la maison au faible intérêt, cadences à 
long terme. Tandis que le FHA aidait les propriétaires d'une 
maison moyens de revenu, il a refusé d'assurer des hypothèques dans 
des zones plus faibles d'intérieur-ville où les risques du défaut 
ont été vus comme plus grands que dans les banlieues. 
Directives de FHA également en supportant les engagements 
raciaux qui ont empêché les Américains africains d'entrer dans _ le
blanc ? voisinages. Le rapport suivant de Newark, 
New Jersey, journal afro-américain à un comité congressionnel commun 
sur le logement -- créé par des législateurs de réforme 
d'anti-logement pour caler le passage d'une facture de logement public
-- chargé que les politiques de la discrimination raciale niées 
accèdent aux gens de couleur pour loger dans les équipements privés
et publics. La cour suprême a régné en 1948 que les 
engagements restrictifs n'étaient pas légalement exécutoires et FHA
a ultérieurement interdit des clauses restrictives d'engagement dans 
les contrats. La discrimination raciale dans le logement a 
continué, cependant, dans les ventes des maisons existantes et par 
accords les "des messieurs non écrits" entre les agents immobiliers 
et les acheteurs. La Loi de droits civiques de 1964 a barré la 
discrimination dans le logement public, mais la ségrégation de fait 
continuée dans beaucoup de régions des États-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os trabalhos públicos administração de negócio
novo, criada em 1933, construíram instituições públicas, mas não 
facilitaram a falta de carcaça severa construindo HOME. Em 
1934, o congress criou a administração de carcaça federal (FHA) 
para segurar os mortgages home e os empréstimos para os reparos home 
em taxas low-interest, a longo prazo. Quando o FHA ajudou a 
homeowners médios da renda, recusou segurar mortgages em umas áreas 
mais deficientes da interno-cidade onde os riscos de opção fossem 
vistos como mais grandes do que nos suburbs. Guidelines de FHA 
também suportando os convénios raciais que impediram que os 
americanos africanos se movam _ no branco? vizinhanças. A
seguinte indicação por um Newark, Novo-Jersey, jornal 
Africano-Americano a um comitê congressional comum na carcaça -- 
criada por legislators da reforma da anti-carcaça para parar a 
passagem de uma conta da carcaça pública -- carregada que as 
políticas da discriminação racial negadas alcançam aos povos da 
cor para abrigar  em facilidades confidenciais e públicas. A 
corte suprema governou em 1948 que os convénios restritivos não eram
legalmente enforceable e FHA proibiu subseqüentemente cláusulas 
restritivas do convénio nos contratos. A discriminação racial
na carcaça continuou, entretanto, nas vendas de casas existentes e 
com os acordos dos "gentlemen unwritten" entre realtors e compradores.
O ato das direitas civis de 1964 barrou a discriminação em 
acomodações públicas, mas o segregation de de facto continuado em 
muitas partes dos E. U..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I lavori pubblici gestione di nuovo affare, creata
in 1933, hanno sviluppato le istituzioni pubbliche, ma non sono 
riuscito a facilitare la carenza edilizia severa costruendo le sedi. 
In 1934, il congresso ha creato la gestione di alloggiamento 
federale (FHA) per assicurare le ipoteche domestiche ed i prestiti per
le riparazioni domestiche ai tassi low-interest e di lunga durata. 
Mentre il FHA ha aiutato i proprietari di abitazione centrali di
reddito, ha rifiutato di assicurare le ipoteche nelle più povere 
zone della interno-città dove i rischi di difetto sono stati visti 
come più grandi di nella periferia. Guida di riferimento di 
FHA anche sostenendo i patti razziali che hanno impedito agli 
Americani africani di entrare _ nel bianco? vicinanze. La 
seguente istruzione di Newark, Nuovo-Jersey, giornale 
Africano-Americano ad un comitato congressuale unito per alloggiamento
-- creato dai legislatori di riforma dell'anti-alloggiamento per 
arrestarsi passaggio di una fattura dell'edilizia popolare -- caricato
che le politiche di distinzione razziale negate accedono a alla gente 
di colore per l'alloggio sia nelle attrezzature riservate che 
pubbliche. La Corte suprema ha regolato in 1948 che i patti 
restrittivi non erano legalmente enforceable e FHA successivamente ha 
vietato le clausole restrittive del patto nei contratti. La 
distinzione razziale in alloggiamento è continuato, tuttavia, nelle 
vendite delle case attuali e con gli accordi "dei signori non scritti"
fra i realtors ed i compratori. La Legge di diritti civili di 
1964 ha escluso la distinzione nelle sistemazioni pubbliche, ma la 
segregazione de facto continuata in molte zone degli Stati Uniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα διοίκηση δημόσιων έργων διαπραγμάτευσης, που 
δημιουργήθηκε το 1933, έχτισε τα δημόσια όργανα, αλλά 
απέτυχε να διευκολύνει την αυστηρή έλλειψη κατοικίας με την 
κατασκευή των σπιτιών. Το 1934, το συνέδριο δημιούργησε 
την ομοσπονδιακή διοίκηση κατοικίας (FHA) για να ασφαλίσει τις 
βασικά υποθήκες και τα δάνεια για τις βασικές επισκευές στα με 
χαμηλό επιτόκιο, μακροπρόθεσμα ποσοστά. Ενώ το FHA 
βοήθησε τους μεσαίου εισοδήματος ιδιοκτήτες σπιτιού, αρνήθηκε να
ασφαλίσει τις υποθήκες στις φτωχότερες inner-city περιοχές 
όπου οι κίνδυνοι προκαθορισμέού εβλέίδαν όπως 
μεγαλύτεροι απ'ό,τι στα προάστια. Οδηγίες FHA επίσης με 
την υποστήριξη των φυλετικών συμβολαίων που απέτρεψαν 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς από την κίνηση _ στο λευκό; 
γειτονιές. Η ακόλουθη δήλωση από ένα Newark, Νιου 
Τζέρσεϋ, αφρικανικός-αμερικανική εφημερίδα σε μια μικτή του 
Κογκρέσου επιτροπή της κατοικίας -- που δημιουργείται με την 
αντι-στέγαση των νομοθετών μεταρρύθμισης στη μετάβαση στάβλων 
ενός λογαριασμού δημόσιας κατοικίας -- χρέωσε ότι οι πολιτικές 
της φυλετικής διάκρισης αρνήθηκαν την πρόσβαση στους ανθρώπους 
του χρώματος για την κατοικία και στις ιδιωτικές και δημόσιες 
εγκαταστάσεις. Το ανώτατο δικαστήριο διέταξε το 1948 ότι
τα περιοριστικά συμβόλαια δεν ήταν νόμιμα εκτελέσιμα και FHA 
απαγόρευσε στη συνέχεια τις περιοριστικές προτάσεις συμβολαίων 
στις συμβάσεις. Η φυλετική διάκριση στην κατοικία 
συνεχίστηκε, εντούτοις, στις πωλήσεις των υπαρχόντων σπιτιών και 
μέσω των άγραφων "συμφωνιών κυρίων" μεταξύ των realtors και 
των αγοραστών. Ο νόμος αστικών δικαιωμάτων του 1964 
έφραξε τη διάκριση στις δημόσιες στεγάσεις, αλλά ο de facto
διαχωρισμός συνεχίστηκε σε πολλά μέρη των ΗΠΑ</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los trabajos públicos administración del nuevo 
reparto, creada en 1933, construyeron a instituciones públicas, pero 
no pudieron facilitar la escasez de cubierta severa construyendo 
hogares. En 1934, el congreso creó la administración de 
cubierta federal (FHA) para asegurar las hipotecas caseras y los 
préstamos para las reparaciones caseras en las tarifas de bajo 
interés, a largo plazo. Mientras que el FHA ayudó a dueños de
una casa medios de la renta, rechazó asegurar hipotecas en áreas 
más pobres de la interno-ciudad donde los riesgos del valor por 
defecto fueron considerados como mayores que en los suburbios. 
¿Guías de consulta de FHA también utilizando los convenios 
raciales que evitaron que los americanos africanos se movieran en _ 
blanco? vecindades. La declaración siguiente por una 
Newark, Nuevo-Jersey, periódico Africano-Americano a un comité del 
congreso común sobre la cubierta -- creada por los legisladores de la
reforma de la contra-cubierta para atascar el paso de una cuenta de la
cubierta pública -- cargada que las políticas de la discriminación 
racial negadas tengan acceso a la gente del color para contener en 
recursos privados y públicos. El Tribunal Supremo gobernó en 
1948 que los convenios restrictivos no eran legalmente ejecutorios y 
FHA prohibió posteriormente cláusulas restrictivas del convenio en 
contratos. La discriminación racial en la cubierta continuó, 
sin embargo, en ventas de casas existentes y con acuerdos los "de los 
caballeros no escritos" entre los realtors y los compradores. El
acto de las derechas civiles de 1964 barró la discriminación en 
comodidades públicas, pero la segregación de hecho continuada en 
muchas partes de los E.E.U.U..</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087038</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105243</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-right-to-housing-is-a-civil-right-due-without-discrimination-racial-bias-in-public-and-private-housing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
