<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106681</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106681</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087509</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Contrabands accompanying the line of Sherman's march through Georgia."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Schmuggelwaren, welche begleiten die Zeile von 
März Shermans durch Georgia."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"contrebandes accompagnant la ligne de la marche 
de Sherman par la Géorgie."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"contrabands que acompanham a linha do março de 
Sherman através de Geórgia."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"contrabbandi che accompagnano la riga del 
procedere dello Sherman attraverso la Georgia."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Παράνομες διακινήσεις που συνοδεύουν τη γραμμή του 
Μαρτίου Sherman μέσω της Γεωργίας."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"contrabandos que acompañan la línea del marzo 
de Sherman a través de Georgia."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After the fall of Atlanta in 1864, the Union Army under General William T. Sherman marched through Georgia to the sea, bringing destruction in its wake. Nearly 18,000 slaves left plantations and attached themselves to the army during its march. This 1865 illustration showed a stereotyped view of the men, women, and children who followed Sherman's army. But to northern readers, the engraving's significance may have lay in its unmistakable message about slaves' utter hatred of slavery. The oft expressed fallacy that they preferred slavery to freedom</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachdem der Fall von Atlanta 1864, die Anschluß-Armee 
unter General William T. Sherman durch Georgia zum Meer grenzte und 
holte Zerstörung in seiner Spur. Fast 18.000 Sklaven verließen
Plantagen und brachten sich zur Armee während seines Märzes an. 
Diese Abbildung 1865 zeigte eine stereotyped Ansicht der 
Männer, der Frauen und der Kinder, die Armee Shermans folgten. 
Aber zu den Nordlesern, kann die Stichhaltigkeit des Stiches in 
seine unmißverständliche Meldung über der Sklaven gelegt haben 
äußern Haß der Sklaverei. Der oft ausgedrückte 
Irrtum, daß sie Sklaverei gegenüber Freiheit bevorzugten</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après que la chute d'Atlanta en 1864, l'armée des 
syndicats sous le Général William T. Sherman ait marché par la 
Géorgie à la mer, apportant la destruction dans son sillage. 
Presque 18.000 esclaves ont laissé des plantations et se sont 
attachés à l'armée pendant sa marche. Cette illustration 1865
a montré une vue stéréotypée des hommes, des femmes, et des 
enfants qui ont suivi l'armée de Sherman. Mais aux lecteurs 
nordiques, la signification de la gravure a pu s'être étendue dans 
son message indubitable au sujet de la haine totale des esclaves de 
l'esclavage. L'erreur souvent exprimée qu'ils ont préféré 
l'esclavage à la liberté</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Depois que a queda de Atlanta em 1864, o exército de 
união sob o general William T. Sherman marchou através de Geórgia 
ao mar, trazendo a destruição em sua vigília. Quase 18.000 
escravos sairam de plantações e uniram-se ao exército durante seu 
março. Esta ilustração 1865 mostrou uma opinião stereotyped 
os homens, as mulheres, e as crianças que seguiram o exército de 
Sherman. Mas aos leitores do norte, o significado do engraving 
pode ter colocado em sua mensagem unmistakable sobre o hatred total 
dos escravos do slavery. O fallacy oft expressado que preferiram
o slavery à liberdade</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo che la caduta di Atlanta in 1864, l'esercito del 
sindacato sotto il General William T. Sherman marci attraverso la 
Georgia al mare, portante distruzione nel relativo risveglio. 
Quasi 18.000 schiavi hanno lasciato le piantagioni e si sono 
fissati all'esercito durante il relativo procedere. Questa 
illustrazione 1865 ha mostrato un punto di vista stereotipato degli 
uomini, delle donne e dei bambini che hanno seguito l'esercito dello 
Sherman. Ma ai lettori nordici, l'importanza dell'incisione può
risiedere nel relativo messaggio inequivocabile circa odio assoluto 
degli schiavi di slavery. L'errore oft espresso che hanno 
preferito lo slavery alla libertà</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από την πτώση της Ατλάντας το 1864, ο στρατός
ένωσης κάτω από General William Τ. Sherman βάδισε μέσω 
της Γεωργίας στη θάλασσα, που φέρνει την καταστροφή στα ίχνη του.
Σχεδόν 18.000 σκλάβοι άφησαν τις φυτείες και συνδέθηκαν 
με το στρατό κατά τη διάρκεια του του Μαρτίου του. Αυτή η 
απεικόνιση 1865 εμφάνισε στερεοτυπημένη όψη των ανδρών, των 
γυναικών, και των παιδιών που ακολούθησαν το στρατό Sherman. 
Αλλά στους βόρειους αναγνώστες, η σημασία της χάραξης 
μπορεί να πρέπει να βάλει στο καταφανές μήνυμά της για την 
παντελή έχθρα των σκλάβων της σκλαβιάς. Η συχνά εκφρασμένη
πλάνη ότι προτίμησαν τη σκλαβιά από την ελευθερία</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de que la caída de Atlanta en 1864, el ejército
de unión bajo general Guillermo T. Sherman marchara a través de 
Georgia al mar, trayendo la destrucción en su estela. Casi 
18.000 esclavos salieron de plantaciones y se asociaron al ejército 
durante su marzo. Esta ilustración 1865 mostró una opinión 
estereotipada los hombres, las mujeres, y los niños que siguieron a 
ejército de Sherman. Pero a los programas de lectura norteños,
la significación del grabado pudo haber puesto en su mensaje 
inequívoco sobre el odio completo de los esclavos de la esclavitud. 
El error oft expresado que prefirieron esclavitud a la libertad</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087509</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106681</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/contrabands-accompanying-the-line-of-shermans-march-through-georgia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
