<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103886</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103886</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086137</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Experiences of a 'Hired Girl'": An Early Twentieth-Century Domestic Worker Speaks Out</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Erfahrungen eines ' angestellten Mädchens '": 
Ein Frühes Zwanzigst-Jahrhundert Inländischer Arbeiter Spricht
Heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"expériences 'd'une fille louée '" : Un 
Ouvrier Domestique de Vingtième-Siècle Tôt Parle Dehors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"experiências ' de uma menina empregada '": 
Um Trabalhador Doméstico De Vigésimo-Século Adiantado Fala 
Para fora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"esperienze 'in una ragazza assunta '": Un 
Operaio Domestico Di Ventesimo-Secolo In anticipo Parla Fuori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εμπειρία ενόσ" μισθωμένου κοριτσιού "": Ένας 
πρώτος εσωτερικός εργαζόμενος εικοστός-αιώνα μιλά έξω</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"experiencias de una ' muchacha empleada '": 
Un Trabajador Doméstico Del Vige'simo-Siglo Temprano Habla 
Hacia fuera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This anonymous worker articulated common grievances of domestic workers in her 1912 article in  Outlook  magazine. A veteran of thirty-three years of household labor, she protested the unsystematic work and arbitrary supervision of domestic service, the most common category of female employment until World War II. She advised,"If the mistress of the house . . . would treat housework like a business, and treat their maids like the employees of a business, many of the problems of domestic service would be solved." Explicitly comparing domestic service and industrial work, this writer articulated the reasons that young women increasingly left household labor for the regular wages, fixed hours, and less intrusive supervision of factory jobs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser anonyme Arbeiter artikulierte geläufige 
Beschwerden der inländischen Arbeiter in ihrem Artikel 1912 in der 
Aussichtzeitschrift. Ein Veteran der thirty-three Jahre der 
Haushalt Arbeit, protestierte sie die unsystematische Arbeit und die 
willkürliche Überwachung des inländischen Services, die 
geläufigste Kategorie der weiblichen Beschäftigung bis den Zweiten 
Weltkrieg. Sie riet, "wenn die Geliebte des Hauses. . 
. würde Hausarbeit wie ein Geschäft behandeln und 
behandelt ihre Mädchen wie die Angestellten eines Geschäfts, viele 
der Probleme inländischem Service würde gelöst." 
Inländischen Service und industrielle Arbeit ausdrücklich, 
vergleichend, artikulierte dieser Verfasser die Gründe, daß junge 
Frauen in zunehmendem Maße Haushalt Arbeit für die regelmäßigen 
Löhne, die festgelegten Uhrzeiten und weniger aufdringliche 
Überwachung der Fabrikjobs ließen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet ouvrier anonyme a articulé des réclamations 
communes des ouvriers domestiques en son article 1912 en magazine de 
perspectives. Un vétéran des années de thirty-three de 
travail de ménage, elle a protesté le travail non systématique et 
la surveillance arbitraire du service domestique, la catégorie la 
plus commune de l'emploi femelle jusqu'à la deuxième guerre 
mondiale. Elle a informé, "si la maîtresse de la maison. 
. . traiterait les travaux domestiques comme des 
affaires, et traite leurs bonnes comme les employés des affaires, 
plusieurs des problèmes du service domestique serait résolu." 
Explicitement comparant le service domestique et le travail 
industriel, cet auteur a articulé les raisons pour laquelle les 
jeunes femmes ont de plus en plus laissé le travail de ménage pour 
les salaires réguliers, l'horaire fixe, et moins de surveillance 
intrusive des travaux d'usine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este trabalhador anonymous articulou queixas 
comuns de trabalhadores domésticos em seu artigo 1912 no 
compartimento do outlook. Um veteran de anos do thirty-three do 
trabalho da casa, protestou o trabalho unsystematic e a supervisão 
arbitrária do serviço doméstico, a categoria a mais comum de 
emprego fêmea até a segunda guerra mundial. Recomendou, "se o 
mistress da casa. . . trataria o housework como um 
negócio, e tratam suas empregadas domésticas como os empregados de 
um negócio, muitos dos problemas do serviço doméstico seria 
resolvido." Explicitamente comparando o serviço doméstico e o 
trabalho industrial, este escritor articulou as razões que as 
mulheres novas deixaram cada vez mais o trabalho da casa para os 
salários regulares, as horas fixas, e menos supervisão intrusive de 
trabalhos da fábrica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo operaio anonimo ha articolato le 
rimostranze comuni degli operai domestici in suo articolo 1912 in 
scomparto di prospettiva. Un veterano degli anni di thirty-three
del lavoro della famiglia, ha protestato il lavoro non 
sistematico ed il controllo arbitrario di servizio domestico, la 
categoria più comune di occupazione delle donne fino alla seconda 
guerra mondiale. Ha raccomandato, "se il mistress della casa. 
. . tratterebbe i lavori domestici come un commercio
e curano le loro domestiche come gli impiegati di un commercio, molti 
dei problemi di servizio domestico sarebbe risolto." 
Esplicitamente confrontando il servizio domestico ed il lavoro 
industriale, questo produttore ha articolato le ragioni per cui le 
donne giovani sempre più hanno lasciato il lavoro della famiglia
per gli stipendi normali, l'orario e meno controllo intrusivo dei 
lavori della fabbrica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ανώνυμος εργαζόμενος άρθρωσε τις κοινές 
διαμαρτυρίες των εσωτερικών εργαζομένων στο άρθρο του 1912 της 
στο περιοδικό προοπτικής. Ένας παλαίμαχος τριάντα τριών 
ετών οικιακής εργασίας, διαμαρτυρήθηκε τη unsystematic εργασία
και την αυθαίρετη επίβλεψη της εσωτερικής υπηρεσίας, η πιό κοινή
κατηγορία γυναικείας απασχόλησης μέχρι τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. 
Συμβούλεψε, "εάν η κυρία του σπιτιού. .. θα 
μεταχειριζόταν τα οικιακά όπως μια επιχείρηση, και θα θεράπευε τα
κορίτσια τους όπως τους υπαλλήλους μιας επιχείρησης, πολλά από 
τα προβλήματα της εσωτερικής υπηρεσίας θα λύνονταν." Ρητά 
συγκρίνοντας την εσωτερική υπηρεσία και τη βιομηχανική εργασία, 
αυτός ο συγγραφέας άρθρωσε τους λόγους ότι οι νέες γυναίκες 
άφησαν όλο και περισσότερο την οικιακή εργασία για τις κανονικές
αμοιβές, τις σταθερές ώρες, και τη λιγότερο παρεισφρητική 
επίβλεψη των εργασιών εργοστασίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este trabajador anónimo articuló agravios 
comunes de trabajadores domésticos en su artículo 1912 en 
compartimiento de la perspectiva. Un veterano de los años del 
thirty-three del trabajo de la casa, ella protestó el trabajo poco 
metódico y la supervisión arbitraria del servicio doméstico, la 
categoría más común del empleo femenino hasta la Segunda Guerra 
Mundial. Ella aconsejó, "si la amante de la casa. . 
. trataría el quehacer doméstico como un negocio, y 
tratan a sus criadas como los empleados de un negocio, muchos de los 
problemas del servicio doméstico sería solucionado." 
Explícitamente comparando servicio doméstico y el trabajo 
industrial, este programa de escritura articuló las razones que las 
mujeres jóvenes dejaron cada vez más el trabajo de la casa para los 
salarios regulares, los horarios fijos, y menos supervisión intrusa 
de los trabajos de la fábrica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086137</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103886</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/experiences-of-a-hired-girl-an-early-twentieth-century-domestic-worker-speaks-out</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
