<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108458</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108458</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086828</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Shut the Door": A Senator Speaks for Immigration Restriction</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"schließen Sie die Tür": Ein Senator 
Speaks für Einwanderungsbeschränkung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"fermez la porte" : Un sénateur Speaks pour
la restriction d'immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"feche a porta": Um senator Discurso para a 
limitação de immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"chiuda il portello": Il senatore Speaks per
la limitazione di immigrazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κλείστε την πόρτα": Ένας γερουσιαστής Speaks
για τον περιορισμό μετανάστευσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cierre la puerta": Un senador Speaks para 
la restricción de inmigración</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">At the turn of the 20th century, unprecedented levels of immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe to the United States aroused public support for restrictive immigration laws. After World War I, which temporarily slowed immigration levels, anti-immigration sentiment rose again. Congress passed the Quota Act of 1921, limiting entrants from each nation to 3 percent of that nationality's presence in the U.S. population as recorded by the 1910 census. As a result, immigration from Southern and Eastern Europe dropped to less than one-quarter of pre-World War I levels. Even more restrictive was the Immigration Act of 1924 (Johnson-Reed Act) that shaped American immigration policy until the 1960s. During congressional debate over the 1924 Act, Senator Ellison DuRant Smith of South Carolina drew on the racist theories of Madison Grant to argue that immigration restriction was the only way to preserve existing American resources. Although blatant racists like Smith were in the minority in the Senate, almost all senators supported restriction, and the Johnson-Reed bill passed with only six dissenting votes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An der Jahrhundertwende 20., weckten beispiellose 
Stufen der Immigration von südlichem und Osteuropa in die Vereinigten
Staaten allgemeinen Support für einschränkende Immigrationgesetze. 
Nach dem Ersten Weltkrieg der vorübergehend Immigrationstufen 
verlangsamte, stieg Anti-Immigration Gefühl wieder. Kongreß 
führte die Quote-Tat, von 1921 und begrenzte Eintretende von jeder 
Nation zu 3 Prozent Anwesenheit dieser Nationalität in der VEREINIGTE
STAATEN Bevölkerung, wie gespeichert durch die Zählung 1910. 
Infolgedessen fiel Immigration von südlichem und von Osteuropa 
auf weniger als ein viertel von Stufen des VorWeltkrieges I ab. 
War die Immigration-Tat von 1924 sogar einschränkender 
(Johnson-Schilf Tat) die amerikanische Immigrationpolitik formte, bis 
die sechziger Jahre während der Kongreßdebatte über den 1924 Tat, 
Senator Ellison DuRant Smith von Südcarolina auf die rassistischen 
Theorien von Madison Grant zeichnete, um zu argumentieren, daß 
Einwanderungsbeschränkung die einzige Methode war, existierende 
amerikanische Betriebsmittel zu konservieren. Obgleich krasse 
Rassisten wie Smith in der Minorität im Senat waren, unterstützten 
fast alle Senatoren Beschränkung und den Johnson-Schilf Gesetz, der 
mit nur sechs andersdenkenden Stimmen verabschiedet wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À la fin du 20ème siècle, les niveaux sans 
précédent de l'immigration de méridional et l'Europe de l'Est vers 
les Etats-Unis ont réveillé le soutien public des lois restrictives 
d'immigration. Après la Première Guerre Mondiale, qui a 
temporairement ralenti des niveaux d'immigration, le sentiment 
d'anti-immigration a monté encore. Le congrès a passé l'acte 
de quote-part de 1921, limitant des débutants de chaque nation à 3 
pour cent de la présence de cette nationalité dans la population des
ETATS-UNIS comme enregistré par le recensement 1910. En 
conséquence, l'immigration méridional et d'Europe de l'Est a chuté 
moins de à un quart de niveaux de la guerre I de pré-Monde. 
Bien plus restrictive était la Loi d'immigration de 1924 (acte 
de Johnson-reed) qui a formé la politique américaine d'immigration 
jusqu'aux années 60. Pendant la discussion congressionnelle 
au-dessus des 1924 acte, le sénateur Ellison DuRant Smith de la 
Caroline du sud a dessiné sur les théories racistes de Madison
Grant pour arguer du fait que la restriction d'immigration était la 
seule voie de préserver les ressources américaines existantes. 
Bien que les racistes flagrants comme Smith aient été dans la 
minorité dans le sénat, presque tous les sénateurs ont supporté la
restriction, et la facture de Johnson-reed passée avec seulement 
six voix discordantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na volta do 20o século, os níveis unprecedented 
do immigration de do sul e Europa Oriental aos estados unidos 
despertaram a sustentação pública para leis restritivas do 
immigration. Após o world.war.i, que retardou temporariamente 
níveis do immigration, o sentiment do anti-anti-immigration 
levantou-se outra vez. O congress passou o ato do quota de 1921,
limitando entrants de cada nação a 3 por cento da presença dessa 
nacionalidade na população de ESTADOS UNIDOS como gravado pelo 
census 1910. Em conseqüência, o immigration de do sul e de 
Europa Oriental deixou cair menos a de um quarto de níveis da guerra 
I do pre-Mundo. Mesmo mais restritivo foi o ato do immigration 
de 1924 (ato da Johnson-Lingüeta) que deu forma à política 
americana do immigration até que os 1960s. durante o debate 
congressional sobre os 1924 ato, o senator Ellison DuRant Smith de 
carolina sul desenhou nas teorias racist de Madison Grant para 
discutir que a limitação de immigration era a única maneira 
preservar recursos americanos existentes. Embora os racists 
blatant como Smith estivessem no minority no senate, quase todos os 
senators suportaram a limitação, e a conta da Johnson-Lingüeta 
passada com somente seis votos dissenting.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alla fine del ventesimo secolo, i livelli senza 
precedente dell'immigrazione da del sud e l'Europa Orientale al unito 
Dichiara il sostegno pubblico destato le leggi restrittive di 
immigrazione. Dopo il world.war.i, che temporaneamente ha 
ritardato i livelli di immigrazione, il sentimento di 
anti-immigrazione è aumentato ancora. Il congresso ha passato 
la Legge di quota di 1921, di limitazione i debuttanti da ogni nazione
a 3 per cento di presenza di quella nazionalità nella popolazione 
degli STATI UNITI come registrato tramite il censimento 1910. Di
conseguenza, l'immigrazione da del sud e dall'Europa Orientale è 
caduto più meno a d'un quarto dei livelli di guerra I del pre-Mondo. 
Ancor più restrittiva era la Legge di immigrazione di 1924 
(Legge della Johnson-Canna) che ha modellato la politica americana di 
immigrazione fino a che gli anni 60 durante il dibattito congressuale 
più dei 1924 Legge, il senatore Ellison DuRant Smith di Carolina del 
Sud non dissipasse sulle teorie razziste di Madison Grant per 
sostenere che la limitazione di immigrazione era l'unico modo 
conservare le risorse americane esistenti. Anche se i razzisti 
blatant come Smith erano nella minoranza nel senato, quasi tutti i 
senatori hanno sostenuto la limitazione e la fattura della 
Johnson-Canna passata con soltanto sei voti dissenting.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο γύρισμα του 20ού αιώνα, τα πρωτοφανή επίπεδα 
μετανάστευσης από νότιο και την Ανατολική Ευρώπη στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες ξύπνησαν δημόσια υποστήριξη για τους περιοριστικούς 
νόμους μετανάστευσης. Μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, που
επιβράδυνε προσωρινά τα επίπεδα μετανάστευσης, το συναίσθημα 
αντι-μετανάστευσης αυξήθηκε πάλι. Το συνέδριο πέρασε το 
νόμο ποσόστωσης του 1921, που περιορίζει τους εισερχόμενους 
από κάθε έθνος σε 3 τοις εκατό της παρουσίας εκείνης της 
υπηκοότητας στον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ πληθυσμό όπως καταγράφεται από την 
απογραφή 1910. Κατά συνέπεια, η μετανάστευση από νότιο 
και την Ανατολική Ευρώπη έριξε λιγότερο από στο τέταρτο του 
προ-παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι τα επίπεδα. Ακόμα πιό 
περιοριστικός ήταν ο νόμος μετανάστευσης του 1924 (νόμος 
ιοχνσον-καλάμων) που διαμόρφωσε την αμερικανική πολιτική 
μετανάστευσης μέχρι τη δεκαετία του '60 Κατά τη διάρκεια 
της του Κογκρέσου συζήτησης πέρα από το νόμο του 1924, ο 
γερουσιαστής Ellison DuRant Smith της νότιας Καρολίνας 
επέσυρε την προσοχή στις ρατσιστικές θεωρίες της επιχορήγησης του
Μάντισον για να υποστηρίξει ότι ο περιορισμός μετανάστευσης ήταν
ο μόνος τρόπος να συντηρηθούν τα υπάρχοντα αμερικανικά στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς. Αν και οι κραυγαλέοι ρατσιστές όπως Smith 
ήταν στη μειονότητα στη Σύγκλητο, σχεδόν όλοι οι γερουσιαστές 
υποστήριξαν τον περιορισμό, και ο λογαριασμός ιοχνσον-καλάμων 
πέρασε με μόνο έξι ψήφους διαφωνίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Al final del vigésimo siglo, los niveles sin 
precedentes de la inmigración de meridional y Europa Oriental a los 
Estados Unidos despertaron la ayuda pública para los leyes 
restrictivos de la inmigración. Después de la Primera Guerra 
Mundial, que retardó temporalmente niveles de la inmigración, el 
sentimiento de la contra-inmigracio'n se levantó otra vez. El 
congreso pasó el acto del contingente de 1921, limitando 
principiantes de cada nación a 3 por ciento de la presencia de esa 
nacionalidad en la población de ESTADOS UNIDOS según lo registrado 
por el censo 1910. Consecuentemente, la inmigración de 
meridional y de Europa Oriental cayó menos a de un cuarto de niveles 
de la guerra I del pre-Mundo. Aún más restrictivo era el acto 
de la inmigración de 1924 (acto de la Johnson-Caña) que formó la 
política americana de la inmigración hasta que los años 60 durante 
el discusión del congreso sobre los 1924 acto, senador Ellison DuRant
Smith de Carolina del Sur trazó en las teorías racist de Madison 
Grant para discutir que la restricción de inmigración era la única 
manera de preservar recursos americanos existentes. Aunque los 
racistas evidentes como Smith estaban en la minoría en el senado, 
casi todos los senadores utilizaron la restricción, y la cuenta de la
Johnson-Caña aprobada con solamente seis votos disidentes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086828</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108458</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shut-the-door-a-senator-speaks-for-immigration-restriction</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
