<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106400</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106400</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086688</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">On the road.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf der Straße.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sur la route.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na estrada.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sulla strada.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο δρόμο.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el camino.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Their worldly possessions piled on two rundown vehicles, a migrant family paused en route to California in February, 1936. They joined 400,000 people who left western and southwestern agricultural areas for California during the Great Depression, fleeing drought, dust storms, and a dramatic drop in agricultural prices. From 1929 to 1932, wheat prices dropped 50 percent and cotton fell more than two-thirds. The income of many farm families was too low to meet mortgage payments, repay loans, or pay taxes. Hundreds of thousands of families lost their farms. Drought made a bad situation worse, as dust storms tore across the Great Plains, carrying walls of dirt 8,000 feet high and destroying crops, livestock, and a whole way of life.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ihr worldly Besitz, der auf zwei Verminderungträgern, 
eine Wander- Familie angehäuft wurde, pausierte auf dem Weg zu 
Kalifornien im Februar, 1936. Er verbanden 400.000 Leute, die 
linke westliche und südwestliche landwirtschaftliche Bereiche für 
Kalifornien während des großen Tiefstands, der Fliehendürre, der 
Staubstürme und eines drastischen Tropfens der landwirtschaftlichen 
Preise. Von ließen 1929 bis 1932, Weizenpreise 50 Prozent 
fallen und Baumwolle fiel mehr als zweidrittel. Das Einkommen 
vieler Bauernhoffamilien war zu niedrig, Hypothek Zahlungen zu 
treffen, Darlehen zurückzuerstatten oder Steuern zu zahlen. 
Hunderte Tausenden Familien verloren ihre Bauernhöfe. Die
Dürre, die eine falsche Situation falscher ist, als Staubstürme 
gebildet wurde, zerriß über die Prairien heftig und trug Wände des 
Schmutzes 8.000 Fuß hohe und zerstörende Getreide, Vieh und eine 
vollständige Lebensart.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Leurs possessions mondaines empilées sur deux 
véhicules de diminution des effectifs, une famille migratrice ont 
fait une pause en route à la Californie en février, 1936. 
Elles ont joint 400.000 personnes que les zones agricoles 
occidentales et du sud-ouest gauches pour la Californie pendant la 
grande dépression, sécheresse de fuite, la poussière 
donne l'assaut à, et une baisse excessive dans des prix agricoles. 
De 1929 à 1932, prix de blé ont relâché 50 pour cent et le 
coton est tombé plus de deux-tiers. Le revenu de beaucoup de 
familles de ferme était trop bas pour rencontrer des paiements 
d'hypothèque, pour rembourser des prêts, ou pour payer des impôts. 
Les centaines de milliers de familles ont détruit leurs fermes.
La sécheresse faite une mauvaise situation plus mauvaise, comme
poussière donne l'assaut à a déchiré à travers les grandes plaines,
portant les murs de la saleté les collectes de 8.000 pieds d'hauteur 
et détruisante, le bétail, et une façon de vivre entière.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Suas possessões worldly empilhadas em dois veículos do 
rundown, uma família emigrante pausaram a caminho a Califórnia em 
fevereiro, 1936. Juntaram 400.000 povos que áreas agriculturais
ocidentais e do sudoeste esquerdas para Califórnia durante o 
depression grande, a seca fujir, as tempestades de poeira, e uma gota 
dramática em preços agriculturais. 1929 a 1932, preços do 
trigo deixaram cair 50 por cento e o algodão caiu mais de dois 
terços. A renda de muitas famílias da fazenda era demasiado 
baixa encontrar-se com pagamentos de mortgage, reembolsar 
empréstimos, ou pagar impostos. As centenas dos milhares das 
famílias perderam suas fazendas. A seca feita uma situação 
má mais má, como tempestades de poeira rasgou através das 
planícies grandes, carregando paredes da sujeira colheitas de 8.000 
pés de altura e destruindo, animais domésticos, e uma maneira de 
vida inteira.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I loro possessi worldly accatastati su due veicoli della 
riduzione di attività, una famiglia migratore hanno fatto una pausa 
in viaggio alla California in febbraio, del 1936. Hanno unito 
400.000 genti che zone agricole occidentali e del sud-ovest di 
sinistra per la California durante la depressione grande, la siccità 
fuggire, le tempeste di polvere ed il calo drammatico nei prezzi 
agricoli. 1929 - 1932, prezzi del frumento hanno caduto 50 per 
cento ed il cotone è caduto più di due terzi. Il reddito di 
molte famiglie dell'azienda agricola era troppo basso per venire a 
contatto dei pagamenti ipotecari, per rimborsare i prestiti, o per 
pagare le tasse. Le centinaia dei migliaia delle famiglie hanno 
perso i loro poderi. La siccità resa ad una situazione 
difettosa più difettosa, come tempeste di polvere si è strappata 
attraverso le pianure grandi, trasportanti le pareti di sporcizia 
d'altezza 8.000 piedi e distruggere i raccolti, il bestiame e un 
modo di vivere intero.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι κοσμικές κατοχές τους που συσσωρεύθηκαν σε δύο 
οχήματα μείωσης, μια αποδημητική οικογένεια σταμάτησαν καθ'οδόν 
σε Καλιφόρνια τον Φεβρουάριο, του 1936. Προσχώρησαν σε 
400.000 ανθρώπους που άφησαν τις δυτικές και νοτιοδυτικές 
γεωργικές περιοχές για Καλιφόρνια κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης 
οικονομικής κρίσης, της φεύγοντας ξηρασίας, των θυελλών σκόνης, 
και μιας δραματικής μείωσης των γεωργικών τιμών. Από το 
1929 ως το 1932, οι τιμές σίτου που ρίχτηκαν 50 τοις εκατό 
και το βαμβάκι έπεσαν περισσότερο από δύο τρίτα. Το 
εισόδημα πολλών αγροτικών οικογενειών ήταν πάρα πολύ χαμηλό 
για να συναντήσει τις πληρωμές υποθηκών, να ξεπληρώσει τα δάνεια,
ή να πληρώσει τους φόρους. Οι εκατοντάδες χιλιάδες των 
οικογενειών έχασαν τα αγροκτήματά τους. Η ξηρασία 
κατέστησε μια κακή κατάσταση χειρότερη, όπως οι θύελλες σκόνης 
έσχισαν στις μεγάλες πεδιάδες, που φέρνουν τους τοίχους του 
ρύπου 8.000 πόδια υψηλού και που καταστρέφουν τις συγκομιδές, 
το ζωικό κεφάλαιο, και ολόκληρο έναν τρόπο της ζωής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sus posesiones worldly llenadas en dos vehículos de la 
reducción, una familia migratoria se detuvieron brevemente en el 
camino a California en febrero de 1936. Ensamblaron a 400.000 
personas que las áreas agrícolas occidentales y al sudoeste 
izquierdas para California durante la gran depresión, la sequía el 
huir, tormentas de polvo, y una gota dramática en precios agrícolas.
A partir la 1929 a 1932, precios del trigo cayó 50 por ciento y
el algodón cayó más de dos tercios. La renta de muchas 
familias de la granja era demasiado baja resolver pagos de hipoteca, 
compensar préstamos, o pagar impuestos. Los centenares de 
millares de familias perdieron sus granjas. La sequía hecha una
mala situación peor, como tormentas de polvo se rasgó a través de 
los grandes llanos, llevando las paredes de la suciedad las cosechas 
de 8.000 pies de alto y que destruía, el ganado, y una manera de la 
vida entera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086688</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106400</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/on-the-road</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
