<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106749</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106749</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212237</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Squid Lab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalmar-Labor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Laboratoire de Calmar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Laboratório Do Calamar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Laboratorio Del Calamaro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εργαστήριο καλαμαριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Laboratorio Del Calamar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This online handbook features a downloadable PDF of pre-and post-visit activities for the Squid Lab, a traveling outreach program hosted by the National Aquarium in Baltimore. The hands-on activities and student sheets may be incorporated into any life science classroom. The Squid Lab begins with an overview of the cephalopods, with a particular emphasis on squid. The overall anatomy of the squid is also discussed to provide students with a preview of what they will see when the dissection begins. Students will learn about the adaptations, defense mechanisms, feeding habits, predators and reproductive strategies of squid. Step by step directions are given to guide the students through the dissection.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Onlinehandbuch kennzeichnet ein 
downloadablepdf von vor-und Pfosten-besucht Aktivitäten für das 
Kalmar-Labor, ein Reisen übertreffen das Programm, das durch das 
nationale Aquarium in Baltimore bewirtet wird. Die Blindeinschub
Aktivitäten und die Kursteilnehmerblätter können in jedes 
mögliches Lebenwissenschaft Klassenzimmer enthalten werden. Das
Kalmar-Labor fängt mit einem Überblick über die Kopffüßer, mit 
einem bestimmten Hauptgewicht auf Kalmar an. Die gesamte 
Anatomie des Kalmars wird auch behandelt, um zu versehen 
Kursteilnehmer mit einer Vorbetrachtung von, was sie sehen, wann die 
Zerlegung anfängt. Kursteilnehmer erlernen über die 
Anpassungen, die Abwehrmechanismen, die einziehenden Gewohnheiten, die
Fleischfresser und die reproduktiven Strategien des Kalmars. 
Schrittweisee Richtungen werden gegeben, um die Kursteilnehmer 
durch die Zerlegung zu führen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce manuel en ligne comporte un pdf downloadable de
pré-et poteau-visite des activités pour le laboratoire de calmar, un
déplacement dépassent le programme accueilli par l'aquarium national
à Baltimore. Les activités et les feuilles à commande 
manuelle d'étudiant peuvent être incorporées à n'importe quelle 
salle de classe de la science de vie. Le laboratoire de calmar 
commence par une vue d'ensemble des céphalopodes, avec une emphase 
particulière sur le calmar. L'anatomie globale du calmar est 
également discutée pour fournir à des étudiants une prévision de 
ce qu'ils verront quand la dissection commence. Les étudiants 
se renseigneront sur les adaptations, les mécanismes de défense, les
habitudes d'alimentation, les prédateurs et les stratégies 
reproductrices du calmar. Des directions pas à pas sont 
données pour guider les étudiants par la dissection.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este manual em linha caracteriza um pdf 
downloadable de pre-e borne-visita atividades para o laboratório do 
calamar, viajar excede o programa hospedado pelo aquário nacional em 
Baltimore. As atividades e as folhas hands-on do estudante podem
ser incorporadas em toda a sala de aula da ciência de vida. O 
laboratório do calamar começa com uma vista geral dos cefalópodes, 
com uma ênfase particular no calamar. O anatomy total do 
calamar é discutido também para fornecer estudantes com uma 
inspecção prévia de o que verão quando o dissection começa. 
Os estudantes aprenderão sobre as adaptações, os mecanismos 
de defesa, os hábitos de alimentação, os predadores e as 
estratégias reproductive do calamar. A etapa por sentidos da 
etapa é dada para guiar os estudantes com o dissection.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo manuale in linea caratterizza un pdf 
downloadable di pre-e alberino-visita le attività per il laboratorio 
del calamaro, viaggiare supera il programma ospitato dall'acquario 
nazionale a Baltimora. Le attività ed i fogli hands-on 
dell'allievo possono essere incorporati in tutta l'aula di scienze 
biologiche. Il laboratorio del calamaro comincia con una 
descrizione dei cefalopodi, con particolare rilievo sul calamaro. 
L'anatomia generale del calamaro egualmente è discussa per 
fornire agli allievi una previsione di che cosa vedranno quando la 
dissezione comincia. Gli allievi impareranno circa gli 
adattamenti, i meccanismi di difesa, le abitudini d'alimentazione, i 
predatori e le strategie riproduttive del calamaro. I sensi 
graduali sono dati per guidare gli allievi con la dissezione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σε απευθείας σύνδεση εγχειρίδιο χαρακτηρίζει 
ένα τηλεκατεγραφόμενο PDF προ-και οι δραστηριότητες 
μετα-επίσκεψης για το εργαστήριο καλαμαριών, ένα ταξίδι 
ξεπερνούν το πρόγραμμα που φιλοξενείται από το εθνικό ενυδρείο 
στη Βαλτιμόρη. Οι εμπράγματα δραστηριότητες και τα φύλλα 
σπουδαστών μπορούν να ενσωματωθούν σε οποιαδήποτε τάξη 
βιολογικής επιστήμης. Το εργαστήριο καλαμαριών αρχίζει με 
μια επισκόπηση των κεφαλόποδων, με μια ιδιαίτερη έμφαση στο 
καλαμάρι. Η γενική ανατομία του καλαμαριού συζητείται 
επίσης για να παρέχει στους σπουδαστές μια επίδειξη αυτού που θα 
δουν όταν αρχίζει η ανατομή. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
μάθουν για τις προσαρμογές, τους αμυντικούς μηχανισμούς, τις 
συνήθειες σίτισης, τα αρπακτικά ζώα και τις αναπαραγωγικές 
στρατηγικές του καλαμαριού. Οι βαθμιαίες κατευθύνσεις 
δίνονται για να καθοδηγήσουν τους σπουδαστές μέσω της ανατομής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este manual en línea ofrece un pdf downloadable 
de pre-y poste-visita las actividades para el laboratorio del calamar,
el viajar excede el programa recibido por el acuario nacional en 
Baltimore. Las actividades y las hojas con manos del estudiante 
se pueden incorporar en cualquier sala de clase de la ciencia de vida.
El laboratorio del calamar comienza con una descripción de los 
cefalópodos, con un énfasis determinado en el calamar. La 
anatomía total del calamar también se discute para proveer de 
estudiantes una inspección previo de lo que verán cuando la 
disección comienza. Los estudiantes aprenderán sobre las 
adaptaciones, los mecanismos de defensa, los hábitos de 
alimentación, los depredadores y las estrategias reproductivas del 
calamar. Las direcciones paso a paso se dan para dirigir a los 
estudiantes con la disección.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL AQUARIUM IN BALTIMORE
FN:NATIONAL AQUARIUM IN BALTIMORE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212237</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106749</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/squid-lab</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
