<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107772</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107772</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205298</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Daughter from Danang: Culture Clash, a Perspective From Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tochter von Danang: Kultur-Zusammentreffen, 
eine Perspektive von Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fille de Danang : Désaccord de culture, une
perspective du Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Filha de Danang: Clash da cultura, um 
perspective de Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Figlia da Danang: Disaccordo della coltura, 
una prospettiva dal Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κόρη από Danang: Διαφωνία πολιτισμού, μια 
προοπτική από το Βιετνάμ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hija de Danang: Choque de la cultura, una 
perspectiva de Vietnam</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The lesson focuses on the cultural differences and the impact to family structure and dynamics. A Vietnamese mother and her Amerasian daughter are reunited after 22 years. Both have dreamed of a joyful reunion but cultural differences and years of separation cause a different result. This film is about a war in the past and making peace in the present. The topics of culture, adoption and the meaning of family will be explored in this lesson.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Lektionfoki auf den kulturellen Unterschieden 
und der Auswirkung zur Familie Struktur und der Dynamik. Eine 
vietnamesische Mutter und ihre Amerasian Tochter werden nach 22 Jahren
gewiedervereinigt. Beide haben von einer frohen 
Wiedervereinigung geträumt, aber kulturelle Unterschiede und Jahre 
der Trennung verursachen ein anderes Resultat. Dieser Film ist 
über einen Krieg in der Vergangenheit und Bildenfrieden im Geschenk. 
Die Themen der Kultur, der Annahme und der Bedeutung der Familie
werden in dieser Lektion erforscht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les foyers de leçon sur les différences 
culturelles et l'impact à la structure et à la dynamique de famille.
Une mère vietnamienne et son fille d'Amerasian sont réunies 
après 22 ans. Tous les deux ont rêvé d'une réunion joyeuse 
mais les différences et les années culturelles de la séparation 
causent un résultat différent. Ce film est au sujet d'une 
guerre dans le passé et paix de fabrication dans le présent. 
Les sujets de la culture, de l'adoption et de la signification 
de la famille seront explorés dans cette leçon.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os focos da lição nas diferenças cultural e no 
impacto à estrutura e à dinâmica da família. Uma matriz 
vietnamese e sua filha de Amerasian são reun após 22 anos. 
Ambos sonharam de um reunion alegre mas as diferenças e os anos
cultural da separação causam um resultado diferente. Esta 
película é sobre uma guerra no passado e paz fazer no presente. 
Os tópicos da cultura, do adoption e do meaning da família 
serão explorados nesta lição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I fuochi di lezione sulle differenze culturali e 
sull'effetto alla struttura ed al dynamics della famiglia. Una 
madre vietnamita e la sua figlia di Amerasian reunited dopo 22 anni. 
Entrambi hanno sognato di una riunione allegra ma le differenze 
e gli anni culturali della separazione causano un risultato 
differente. Questa pellicola è circa una guerra nel passato e 
pace fare nel presente. I soggetti di coltura, di approvazione e
del significato della famiglia saranno esplorati in questa lezione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εστίαση μαθήματος στις πολιτιστικές διαφορές και ο 
αντίκτυπος στην οικογενειακή δομή και τη δυναμική. Μια 
βιετναμέζικη μητέρα και η κόρη Amerasian της επανασυνδέονται 
μετά από 22 έτη. Και οι δύο έχουν ονειρευτεί μια 
χαρούμενη συγκέντρωση αλλά οι πολιτιστικά διαφορές και τα έτη 
χωρισμού προκαλούν ένα διαφορετικό αποτέλεσμα. Αυτή η 
ταινία είναι για έναν πόλεμο στην προηγούμενη και κάνοντας 
ειρήνη στο παρόν. Τα θέματα του πολιτισμού, της υιοθέτησης 
και της έννοιας της οικογένειας θα εξερευνηθούν σε αυτό το 
μάθημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los focos de la lección en las diferencias 
culturales y el impacto a la estructura y a la dinámica de la 
familia. Una madre vietnamita y su hija de Amerasian se juntan 
después de 22 años. Ambos han soñado con una reunión alegre 
pero las diferencias y los años culturales de la separación causan 
un diverso resultado. Esta película está sobre una guerra en 
el pasado y paz de la fabricación en el presente. Los asuntos 
de la cultura, de la adopción y del significado de la familia serán 
explorados en esta lección.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205298</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107772</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/daughter-from-danang-culture-clash-a-perspective-from-vietnam</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
