<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105377</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105377</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211594</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Plankton*Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Plankton*Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plankton*Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Plankton*Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Plankton*Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Plankton*Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plankton*Net</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Plankton*net is a communal source of information about marine phytoplankton. Users can browse through an extensive collection of descriptions and images organized alphabetically or by taxon. The software also allows registered users to contribute information and images online. Linkouts are provided with each species description to numerous websites containing information about the organism, including genetic sequences, images and culture collections. Plankton net is based on micro*scope software v. 6 and supports the features found in micro*scope.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Plankton*net ist eine Kommunalquelle der 
Informationen über Marinephytoplankton. Benutzer können durch 
eine umfangreiche Ansammlung durchstöbern Beschreibungen und Bilder, 
die alphabetisch organisiert werden oder durch Taxon. Die 
Software erlaubt auch zugelassenen Benutzern, Informationen und Bilder
online beizutragen. Linkouts werden mit jeder Sortebeschreibung 
zu den zahlreichen Web site versehen, die Informationen über den 
Organismus, einschließlich genetische Reihenfolgen, die Bilder und 
die Kulturansammlungen enthalten. Planktonnetz basiert auf 
micro*scope Software V. 6 und unterstützt die Merkmale, die im 
micro*scope gefunden werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plankton*net est une source communale 
d'informations sur le phytoplancton marin. Les utilisateurs 
peuvent parcourir par une collection étendue de descriptions et 
d'images organisées alphabétiquement ou par taxon. Le 
logiciel permet également aux utilisateurs enregistrés de contribuer
l'information et des images en ligne. Linkouts sont équipés de
chaque description d'espèces à de nombreux sites Web contenant 
des informations sur l'organization, y compris des ordres 
génétiques, des images et des collections de culture. Le filet
de plancton est basé sur le logiciel v de micro*scope. 6 et 
supporte les dispositifs trouvés dans le micro*scope.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Plankton*net é uma fonte communal da informação
sobre o phytoplankton marinho. Os usuários podem browse 
através de uma coleção extensiva das descrições e das imagens 
organizadas alfabeticamente ou pelo táxon. O software permite 
também que os usuários registados contribuam a informação e as 
imagens em linha. Linkouts é fornecido com cada descrição da 
espécie aos Web site numerosos que contêm a informação sobre o 
organismo, including seqüências genetic, imagens e coleções da 
cultura. A rede do plankton é baseada no software v do 
micro*scope. 6 e suportam as características encontradas no 
micro*scope.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Plankton*net è una sorgente comunale delle 
informazioni sul fitoplancton marino. Gli utenti possono passare
in rassegna attraverso una vasta collezione delle descrizioni e delle 
immagini organizzate in ordine alfabetico o dal taxon. Il 
software egualmente permette che gli utenti registrati contribuiscano 
le informazioni e le immagini in linea. Linkouts è fornito di 
ogni descrizione di specie ai Web site numerosi che contengono le 
informazioni sull'organismo, compreso le sequenze genetiche, sulle 
immagini e sulle collezioni della coltura. La rete del plancton 
è basata sul software v del micro*scope. 6 e sostengono le 
caratteristiche trovate nel micro*scope.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Plankton*net είναι μια κοινοτική πηγή 
πληροφοριών για το θαλάσσιο φυτοπλαγκτόν. Οι χρήστες 
μπορούν να περιοδεύσουν μέσω μιας εκτενούς συλλογής των 
περιγραφών και των εικόνων που οργανώνονται αλφαβητικά ή από το 
taxon. Το λογισμικό επιτρέπει επίσης στους εγγραμμένους 
χρήστες για να συμβάλει τις πληροφορίες και τις εικόνες 
on-line. Στο Linkouts παρέχεται κάθε περιγραφή ειδών 
στους πολυάριθμους ιστοχώρους που περιέχουν τις πληροφορίες για 
τον οργανισμό, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των γενετικών ακολουθιών, των 
εικόνων και των συλλογών πολιτισμού. Το πλαγκτόν καθαρό 
είναι βασισμένο στο λογισμικό V. 6 micro*scope και 
υποστηρίζει τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα που βρίσκονται στο 
micro*scope.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plankton*net es una fuente comunal de la 
información sobre phytoplankton marina. Los utilizadores pueden
hojear a través de una colección extensa de descripciones y de 
imágenes ordenadas alfabéticamente o por la taxonomía. El 
software también permite que los utilizadores registrados contribuyan
la información e imágenes en línea. Linkouts se proporciona 
cada descripción de la especie a los Web site numerosos que contienen
la información sobre el organismo, incluyendo secuencias genéticas, 
imágenes y colecciones de la cultura. La red del plancton se 
basa en el software v del micro*scope. 6 y utiliza las 
características encontradas en micro*scope.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ALEXANDRA KRABERG
FN:ALEXANDRA KRABERG
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID PATTERSON
FN:DAVID PATTERSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ADORIAN ARDELEAN
FN:ADORIAN ARDELEAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ANA MACARIO
FN:ANA MACARIO
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BASTIAN ONKEN
FN:BASTIAN ONKEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ALFRED WEGENER INSTITUTE FOR POLAR AND MARINE RESEARCH (AWI)
FN:ALFRED WEGENER INSTITUTE FOR POLAR AND MARINE RESEARCH (AWI)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211594</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105377</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/plankton-net</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
