<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Architecture and Interior Design for 20th Century America: Samuel Gottscho and William Schleisner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Architektur und Innenarchitektur für 20. 
Jahrhundert Amerika: Samuel Gottscho und William Schleisner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Architecture et conception intérieure pour le 
20ème siècle Amérique : Samuel Gottscho et William 
Schleisner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Arquitetura e projeto interior para o 20o século 
América: Samuel Gottscho e William Schleisner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Architettura e disegno interno per il ventesimo 
secolo America: Samuel Gottscho e William Schleisner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχιτεκτονική και εσωτερικό σχέδιο για το 20ό αιώνα 
Αμερική: Θ*Σαμuελ Gottscho και William Schleisner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Configuración y diseño interior para el 
vigésimo siglo América: Samuel Gottscho y Guillermo 
Schleisner</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offer over 29,000 images primarily of architectural subjects, including interiors and exteriors of homes, stores, offices, factories, historic buildings, and other structures. Subjects are concentrated chiefly in the northeastern United States, especially the New York City area, and Florida. Included are the homes of notable Americans, such as Raymond Loewy, and of several U.S. presidents, as well as color images of the 1939-40 New York World's Fair.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebot über 29.000 Bildern hauptsächlich der 
architektonischen Themen, einschließlich Inneren und Äußere der 
Häuser, der Speicher, der Büros, der Fabriken, der historischen 
Gebäude und anderer Strukturen. Themen werden hauptsächlich in
den nordöstlichen Vereinigten Staaten, besonders der New York City 
Bereich und in Florida konzentriert. Sind die Häuser der 
bemerkenswerten Amerikaner, wie Raymond Loewy und einiger VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Präsidenten enthalten, sowie Farbe Bilder der angemessenen 
New York Welt 1939-40.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre plus de 29.000 images principalement des 
sujets architecturaux, y compris des intérieurs et des extérieurs 
des maisons, des mémoires, des bureaux, des usines, des bâtiments 
historiques, et d'autres structures. Des sujets sont concentrés
principalement la région Etats-Unis du nord-est, particulièrement 
New York City, et Floride. Incluses sont les maisons des 
Américains notables, telles que Raymond Loewy, et de plusieurs 
présidents des ETATS-UNIS, aussi bien que des images de couleur de 
1939-40 de New York mondial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferta sobre 29.000 imagens primeiramente de 
assuntos architectural, including interiores e exteriores das HOME, de
lojas, de escritórios, de fábricas, de edifícios historic, e de 
outras estruturas. Os assuntos são concentrados principalmente 
nos estados unidos do nordeste, especial na área de New York City, e 
em Florida. Incluídas são as HOME de americanos notáveis, 
tais como Raymond Loewy, e de diversos presidentes de ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
as.well.as imagens da cor do mundo 1939-40 de New York justo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offerta oltre 29.000 immagini soprattutto degli 
oggetti architettonici, compreso gli interiori e gli esterni delle 
sedi, dei depositi, degli uffici, delle fabbriche, delle costruzioni 
storiche e di altre strutture. Gli oggetti sono concentrati 
principalmente nel di nordest unito Dichiara, particolarmente 
la zona de New York City e Florida. Incluse sono le sedi degli 
Americani notevoli, quale Raymond Loewy e di parecchi presidenti degli
STATI UNITI, così come le immagini di colore del mondo 1939-40 de New
York giusto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφορά άνω των 29.000 εικόνων πρώτιστα των 
αρχιτεκτονικών θεμάτων, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του εσωτερικού και των
εξωτερικών των σπιτιών, των καταστημάτων, των γραφείων, των 
εργοστασίων, των ιστορικών κτηρίων, και άλλων δομών. Τα 
θέματα συγκεντρώνονται κυρίως στις βορειοανατολικές Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες, ειδικά την περιοχή πόλεων της Νέας Υόρκης, και τη 
Φλώριδα. Περιλαμβάνονται τα σπίτια ξεχωριστών Αμερικανών, 
όπως Raymond Loewy, και διάφορων ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ Προέδρων, 
καθώς επίσης και των εικόνων χρώματος της παγκόσμιας έκθεσης της
Νέας Υόρκης του 1939-40.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">oferta sobre 29.000 imágenes sobre todo de temas 
arquitectónicos, incluyendo interiores y exteriores de hogares, de 
almacenes, de oficinas, de fábricas, de edificios históricos, y de 
otras estructuras. Los temas se concentran principalmente en New
York City el área de los Estados Unidos del noreste, especialmente, y
la Florida. Incluidos son los hogares de americanos notables, 
tales como Raymond Loewy, y de varios presidentes de ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
así como las imágenes del color del mundo 1939-40 de Nueva York 
justo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103671</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/architecture-and-interior-design-for-20th-century-america-samuel-gottscho-and-william-schleisner</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
