<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086737</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Please Help Us Mr. President": Black Americans Write to FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Helfen Sie Uns Bitte Herr Präsident": 
Schwarze Amerikaner schreiben zu FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Svp Aidez-Nous M. Président" : Les 
Américains noirs écrivent au FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Ajude-nos Por favor Sr. Presidente": Os 
americanos pretos escrevem ao FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Aiutili Prego Signor presidente": Gli 
Americani neri scrivono al FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Παρακαλώ μας βοηθήστε Κύριε Πρόεδρε": Μαύροι 
Αμερικανοί γράφουν σε FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ayúdenos Por favor Sr. Presidente": Los 
americanos negros escriben al FDR</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although Franklin D. Roosevelt never endorsed anti-lynching legislation and condoned discrimination against blacks in federally funded relief programs, he still won the hearts and the votes of many African. Yet this support and even veneration for Roosevelt did not blind black Americans to the continuing discrimination that they faced. Indeed, the two views were often combined when they wrote letters to the president asking him to do something about discrimination that they confronted in their daily lives. Three letters are included here from the thousands that poured in to Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt from black Americans during the 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich Franklin D. Roosevelt nie Anti-lynchende 
Gesetzgebung indossierte und Diskriminierung gegen Schwarze in 
föderativ gefinanzierten Entlastung Programmen verzieh, gewann er 
noch die Inneren und die Stimmen von vielen Afrikaner. Noch 
machten dieser Support und sogar veneration für Roosevelt schwarze 
Amerikaner nicht zur fortfahrenden Unterscheidung blind, die sie 
gegenüberstellten. In der Tat wurden die zwei Ansichten häufig
kombiniert, als sie dem Präsidenten Briefe schrieben, der ihn bittet,
etwas über Unterscheidung zu tun, daß sie in ihren täglichen 
Lebensdauern konfrontierten. Drei Zeichen sind hier von den 
Tausenden eingeschlossen, die innen zu Franklin und zu Eleanor 
Roosevelt von den schwarzen Amerikanern während der dreißiger Jahre 
gossen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que la législation anti-lynchante non jamais
approuvée de Franklin D. Roosevelt et a pardonné la discrimination 
contre des noirs dans des programmes fédéralement placés de 
soulagement, il gagnait toujours les coeurs et les voix des beaucoup 
d'Africain. Pourtant ces soutien et même vénération de 
Roosevelt n'ont pas aveuglé les Américains noirs à la 
discrimination continue à la laquelle ils ont faite face. En 
effet, les deux vues ont été souvent combinées quand elles ont 
écrit des lettres au président lui demandant de faire quelque chose 
au sujet de la discrimination qu'elles ont confronté dans leurs vies 
quotidiennes. Trois lettres sont incluses ici des milliers qui 
ont afflué à Franklin et à Eleanor Roosevelt des Américains noirs 
pendant les années 30.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora Franklin D. Roosevelt nunca endossasse a 
legislação anti-anti-lynching e desculpasse a discriminação de 
encontro aos pretos em programas federal financiados do relevo, ganhou
ainda os corações e os votos dos muitos africano. Contudo 
estes sustentação e mesmo veneration para Roosevelt não cegaram 
americanos pretos à discriminação continuando que enfrentou. 
Certamente, as duas vistas foram combinadas frequentemente 
quando escreveram letras ao presidente que pede que faça algo sobre a
discriminação que confrontaram em suas vidas diárias. Três 
letras são incluídas aqui dos milhares que derramaram dentro a 
Franklin e a Eleanor Roosevelt dos americanos pretos durante os 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se la legislazione anti-anti-lynching mai 
non firmata del Franklin D. Roosevelt ed ha perdonato la distinzione 
contro i neri nei programmi federalmente costituiti un fondo per di 
rilievo, ancora ha vinto i cuori ed i voti dei molti Africano. 
Tuttavia questi sostegno e perfino veneration Roosevelt non 
hanno accecato gli Americani neri alla distinzione continua che hanno 
affrontato. Effettivamente, le due viste sono state unite spesso
quando hanno scritto le lettere al presidente gli che chiede di fare 
qualcosa circa distinzione che confrontassero nelle loro vite 
quotidiane. Tre lettere sono incluse qui dalle migliaia che si 
sono versate dentro a Franklin ed a Eleanor Roosevelt dagli Americani 
neri durante i 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και Franklin Δ. Roosevelt δεν επικύρωσε ποτέ τη
νομοθεσία αντι-λυντσαρίσματος και τη συγχωρημένη διάκριση ενάντια
στους Μαύρους στα ομοσπονδιακά χρηματοδοτημένα προγράμματα 
ανακούφισης, κέρδισε ακόμα τις καρδιές και τις ψηφοφορίες πολύ 
Αφρικανού. _ ακόμα αυτός υποστήριξη και ούτε σέβας για 
Ροοσεβελτ όχι τυφλώνω μαύρος Αμερικανός ο συνεχίζομαι διάκριση 
που αυτός αντιμετωπίζω. Πράγματι, οι δύο όψεις 
συνδυάστηκαν συχνά όταν έγραψαν τις επιστολές στον Πρόεδρο που 
ζητά τον για να κάνουν κάτι για τη διάκριση που αντιμετώπισαν 
στις καθημερινές ζωές τους. Τρεις επιστολές 
συμπεριλαμβάνονται εδώ από τις χιλιάδες που έχυσαν μέσα σε 
Franklin και Eleanor Roosevelt από μαύρους Αμερικανούς 
κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '30.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque la legislación contra-anti-lynching nunca 
endosada de Franklin D. Roosevelt y perdonó la discriminación contra
negros en programas federal financiados de la relevación, él 
todavía ganó los corazones y los votos de muchos africano. Con
todo esta ayuda e incluso veneration para Roosevelt no cegaron a 
americanos negros a la discriminación de continuación a que hicieron
frente. De hecho, las dos opiniónes fueron combinadas a menudo 
cuando escribieron letras al presidente que pedía que él haga algo 
sobre la discriminación que enfrentaron en sus vidas diarias. 
Tres cartas se incluyen aquí de los millares que vertieron 
adentro a Franklin y a Eleanor Roosevelt de americanos negros durante 
los años 30.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086737</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103990</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/please-help-us-mr-president-black-americans-write-to-fdr</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
