<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107116</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107116</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087668</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Math Forum at Drexel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathe-Forum bei Drexel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Forum de maths chez Drexel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Forum do math em Drexel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tribuna di per la matematica a Drexel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φόρουμ Math σε Drexel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Foro de la matemáticas en Drexel</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Math Forum is a leading center for mathematics and mathematics education on the Internet. Operating under Drexel's School of Education, our mission is to provide resources, materials, activities, person-to-person interactions, and educational products and services that enrich and support teaching and learning in an increasingly technological world.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Mathe-Forum ist eine führende Mitte für 
Mathematik und Mathematikausbildung auf dem Internet. 
Funktionierend unter Schule Drexels der Ausbildung, ist unsere 
Mission, Betriebsmittel, Materialien, Aktivitäten, person-to-person 
Interaktionen und pädagogische Produkte und Dienstleistungen zur 
Verfügung zu stellen, die das Unterrichten und das Lernen in einer in
zunehmendem Maße technologischen Welt anreichern und unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le forum de maths est un principal centre pour des
mathématiques et l'éducation de mathématiques sur l'Internet. 
Fonctionnant sous l'école de Drexel de l'éducation, notre 
mission est de fournir des ressources, des matériaux, des activités,
des interactions avec préavis, et des produits éducatifs et des 
services qui enrichissent et supportent l'enseignement et l'étude 
dans un monde de plus en plus technologique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O forum do math é um centro principal para a 
matemática e a instrução da matemática no Internet. 
Operando-se sob a escola de Drexel da instrução, nossa missão
é fornecer recursos, materiais, atividades, interações 
person-to-person, e os produtos educacionais e os serviços que 
enriquecem e suportam ensinar e aprender em um mundo cada vez mais 
technological.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La tribuna di per la matematica è un centro 
principale per la matematica e la formazione di matematica sul 
Internet. Funzionando sotto la scuola del Drexel di formazione, 
la nostra missione è di fornire le risorse, materiali, attività, 
interazioni person-to-person e prodotti educativi e servizi che 
arricchiscono e sostengono l'istruzione ed imparare in un mondo sempre
più tecnologico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το φόρουμ Math είναι κύριο κέντρο για τα 
μαθηματικά και εκπαίδευση μαθηματικών στο διαδίκτυο. 
Λειτουργούσα κάτω από το σχολείο Drexel της εκπαίδευσης,
η αποστολή μας είναι να παράσχουμε τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, τα 
υλικά, τις δραστηριότητες, τις person-to-person αλληλεπιδράσεις,
και τα εκπαιδευτικές προϊόντα και τις υπηρεσίες που εμπλουτίζουν 
και υποστηρίζουν τη διδασκαλία και την εκμάθηση σε έναν όλο και 
περισσότερο τεχνολογικό κόσμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El foro de la matemáticas es un centro principal 
para las matemáticas y la educación de las matemáticas en el 
Internet. Funcionando bajo la escuela de Drexel de la 
educación, nuestra misión es proporcionar a recursos, los 
materiales, las actividades, las interacciones personales, y los 
productos educativos y los servicios que enriquecen y utilizan la 
enseñanza y aprender en un mundo cada vez más tecnológico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087668</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107116</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/math-forum-at-drexel</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
