<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105493</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105493</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087088</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Their Habits Of Order Are Carried to the Extreme": A Lowell Mill Worker Visits the Shakers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ihre Gewohnheiten der Ordnung werden zum 
Übermaß" getragen: Ein Lowell Tausendstel-Arbeiter besucht die
Schüttele-Apparat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"leurs habitudes de commande sont portées à 
l'extrémité" : Un ouvrier de moulin de Lowell visite les 
dispositifs trembleurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"seus hábitos da ordem são carregados ao 
extremo": Um trabalhador do moinho de Lowell visita os shakers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"le loro abitudini di ordine sono trasportate 
all'estremo": Un operaio del laminatoio de Lowell visita gli 
agitatori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι συνήθειες κατάταξής τους φέρονται στο άκρο": 
Ένας εργαζόμενος μύλων του Lowell επισκέπτεται τους 
δονητές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"sus hábitos de la orden se llevan al extremo": 
Un trabajador del molino de Lowell visita las coctelera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the second quarter of the nineteenth century numerous reform movements emerged; some people even chose to withdraw from society and form ideal or utopian communities. The Shakers were the oldest of these utopian movements. Founded by Mother Ann Lee in 1774, they abandoned the traditional family in favor of a new fellowship of men and women living as celibate brothers and sisters. Many entered Shaker communities in the 1820s and 1830s, attracted by their equality and simple, but spiritual, lifestyle. This anonymous Lowell mill worker made two visits to a Shaker community in New York State and offered a glimpse into the isolated world within. Her opinions changed over time as she found some interesting similarities to factory life; the Shakers were as industrious as any factory worker, paying close attention to their bell schedule.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im zweiten Viertel des 19.jahrhunderts 
zahlreichen tauchten die Reformbewegungen auf; einige Leute 
beschlossen sogar, von der Gesellschaft zurückzutreten und die 
idealen oder utopischen Gemeinschaften zu bilden. Die 
Schüttele-Apparat waren dieser utopischen Bewegungen das älteste. 
Gegründet durch Motherann Schutze 1774, verließen sie die 
traditionelle Familie zugunsten eines neuen Stipendiums der Männer 
und der Frauen, die als celibate Brüder und Schwestern leben. 
Viele trugen Schüttel-Apparatgemeinschaften in in das durch 
ihre Gleichheit angezogene ein und einfache 1820s und das 1830s, aber 
Angelegenheiten, Lebensstil. Dieser anonyme Lowell 
Tausendstelarbeiter bildete einer Schüttel-Apparatgemeinschaft im 
Staat New-York zwei Besuche und bot einen Blick in die lokalisierte 
Welt innen an. Ihre Meinungen änderten Überzeit, während sie 
etwas interessante Ähnlichkeiten zum Fabrikleben fand; die 
Schüttele-Apparat waren so industrious wie jeder möglicher Arbeiter 
und lenkten nahe Aufmerksamkeit auf ihren Glocke Zeitplan.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le deuxième trimestre du dix-neuvième 
siècle nombreux les mouvements de réforme ont émergé ; 
certains ont même choisi de se retirer de la société et de 
former les communautés idéales ou utopiques. Les dispositifs 
trembleurs étaient les plus vieux de ces mouvements utopiques. 
Fondé par la lie de Mother Ann en 1774, ils ont abandonné la 
famille traditionnelle en faveur d'une nouvelle camaraderie des hommes
et des femmes vivant comme frères et soeurs de célibataire. 
Beaucoup ont écrit les communautés de dispositif trembleur 
dans le 1820s et le 1830s, attirés par leur égalité et simples, 
mais le chant religieux, style de vie. Cet ouvrier anonyme de 
moulin de Lowell a fait deux visites à une communauté de dispositif 
trembleur dans l'état de New-York et a offert un aperçu dans le 
monde d'isolement en dedans. Ses avis ont changé le temps fini 
pendant qu'elle trouvait quelques similitudes intéressantes à la vie
d'usine ; les dispositifs trembleurs étaient aussi travailleurs
que n'importe quel ouvrier d'usine, prêtant une attention 
particulière à leur programme de cloche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No segundo quarto do décimo nono século os 
movimentos de reforma numerosos emergiram; alguns povos 
escolheram mesmo retirar-se da sociedade e dar forma a comunidades 
ideais ou utópicas. Os shakers eram os mais velhos destes 
movimentos utópicos. Fundado por lee de Matriz Ann em 1774, 
abandonaram a família tradicional no favor de um fellowship novo dos 
homens e das mulheres que vivem como irmãos e irmãs do celibate. 
Muitos incorporaram comunidades do shaker ao 1820s e ao 1830s, 
atraídos por sua igualdade e simples, mas espiritual, lifestyle. 
Este trabalhador anonymous do moinho de Lowell fêz duas visitas
a uma comunidade do shaker no estado de New York e ofereceu um glimpse
no mundo isolado dentro. Suas opiniões mudaram o tempo 
excedente enquanto encontrou algumas similaridades interessantes à 
vida da fábrica; os shakers eram tão industrious quanto todo o
trabalhador de fábrica, pagando a atenção próxima a sua 
programação do sino.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel secondo trimestre del diciannovesimo secolo i 
movimenti di riforma numerosi sono emerso; qualche gente persino
ha scelto ritirarsi dalla società e formare le Comunità ideali o 
utopian. Gli agitatori erano il più vecchio di questi movimenti
utopian. Fondato dai rifugi della Mother Ann in 1774, hanno 
abbandonato la famiglia tradizionale per un nuovo fellowship degli 
uomini e delle donne che vivono come i fratelli e sorelle del 
celibate. Molti Comunità inserite dell'agitatore nel 1820s e 
nel 1830s, attratto dalla loro uguaglianza e semplice, ma spiritual, 
lifestyle. Questo operaio anonimo del laminatoio de Lowell reso 
a due chiamate ad una Comunità dell'agitatore a New York 
Dichiara ed offerto un glimpse nel mondo isolato dentro. 
I suoi pareri hanno cambiato col tempo mentre ha trovato alcune 
somiglianze interessanti a vita della fabbrica; gli agitatori 
erano industrious quanto tutto l'operaio di fabbrica, prestante 
l'attenzione particolare al loro programma della flangia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο δεύτερο τέταρτο του δέκατου έννατου αιώνα τα 
πολυάριθμα κινήματα μεταρρύθμισης προέκυψαν  μερικοί 
άνθρωποι επέλεξαν ακόμη και να αποσύρουν από την κοινωνία και να
διαμορφώσουν τις ιδανικές ή ουτοπιστικές κοινότητες. Οι 
δονητές ήταν οι παλαιότεροι αυτών των ουτοπιστικών μετακινήσεων.
Ιδρυμένοι από τη μητέρα ANN Lee το 1774, 
εγκατέλειψαν την παραδοσιακή οικογένεια υπέρ μιας νέας 
υποτροφίας των ανδρών και των γυναικών που ζουν ως άγαμοι αδελφοί
και αδελφές. Πολλοί μπήκαν στις κοινότητες δονητών στο 
1820s και το 1830s, που προσελκύστηκαν από την ισότητα και 
απλός, αλλά το σπιρίτσουάλ τους, τρόπος ζωής. Αυτός ο 
ανώνυμος εργαζόμενος μύλων του Lowell έκανε δύο επισκέψεις σε
μια κοινότητα δονητών στο κράτος της Νέας Υόρκης και πρόσφερε 
μια αναλαμπή στον απομονωμένο κόσμο μέσα. Οι απόψεις της 
άλλαξαν κατά τη διάρκεια του χρόνου δεδομένου ότι βρήκε 
μερικές ενδιαφέρουσες ομοιότητες στη ζωή εργοστασίων  οι 
δονητές ήταν τόσο εργατικοί όσο οποιοσδήποτε εργαζόμενος 
εργοστασίων, που δίνει μεγάλη προσοχή στο πρόγραμμα κουδουνιών 
τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el segundo trimestre del diecinueveavo siglo 
los movimientos de reforma numerosos emergieron; alguna gente 
incluso eligió retirarse de sociedad y formar a comunidades ideales o
utópicas. Las coctelera eran las más viejas de estos 
movimientos utópicos. Fundado por las heces de Mother Ana en 
1774, abandonaron a familia tradicional en favor de una nueva beca de 
los hombres y de las mujeres que vivían como hermanos y hermanas del 
celibate. Muchos incorporaron comunidades de la coctelera al 
1820s y al 1830s, atraídos por su igualdad y simples, pero el 
espiritual, forma de vida. Este trabajador anónimo del molino 
de Lowell hizo dos visitas a una comunidad de la coctelera en el 
estado de Nueva York y ofreció una ojeada en el mundo aislado dentro.
Sus opiniones cambiaron en un cierto plazo mientras que ella 
encontró algunas semejanzas interesantes a la vida de la fábrica; 
las coctelera eran tan industrious como cualquier trabajador de 
fábrica, prestando la atención cercana a su horario de la alarma.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087088</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105493</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/their-habits-of-order-are-carried-to-the-extreme-a-lowell-mill-worker-visits-the-shakers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
