<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108207</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108207</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086092</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Divided We Conquer: A White Plantation Owner Undermines the Knights of Labor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geteilt Erobern Wir: Ein weißer 
Plantage-Inhaber untergräbt die Ritter der Arbeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Divisé Nous Conquérons : Un propriétaire 
blanc de plantation mine les chevaliers du travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dividido Nós Conquistamos: Um proprietário
branco da plantação undermines os knights do trabalho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Diviso Conquistiamo: Un proprietario bianco 
della piantagione insidia i cavalieri del Lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαιρεμένοι κατακτάμε: Ένας λευκός ιδιοκτήτης 
φυτειών υπονομεύει τους ιππότες της εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dividido Conquistamos: Un propietario blanco
de la plantación mina a caballeros del trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The issue of race divided the Southern Populist movement. In some ways, it can be seen as uniquely interracial for its time, yet in other respects it was critically limited by racial divisions. Even in the heyday of Populism, not all members of the Southern Farmers' Alliance were equally committed to the interracial program that some leaders advocated. While white and Colored Farmers' Alliances joined at times in cooperative purchasing and marketing arrangements, the tension between black and white agrarians remained strong. In the late 1880s, African Americans, who were suspicious of the white Alliance, joined the Knights of Labor. Many southern whites--including members of the Farmers' Alliance--saw the growth of black locals of the Knights as a serious threat. This 1889 memorandum by white North Carolina plantation owner John Bryan Grimes recorded his efforts to infiltrate a Knights of Labor local that some of his black workers had joined. Although Grimes was himself a Populist, he viewed the Knights as a threat to his interests.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ausgabe des Rennens teilte die südliche 
Volksbewegung. Irgendwie kann es gesehen werden, wie eindeutig 
interracial während seiner Zeit, dennoch in anderem Respekt wurde es 
kritisch durch rassische Abteilungen begrenzt. Sogar in der 
Blütezeit des Populismus, wurden nicht alle Bauteile des 
südlichen Bündnisses der Landwirte gleichmäßig am interracial 
Programm festgelegt, das einige Führer befürworteten. Während
die Bündnisse der weißen und farbigen Landwirte, die manchmal in den
Mitwirkendkauf- und -marketing-Vorbereitungen, die Spannkraft zwischen
den schwarzen und weißen agrarians verbunden wurden, stark blieben. 
Im späten 1880s verbanden afrikanische Amerikaner, die vom 
weißen Bündnis mißtrauisch waren, die Ritter der Arbeit. Viel
südliches Weiß -- einschließlich Bauteile des Bündnisses der 
Landwirte -- Säge das Wachstum der schwarzen Einheimischer der Ritter
als ernste Drohung. Dieses Protokoll 1889 durch weißen 
Nord-Carolina Plantageinhaber John Bryan Grimes speicherte seine 
Bemühungen, Ritter des Arbeit Einheimischen einzusickern, die einige 
seiner schwarzen Arbeiter verbunden hatten. Obgleich Grimes 
selbst ein Populist war, sah er die Ritter als Drohung zu seinen 
Interessen an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La question de la course a divisé le mouvement 
populiste méridional. Par certains côtés, il peut voir comme 
seulement interracial pour son temps, pourtant à d'autres égards il 
a été en critique limité par des divisions raciales. Même 
dans l'apogée du Populisme, non tous les membres de l'alliance 
des fermiers méridionaux ont été également investis dans le 
programme interracial que quelques amorces ont préconisé. 
Tandis que les alliances des fermiers blancs et colorés 
associées parfois aux agencements d'achat et de vente de 
coopérative, la tension entre les agrarians noirs et blancs 
demeuraient fortes. Vers la fin de 1880s, les Américains 
africains, qui étaient soupçonneux de l'alliance blanche, ont joint 
les chevaliers du travail. Beaucoup de blancs méridionaux -- 
comprenant des membres de l'alliance des fermiers -- scie la 
croissance des gens du pays noirs des chevaliers comme menace 
sérieuse. Ce mémorandum 1889 par le propriétaire du nord 
blanc John Bryan Grimes de plantation de la Caroline a enregistré ses
efforts d'infiltrer les chevaliers des gens du pays de travail que 
certains de ses ouvriers noirs avaient joints. Bien que Grimes 
ait été lui-même un populiste, il a visualisé les chevaliers comme
menace à ses intérêts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A introdução da raça dividiu o movimento 
populist do sul. Em algumas maneiras, pode-se ver como 
excepcionalmente interracial por seu tempo, contudo em outros 
respeitos foi limitado crìticamente por divisões raciais. 
Mesmo no heyday de Populism, não todos os membros do alliance 
dos fazendeiros do sul foram cometidos ingualmente ao programa 
interracial que alguns líderes advogaram. Quando os alliances 
dos fazendeiros brancos e coloridos juntados às vezes nos arranjos 
comprar e de marketing do cooperative, a tensão entre agrarians 
pretos e brancos remanesceram fortes. No 1880s atrasado, os 
americanos africanos, que eram suspicious do alliance branco, juntaram
os knights do trabalho. Muitos brancos do sul -- including 
membros do alliance dos fazendeiros -- serra o crescimento de locals 
pretos dos knights como uma ameaça séria. Este memorando 1889 
pelo proprietário branco John Bryan Grimes da plantação de 
North.carolina gravou seus esforços infiltrate os knights do local do
trabalho que alguns de seus trabalhadores pretos tinham juntado. 
Embora Grimes fosse ele mesmo um populist, viu os knights como 
uma ameaça a seus interesses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'emissione della corsa ha diviso il movimento 
populistico del sud. Per alcuni versi, può essere visto come 
unicamente interracial per il relativo tempo, tuttavia in altri 
rispetti è stato limitato criticamente dalle divisioni razziali. 
Anche nel heyday di Populism, non tutti i membri dell'alleanza 
dei coltivatori del sud sono stati impegnati ugualmente nel programma 
interracial che alcuni capi hanno sostenuto. Mentre le 
alleanze dei coltivatori bianchi e colorati si sono associate 
occasionalmente alle disposizioni di acquisto e di vendita della 
cooperativa, il tensionamento fra i agrarians neri e bianchi è 
rimasto forte. Verso la fine di 1880s, gli Americani africani, 
che erano sospettosi dell'alleanza bianca, hanno unito i cavalieri del
Lavoro. Molti bianchi del sud -- compreso i membri 
dell'alleanza dei coltivatori -- sega lo sviluppo dei locals neri dei 
cavalieri come minaccia seria. Questo memorandum 1889 dal 
proprietario bianco John Bryan Grimes della piantagione del 
North.carolina ha registrato i suoi sforzi infiltrarsi nei cavalieri 
del local di Lavoro che alcuni dei suoi operai neri avevano 
unito. Anche se Grimes era egli stesso un populist, ha osservato
i cavalieri come minaccia ai suoi interessi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ζήτημα της φυλής διαίρεσε τη νότια λαϊκιστική 
μετακίνηση. Με κάποιους τρόπους, μπορεί να δει 
όπως μεμονωμένα διαφυλετικός για το χρόνο της, όμως από άλλες 
απόψεις περιορίστηκε αυστηρά από τα φυλετικά τμήματα. 
Ακόμη και στο απόγειο του λαϊκισμού, δεν ήταν όλα τα μέλη
της συμμαχίας των νότιων αγροτών εξίσου δεσμευμένα στο 
διαφυλετικό πρόγραμμα που μερικοί ηγέτες υποστήριξαν. Ενώ 
οι άσπρες και χρωματισμένες συμμαχίες των αγροτών ένωσαν κατά 
περιόδους στις συνεταιριστικές ρυθμίσεις αγοράς και μάρκετινγκ, η
ένταση μεταξύ των μαύρων και άσπρων agrarians παρέμεινε 
ισχυρή. Προς το τέλος 1880s, αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί, που 
ήταν ύποπτοι της άσπρης συμμαχίας, ένωσαν τους ιππότες της 
εργασίας. Πολλά νότια λευκά -- συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
μελών της συμμαχίας των αγροτών -- εβλέίδαν την αύξηση των
μαύρων locals των ιπποτών ως σοβαρή απειλή. Αυτό το 
υπόμνημα 1889 από το λευκό ιδιοκτήτη John Bryan Grimes
φυτειών της βόρειας Καρολίνας κατέγραψε τις προσπάθειές του να 
διεισδύσει τους ιππότες της εργασίας τοπικούς που μερικοί από 
τους μαύρους εργαζομένους του είχαν ενώσει. Αν και Grimes
ήταν ο ίδιος ένα λαϊκιστικό, εμφάνισε τους ιππότες ως απειλή 
στα ενδιαφέροντά του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La aplicación la raza dividió el movimiento 
populista meridional. De algunas maneras, puede ser visto como 
únicamente interracial por su tiempo, con todo en otros respectos fue
limitado críticamente por divisiones raciales. Incluso en el 
apogeo del Populismo, no todos los miembros de la alianza de los 
granjeros meridionales fueron confiados igualmente al programa 
interracial que algunos arranques de cinta abogaron. Mientras 
que las alianzas de los granjeros blancos y coloreados unidas 
ocasionalmente en los arreglos el comprar y de la comercialización de
la cooperativa, la tensión entre los agrarians negros y blancos 
seguían siendo fuertes. En el último 1880s, los americanos 
africanos, que eran sospechosos de la alianza blanca, ensamblaron a 
caballeros del trabajo. Muchos blancos meridionales -- 
incluyendo los miembros de la alianza de los granjeros -- sierra el 
crecimiento de los locals negros de los caballeros como amenaza seria.
Este memorándum 1889 del propietario blanco Juan Bryan Grimes 
de la plantación de Carolina del Norte registró sus esfuerzos de 
infiltrar a los caballeros del local del trabajo a que algunos de sus 
trabajadores negros habían ensamblado. Aunque Grimes era sí 
mismo un populist, él vio a caballeros como amenaza a sus intereses.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086092</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108207</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/divided-we-conquer-a-white-plantation-owner-undermines-the-knights-of-labor</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
