<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103643</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103643</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087275</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Black Joke."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ein Schwarzer Witz."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Une Plaisanterie Noire."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Um Gracejo Preto."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Uno Scherzo Nero."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα μαύρο αστείο."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Una Broma Negra."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Free African Americans living in the North before the Civil War suffered enormous disadvantages and discriminations. Forced to sit in separate and inferior sections in theaters, public transit, and churches, free blacks were also barred from all but the most menial jobs and denied entrance to white trade unions. This racist cartoon in an 1854 edition of the humor magazine  Yankee Notions  inadvertently illustrated the everyday harassment and cruelty to which northern African Americans were subjected. At a performance of a play based on Harriet Beecher Stowe's antislavery novel,  Uncle Tom's Cabin , some white members altered a seat reservation card and, to the derisive laughter of the rest of the audience, pinned it on a black woman's shawl.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geben Sie die afrikanischen Amerikaner frei, die im Norden
vor den erlittenen enormen Nachteilen und den Unterscheidungen des 
Bürgerkrieges leben. Erzwungen, um in den unterschiedlichen und
minderwertigen Kapiteln in den Theatern, allgemeine Durchfahrt zu 
sitzen und Kirchen, wurden freie Schwarze auch von allen aber von den 
menial Jobs abgehalten und den weißen Gewerkschaften Eingang 
verweigerten. Diese rassistische Karikatur in einer Ausgabe 1854
der Stimmungzeitschrift Yankee Begriffe veranschaulichte 
unbeabsichtigt die tägliche Belästigung und die Grausamkeit, denen 
afrikanische Nordamerikaner unterworfen wurden. An einer 
Leistung eines Spiels, das auf Harriet Beecher Stowes antislavery 
Roman, Onkel Toms Cabin basierte, änderten einige weiße Bauteile 
eine Platzreservierung Karte und, zum spöttischen Gelächter des 
Restes der Publikum, steckten sie auf einem Schal der schwarzen Frau 
fest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Libérez les Américains africains vivant dans le 
nord avant inconvénients soufferts et les discriminations de 
guerre civile les énormes. Forcé à se reposer dans les 
sections séparées et inférieures dans les théâtres, passage 
public, et les églises, des noirs libres ont été également 
empêchés de tout sauf des travaux les plus serviles et ont nié 
l'entrée aux syndicats blancs. Ce dessin animé raciste dans 
une édition 1854 des notions de Yankee de magasin d'humeur a par 
distraction illustré le harcèlement et la cruauté journaliers 
auxquels des Américains africains nordiques ont été soumis. 
À une exécution d'un jeu basé sur le roman d'antiesclavagiste de 
Harriet Beecher Stowe, la carlingue d'oncle Tom, quelques 
membres blancs a modifié une carte de réservation de siège et, au 
rire dérisoire du reste des assistances, l'a goupillée sur un châle
de femme noire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Livre os americanos africanos que vivem no norte antes das
desvantagens enormes sofridas e das discriminações da guerra civil. 
Forçado para sentar-se em seções separadas e inferior nos 
teatros, trânsito público, e as igrejas, os pretos livres também 
foram barrados de tudo mas dos trabalhos os mais menial e negaram a 
entrada às uniões de comércio brancas. Este cartoon racist em
uma edição 1854 das noções de Yankee do compartimento do humor 
ilustrou inadvertidamente o harassment e a crueldade diários a que os
americanos africanos do norte foram sujeitados. Em um desempenho
de um jogo baseado na novela do antislavery de Harriet Beecher Stowe, 
Cabine do tio Tom, alguns membros brancos alteraram um cartão do 
reservation de assento e, ao laughter derisive do descanso das 
audiências, fixaram-no em um shawl de mulher preta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Liberi gli Americani africani che vivono nel nord prima 
degli svantaggi enormi sofferti e delle distinzioni di guerra civile. 
Forzato per sedersi nelle sezioni separate ed inferiori nei 
teatri, transito pubblico e chiese, i neri liberi egualmente sono 
stati esclusi tutti ma dai lavori più menial ed hanno negato 
l'entrata ai sindacati bianchi. Questo fumetto razzista in 
un'edizione 1854 delle nozioni di Yankee dello scomparto di umore ha 
illustrato involontariamente il harassment e la crudeltà giornalieri 
a cui gli Americani africani nordici sono stati sottoposti. Alle
prestazioni di un gioco basato sul romanzo di antislavery di Harriet 
Beecher Stowe, Cabin dello zio Tom, alcuni membri bianchi hanno 
alterato una scheda di prenotazione posti e, al laughter derisive del 
resto dei pubblici, la hanno appuntata su uno scialle della donna 
nera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ελεύθεροι αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί που ζουν στο Βορρά 
πριν από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο υπέστησαν τα τεράστιες μειονεκτήματα
και τις διακρίσεις. Αναγκασμένοι να καθίσουν στα χωριστά και
κατώτερα τμήματα στα θέατρα, δημόσια διέλευση, και εκκλησίες, οι
ελεύθεροι Μαύροι φράχτηκαν επίσης από όλες εκτός από τις 
menial εργασίες και αρνήθηκαν την είσοδο στα λευκά συνδικάτα. 
Αυτά τα ρατσιστικά κινούμενα σχέδια σε μια έκδοση 1854 
των εννοιών Αμερικανού περιοδικών χιούμορ επεξήγησαν ακούσια την
καθημερινές παρενόχληση και τη σκληρότητα στις οποίες βόρειοι 
αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί υποβλήθηκαν. Σε μια απόδοση ενός 
παιχνιδιού βασισμένου στο ενάντιο στη δουλεία μυθιστόρημα του 
Harriet Beecher Stowe's, καμπίνα θείου Tom, μερικά 
λευκά μέλη άλλαξαν μια κάρτα επιφύλαξης καθισμάτων και, στο 
derisive γέλιο του υπολοίπου του ακροατηρίου, την κάρφωσαν στο 
σάλι μιας μαύρης γυναίκας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Libere a americanos africanos que viven en el norte antes 
de las desventajas enormes sufridas y de las discriminaciones de la 
guerra civil. Forzado para sentarse en secciones separadas e 
inferiores en los teatros, tránsito público, y las iglesias, los 
negros libres también fueron barrados de todos pero de los trabajos 
ma's menial y negaron la entrada a los sindicatos blancos. Esta 
historieta racist en una edición 1854 de las nociones de Yankee del 
compartimiento del humor ilustró inadvertidamente el hostigamiento y 
la crueldad diarios a los cuales sujetaron a los americanos africanos 
norteños. En un funcionamiento de un juego basado en la novela 
del antislavery de Harriet Beecher Stowe, Cabin de tío Tom, algunos 
miembros blancos alteraron una tarjeta de la reservación de asiento 
y, a la risa burlona del resto de las audiencias, la fijaron en un 
mantón de la mujer negra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087275</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103643</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-black-joke</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
