<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104456</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104456</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087008</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The New Woman of the 1920s: Debating Bobbed-Hair</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die neue Frau der zwanziger Jahre: 
Debattieren Des Ruckartig bewegen-Haares</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La nouvelle femme des années 20 : Discussion
Des Pendiller-Cheveux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A mulher nova dos 1920s: Debatendo O 
Sacud-Cabelo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La nuova donna degli anni 20: Dibattere 
Bobbed-Capelli</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα γυναίκα της δεκαετίας του '20: 
Ψοψψεδ-τρίχα συζήτησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La nueva mujer de los años 20: Discutir El 
Menear-Pelo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The "new woman" of the 1910s and 1920s rejected the pieties (and often the politics) of the older generation, smoked and drank in public, celebrated the sexual revolution, and embraced consumer culture. While earlier generations had debated suffrage, political discussions of feminism were seldom the stuff of popular media in the 1920s. Instead, magazines such as  Ladies Home Journal  and  Pictorial Review  presented readers with the debate: "To Bob or Not to Bob?" The short, sculpted hair of the "bob" marked a startling visual departure from the upswept and carefully dressed hair of the early twentieth-century Gibson Girl. Dancer Irene Castle (Treman) inadvertently helped set the fashion when she cut her hair for convenience before entering the hospital for an appendectomy. In these magazine excerpts, Castle, singer Mary Garden, and film star Mary Pickford (known as "America's Sweetheart"), described their decisions to adopt, or not adopt, the new style.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die "neue Frau" der 1910s und der zwanziger Jahre 
wies die pieties (und häufig die Politik) des älteren Erzeugung 
zurück, rauchte und trank in der Öffentlichkeit, gefeiert die 
sexuelle Umdrehung und umfaßte Verbraucherkultur. Während 
frühere Erzeugungen Stimmrecht debattiert hatten, waren politische 
Diskussionen über den Feminismus selten das Material der populären 
Media in den zwanziger Jahren anstatt, Zeitschriften wie 
Dame-Hauptjournal und die bildhafte Zusammenfassung, die Leser mit der
Debatte dargestellt wurde: "zu Bob oder nicht zu Bob?" Der
Kurzschluß, sculpted Haar des "Pendels" kennzeichnete eine startling 
Sichtabfahrt vom upswept und kleidete sorgfältig Haar des frühen 
Zwanzigstjahrhundert Gibson Mädchens. Geholfenes Set des 
Tänzer Irene Schlosses (Treman) unbeabsichtigt die Art und Weise, als
sie ihr Haar für Bequemlichkeit schnitt, bevor sie das Krankenhaus 
für einen Appendectomy betrat. In diesen Zeitschrift Excerpts 
beschrieben Schloß, Sänger Mary Garten und Filmstar Mary Pickford 
(bekannt als "Schatz Amerikas"), ihre Entscheidungen, um anzunehmen 
oder nicht anzunehmen, die neue Art.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La "nouvelle femme" des années 10 et des années 
20 a rejeté les pieties (et souvent la politique) de la génération 
plus ancienne, a fumé et a bu l'en public, célébré la révolution 
sexuelle, et culture embrassée du consommateur. Tandis que les 
premières générations avaient discuté le suffrage, les discussions
politiques du féminisme étaient rarement la substance des medias 
populaires dans les années 20. Au lieu de cela, les magasins 
tels que le journal à la maison de dames et la revue imagée ont 
présenté des lecteurs avec la discussion : "à Bob ou pas à 
Bob?" Le short, sculpted des cheveux du "plomb" a marqué un 
départ visuel effrayant aux cheveux élevés et soigneusement 
habillés de la première fille de Gibson de vingtième-siècle. 
Positionnement par distraction aidé de château d'Irene de 
danseur (Treman) la mode quand elle a coupé ses cheveux pour la 
convenance avant d'entrer dans l'hôpital pour un appendectomy. 
Dans ces extraits de magasin, le château, le jardin de Mary de 
chanteur, et le film tiennent le premier rôle Mary Pickford (connu sous le nom 
de "amoureux de l'Amérique"), décrit leurs décisions pour adopter, 
ou pour ne pas adopter, le nouveau modèle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a mulher nova" dos 1910s e dos 1920s rejeitou os 
pieties (e frequentemente a política) da geração mais velha, fumou 
e bebeu-os no público, comemorado a volta sexual, e cultura embraced 
do consumidor. Quando umas gerações mais adiantadas tinham 
debatido o suffrage, as discussões políticas do feminismo eram 
raramente o material de media populares nos 1920s. preferivelmente, 
compartimentos tais como o jornal home das senhoras e revisão 
pictorial apresentada leitores com o debate: "a Bob ou não a 
Bob?" O short, sculpted o cabelo do "prumo" marcou uma partida 
visual startling do upswept e vestiu com cuidado o cabelo da menina de
Gibson adiantada de vigésimo-século. Jogo inadvertidamente 
ajudado do castelo de Irene do dancer (Treman) a forma quando cortou 
seu cabelo para a conveniência antes de entrar no hospital para um 
appendectomy. Nestes excerpts do compartimento, o castelo, o 
jardim de Mary do singer, e a estrela de película Mary Pickford 
(sabido como de "o sweetheart América"), descreveram suas decisões 
para adotar, ou para não adotar, o estilo novo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la nuova donna" degli anni 10 e degli anni 20 ha 
rifiutato i pieties (e spesso la politica) di più vecchia 
generazione, ha fumato e bevuto in pubblico, celebrato la rivoluzione 
sessuale e coltura abbracciata del consumatore. Mentre le prime 
generazioni avevano dibattuto il suffrage, le discussioni politiche su
feminism erano raramente il roba dei media popolari negli anni 
20 preferibilmente, scomparti quale il giornale domestico delle 
signore e revisione pittorica presentata i lettori con il dibattito: 
"a Bob o non a Bob?" Lo short, sculpted i capelli "del 
peso" ha contrassegnato una partenza visiva startling dal upswept e 
con attenzione ha vestito i capelli della ragazza di Gibson in 
anticipo di ventesimo-secolo. Insieme involontariamente aiutato 
del castello di Irene del ballerino (Treman) il modo quando ha 
tagliato i suoi capelli per convenienza prima di entrare nell'ospedale
per un appendectomy. In questi brani dello scomparto, il 
castello, il giardino della Mary del cantante e la stella di pellicola
Mary Pickford (conosciuto come "l'innamorato dell'America"), hanno 
descritto le loro decisioni per adottare, o per non adottare, il nuovo
stile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η "νέα γυναίκα" του 1910s και της δεκαετίας του '20 
απέρριψε τις ευσέβειες (και συχνά την πολιτική) της παλαιότερης 
γενεάς, κάπνισε και ήπιε στο κοινό, γιόρτασε τη σεξουαλική 
επανάσταση, και αγκαλίασε τον καταναλωτικό πολιτισμό. Ενώ 
οι προηγούμενες γενεές είχαν συζητήσει την ψήφο, οι πολιτικές 
συζητήσεις του φεμινισμού ήταν σπάνια η ουσία των δημοφιλών 
μέσων στη δεκαετία του '20 Αντ' αυτού, τα περιοδικά όπως το
περιοδικό γυναικείων "Οικιαών και η εικονογραφική αναθεώρηση 
παρουσίασαν στους αναγνώστες με τη συζήτηση: "Στο βαρίδι ή 
όχι στο βαρίδι;" Ο κοντός, η τρίχα του "βαριδιού" 
χαρακτήρισε μια τρομάζοντας οπτική αναχώρηση από την ανυψωμένη 
και προσεκτικά ντυμένη τρίχα του πρώτου κοριτσιού Gibson 
εικοστός-αιώνα. Ο χορευτής Irene Castle (Treman) 
ακούσια βοήθησε το σύνολο η μόδα όταν έκοψε την τρίχα της για 
την ευκολία πρίν εισάγει το νοσοκομείο για ένα appendectomy. 
Σε αυτά τα αποσπάσματα περιοδικών, το Castle, ο 
τραγουδιστής Mary Garden, και το αστέρι Mary Pickford 
ταινιών (γνωστό ως "αγαπημένος της Αμερικήσ"), περιέγραψαν τις 
αποφάσεις τους να υιοθετήσουν, ή να μην υιοθετήσουν, το νέο 
ύφος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La "nueva mujer" de los años 10 y de los años 20 
rechazó los pieties (y a menudo la política) de la más vieja 
generación, fumó y bebió en el público, celebrado la revolución 
sexual, y cultura abrazada del consumidor. Mientras que 
generaciones primeras habían discutido sufragio, las discusiones 
políticas del feminismo eran raramente la materia de media populares 
en los años 20 en lugar de otro, compartimientos tales como diario 
casero de las señoras y revisión ilustrada presentada programas de 
lectura con el discusión: "a Bob o no a Bob?" El 
cortocircuito, sculpted el pelo de la "sacudida" marcó una salida 
visual alarmante del upswept y vistió cuidadosamente el pelo de la 
muchacha de Gibson temprana del vige'simo-siglo. Conjunto 
inadvertidamente ayudado del castillo de Irene del bailarín (Treman) 
la manera cuando ella cortó su pelo para la conveniencia antes de 
entrar en el hospital para un appendectomy. En estos extractos 
del compartimiento, el castillo, el jardín de Maria del cantante, y 
el actor de cine Maria Pickford (conocido como "amor de América"), 
describieron sus decisiones para adoptar, o para no adoptar, el nuevo 
estilo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087008</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104456</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-new-woman-of-the-1920s-debating-bobbed-hair</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
