<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104920</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104920</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206370</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Maps of Indian Territory, the Dawes Act, and Will Rogers' Enrollment Case File</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Karten der indischen Gegend, der Dawes Tat und der
Einschreibung-Fall-Datei Willerogers'</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cartes de territoire indien, de la Loi de Dawes, 
et de fichier de cas de l'inscription de Rogers de volonté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mapas do território indian, do ato de Dawes, e da
lima do caso do registro de Rogers' da vontade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programmi del territorio indiano, della Legge di 
Dawes e dell'archivio di caso di iscrizione del Rogers di volontà</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι χάρτες του ινδικού εδάφους, ο νόμος Dawes, και 
αρχείο περίπτωσης εγγραφής Rogers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Correspondencias del territorio indio, del acto de
Dawes, y del fichero del caso de la inscripción de Rogers de la 
voluntad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">encourages students to study a variety of documents to understand the impact of a particular piece of legislation and relates to the powers granted to Congress in Article I, Section 8 , of the Constitution, related to making laws. It correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences. It also has cross-curricular connections with with history, government, global studies, and music.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">regt Kursteilnehmer an, eine Vielzahl der 
Dokumente zu studieren, um die Auswirkung eines bestimmten Stückes 
Gesetzgebung zu verstehen und steht auf den Energien in Verbindung, 
die Kongreß in Artikel I, das Kapitel 8, der Beschaffenheit bewilligt
werden, in Verbindung gestanden auf dem Bilden von von Gesetzen. 
Sie bezieht mit den nationalen Geschichte Standards und den 
nationalen Standards für Gemeinschaftskunde und Sozialwissenschaften 
aufeinander. Sie hat auch Kreuzlehrplananschlüsse mit mit 
Geschichte, Regierung, globalen Studien und Musik.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">encourage des étudiants à étudier une variété
de documents pour comprendre l'impact d'un texte de loi particulier et
associe aux puissances accordées au congrès en article I, la section
8, de la constitution, liée à faire des lois. Elle se corrèle
avec les normes nationales d'histoire et les normes nationales pour 
l'éducation civique et les sciences sociales. Elle a également
les connexions croix-curriculaires avec avec l'histoire, le 
gouvernement, les études globales, et la musique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">incentiva estudantes estudar uma variedade dos 
originais para compreender o impacto de uma parte de legislação 
particular e relaciona-se às potências concedidas ao congress no 
artigo I, seção 8, do constitution, relacionada a fazer leis. 
Correlaciona aos padrões nacionais do history e aos padrões 
nacionais para o civics e ciências sociais. Tem também 
conexões cruz-cross-curricular com com o history, o governo, os 
estudos globais, e a música.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiglia agli allievi studiare una varietà di 
documenti per capire l'effetto di una parte di legislazione 
particolare e si riferisce alle potenzi assegnate al congresso in 
articolo I, la parte 8, della costituzione, relativa a fare le leggi. 
Correla agli standard nazionali di storia ed agli standard 
nazionali per civics e le scienze sociali. Egualmente ha 
collegamenti traversa-d'insegnamento con con storia, il governo, gli 
studi globali e la musica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ενθαρρύνει τους σπουδαστές για να μελετήσει ποικίλα 
έγγραφα για να καταλάβει τον αντίκτυπο ενός ιδιαίτερου κομματιού
της νομοθεσίας και αφορά τις δυνάμεις που χορηγούνται το συνέδριο
στο άρθρο Ι, παράγραφος 8, του συντάγματος, σχετική με την 
παραγωγή των νόμων. Συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας
και τα εθνικά πρότυπα για Civics και τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες. 
Έχει επίσης τις διαγώνιος-διδακτικές συνδέσεις με με την 
ιστορία, την κυβέρνηση, τις σφαιρικές μελέτες, και τη μουσική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">anima a estudiantes que estudien una variedad de 
documentos para entender el impacto de un pedazo de legislación 
determinado y se relaciona con las potencias concedidas al congreso en
el artículo I, sección 8, de la constitución, relacionada con la 
fabricación de leyes. Correlaciona a los estándares nacionales
de la historia y a los estándares nacionales para el civics y las 
ciencias sociales. También tiene conexiones cruz-del plan de 
estudios con con historia, el gobierno, estudios globales, y música.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206370</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104920</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/maps-of-indian-territory-the-dawes-act-and-will-rogers-enrollment-case-file</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
