<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103783</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103783</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chemical Weathering</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chemischer Weathering</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Désagrégation chimique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Weathering Químico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Weathering Chimico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χημική διάβρωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Desgaste por la acción atmosférica Químico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides visual resources that illustrate the process of chemical weathering. Animations demonstrate how temperature and precipitation affect the evolution of parent material from highly resistant primary minerals to both secondary minerals and minerals in solution, as well as showing rates of weathering of various common minerals. A collection of photographs gives examples of chemical weathering in both natural outcrops and constructed features such as tombstones and carvings. These resources can be integrated into lectures, labs or other activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert Sichtbetriebsmittel, die den 
Prozeß des chemischen Weathering veranschaulichen. Animationen 
zeigen, wie Temperatur und Niederschlag die Entwicklung des 
Grundwerkstoffs von den in hohem Grade beständigen Primärmineralien 
zu beiden Sekundärmineralien und von den Mineralien in gelöster Form
beeinflussen, sowie das Zeigen von von Kinetik von Weathering der 
verschiedenen geläufigen Mineralien. Eine Ansammlung 
Fotographien gibt Beispiele des chemischen Weathering im natürlichen 
Zutageliegen und in konstruierten Merkmalen wie Finanzanzeigen und 
Carvings. Diese Betriebsmittel können in Vorträge, in Labors 
oder in andere Aktivitäten integriert werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit les ressources visuelles qui 
illustrent le processus de la désagrégation chimique. Les 
animations démontrent comment la température et la précipitation 
affectent l'évolution du matériel de parent des minerais primaires 
fortement résistants aux deux minerais secondaires et des minerais en
solution, aussi bien que montrer des cadences de la désagrégation de 
divers minerais communs. Une collection de photographies donne 
des exemples de produit chimique survivant à dans les 
affleurements normaux et les dispositifs construits tels que des 
pierres tombales et des découpages. Ces ressources peuvent 
être intégrées dans des conférences, des laboratoires ou d'autres 
activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece os recursos visuais que 
ilustram o processo do weathering químico. Os animations 
demonstram como a temperatura e a precipitação afetam a evolução 
do material de pai dos minerais preliminares altamente resistentes a 
ambos os minerais secundários e dos minerais na solução, as.well.as
mostrar taxas do weathering de vários minerais comuns. Uma 
coleção das fotografias dá exemplos do weathering químico  em 
outcrops naturais e em características construídas tais como 
tombstones e carvings. Estes recursos podem ser integrados em 
lectures, em laboratórios ou em outras atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce le risorse visive che 
illustrano il processo di weathering chimico. Le animazioni 
dimostrano come la temperatura e la precipitazione interessano lo 
sviluppo del materiale di genitore dai minerali primari altamente 
resistenti ad entrambi i minerali secondari e dai minerali in 
soluzione, così come mostrare i tassi di weathering di vari minerali 
comuni. Una collezione di fotografie fornisce gli esempi di 
weathering chimico sia in affioramenti naturali che nelle 
caratteristiche costruite quali i tombstones e le sculture. 
Queste risorse possono essere integrate nelle conferenze, nei 
laboratori o in altre attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει τα οπτικά στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς που επεξηγούν τη διαδικασία της χημικής διάβρωσης. 
Οι ζωτικότητες καταδεικνύουν πώς η θερμοκρασία και η πτώση 
έχουν επιπτώσεις στην εξέλιξη του υλικού γονέων από τα 
ιδιαίτερα ανθεκτικά αρχικά μεταλλεύματα και στα δευτεροβάθμια 
μεταλλεύματα και στα μεταλλεύματα στη λύση, καθώς επίσης και 
εμφανίζοντας ποσοστά διάβρωσης των διάφορων κοινών 
μεταλλευμάτων. Μια συλλογή των φωτογραφιών δίνει τα 
παραδείγματα της χημικής διάβρωσης και στις φυσικές επανθίσεις 
και στα κατασκευασμένα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα όπως οι 
ταφόπετρες και οι γλυπτικές. Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς 
μπορούν να ενσωματωθούν στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια ή άλλες 
δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a los recursos visuales que
ilustran el proceso del desgaste por la acción atmosférica químico.
Las animaciones demuestran cómo la temperatura y la 
precipitación afectan la evolución del material de padre de los 
minerales primarios altamente resistentes a ambos minerales 
secundarios y de los minerales en la solución, así como mostrar 
índices del desgaste por la acción atmosférica de varios minerales 
comunes. Una colección de fotografías da ejemplos del desgaste
por la acción atmosférica químico en afloramientos naturales y 
características construidas tales como piedras sepulcrales y tallas. 
Estos recursos se pueden integrar en conferencias, laboratorios 
u otras actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200871</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103783</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chemical-weathering</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
