<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104490</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104490</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085260</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Struggles for Social Justice</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kämpft für Sozialgerechtigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lutte pour la justice sociale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esforça-se para a justiça social</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lotta per giustizia sociale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προσπάθειες για την κοινωνική δικαιοσύνη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lucha para la justicia social</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The 1960s and early 1970s were characterized by a series of protests as groups that had long felt disempowered sought to make their voices heard. California was the heart of many of these new movements. The protests put into motion by the Civil Rights movement evolved to address social justice issues affecting many groups, including students facing the draft, ordinary people protesting the war, farm workers fighting for better working conditions, Chicanos expressing a new identity, and African Americans who felt that nonviolence as a tactic was no longer working. America's continued involvement in the Vietnam War galvanized many groups. Across the United States, students protested US involvement in the war by resisting the draft. All sorts of people joined in by disrupting "business as usual," marching, and going on strike. One photograph shows a banner declaring "On Strike" hanging over UC Berkeley's Sather Gate; the deserted campus demonstrates widespread support among both faculty and students. Other photographs depict students marching in protest against the war, signing a "Women for Peace" petition, and waving an American flag in an anti-war parade. The Chicano Moratorium Committee protested the war by marching in parades, but they also registered their own social justice agenda: one photograph shows them carrying banners that read, "Our fight is in the barrio, not Vietnam."
People also rallied around workers' rights, pushing boundaries and demanding better working conditions. The United Farm Workers (UFW), co-founded and led by Cesar Chavez, used strikes to protest the unfair treatment that California's mainly Mexican field workers received. In one photograph pickets stand at the edge of a Central California grape field and carry placards that say "Huelga," Spanish for "strike." Another photograph shows UFW co-founder Dolores Huerta addressing a group. Groups demanding their rights did not work in isolation; a 1971 letter from Cesar Chavez to the NAACP reflects the support that existed between the two groups, both of which were fighting for equal treatment under the law. The Oakland, California-based Black Nationalist organization, the Black Panther Party, was fighting for social justice on several fronts, in a way that often confused their more moderate supporters. They strongly promoted important and positive social issues such as free clinics, programs to feed children, and drug rehabilitation programs; yet, at the same time, they embraced controversial and at times violent tactics. Although Panthers were involved in violent clashes with police, it is still unclear whether the Panthers initiated these actions or were simply defending themselves against police violence directed at them. Many of the Panther leaders were persuasive and charismatic speakers, and photographs here show many of them in action: Black Panther Minister of Defense Huey Newton and his wife, Gwen; Black Panther Chairman Bobby Seale in jail; members of the Black Panthers at a press conference; Kathleen Cleaver in a prosecutor's office; and Angela Davis in Los Angeles speaking to the press after a Black Panther shootout. When Huey Newton was put on trial in 1968, accused of murdering a police officer, Black Panthers lined up on the second day of trial to show their support. Another image shows a multiracial crowd gathered at a Huey Newton rally in 1969 at San Francisco's Federal Building.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die sechziger Jahre und die frühen siebziger Jahre
wurden durch eine Reihe Proteste als Gruppen gekennzeichnet, die 
langen Filz disempowered gesucht, ihre gehörten Stimmen zu bilden 
hatten. Kalifornien war das Innere von vielen dieser neuen 
Bewegungen. Die Proteste setzten sich in Bewegung durch die 
Zivilrechtbewegung, die entwickelt wurde, um die 
Sozialgerechtigkeitpunkte anzusprechen, die viele Gruppen, 
einschließlich die Kursteilnehmer beeinflussen, die den Entwurf 
gegenüberstellen, die normalen Leute, die den Krieg protestieren, die
Landarbeiter, die für bessere Arbeitsbedingungen kämpfen, die 
Mexico-Amerikaner, die eine neue Identität ausdrücken, und die 
afrikanischen Amerikaner, die daß Gewaltlosigkeiten glaubten, während 
eine Taktik nicht mehr arbeitete. Amerikas anhaltende 
Miteinbeziehung im Vietnam Krieg galvanisierte viele Gruppen. 
Über den Vereinigten Staaten protestierten Kursteilnehmer US 
Miteinbeziehung im Krieg, indem sie dem Entwurf widerstanden. 
Alle Sortierungen der Leute verbanden innen durch störendes 
"Geschäft, wie üblich,", grenzend, und streikend. Eine 
Fotographie zeigt eine Fahne, die "auf dem Schlag erklärt", der über
Gatter Sather UC Berkeley hängt; der verlassene Campus zeigt 
weitverbreiteten Support unter Lehrkörper und Kursteilnehmern. 
Andere Fotographien stellen die Kursteilnehmer bildlich dar, die
in Protest gegen den Krieg grenzen, eine "Frauen für Friedens" 
Petition unterzeichnen und eine amerikanische Markierungsfahne in 
einer Antikriegsparade wellenartig bewegen. Der 
mexiko-amerikanische Moratorium-Ausschuß protestierte den Krieg, 
indem er in Paraden grenzte, aber sie registrierten auch ihre eigene 
Sozialgerechtigkeittagesordnung: eine Fotographie zeigt ihnen 
tragende Fahnen, die lesen, "unser Kampf ist im Barrio, nicht 
Vietnam."People auch gesammelt um die Rechte der Arbeiter, drückt 
Grenzen und verlangt bessere Arbeitsbedingungen. Die vereinigten
Landarbeiter (UFW), Co-gegründet und von Cesar Chavez geführt, 
verwendete Schläge, die unfaire Behandlung zu protestieren, der 
Kaliforniens, das hauptsächlich mexikanisch ist, die empfangenen 
Arbeiter auffangen. In einer Fotographie stehen Pfosten
am Rand einer Zentrale-Kalifornien Traube auffangen und 
tragen Plakate, die "Huelga sagen," Spanisch für "Schlag." Eine
andere Fotographie zeigt UFW Co-Gründer Dolores Huerta, das eine 
Gruppe anredet. Die Gruppen, die ihre Rechte verlangen, 
arbeiteten nicht isoliert; ein Zeichen 1971 von Cesar Chavez zum
NAACP reflektiert den Support, der zwischen den zwei Gruppen 
existierte, von denen beide für gleiche Behandlung unter dem Gesetz 
kämpften. Das Oakland, Kalifornien-gegründete schwarze 
nationalistische Organisation, die schwarzer Panther-Partei, 
kämpfte für Sozialgerechtigkeit auf einigen Frontseiten, in einer 
Methode, die häufig ihre gemäßigteren Verfechter verwirrte. 
Sie förderten stark wichtige und positive Sozialausgaben wie 
freie Kliniken, Programme, um Kinder und Drogerehabilitationprogramme 
einzuziehen; jedoch gleichzeitig umfaßten sie die umstrittenen 
und manchmal heftigen Taktiken. Obgleich Leoparden in heftiges 
Zusammentreffen in Polizei miteinbezogen wurden, ist sie noch unklar, 
ob die Leoparden diese Tätigkeiten initialisieren oder verteidigte 
sich einfach gegen die Polizeigewalttätigkeit, die an ihnen verwiesen
wird. Viele der Leopard Führer waren überzeugende und 
charismatische Sprecher, und Fotographien hier zeigen viele von ihnen 
in der Tätigkeit: Schwarzer Panther-Minister des Verteidigung 
Huey Newtons und seine Frau, Gwen; Schwarzer 
Panther-Vorsitzend-Schupo Seale im Gefängnis; Bauteile der 
schwarzen Panther bei einer Pressekonferenz; Kathleen Cleaver im
Büro eines Verfolgers; und Angela Davis in Los Angeles, das mit
der Presse nach einem schwarzer Panther shootout spricht. Als 
Huey Newton auf Versuch 1968 gesetzt wurde, beschuldigt von der 
Ermordung eines Polizeioffiziers, die schwarzen Panther, die am 
zweiten Tag des Versuches ausgerichtet wurden, um ihren Support zu 
zeigen. Ein anderes Bild zeigt eine gemischtrassige Masse, die an 
einer Huey Newtonsammlung 1969 San Franciscos am Bundesgebäude 
erfaßt wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les années 60 et le début des années 70 ont 
été caractérisés par une série de protestations comme groupes qui
ont eu le long feutre disempowered recherché à faire leurs voix 
entendues. La Californie était le coeur de plusieurs de ces 
nouveaux mouvements. Les protestations ont mis dans le mouvement
par le mouvement de droits civiques évolué pour aborder les 
questions sociales de justice affectant beaucoup de groupes, y compris
des étudiants faisant face à l'ébauche, gens du commun protestant 
la guerre, ouvriers de ferme combattant pour de meilleures conditions 
de travail, chicanos exprimant une nouvelle identité, et Américains 
africains qui ont estimé que nonviolence pendant qu'une tactique ne 
fonctionnait plus. L'intervention continue de l'Amérique dans 
la guerre de Vietnam a galvanisé beaucoup de groupes. À 
travers les Etats-Unis, les étudiants ont protesté l'intervention 
des USA dans la guerre en résistant à l'ébauche. Tous les 
tris des personnes se sont joints dedans par des "affaires de 
perturbation comme d'habitude," marchant, et faisant la grève. 
Une photographie montre un drapeau déclarant "en grève" 
s'arrêtant au-dessus de la porte de Sather de Berkeley UC ; le 
campus abandonné démontre le support répandu parmi le corps 
enseignant et les étudiants. D'autres photographies dépeignent
des étudiants marchant dans la protestation contre la guerre, signant
des "femmes une pétition pour paix", et ondulant un indicateur 
américain dans un défilé pacifiste. Le Comité chicano de 
moratoire a protesté la guerre en marchant dans les défilés, mais 
elles ont également enregistré leur propre ordre du jour social de 
justice : une photographie leur montre les drapeaux portants qui
lisent, "notre combat est en banlieue, pas Vietnam."People également 
rassemblé autour des droits des ouvriers, poussant des bornes et 
exigeant de meilleures conditions de travail. Les ouvriers unis 
de ferme (UFW), Co-fondés et menés par Cesar Chavez, grèves 
utilisées à protester le traitement injuste que les ouvriers de zone
mexicains de la Californie principalement ont reçu. En une 
photographie les piquets se tiennent au bord d'un gisement central de 
raisin de la Californie et portent les plaquettes qui indiquent 
"Huelga," Espagnol pour la "grève." Une autre photographie 
montre le co-fondateur Dolores Huerta d'UFW s'adressant à un groupe. 
Les groupes exigeant leurs droites n'ont pas travaillé en 
isolation ; une lettre 1971 de Cesar Chavez au NAACP 
reflète le support qui a existé entre les deux groupes, dont tous 
les deux combattaient pour l'égalité de traitement en vertu de la 
loi. Oakland, organisation nationaliste noire Californie-basée,
la partie de panthère noire, combattait pour la justice sociale sur 
plusieurs avants, d'une manière dont a souvent confondu leurs 
défenseurs plus modérés. Ils ont fortement favorisé les 
issues sociales importantes et positives telles que les cliniques 
libres, programmes pour alimenter des enfants, et des programmes de 
réadaptation de drogue ; encore, en même temps, ils ont 
embrassé la tactique controversée et parfois violente. Bien 
que des panthères aient été impliquées dans des désaccords 
violents de la police, elle est encore peu claire si les panthères 
aient lancé ces actions ou se défendait simplement contre la 
violence de police dirigée à eux. Plusieurs des amorces de 
panthère étaient les orateurs persuasifs et charismatiques, et les 
photographies ici montrent bon nombre d'entre elles dans l'action : 
Ministre de panthère noire de newton de Huey de la défense et 
son épouse, Gwen ; Policier Seale de Président de panthère 
noire en prison ; membres des panthères noires à une 
conférence de presse ; Fendoir de Kathleen dans le bureau d'un 
procureur ; et Angela Davis à Los Angeles parlant à la presse 
après un échange de tirs de panthère noire. Quand newton de Huey 
a été mis sur l'épreuve en 1968, accusé d'assassiner un officier 
de police, panthères noires alignées le deuxième jour de l'épreuve
pour montrer leur support. Une autre image montre une foule 
multiraciale recueillie à un rassemblement de newton de Huey en 1969 
au bâtiment fédéral de San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os 1960s e os 1970s adiantados foram 
caracterizados por uma série dos protestos como os grupos que tiveram
o feltro longo disempowered procurado fazer suas vozes ouvidas. 
Califórnia era o coração de muitos destes movimentos novos. 
Os protestos puseram no movimento pelo movimento das direitas 
civis evoluído para dirigir-se às edições sociais da justiça que 
afetam muitos grupos, including os estudantes que enfrentam o esboço,
os povos ordinários que protestam a guerra, os trabalhadores de 
fazenda que lutam por condições de funcionamento melhores, os 
chicanos que expressam uma identidade nova, e os americanos africanos 
que sentiram que nonviolence porque uma tática era um funcionamento 
não mais longo. A participação continuada de América na 
guerra de Vietnam galvanized muitos grupos. Através dos estados
unidos, os estudantes protestaram a participação dos E. U. na guerra
resistindo o esboço. Todas as sortes dos povos juntaram dentro 
pelo "negócio disrupting como usual," marchando, e indo na batida. 
Uma fotografia mostra uma bandeira que declara "na batida" que 
pendura sobre a porta de Sather de Berkeley UC; o campus 
deserted demonstra sustentação difundida entre  a faculdade e os 
estudantes. Outras fotografias descrevem os estudantes que 
marcham no protesto de encontro à guerra, assinando "mulheres para 
uma petição da paz", e acenando uma bandeira americana em uma parada
anti-war. O comitê chicano do moratorium protestou a guerra 
marchando nas paradas, mas registaram também sua própria agenda 
social da justiça: uma fotografia mostra-lhes as bandeiras 
carregando que lêem, "nossa luta está no barrio, não 
Vietnam."People rallied também em torno das direitas dos 
trabalhadores, empurrando limites e exijindo condições de 
funcionamento melhores. Os trabalhadores de fazenda unidos 
(UFW), co-fundados e conduzidos por Cesar Chavez, batidas usadas 
protestar o tratamento unfair que os trabalhadores de campo mexicanos 
de Califórnia principalmente receberam. Em uma fotografia os 
piquetes estão na borda de um campo central da uva de Califórnia e 
carregam os cartazes que dizem "Huelga," espanhol para a "batida." 
Uma outra fotografia mostra o co-co-founder Dolores Huerta de 
UFW que dirige-se a um grupo. Os grupos que exigem suas direitas
não trabalharam na isolação; uma letra 1971 de Cesar Chavez 
ao NAACP reflete a sustentação que existiu entre os dois grupos, 
ambos que estavam lutando pelo tratamento igual sob a lei. O 
Oakland, organização nacionalista preta Califórnia-baseada, o 
partido da pantera preta, estava lutando pela justiça social em 
diversas partes dianteiras, em uma maneira que confundisse 
frequentemente seus supporters mais moderados. Promoveram 
fortemente edições sociais importantes e positivas tais como 
clínicas livres, programas para alimentar crianças, e programas da 
reabilitação da droga; ainda, ao mesmo tempo, embraced 
táticas controversas e às vezes violentas. Embora as panteras 
sejam envolvidas em clashes violentos com as polícias, é ainda 
unclear se as panteras inicíam estas ações ou defendia-se 
simplesmente de encontro à violência das polícias dirigida neles. 
Muitos dos líderes da pantera eram altofalantes persuasive e 
charismatic, e as fotografias aqui mostram muita deles na ação: 
Ministro da pantera preta do newton de Huey da defesa e sua 
esposa, Gwen; Bobby Seale do presidente da pantera preta na 
cadeia; membros das panteras pretas em uma conferência de 
imprensa; Cleaver de Kathleen no escritório de um prosecutor; 
e Angela Davis em Los Angeles que fala à imprensa após um 
shootout da pantera preta. Quando o newton de Huey foi posto 
sobre a experimentação em 1968, acusado de assassinar um oficial de 
polícias, panteras pretas alinhadas acima no segundo dia da 
experimentação para mostrar sua sustentação. Uma outra 
imagem mostra uma multidão multiracial recolhida em um rally do 
newton de Huey em 1969 no edifício federal do San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli anni 60 e l'inizio degli anni 70 sono stati 
caratterizzati da una serie di proteste come gruppi che hanno avuti 
feltro lungo disempowered cercato di fare le loro voci sentite. 
La California era il cuore di molti di questi nuovi movimenti. 
Le proteste hanno messo in movimento tramite il movimento di 
diritti civili evoluto per richiamare le edizioni sociali della 
giustizia che interessano molti gruppi, compreso gli allievi che 
affrontano la brutta copia, la gente ordinaria che protestano la 
guerra, il combattimento della manodopera agricola per le condizioni di 
lavoro migliori, i chicanos che esprimono una nuova identità e gli 
Americani africani che hanno ritenuto che nonviolence mentre una 
tattica più non stava funzionando. La partecipazione continuata
dell'America alla guerra di Vietnam ha galvanizzato molti gruppi. 
Attraverso unito Dichiara, allievi protestati 
partecipazione degli Stati Uniti alla guerra resistendo alla brutta 
copia. Tutti gli ordinamenti della gente si sono uniti dentro 
"dal commercio d'interruzione come di consueto," marciando ed andando 
sul colpo. Una fotografia mostra una bandiera che dichiara "sul 
colpo" che appende sopra il cancello di Sather del Berkeley UC; 
la città universitaria deserted dimostra il supporto diffuso 
fra sia la facoltà che gli allievi. Altre fotografie descrivono
gli allievi che marciano nella protesta contro la guerra, firmanti 
"donne per una petizione di pace" e fluttuanti una bandierina 
americana in una parata pacifista. Il comitato chicano di 
moratoria ha protestato la guerra marciando nelle parate, ma 
egualmente hanno registrato il loro proprio ordine del giorno sociale 
della giustizia: una fotografia mostra loro le bandiere 
trasportanti che leggono, "la nostra lotta è nel barrio, non 
Vietnam."People anche radunata intorno ai diritti degli operai, 
spingenti i contorni ed esigenti le condizioni di lavoro migliori. 
La manodopera agricola unita (UFW), co-fondata e condotta da 
Cesar Chavez, colpi usati protestare il trattamento ingiusto che gli 
operai di campo messicani della California pricipalmente hanno 
ricevuto. In una fotografia i picchetti si levano in piedi al 
bordo di un giacimento centrale dell'uva della California e 
trasportano i cartelli che dicono "Huelga," Spagnolo per "il colpo." 
Un'altra fotografia mostra il co-fondatore Dolores Huerta di UFW
che parla ad un gruppo. I gruppi che richiedono i loro diritti 
non hanno lavorato nell'isolamento; una lettera 1971 da Cesar 
Chavez al NAACP riflette il supporto che ha esistito fra i due gruppi,
entrambi cui erano combattimento per la parità di trattamento secondo 
la legge. Oakland, l'organizzazione nazionalista nera 
California-basata, il partito della pantera nera, era combattimento per
giustizia sociale su parecchie parti anteriori, in un modo che ha 
confuso spesso i loro sostenitori più moderati. Hanno promosso 
fortemente edizioni sociali importanti e positive quali le cliniche 
libere, programmi alimentare i bambini ed i programmi di 
riabilitazione della droga; ancora, allo stesso tempo, hanno 
abbracciato le tattiche discutibili ed occasionalmente violente. 
Anche se le pantere sono state coinvolgere nei disaccordi 
violenti con la polizia, è ancora poco chiara se le pantere iniziano 
queste azioni o semplicemente stava difendendosi contro la violenza 
della polizia diretta loro. Molti dei capi della pantera
erano altoparlanti convincenti e charismatic e le fotografie qui 
mostrano molte di loro nell'azione: Ministro della pantera 
nera del Newton di Huey della difesa e la sua moglie, Gwen; 
Bobby Seale del presidente della pantera nera in prigione; 
membri delle pantere nere ad una conferenza stampa; 
Cleaver di Kathleen nell'ufficio del procuratore; ed 
Angela Davis a Los Angeles che parla alla pressa dopo uno shootout 
della pantera nera. Quando il Newton di Huey è stato messo 
sulla prova in 1968, accusato di assassinio dell'ufficiale di polizia,
pantere nere allineate il secondo giorno della prova per mostrare il 
loro supporto. Un'altra immagine mostra una folla multiracial 
riunita ad un raduno di Newton di Huey in 1969 alla 
costruzione federale de San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η δεκαετία του '60 και η πρόωρη δεκαετία του '70 
χαρακτηρίστηκαν από μια σειρά διαμαρτυριών καθώς οι ομάδες που 
είχαν αισθανθεί από καιρό επιδιωκόμενος να καταστήσουν τις 
φωνές τους ακουσμένες. Καλιφόρνια ήταν η καρδιά πολλές 
από αυτές τις νέες μετακινήσεις. Οι διαμαρτυρίες που 
τέθηκαν στην κίνηση από τη μετακίνηση αστικών δικαιωμάτων 
εξελίχθηκαν για να αντιμετωπίσουν τα κοινωνικά ζητήματα 
δικαιοσύνης που έχουν επιπτώσεις σε πολλές ομάδες, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των σπουδαστών αντιμετωπίζοντας το σχέδιο, 
τους απλούς ανθρώπους που διαμαρτύρονται τον πόλεμο, τους αγρότες
που παλεύουν για τις καλύτερες συνθήκες εργασίας, Chicanos 
εκφράζοντας μια νέα ταυτότητα, και αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς που 
αισθάνθηκαν εκείνη την πολιτική της μη βίας δεδομένου ότι μια 
τακτική δεν λειτουργούσε πλέον. Η συνεχής συμμετοχή της 
Αμερικής στον πόλεμο του Βιετνάμ γαλβάνισε πολλές ομάδες. 
Στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, οι σπουδαστές διαμαρτυρήθηκαν 
αμερικανική συμμετοχή στον πόλεμο με την αντίσταση του σχεδίου. 
Όλα τα είδη των ανθρώπων που προσχωρούνται μέσα με να 
αναστατώσει "την επιχείρηση όπως συνηθισμένη," την πορεία, και τη
μετάβαση στην απεργία. Μια φωτογραφία εμφανίζει ένα 
έμβλημα δηλώνοντας "στην απεργία" κρεμώντας πέρα από την πύλη 
Sather UC Μπέρκλευ!  η εγκαταλειμμένη πανεπιστημιούπολη
καταδεικνύει τη διαδεδομένη υποστήριξη και μεταξύ της σχολής και 
των σπουδαστών. Αλλες φωτογραφίες απεικονίζουν τους 
σπουδαστές που βαδίζουν στη διαμαρτυρία ενάντια στον πόλεμο, που 
υπογράφουν μια αίτηση "γυναικών για την ειρήνη", και που 
κυματίζουν μια αμερικανική σημαία σε μια αντιπολεμική παρέλαση. 
Η τσικάνα Επιτροπή ανάπαυλας διαμαρτυρήθηκε τον πόλεμο με 
την πορεία στις παρελάσεις, αλλά καταχώρησαν επίσης την 
κοινωνική ημερήσια διάταξη δικαιοσύνης τους: μια φωτογραφία
τους εμφανίζει φέρνοντας εμβλήματα που διαβάζουν, "η πάλη μας 
είναι στο barrio, όχι Vietnam."People που συναθροίζονται 
επίσης γύρω από τα δικαιώματα των εργαζομένων, όρια ώθησης και 
απαιτητικές καλύτερες συνθήκες εργασίας. Οι ενωμένοι 
αγρότες (UFW), ομο-που ιδρύθηκε και που οδηγήθηκε από Cesar 
Chavez, χρησιμοποίησαν τις απεργίες για να διαμαρτυρηθούν την 
άδικη επεξεργασία που εργαζόμενοι πεδίων Καλιφόρνιας κυρίως οι 
μεξικάνικοι έλαβαν. Σε μια φωτογραφία οι στύλοι στέκονται 
στην άκρη ενός κεντρικού πεδίου σταφυλιών Καλιφόρνιας και 
φέρνουν τις αφίσσες που λένε "Huelga," ισπανικά για "την 
απεργία." Μια άλλη φωτογραφία εμφανίζει UFW ομο-ιδρυτή 
Dolores huerta που απευθύνεται σε μια ομάδα. Οι ομάδες 
που απαιτούν τα δικαιώματά τους δεν εργάστηκαν μεμονωμένα  
μια επιστολή του 1971 από Cesar Chavez στο NAACP 
απεικονίζει την υποστήριξη που υπήρξε μεταξύ των δύο ομάδων, και
οι δύο από τις οποίες πάλευαν για την ίση μεταχείριση βάσει του
νόμου. Το Όουκλαντ, Καλιφόρνια-βασισμένη στο μαύρη 
εθνικιστική οργάνωση, το μαύρο συμβαλλόμενο μέρος πάνθηρων, 
πάλευε για την κοινωνική δικαιοσύνη σε διάφορα μέτωπα, με έναν 
τρόπο που συνέχυσε συχνά τους μετριότερους υποστηρικτές τους. 
Προώθησαν έντονα τα σημαντικά και θετικά κοινωνικά 
ζητήματα όπως οι ελεύθερες κλινικές, τα προγράμματα για να 
ταϊστούν τα παιδιά, και τα προγράμματα αποκατάστασης φαρμάκων  
ακόμα, συγχρόνως, αγκαλίασαν την αμφισβητούμενη και κατά 
περιόδους βίαια τακτική. Αν και οι πάνθηρες περιλήφθηκαν 
στις βίαιες διαφωνίες με την αστυνομία, είναι ακόμα ασαφές εάν 
οι πάνθηρες άρχισαν αυτές τις ενέργειες ή υπερασπίζονταν απλά 
ενάντια στη βία αστυνομίας που κατευθύνθηκε σε τις. Πολλοί 
από τους ηγέτες πάνθηρων ήταν πειστικοί και χαρισματικοί 
ομιλητές, και οι φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν εδώ πολλών από τους στην
ενέργεια: Μαύρος Υπουργός πάνθηρων της άμυνας Huey 
Newton και η σύζυγός του, Gwen  Μαύρος πάνθηρας 
πρόεδρος Bobby Seale στη φυλακή  μέλη των μαύρων 
πάνθηρων σε μια συνέντευξη τύπου  Θ*Κατχλεεν Cleaver στο 
γραφείο ενός κατηγόρου  και Angela Davis στο Λος 
Αντζελες που μιλά στον Τύπο μετά από έναν μαύρο πάνθηρα 
ανταλλαγή πυροβολισμών. Όταν Huey Newton τέθηκε στη δοκιμή το 
1968, κατηγορούμενος για τη δολοφονία ενός αστυνομικού, οι 
μαύροι πάνθηρες παράταξαν τη δεύτερη ημέρα της δοκιμής για να 
εμφανίσουν υποστήριξή τους. Μια άλλη εικόνα εμφανίζει 
πολυφυλετικό πλήθος που μαζεύεται σε μια συνάθροιση Huey 
Newton το 1969 στο ομοσπονδιακό κτήριο του Σαν Φρανσίσκο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los años 60 y los años 70 tempranos fueron 
caracterizados por una serie de protestas como grupos que tenían 
fieltro largo disempowered intentado hacer sus voces oídas. 
California era el corazón de muchos de estos nuevos 
movimientos. Las protestas pusieron en el movimiento por el 
movimiento de las derechas civiles desarrollado para tratar las 
ediciones sociales de la justicia que afectaban a muchos grupos, 
incluyendo los estudiantes que hacían frente al bosquejo, a las 
gentes normales que protestaban la guerra, a los trabajadores de 
granja que luchaban para condiciones de trabajo mejores, a los 
chicanos que expresaban una nueva identidad, y a los americanos 
africanos que se sentían que nonviolence pues una táctica era un 
funcionamiento no más largo. La implicación continuada de 
América en la guerra de Vietnam galvanizó a muchos grupos. A 
través de los Estados Unidos, los estudiantes protestaron la 
implicación de los E.E.U.U. en la guerra oponiéndose al bosquejo. 
Todas las clases de gente ensamblaron adentro por "negocio de 
interrupción como de costumbre," marchando, y yendo en huelga. 
Una fotografía muestra una bandera que declara "en la huelga" 
que cuelga sobre la puerta de Sather de Berkeley UC; el campus 
abandonado demuestra la ayuda extensa entre facultad y estudiantes. 
Otras fotografías representan a estudiantes que marchan en 
protesta contra la guerra, firmando las "mujeres para una petición de
la paz", y agitando un indicador americano en un desfile pacifista. 
El comité chicano de la moratoria protestó la guerra marchando
en desfiles, pero también colocaron su propia agenda social de la 
justicia: una fotografía les muestra las banderas que llevan 
que leen, "nuestra lucha está en el barrio, no Vietnam."People 
también reunida alrededor de las derechas de los trabajadores, 
empujando límites y exigiendo condiciones de trabajo mejores. 
Los trabajadores de granja unidos (UFW), co-fundados y 
conducidos por Cesar Chavez, huelgas usadas a protestar el tratamiento
injusto que los trabajadores de campo mexicanos de California 
principalmente recibieron. En una fotografía los piquetes 
están parados en el borde de un campo central de la uva de California
y llevan los carteles que dicen "Huelga," español para la "huelga." 
Otra fotografía muestra a co-fundador Dolores Huerta de UFW que
se dirige a un grupo. Los grupos que exigían las sus derechas 
no trabajaron en el aislamiento; una carta 1971 de Cesar Chavez 
al NAACP refleja la ayuda que existió entre los dos grupos, que 
luchaban para la igualdad de tratamiento bajo ley. La Oakland, 
organización nacionalista negra California-basada, el partido de la 
pantera negra, luchaba para la justicia social en varios frentes, de 
una manera que confundió a menudo sus partidarios más moderados. 
Promovieron fuertemente las ediciones sociales importantes y 
positivas tales como clínicas libres, programas para alimentar 
niños, y programas de la rehabilitación de la droga; todavía,
en el mismo tiempo, abrazaron táctica polémicas y ocasionalmente 
violentas. Aunque las panteras estuvieron implicadas en choques 
violentos con policía, sigue siendo no entendible si las panteras 
emprender estas acciones o se defendía simplemente contra la 
violencia del policía dirigida en ellos. Muchos de los 
arranques de cinta de la pantera eran locutores persuasivos y 
carismáticos, y las fotografías aquí muestran a muchos de ellos en 
la acción: Ministro de la pantera negra del neutonio de Huey de
la defensa y su esposa, Gwen; Bobby Seale del presidente de la 
pantera negra en cárcel; miembros de las panteras negras en una
rueda de prensa; Cuchilla de Kathleen en la oficina de un 
querellante; y Angela Davis en Los Ángeles que habla a la 
prensa después de un shootout de la pantera negra. Cuando el 
neutonio de Huey fue puesto en ensayo en 1968, acusado de asesinar a 
un oficial de policía, panteras negras alineadas en el segundo día 
del ensayo para mostrar su ayuda. Otra imagen muestra a 
muchedumbre multirracial recolectada en una reunión del neutonio de 
Huey en 1969 en el edificio federal de San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085260</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104490</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/struggles-for-social-justice</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
