<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107133</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107133</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087037</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Rich Are Good-Natured": William Graham Sumner Defends the Wealthy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Rich Sind" Gut-Natured: William Graham 
Sumner verteidigt das wohlhabende</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Les Riches Sont Bons-Natured" : William 
Graham Sumner défend le riche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Os Rich São Bons-Natured": William Graham 
Sumner defende o rico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"I Rich Sono Buoni-Natured": William Graham 
Sumner difende il ricco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι πλούσιοι είναι good-Natured": Θ*Ωηλληαμ 
Graham Sumner Defends ο πλούσιος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Los Ricos Son Buenos-Natured": Guillermo 
Graham Sumner defiende el rico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the late 19th century, William Graham Sumner, an Episcopal minister turned academic sociologist, brought a distinctly conservative perspective to the new "science" of sociology. Some of his ideas about the economic survival of the fittest and opposition to government intervention in the economy were applications of Darwin's scientific ideas of evolution to the social sphere. He also drew upon the doctrines of laissez-faire British economists like Thomas Malthus and David Ricardo to argue that government intervention would disturb the "natural" and self-regulating market. Sumner's writings justified government inaction in the face of vast social dislocations caused by rapid industrialization and the periodic economic depressions that accompanied it. Not surprisingly, his work had a broad influence beyond the academy. In this excerpt from his 1883 essay, "What the Social Classes Owe To Each Other," Sumner portrayed the wealthy elite as a put-upon class whose misunderstood ambitions and intentions would benefit everyone.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert holte 
William Graham Sumner, ein episkopaler Minister gedrehter akademischer
Soziologe, eine deutlich konservative Perspektive zur neuen 
"Wissenschaft" der Soziologie. Einige seiner Ideen über das 
ökonomische Überleben vom passendsten und von der Opposition zur 
Regierung Intervention in der Wirtschaft waren Anwendungen von Darwins
wissenschaftlichen Ideen der Entwicklung zum Sozialbereich. Er 
zeichnete auch nach den Lehren Laissez-Faire der britischen 
Wirtschaftswissenschaftler wie Thomas Malthus und David Ricardo, um zu
argumentieren, daß Regierung Intervention den "natürlichen" und 
selbstregulierenden Markt stören würde. Schreiben Sumners 
schlossen Regierung Untätigkeit angesichts der beträchtlichen 
Sozialversetzungen aus, die durch schnelle Industrialisierung und die 
periodischen Wirtschaftskrisen, die, verursacht wurden sie 
begleiteten. Nicht überraschend, hatte seine Arbeit einen 
ausgedehnten Einfluß über der Akademie hinaus. In diesem 
Excerpt von seinem Versuch 1883, "was die Gesellschaftsklassen 
miteinander verdanken," schilderte Sumner die wohlhabende Auslese, da 
a setzen-nach Kategorie deren mißverstand, Ehrgeiz und Absichten 
jeder fördern würde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vers la fin du 19ème siècle, William Graham 
Sumner, un ministre épiscopal sociologue tourné d'universitaire, a 
apporté une perspective distinctement conservatrice à la nouvelle 
"science" de la sociologie. Certaines de ses idées au sujet de 
la survie économique du plus convenable et de l'opposition à 
l'intervention de gouvernement dans l'économie étaient des 
applications des idées scientifiques de Darwin de l'évolution à la 
sphère sociale. Il a également utilisé les doctrines des 
économistes britanniques de laissez-faire comme Thomas Malthus et 
David Ricardo pour arguer du fait que l'intervention de gouvernement
dérangerait le marché "normal" et de art de l'auto-portrait-regulating. Les 
écritures de Sumner ont justifié l'inaction de gouvernement face à 
de vastes dislocations sociales provoquées par l'industrialisation 
rapide et les dépressions économiques périodiques qui l'ont 
accompagnée. Pas étonnamment, son travail a eu une large 
influence au delà de l'académie. Dans cet extrait de son essai
1883, "ce que les classes sociales doivent entre eux," Sumner a 
dépeint l'élite riche car a mettre-sur la classe dont a mal comprise
des ambitions et des intentions bénéficierait chacun.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 1ø século atrasado, William Graham Sumner, um 
ministro episcopal sociologist academic girado, trouxe um perspective 
distintamente conservador à "ciência nova" do sociology. 
Algumas de suas idéias sobre a sobrevivência econômica do 
mais apto e da oposição à intervenção do governo na economia eram
aplicações de idéias científicas de Darwin da evolução à esfera
social. Desenhou também em cima das doutrinas de economistas 
britânicos do laissez-faire como Thomas Malthus e David Ricardo para 
discutir que a intervenção do governo perturbaria "o mercado 
natural" e self-regulating. As escritas de Sumner justificaram o
inaction do governo na cara dos dislocations sociais vastos causados 
pelo industrialization rápido e pelos depressions econômicos 
periódicos que a acompanharam. Não surprisingly, seu trabalho 
teve uma influência larga além do academy. Neste excerpt de 
seu essay 1883, "o que as classes sociais se devem," Sumner portrayed 
o elite rico porque a po-em cima da classe o cujo entendeu mal 
ambições e intenções beneficiaria todos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verso la fine del diciannovesimo secolo, William 
Graham Sumner, un ministro episcopal sociologist accademico girato,
ha portato una prospettiva distintamente conservatrice alla nuova 
"scienza" della sociologia. Alcune delle sue idee circa la 
sopravvivenza economica dell'più adatto e dell'opposizione ad 
intervento di governo nell'economia erano applicazioni delle idee 
scientifiche del Darwin di sviluppo alla sfera sociale. 
Egualmente ha dissipato sulle dottrine degli economisti 
britannici di "laissez faire" come Thomas Malthus e David Ricardo per 
sostenere che l'intervento di governo disturberebbe "il mercato 
naturale" ed autoregolatore. Le scritture del Sumner hanno 
giustificato l'inerzia di governo di fronte alle dislocazioni sociali 
ampie causate dall'industrializzazione veloce e dalle depressioni 
economiche periodiche che la hanno accompagnata. Non 
sorprendentemente, il suo lavoro ha avuto una vasta influenza oltre 
l'accademia. In questo brano dal suo saggio 1883, "che cosa le
classi sociali devono l'un l'altro," Sumner ha ritratto l'elite ricca 
poichè la a mett- su codice categoria di cui ha compreso male 
ambizioni ed intenzioni avvantaggerebbe tutto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, William Graham 
Sumner, ένας επισκοπικός γυρισμένος υπουργός ακαδημαϊκός 
κοινωνιολόγος, έφερε μια ευδιάκριτα συντηρητική προοπτική στη 
νέα "επιστήμη" της κοινωνιολογίας. Μερικές από τις ιδέες 
του για την οικονομική επιβίωση του καταλληλότερου και της 
αντίθεσης στην κυβερνητική επέμβαση στην οικονομία ήταν 
εφαρμογές των επιστημονικών ιδεών Δαρβίνου της εξέλιξης στην 
κοινωνική σφαίρα. Βασίστηκε επίσης στα δόγματα των 
βρετανικών οικονομολόγων ελεύθερης οικονομίας όπως τον Thomas 
Malthus και το Δαβίδ Ricardo για να υποστηρίξει ότι η 
κυβερνητική επέμβαση θα ενοχλούσε τη "φυσική" και 
self-regulating αγορά. Οι γραφές του Sumner 
δικαιολόγησαν την κυβερνητική απραξία παρά τις απέραντες 
κοινωνικές εξαρθρώσεις που προκλήθηκαν από τη γρήγορη 
εκβιομηχάνιση και τις περιοδικές οικονομικές υφέσεις που την 
συνόδευσαν. Όπως ήταν αναμενόμενο, η εργασία του είχε μια 
ευρεία επιρροή πέρα από την ακαδημία. Σε αυτό το 
απόσπασμα από το δοκίμιο 1883 του, "τι οι κοινωνικές τάξεις 
οφείλουν η μια στην άλλη," Sumner απεικόνισε την πλούσια ελίτ 
ως α βάζω-επάνω στην κλάση οι της οποίας παρανοημένες φιλοδοξίες
και οι προθέσεις θα ωφελούσαν η καθεμία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la a fines del siglo XIX, Guillermo Graham 
Sumner, ministro episcopal sociólogo académico dado vuelta, trajo 
una perspectiva distintamente conservadora a la nueva "ciencia" de la 
sociología. Algunas de sus ideas sobre la supervivencia 
económica del más apto y de la oposición a la intervención del 
gobierno en la economía eran aplicaciones de las ideas científicas 
de Darwin de la evolución a la esfera social. Él también 
trazó sobre las doctrinas de los economistas británicos del 
liberalismo como Thomas Malthus y David Ricardo para discutir que la 
intervención del gobierno disturbaría "el mercado natural" y 
autorregulador. Las escrituras de Sumner alinearon la inacción 
del gobierno en la cara de las dislocaciones sociales extensas 
causadas por la industrialización rápida y las depresiones 
económicas periódicas que la acompañaron. No asombrosamente, 
su trabajo tenía una amplia influencia más allá de la academia. 
En este extracto de su ensayo 1883, "qué las clases sociales 
deben el uno al otro," Sumner retrató la élite rica pues a 
poner-sobre la clase que entendía mal las ambiciones y las 
intenciones beneficiaría cada uno.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087037</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107133</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-rich-are-good-natured-william-graham-sumner-defends-the-wealthy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
