<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104119</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104119</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204644</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Interracial "harmony" and the Great Awakening</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Interracial "Harmonie" und das große Wecken</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Interracial "harmonie" et le grand réveil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Interracial "harmonia" e awakening grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Interracial "armonia" ed il risveglio grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαφυλετική "αρμονία" και το μεγάλο ξύπνημα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Interracial "armonía" y el gran despertar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The students will be introduced to two episodes in 19th century American history, around the time of the Great Awakening, that show glimpses of some positive and negative consequences of interracial interaction in a religious context. The students will examine primary sources from the Documenting the American South collection to then be able to write a "sermon" from the perspective of a southern itinerant preacher during the Great Awakening arguing for or against religion as a cure for the social ill of racism and slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kursteilnehmer werden zu zwei Episoden in der 
amerikanischen Geschichte des 19. Jahrhunderts, um die Zeit des 
großen Weckens eingeführt, die Blicke etwas positiver und negativer 
Konsequenzen der interracial Interaktion in einem frommen Kontext 
zeigen. Die Kursteilnehmer überprüfen Primärquellen vom 
Dokumentieren der amerikanischen Südansammlung, um dann zu können, 
eine "Predigt" von der Perspektive eines südlichen reisenden 
Predigers während des großen weckenden Argumentierens für oder 
gegen Religion als Heilung für den Sozialkranken von Rassismus und 
von Sklaverei zu schreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants seront présentés à deux 
épisodes dans l'histoire américaine du 19ème siècle, autour de la 
période du grand réveil, qui montrent des aperçus de quelques 
conséquences positives et négatives d'interaction interracial dans 
un contexte religieux. Les étudiants examineront des sources 
primaires de documenter la collection du sud américaine pour 
pouvoir alors écrire un "sermon" de la perspective d'un prédicateur 
ambulant méridional pendant grand discuter de réveil pour ou contre 
la religion comme traitement pour la défectuosité sociale du racisme
et de l'esclavage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes serão introduzidos a dois episodes 
no history americano do 1ø século, em torno da época do awakening 
grande, que mostram glimpses de algumas conseqüências positivas e 
negativas da interação interracial em um contexto religioso. 
Os estudantes examinarão fontes preliminares de documentar a 
coleção sul americana então para poder  escrever um "sermon" do 
perspective de um preacher itinerant do sul durante discutir awakening
grande para ou de encontro à religião como uma cura para o mal 
social do racism e do slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi saranno introdotti a due episodi nella
storia americana di diciannovesimo secolo, intorno al periodo del 
risveglio grande, che mostrano i glimpses di alcune conseguenze 
positive e negative di interazione interracial in un contesto 
religioso. Gli allievi esamineranno le sorgenti primarie dalla 
documentazione dell'accumulazione del sud americana allora per potere 
scrivere "un sermon" dalla prospettiva di un preacher ambulante del 
sud durante la discussione di risveglio grande per o contro la 
religione come cura per il ill sociale del razzismo e dello slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα εισαχθούν σε δύο επεισόδια στην 
αμερικανική ιστορία του 19$ου αιώνα, γύρω από το χρόνο του 
μεγάλου ξυπνήματος, των αναλαμπών εκείνης της επίδειξης μερικών 
θετικών και αρνητικών συνεπειών της διαφυλετικής αλληλεπίδρασης 
σε ένα θρησκευτικό πλαίσιο. Οι σπουδαστές θα εξετάσουν τις 
αρχικές πηγές από την τεκμηρίωση η αμερικανική νότια συλλογή 
για να είναι σε θέση έπειτα να γράψουν ένα "κήρυγμα" από την 
προοπτική ενός νότιου πλανόδιου ιεροκήρυκα κατά τη διάρκεια του
μεγάλου ξυπνήματος μιλώντας ή ενάντια στη θρησκεία ως θεραπεία 
για κοινωνικό τον άρρωστο του ρατσισμού και της σκλαβιάς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Introducirán a los estudiantes a dos episodios en
historia americana del diecinueveavo siglo, alrededor de la época de 
gran despertar, que muestran ojeadas de algunas consecuencias 
positivas y negativas de la interacción interracial en un contexto 
religioso. Los estudiantes examinarán fuentes primarias de 
documentar la colección del sur americana entonces para poder 
escribir un "sermón" de la perspectiva de un predicador ambulante 
meridional durante la gran discusión que despierta para o contra la 
religión como curación para la enfermedad social del racismo y de la
esclavitud.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JAMIE LATHAN
FN:JAMIE LATHAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204644</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104119</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/interracial-harmony-and-the-great-awakening</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
