<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106903</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106903</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086819</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Shame Bows Her to the Earth":  Charlotte Temple , a Seduction Tale From Revolutionary New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Schande beugt sie zur Masse": Charlotte 
Bügel, eine Seduction Geschichte von revolutionärem New York</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la "honte la cintre à la terre" : Temple de
Charlotte, un conte de Séduction de New York révolutionnaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o "shame curva-a à terra": Temple de 
Charlotte, um tale de Seduction de New York revolucionária</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la Vergogna la piega alla terra": 
Tempiale de Charlotte, un racconto di Seduction da New York 
rivoluzionaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η ντροπή την υποκύπτει στη γη": Ναός του 
Σαρλόττα, μια ιστορία αποπλάνησης από την επαναστατική Νέα 
Υόρκη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "vergüenza la arquea a la tierra": 
Templo de Charlotte, un cuento de Seduction de Nueva York 
revolucionaria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Charlotte Temple: A Tale of Truth , published in 1791, was the first American bestseller. The author, Susanna Haswell Rowson, was born in England circa 1762, and died in Massachusetts, where she spent most of her life, in 1824. Charlotte Temple tells the story of a young English girl who is lured away from her school by an army officer, Montraville. On board ship to his posting in revolutionary-era New York, Montraville seduces Charlotte. Once in New York, Montraville gradually abandons the "ruined" Charlotte who, after a downward spiral into remorse, illness, poverty, and the birth of a child, dies. Seduction novels were popular in the 18th century, and the widely read Charlotte Temple went through more than two hundred editions. But Rowson, who despite her childhood as the daughter of an English revenue officer became a committed republican, used her novel to protest the sexual double standard that ruined the lives of women like Charlotte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Charlotte Bügel: Eine Geschichte der 
Wahrheit, veröffentlicht 1791, war der erste amerikanische 
Bestseller. Der Autor, Susanna Haswell Rowson, war in England 
circa 1762 geboren und starb in Massachusetts, in dem sie die meisten 
ihrer Lebensdauer verbrachte, 1824. Charlotte Bügel erklärt 
die Geschichte eines jungen englischen Mädchens, das weg von ihrer 
Schule von einem Offizier in der Armee angelockt wird, Montraville. 
An Bord des Schiffs zu seinem, das in der Revolutionärära New 
York bekanntgibt, seduces Montraville Charlotte. Einmal in neuem
York, verläßt Montraville stufenweise das "ruinierte" Charlotte, 
das, nach einer abwärts Spirale in remorse, in Krankheit, in 
Armut und in die Geburt eines Kindes, Würfel. Seduction Romane 
waren im 18. Jahrhundert populär, und der weit gelesene Charlotte 
Bügel lief mehr als zweihundert Ausgaben durch. Aber Rowson, 
das trotz ihrer Kindheit als der Tochter eines englischen Einkommen 
Offiziers einem festgelegten Republikaner stand, benutzte ihren Roman,
um den sexuellen doppelten Moralkodex zu protestieren, der die Leben 
der Frauen wie Charlotte ruinierte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Temple de Charlotte : Un conte de la 
vérité, édité en 1791, était le premier best-seller américain. 
L'auteur, Susanna Haswell Rowson, est né dans le circa 1762 de 
l'Angleterre, et est mort dans le Massachusetts, où elle a passé la 
majeure partie de sa vie, en 1824. Le temple de Charlotte 
indique l'histoire d'une jeune fille anglaise qui est leurrée loin de
son école par un officier d'armée, Montraville. À bord du 
bateau au sien qui signale dans la révolutionnaire-ère New York, 
Montraville séduit Charlotte. Une fois à New York, Montraville
abandonne graduellement Charlotte "ruiné" qui, après une spirale de 
haut en bas dans des remords, la maladie, la pauvreté, et la 
naissance d'un enfant, des matrices. Les romans de séduction 
étaient populaires au 18ème siècle, et le temple largement indiqué
de Charlotte est passé par plus de deux cents éditions. Mais 
Rowson, qui en dépit de son enfance en tant que fille d'un inspecteur
de contributions anglais est allé bien à un républicain commis, a 
employé son roman pour protester la double norme sexuelle qui a 
ruiné les vies des femmes comme Charlotte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Temple De Charlotte: Um tale da verdade, 
publicado em 1791, era o primeiro bestseller americano. O autor,
Susanna Haswell Rowson, foi carregado no circa 1762 de Inglaterra, e 
morreu em Massachusetts, onde gastou a maioria de sua vida, em 1824. 
O temple de Charlotte diz a história de uma menina inglesa nova
que lured afastado de sua escola por um oficial de exército, 
Montraville. No navio da placa a his que afixa na 
revolucionário-era New York, Montraville seduz Charlotte. Uma 
vez em New York, Montraville abandona gradualmente o Charlotte 
"arruinado" que, após uma espiral descendente no remorse, na doença,
na pobreza, e no nascimento de uma criança, dados. As novelas 
de Seduction eram populares no 18o século, e o temple extensamente 
lido de Charlotte atravessou mais de dois cem edições. Mas 
Rowson, que apesar de sua infância como a filha de um oficial de 
rendimento inglês assentou bem em um republicano cometido, usou sua 
novela protestar o padrão dobro sexual que arruinou as vidas das 
mulheres como Charlotte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tempiale De Charlotte: Un racconto della 
verità, pubblicato in 1791, era il primo bestseller americano. 
L'autore, Susanna Haswell Rowson, è stato sopportato in circa 
1762 dell'Inghilterra ed è morto in Massachusetts, in cui ha 
speso la maggior parte della sua vita, in 1824. Il 
tempiale de Charlotte dice alla storia di una ragazza inglese giovane 
che lured via dalla sua scuola da un ufficiale di esercito, 
Montraville. A bordo spedisca a suo che invia 
nell'rivoluzionario-era New York, Montraville seduce Charlotte. 
Una volta a New York, Montraville abbandona gradualmente 
Charlotte "rovinata" che, dopo una spirale in discesa in remorse, 
nella malattia, nella povertà e nella nascita di un bambino, dadi. 
I romanzi di Seduction erano popolari nel diciottesimo secolo ed
il tempiale ampiamente indicato de Charlotte ha passato attraverso 
più di duecento edizioni. Ma Rowson, che malgrado la sua 
infanzia come la figlia di un ufficiale di reddito inglese ha stato 
bene ad un repubblicano commesso, ha usato il suo romanzo per 
protestare il doppio standard sessuale che ha rovinato le vite delle 
donne come Charlotte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ναός του Σαρλόττα: Μια ιστορία της αλήθειας, που
δημοσιεύθηκε το 1791, ήταν το πρώτο αμερικανικό 
best-$l*seller. Ο συντάκτης, Susanna Haswell 
Rowson, γεννήθηκε στο circa 1762 της Αγγλίας, και πέθανε 
στη Μασαχουσέτη, όπου πέρασε την μεγαλύτερη μέρος της ζωής της, 
στο ναό 1824, Σαρλόττα λέει την ιστορία ενός νέου αγγλικού 
κοριτσιού που δελεάζεται μακρυά από το σχολείο της από έναν 
ανώτερο υπάλληλο στρατού, Montraville. Στο σκάφος στην 
ταχυδρόμησή του στην επαναστατικός-εποχή Νέα Υόρκη, 
Montraville παραπλανεί το Σαρλόττα. Μιά φορά στη Νέα 
Υόρκη, Montraville εγκαταλείπει βαθμιαία το "" Σαρλόττα που, 
μετά από μια προς τα κάτω σπείρα στην τύψη, η ασθένεια, η 
ένδεια, και η γέννηση ενός παιδιού, πεθαίνουν. Τα 
μυθιστορήματα αποπλάνησης ήταν δημοφιλή στο 18$ο αιώνα, και ο 
ευρέως διαβασμένος ναός του Σαρλόττα επέρασε από περισσότερες 
από διακόσιες εκδόσεις. Αλλά Rowson, που παρά την 
παιδική ηλικία της ως κόρη ενός αγγλικού ανώτερου υπαλλήλου 
εισοδήματος έγινε δεσμευμένος Δημοκρατικός, χρησιμοποίησε το 
μυθιστόρημά της για να διαμαρτυρηθεί τα σεξουαλικά διπλά πρότυπα
που κατέστρεψαν τις ζωές των γυναικών όπως το Σαρλόττα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Templo De Charlotte: Un cuento de la verdad,
publicado en 1791, era el primer bestseller americano. El autor,
Susanna Haswell Rowson, nació en el circa 1762 de Inglaterra, y 
murió en Massachusetts, en donde ella pasó la mayoría de su vida, 
en 1824. El templo de Charlotte cuenta la historia de una 
muchacha inglesa joven que sea engañada lejos de su escuela por un 
oficial de ejército, Montraville. A bordo de la nave el suyo 
que fija en la revolucionario-era Nueva York, Montraville seduce 
Charlotte. Una vez en Nueva York, Montraville abandona 
gradualmente la Charlotte "arruinada" que, después de un espiral 
hacia abajo en remordimiento, enfermedad, pobreza, y el nacimiento de un 
niño, los dados. Las novelas de Seduction eran populares en el 
décimo octavo siglo, y el templo extensamente leído de Charlotte 
pasó a través de más de doscientas ediciones. Pero Rowson, 
que a pesar de su niñez como la hija de un oficial de rédito inglés
sintió bien a un republicano confiado, utilizó su novela para 
protestar el estándar doble sexual que arruinó las vidas de mujeres 
como Charlotte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086819</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106903</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shame-bows-her-to-the-earth-charlotte-temple-a-seduction-tale-from-revolutionary-new-york</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
