<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205609</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">East Asian Trading Ships</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ostasiat-Handelnde Schiffe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bateaux Marchands d'Asiatique Est</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Navios Negociando Do Asian Do leste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Navi Commerciali Dell'Asiatico Orientale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκάφη ανατολικών ασιατικά εμπορικών συναλλαγών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Naves Que negocian Del Asiático Del este</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Each student will work with a partner as an owner of an overseas shipping company with one cargo ship in East Asia. Students are given these instructions in the overview: In each Asian country that you travel to you will fill your cargo ship with items that you can buy from the list of exports. You will then try to sell these items when you travel to another country that is willing to import these commodities. The winner of the game is the company with the biggest profits at the end of the pretend 15 day time period</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jeder Kursteilnehmer arbeitet mit einem Partner 
als Inhaber einer Überseeverschiffenfirma mit einem Frachtschiff in 
Ostasien. Kursteilnehmern werden diese Anweisungen im Überblick
erteilt: In jedem asiatischen Land, daß Sie zu Ihnen reisen, 
füllt Ihr Frachtschiff mit Einzelteilen, die Sie von der Liste der 
Exporte kaufen können. Sie versuchen dann, diese Einzelteile zu
verkaufen, wenn Sie zu einem anderen Land reisen, das bereit ist, 
diese Gebrauchsgüter zu importieren. Der Sieger des Spiels ist 
die Firma mit den größten Profiten am Ende vortäuschen 15 
Tageszeitabschnitt</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chaque étudiant travaillera avec un associé en 
tant que propriétaire d'un compagnie maritime d'outre-mer avec un 
cargo en Asie de l'Est. Des étudiants sont donnés ces 
instructions dans la vue d'ensemble : Chaque pays asiatique que 
vous vous voyagez remplira votre cargo d'éléments que vous pouvez 
acheter de la liste d'exportations. Vous essayerez alors de 
vendre ces éléments quand vous voyagez à un autre pays qui est 
disposé à importer ces produits. Le gagnant du jeu est la 
compagnie avec les plus grands bénéfices à l'fin du feindre 
période de temps de 15 jours</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cada estudante trabalhará com um sócio como um 
proprietário de uma companhia de transporte ultramarina com o um 
navio de carga em Ásia do leste. Os estudantes são dados estas
instruções na vista geral: Em cada país asian que você lhe 
viaja encherá seu navio de carga com os artigos que você pode 
comprar da lista das exportações. Você tentará então vender
estes artigos quando você viaja a um outro país que seja disposto 
importar estes productos. O vencedor do jogo é a companhia com 
os lucros os mais grandes no fim fingir período de tempo de 15 dias</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ogni allievo lavorerà con un socio come 
proprietario di un'azienda di trasporto d'oltremare con una nave da 
carico in Asia orientale. Gli allievi sono dati queste 
istruzioni nella descrizione: In ogni paese asiatico che 
viaggiate voi riempirà la vostra nave da carico di articoli che 
potete comprare dalla lista delle esportazioni. Allora proverete
a vendere questi articoli quando viaggiate ad un altro paese che è 
disposto ad importare questi prodotti. Il vincitore del gioco è
l'azienda con i profitti più grandi alla conclusione della finzione 
periodo di tempo di 15 giorni</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάθε σπουδαστής θα συνεργαστεί με έναν συνεργάτη ως 
ιδιοκτήτης μιας υπερπόντιας ναυτιλιακής εταιρίας με ένα σκάφος 
φορτίου στην ανατολική Ασία. Στους σπουδαστές δίνονται 
αυτές οι οδηγίες στην επισκόπηση: Σε κάθε Ασιάτη η χώρα 
που ταξιδεύετε σε σας θα γεμίσει το σκάφος φορτίου σας με τα 
αντικείμενα που μπορείτε να αγοράσετε από τον κατάλογο εξαγωγών.
Θα προσπαθήσετε έπειτα να πωλήσετε αυτά τα αντικείμενα 
όταν ταξιδεύετε σε μια άλλη χώρα που είναι πρόθυμη να εισαγάγει
αυτά τα προϊόντα. Ο νικητής του παιχνιδιού είναι η 
επιχείρηση με τα μεγαλύτερα κέρδη στο τέλος προσποιείται το 
χρονικό διάστημα 15 ημερών</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cada estudiante trabajará con un socio como 
propietario de una compañía de envío de ultramar con un buque de 
carga en Asia del este. Dan los estudiantes estas instrucciones 
en la descripción: En cada país asiático que usted le viaja 
llenará su buque de carga de los items que usted puede comprar de la 
lista de exportaciones. Usted entonces intentará vender estos 
items cuando usted viaja a otro país que esté dispuesto a importar 
estas materias. El ganador del juego es la compañía con los 
beneficios más grandes en el final del fingimiento período de 15 
días</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TAMI KAISER POLGE
FN:TAMI KAISER POLGE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205609</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108671</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/east-asian-trading-ships</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
