<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108073</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108073</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211495</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Paleoclimate: Climate Change Through Time</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Paleoclimate: Klima-Änderung Durch Zeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Paleoclimate : Changement de Climat Par Le 
Temps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Paleoclimate: Mudança Do Clima Com O Tempo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Paleoclimate: Cambiamento Di Clima Con Tempo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Paleoclimate: Αλλαγή κλίματος μέσω του 
χρόνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paleoclimate: Cambio Del Clima Con Tiempo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides access to a spectrum of web-based visual resources and supporting material that can be used to teach students about paleoclimate through geologic time. Visualizations include simple animations, GIS-based animated maps and paleogeographic maps, as well as numerous illustrations and photos. Resources can be integrated into lectures, labs, classes, or other activities about paleoclimate and land cover and land use change over time.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert Zugriff zu einem Spektrum der 
Web-gegründeten Sichtbetriebsmittel und des Hilfsmaterials, die 
benutzt werden können, um Kursteilnehmer über paleoclimate durch 
geologische Zeit zu unterrichten. Sichtbarmachungen schließen 
einfache Animationen, GIS-gegründete lebhafte Karten und 
paläogeographische Karten, so gut wie zahlreiche Abbildungen und 
Fotos ein. Betriebsmittel können in Vorträge, Labors, 
Kategorien integriert werden, oder andere Aktivitäten über 
paleoclimate und Landabdeckung und Flächennutzung ändern Überzeit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site permet d'accéder à un spectre des 
ressources et du matériel de support visuels Web-basés qui peut 
être employé pour enseigner des étudiants au sujet de paleoclimate 
par le temps géologique. Les visualisations incluent des 
animations simples, des cartes animées par GI-based et des 
cartes paléogéographiques, aussi bien que de nombreuses 
illustrations et photos. Des ressources peuvent être 
intégrées dans des conférences, laboratoires, classes, ou d'autres 
activités au sujet de couverture de paleoclimate et de terre et 
d'utilisation de la terre changent le temps fini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece o acesso a um spectrum dos 
recursos e do material suportando visuais Web-baseados que podem ser 
usados ensinar estudantes sobre o paleoclimate com o tempo geologic. 
Os visualizations incluem animations simples, mapas animated 
Soldado-baseados e mapas paleogeographic, as.well.as ilustrações e 
fotos numerosas. Os recursos podem ser integrados em lectures, 
laboratórios, classes, ou outras atividades sobre a tampa do 
paleoclimate e de terra e o uso de terra mudam o tempo excedente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce l'accesso ad uno spettro 
delle risorse e del materiale visivi Web-basati di sostegno che può 
essere usato per insegnare gli allievi circa paleoclimate con tempo 
geologico. Le visualizzazioni includono le animazioni semplici, 
programmi animati GIS-basati e programmi paleogeographic, così come 
le illustrazioni e le foto numerose. Le risorse possono essere 
integrate nelle conferenze, laboratori, codici categoria, o altre 
attività circa i tipi di terreno e del paleoclimate e l'utilizzazione
delle terre cambiano col tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει την πρόσβαση σε ένα φάσμα των
βασισμένων στο WEB οπτικών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς και του 
ενισχυτικού υλικού που μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για να διδάξουν
τους σπουδαστές για paleoclimate μέσω του γεωλογικού χρόνου. 
Οι απεικονίσεις περιλαμβάνουν τις απλές ζωτικότητες, τους 
GIS-VASJSME'NOYS στο ζωντανεψονταυς χάρτες και τους 
paleogeographic χάρτες, καθώς επίσης και τις πολυάριθμες 
απεικονίσεις και τις φωτογραφίες. Τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς 
μπορούν να ενσωματωθούν στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, τις 
κλάσεις, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες για paleoclimate και η κάλυψη 
εδάφους και η χρήση εδάφους αλλάζουν κατά τη διάρκεια του 
χρόνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona al acceso a un espectro de 
los recursos y del material que utiliza visuales Web-basados que se 
pueden utilizar para enseñar a estudiantes sobre paleoclimate con 
tiempo geológico. Las visualizaciones incluyen las animaciones 
simples, correspondencias animadas Soldado-basadas y correspondencias 
paleogeográficas, así como ilustraciones y fotos numerosas. 
Los recursos se pueden integrar en las conferencias, 
laboratorios, clases, u otras actividades sobre la cubierta del 
paleoclimate y de pista y la utilización del suelo cambian en un 
cierto plazo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211495</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108073</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/paleoclimate-climate-change-through-time</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
