<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105014</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105014</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201368</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Measuring Distance and Area in Satellite Images</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Messender Abstand und Bereich in den Satellitenbildern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Distance et zone de mesure dans des images satellites</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Distância e área de medição em imagens satellite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Distanza e zona di misurazione nelle immagini satelliti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: Μέτρηση
της απόστασης και της περιοχής στις δορυφορικές εικόνες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Distancia y área que miden en imágenes basadas en los 
satélites</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Users download and analyze MODIS imagery from 2001 and 2003 to quantify the shrinking of the Aral Sea. The chapter steps users through downloading, installing, and measuring with ImageJ, a freely available image analysis program. Users employ the software to set the spatial calibration of an image, then select and measure distances directly from the image. Measurement results are reported in real-world units. Users also select, measure, and compare the area covered by the sea in three time-series images. The techniques described are useful only for nadir view (straight down) images.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Benutzer downloaden und analysieren MODIS Bilder 
von 2001 und von 2003, um die Schrumpfung des Aral Meeres 
mengenmäßig zu bestimmen. Das Kapitel tritt Benutzer durch das
Downloading, das Installieren und das Messen mit ImageJ, ein frei 
vorhandenes Bildanalyseprogramm. Benutzer setzen die Software 
ein, um die räumliche Kalibrierung eines Bildes einzustellen, dann 
wählen aus und messen Abstände direkt vom Bild. 
Messen-Resultate werden in den realistischen Maßeinheiten 
berichtet. Benutzer auch wählen aus, messen und vergleichen den
Bereich, der durch das Meer in drei Zeitfolgebildern umfaßt wird. 
Die Techniken, die beschrieben werden, sind nur für Bilder der 
Nadiransicht (gerader Abstieg) nützlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les utilisateurs téléchargent et analysent le 
langage figuré de MODIS de 2001 et de 2003 pour mesurer le 
rétrécissement de la mer d'Aral. Le chapitre fait un pas des 
utilisateurs par le téléchargement, l'installation, et la mesure 
avec ImageJ, un programme librement disponible d'analyse d'image. 
Les utilisateurs utilisent le logiciel pour placer l'étalonnage
spatial d'une image, puis choisissent et mesurent des distances 
directement de l'image. Des résultats de mesure sont 
enregistrés dans les unités réelles. Les utilisateurs 
également choisissent, mesurent, et comparent la zone couverte par la
mer dans trois images de série de temps. Les techniques 
décrites sont utiles seulement pour des images de vue de nadir 
(bas droit).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os usuários download e analisam o imagery de 
MODIS de 2001 e de 2003 para quantify encolher do mar de Aral. O
capítulo pisa usuários com downloading, instalar, e medir com 
ImageJ, um programa livremente disponível da análise de imagem. 
Os usuários empregam o software para ajustar a calibração 
spatial de uma imagem, a seguir selecionam e medem distâncias 
diretamente da imagem. Os resultados da medida são relatados em
unidades real-world. Os usuários também selecionam, medem, e 
comparam a área coberta pelo mar em três imagens do time-series. 
As técnicas descritas são úteis somente para imagens da vista
do nadir (pena reta).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli utenti trasferiscono ed analizzano il 
linguaggio figurato dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti di MODIS da
2001 e da 2003 per misurare il restringimento del mare di Aral. 
Il capitolo fa un passo utenti con il trasferimento dal sistema 
centrale verso i satelliti, l'installazione e la misurazione con 
ImageJ, un programma liberamente disponibile di analisi di immagine. 
Gli utenti impiegano il software per regolare la calibratura 
spaziale di un'immagine, quindi selezionano e misurano le distanze 
direttamente dall'immagine. I risultati di misura sono segnalati
nelle unità nell'ambiente. Gli utenti egualmente selezionano, 
misurano e confrontano la zona coperta dal mare in tre immagini di 
serie cronologica. Le tecniche descritte sono utili soltanto per
le immagini di vista di nadir (basso diritto).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι χρήστες μεταφορτώνουν και αναλύουν τα καλολογικά 
στοιχεία MODIS από το 2001 και το 2003 για να ποσολογήσουν
το στένεμα της θάλασσας της ARAL. Οι χρήστες βημάτων 
κεφαλαίου μέσω της μεταφόρτωσης, της εγκατάστασης, και της 
μέτρησης με ImageJ, ένα ελεύθερα διαθέσιμο πρόγραμμα ανάλυσης
εικόνας. Οι χρήστες χρησιμοποιούν το λογισμικό για να 
θέσουν τη χωρική βαθμολόγηση μιας εικόνας, κατόπιν επίλεκτες και
αποστάσεις μέτρου άμεσα από την εικόνα. Τα αποτελέσματα 
μέτρησης αναφέρονται στις πραγματικές μονάδες. Οι χρήστες 
επιλέγουν επίσης, μετρούν, και συγκρίνουν την περιοχή που 
καλύπτεται θαλασσίως σε τρεις time-series εικόνες. Οι 
τεχνικές που περιγράφονται είναι χρήσιμες μόνο για τις εικόνες 
όψης ναδίρ (ευθύς κάτω).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los utilizadores descargan y analizan imágenes de
MODIS a partir de 2001 y de 2003 para cuantificar contraerse del mar 
de Aral. El capítulo camina los utilizadores con descargar, la 
instalación, y medir con ImageJ, un programa libremente disponible 
del análisis de imagen. Los utilizadores emplean el software 
para fijar la calibración espacial de una imagen, después 
seleccionan y miden distancias directamente de la imagen. Los 
resultados de la medida están señalados en unidades del mundo real. 
Los utilizadores también seleccionan, miden, y comparan el 
área cubierta por el mar en tres imágenes del time-series. Las
técnicas descritas son útiles solamente para las imágenes de la 
opinión del nadir (llanura recta).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LUANN DAHLMAN
FN:LUANN DAHLMAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201368</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105014</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-measuring-distance-and-area-in-satellite-images</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
