<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103430</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103430</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212489</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Bad Bug Book</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Falsche Programmfehler-Buch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Mauvais Livre d'Anomalie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Livro Mau Do Erro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Libro Difettoso Dell'Insetto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κακό βιβλίο προγραμματιστικού λάθους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Mal Libro Del Fallo de funcionamiento</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition (CFSAN) prepared this online handbook on foodborne pathogenic microorganisms (bacteria, viruses and parasites) and natural toxins. Chapters are arranged under the following headings: Pathogenic Bacteria, Enterovirulent Escherichia Coli Group, Parasitic Protozoa and Worms, Viruses, Natural Toxins, Other Pathogenic Agents, and Appendices. The intent of each chapter is to provide basic facts regarding these organisms and toxins including their characteristics, habitat or source, associated foods, infective dose, characteristic disease symptoms, complications, recent and/or major outbreaks, and any susceptible populations. The chapters also contain minimal information on the analytical methods used to detect, isolate, and/or identify the pathogens or natural toxins.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Mitte zur Nahrungsmittelsicherheit und zu 
angewandter Nahrung (CFSAN) bereitete dieses Onlinehandbuch auf 
foodborne pathogenen Mikroorganismen (Bakterium, Viren und Parasiten) 
und natürlichen Giftstoffen vor. Kapitel werden unter den 
folgenden Kopftexten geordnet: Pathogenes Bakterium, 
Enterovirulent Escherichia Coli Gruppe, parasitsche Protozoen und 
Endlosschrauben, Viren, natürliche Giftstoffe, andere pathogene 
Mittel und Anhänge. Die Absicht jedes Kapitels ist, die 
grundlegenden Tatsachen betreffend sind diese organismen und 
Giftstoffe einschließlich ihre Eigenschaften zur Verfügung zu 
stellen, Lebensraum oder Quelle, verbundene Nahrungsmittel, 
ansteckende Dosis, charakteristische Krankheitsymptome, 
Komplikationen, neue und/oder Hauptausbrüche und alle empfindlilchen 
Bevölkerungen. Die Kapitel enthalten auch minimale 
Informationen über die analytischen Methoden, die verwendet werden, 
um die Krankheitserreger oder die natürlichen Giftstoffe zu 
entdecken, zu lokalisieren und/oder zu kennzeichnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le centre pour la sûreté de nourriture et la 
nutrition appliquée (CFSAN) a préparé ce manuel en ligne sur les 
micro-organismes pathogènes portés par les aliments (bactéries, 
virus et parasites) et les toxines normales. Des chapitres sont 
arrangés sous les rubriques suivantes : Bactéries pathogènes,
groupe d'Enterovirulent Escherichia coli, protozoaires et vers 
parasites, virus, toxines normales, d'autres agents pathogènes, et 
annexes. L'intention de chaque chapitre est de fournir les faits
de base concernant ces organizations et toxines comprenant leurs 
caractéristiques, l'habitat ou la source, les nourritures associées,
la dose contagieuse, les symptômes caractéristiques de la maladie, 
les complications, les manifestations récentes et/ou principales, et 
toutes les populations susceptibles. Les chapitres contiennent 
également l'information minimale sur les méthodes analytiques 
employées pour détecter, isoler, et/ou identifier les microbes 
pathogènes ou les toxines normales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O centro para a segurança do alimento e o 
nutrition aplicado (CFSAN) preparou este manual em linha em 
microorganisms pathogenic foodborne (bactérias, vírus e parasites) e
em toxins naturais. Os capítulos são arranjados sob os 
seguintes títulos: Bactérias pathogenic, grupo de coli de 
escherichia de Enterovirulent, protozoa e sem-fins parasíticos, 
vírus, toxins naturais, outros agentes pathogenic, e apêndices. 
A intenção de cada capítulo é fornecer os fatos básicos a 
respeito destes organismos e toxins including suas características, o
habitat ou a fonte, alimentos associados, dose infective, sintomas 
característicos da doença, complicações, outbreaks recentes e/ou 
principais, e todas as populações suscetíveis. Os capítulos 
contêm também a informação mínima nos métodos analíticos usados
detectar, isolar, e/ou identificar os pathogens ou os toxins naturais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il centro per sicurezza dell'alimento e nutrizione
applicata (CFSAN) ha preparato questo manuale in linea sui 
microorganismi patogeni portati dagli alimenti (batteri, virus e 
parassiti) e sulle tossine naturali. I capitoli sono organizzati
sotto le seguenti intestazioni: Batteri patogeni, gruppo di 
Enterovirulent Escherichia coli, protozoi e viti senza fine parassita,
virus, tossine naturali, altri agenti patogeni ed appendici. 
L'intenzione di ogni capitolo è di fornire i fatti di base per 
quanto riguarda questi organismi e tossine compreso le loro 
caratteristiche, habitat o sorgente, alimenti collegati, dose 
infettiva, sintomi caratteristici di malattia, complicazioni, scoppi 
recenti e/o importanti e tutte le popolazioni suscettibili. I 
capitoli egualmente contengono le informazioni minime sui metodi 
analitici impiegati per rilevare, isolare e/o identificare gli agenti 
patogeni o le tossine naturali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κέντρο για την ασφάλεια τροφίμων και την 
εφαρμοσμένη διατροφή (CFSAN) προετοίμασε αυτό το σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση εγχειρίδιο στους τροφικούς παθογόνους μικροοργανισμούς 
(βακτηρίδια, ιοί και παράσιτα) και τις φυσικές τοξίνες. Τα 
κεφάλαια τακτοποιούνται υπό τους ακόλουθους τίτλους: 
Παθογόνα βακτηρίδια, ομάδα Enterovirulent Escherichia 
coli, παρασιτικά πρωτόζωες και σκουλήκια, ιοί, φυσικές 
τοξίνες, άλλοι παθογόνοι πράκτορες, και παραρτήματα. Η 
πρόθεση κάθε κεφαλαίου πρόκειται να παράσχει τα βασικά γεγονότα
σχετικά με αυτούς τους οργανισμούς και τοξίνες 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των χαρακτηριστικών τους, το βιότοπο ή την 
πηγή, τα σχετικά τρόφιμα, τη μολυσματική δόση, τα χαρακτηριστικά
συμπτώματα ασθενειών, περιπλοκές, πρόσφατα ή/και σημαντικά 
ξεσπάσματα, και οποιουσδήποτε ευαίσθητους πληθυσμούς. Τα 
κεφάλαια περιέχουν επίσης τις ελάχιστες πληροφορίες για τις 
αναλυτικές μεθόδους που χρησιμοποιούνται για να ανιχνεύσουν, να 
απομονώσουν, ή/και να προσδιορίσουν τα παθογόνα ή τις φυσικές 
τοξίνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El centro para la seguridad y la nutrición 
aplicada (CFSAN) del alimento preparó este manual en línea en los 
microorganismos patógenos producidos por los alimentos (bacterias, 
virus y parásitos) y las toxinas naturales. Los capítulos se 
arreglan bajo títulos siguientes: Bacterias patógenas, grupo 
de coli de escherichia de Enterovirulent, protozoos y gusanos 
parásitos, virus, toxinas naturales, otros agentes patógenos, y 
apéndices. El intento de cada capítulo es proporcionar a 
hechos básicos con respecto a estos organismos y toxinas incluyendo 
sus características, habitat o fuente, los alimentos asociados, dosis
contagiosa, los síntomas característicos de la enfermedad, las 
complicaciones, los brotes recientes e importantes, y cualquier 
población susceptible. Los capítulos también contienen la 
información mínima sobre los métodos analíticos usados para 
detectar, para aislar, y/o para identificar los patógeno o las 
toxinas naturales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:THE CENTER FOR FOOD SAFETY AND APPLIED NUTRITION
FN:THE CENTER FOR FOOD SAFETY AND APPLIED NUTRITION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:U.S. FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION
FN:U.S. FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212489</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103430</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-bad-bug-book</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
