<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107827</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107827</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205569</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Madrid Pub Quiz: Culture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Madrid Publikation Quiz: Kultur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Jeu de Publication de Madrid : Culture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Quiz Da Publicação De Madrid: Cultura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Quiz Della Pubblicazione De Madrid: 
Coltura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο διαγωνισμός γνώσεων μπαρ της Μαδρίτης: 
Πολιτισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Concurso De la Publicación De Madrid: 
Cultura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Madrid Pub Quiz was released into the public domain at http://www.avendano.org/quiz. The wording of the original license is 'Feel free to use these questions in your quizzes'. The conversion of the questions into Qedoc format has required changes to questions, such as wording changes and changes of question types to suit the electronic, automatically correcting environment. In the culture quiz, some paintings and photographs have also been inserted where relevant. Most of the questions in the Madrid Pub Quiz are text response questions. Answers are usually short words or phrases which must be typed in. Occasionally multiple text response task types and numerical task types (such as sliders) are used instead. There is a single level, consisting of 15 questions drawn at random from the much larger question bank. Scoring is automatic and it is possible to monitor improvements over time.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Madrid Publikation Quiz wurde in das public 
domain an http://www.avendano.org/quiz freigegeben. Der Wording 
der ursprünglichen Lizenz ist ' das Gefühl, frei, zum dieser Fragen 
in Ihren Quizen zu verwenden. Die Konvertierung der Fragen in 
Qedoc Format hat Änderungen an den Fragen, wie Wordingänderungen und
Änderungen der Frage Typen benötigt, um das elektronische zu 
entsprechen und Umgebung automatisch behoben. Im Kulturquiz sind
einige Anstriche und Fotographien auch eingesetzt worden, wo relevant.
Die meisten Fragen im Madrid Publikation Quiz sind 
Textwartefragen. Antworten sind normalerweise kurze Wörter oder
Phrasen, die eingetippt werden müssen. Gelegentlich mehrfache 
Textwarteaufgabetypen und numerische Aufgabetypen (wie Schweber) 
werden anstatt benutzt. Es gibt eine einzelne Stufe und besteht 
aus 15 Fragen, die zufällig von der viel größeren Frage Bank 
gezeichnet werden. Das Zählen ist automatisch und es ist 
möglich, Verbesserungen über Zeit zu überwachen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le jeu de publication de Madrid a été déchargé
dans le public domain à http://www.avendano.org/quiz. Les mots 
du permis initial sont 'sensation librement pour utiliser ces 
questions dans vos jeux. La conversion des questions dans le 
format de Qedoc a exigé des changements aux questions, telles que des
changements de mots et des changements des types de question pour 
convenir à l'électronique, corrigeant automatiquement 
l'environnement. Dans le jeu de culture, quelques peintures et 
photographies ont été également insérées là où approprié. 
La plupart des questions dans le jeu de publication de Madrid 
sont des questions de réponse des textes. Les réponses sont 
habituellement des mots ou des expressions courts qui doivent être 
saisis. La réponse de temps en temps multiple des textes 
chargent des types et numérique chargez les types 
(tels que des glisseurs) sont utilisés à la place. Il y a un 
niveau simple, se composant de 15 questions tirées au hasard de la 
banque beaucoup plus grande de question. Le marquage est 
automatique et il est possible de surveiller des améliorations avec 
le temps.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O quiz da publicação de Madrid foi liberado no 
public domain em http://www.avendano.org/quiz. O fraseio da 
licença original é ' sensação livre para usar estas perguntas em 
seus quizzes'. A conversão das perguntas no formato de Qedoc 
requereu mudanças às perguntas, tais como as mudanças do fraseio e 
as mudanças de tipos da pergunta para servir o eletrônico, 
corrigindo automaticamente o ambiente. No quiz da cultura, 
algumas pinturas e fotografias foram introduzidas também onde 
relevante. A maioria das perguntas no quiz da publicação de 
Madrid são perguntas da resposta do texto. As respostas são 
geralmente as palavras ou as frases curtas que devem ser 
datilografadas dentro. Os tipos ocasionalmente múltiplos da 
tarefa da resposta do texto e os tipos numéricos da tarefa (tais como
sliders) são usados preferivelmente. Há um único nível, 
consistindo em 15 perguntas desenhadas em aleatório do banco muito 
maior da pergunta. Marcar é automático e é possível 
monitorar melhorias sobre o tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il quiz della pubblicazione de Madrid è stato 
scaricato nel public domain a http://www.avendano.org/quiz. Il 
wording dell'autorizzazione originale è liberamente 'tatto per usare 
queste domande nei vostri quiz. La conversione delle domande nel
formato di Qedoc ha richiesto i cambiamenti alle domande, quali i 
cambiamenti di wording ed i cambiamenti dei tipi di domanda per 
soddisfare l'elettronico, correggenti automaticamente l'ambiente. 
Nel quiz della coltura, alcune pitture e fotografie egualmente 
sono state inserite dove relativo. La maggior parte delle 
domande nel quiz della pubblicazione de Madrid sono domande di 
risposta del testo. Le risposte sono solitamente parole o frasi 
corte che devono essere digitate dentro. I tipi occasionalmente 
multipli di operazione di risposta del testo ed i tipi numerici di 
operazione (quali i cursori) sono usati preferibilmente. Ci è 
un singolo livello, consistente di 15 domande dissipate a caso dalla 
banca molto più grande di domanda. Notare è automatico 
ed è possibile controllare i miglioramenti col tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο διαγωνισμός γνώσεων μπαρ της Μαδρίτης εκδόθηκε στο 
δημόσιο τομέα σε http://www.avendano.org/quiz. Η διατύπωση
της αρχικής άδειας είναι "αίσθηση ελεύθερη να χρησιμοποιήσει 
αυτές τις ερωτήσεις στους διαγωνισμοους γνώσεών σασ". Η 
μετατροπή των ερωτήσεων στη μορφή Qedoc έχει απαιτήσει τις 
αλλαγές στις ερωτήσεις, όπως η διατύπωση των αλλαγών και των 
αλλαγών των τύπων ερώτησης για να ταιριάξει το ηλεκτρονικό, 
διορθώνοντας αυτόματα περιβάλλον. Στο διαγωνισμό γνώσεων 
πολιτισμού, μερικές έργα ζωγραφικής και φωτογραφίες έχουν 
παρεμβληθεί επίσης στις σχετικές περιπτώσεις. Οι 
περισσότερες από τις ερωτήσεις στο διαγωνισμό γνώσεων μπαρ της 
Μαδρίτης είναι ερωτήσεις απάντησης κειμένων. Οι απαντήσεις
είναι συνήθως σύντομες λέξεις ή φράσεις που πρέπει να 
δακτυλογραφηθούν μέσα. Περιστασιακά οι πολλαπλάσιοι 
στοιχειώδεις τύποι απάντησης κειμένων και οι αριθμητικοί 
στοιχειώδεις τύποι (όπως οι ολισθαίνοντες ρυθμιστές) 
χρησιμοποιούνται αντ' αυτού. Υπάρχει ένα ενιαίο επίπεδο, 
που αποτελείται από 15 ερωτήσεις που προέρχονται τυχαία από 
την πολύ μεγαλύτερη τράπεζα ερώτησης. Η σημείωση είναι 
αυτόματη και είναι δυνατό να ελεγχθούν οι βελτιώσεις κατά τη 
διάρκεια του χρόνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El concurso de la publicación de Madrid 
release/versión en el public domain en http://www.avendano.org/quiz. 
La fraseología de la licencia original es ' sensación 
libremente para utilizar estas preguntas en sus concursos. La 
conversión de las preguntas en el formato de Qedoc ha requerido 
cambios a las preguntas, tales como cambios de la fraseología y 
cambios de los tipos de la pregunta para satisfacer el electrónico, 
corrigiendo automáticamente el ambiente. En el concurso de la 
cultura, algunas pinturas y fotografías también se han insertado 
cuando sea relevante. La mayoría de las preguntas en el 
concurso de la publicación de Madrid son preguntas de la respuesta 
del texto. Las respuestas son generalmente las palabras o las 
frases cortas que se deben pulsar adentro. Los tipos de vez en 
cuando múltiples de la tarea de la respuesta del texto y los tipos 
numéricos de la tarea (tales como resbaladores) se utilizan en lugar 
de otro. Hay un solo nivel, consistiendo en 15 preguntas 
trazadas al azar de la batería mucho más grande de la pregunta. 
El anotar es automático y es posible vigilar mejoras en un 
cierto plazo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:QEDOC EDUCATIONAL TEAM
FN:QEDOC EDUCATIONAL TEAM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205569</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107827</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-madrid-pub-quiz-culture</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
