<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105501</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105501</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086417</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Looking for America: The Index of American Design</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Suchen nach Amerika: Der Index des 
amerikanischen Designs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Recherche de l'Amérique : L'incrément de la
conception américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Procurando América: O deslocamento 
predeterminado do projeto americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ricerca dell'America: L'indice del disegno 
americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έρευνα της Αμερικής: Το ευρετήριο του 
αμερικανικού σχεδίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Buscar América: El índice del diseño 
americano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">New Deal arts projects were guided by two novel assumptions: artists were workers and art was cultural labor worthy of government support. That commitment was demonstrated most dramatically in the Federal Art Project (FAP), a relief program for depression-era artists. Some painters and sculptors continued working in their studios with the assistance of relief checks--their work was placed in libraries, schools, and other public buildings. Others lent their talents to community art centers that made art training and appreciation accessible to wider audiences. FAP also sponsored the Index of American Design, which set out to discover what was "American" in decorative arts: several hundred artists produced illustrations of thousands of objects in museums and private collections, a source that remains invaluable for historians of American art, society, and culture. In essays written as part of the New Deal's documentation of its own efforts, two editors of the Index of American Design explained the exhaustive search for a distinctive American art in the artifacts of everyday use and decoration.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kunstprojekte des neuen Abkommens wurden durch 
zwei Romanannahmen geführt: Künstler waren Arbeiter und kunst 
war der Regierungsunterstützung kulturelles Arbeitsangemessenes. 
Diese Verpflichtung wurde drastisch im Bundeskunst-Projekt 
(FAP), ein Entlastung Programm für Tiefstand-Ära Künstler 
demonstriert. Einige Maler und Sculptors fuhren fort, in ihren 
Studios mit der Unterstützung der Entlastung Überprüfungen zu 
arbeiten -- ihre Arbeit wurde in Bibliotheken, in Schulen und in 
andere allgemeine Gebäude gelegt. Andere verliehen ihre Talente
zu den Gemeinschaftskunstmitten, die das kunsttraining und 
-anerkennung zugänglich zu den breiteren Publikum bildeten. FAP
förderte auch den Index des amerikanischen Designs, der darlegte, um 
zu entdecken, was "Amerikaner" in den dekorativen künsten war: 
mehreree hundert Künstler produzierten Abbildungen von 
Tausenden Nachrichten in den Museen und in den privaten Ansammlungen, 
eine Quelle, die für Historiker der amerikanischen kunst, 
Gesellschaft und Kultur unschaetzbar bleibt. In den Versuchen, 
die als Teil der Unterlagen des neuen Abkommens seiner eigenen 
Bemühungen geschrieben wurden, erklärten zwei Herausgeber des 
Indexes des amerikanischen Designs die vollständige Suche nach einer 
unterscheidenden amerikanischen kunst in den Kunstprodukten des 
täglichen Gebrauches und der Dekoration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des projets d'arts de nouvelle affaire ont été 
guidés par deux prétentions de roman : les artistes étaient 
des ouvriers et l'art était digne de travail culturel du soutien 
gouvernemental. Cet engagement a été démontré le plus 
excessivement dans le projet fédéral d'art (FAP), un programme de 
soulagement pour des artistes de dépression-ère. Quelques 
peintres et sculpteurs ont continué de travailler dans leurs studios 
avec l'aide des contrôles de soulagement -- leur travail a été 
placé dans les bibliothèques, les écoles, et d'autres bâtiments 
publics. D'autres ont prêté leurs talents aux centres d'art de
la communauté qui ont rendu la formation et l'appréciation d'art 
accessibles à des assistances plus larges. FAP a également 
commandité l'incrément de la conception américaine, qui s'est mis 
à découvrir ce qui était "Américain" dans des arts décoratifs : 
plusieurs centaines d'artistes ont produit des illustrations des
milliers d'objets dans les musées et les collections privées, une 
source qui demeure de valeur inestimable pour les historiens de l'art 
américain, la société, et la culture. Dans les essais écrits
en tant qu'élément de la documentation de nouvelle affaire de ses 
propres efforts, deux éditeurs de l'incrément de la conception 
américaine ont expliqué la recherche approfondie d'un art américain
distinctif dans les objets façonnés d'une utilité journalière et 
de la décoration.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os projetos das artes do negócio novo foram 
guiados por duas suposições da novela: os artistas eram 
trabalhadores e a arte era digna labor cultural da sustentação de 
governo. Esse compromisso foi demonstrado o mais dramàtica no 
projeto federal da arte (FAP), um programa do relevo para artistas da 
depression-era. Alguns pintores e sculptors continuaram 
trabalhando em seus estúdios com o auxílio de verificações do 
relevo -- seu trabalho foi colocado nas bibliotecas, nas escolas, e em
outros edifícios públicos. Outros emprestaram seus talents aos
centros da arte da comunidade que fizeram o treinamento e a 
apreciação da arte acessíveis a umas audiências mais largas. 
FAP patrocinou também o deslocamento predeterminado do projeto 
americano, que se ajustou para fora para descobrir o que era 
"americano" em artes decorativas: diverso cem artistas 
produziram ilustrações dos milhares dos objetos nos museus e em 
coleções confidenciais, uma fonte que remanescesse invaluable para 
historians da arte americana, sociedade, e cultura. Nos essays 
escritos como a parte da documentação de negócio novo de seus 
próprios esforços, dois editores do deslocamento predeterminado do 
projeto americano explicaram a busca exhaustive para uma arte 
americana distintiva nos artifacts do uso diário e da decoração.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I progetti di arti di nuovo affare sono stati 
guidati da due presupposti del romanzo: gli artisti erano operai
e l'arte era degno di lavoro culturale del supporto di governo. 
Quell'impegno è stato dimostrato il più drammaticamente nel 
progetto federale di arte (FAP), un programma di rilievo per gli 
artisti di depressione-era. I certi pittori e funzionamento 
continuato scultori nei loro studi con l'assistenza dei controlli di 
rilievo -- il loro lavoro è stato disposto in librerie, in scuole ed 
in altre costruzioni pubbliche. Altri hanno prestato i loro 
talenti ai centri di arte della Comunità che hanno reso 
l'addestramento e l'apprezzamento di arte accessibili ai pubblici più
larghi. FAP egualmente ha patrocinato l'indice del disegno 
americano, che ha precisato per scoprire che cosa era "americano" 
nelle arti decorative: diverse centinaia artisti hanno prodotto 
le illustrazioni delle migliaia degli oggetti in musei e nelle 
collezioni riservate, una sorgente che rimane inestimabile per gli 
storici dell'arte americana, la società e la coltura. Nei saggi
scritti come componente della documentazione del nuovo affare dei 
relativi propri sforzi, due editori dell'indice del disegno americano 
hanno spiegato la ricerca esauriente di un'arte americana distintiva 
nei manufatti di uso giornaliere e della decorazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα νέα προγράμματα τεχνών διαπραγμάτευσης 
καθοδηγήθηκαν από δύο νέες υποθέσεις: οι καλλιτέχνες ήταν
εργαζόμενοι και η τέχνη ήταν πολιτιστική εργασία αντάξια της 
κυβερνητικής υποστήριξης. Εκείνη η υποχρέωση καταδείχθηκε ο
πιό εντυπωσιακά στο ομοσπονδιακό έργο τέχνης (FAP), ένα 
πρόγραμμα ανακούφισης για τους καλλιτέχνες κατάθλιψη-εποχής. 
Μερικοί ζωγράφοι και γλύπτες συνέχισαν στα στούντιό τους 
με τη βοήθεια των ελέγχων ανακούφισης -- η εργασία τους 
τοποθετήθηκε στις βιβλιοθήκες, τα σχολεία, και άλλα δημόσια 
κτήρια. Αλλοι δάνεισαν τα ταλέντα τους στα κοινοτικά 
κέντρα τέχνης που κατέστησαν την κατάρτιση και την εκτίμηση 
τέχνης προσιτές στα ευρύτερα ακροατήρια. FAP υποστήριξε
επίσης το ευρετήριο του αμερικανικού σχεδίου, το οποίο καθόρισε 
να ανακαλύψει αυτό που ήταν "αμερικανικά" στις διακοσμητικές 
τέχνες: αρκετοί καλλιτέχνες παρήγαγαν τις απεικονίσεις 
χιλιάδων αντικείμενα στα μουσεία και τις ιδιωτικές συλλογές, μια 
πηγή που παραμένει ανεκτίμητη για τους ιστορικούς της 
αμερικανικής τέχνης, την κοινωνία, και τον πολιτισμό. Στα 
δοκίμια που γράφτηκαν ως τμήμα της τεκμηρίωσης της νέας 
διαπραγμάτευσης των προσπαθειών του, δύο επεξεργαστές του 
ευρετηρίου του αμερικανικού σχεδίου εξήγησαν την εξαντλητική 
αναζήτηση μιας διακριτικής αμερικανικής τέχνης στα χειροποίητα 
αντικείμενα της καθημερινής χρήσης και της διακόσμησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los proyectos de los artes del nuevo reparto 
fueron dirigidos por dos asunciones de la novela: los artistas 
eran trabajadores y el arte era digno de trabajo cultural de la ayuda 
de gobierno. Esa consolidación fue demostrada lo más 
dramáticamente posible en el proyecto federal del arte (FAP), un 
programa de la relevación para los artistas de la depresio'n-era. 
Algunos pintores y escultores continuaron trabajando en sus 
estudios con la ayuda de los cheques de la relevación -- su trabajo 
fue puesto en bibliotecas, escuelas, y otros edificios públicos. 
Otros prestaron sus talentos a los centros del arte de la 
comunidad que hicieron el entrenamiento y el aprecio del arte 
accesibles a audiencias más anchas. FAP también patrocinó el 
índice del diseño americano, que precisó para descubrir cuál era 
"americano" en artes decorativos: vario cientos artistas 
produjeron ilustraciones de millares de objetos en los museos y las 
colecciones privadas, una fuente que sigue habiendo inestimable para 
los historiadores del arte americano, la sociedad, y la cultura. 
En los ensayos escritos como parte de la documentación del 
nuevo reparto de sus propios esfuerzos, dos editores del índice del 
diseño americano explicaron la búsqueda exhaustiva para un arte 
americano distintivo en los artefactos del uso diario y de la 
decoración.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086417</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105501</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/looking-for-america-the-index-of-american-design</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
