<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106002</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106002</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973938</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: MRI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: MRI</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Magnetic resonance imaging, MRI, represents a breakthrough in medical diagnostics and research. Worldwide, more than 60 million investigations with MRI are performed each year. In 2003, this imaging technique was awarded the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Kerspintomographie, MRI, stellt einen Durchbruch in der 
medizinischen Diagnose und in der Forschung dar. Weltweit werden
mehr als 60 Million Untersuchungen mit MRI jedes Jahr durchgeführt. 
2003 wurde diese Belichtung Technik den Nobelpreis in der 
Physiologie oder in der Medizin zugesprochen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! La 
formation image de résonance magnétique, MRI, représente une 
découverte dans le diagnostic et la recherche médicaux. Dans 
le monde entier, plus de 60 millions d'investigations avec MRI sont 
exécutées tous les ans. En 2003, cette technique de formation 
image a été attribuée le prix Nobel dans la physiologie ou la 
médecine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! A 
imagem latente de resonance magnético, MRI, representa uma descoberta
no diagnóstico e na pesquisa médicos. Worldwide, mais de 60 
milhão investigações com MRI são executadas cada ano. Em 
2003, esta técnica da imagem latente foi concedida o prêmio de nobel
no physiology ou na medicina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! La formazione immagine di 
risonanza magnetica, MRI, rappresenta un'innovazione nel sistema 
diagnostico e nella ricerca medici. Universalmente, più di 60 
milione indagini con MRI sono realizzate ogni anno. In 2003, 
questa tecnica di formazione immagine ha ricevuto il premio Nobel 
nella fisiologia o nella medicina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Η 
απεικόνιση μαγνητικής αντήχησης, MRI, αντιπροσωπεύει μια 
σημαντική ανακάλυψη στα ιατρικές διαγνωστικά και την έρευνα. 
Παγκοσμίως, περισσότερες από 60 εκατομμύριο έρευνες με 
MRI εκτελούνται κάθε έτος. Το 2003, αυτή η τεχνική 
απεικόνισης απονεμήθηκε το βραβείο Νόμπελ στη φυσιολογία ή την 
ιατρική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un descubrimiento
o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! La proyección de 
imagen de resonancia magnética, MRI, representa un descubrimiento en 
diagnóstico y la investigación médicos. Por todo el mundo, 
más de 60 millones de investigaciones con MRI se realizan cada año. 
En 2003, esta técnica de la proyección de imagen fue concedida
el premio Nobel en fisiología o medicina.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973938</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106002</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-mri</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
