<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103344</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103344</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Column That Launched a Union</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Spalte, die einen Anschluß ausstieß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La colonne qui a lancé une union</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A coluna que lançou uma união</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La colonna che ha lanciato un'unione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η στήλη που προώθησε μια Ένωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La columna que lanzó una unión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The National Industrial Recovery Act, passed in 1933, was a New Deal program intended to strengthen the economy by regulating production and prices; it also included a provision protecting the right of workers to form unions. One odd place in which a union drive emerged was among newspaper reporters, a group that had long resisted unionization efforts, in part because of their status as "professional" and "white-collar" workers. Newspaper columnist Heywood Broun was a sportswriter who gradually turned to writing book reviews and personal essays; in the 1930s Broun became a member of the Socialist Party and ran unsuccessfully for Congress. On August 7, 1933, Broun published this famous column calling--with some ambivalence--for a journalists' union. The combination of Broun's column, the intransigence of publishers, and the general labor unrest sweeping the nation led to a nationwide flurry of activity among newspaper people, culminating in the December 1933 formation of the American Newspaper Guild (ANG).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die nationale industrielle Wiederanlauf-Tat, 
geführt 1933, war ein Programm des neuen Abkommens, das die 
Wirtschaft verstärken sollte, indem sie Produktion und Preise 
regelte; sie schloß auch eine Bestimmung ein, die das Recht der
Arbeiter schützt, Anschlüße zu bilden. Ein ungerader Platz, 
in dem ein Anschlußlaufwerk auftauchte, gehörte zu 
Zeitungsreportern, eine Gruppe, die lang Unionizationbemühungen 
widerstanden hatte, im Teil wegen ihres Status als Arbeiter "des 
Fachmannes" und "des weißen Stellringes". Zeitung Feuilletonist
Heywood Broun war ein sportswriter, das stufenweise an Schreiben 
Buchbesprechungen und persönliche Versuche wendete; in den 
dreißiger Jahren stand Broun einem Bauteil der sozialistischen 
Partei und lief erfolglos für Kongreß. An August 7, 
1933, Broun veröffentlichte diese berühmte verlangende Spalte -- mit
etwas ambivalenz -- einen Anschluß der Journalisten. Die 
Kombination von Spalte Brouns, die Unnachgiebigkeit der Verleger und die
allgemeine Arbeitsruhelosigkeit, welche die Nation fegt, führten zu 
eine allgemein Aufregung der Aktivität unter Zeitung Leuten und 
kulminierten in der Dezember 1933 Anordnung der amerikanischen Zeitung
Zünft (ANG).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'acte industriel national de reprise, passé en 
1933, était un programme de nouvelle affaire destiné pour renforcer 
l'économie en réglant la production et les prix ; il a 
également inclus une disposition protégeant la droite des ouvriers 
de former des syndicats. Un endroit impair dans lequel un 
lecteur des syndicats a émergé était parmi les journalistes de 
journal, un groupe qui avait longtemps résisté à des efforts de 
syndicalisation, en partie en raison de leur mode en tant qu'ouvriers 
de "professionnel" et "de collier blanc". Le chroniqueur Heywood
Broun de journal était un sportswriter qui s'est graduellement 
tourné vers des revues de livre d'écriture et des essais personnels 
; dans les années 30 Broun est allé bien à un membre du parti
socialiste et a fonctionné sans succès pour le congrès. Août
7, 1933, Broun a édité cette colonne célèbre nécessitant -- avec 
de l'ambivalence -- une union des journalistes. La combinaison 
de la colonne de Broun, l'intransigeance des éditeurs, et le malaise 
ouvrier général balayant la nation ont mené à une bourrasque dans 
tout le pays d'activité parmi des personnes de journal, aboutissant 
à la formation de décembre 1933 de la guilde américaine de journal 
(ANG).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato industrial nacional da recuperação, 
passado em 1933, era um programa do negócio novo pretendido 
strengthen a economia regulando a produção e os preços; 
incluiu também uma provisão que protege a direita dos 
trabalhadores dar forma a uniões. Um lugar impar em que uma 
movimentação da união emergiu era entre os repórteres de jornal, 
um grupo que resistisse por muito tempo esforços do unionization, na 
parte por causa de seu status como trabalhadores do "profissional" e 
"do colar branco". O columnist Heywood Broun do jornal era um 
sportswriter que girasse gradualmente para revisões de livro da 
escrita e essays pessoais; nos 1930s Broun assentou bem em um 
membro do partido socialist e funcionou-o em vão para o congress. 
Agosto em 7, 1933, Broun publicou esta coluna famosa que 
chama-se -- com algum ambivalence -- para uma união dos journalists'.
A combinação da coluna de Broun, o intransigence dos 
publishers, e o unrest labor geral que varre a nação conduziram a um
flurry de âmbito nacional da atividade entre povos do jornal, 
culminando na formação de dezembro 1933 do guild americano do jornal
(ANG).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge industriale nazionale di recupero, 
passata in 1933, era un programma di nuovo affare progettato per 
rinforzare l'economia regolando la produzione ed i prezzi; 
egualmente ha incluso una misura che protegge la destra degli 
operai formare i sindacati. Un posto dispari in cui un 
azionamento del sindacato è emerso era fra i reporter del 
giornale, un gruppo che lungamente aveva resistito agli sforzi di 
unionization, in parte a causa della loro condizione come operai del 
collare bianco "e" "" del professionista. Il columnist Heywood 
Broun del giornale era uno sportswriter che si è girato gradualmente 
verso le revisioni di libro di scrittura ed i saggi personali; 
nei 1930s Broun ha stato bene ad un membro del partito 
socialista ed ha funzionato senza successo per il congresso. Il 
7 agosto 1933, Broun ha pubblicato questa colonna famosa che richiede 
-- con una certa ambivalenza -- un'unione dei giornalisti. La 
combinazione della colonna del Broun, il intransigence degli editori e
l'agitazione di lavoro generale che scopa la nazione hanno condotto 
ad un turbine di neve nazionale di attività fra la gente del 
giornale, culminante nella formazione di dicembre del 1933 della 
cooperativa americana del giornale (ANG).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον εθνικό βιομηχανικό νόμο ανάκαμψης, που πέρασαν το
1933, ήταν ένα νέο πρόγραμμα διαπραγμάτευσης που προορίστηκε 
για να ενισχύσει την οικονομία με τη ρύθμιση της παραγωγής και των
τιμών  περιέλαβε επίσης μια διάταξη που προστατεύει το 
δικαίωμα των εργαζομένων να συγκροτήσουν τις συνδικαλιστικές 
οργανώσεις. Μια περίεργη θέση στην οποία μια κίνηση ένωσης
προέκυψε ήταν μεταξύ των δημοσιογράφων εφημερίδων, μια ομάδα που
είχε αντισταθεί από καιρό στις προσπάθειες συνδικαλικοποίησης, 
εν μέρει λόγω της θέσης τους όπως "επαγγελματικούσ" και 
"υπαλληλικούσ" εργαζομένους. Ο αρθρογράφος Heywood 
Broun εφημερίδων ήταν ένα sportswriter που γύρισε βαθμιαία 
στο γράψιμο των αναθεωρήσεων βιβλίων και των προσωπικών δοκίμιων 
στη δεκαετία του '30 Broun έγινε μέλος του Σοσιαλιστικού 
Κόμματος και έτρεξε ανεπιτυχώς για το συνέδριο. Στις 7 
Αυγούστου ..1933, Broun δημοσίευσε αυτήν την διάσημη στήλη 
που απαιτεί -- με κάποια αμφιθυμία -- μια ένωση των 
δημοσιογράφων. Ο συνδυασμός στήλης Broun, η αδιαλλαξία 
των εκδοτών, και η γενική ανησυχία εργασίας που σκουπίζει το 
έθνος οδήγησαν σε μια σε εθνικό επίπεδο αναταραχή της 
δραστηριότητας μεταξύ των ανθρώπων εφημερίδων, που καταλήγει στο 
σχηματισμό Δεκεμβρίου 1933 της αμερικανικής συντεχνίας 
εφημερίδων (ANG).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto industrial nacional de la recuperación, 
pasado en 1933, era un programa del nuevo reparto previsto para 
consolidar la economía regulando la producción y precios; 
también incluyó una disposición que protegía la derecha de 
trabajadores de formar uniones. Un lugar impar en el cual un 
mecanismo impulsor de la unión emergió estaba entre los reporteros, 
grupo que se había opuesto de largo a esfuerzos de la 
sindicalización, en parte debido a su estatus como trabajadores del 
"profesional" y del "collar blanco". El columnista Heywood Broun
del periódico era un sportswriter que dio vuelta gradualmente a las 
revisiones de libro de la escritura y a los ensayos personales; 
en los años 30 Broun sintió bien a un miembro del partido 
socialista y se ejecutó sin éxito para el congreso. De agosto 
el 7 de 1933, Broun publicó esta columna famosa que llamaba -- con 
una cierta ambivalencia -- para una unión de los periodistas. 
La combinación de la columna de Broun, la intransigencia de 
editores, y el malestar de trabajo general que barría la nación 
condujeron a una ráfaga a nivel nacional de la actividad entre la 
gente del periódico, culminando en la formación de diciembre de 1933
del gremio americano del periódico (ANG).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103344</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-column-that-launched-a-union</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
