<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086061</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Deaf and Unemployed in Dubuque: The DiMarcos Remember the Great Depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Taub und Arbeitslose in Dubuque: Das 
DiMarcos erinnern sich den an großen Tiefstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sourd et chômeurs dans Dubuque : Le 
DiMarcos se rappellent la grande dépression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Surdo e desempregados em Dubuque: O DiMarcos
recorda o depression grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sordo e disoccupati in Dubuque: Il DiMarcos 
si ricorda della depressione grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κωφός και άνεργος σε Dubuque: Τα DiMarcos 
θυμούνται τη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sordo y parados en Dubuque: El DiMarcos 
recuerda la gran depresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The New Deal launched a series of federal employment programs, including the Works Progress Administration (WPA), which not only provided jobs but also initiated many important studies of the depression_s human toll. One such study, published by the WPA Division of Research in 1939, included transcripts of interviews by WPA workers with Dubuque, Iowa, families. The DiMarcos interview revealed that the disabled faced a double challenge during the depression: finding employment while competing for scarce jobs with the able-bodied. The DiMarcos, a deaf couple with a small child, recall in their own words (because they were deaf they had to write responses to the WPA interviewer's questions), the struggles they endured during six years of unemployment.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das neue Abkommen stieß eine Reihe 
Bundesbeschäftigungprogramme, einschließlich die Arbeiten 
Fortschritt-Leitung aus (WPA), das nicht nur Jobs lieferte, aber 
initialisiert auch viele wichtige Studien der depression_s Mensch 
Abgabe. Eine solche Studie, veröffentlicht durch die WPA 
Abteilung der Forschung 1939, schloß Abschriften von Interviews mit 
WPA Arbeitern mit Dubuque, Iowa, Familien ein. Das DiMarcos 
Interview deckte auf, daß das untaugliche eine doppelte 
Herausforderung während des Tiefstands gegenüberstellte: 
Finden von von Beschäftigung beim Konkurrieren für knappe Jobs
mit dem kerngesunden. Das DiMarcos, ein taubes Paar mit einem 
kleinen Kind, Rückruf in ihren eigenen Wörtern (weil sie sie mußten
Antworten zu den Fragen des WPA Interviewers schreiben taub waren), 
die Kämpfe, die sie während sechs Jahre Arbeitslosigkeit aushielten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La nouvelle affaire a lancé une série de 
programmes fédéraux d'emploi, y compris la gestion d'avancement de 
travaux (WPA), qui a non seulement fourni les travaux mais lance 
également beaucoup d'études importantes du péage d'humain de 
depression_s. Une telle étude, éditée par la Division de WPA 
de la recherche en 1939, a inclus des transcriptions des entrevues par
des ouvriers de WPA avec Dubuque, Iowa, familles. L'entrevue de 
DiMarcos a indiqué que l'handicapé a relevé un double défi pendant
la dépression : conclusion de l'emploi tout en concurrençant 
pour les travaux rares l'apte. Le DiMarcos, un couple sourd avec
un petit enfant, rappel dans leurs propres mots (parce qu'ils étaient
sourds ils ont dû écrire des réponses aux questions de 
l'interviewer de WPA), les luttes qu'elles ont supportées pendant six
ans du chômage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O negócio novo lançou uma série de programas 
federais do emprego, including a administração do progresso de 
trabalhos (WPA), que não somente os trabalhos fornecidos mas iniciado
também muitos estudos importantes do ser humano dos depression_s 
anunciam. Um tal estudo, publicado pela divisão de WPA da 
pesquisa em 1939, incluiu transcripts das entrevistas por 
trabalhadores com Dubuque, Iowa de WPA, famílias. A entrevista 
de DiMarcos revelou que o disabled enfrentou um desafio dobro durante 
o depression: encontrando o emprego ao competir para trabalhos 
escassos com o são. O DiMarcos, um par surdo com uma criança 
pequena, recordação em suas próprias palavras (porque eram surdos 
eles tiveram que escrever respostas às perguntas do interviewer de 
WPA), os esforços que resistiram durante seis anos do desemprego.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il nuovo affare ha lanciato una serie di programmi
federali di occupazione, compreso la gestione di progresso degli 
impianti (WPA), che a rintocchi non soltanto i lavori forniti ma anche
iniziato molti studi importanti dell'essere umano dei depression_s 
suonano. Uno tale studio, pubblicato dalla divisione di WPA di 
ricerca in 1939, ha incluso le trascrizioni delle interviste dagli 
operai con Dubuque, Iowa, famiglie del WPA. L'intervista di 
DiMarcos ha rivelato che il disabled ha affrontato una doppia sfida 
durante la depressione: individuazione dell'occupazione mentre 
competendo per i lavori limitati al sano. Il DiMarcos, una 
coppia sorda con un piccolo bambino, richiamo nelle loro proprie 
parole (perché erano sordi hanno dovuto scrivere le risposte alle 
domande dell'intervistatore di WPA), le lotte che hanno resistito a 
durante i sei anni di disoccupazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα διαπραγμάτευση εγκαινίασε μια σειρά 
ομοσπονδιακών προγραμμάτων απασχόλησης, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της 
διοίκησης προόδου εργασιών (WPA), η οποία όχι μόνο παρείχε 
τις εργασίες αλλά και άρχισε πολλές σημαντικές μελέτες του 
ανθρώπινου φόρου depression_s. Μια τέτοια μελέτη, που 
δημοσιεύθηκε από το τμήμα WPA της έρευνας το 1939, 
περιέλαβε τα αντίγραφα των συνεντεύξεων από WPA τους 
εργαζομένους με Dubuque, Iowa, οικογένειες. Η 
συνέντευξη DiMarcos αποκάλυψε ότι τα άτομα με ειδικές ανάγκες
αντιμετώπισαν μια διπλή πρόκληση κατά τη διάρκεια της 
κατάθλιψης: εύρεση της απασχόλησης ανταγωνιστικός για τις 
λιγοστές εργασίες με τον αρτιμελή. Το DiMarcos, ένα κωφό
ζεύγος με ένα μικρό παιδί, ανάκληση στις λέξεις τους (επειδή 
ήταν κωφοί αυτοί έπρεπε να γράψουν τις απαντήσεις στις 
ερωτήσεις του ερευνητή WPA), οι προσπάθειες υπόμειναν κατά τη 
διάρκεια έξι ετών ανεργίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El nuevo reparto lanzó una serie de programas 
federales del empleo, incluyendo la administración del progreso de 
trabajos (WPA), que no solamente los trabajos proporcionados pero 
también iniciado muchos estudios importantes del ser humano de los 
depression_s tocan. Un tal estudio, publicado por la división 
de WPA de la investigación en 1939, incluyó transcripciones de 
entrevistas de los trabajadores con Dubuque, Iowa, familias de WPA. 
La entrevista de DiMarcos reveló que el lisiado hizo frente a 
un desafío doble durante la depresión: encontrar el empleo 
mientras que compite para los trabajos escasos con el sano. El 
DiMarcos, un par sordo con un niño pequeño, memoria en sus propias 
palabras (porque eran sordos ellos tuvieron que escribir respuestas a 
las preguntas del entrevistador de WPA), las luchas que aguantaron 
durante seis años de desempleo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086061</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104755</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/deaf-and-unemployed-in-dubuque-the-dimarcos-remember-the-great-depression</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
