<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106382</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106382</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201606</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Excel Tutorial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Übertreffen Sie Tutorial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Excelez Le Cours d'instruction</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Excel O Tutorial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Eccella La Lezione privata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σεμινάριο Excel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sobresalga La Guía</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is a basic tutorial for Excel spreadsheet software designed by Brad James of University of South Dakota. The tutorial is designed as a general walkthrough for Excel and it is recommended that users run the Excel program at the same time as the tutorial. The tutorial includes a variety of topics including, but not restricted to, the basics of spreadsheets, types of data, specific formulas and formatting instructions. This is an excellent beginners guide to Excel complete with images depicting screens you may encounter while using Excel.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist ein grundlegender Tutorial für 
übertreffen die Kalkulationstabelle Software, die von Brad James der 
Universität von South Dakota konzipiert ist. Der Tutorial ist 
konzipiert, während ein allgemeines walkthrough für übertreffen und
es empfohlen wird, daß Benutzer das übertreffenprogramm zur gleichen
Zeit wie der Tutorial laufen lassen. Der Tutorial schließt eine
Vielzahl von Themen einschließlich ein, aber eingeschränkt nicht 
auf, die Grundlagen der Kalkulationstabellen, die Typen von Daten, die
spezifischen Formeln und die Formatierung Anweisungen. Dieses 
ist eine ausgezeichnete Anfängeranleitung, zum komplettes mit den 
Bildern zu übertreffen, die Bildschirme bildlich darstellen, die Sie 
beim Verwenden antreffen können, übertreffen Sie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un cours d'instruction de base pour 
excellent le logiciel de tableur conçu par Brad James 
d'université du Dakota du sud. Le cours d'instruction est 
conçu pendant qu'un walkthrough général pour excellent et on lui 
recommande que les utilisateurs exécutent le programme d'exceler 
pendant que le cours d'instruction. Le cours d'instruction 
inclut une variété de sujets comprenant, entre autres, des 
fondations des tableurs, de types de données, de formules 
spécifiques et d'instructions de formatage. C'est un excellent 
guide de débutants pour exceler complet avec des images dépeignant 
des écrans que vous pouvez rencontrer tout en en utilisant excelez.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um tutorial básico para excel o software 
do spreadsheet projetado por Brad James da universidade de Dakota sul.
O tutorial está projetado enquanto um walkthrough geral para 
excel e se recomenda que os usuários funcionam o programa do excel ao
mesmo tempo que o tutorial. O tutorial inclui uma variedade dos 
tópicos including, mas não restringido a, os princípios dos 
spreadsheets, tipos de dados, fórmulas específicas e instruções do
formato. Esta é uma guia excelente dos novatos para excel 
completo com as imagens que descrevem telas que você pode encontrar 
ao se usar excel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è una lezione privata di base per eccelle il
software del foglio elettronico progettato da Brad James 
dell'università di Dakota del Sud. La lezione privata è 
progettata mentre un walkthrough generale per eccelle ed è suggerito 
che gli utenti fanno funzionare il programma di supremazia nello 
stesso momento in cui la lezione privata. La lezione privata 
include una varietà di soggetti compreso, ma non limitato a, i 
principi fondamentali dei fogli elettronici, i tipi di dati, le 
formule specifiche e le istruzioni di formattazione. Ciò è 
una guida eccellente dei principianti per eccellere completo con le 
immagini che descrivono gli schermi che potete incontrare mentre 
usando eccella.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι ένα βασικό σεμινάριο για το λογισμικό 
υπολογισμών με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet) Excel που 
σχεδιάζεται από το καρφί james του πανεπιστημίου της νότιας 
Ντακότας. Το σεμινάριο σχεδιάζεται ως γενικό πέρασμα για 
Excel και συνιστάται οι χρήστες να τρέχουν το πρόγραμμα 
Excel ταυτόχρονα με το σεμινάριο. Το σεμινάριο 
περιλαμβάνει ποικίλα θέματα συμπεριλαμβανομένου, αλλά μην 
περιορισμένος, τα βασικά των υπολογισμών με λογιστικό φύλλο 
(spreadsheet), τους τύπους στοιχείων, τους συγκεκριμένους 
τύπους και τις οδηγίες μορφοποίησης. Αυτό είναι ένας 
άριστος οδηγός αρχαρίων σε Excel πλήρες με τις εικόνες 
απεικονίζοντας τις οθόνες που μπορείτε να αντιμετωπίσετε 
χρησιμοποιώντας Excel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es una guía básica para sobresale el 
software de la hoja de balance diseñado por Brad James de la 
universidad de Dakota del Sur. Se diseña la guía mientras que 
un walkthrough general para sobresale y se recomienda que los 
utilizadores ejecutan el programa del sobresalir al mismo tiempo que 
la guía. La guía incluye una variedad de asuntos incluyendo, 
pero no restringido a, los fundamentos de hojas de balance, los tipos 
de datos, los fórmulas específicos y las instrucciones del formato. 
Esto es una guía excelente de los principiantes para sobresalir
completo con las imágenes que representan las pantallas que usted 
puede encontrar mientras que usa sobresalga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BRAD JAMES
FN:BRAD JAMES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201606</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106382</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/excel-tutorial</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
