<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207093</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Women: A Reference Guide</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanische Frauen: Eine 
Referenzanleitung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Femmes Américaines : Un Guide de 
Référence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mulheres Americanas: Uma Guia De 
Referência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Donne Americane: Una Guida Di Riferimento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικές γυναίκες: Ένας οδηγός αναφοράς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mujeres Americanas: Una Guía De Referencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a first stop for using Library of Congress resources to do research in the field of American women's history. It presents some digital items; however, it serves primarily as a comprehensive guide to the entirety of the Library's holdings on women's history. It includes exhibits that feature women and how to find women within exhibits where they're not featured. Essays examine women as a symbol 1590-1800, the women's suffrage parade of 1913, and the equal rights amendment.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein erster Anschlag für das Verwenden der 
Bibliothek der Kongreßbetriebsmittel, um Forschung in auffangene 
der Geschichte der amerikanischen Frauen zu tun. Er stellt 
einige digitale Einzelteile dar; jedoch dient er hauptsächlich 
als komplette Anleitung zur Ganzheit der Holdings der Bibliothek auf 
Geschichte der Frauen. Er enthält Ausstellungen, die Frauen 
kennzeichnen und wie man Frauen innerhalb der Ausstellungen findet, in
denen sie nicht gekennzeichnet werden. Versuche überprüfen 
Frauen als Symbol 1590-1800, die Stimmrechtparade der Frauen von 1913 
und die Gleichgestelltrechtänderung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un premier arrêt pour l'usage de la 
bibliothèque des ressources du congrès pour faire la recherche dans 
le domaine de l'histoire des femmes américaines. Il présente 
quelques éléments digitaux ; cependant, il sert principalement
de guide complet de l'intégralité des possessions de bibliothèque 
sur l'histoire des femmes. Il inclut les objets exposés qui 
comportent des femmes et comment trouver des femmes dans des objets 
exposés où elles ne sont pas décrites. Les essais examinent 
des femmes comme symbole 1590-1800, défilé du suffrage des femmes de
1913, et amendement d'égalité des droits.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um primeiro batente para usar a biblioteca de 
recursos do congress fazer a pesquisa no campo do history das mulheres
americanas. Apresenta alguns artigos digitais; entretanto,
serve primeiramente como uma guia detalhada à totalidade das terras 
arrendadas de biblioteca no history das mulheres. Inclui as 
exibições que caracterizam mulheres e como encontrar mulheres dentro
das exibições onde não são caracterizadas. Os essays 
examinam mulheres como um símbolo 1590-1800, a parada do suffrage das
mulheres de 1913, e a emenda das direitas do igual.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un primo arresto per usando la libreria delle 
risorse del congresso per fare la ricerca nel campo di storia delle 
donne americane. Presenta alcuni articoli digitali; 
tuttavia, serve soprattutto da guida completa all'interezza 
delle azioni delle biblioteche su storia delle donne. 
Include le esposizioni che caratterizzano le donne e come 
trovare le donne all'interno delle esposizioni in cui non sono 
descritte. I saggi esaminano le donne come un simbolo 1590-1800,
la parata di suffrage delle donne di 1913 e la correzione di diritti 
del uguale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια πρώτη στάση για τη χρησιμοποίηση των 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς βιβλιοθήκης του συνεδρίου για να κάνει την
έρευνα στον τομέα της ιστορίας των αμερικανικών γυναικών. 
Παρουσιάζει μερικά ψηφιακά αντικείμενα  εντούτοις, 
χρησιμεύει πρώτιστα ως ένας περιεκτικός οδηγός στην ολότητα των 
μετοχών της βιβλιοθήκης στην ιστορία των γυναικών. 
Περιλαμβάνει τα εκθέματα που χαρακτηρίζουν τις γυναίκες και 
πώς να βρούν τις γυναίκες μέσα στα εκθέματα όπου δεν 
χαρακτηρίζονται. Τα δοκίμια εξετάζουν τις γυναίκες ως 
σύμβολο 1590-1800, παρέλαση ψήφου των γυναικών του 1913, και
ίση τροποποίηση δικαιωμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una primera parada para usar la biblioteca de 
los recursos del congreso para hacer la investigación en el campo de 
la historia de las mujeres americanas. Presenta algunos items 
digitales; sin embargo, sirve sobre todo como guía comprensiva 
a la totalidad de las tenencias de biblioteca en la historia de las 
mujeres. Incluye los objetos expuestos que ofrecen a mujeres y 
cómo encontrar a mujeres dentro de los objetos expuestos donde las no
ofrecen. Los ensayos examinan a mujeres como un símbolo 
1590-1800, el desfile del sufragio de las mujeres de 1913, y la 
enmienda de las derechas del igual.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207093</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104131</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-women-a-reference-guide</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
