<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105898</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105898</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086463</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Marshall Kirkman Dissects the Science of Railroads</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Marschallkirkman zergliedert die Wissenschaft der 
Eisenbahnen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le kirkman de maréchal dissèque la Science des 
chemins de fer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O kirkman do marshall dissects a ciência das 
estradas de ferro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il kirkman del marshall disseca la scienza delle 
ferrovie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τακτοποιήστε Kirkman τεμαχίζει την επιστήμη των 
σιδηροδρόμων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El kirkman del ordenar diseca la ciencia de 
ferrocarriles</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Railroads were among the earliest U.S. industries to apply modern management principles to their operations. Beginning in the 1850s and 1860s, railroads were the first American businesses to have a large number of salaried managers and an internal organizational structure with clear lines of communication, responsibility, and authority. These managerial innovations, standard by the 1880s, were necessary to control a large number of employees and offices scattered over a vast geographical area. With the growing professionalization of railroad management came a burgeoning professional literature. Marshall M. Kirkman wrote prolifically about railroad management. This excerpt from his multi-volume  The Science of Railways: Organization and Forces  (1896) extolled the virtues of military-like discipline in the running of American railroads.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eisenbahnen gehörten zu den frühesten VEREINIGTE
STAATEN Industrien, zum der modernen Verwaltungsprinzipien an ihren 
Operationen anzuwenden. Anfangend im 1850s und im 1860s, waren 
Eisenbahnen die ersten amerikanischen Geschäfte zum Haben viele 
salaried Manager und eine interne Organisationsstruktur mit freien 
Zeilen der Kommunikation, der Verantwortlichkeit und der Berechtigung.
Diese Verwaltungsinnovationen, die durch das 1880s Standard 
sind, waren notwendig, um viele Angestellte und Büros zu steuern, die
über einen beträchtlichen geographischen Bereich zerstreut wurden. 
Mit der wachsenden Professionalisierung der Eisenbahn kam 
Management eine sprießende professionelle Literatur. Marschall 
M. Kirkman schrieb reich über Eisenbahnmanagement. Dieses 
Excerpt von seinem Mehrbänder die Wissenschaft der Gleise: 
Organisation und Kräfte (1896) priesen die Tugenden 
militärisch-wie der Disziplin in der Ausführung amerikanische 
Eisenbahnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les chemins de fer étaient parmi les industries 
des ETATS-UNIS les plus tôt pour s'appliquer des principes de gestion
modernes à leurs exécutions. Commençant dans le 1850s et le 
1860s, les chemins de fer étaient les premières entreprises 
américaines pour avoir un grand nombre de gestionnaires salariés et 
une structure d'organisation interne avec les lignes claires de la 
transmission, de la responsabilité, et de l'autorité. Ces 
innovations gestionnaires, standard par le 1880s, étaient 
nécessaires pour contrôler un grand nombre d'employés et de bureaux
dispersés au-dessus d'une vaste zone géographique. Avec la 
professionnalisation croissante du chemin de fer la gestion est venue 
une littérature professionnelle bourgeonnante. Le maréchal M. 
Kirkman a écrit prolifique au sujet de la gestion de chemin de fer. 
Cet extrait de son multivolume la Science des chemins de fer : 
L'organisation et les forces (1896) ont exalté les vertus de 
militaire-comme la discipline dans le fonctionnement des chemins de 
fer américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As estradas de ferro eram entre as indústrias as 
mais adiantadas de ESTADOS UNIDOS para aplicar princípios de 
gerência modernos a suas operações. Começando no 1850s e no 
1860s, as estradas de ferro eram os primeiros negócios americanos 
para ter um grande número gerentes remunerados e uma estrutura 
organizational interna com linhas desobstruídas de uma comunicação,
da responsabilidade, e da autoridade. Estas inovações 
managerial, padrão pelo 1880s, eram necessárias para controlar um 
grande número empregados e escritórios dispersados sobre uma área 
geográfica vasta. Com o professionalization crescente da 
estrada de ferro a gerência veio uma literatura profissional 
burgeoning. O marshall M. Kirkman escreveu prolifically sobre a 
gerência da estrada de ferro. Este excerpt do seu multi-volume 
a ciência das estradas de ferro: A organização e as forças 
(1896) extolled os virtues militar-como da disciplina no corredor de 
estradas de ferro americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le ferrovie erano fra le industrie degli STATI 
UNITI più iniziali per applicare i principii di gestione moderni ai 
loro funzionamenti. Cominciando nel 1850s e nel 1860s, le 
ferrovie erano i primi commerci americani per avere tantissimi gestori
stipendiati e una struttura organizzativa interna con le righe libere 
della comunicazione, della responsabilità e dell'autorità. 
Queste innovazioni direttive, standard dal 1880s, erano 
necessarie da gestire tantissimi impiegati ed uffici sparsi sopra una 
zona geografica ampia. Con il professionalization crescente 
della ferrovia la gestione è venuto una letteratura professionale 
burgeoning. Il marshall M. Kirkman ha scritto prolifico circa la
gestione della ferrovia. Questo brano dal suo multi-volume 
scienza delle ferrovie: L'organizzazione e le forze (1896) 
extolled le virtù militare-come di disciplina nel funzionamento delle
ferrovie americane.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σιδηρόδρομοι ήταν μεταξύ των πιό πρώτων 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ βιομηχανιών για να εφαρμόσουν τις σύγχρονες 
διοικητικές αρχές στις διαδικασίες τους. Αρχίζοντας στο 
1850s και το 1860s, οι σιδηρόδρομοι ήταν οι πρώτες 
αμερικανικές επιχειρήσεις για να έχουν έναν μεγάλο αριθμό 
μισθοδοτημένων διευθυντών και μια εσωτερική οργανωτική δομή με 
τις σαφείς γραμμές επικοινωνίας, ευθύνης, και αρχής. Αυτές
οι διευθυντικές καινοτομίες, πρότυπα από το 1880s, ήταν 
απαραίτητες για να ελέγξουν έναν μεγάλο αριθμό υπαλλήλων και 
γραφείων που διασκορπίστηκαν πέρα από μια απέραντη γεωγραφική 
περιοχή. Με την αυξανόμενη επαγγελματικοποίηση του 
σιδηροδρόμου η διαχείριση ήρθε μια να φυτρώσει επαγγελματική 
λογοτεχνία. Τακτοποιήστε Μ. Kirkman έγραψε prolifically
για τη διαχείριση σιδηροδρόμου. Αυτό το απόσπασμα από 
multi-volume του η επιστήμη των σιδηροδρόμων: Η οργάνωση 
και οι δυνάμεις (1896) οι αρετές της στρατιωτικός-όπως 
πειθαρχίας στο τρέξιμο των αμερικανικών σιδηροδρόμων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los ferrocarriles estaban entre las industrias 
más tempranas de ESTADOS UNIDOS para aplicar principios de gerencia 
modernos a sus operaciones. Comenzando en el 1850s y el 1860s, 
los ferrocarriles eran los primeros negocios americanos para tener una
gran cantidad de encargados a sueldo y una estructura de organización
interna con las líneas claras de la comunicación, de la 
responsabilidad, y de la autoridad. Estas innovaciones 
directivas, estándares por el 1880s, eran necesarias controlar una 
gran cantidad de empleados y de oficinas dispersados sobre un área 
geográfica extensa. Con la profesionalización cada vez mayor 
del ferrocarril la gerencia vino una literatura profesional 
burgeoning. El ordenar M. Kirkman escribió prolífico sobre la 
gerencia del ferrocarril. Este extracto de su multivolumen la 
ciencia de ferrocarriles: La organización y las fuerzas (1896) 
extolled las virtudes militar-como de la disciplina en el 
funcionamiento de ferrocarriles americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086463</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105898</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/marshall-kirkman-dissects-the-science-of-railroads</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
