<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103074</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103074</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Springwood: Birthplace and Home to Franklin D. Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Springwood: Geburtsort und Haus zu Franklin
D. Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Springwood : Lieu de naissance et maison à
Franklin D. Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Springwood: Birthplace e HOME a Franklin D.
Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Springwood: Luogo di nascita e sede a 
Franklin D. Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Springwood: Τόπος γεννήσεως και "Οικία" 
Franklin Δ. Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Springwood: Lugar de nacimiento y hogar a 
Franklin D. Roosevelt</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the only place in the U.S. where a President was born, maintained a lifelong connection, and lies buried. The estate, located in Hyde Park on the Hudson River (New York), is where he was raised and where he and his wife, Eleanor, raised their five children. During his first political election he delivered his acceptance speeches from the portico of this house. Cabinet members, heads of state, royalty, congressmen, senators, and Secret Service stayed at the house during his presidency.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist der einzige Platz in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN,
in dem ein Präsident geboren war, beibehalten einem lebenslänglichen
Anschluß, und den begrabenen Lügen. Der Zustand, gelegen in 
Hyde Park auf dem Hudson Fluß (New York), ist, wohin er angehoben 
wurde und wo er und seine Frau, Eleanor, anhob ihre fünf Kinder. 
Während seiner ersten politischen Wahl lieferte er seine 
Abnahmereden vom Portico dieses Hauses. Kabinettsmitgliedas, 
Staatsoberhäupter, Abgabe, Kongreßabgeordnete, Senatoren und 
geheimer Service blieben am Haus während seines Vorsitzes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le seul endroit aux ETATS-UNIS où un 
président est né, mis à jour une connexion perpétuelle, et des 
mensonges enterrés. Le domaine, situé dans Hyde Park sur le 
fleuve de Hudson (New York), est où il a été élevé et où lui et 
son épouse, Eleanor, a élevé leurs cinq enfants. Pendant sa 
première élection politique il a fourni ses discours d'acceptation 
du portique de cette maison. Les membres du conseil, les 
chefs d'Etat, la redevance, les membres du Congrès, les sénateurs, 
et le service secret sont restés à la maison pendant sa présidence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o único lugar nos ESTADOS UNIDOS onde um 
presidente foi carregado, mantido uma conexão lifelong, e as mentiras
enterradas. A propriedade, situada em Hyde Park no rio de Hudson
(New York), é o lugar aonde foi levantado e onde ele e sua esposa, 
Eleanor, levantou suas cinco crianças. Durante sua primeira 
eleição política entregou seus discursos da aceitação do portico 
desta casa. Os membros de armário, as cabeças de estado, o 
royalty, os congressistas, os senators, e o serviço secreto 
permaneceram na casa durante seu presidency.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è l'unico posto negli STATI UNITI in cui un 
presidente è stato sopportato, effettuato un collegamento lifelong e 
bugie sepolte. La proprietà, situata in Hyde Park sul fiume di 
Hudson (New York), è dove è stato alzato e dove lui e la sua moglie,
Eleanor, ha alzato i loro cinque bambini. Durante la sua prima 
elezione politica ha trasportato i suoi discorsi di accettazione dal 
portico di questa casa. I membri del Governo, teste di 
dichiarano, la sovranità, membri del Congresso, senatori e 
servizio segreto rimasto alla casa durante la sua presidenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι το μόνο μέρος στις ΗΠΑ όπου ένας Πρόεδρος 
γεννήθηκε, διατήρησε μια ισόβια σύνδεση, και βρίσκεται θαμμένος.
Το κτήμα, που βρίσκεται στο πάρκο Hyde στον ποταμό 
Hudson (Νέα Υόρκη), είναι όπου ανατράφηκε και πού αυτός και 
η σύζυγός του, Eleanor, ανέθρεψαν πέντε παιδιά τους. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια της πρώτης πολιτικής εκλογής του παρέδωσε
τις ομιλίες αποδοχής του από το portico αυτού του σπιτιού. 
Τα μέλη γραφείου, αρχηγοί κράτους, του δικαιώματος, των 
μελών του Κογκρέσσου, των γερουσιαστών, και της μυστικής 
υπηρεσίας έμειναν στο σπίτι κατά τη διάρκεια της προεδρίας του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el único lugar en los ESTADOS UNIDOS en donde
un presidente nació, mantenido una conexión de por vida, y las 
mentiras enterradas. El estado, situado en Hyde Park en el río 
de Hudson (Nueva York), es adonde lo criaron y donde él y su esposa, 
Eleanor, crió a sus cinco niños. Durante su primera elección 
política él entregó sus discursos de la aceptación del pórtico de
esta casa. Los miembros del Consejo, los jefes de estado, los 
derechos, los miembros del Congreso, los senadores, y el servicio 
secreto permanecían en la casa durante su presidencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103074</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/springwood-birthplace-and-home-to-franklin-d-roosevelt</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
