<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107025</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107025</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087187</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Didn't Have Flies Until the White Man Came": A Yankton Sioux Remembers Life on the Plains in the Late 19th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir hatten nicht fliegen, bis der weiße Mann" 
kam: Ein Yankton Sioux erinnert sich das an Leben auf den Ebenen
im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous n'avons pas eu vole jusqu'à ce que l'homme
blanc soit venu" : Un Yankton Sioux se rappelle la vie sur les 
plaines vers la fin du 19ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós não tivemos voamos até que o homem branco
veio": Um Yankton Sioux recorda a vida nas planícies no 1ø 
século atrasado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non abbiamo avuti voliamo fino a che l'uomo 
bianco non venisse": Un Yankton Sioux si ricorda della vita 
sulle pianure verso la fine del diciannovesimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν είχαμε τις μύγες έως ότου ήρθε το λευκό 
άτομο": Ένα Yankton Σιού θυμάται τη ζωή στις πεδιάδες 
προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no teníamos volamos hasta que vino el hombre 
blanco": Un Yankton Sioux recuerda vida en los llanos en la a 
fines del siglo XIX</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the era before the U. S. Army conquered the Great Plains Indians the region's giant buffalo herds provided the primary food and clothing source for the Indians who lived there. Indeed, in 19th century America buffalo were more numerous than people. The various Lakota Sioux tribes who lived in the area that became South Dakota and Nebraska depended largely on the buffalo hunt according to Paul Picotte, a Yankton Sioux born in 1880. In this transcript of a 1968 interview with historian Joseph Cash, Picotte recalled the elaborate process used to hunt, dress, and preserve buffalo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Ära, bevor die USARMEE die Prairie-Inder 
eroberte, stellten die riesigen Büffelherden der Region die 
Primärnahrungsmittel- und Kleidungquelle für die Inder zur 
Verfügung, die dort lebten. In der Tat in 19. Jahrhundert 
Amerika waren Büffel zahlreicher als Leute. Die verschiedenen 
Lakota Sioux Stämme, die im Bereich lebten, der South Dakota wurde 
und Nebraska groß von der Büffeljagd entsprechend Paul Picotte 
abhing, ein Yankton Sioux getragen 1880. In dieser Abschrift 
eines Interviews 1968 mit Historiker Joseph Bargeld, erinnerte an 
Picotte den durchdachten Prozeß, der verwendet wurde, um Büffel zu 
jagen, zu kleiden und zu konservieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans l'ère avant que l'armée américain Ait 
conquis les Indiens de grandes plaines les troupeaux géants du buffle
de la région ont fourni la source primaire de nourriture et 
d'habillement pour les Indiens qui ont vécus là. En effet, en 
19ème Amérique de siècle le buffle étaient plus nombreux que des 
personnes. Les diverses tribus de Lakota Sioux qui ont vécu 
dans la zone qui est devenue le Dakota du sud et le Nébraska a 
dépendu en grande partie de la chasse à buffle selon Paul Picotte, 
un Yankton Sioux soutenu en 1880. Dans cette transcription d'une
entrevue 1968 avec l'argent comptant de Joseph d'historien, Picotte a 
rappelé le processus raffiné employé pour chasser, habiller, et 
préserver le buffle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na era antes que o exército de E. U. conquistou 
os indians de planícies grandes os rebanhos gigantes do búfalo da 
região forneceram a fonte preliminar do alimento e da roupa para os 
indians que viveram lá. Certamente, em 19a América do século 
o búfalo era mais numeroso do que povos. Os vários tribes que 
viveram na área que se transformou Dakota sul e Nebraska dependeu 
pela maior parte da caça do búfalo de acordo com Paul Picotte, um 
Yankton Sioux de Lakota Sioux carregado em 1880. Neste 
transcript de uma entrevista 1968 com dinheiro de Joseph do historian,
Picotte recordou o processo elaborado usado caçar, vestir, e 
preservar o búfalo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'era prima che l'esercito di Stati Uniti 
conquistasse gli indiani di pianure grandi le greggi giganti del 
bufalo della regione hanno fornito la sorgente primaria dei vestiti e 
dell'alimento per gli indiani che hanno vissuto là. 
Effettivamente, in diciannovesima America di secolo il bufalo 
era più numeroso della gente. Le varie tribù che hanno vissuto
nella zona che si è transformata in nel Dakota del Sud ed il Nebraska
dipendeva in gran parte dal bufalo cerca secondo Paul 
Picotte, un Yankton Sioux di Lakota Sioux sopportato in 1880. In
questa trascrizione di un'intervista 1968 con i contanti del Joseph 
dello storico, Picotte ha ricordato il processo elaborato usato per 
cercare, vestire e conservare il bufalo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην εποχή προτού το Θ*u. να κατακτήσει το Θ*ς. 
στρατός τις μεγάλες πεδιάδες Ινδοί τα γιγαντιαία κοπάδια 
βούβαλων της περιοχής παρείχαν την αρχική πηγή τροφίμων και 
ιματισμού για τους Ινδούς που έζησαν εκεί. Πράγματι, στην 
Αμερική του 19$ου αιώνα οι βούβαλοι ήταν πιό πολυάριθμοι από 
τους ανθρώπους. Οι διάφορες σιού φυλές Lakota που έζησαν
στην περιοχή που έγινε νότια Ντακότα και η Νεμπράσκα εξαρτήθηκαν
κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος από το κυνήγι βούβαλων σύμφωνα με 
Paul Picotte, σιού ένας γεννημένος Yankton το 1880. 
Σε αυτό το αντίγραφο μιας συνέντευξης του 1968 με τον 
ιστορικό Joseph Cash, Picotte υπενθύμισε την επιμελημένη 
διαδικασία που χρησιμοποιήθηκε για να κυνηγήσει, να ντύσει, και 
συντηρεί τους βούβαλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la era antes de que el ejército americano 
Conquistara a indios de grandes llanos las manadas gigantes del 
búfalo de la región proporcionaron a la fuente primaria del alimento
y de la ropa para los indios que vivieron allí. De hecho, en 
diecinueveavo América del siglo el búfalo era más numeroso que la 
gente. Las varias tribus que vivieron en el área que se 
convirtió en Dakota del Sur y Nebraska dependió en gran parte de la 
caza del búfalo según Paul Picotte, un Yankton Sioux de Lakota Sioux
llevado en 1880. En esta transcripción de una entrevista 1968 
con el efectivo de José del historiador, Picotte recordó el proceso 
elaborado usado para buscar, para vestir, y para preservar el búfalo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087187</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107025</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-didnt-have-flies-until-the-white-man-came-a-yankton-sioux-remembers-life-on-the-plains-in-the-late-19th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
