<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105198</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105198</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086227</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hear TR's Speech "The Liberty of the People"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hören Sie Rede TRs "die Freiheit der Leute"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entendez la parole du TR "la liberté du peuple"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ouça o discurso do TR "a liberdade dos povos"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Senta il discorso del TR "la libertà della 
gente"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακούστε την ομιλία του TR "η ελευθερία των 
ανθρώπων"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Oiga el discurso del TR "la libertad de la gente"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The 1912 presidential election offered American voters a choice between a conservative and generally unpopular Republican incumbent (William Howard Taft), a moderate governor who won the heavily contested Democratic nomination (Woodrow Wilson), third party candidate former President Theodore Roosevelt, and a Socialist Party candidate running for the fourth time (Eugene V. Debs). Angered over what he felt was a betrayal of his policies by Taft, his hand-picked successor, Roosevelt and others abandoned the Republican party and founded the Progressive or "Bull Moose" Party. Voter interest, already piqued by the unusual campaign and the candidates' slashing attacks on one another, was further heightened by the availability of sound recordings of campaign addresses and, for the first time, film footage of the candidates on the campaign trail. In this recorded speech, entitled "The Liberty of the People," Roosevelt took the most openly pro-labor stance of the three major candidates. When the voters went to the polls in November, however, Wilson was the clear victor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Präsidentenwahl 1912 amerikanischen Wählern 
eine Wahl zwischen einem Konservativen und im Allgemeinen ein 
unpopulärer republikanischer Amtsinhaber (William Howard Taft), ein 
gemäßigter Gouverneur, die die schwer gewetteiferte demokratische 
Nennung (Woodrow Wilson) gewannen, dritter 
Parteianwärterehemaliger Präsident Theodore Roosevelt und ein 
sozialistischer Parteianwärter angeboten, der für das vierte mal
läuft (Eugene V. Debs). Verärgert über was er war ein Verrat 
seiner politischen Richtlinien durch Taft, sein handverlesener 
Nachfolger, Roosevelt glaubte und andere verließ die republikanische 
Partei und gründet dem Progressisten oder "die Bull Elch-" 
Partei. Wählerinteresse, piqued bereits durch die 
ungewöhnliche Kampagne und die schneidenden Angriffe auf einem andere
der Anwärter, wurden weiter durch die Verwendbarkeit der Tonaufnahmen
der Kampagne Adressen und zum ersten Mal der Filmgesamtlänge der 
Anwärter auf der Kampagne Spur erhöht. In dieser gespeicherten
Rede erlaubt "die Freiheit der Leute," nahm Roosevelt Pro-bearbeiten 
öffentlich Position der drei Hauptanwärter. Als die Wähler zu
den Abstimmungen im November jedoch gingen war Wilson der freie 
Victor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élection 1912 présidentielle offerte 
électeurs américains un choix entre un conservateur et un candidat 
sortant républicain généralement inpopulaire (William Howard 
Taft), un gouverneur modéré qui ont gagné la nomination 
démocratique fortement contestée (Woodrow Wilson), Président 
Theodore Roosevelt de candidat de tiers l'ancien, et un candidat de 
parti socialiste exécutant pour la quatrième fois (Eugene V. Debs). 
Irrité au-dessus de ce que s'est senti il était une trahison 
de ses politiques par Taft, son successeur trié à la main, Roosevelt
et d'autres a abandonné la partie républicaine et fonde la partie 
d'orignaux de progressif ou "de Bull". L'intérêt d'électeur, 
piqued déjà par la campagne peu commune et les attaques de 
réduction sur une des autres des candidats, ont été encore 
intensifiées par la disponibilité des enregistrements sonores des 
adresses de campagne et, pour la première fois, de la longueur de 
film des candidats sur la traînée de campagne. Dans ce 
discours enregistré, intitulé "la liberté du peuple," Roosevelt a 
pris pro-travaillent le plus ouvrir la position des trois candidats 
principaux. Quand les électeurs sont allés aux balayages en 
novembre, cependant, Wilson était le vainqueur clair.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A eleição 1912 presidencial oferecida eleitores 
americanos uma escolha entre um conservador e um encarregado 
republicano geralmente unpopular (William Howard Taft), um regulador 
moderado que ganhassem o nomination democrático pesadamente 
contestado (Woodrow Wilson), presidente anterior Theodore Roosevelt do
candidato do terceiro partido, e um candidato do partido socialist que
funciona para a quarta vez (Eugene V. Debs). Irritado sobre o 
que sentiu era um betrayal de suas políticas por Taft, seu sucessor 
hand-picked, Roosevelt e outro abandonou o partido republicano e funda
o partido dos alces do progressista ou da "Bull". O interesse do
eleitor, piqued já pela campanha incomun e os ataques slashing em um 
outros dos candidatos, heightened mais mais pela disponibilidade de 
gravações sadias de endereços da campanha e, para a primeira vez, 
de footage da película dos candidatos na fuga da campanha. 
Neste discurso gravado, intitulado "a liberdade dos povos," 
Roosevelt fêz exame do pro-trabalha o mais abertamente o stance dos 
três candidatos principais. Quando os eleitores foram às 
votações em novembro, entretanto, Wilson era o vencedor 
desobstruído.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'elezione presidenziale 1912 offerta ad elettori 
americani una scelta fra un conservatore e un incumbent Repubblicano 
generalmente impopolare (William Howard Taft), un regolatore moderato 
che hanno vinto la nomina democratica pesante contestata (Woodrow 
Wilson), presidente Theodore Roosevelt del candidato dei terzi ex e un
candidato del partito socialista che funziona per il tempo di 
quarto (Eugene V. Debs). Fatto arrabbiare sopra che cosa 
ha ritenuto era un betrayal delle sue politiche da Taft, il suo 
successore raccolto a mano, Roosevelt ed altri ha abbandonato il 
partito Repubblicano e fondati il partito delle alci del Bull "o del 
progressive". L'interesse dell'elettore, già piqued dalla 
campagna insolita e gli attacchi riducenti ad uno un altro dei 
candidati, più ulteriormente sono stati intensificati dalla 
disponibilità delle registrazioni del suono degli indirizzi di 
campagna e, per la prima volta, del metraggio della pellicola dei 
candidati alla traccia di campagna. In questo discorso 
registrato, intitolato "la libertà della gente," Roosevelt ha preso 
il più apertamente la posizione di pro-lavoro dei tre candidati 
principali. Quando gli elettori sono andato alle urne in 
novembre, tuttavia, Wilson era il victor libero.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προεδρική εκλογή του 1912 πρόσφερε στους 
αμερικανικούς ψηφοφόρους μια επιλογή μεταξύ ενός συντηρητικού 
και γενικά μη δημοφιλούς δημοκρατικού κατέχοντος υπεύθυνη θέση 
(William Howard Taft), ένας μέτριος κυβερνήτης που 
κέρδισε το βαριά αμφισβητημένο δημοκρατικό διορισμό (Woodrow 
Wilson), τον υποψήφιο προηγούμενος Πρόεδρος Theodore 
Roosevelt τρίτων, και έναν σοσιαλιστικό υποψήφιο συμβαλλόμενου
μέρους που τρέχει για την τέταρτη φορά (Eugene Θ*Β. Debs). 
Θυμώθηκε πέρα από αυτό που αισθάνθηκε μια προδοσία των 
πολιτικών του από Taft, ο μαζεμμένος με το χέρι διάδοχός του,
Roosevelt και άλλα εγκατέλειψαν το δημοκρατικό κόμμα και 
ίδρυσαν το προοδευτικό ή συμβαλλόμενο μέρος "αλκών του Bull".
Το ενδιαφέρον ψηφοφόρων, ήδη από την ασυνήθιστη εκστρατεία
και οι επιθέσεις κοψίματος των υποψηφίων στο ένα άλλη, υψώθηκαν 
περαιτέρω από τη διαθεσιμότητα των υγιών καταγραφών των 
διευθύνσεων εκστρατείας και, για πρώτη φορά, του μήκους σε πόδηα
ταινιών των υποψηφίων στο ίχνος εκστρατείας. Σε αυτήν την 
καταγραμμένη ομιλία, που τιτλοφορήθηκε "ελευθερία των ανθρώπων," 
Roosevelt πήρε την ο πιό ανοιχτά θέση υπέρ-εργασίας των 
τριών σημαντικών υποψηφίων. Όταν οι ψηφοφόροι πήγαν στις 
ψηφοφορίες το Νοέμβριο, εντούτοις, Wilson ήταν το σαφές 
victor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La elección presidencial 1912 ofrecida votantes 
americanos una opción entre un conservador y un titular republicano 
generalmente impopular (Guillermo Howard Taft), un gobernador moderado
que ganaron el nombramiento democrático pesadamente disputado 
(Woodrow Wilson), presidente anterior Theodore Roosevelt del candidato
de los terceros, y un candidato del partido socialista que se ejecuta 
para la cuarta vez (Eugene V. Debs). Encolerizado sobre lo que 
él se sentía era una traición de sus políticas de Taft, su sucesor
recogido a mano, Roosevelt y otros abandonó el partido republicano y 
fundados el partido de los alces del progresista o "de Bull". El
interés del votante, piqued ya por la campaña inusual y los ataques 
de reducción radical contra uno otros de los candidatos, fueron 
aumentados más a fondo por la disponibilidad de las grabaciones de 
sonidos de los direccionamientos de la campaña y, para la primera 
vez, de la cantidad de la película de los candidatos contra el rastro
de la campaña. En este discurso registrado, dado derecho "la 
libertad de la gente," Roosevelt tomó favorable-trabaja lo más 
abiertamente posible la postura de los tres candidatos principales. 
Cuando los votantes fueron a las encuestas en noviembre, sin 
embargo, Wilson era el vencedor claro.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086227</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105198</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hear-trs-speech-the-liberty-of-the-people</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
