<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106499</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106499</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087193</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Had to Be So Careful" A German Farmer's Recollections of Anti-German Sentiment in World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir mußten so achtgeben" die Erinnerungen eines 
Deutsch-Landwirts des Anti-Deutschen Gefühls im Ersten Weltkrieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous avons dû faire attention si" les souvenirs 
d'un fermier d'Allemand du sentiment Anti-Allemand dans la Première 
Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós tivemos que ter assim cuidados" 
recollections de um fazendeiro do alemão do sentiment Anti-Alemão no
world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"abbiamo dovuto fare attenzione così" ricordi del
coltivatore del tedesco del sentimento Anti-Tedesco nel world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έπρεπε να είμαστε τόσο προσεκτικέσ" αναμνήσεις ενός
γερμανικού αγρότη του αντι-γερμανικού συναισθήματος στον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tuvimos que tener tan cuidados" los recuerdos de 
un granjero del alemán del sentimiento Contra-Alema'n en Primera 
Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">German Americans had a complex response to the attacks on their loyalty that emerged when the United States went to war against Germany in 1917. During and after the war, many German Americans began to conceal their ethnic identity--some changed their names; others stopped speaking German; still others quit German-American organizations. Many, like Frank Brocke, son of a German-American farmer, tried to keep a low profile. In this interview, Frank Brocke discussed his own assimilation (he later became the president of the local bank) which led him to justify the internment of Japanese Americans during World War II--a stance that many Japanese Americans and others would disclaim.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Deutsche Amerikaner hatten eine komplizierte 
Antwort zu den Angriffen auf ihrer Loyalität, daß aufgetaucht, als 
die vereinigten Zustände war gegen Deutschland 1917 gingen. 
Während und nach des Krieges fingen viele deutsche Amerikaner 
an, ihre ethnische Identität zu verbergen -- einige änderten ihre 
Namen; andere stoppten, Deutsches zu sprechen; noch 
beendeten andere Deutsch-Amerikanische Organisationen. Viele, 
wie aufrichtiges Brocke, Sohn eines Deutsch-Amerikanischen Landwirts, 
versucht, um ein niedriges Profil zu halten. In diesem Interview
behandelte aufrichtiges Brocke seine eigene Assimilation (ihn wurde 
später der Präsident der örtlichen Bank), die ihn führte, die 
Internierung der japanischen Amerikaner während des Zweiten 
Weltkrieges -- eine Position auszuschließen, die viele japanische 
Amerikaner und andere dementieren würden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Américains allemands ont eu une réponse 
complexe aux attaques sur leur fidélité qui a émergé quand les 
Etats-Unis sont allés faire la guerre contre l'Allemagne en 1917. 
Pendant et après la guerre, beaucoup d'Américains allemands 
ont commencé à cacher leur identité ethnique -- certains ont 
changé leurs noms ; d'autres ont cessé de parler allemand ; 
encore d'autres ont quitté des organismes Allemand-Américains.
Beaucoup, comme Brocke franc, fils d'un fermier 
Allemand-Américain, jugé pour garder un profil bas. Dans cette
entrevue, Brocke franc a discuté sa propre assimilation (il plus tard
est devenu le président de la banque locale) qui l'a mené à 
justifier l'internement des Américains japonais pendant la deuxième 
guerre mondiale -- une position que beaucoup d'Américains japonais et
d'autres démentiraient.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os americanos alemães tiveram uma resposta 
complexa aos ataques em sua lealdade que emerso quando os estados 
unidos foram guerrear de encontro a Germany em 1917. Durante e 
após a guerra, muitos americanos alemães começaram a esconder sua 
identidade étnica -- alguns mudaram seus nomes; outros pararam 
de falar o alemão; ainda outros pararam organizações 
Alemão-Americanas. Muitos, como Brocke frank, filho de um 
fazendeiro Alemão-Americano, tentado manter um perfil baixo. 
Nesta entrevista, Brocke frank discutiu seu próprio 
assimilation (se transformou mais tarde o presidente do banco local) 
que lhe conduziu justificar o internamento de americanos japoneses 
durante a segunda guerra mundial -- um stance que muitos americanos 
japoneses e outros desmentissem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli Americani tedeschi hanno avuti una risposta 
complessa agli attacchi alla loro lealtà che è emerso quando unito 
Dichiara è andato fare la guerra contro la Germania in 1917. 
Durante e dopo la guerra, molti Americani tedeschi hanno 
cominciato a celare la loro identità etnica -- alcuni hanno cambiato 
i loro nomi; altri hanno smesso di parlare tedesco; ancora
altri hanno rinunciato le organizzazioni Tedesco-Americane. 
Molti, come Brocke franco, figlio di un coltivatore 
Tedesco-Americano, provato per mantenere un profilo basso. In 
questa intervista, Brocke franco ha discusso la sua propria 
assimilazione (più successivamente è diventato il presidente della 
banca locale) che lo ha condotto giustificare l'internamento 
degli Americani giapponesi durante la seconda guerra mondiale -- una 
posizione che molti Americani giapponesi ed altri smentirebbero.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γερμανικοί Αμερικανοί είχαν μια σύνθετη απάντηση στις
επιθέσεις στην πίστη τους που προέκυψε πότε οι Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες πήγαν στον πόλεμο ενάντια Γερμανία σε 1917, 
Κατά τη διάρκεια και μετά από του πολέμου, πολλοί 
γερμανικοί Αμερικανοί άρχισαν να κρύβουν την εθνική ταυτότητά 
τους -- μερικοί άλλαξαν τα ονόματά τους  άλλοι σταμάτησαν 
τα γερμανικά  ακόμα άλλοι εγκαταλειμμένες 
γερμανικός-αμερικανικές οργανώσεις. Πολλοί, όπως το 
Frank Brocke, γιος ενός γερμανικός-αμερικανικού αγρότη, 
προσπάθησαν να κρατήσουν μια μικρή ακτινοβολία. Σε αυτήν 
την συνέντευξη, ο Frank Brocke συζήτησε την αφομοίωσή του 
(έγινε αργότερα ο Πρόεδρος της τοπικής τράπεζας) που τον οδήγησε
για να δικαιολογήσει τον περιορισμό ιαπωνικών Αμερικανών κατά τη 
διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ -- μια θέση που πολλοί 
ιαπωνικοί Αμερικανοί και άλλοι θα αποκήρυσσαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los americanos alemanes tenían una respuesta 
compleja a los ataques contra su lealtad que emergió cuando los 
Estados Unidos fueron a guerrear contra Alemania en 1917. 
Durante y después de la guerra, muchos americanos alemanes 
comenzaron a encubrir su identidad étnica -- algunos cambiaron sus 
nombres; otros pararon el hablar de alemán; todavía 
otros salieron organizaciones Alema'n-Americanas. Muchos, como 
Brocke franco, hijo de un granjero Alema'n-Americano, intentado para 
guardar un perfil bajo. En esta entrevista, Brocke franco 
discutió su propia asimilación (él hizo más adelante el presidente
de la batería local) que lo condujo a alinear la internación de 
americanos japoneses durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial -- una postura 
que muchos americanos japoneses y otros negarían.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087193</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106499</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-had-to-be-so-careful-a-german-farmers-recollections-of-anti-german-sentiment-in-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
