<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103219</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103219</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087360</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"After the Ball": Lyrics from the Biggest Hit of the 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"nach der Kugel": Lyriken vom 
größten Hit des 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"après la boule" : Lyrique du succès du 
1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"após a esfera": Lyrics da batida a mais 
grande do 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"dopo la sfera": Lyrics dal colpo più 
grande del 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μετά από τη σφαίρα": Λυρικά ποιήματα από το 
μεγαλύτερο χτύπημα του 1890s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"después de la bola": Líricas del golpe 
más grande del 1890s</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The 1890s witnessed the emergence of a commercial popular music industry in the United States. Sales of sheet music, enabling consumers to play and sing songs in their own parlors, skyrocketed during the "Gay Nineties," led by Tin Pan Alley, the narrow street in midtown Manhattan that housed the country's major music publishers and producers. Although Tin Pan Alley was established in the 1880s, it only achieved national prominence with the first "platinum" song hit in American music history--Charles K. Harris's "After the Ball"--that sold two million pieces of sheet music in 1892 alone. "After the Ball's" sentimentality ultimately helped sell over five million copies of sheet music, making it the biggest hit in Tin Pan Alley's long history. Typical of most popular 1890s tunes, the song was a tearjerker, a melodramatic evocation of lost love.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das 1890s zeugte das Hervortreten einer 
kommerziellen populären Musikindustrie in den Vereinigten Staaten. 
Verkäufe von Blattmusik, Verbraucher aktivierend, Liede in 
ihren eigenen Wohnzimmern zu spielen und zu singen, schnellten 
während der "homosexuellen neunziger Jahre empor," geführt durch Tin
Pan Alley, die schmale Straße im Midtown Manhattan, das die 
Hauptmusikverleger und -produzenten des Landes unterbrachte. 
Obgleich Tin Pan Alleyim 1880s hergestellt wurde, erzielte es 
nur nationalen Vorsprung mit dem ersten "Platin" Lied, das in der 
amerikanischen Musikgeschichte geschlagen wurde -- Charles K. Harriss 
"nach der Kugel" -- die zwei Million Stücke Blattmusik in 1892 allein
verkaufte. "nachdem die Sentimentalität der Kugel" schließlich
Verkauf über fünf Million Exemplaren von Blattmusik half und bildete
es den größten Hit in der langen Geschichte Tin- Pan Alley. 
Typisch vom meisten populären 1890s justiert, das Lied war ein 
tearjerker, eine melodramatische Hervorrufung der verlorenen Liebe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le 1890s était témoin de l'apparition d'une 
industrie populaire commerciale de musique aux Etats-Unis. Les 
ventes de la musique de feuille, permettant à des consommateurs de 
jouer et chanter des chansons dans leurs propres salons, ont monté en
flèche pendant "les années '90 gaies," mené par la ruelle de 
casserole de bidon, la rue étroite dans le Midtown Manhattan qui a 
logé les éditeurs et les producteurs principaux de la musique du 
pays. Bien que la ruelle de casserole de bidon ait été 
établie dans le 1880s, elle a seulement réalisé la proéminence 
nationale avec la première chanson de "platine" frappée dans 
l'histoire américaine de musique -- Charles K. Harris's "après la 
boule" -- qui a vendu deux millions de morceaux de musique de feuille 
dans 1892 seuls. "après que la sentimentalité de la boule" a 
finalement aidé la vente plus de cinq millions de copies de la 
musique de feuille, lui faisant le succès dans histoire de ruelle de 
casserole de bidon la longue. Typique de la plupart des 1890s 
populaire accorde, la chanson était un tearjerker, une évocation 
mélodramatique de l'amour perdu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O 1890s testemunhou o emergence de uma indústria 
popular comercial da música nos estados unidos. As vendas da 
música da folha, permitindo consumidores de jogar e cantar canções 
em suas próprias salas de estar, skyrocketed durante "os nineties 
gay," conduzido pela aléia de bandeja de lata, a rua estreita no 
Midtown Manhattan que abrigou os publishers e os produtores principais
da música do país. Embora a aléia de bandeja de lata fosse 
estabelecida no 1880s, conseguiu somente o prominence nacional com a 
primeira canção da "platina" batida no history americano da música 
-- Charles K. Harris "após a esfera" -- que vendeu dois milhão 
partes de música da folha em 1892 sozinhos. "depois que o 
sentimentality da esfera" ajudou finalmente ao sell sobre cinco 
milhão cópias da música da folha, fazendo lhe a batida a mais 
grande no history longo de aléia de bandeja de lata. Típico de
a maioria de 1890s popular ajusta, a canção era um tearjerker, um 
evocation melodramatic de amor perdido.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 1890s ha testimoniato l'emersione di 
un'industria popolare commerciale di musica in unito Dichiara. 
Le vendite di musica del foglio, permettendo ai consumatori di 
giocare e cantare le canzoni nei loro propri saloni, skyrocketed 
durante "gli anni '90 di Gay," condotto dal vicolo di 
vaschetta di latta, la via stretta nel Midtown Manhattan che ha 
alloggiato gli editori ed i produttori principali di musica del paese.
Anche se il vicolo di vaschetta di latta è stato stabilito nel 
1880s, ha realizzato soltanto la protuberanza nazionale con la prima 
canzone "del platino" colpita nella storia americana di musica -- 
Charles K. Harris "dopo la sfera" -- che ha venduto due milione parti 
di musica del foglio in 1892 soli. "dopo che il sentimentality 
della sfera" infine aiuti la vendita oltre cinque milione copie di 
musica del foglio, rendentegi il colpo più grande nella storia lunga 
del vicolo di vaschetta di latta. Tipico della maggior parte del
1890s popolare sintonizza, la canzone era un tearjerker, un evocation 
melodramatic di amore perso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1890s βεβαίωσε την εμφάνιση εμπορική δημοφιλής 
βιομηχανία μουσικής στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Οι πωλήσεις 
της μουσικής φύλλων, που επιτρέπει στους καταναλωτές για να 
παίξουν και να τραγουδήσουν τα τραγούδια στις αίθουσές τους, 
ανέβασαν στα ύψη κατά τη διάρκεια της "ομοφυλοφιλικής δεκαετίας 
του '90," οδηγημένος από την παν αλέα κασσίτερου, η στενή οδός 
στο της περιφέρειας του κέντρου Μανχάτταν που στέγασε τους 
κυριότερους εκδότες και τους παραγωγούς μουσικής της χώρας. 
Αν και η παν αλέα κασσίτερου καθιερώθηκε στο 1880s, 
επέτυχε μόνο την εθνική προεξοχή με το πρώτο τραγούδι 
"λευκόχρυσου" που χτυπήθηκε στην αμερικανική ιστορία μουσικής -- 
Charles K. Harris's "μετά από τη σφαίρα" -- που πώλησε 
δύο εκατομμύριο κομμάτια της μουσικής φύλλων το 1892 μόνης. 
"Μετά από το sentimentality της σφαίρασ" που ενισχύεται 
τελικά να πωλήσει πάνω από πέντε εκατομμύριο αντίγραφα της 
μουσικής φύλλων, που κάνουν τον το μεγαλύτερο χτύπημα στη 
μακροχρόνια ιστορία της παν αλέας κασσίτερου. 
Χαρακτηριστικός του περισσότερου δημοφιλούς 1890s 
συντονίζει, το τραγούδι ήταν ένα tearjerker, μια μελοδραματική
επίκληση της χαμένης αγάπης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El 1890s atestiguó la aparición de una industria
popular comercial de la música en los Estados Unidos. Las 
ventas de la música de la hoja, permitiendo a consumidores jugar y 
cantar canciones en sus propias salas, se elevaron súbitamente 
durante los "an'os noventa Gays," conducido por el callejón 
de cacerola de lata, la calle estrecha en el Midtown Manhattan que 
contuvo a los editores y a productores principales de la música del 
país. Aunque el callejón de cacerola de lata fue establecido 
en el 1880s, alcanzó solamente la prominencia nacional con la primera
canción del "platino" golpeada en historia americana de la música --
Charles K. Harris "después de la bola" -- que vendió dos millones de
pedazos de música de la hoja en 1892 solos. "después de que el
sentimentalismo de la bola" ayudó en última instancia a venta sobre 
cinco millones de copias de la música de la hoja, haciéndole el 
golpe más grande de la historia larga del callejón de cacerola de 
lata. Típico de la mayoría del 1890s popular templa, la 
canción era un tearjerker, un evocation melodramatic del amor 
perdido.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087360</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103219</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/after-the-ball-lyrics-from-the-biggest-hit-of-the-1890s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
