<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107269</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107269</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086337</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Introducing New Recruits to "Labor's Catechism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neue Rekruten vorstellen, "Katechismus zu 
bearbeiten"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Présentant de nouvelles recrues "pour travailler 
le catéchisme"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Introduzindo recrutas novos "para trabalhar o 
catechism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Introducendo le nuove reclute "catechism 
Di lavoro"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εισάγοντας τους νέους νεοσυλλέκτους στη "κατήχηση της 
εργασίασ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Introduciendo a nuevos reclutas "para trabajar el 
catechism"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Religious concepts and metaphors suffused the words and ideas of many late nineteenth-century American workers. The New and Old Testaments provided not only personal succor to many working people but also a set of allusions and parables they applied directly to their lives and struggles in industrial America. Working-class ideas and writing often were cast in stark millenarian terms, with prophesies of imminent doom predicted for capitalists who worshipped at Mammon's temple and imminent redemption for hard-working, long-suffering, and God-fearing laboring men and women. Christ was uniformly depicted in workers' writing as a poor workingman put on Earth to teach the simple principles of brotherhood and unionism. The power loom weavers of Rhode Island were the intended audience of this "catechism" written by labor activists "Bobba Chuttle" and "Betty Reedhook" (pseudonymns evocative of the tools of the textile worker's trade) in 1887. Drawing on church traditions, the pair patterned their educational effort, published in  The People , along the lines of a call-and-response format.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fromme Konzepte und Metaphern suffused die Wörter
und die Ideen vieler später 19.-Jahrhundert Amerikanerarbeiter. 
Die neuen und alten Testaments stellten nicht nur persönliches 
succor zu vielen Arbeitsleute aber auch ein Set Anspielungen und 
Parabeln zur Verfügung, die sie direkt an ihren Lebensdauern und an 
Kämpfen in industriellem Amerika auftrugen. Arbeiterklasseideen
und -schreiben häufig wurden in den steifen millenarian Bezeichnungen
geworfen, mit prophezeit vom unmittelbar drohenden Schicksal, das für
Kapitalisten vorausgesagt wird, die am Bügel und unmittelbar drohende
Abzahlung Mammons für fleißiges anbeteten und lang-leidet und 
God-fearing bearbeitenmänner und Frauen. Christ wurde 
gleichmäßig im Schreiben der Arbeiter als schlechter Workingman 
bildlich dargestellt, der auf Masse gesetzt wurde, um die einfachen 
Grundregeln der Bruderschaft und des unionism zu unterrichten. 
Die Energie Webstuhlweber von Rhode-Insel waren die 
beabsichtigten Publikum dieses "Katechismus", der von den 
Arbeitsaktivisten "Bobba Chuttle" und "Betty Reedhook" geschrieben 
wurde (die pseudonymns evocative von den Hilfsmitteln des Handels des 
Textilarbeiters) 1887. Zeichnend auf Kirchetraditionen, 
patterned das Paar ihre pädagogische Bemühung, veröffentlicht in 
den Leuten, die nach einem Benennen-undantwort Format.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les concepts et les métaphores religieux ont 
répandu les mots et les idées de beaucoup de défunts ouvriers 
d'Américain de dix-neuvième-siècle. Les nouveaux et vieux 
testaments ont fourni non seulement le succor personnel à beaucoup 
des personnes travaillantes mais également un ensemble d'allusions et
de paraboles qu'ils ont appliquées directement aux leurs vies et 
luttes en Amérique industrielle. Des idées et l'écriture de 
classe ouvrière souvent ont été moulées en termes millenarian 
rigides, avec prédit du sort malheureux imminent prévu pour les 
capitalistes qui ont adoré au temple et le rachat imminent de Mammon 
pour assidu, long-souffrant, et les hommes et les femmes travaillants 
très croyants. Le Christ a été uniformément dépeint dans 
l'écriture des ouvriers comme ouvrier pauvre mis sur terre pour 
enseigner les principes simples de la confrérie et du syndicalisme. 
Les tisserands de manche de puissance d'île de Rhode étaient les
assistances destinées de ce "catéchisme" écrit par les activistes 
de travail "Bobba Chuttle" et "Betty Reedhook" (des pseudonymns 
évocateurs des outils du commerce de l'ouvrier de textile) en 1887. 
Dessinant sur des traditions d'église, la paire a modelé leur 
effort éducatif, édité dans les personnes, le long des lignes d'un 
format d'appeler-et-réponse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os conceitos e os metaphors religiosos suffused as
palavras e as idéias de muitos trabalhadores atrasados do americano 
de décimo-século. Os testaments novos e velhos forneceram não
somente o succor pessoal a muitos povos trabalhando mas também um 
jogo dos allusions e dos parables que se aplicaram diretamente a seus 
vidas e esforços em América industrial. As idéias e a escrita
do working-class foram moldadas frequentemente em termos millenarian 
stark, com prophesies do doom imminent predito para os capitalistas 
que adoraram no temple e redemption imminent de Mammon para 
hard-working, longo-sofrendo, e homens e mulheres trabalhando 
god-fearing. Christ foi descrito uniformemente na escrita dos 
trabalhadores como um workingman deficiente posto sobre a terra para 
ensinar os princípios simples do brotherhood e do unionism. Os 
weavers do tear da potência do console de Rhode eram as audiências 
pretendidas deste "catechism" escrito por activistas labor "Bobba 
Chuttle" e "Betty Reedhook" (os pseudonymns evocative das ferramentas 
do comércio do trabalhador de textile) em 1887. Desenhando em 
tradições da igreja, o par modelou seu esforço educacional, 
publicado nos povos, ao longo das linhas de um formato da 
cham-e-resposta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I concetti e le metafore religiosi suffused le 
parole e le idee di molti operai ritardati dell'americano di 
diciannovesimo-secolo. I nuovi e vecchi Testamenti hanno 
fornito non soltanto il succor personale a molti gente lavorante ma 
anche un insieme delle allusioni e dei parables che si sono 
applicati direttamente alle loro vite e lotte in America industriale. 
Le idee e la scrittura della classe operaia sono state lanciate 
spesso nei termini millenarian rigidi, con prophesies della sorte 
avversa imminente prevista per i capitalisti che hanno adorato al 
tempiale ed estinzione imminente del Mammon per hard-working, 
lungo-soffrendo ed uomini e donne lavoranti god-fearing. Christ 
è stato descritto uniformemente nella scrittura degli operai come 
povero workingman messo su terra per insegnare i principii 
semplici di fratellanza e del unionism. I tessitori del telaio 
di potenza dell'Rhode-isola erano i pubblici progettati di questo 
"catechism" scritto dagli attivisti di lavoro "Bobba Chuttle" e 
"Betty Reedhook" (pseudonymns evocative degli strumenti del commercio 
dell'operaio della tessile) in 1887. Dissipando sulle tradizioni
della chiesa, l'accoppiamento ha modellato il loro sforzo educativo, 
pubblicato nella gente, seguendo le righe di un formato di 
chiam-e-risposta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι θρησκευτικές έννοιες και οι μεταφορές εδιάχυσαν τις
λέξεις και τις ιδέες πολλών πρώην αμερικανικών εργαζομένων 
δέκατος-αιώνα. Οι νέες και παλαιές διαθήκες παρείχαν όχι 
μόνο την προσωπική συμπαράσταση σε πολλούς εργαζόμενους 
ανθρώπους αλλά και ένα σύνολο νύξεων και παραβολών που ίσχυσαν 
άμεσα για τις ζωές και τις προσπάθειές τους στη βιομηχανική 
Αμερική. Οι ιδέες εργατικής τάξης και το γράψιμο συχνά 
πετάχτηκαν στους άκαμπτους χιλιαστείς όρους, με τα prophesies 
της επικείμενης μοίρας που προβλέφθηκαν για τους κεφαλαιοκράτες 
που λάτρεψαν την επικείμενη εξαγορά Mammon στο ναό και για 
εργατικό, το μακρύς-βάσανο, και θεοσεβείς τις εργαμένος άνδρες 
και γυναίκες. Χριστός απεικονίστηκε ομοιόμορφα στο γράψιμο 
των εργαζομένων ως φτωχός workingman που τέθηκε στη γη για να 
διδάξει τις απλές αρχές της αδελφοσύνης και του συνδικαλισμού. 
Οι υφαντές αργαλειών δύναμης της Ρόδου ήταν το 
προοριζόμενο ακροατήριο αυτής της "κατήχησησ" που γράφτηκε από 
τα ενεργά στελέχη "Bobba Chuttle" εργασίας και "η Betty 
Reedhook" (pseudonymns προκαλών των εργαλείων του εμπορίου 
του υφαντικού εργαζομένου) σε 1887, που επισύρουν την προσοχή 
στις παραδόσεις εκκλησιών, το ζευγάρι διαμόρφωσε την εκπαιδευτική
προσπάθειά τους, που δημοσιεύθηκε στους ανθρώπους, σύμφωνα με τις
γραμμές μιας μορφής κλήση-και-απάντησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los conceptos y las metáforas religiosos 
cubrieron las palabras y las ideas de muchos últimos trabajadores del
americano del diecinueveavo-siglo. Los nuevos y viejos 
testamentos proporcionaron no solamente a succor personal a muchos 
gente de trabajo pero también un conjunto de alusiones y de 
parábolas que se aplicaron directamente a sus vidas y luchas en 
América industrial. Las ideas y la escritura de la clase obrera
fueron echadas a menudo en términos millenarian rígidos, con 
prophesies de la condenación inminente predicha para los capitalistas
que se adoraban en el templo y el rescate inminente de Mammon para 
trabajador, largo-sufriendo, y los hombres y las mujeres que trabajan 
temerosos de Dios. Representaron a Cristo uniformemente en la 
escritura de los trabajadores como workingman pobre puesto en la 
tierra para enseñar los principios simples de la fraternidad y del 
unionism. Los tejedores del telar de la potencia de la 
Rhode-isla eran las audiencias previstas de este "catechism" escrito 
por los activistas de trabajo "Bobba Chuttle" y "Betty Reedhook" (los 
pseudonymns evocadores de las herramientas del comercio del trabajador
del textil) en 1887. Trazando en tradiciones de la iglesia, el 
par modeló su esfuerzo educativo, publicado en la gente, a lo largo 
de las líneas de un formato de la llamar-y-respuesta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086337</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107269</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/introducing-new-recruits-to-labors-catechism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
