<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/171002628</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>171002628</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212351</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Study of Place: Antarctic Exploration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Studie des Platzes: Antarktische 
Erforschung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude d'endroit : Exploration Antarctique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estudo do lugar: Exploração Antarctic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studio sul posto: Esplorazione Antartica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μελέτη της θέσης: Ανταρκτική εξερεύνηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estudio del lugar: Exploración Antártica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Each two-week module in the Study of Place curriculum is framed by an historical event that makes a connection between the physical environment and human activity. The activities focus primarily on physical and earth science content, geography, and inquiry skills. Assessments and scoring rubrics, including a pre-assessment that can be used for both modules, are embedded in each module, providing opportunities for tracking student learning. The Antarctic Exploration module is framed by Sir Ernest Shackelton's expedition to Antarctica. It explores the relationship between the expanse of sea ice and seasonal change. Students: * examine satellite images of Antarctica, comparing and contrasting the information provided by the various types of technology; * explore seasonal changes in the expanse of sea ice and learn about the Sun's seasonal effect on the concentration of energy on Earth's surface; * explore the differences between fresh and salt water and salinity levels in the Antarctic Ocean; * study the effect of albedo and insulation on sea ice and heat transfer and apply these concepts to a discussion of global climate change.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jedes zweiwöchige Modul in der Studie des 
Platzlehrplans wird durch einen historischen Fall gestaltet, der eine 
Beziehung zwischen der körperlichen Umgebung und der menschlichen 
Aktivität herstellt. Die Aktivitäten konzentrieren 
hauptsächlich auf Systemtest und Geowissenschaftinhalt, Geographie 
und Anfragefähigkeiten. Einschätzungen und zählende Rubriken,
einschließlich eine Voreinschätzung, die für beide Module verwendet
werden kann, werden in jedem Modul eingebettet und stellen 
Gelegenheiten für das aufspürenkursteilnehmerlernen bereit. 
Das antarktische Erforschungmodul wird von der Expedition des 
Sirs Ernest Shackeltons nach Antarktik gestaltet. Es erforscht 
das Verhältnis zwischen der Ausdehnung des Seeeises und 
Saisonänderung. Kursteilnehmer: * überprüfen Sie die 
Satellitenbilder von Antarktik und die Informationen vergleichen und 
kontrastieren, die nach den verschiedenen Typen der Technologie 
bereitgestellt werden; * erforschen Sie Saisonänderungen in der
Ausdehnung des Seeeises und erlernen Sie über den Saisoneffekt des 
Sonnen auf die Konzentration von Energie auf Oberfläche der Masse; 
* erforschen Sie die Unterschiede zwischen frischem und 
Salzwasser und Salzigkeitstufen im Südpolarmeer; * studieren 
Sie den Effekt von Albedo und von Isolierung auf Seeeis- und - 
wärmeübertragung und wenden Sie diese Konzepte an einer Diskussion 
über globale Klimaänderung an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chaque module de deux semaines dans l'étude du 
programme d'études d'endroit est encadré par un événement 
historique qui établit un rapport entre l'environnement physique et 
l'activité humaine. Les activités se concentrent 
principalement sur l'examen médical et le contenu de science de la 
terre, la géographie, et les qualifications d'enquête. Des 
évaluations et les rubriques de marquage, y compris une 
pré-évaluation qui peut être utilisée pour les deux modules, sont 
encastrées dans chaque module, présentant des moyens de l'étude de 
cheminement d'étudiant. Le module antarctique d'exploration est
encadré par expédition de monsieur Ernest Shackelton's vers 
l'Antarctique. Il explore le rapport entre l'étendue de la 
glace de mer et le changement saisonnier. Étudiants : * 
examinez les images satellites de l'Antarctique, comparant et 
contrastant l'information fournie par les divers types de technologie 
; * explorez les changements saisonniers de l'étendue de la 
glace de mer et renseignez-vous sur l'effet saisonnier du soleil sur 
la concentration de l'énergie sur la surface de la terre ; * 
explorez les différences entre l'eau salée fraîche et et les 
niveaux de salinité dans l'océan antarctique ; * étudiez 
l'effet de l'albedo et de l'isolation sur le transfert de glace de mer
et thermique et appliquez-vous ces concepts à une discussion de 
changement global de climat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cada módulo two-week no estudo do curriculum do 
lugar é moldado por um evento histórico que faça uma conexão entre
o ambiente físico e a atividade humana. As atividades focalizam
primeiramente no exame e o índice da ciência de terra, a geografia, 
e as habilidades do inquérito. As avaliações e os rubrics 
marcando, including uma pre-avaliação que possa ser usada para ambos
os módulos, são encaixados em cada módulo, fornecendo oportunidades
para a aprendizagem seguindo do estudante. O módulo antarctic 
da exploração é moldado pela expedição do senhor Ernest 
Shackelton ao antarctica. Explora o relacionamento entre a 
extensão do gelo do mar e a mudança seasonal. Estudantes: 
* examine as imagens satellite do antarctica, comparando e 
contrastando a informação fornecida pelos vários tipos de 
tecnologia; * explore mudanças seasonal na extensão do gelo do
mar e aprenda-as sobre o efeito seasonal do sun na concentração da 
energia na superfície da terra; * explore as diferenças entre 
a água fresca e de sal e os níveis do salinity no oceano antarctic; 
* estude o efeito do albedo e da isolação no gelo do mar e na 
transferência de calor e aplique estes conceitos a uma discussão da 
mudança global do clima.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ogni modulo di due settimane nello studio sul 
programma di studi del posto è incorniciato da un evento storico che 
fa un collegamento fra l'ambiente fisico e l'attività umana. Le
attività mettono a fuoco soprattutto sul fisico medica e soddisfare 
di scienze della terra, geografia ed abilità di inchiesta. Le 
valutazioni e le rubriche notanti, compreso una pre-valutazione che 
può essere usata per entrambi i moduli, sono incastonate in ogni 
modulo, offrente le occasioni dell'imparare d'inseguimento 
dell'allievo. Il modulo antartico di esplorazione è 
incorniciato dalla spedizione del sir Ernest Shackelton in Antartide. 
Esplora il rapporto fra la distesa del ghiaccio del mare ed il 
cambiamento stagionale. Allievi: * esamini le immagini 
satelliti dell'Antartide, confrontanti e contrapponenti le 
informazioni fornite dai vari tipi di tecnologie; * esplori i 
cambiamenti stagionali nella distesa del ghiaccio del mare ed impari 
circa l'effetto stagionale del sun sulla concentrazione di energia 
sulla superficie della terra; * esplori le differenze fra 
l'acqua salata e fresca ed i livelli di salinità nell'oceano 
antartico; * studi l'effetto di albedo e di isolamento sullo 
scambio di calore del ghiaccio e del mare ed applichi questi concetti 
ad una discussione sul cambiamento globale di clima.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάθε δεκαπενθήμερη ενότητα στη μελέτη του 
προγράμματος σπουδών θέσεων πλαισιώνεται από ένα ιστορικό 
γεγονός που κάνει μια σύνδεση μεταξύ του σωματικού περιβάλλοντος
και της ανθρώπινης δραστηριότητας. Οι δραστηριότητες 
εστιάζουν πρώτιστα στο περιεχόμενο φυσικής και γήινης επιστήμης,
τη γεωγραφία, και τις δεξιότητες έρευνας. Οι αξιολογήσεις 
και οι σημειώνοντας ρουμπρίκες, συμπεριλαμβανομένης μιας 
προ-αξιολόγησης που μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί και για τις δύο 
ενότητες, ενσωματώνονται σε κάθε ενότητα, που παρέχει τις 
ευκαιρίες για την εκμάθηση σπουδαστών. Η ανταρκτική ενότητα
εξερεύνησης πλαισιώνεται από το Sir αποστολή Ernest 
Shackelton's στην Ανταρκτική. Ερευνά τη σχέση μεταξύ της 
έκτασης του πάγου θάλασσας και της εποχιακής αλλαγής. 
Σπουδαστές: * εξετάστε τις δορυφορικές εικόνες της 
Ανταρκτικής, που συγκρίνουν και που αντιπαραβάλλουν τις 
πληροφορίες που παρέχονται από τους διάφορους τύπους τεχνολογιών
* ερευνήστε τις εποχιακές αλλαγές στην έκταση του πάγου 
θάλασσας και μάθετε για την εποχιακή επίδραση του ήλιου στη 
συγκέντρωση της ενέργειας στη γήινη επιφάνεια  * ερευνήστε 
τις διαφορές μεταξύ του φρέσκου και επιπέδου αλμυρού ύδατος και 
αλατότητας στον ανταρκτικό ωκεανό  * μελετήστε την επίδραση
albedo και της μόνωσης στον πάγο θάλασσας και τη μεταφορά 
θερμότητας και εφαρμόστε αυτές τις έννοιες σε μια συζήτηση της 
σφαιρικής αλλαγής κλίματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cada módulo de dos semanas en el estudio del plan
de estudios del lugar es enmarcado por un acontecimiento histórico 
que haga una conexión entre el ambiente físico y la actividad 
humana. Las actividades se centran sobre todo en la 
comprobación y contenido de la geología, geografía, y las 
habilidades de la pregunta. Los gravámenes y las rúbricas que 
anotan, incluyendo un pre-gravamen que se pueda utilizar para ambos 
módulos, se embuten en cada módulo, proporcionando a las 
oportunidades para aprender del estudiante que sigue. El módulo
antártico de la exploración es enmarcado por la expedición de sir 
Ernest Shackelton al antártida. Explora el lazo entre la 
extensión del hielo del mar y el cambio estacional. 
Estudiantes: * examine las imágenes basadas en los 
satélites del antártida, comparando y poniendo en contraste la 
información proporcionada por los varios tipos de tecnología; 
* explore los cambios estacionales en la extensión del hielo 
del mar y aprenda sobre el efecto estacional del sun sobre la 
concentración de la energía en la superficie de la tierra; * 
explore las diferencias entre el agua salada fresca y y los niveles de
la salinidad en el océano antártico; * estudie el efecto del 
albedo y del aislante en traspaso térmico del hielo y del mar y 
aplique estos conceptos a una discusión del cambio global del clima.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212351</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Copyright</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>171002628</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/study-of-place-antarctic-exploration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
