<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104365</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104365</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086738</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Please, Let Me Put Him in a Macaroni Box" The Spanish Influenza of 1918 in Philadelphia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"bitte, lassen Sie mich ihn in einen 
Makkaroni-Kasten einsetzen" die spanische Grippe von 1918 in 
Philadelphia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"svp, laissez-moi le mettre dans une boîte à 
macaronis" la grippe espagnole de 1918 à Philadelphie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"por favor, deixe-me pô-lo em uma caixa do 
macarrão" o influenza espanhol de 1918 em Filadélfia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"per favore, lascilo metterlo in un contenitore di
maccheroni" la riossidazione spagnola di 1918 a Filadelfia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Παρακαλώ, με επιτρέψτε να τον βάλω σε ένα macaroni
κιβώτιο" η ισπανική γρίπη του 1918 στη Φιλαδέλφεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"por favor, déjeme ponerlo en un rectángulo de 
los macarrones" la gripe española de 1918 en Philadelphia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1918 and 1919 the Spanish influenza killed more humans than any other disease in a similar period in the history of the world. In the United States a quarter of the population (25 million people or more) contracted the flu; 550,000 died. In the early 1980s, when historian Charles Hardy did interviews for the Philadelphia radio program "The Influenza Pandemic of 1918," he was struck by the painful memories as many older Philadelphians recalled the inability of the city to care for the dead and dying. In these excerpts from Hardy's radio program, Clifford Adams, an African American from the South; Anna Lavin, a Jewish immigrant; Anne Van Dyke and Elizabeth Struchesky; and Louise Abruchezze, an Italian immigrant, discussed their shared experience in Philadelphia--shocked by the scale of the influenza outbreak, none could fathom the lack of respect shown for those who had died.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1918 und 1919 beendete die Spanischgrippe mehr 
Menschen als jede mögliche andere Krankheit in einer ähnlichen 
Periode in der Geschichte der Welt. In den Vereinigten Staaten 
ein Viertel der Bevölkerung (25 Million Leute oder mehr) schloß 
Vertrag Grippe ab; 550.000 starben. In den frühen 
achtziger Jahren als Historiker robuster Charles Interviews für das 
Philadelphia Radioprogramm "die Grippe Pandemic von 1918," wurde er 
durch die schmerzlichen Speicher angeschlagen, die bis zu älteres 
Philadelphians die Unfähigkeit der Stadt zur Obacht für die Toten 
und das Sterben erinnerte an. In diesen Excerpts vom robusten 
Radioprogramm, Clifford Adams, ein afrikanischer Amerikaner vom 
Süden; Anna Lavin, ein jüdischer Immigrant; Anne Van 
Dyke und Elizabeth Struchesky; und Louise Abruchezze, ein 
italienischer Immigrant, behandelte ihre geteilte Erfahrung in 
Philadelphia --, das durch die Skala des Grippeausbruchs entsetzt 
wurde, konnten keine fathom den Mangel an Respekt gezeigt für die, 
die gestorben waren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1918 et 1919 la grippe d'Espagnol a détruit 
plus d'humains que n'importe quelle autre maladie dans une période 
semblable dans l'histoire du monde. Aux Etats-Unis par quart de 
la population (25 millions de personnes ou plus) a contracté la 
grippe ; 550.000 sont morts. Au début des années 80, 
quand l'historien Charles robuste  des entrevues pour le programme par
radio de Philadelphie "la Pandémie de grippe de 1918," il a été 
frappé par les mémoires douloureuses qu'autant de Philadelphians 
plus ancien a rappelé l'incapacité de la ville au soin pour les 
morts et la mort. Dans ces extraits de programme par radio 
robuste, Clifford Adams, un Américain africain des Sud ; 
Anna Lavin, un immigré juif ; Anne Van Dyke et 
Elizabeth Struchesky ; et Louise Abruchezze, un immigré 
italien, a discuté leur expérience partagée à Philadelphie -- 
choquée par l'échelle de la manifestation de grippe, aucun ne 
pourrait sonder le manque de respect montré pour ceux qui était 
mort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1918 e em 1919 o influenza do espanhol matou 
mais seres humanos do que toda a outra doença em um período similar 
no history do mundo. Nos estados unidos um o quarto da 
população (25 milhão povos ou mais) contraiu o flu; 550.000 
morreram. Nos 1980s adiantados, quando o historian Charles hardy
entrevistas para o programa de rádio de Filadélfia "o influenza 
Pandemic de 1918," foi golpeado pelas memórias que dolorosas tanto 
como Philadelphians mais velho recordou a inabilidade da cidade ao 
cuidado para os mortos e morrer. Nestes excerpts do programa de 
rádio hardy, Clifford Adams, um americano africano do sul; Anna
Lavin, um immigrant jewish; Anne Camionete Dyke e Elizabeth 
Struchesky; e Louise Abruchezze, um immigrant italiano, discutiu
sua experiência compartilhada em Filadélfia -- chocada pela escala 
do outbreak do influenza, nenhuns poderiam fathom a falta do respeito 
mostrada para aquelas que tinham morrido.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1918 ed in 1919 la riossidazione dello Spagnolo
ha ucciso più esseri umani che qualunque altra malattia in un periodo
simile nella storia del mondo. In unito Dichiara un 
quarto della popolazione (25 milione di persone o più) ha contratto 
il flu; 550.000 sono morto. Nell'inizio degli anni 80, 
quando lo storico Charles hardy interviste per il programma 
radiofonico de Filadelfia "la riossidazione Pandemic di 1918," è 
stato colpito dalle memorie che dolorose altretanto più vecchio 
Philadelphians ha ricordato l'inabilità della città a cura per i 
morti e morire. In questi brani dal programma radiofonico hardy,
Clifford Adams, un americano africano dal sud; Anna Lavin, un 
immigrante ebreo; Anne Van Dyke ed Elizabeth Struchesky; e
Louise Abruchezze, un immigrante italiano, ha discusso la loro 
esperienza comune a Filadelfia -- scossa dalla scala dello scoppio di 
riossidazione, nessun potrebbero fathom la mancanza di rispetto 
indicata per coloro che era morto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1918 και το 1919 η ισπανική γρίπη σκότωσε 
περισσότερους ανθρώπους από οποιαδήποτε άλληδήποτε ασθένεια σε 
παρόμοια περίοδο στην ιστορία του κόσμου. Στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες τέταρτο του πληθυσμού (25 εκατομμύριο άνθρωποι ή 
περισσότεροι) συμβλήθηκε τη γρίπη  550.000 πέθαναν. 
Στις αρχές της δεκαετίας του '80, όταν έκανε ο ιστορικός 
Charles Hardy τις συνεντεύξεις για το ραδιο πρόγραμμα της 
Φιλαδέλφειας "η πανδημία γρίπης του 1918," χτυπήθηκε από τις 
επίπονες μνήμες δεδομένου ότι πολλοί παλαιότερο 
Philadelphians υπενθύμισαν την ανικανότητα της πόλης να 
φροντίσει για τους νεκρούς και το θάνατο. Σε αυτά τα 
αποσπάσματα από το σκληραγωγημένο ραδιο πρόγραμμα, Clifford 
Adams, ένας αφρικανικός Αμερικανός από το νότο  Θ*Αννα 
Lavin, ένας εβραϊκός μετανάστης  Θ*Αννε Van Dyke 
και Elizabeth Struchesky  και Louise Abruchezze, 
ένας ιταλικός μετανάστης, συζήτησε την κοινή εμπειρία τους στη 
Φιλαδέλφεια -- που συγκλονίστηκε από την κλίμακα του ξεσπάσματος 
γρίπης, κανένα δεν θα μπορούσε οργιά η έλλειψη σεβασμού που 
εμφανίστηκε για εκείνους που είχαν πεθάνει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1918 y 1919 la gripe del español mató a más 
seres humanos que cualquier otra enfermedad en un período similar en 
la historia del mundo. En los Estados Unidos al cuarto de la 
población (25 millones de personas de o más) contrajo la gripe; 
550.000 murieron. En los años 80 tempranos, cuando lo 
hizo el historiador Charles robusto las entrevistas para el programa 
de radio de Philadelphia "la gripe Pandemic de 1918," él pulso por 
las memorias dolorosas que tanto Philadelphians más viejo recordó la
inhabilidad de la ciudad al cuidado para los muertos y morir. En
estos extractos del programa de radio robusto, Clifford Adams, 
americano africano del sur; Ana Lavin, inmigrante judío; 
Anne Van Dyke y Elizabeth Struchesky; y Louise Abruchezze,
inmigrante italiano, discutió su experiencia compartida en 
Philadelphia -- dada una sacudida eléctrica por la escala del brote 
de la gripe, ninguno podría penetrar la carencia del respecto 
mostrada para las que habían muerto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086738</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104365</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/please-let-me-put-him-in-a-macaroni-box-the-spanish-influenza-of-1918-in-philadelphia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
