<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108001</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108001</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086476</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Minute by Minute: The  World 's Account of the Triangle Fire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Minute bis zum Minute: Welt' s Konto des 
Dreieck-Feuers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Minute par Minute : Compte de s du monde 'du
feu de triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Minuto por Minuto: Cliente de s do mundo ' 
do fogo do triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Minuto entro Minute: Cliente di s del mondo 
'del fuoco del triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λεπτό μέχρι το λεπτό: Ο παγκόσμιος "s 
απολογισμός του πυρός τριγώνων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Minuto de Minute: Cuenta de s del mundo ' 
del fuego del triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On the warm spring afternoon of March 25, 1911, a small fire broke out in a bin of rags at the Triangle Shirtwaist factory on New York City's Lower East Side. In less than an hour, 146 people--most of them young immigrant women--died, trapped by blocked exit doors and faulty fire escapes. One of the worst industrial fires in U.S. history, the Triangle fire galvanized working people and middle-class reformers alike, ultimately resulting in the passage of several laws designed to insure workplace safety. The fire received sensational and extensive coverage in all the New York City newspapers. William Gunn Shepherd, a young reporter for the New York  World , happened to be at the scene of the fire when it began. From a phone across the street, he gave a minute-by-minute account of the unfolding events to his city editor. The  World  published them the following day.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Am warmen Frühling Nachmittag von März 25, 1911,
brach ein kleines Feuer in einem Sortierfach der Lappen an der Dreieck
Shirtwaist Fabrik auf untererer Ostseite der New York Stadt aus. 
In kleiner als eine Stunde, 146 Leute -- die meisten ihnen junge
einwandernde Frauen -- gestorben, eingeschlossen durch geblockte 
Ausgang Türen und fehlerhafte Feuerentweichen. Eins der 
falschsten industriellen Feuer in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte, 
die Dreieckfeuer galvanisierten Arbeitsleute und die 
MittelklasseReformer gleich, schließlich resultierend im 
Durchgang einiger Gesetze konzipierte, Arbeitsplatzsicherheit zu 
versichern. Das Feuer empfing sensational und umfangreiche 
Dichte in allen New York City Zeitungen. William Gunn 
Schäferhund, ein junger Reporter für die New York Welt, geschehen, 
um an der Szene des Feuers zu sein, als sie anfing. Von einem 
Telefon über der Straße, berichtete er Minute-durch-Minute über den
Unfoldingfällen zu seinem Stadtherausgeber. Die Welt 
veröffentlichte sie der folgende Tag.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'après-midi chaud de ressort mars de 25, 1911, 
un petit feu a éclaté dans un coffre des chiffons à l'usine de 
Chemisier de triangle du côté est inférieur de la ville de New 
York. En moins d'une heure, 146 personnes -- la plupart d'entre 
elles jeunes femmes immigrées -- mortes, emprisonné par les portes 
bloquées de sortie et les évasions défectueuses du feu. Un 
des plus mauvais feux industriels dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS, les 
personnes de triangle et les réformateurs travaillants de classe 
moyenne galvanisés par feu de même, finalement ayant pour résultat 
le passage de plusieurs lois a conçu pour assurer la sûreté de lieu
de travail. Le feu a reçu l'assurance sensationnelle et étendue 
dans tous les journaux de New York City. Berger de William Gunn,
un jeune journaliste pour le monde de New York, avéré justement pour
être à la scène du feu quand elle a commencé. D'un 
téléphone à travers la rue, il a fait un exposé de 
minute-par-minute des événements de déploiement à son éditeur de 
ville. Le monde les a édités le jour suivant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na tarde morna da mola março de 25, 1911, um fogo
pequeno quebrou para fora em um escaninho dos panos na fábrica de 
Shirtwaist do triângulo em um lado do leste mais baixo da cidade de 
New York. Em menos do que uma hora, 146 povos -- a maioria deles
mulheres immigrant novas -- morridos, prendido por portas obstruídas 
da saída e por escapes defeituosos do fogo. Um dos fogos 
industriais os mais maus no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS, os povos do 
triângulo e os reformers trabalhando galvanized fogo do middle-class 
igualmente, finalmente tendo por resultado a passagem de diversas leis
projetou segurar a segurança do workplace. O fogo recebeu o 
sensational e a cobertura extensiva em todos os jornais de New York 
City. Shepherd de William Gunn, um repórter novo para o mundo 
de New York, acontecido estar na cena do fogo quando começou. 
De um telefone através da rua, deu um cliente de 
minuto-por-minuto dos eventos do unfolding a seu editor local. O
mundo publicou-os o seguinte dia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sul pomeriggio caldo della molla de 25 marzo 1911,
un piccolo fuoco ha scoppiato in uno scomparto dei panni alla fabbrica
di Shirtwaist del triangolo dal lato orientale più basso della città
de New York. In di meno che un'ora, 146 genti -- la maggior 
parte di loro donne immigrate giovani -- morte, intrappolato tramite i
portelli ostruiti dell'uscita e le fughe difettose del fuoco. 
Uno dei fuochi industriali più difettosi nella storia degli 
STATI UNITI, la gente del triangolo ed i reformers lavoranti della 
classe media galvanizzati fuoco egualmente, infine con conseguente 
passaggio di parecchie leggi ha progettato assicurare la sicurezza del
posto di lavoro. Il fuoco ha ricevuto il sensational ed il vasto
riempimento in tutti i giornali de New York City. Shepherd del 
William Gunn, un reporter giovane per il mondo de New York, 
sembrato per essere alla scena del fuoco quando ha cominciato. 
Da un telefono attraverso la via, ha fatto un resoconto di 
minuto-da-minuto degli eventi di spiegamento al suo editore di città.
Il mondo li ha pubblicati il seguente giorno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο θερμό απόγευμα άνοιξη της 25ης Μαρτίου ..1911, 
μια μικρή πυρκαγιά ξέσπησε σε ένα δοχείο των κουρελιών στο 
εργοστάσιο μπλουζών τριγώνων από τη χαμηλότερη ανατολική πλευρά
της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης. Σε μια λιγότερο από ώρα, 146
άνθρωποι -- οι περισσότεροι από τους νέες που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει γυναίκες -- πέθαναν, παγιδεμμένος από τις 
παρεμποδισμένες πόρτες εξόδων και τις ελαττωματικές εξόδους 
κινδύνου. Μια από τις χειρότερες βιομηχανικές πυρκαγιές 
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία, το πυρ τριγώνων γαλβάνισε τους 
εργαζόμενους ανθρώπους και τους μεταρρυθμιστές μεσαίων τάξεων 
ίδια, τελικά με συνέπεια τη μετάβαση διάφορων νόμων με σκοπό να
ασφαλίσουν την ασφάλεια εργασιακών χώρων. Η πυρκαγιά έλαβε
τη συγκλονιστική και εκτενή κάλυψη σε όλες τις εφημερίδες πόλεων
της Νέας Υόρκης. Θ*Ωηλληαμ Gunn Shepherd, ένας νέος 
δημοσιογράφος για τον κόσμο της Νέας Υόρκης, συνέβη να είναι 
στον τόπο διαδραματιζόμενων γεγονότων της πυρκαγιάς όταν άρχισε.
Από ένα τηλέφωνο πέρα από την οδό, έδωσε μια 
μικρός-από-μικρή περιγραφή των εκτυλιγμένος γεγονότων στον 
επεξεργαστή πόλεών του. Ο κόσμος τους δημοσίευσε η επόμενη
ημέρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la tarde caliente del resorte del de marcha 25 
de 1911, un fuego pequeño explotó en un compartimiento de trapos en 
la fábrica de Shirtwaist del triángulo en una cara del este más 
baja de la ciudad de Nueva York. En menos que una hora, 146 
personas -- la mayoría de ellas mujeres inmigrantes jóvenes -- 
muertas, atrapado por las puertas bloqueadas de la salida y los 
escapes defectuosos del fuego. Uno de los fuegos industriales 
peores de la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS, la gente del triángulo y los
reformadores de trabajo galvanizados fuego de la clase media 
igualmente, dando por resultado el paso de varios leyes diseñó en 
última instancia asegurar seguridad del lugar de trabajo. El 
fuego recibió sensational y cobertura extensa en todos los 
periódicos de New York City. Pastor de Guillermo Gunn, 
reportero joven para el mundo de Nueva York, sucedido para estar en la
escena del fuego cuando comenzó. De un teléfono a través de 
la calle, él dio una cuenta del minuto-por-minuto de los 
acontecimientos del unfolding a su editor de ciudad. El mundo 
los publicó el día siguiente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086476</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108001</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/minute-by-minute-the-world-s-account-of-the-triangle-fire</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
