<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105719</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105719</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086361</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Jailed for Freedom: A Women's Suffragist Remembers Prison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gefangengesetzt für Freiheit: Ein 
Suffragist Der Frauen Erinnert Sich an Gefängnis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Emprisonné pour la liberté : Une 
Suffragette de Femmes Se rappelle La Prison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jailed para a liberdade: Um Suffragist Das 
Mulheres Recorda A Prisão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imprigionato per libertà: Un Suffragist 
Delle Donne Si ricorda Della Prigione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φυλακισμένος για την ελευθερία: Suffragist των
γυναικών θυμάται τη φυλακή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encarcelado para la libertad: Un Suffragist 
De las Mujeres Recuerda La Prisión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century suffragists employed many different tactics in their struggle to win the vote for women. Members of the militant National Woman's Party (NWP), for example, rejected the patient waiting espoused by much of the movement. Some NWP members even chained themselves to the White House gates--an action that led to sentences in the Occoquan Workhouse. In this 1973 interview with historian Sherna Gluck, Ernestine Hara Kettler, a young woman of radical immigrant background, recalled her stint in the workhouse.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frühen im 20. Jahrhundert setzten die suffragists
viele unterschiedliche Taktiken in ihrem Kampf ein, um die Stimme für
Frauen zu gewinnen. Bauteile der militanten nationalen 
Partei der Frau (NWP) z.B. wiesen die Patient Aufwartung 
zurück, die durch viel der Bewegung unterstützt wurde. 
Irgendein NWP Bauteile ketteten sich sogar an die Hausgatter an 
-- eine Tätigkeit, die das zu Programmsätze im Occoquan Workhouse 
führte. In diesem Interview 1973 mit Historiker Sherna Gluck, 
Ernestine Hara Kettler, eine junge Frau des radikalen einwandernden 
Hintergrundes, wieder aufgerufen ihrem Pensum im workhouse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle les suffragettes ont 
utilisé beaucoup de différente tactique dans leur lutte pour gagner 
la voix pour des femmes. Les membres de la partie militante 
de la femme nationale (NWP), par exemple, ont rejeté l'attente de 
patient embrassée par une grande partie du mouvement. Les 
membres d'un certain NWP se sont même enchaînés aux portes  de la 
Maison Blanche -- une action que cela a menée aux phrases dans 
l'Occoquan Workhouse. Dans cette entrevue 1973 avec l'historien 
Sherna Gluck, Ernestine Hara Kettler, une jeune femme de fond immigré
radical, rappelée son travail assigné dans le workhouse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado os suffragists empregaram
muitas táticas diferentes em seu esforço para ganhar o voto para 
mulheres. Os membros do partido da mulher nacional militant 
(NWP), para o exemplo, rejeitaram a espera do paciente espoused por 
muito do movimento. Os membros de algum NWP acorrentaram-se 
mesmo às portas brancas da casa -- uma ação que isso conduziu às 
sentenças no Occoquan Workhouse. Nesta entrevista 1973 com 
historian Sherna Gluck, Ernestine Hara Kettler, uma mulher nova do 
fundo immigrant radical, recordada seu stint no workhouse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo i suffragists hanno
impiegato molte tattiche differenti nella loro lotta per vincere il 
voto per le donne. I membri del partito della donna nazionale 
del militante (NWP), per esempio, hanno rifiutato l'attesa del 
paziente espoused da gran parte del movimento. Membri di qualche
NWP persino si sono concatenati ai cancelli della Casa Bianca -- 
un'azione che quello ha condotto alle frasi nel Occoquan Workhouse. 
In questa intervista 1973 con lo storico Sherna Gluck, Ernestine
Hara Kettler, una donna giovane di priorità bassa immigrata radicale,
ricordata il suo stint nel workhouse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα suffragists υιοθέτησαν 
πολλών διαφορετική τακτική στην προσπάθειά τους να κερδίσουν την
ψηφοφορία για τις γυναίκες. Τα μέλη του συμβαλλόμενου 
μέρους της στρατευμένης εθνικής γυναίκας (NWP), παραδείγματος 
χάριν, απέρριψαν την υπομονετική αναμονή που παντρεύτηκε από 
ένα μεγάλο μέρος της μετακίνησης. Μερικά μέλη NWP 
αλυσοδέθηκαν ακόμη και στις πύλες λευκών οίκων -- μια ενέργεια 
που οδήγησε στις προτάσεις στο πτωχοκομείο Occoquan. Σε 
αυτήν την συνέντευξη του 1973 με τον ιστορικό Sherna 
Gluck, Ernestine Hara Kettler, μια νέα γυναίκα του 
ριζικού που έχουν μεταναστεύσει υποβάθρου, υπενθύμισε το όριό 
της στο πτωχοκομείο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el vigésimo siglo temprano los suffragists 
emplearon muchas diversas táctica en su lucha para ganar el voto para
las mujeres. Los miembros del partido militante de la mujer 
nacional (NWP), por ejemplo, rechazaron esperar del paciente espoused 
por mucho del movimiento. Los miembros de algún NWP incluso se 
encadenaron a las puertas blancas de la casa -- una acción que eso 
condujo a las sentencias en el Occoquan Workhouse. En esta 
entrevista 1973 con el historiador Sherna Gluck, Ernestine Hara 
Kettler, mujer joven del fondo inmigrante radical, recordada su 
restricción en el workhouse.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086361</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105719</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/jailed-for-freedom-a-womens-suffragist-remembers-prison</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
