<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106794</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106794</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087116</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Thugs for Hire: Ads for Security Guards</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schurkeen für Miete: ADS für Sicherheit 
Schutz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gangsters pour la location : ADS pour des 
gardes de sécurité</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Thugs para o hire: Ads para protetores de 
segurança</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Thugs per noleggio: Ads per le protezioni di
sicurezza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κακοποιοί για τη μίσθωση: Αγγελίες για τις 
φρουρές ασφάλειας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gamberros para el hire: Ads para los 
protectores de seguridad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Around 1903, employers began to mount organized campaigns to break the power of labor unions, particularly in the metal trades. Employers had a broad array of weapons in their arsenal, including blacklists, strikebreakers, and court injunctions against strikers' use of boycotts and sympathy strikes. In the first two decades of the 20th century, 775 injunctions were issued against labor activities. During the previous two decades, only 150 injunctions were issued. Although early twentieth-century employers had reliable allies in state police forces and tightly controlled local police, they continued to hire their own private police--detective agencies that used secret operatives to disrupt unions and supplied thugs to protect strikebreakers during strikes. This 1903 letter promoted the services of the Corporations' Auxiliary Company of Cleveland, Ohio, to prospective clients.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Herum 1903, Arbeitgeber fing an, organisierte 
Kampagnen einzuhängen, um die Energie der Arbeiterverbände, 
besonders im Metallhandel zu brechen. Arbeitgeber hatten eine 
ausgedehnte Reihe Waffen in ihrem Arsenal, einschließlich schwarze 
Listen, in den Streikbrechern und in den Gerichtinjunktionen gegen 
Gebrauch der Schlaggeräte von Boykotts und Sympathieschlägen. 
In den ersten zwei Dekaden des 20. Jahrhunderts, wurden 775 
Injunktionen gegen Arbeitsaktivitäten herausgegeben. Während 
der vorhergehenden zwei Dekaden wurden nur 150 Injunktionen 
herausgegeben. Obgleich frühe Zwanzigstjahrhundert Arbeitgeber 
zuverlässige Verbündete im Zustand polizeilich überwachen Kräfte 
hatten und fest gesteuerte lokale Polizei, fuhren sie fort, ihre 
eigene private Polizei anzustellen -- Detektivbüros, die geheime 
Arbeiter verwendeten, um Anschlüße zu stören und Schurkeen angaben,
um Streikbrecher während der Schläge zu schützen. Dieses 
Zeichen 1903 förderte die Services von Auxiliary Company 
Corporations' von Cleveland, Ohio, zu den zukünftigen Klienten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Autour 1903, employeurs a commencé à organiser 
des campagnes organisées pour casser la puissance des syndicats, en 
particulier dans les commerces en métal. Les employeurs ont eu 
un large alignement d'armes dans leur arsenal, y compris des listes 
noires, briseurs de grève, et injonctions de cour contre 
l'utilisation des butées des boycotts et des grèves de sympathie de 
solidarité. Dans les deux premières décennies du 20ème 
siècle, 775 injonctions ont été émises contre des activités de 
travail. Pendant les deux décennies précédentes, seulement 
150 injonctions ont été émises. Bien que les premiers 
employeurs de vingtième-siècle aient eu les alliés dignes de 
confiance dans l'état maintiennent l'ordre des forces et police 
locale étroitement commandée, ils ont continué à louer leur propre
police privée -- les agences de détectives qui ont utilisé les 
employés secrets pour perturber des syndicats et ont fourni des 
gangsters pour protéger des briseurs de grève pendant les grèves. 
Cette lettre 1903 a favorisé les services d'Auxiliary Company 
de Corporations'de Cleveland, Ohio, aux clients éventuels.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ao redor 1903, empregadores começaram a montar 
campanhas organizadas para quebrar a potência de uniões labor, 
particularmente nos comércios do metal. Os empregadores tiveram
uma disposição larga das armas em seu arsenal, including listas 
negras, em strikebreakers, e em injunctions da corte de encontro ao 
uso dos grevistas dos boycotts e das batidas de sympathy. Nas 
primeiras duas décadas do 20o século, 775 injunctions foram emitidos
de encontro às atividades labor. Durante as duas décadas 
precedentes, somente 150 injunctions foram emitidos. Embora os 
empregadores adiantados de vigésimo-século tivessem aliados de 
confiança no estado policiassem forças e polícias locais firmemente
controladas, continuaram a empregar suas próprias polícias 
confidenciais -- as agências detective que usaram operatives secretos
disrupt uniões e forneceram thugs para proteger strikebreakers 
durante batidas. Esta letra 1903 promoveu os serviços dos 
Auxiliar Companhia dos Corporation de Cleveland, Ohio, aos clientes em
perspectiva.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Intorno 1903, datori di lavoro ha cominciato ad 
organizzare le campagne organizzate per rompere l'potenza dei 
sindacati di lavoro, specialmente nei commerci del metallo. I 
datori di lavoro hanno avuti un vasto allineamento delle armi nel loro
arsenale, compreso le liste nere, in crumiri e nelle ingiunzioni della
corte contro uso dei percussori dei boicottaggi e dei colpi di 
compassione. Nelle prime due decadi del ventesimo secolo, 775 
ingiunzioni si sono pubblicate contro le attività di lavoro. 
Durante le due decadi precedenti, soltanto 150 ingiunzioni si 
sono pubblicate. Anche se i datori di lavoro in anticipo di 
ventesimo-secolo hanno fatti dichiarare agli alleati certi 
dentro le forze della polizia e la polizia locale strettamente 
gestita, hanno continuato ad assumere la loro propria polizia 
riservata -- agenzie detective che hanno usato gli operatori segreti 
per interrompere i sindacati ed hanno fornito i thugs per proteggere i
crumiri durante i colpi. Questa lettera 1903 ha promosso i 
servizi degli Auxiliary Company delle Corporations di Cleveland, Ohio,
ai futuri clienti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περίπου το 1903, εργοδότες άρχισε να επικολλά τις 
οργανωμένες εκστρατείες για να σπάσει τη δύναμη των εργατικών 
συνδικάτων, ιδιαίτερα στα εμπόρια μετάλλων. Οι εργοδότες 
είχαν μια ευρεία σειρά όπλων στο οπλοστάσιό τους, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των μαύρων λιστών, strikebreakers, και των 
εντολών δικαστηρίων ενάντια στη χρήση των απεργών των 
μποϊκοταρισμάτων και των απεργιών συμπόνοιας. Στις πρώτες 
δύο δεκαετίες του 20ού αιώνα, 775 εντολές εκδόθηκαν ενάντια 
στις δραστηριότητες εργασίας. Κατά τη διάρκεια των 
προηγούμενων δύο δεκαετιών, μόνο 150 εντολές εκδόθηκαν. 
Αν και οι πρώτοι εργοδότες εικοστός-αιώνα είχαν τους 
αξιόπιστους συμμάχους στις δυνάμεις κρατικής αστυνομίας και τη 
στενά ελεγχόμενη τοπική αστυνομία, συνέχισαν να μισθώνουν την 
ιδιωτική αστυνομία τους -- αντιπροσωπείες ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών 
που χρησιμοποίησαν τους μυστικούς χειριστές για να αναστατώσουν 
τις ενώσεις και παρείχαν τους κακοποιούς για να προστατεύσουν 
strikebreakers κατά τη διάρκεια των απεργιών. Αυτή η 
επιστολή του 1903 προώθησε τις υπηρεσίες της βοηθητικής 
επιχείρησης των εταιριών του Κλήβελαντ, Οχάιο, στους ενδεχόμενους
χρήστες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alrededor 1903, patrones comenzó a montar 
campañas ordenadas para romper la potencia de sindicatos, determinado
en los comercios del metal. Los patrones tenían un amplio 
arsenal de armas en su arsenal, incluyendo listas negras, 
rompehuelgas, y prescripciones de la corte contra el uso de los 
huelguistas de boicoteos y de huelgas de condolencia. En las 
primeras dos décadas del vigésimo siglo, 775 prescripciones fueron 
publicadas contra actividades de trabajo. Durante las dos 
décadas anteriores, solamente 150 prescripciones fueron publicadas. 
Aunque los patrones tempranos del vige'simo-siglo tenían 
aliados confiables en estado limpian fuerzas y policía local 
firmemente controlado, continuaron empleando a su propio policía 
privado -- las agencias detectives que utilizaron a operarios secretos
para interrumpir uniones y proveieron a gamberros para proteger a 
rompehuelgas durante huelgas. Esta carta 1903 promovió los 
servicios de los Auxiliary Company de las Corporations' de Cleveland, 
Ohio, a los clientes anticipados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087116</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106794</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/thugs-for-hire-ads-for-security-guards</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
