<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107776</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107776</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086497</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"My children are Just Tied Down Here": Washington Spradling Discusses the Condition of Free Blacks in the South, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"meine Kinder werden gerade hinunter hier" 
gebunden: Washington Spradling behandelt die Bedingung der 
freien Schwarzer im Süden, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"mes enfants sont juste attachés en bas d'ici" : 
Washington Spradling discute la condition des noirs libres dans 
les Sud, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"minhas crianças são amarradas apenas abaixo 
aqui": Washington Spradling discute a condição de pretos 
livres no sul, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i miei bambini sono legati appena giù qui": 
Washington Spradling discute il termine dei neri liberi nel sud,
1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τα παιδιά μου είναι ακριβώς δεμένα κάτω από εδώ": 
Η Ουάσιγκτον Spradling συζητά τον όρο των ελεύθερων 
Μαύρων στο νότο, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">atan a "mis niños apenas abajo de aquí": 
Washington Spradling discute la condición de negros libres en 
el sur, 1863</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While white southerners briefly considered the idea of emancipating slaves in the years following the American Revolution, by the early-nineteenth century that sentiment had been replaced by a systematic campaign to restrict possibilities for emancipation. After the Nat Turner rebellion of 1832, whites viewed the presence of free blacks among the slave population as dangerous and began to limit their rights. The growth of the southern free black population slowed in the second quarter of the nineteenth century and became concentrated in urban areas where they worked as manual laborers, domestics, and artisans. In this 1863 interview, Washington Spradling, 63, the son of an overseer, described how he purchased his family's freedom yet still faced growing restrictions under Kentucky laws that severely hampered free blacks' movements and efforts to achieve justice. Samuel Gridley Howe, an abolitionist and educator of the blind, interviewed Spradling for the American Freedmen's Inquiry Commission, a body created to make recommendations about the plight of freedmen after the war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während weiße southerners kurz betrachteten, 
schuftet die Idee des Emanzipierens in den Jahren, die der 
amerikanischen Umdrehung, bis zum dem früh-19.jahrhundert folgen, 
daß Gefühl durch eine systematische Kampagne ersetzt worden war, um 
Möglichkeiten für Emanzipation einzuschränken. Nach dem 
nationalen Turner Aufstand von 1832, sah Weiß das Vorhandensein der 
freien Schwarzer unter der Sklavenbevölkerung als gefährliches an 
und fing an, ihre Rechte zu begrenzen. Das Wachstum der 
südlichen freien schwarzen Bevölkerung, die in das zweite Viertel 
des 19.jahrhunderts verlangsamt wurde und wurde in den städtischen 
Bereichen konzentriert, in denen es als manuelle Arbeiter, 
Hausangestellte und Handwerker arbeiteten. In diesem Interview 
1863 stellte Washington Spradling, 63, der Sohn eines Aufsehers, 
beschrieben, wie er Freiheit seiner Familie kaufte, dennoch noch 
wachsende Beschränkungen unter Kentucky Gesetzen gegenüber, die 
streng Bewegungen und Bemühungen der freien Schwarzen hemmten, 
Gerechtigkeit zu erzielen. Samuel Gridley Howe, ein abolitionist
und Erzieher des Vorhanges, interviewtes Spradling für die 
amerikanischen Anfrage-Kommission der Freedmens, ein Körper erstellt,
um Empfehlungen über die Lage von Freedmen nach dem Krieg zu bilden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que les habitants du sud blancs considéraient 
brièvement l'idée d'émanciper asservit en années suivant la 
révolution américaine, du tôt-dix-neuvième siècle que le 
sentiment avait été remplacé par une campagne systématique pour 
limiter des possibilités pour l'émancipation. Après la 
rébellion nationale de Turner de 1832, les blancs ont visualisé 
la présence des noirs libres parmi la population slave en tant 
que dangereux et ont commencé à limiter leurs droites. La 
croissance de la population noire libre méridionale ralentie dans le 
deuxième trimestre du dix-neuvième siècle et est devenue 
concentrée dans des zones urbaines où ils ont fonctionné en tant 
que les travailleurs, les domestiques, et artisans manuels. Dans
cette entrevue 1863, Washington Spradling, 63, le fils d'un 
contrôleur, décrit comment il a acheté la liberté de sa famille 
pourtant faisait face toujours à des restrictions croissantes en 
vertu des lois du Kentucky qui ont sévèrement entravé les 
mouvements et les efforts des noirs libres de réaliser la justice. 
Samuel Gridley Howe, un abolitionniste et éducateur de 
l'abat-jour, Spradling interviewé pour la Commission de l'enquête 
des freedmen's américains, un corps créé pour faire des 
recommandations au sujet de la situation difficile des freedmen après
la guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando os southerners brancos consideraram 
momentaneamente a idéia de emancipating slaves nos anos que seguem a 
volta americana, pelo cedo-décimo nono século que o sentiment tinha 
sido substituído por uma campanha sistemática para restringir 
possibilidades para o emancipation. Após a rebelião nat de 
Turner de 1832, os brancos viram a presença de pretos livres entre a 
população slave como perigoso e começaram a limitar suas direitas. 
O crescimento da população preta livre do sul retardada no 
segundo quarto do décimo nono século e tornou-se concentrado nas 
áreas urbanas onde trabalharam como laborers, domestics, e artisans 
manuais. Nesta entrevista 1863, Washington Spradling, 63, filho 
de um overseer, descrito como comprou a liberdade da sua família 
contudo enfrentou ainda limitações crescentes sob as leis de 
Kentucky que hampered severamente movimentos e esforços dos pretos 
livres conseguir a justiça. Samuel Gridley Howe, um 
abolitionist e educador da cortina, Spradling entrevistado para o 
commission do inquérito dos freedmen americanos, um corpo criado para
fazer recomendações sobre o plight dos freedmen após a guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre i southerners bianchi brevemente hanno 
considerato l'idea di emancipating assoggetta durante gli anni che 
seguono la rivoluzione americana, entro il presto-diciannovesimo 
secolo che il sentimento era stato sostituito da una campagna 
sistematica per limitare le possibilità per emancipazione. Dopo
la ribellione nazionale del Turner di 1832, i bianchi hanno osservato
la presenza dei neri liberi fra la popolazione slave come pericoloso 
ed hanno cominciato a limitare i loro diritti. Lo sviluppo della
popolazione di colore libera del sud ritardata nel secondo trimestre 
del diciannovesimo secolo ed è stato concentrato nelle aree urbane 
dove hanno funzionato come i lavoratori, i domestics ed artigianale 
manuali. In questa intervista 1863, Washington Spradling, 63, il
figlio di un overseer, descritto come ha comprato la libertà della 
sua famiglia tuttavia ancora ha affrontato le limitazioni crescenti 
secondo le leggi del Kentucky che hanno impedito severamente i 
movimenti e gli sforzi dei neri liberi realizzare la giustizia. 
Samuel Gridley Howe, un abolitionist ed educatore dei ciechi, 
Spradling intervistato per la Commissione di inchiesta dei freedmen 
americani, un corpo creato per fare le raccomandazioni circa la 
situazione difficile dei freedmen dopo la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ οι λευκοί νότιοι εξέτασαν εν συντομία την ιδέα 
χειραφετών των σκλάβων στα έτη μετά από την αμερικανική 
επανάσταση, μέχρι τον πρόωρος-δέκατο έννατο αιώνα ότι το 
συναίσθημα ήταν αντικατεστημένο από μια συστηματική εκστρατεία 
για να περιορίσει τις δυνατότητες για την χειραφέτηση. 
Μετά από την εθνική εξέγερση τορναδόρων 1832, τα λευκά 
εμφάνισαν την παρουσία ελεύθερων Μαύρων μεταξύ του πληθυσμού 
σκλάβων ως επικίνδυνη και άρχισαν να περιορίζουν τα δικαιώματά 
τους. Η αύξηση του νότιου ελεύθερου μαύρου πληθυσμού 
επιβράδυνε στο δεύτερο τέταρτο του δέκατου έννατου αιώνα και 
έγινε συγκεντρωμένη στις αστικές περιοχές όπου ελειτούργησαν ως 
χειρωνακτικά laborers, domestics, και artisans. Σε 
αυτήν την συνέντευξη 1863, η Ουάσιγκτον Spradling, 63, ο 
γιος ενός overseer, περιέγραψε πώς αγόρασε περιορισμούς 
ελευθερίας της οικογένειάς του τους αντιμέτωπους αυξανόμενους 
ακόμα ακόμα βάσει των νόμων του Κεντάκυ που παρακώλυσαν σοβαρά 
τις μετακινήσεις και τις προσπάθειες των ελεύθερων Μαύρων να 
επιτύχουν τη δικαιοσύνη. Ο Samuel Gridley Howe, ένας
ρεφορμιστής και ένας εκπαιδευτικός του τυφλού, περάσώνταυ από 
συνέντευξη Spradling για την Επιτροπή έρευνας των αμερικανικών 
απελευθέρων, ένα σώμα δημιούργησαν για να υποβάλουν συστάσεις 
για τη δύσκολη θέση των απελευθέρων μετά από τον πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que los southerners blancos consideraban 
abreviadamente la idea de emancipating esclaviza en los años que 
siguen la revolución americana, por el temprano-diecinueveavo siglo 
que el sentimiento había sido substituido por una campaña 
sistemática para restringir las posibilidades de la emancipación. 
Después de la rebelión nacional de Turner de 1832, los blancos
vieron la presencia de negros libres entre la población auxiliar como
peligroso y comenzaron a limitar las sus derechas. El 
crecimiento de la población negra libre meridional retardada en el 
segundo trimestre del diecinueveavo siglo y se concentró en las 
áreas urbanas donde trabajaron como trabajadores, domestics, y 
artesanos manuales. En esta entrevista 1863, Washington 
Spradling, 63, el hijo de un overseer, descrito cómo él compró la 
libertad de su familia con todo todavía hizo frente a restricciones 
cada vez mayor bajo leyes de Kentucky que obstaculizaron seriamente 
los movimientos y los esfuerzos de los negros libres de alcanzar la 
justicia. Samuel Gridley Howe, un abolitionist y educador de la 
persiana, Spradling entrevistado con para la Comisión de la pregunta 
de los freedmen americanos, cuerpo creado para hacer recomendaciones 
sobre el apuro de freedmen después de la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086497</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107776</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/my-children-are-just-tied-down-here-washington-spradling-discusses-the-condition-of-free-blacks-in-the-south-1863</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
