<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105549</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105549</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086075</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Digging for Answers: A Black Miner Ponders Racism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Graben für Antworten: Ein Schwarzes 
Bergmann Erwägt Rassismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Creuser pour des réponses : Un Mineur Noir 
Considère Le Racisme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escavar para respostas: Um Mineiro Preto 
Ponders O Racism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scavando per le risposte: Un Minatore Nero 
Ponders Il Razzismo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκάψιμο για τις απαντήσεις: Ένας μαύρος 
ανθρακωρύχος συλλογίζεται ρατσισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El cavar para las respuestas: Un Minero 
Negro Ponders Racismo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Richard L. Davis, the most important black leader of Ohio's miners, was called upon frequently in the 1880s and 1890s to serve as a spokesman for the many black miners in his home state, as well as the thousands more who labored in Alabama, Tennessee, and West Virginia. He was also called upon to serve as an intermediary between black rank-and-file miners and the white majority and white national leadership of the United Mine Workers of America (UMWA), dealing with such issues as black participation in the union, strike breaking by African Americans, and the racist attitudes of many rank-and-file white miners toward African Americans. (Davis was twice elected to the UMWA's executive board.) In this series of six letters submitted in 1891 to the  National Labor Tribune , Davis reflected on the larger meaning and purpose of interracial unionism in an era of rising racial tensions and institutionalized discrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Um Richard L. Davis, der wichtigste schwarze 
Führer von Bergmännern Ohios, wurde häufig im 1880s und im 1890s 
ersucht, um wie ein Wortführer für die vielen schwarzen Bergmänner 
in seinem Hauptzustand, sowie die Tausenden zu dienen mehr, wer 
bearbeitet in Alabama, in Tennessee und in West Virginia. Um ihn
wurde auch ersucht, um als Vermittler zwischen schwarzen 
Ordnen-unddatei Bergmännern und der weißen Majorität und der 
weißen nationalen Führung der vereinigten Grube Arbeiter von Amerika
(UMWA) zu dienen und beschäftigte solche Ausgaben wie schwarze 
Teilnahme am Anschluß, am Schlag, der von African Americans brechen, 
und an der rassistischen Haltung von vielen Ordnen-unddatei weiße 
Bergmänner in Richtung zu den afrikanischen Amerikanern. (Davis
wurde zweimal zum des UMWAs Exekutivorgan. gewählt) In dieser 
Reihe von sechs Zeichen gab 1891 bei der nationalen 
ArbeitsTribüne, Davis ein, das auf der größeren Bedeutung und
dem Zweck von interracial unionism in einer Ära der steigenden 
rassischen Spannkräfte reflektiert wurde und institutionalisierte 
Unterscheidung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Richard L. Davis, l'amorce noire la plus 
importante des mineurs de l'Ohio, a été invité fréquemment dans le
1880s et le 1890s pour servir  un porte-parole pour les nombreux 
mineurs noirs dans son état à la maison, aussi bien que les milliers
de plus qui travaillé en Alabama, au Tennessee, et la Virginie 
Occidentale. Il a été également invité pour servir 
d'intermédiaire entre les mineurs noirs de ranger-et-fichier et la 
majorité blanche et la conduite nationale blanche des mineurs unis de
l'Amérique (UMWA), traitant des issues telles que la participation 
noire à l'union, à la grève se cassant par African Americans, et 
aux attitudes racistes de beaucoup les mineurs blancs de 
ranger-et-fichier vers les Américains africains. (Davis a été
deux fois élu au conseil exécutif de l'UMWA.) Dans cette 
série de six lettres a soumis en 1891 à Tribune de travail 
national, Davis réfléchi sur la signification et le but plus grands 
du syndicalisme interracial dans une ère des tensions raciales se 
levantes et a institutionalisé la discrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Richard L. Davis, líder preto o mais importante 
de mineiros de Ohio, foi convidado freqüentemente no 1880s e no 1890s
para servir como um spokesman para muitos mineiros pretos em seu 
estado home, as.well.as os milhares mais quem trabalhado em Alabama, 
em Tennessee, e em Virgínia ocidental. Foi convidado também 
para servir como um intermediary entre mineiros pretos da 
espesso-e-lima e a maioria branca e a liderança nacional branca dos 
trabalhadores de mina unidos de América (UMWA), tratando das 
edições como a participação preta na união, na batida que quebram
por Africano Americano, e nas atitudes racist de muitos os mineiros 
brancos da espesso-e-lima para americanos africanos. (Davis foi 
elegido duas vezes à placa executiva do UMWA.) Nesta série de 
seis letras submeteu-se em 1891 ao Tribune labor nacional, Davis 
refletido no meaning e na finalidade maiores do unionism interracial 
em uma era de tensões raciais levantando-se e institutionalized a 
discriminação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Richard L. Davis, il capo nero più 
importante dei minatori dell'Ohio, è stato invitato frequentemente 
nel 1880s ed il 1890s per servire come un portavoce per i molti 
minatori neri nella sua sede dichiara, così come le migliaia 
di più chi lavorato nell'Alabama, Tennessee e la Virginia dell'Ovest.
Egualmente è stato invitato per servire da mediatore fra i 
minatori neri dell'alline-e-archivio e la maggioranza bianca e la 
direzione nazionale bianca dei minatori uniti dell'America (UMWA), 
occupantesi di tali edizioni come la partecipazione nera all'unione, 
al colpo che si rompono dall'African Americans ed agli atteggiamenti 
razzisti di molti minatori bianchi dell'alline-e-archivio verso gli 
Americani africani. (Davis è stato scelto due volte al 
bordo esecutivo del UMWA.) In questa serie di sei lettere 
ha presentato in 1891 al Tribune Di lavoro nazionale, Davis riflesso 
sul più grandi significato e scopo del unionism interracial in un'era
dei tensionamenti razziali aumentanti ed ha istituzionalizzato la 
distinzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Richard Λ. Νταίηβις, ο σημαντικότερος μαύρος 
ηγέτης των ανθρακωρύχων του Οχάιου, κλήθηκε συχνά στο 1880s 
και το 1890s για να χρησιμεύσει ως έναν εκπρόσωπο για τους 
πολλούς μαύρους ανθρακωρύχους στο βασικό κράτος του, καθώς 
επίσης και οι χιλιάδες περισσότερο ποιος εργάστηκε στην Αλαμπάμα,
το Tennessee, και τη δυτική Βιρτζίνια. Κλήθηκε επίσης για
να χρησιμεύσει ως έναν μεσάζοντα μεταξύ των μαύρων ανθρακωρύχων 
πυκνός-και-αρχείων και της λευκιάς πλειοψηφίας και η λευκιά 
εθνική ηγεσία των ενωμένων εργαζομένων ορυχείου της Αμερικής 
(UMWA), εξετάζοντας τέτοια ζητήματα όπως τη μαύρη συμμετοχή 
στην ένωση, το σπάσιμο απεργίας από αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς, 
και τη ρατσιστική στάση πολλών λευκών ανθρακωρύχων 
πυκνός-και-αρχείων απέναντι σε αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. (Ο
Νταίηβις εκλέχτηκε δύο φορές στο εκτελεστικό συμβούλιο του 
UMWA.) Σε αυτήν την σειρά έξι επιστολών που υποβλήθηκαν 
το 1891 στο εθνικό βήμα εργασίας, ο Νταίηβις απεικόνισε στη 
μεγαλύτερους έννοια και το σκοπό του διαφυλετικού συνδικαλισμού 
σε μια εποχή των αυξανόμενων φυλετικών εντάσεων και θεσμοποίησε 
τη διάκριση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Invitaron a Richard L. Davis, el arranque de 
cinta negro más importante de los mineros de Ohio, con frecuencia en 
el 1880s y el 1890s para servir como un portavoz para los muchos 
mineros negros en su estado casero, así como los millares más quién
trabajada en Alabama, Tennessee, y Virginia Occidental. A 
african americans también lo invitó para servir como intermediario 
entre los mineros negros del alinear-y-fichero y la mayoría blanca y 
la dirección nacional blanca de los trabajadores de mina unidos de 
América (UMWA), ocupándose de las ediciones tales como la 
participación negra en la unión, la huelga que se rompía, y las 
actitudes racist de muchos los mineros blancos del alinear-y-fichero 
hacia americanos africanos. (Davis fue elegido dos veces al 
consejo de dirección del UMWA.) En esta serie de seis cartas 
sometió en 1891 al Tribune de trabajo nacional, Davis reflejado en el
significado y el propósito más grandes del unionism interracial en 
una era de tensiones raciales de levantamiento e institucionalizó la 
discriminación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086075</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105549</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/digging-for-answers-a-black-miner-ponders-racism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
