<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105424</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105424</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086879</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Telling Secrets Out of School: Siringo on the Pinkertons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Geheimnisse erklären außerschulisch: 
Siringo auf dem Pinkertons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Disant des secrets extrascolaires : Siringo 
sur le Pinkertons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dizendo segredos fora da escola: Siringo no 
Pinkertons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dicendo ai segreti extrascolastici: Siringo 
sul Pinkertons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μυστικά αφήγησης από το σχολείο: Siringo στο
Pinkertons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diciendo los secretos extraescolares: 
Siringo en el Pinkertons</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With 2,000 active agents and 30,000 reserves, the forces of the Pinkerton National Detective Agency were larger than the nation's standing army in the late-19th century. The Pinkertons provided services for management in labor disputes, including armed guards and secret operatives like Charles A. Siringo. A Texas native and former cowboy, Siringo moved to Chicago in 1886, where first-hand observation of the city's labor conflict (which he attributed to foreign anarchism) moved him to join the Pinkertons. Angry with the agency after it sabotaged the publication of his cowboy memoirs, Siringo published  Two Evil Isms: Pinkertonism and Anarchism , a revealing chronicle of Pinkerton methods and deception. Guarding its reputation, the Pinkerton Agency succeeded in suppressing the book. Operatives bought up all copies available at newsstands and a court order confiscated the book's plates. In the following passage from  Two Evil Isms , Siringo (who, even when alienated from the Pinkertons, never displayed any sympathy for the labor movement) described how he infiltrated and undermined miners' unions in northern Idaho during the 1892 Coeur d'Alene strike.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit 2.000 aktiven Mitteln und 30.000 Reserven 
waren die Kräfte des Pinkerton nationalen Detektivbüros größer als
die stehende Armee der Nation im des späten 19. jahrhunderts 
Jahrhundert. Das Pinkertons stellte Dienstleistungen für 
Management in den arbeitsrechtlichen Streitigkeiten, einschließlich 
bewaffneten Schutz und geheime Arbeiter wie Charles A. Siringo zur 
Verfügung. Ein Texas gebürtiger und ehemaliger Cowboy, Siringo
zog auf Chicago 1886 um, wo aus erster Hand bezogene Beobachtung der 
Arbeitßüberschneidung der Stadt (die er fremder Anarchie zuschrieb),
ihn verschob, um das Pinkertons zu verbinden. Verärgert mit der
Agentur, nachdem sie die Publikation seiner Cowboyabhandlungen 
sabotierte, Siringo veröffentlichte zwei Übel Isms: 
Pinkertonism und Anarchie, eine aufschlußreiche Chronik der 
Pinkerton Methoden und Täuschung. Sein Renommee schützen, die 
Pinkerton Agentur gefolgt, mit, das Buch zu unterdrücken. Alle 
die Arbeiter, die herauf gekauft werden, kopiert vorhandenes an den 
Informationsständen und ein Gerichtsbefehl konfiszierte die Platten 
des Buches. Im folgenden Durchgang von zwei Übel Isms, Siringo 
(wer, selbst wenn entfremdet vom Pinkertons, nie angezeigt irgendeiner
Sympathie für die Arbeiterbewegung) beschrieben, wie er Anschlüße 
der Bergmänner in Nordidaho während des Coeur d'Alene Schlages 1892 
einsickerte und untergrub.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec 2.000 agents actifs et 30.000 réserves, les 
forces de l'agence de détectives nationale de Pinkerton étaient plus
grandes que l'armée debout de la nation en fin du 19me siècle. 
Le Pinkertons a fourni des services pour la gestion dans des 
conflits de travail, y compris les gardes armées et les employés 
secrets comme Charles A. Siringo. Le cowboy indigène et ancien 
d'un Texas, Siringo s'est déplacé à Chicago en 1886, où 
l'observation de première main du conflit de travail de la ville 
(qu'il a attribué à l'anarchisme étranger) l'a déplacé pour 
joindre le Pinkertons. Fâché avec l'agence après qu'elle ait 
saboté la publication de ses mémoires de cowboy, Siringo a édité 
deux le mal Isms : Pinkertonism et anarchisme, une chronique 
d'indication des méthodes de Pinkerton et déception. Gardant 
sa réputation, l'agence de Pinkerton réussie à supprimer le livre. 
Les employés achetés vers le haut de tous copie disponible aux
kiosques à journaux et une commande de cour a confisqué les plats du
livre. Dans le passage suivant deux du mal Isms, Siringo (qui, 
même lorsqu'aliéné du Pinkertons, non jamais affiché toute 
sympathie pour le mouvement de travail) a décrit comment il a 
infiltré et a miné les syndicats des mineurs en Idaho nordique 
pendant la grève 1892 de d'Alene de Coeur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com os 2.000 agentes ativos e as 30.000 reservas, 
as forças da agência detective nacional de Pinkerton eram maiores do
que o exército ereto da nação no século late-19th. O 
Pinkertons forneceu serviços para a gerência em disputas labor, 
including protetores armados e operatives secretos como Charles A. 
Siringo. O vaqueiro nativo e anterior de um Texas, Siringo 
moveu-se para Chicago em 1886, onde a observação first-hand do 
conflito labor da cidade (que atribuiu ao anarchism extrangeiro) o 
moveu para juntar o Pinkertons. Irritado com a agência depois 
que sabotaged a publicação de seus memoirs do vaqueiro, Siringo 
publicou dois o evil Isms: Pinkertonism e anarchism, um 
chronicle revelando de métodos de Pinkerton e deception. 
Guardando sua reputação, a agência de Pinkerton sucedida em 
suprimir o livro. Os operatives comprados acima de todos copíam
disponível em newsstands e uma ordem de corte confiscated as placas 
do livro. Na seguinte passagem dois do evil Isms, Siringo (quem,
nivela quando alienated do Pinkertons, nunca indicado todo o sympathy 
para o movimento labor) descreveu como infiltrated e undermined 
uniões dos mineiros em Idaho do norte durante a batida 1892 do 
d'Alene de Coeur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con 2.000 agenti attivi e 30.000 riserve, le forze
dell'agenzia detective nazionale di Pinkerton erano più grandi 
dell'esercito diritto della nazione nel fine del 19esimo secolo. 
Il Pinkertons ha fornito i servizi per la gestione nelle dispute
di lavoro, compreso le protezioni munite e gli operatori segreti come
Charles A. Siringo. Il cowboy natale ed ex del Texas, Siringo si
è mosso verso Chicago in 1886, dove l'osservazione di prima mano del 
conflitto di lavoro della città (che ha attribuito all'anarchismo 
straniero) lo ha spostato per unire il Pinkertons. Arrabbiato 
con l'agenzia dopo che sabotasse la pubblicazione delle sue memorie 
del cowboy, Siringo ha pubblicato due la malvagità Isms: 
Pinkertonism ed anarchismo, un chronicle rivelante dei metodi di
Pinkerton ed inganno. Custodendo la relativa reputazione, 
l'agenzia di Pinkerton riuscita a sopprimere il libro. Gli 
operatori comprati su tutti copia disponibile ai newsstands e un 
mandato ha confiscato le piastre del libro. Nel seguente 
passaggio due dalla malvagità Isms, Siringo (chi, anche quando 
allontanato dal Pinkertons, mai non visualizzato qualsiasi compassione
per il movimento di lavoro) ha descritto come si è infiltrato ed 
insidiato nei sindacati dei minatori nell'Idaho del Nord durante il 
colpo 1892 del d'Alene di Coeur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με 2.000 ενεργούς πράκτορες και 30.000 
επιφυλάξεις, οι δυνάμεις της εθνικής αντιπροσωπείας ιδιωτικών 
αστυνομικών Pinkerton ήταν μεγαλύτερες από το μόνιμο στρατό 
του έθνους στο late-19th αιώνα. Το Pinkertons παρείχε 
τις υπηρεσίες για τη διαχείριση στις διαφωνίες εργασίας, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των οπλισμένων φρουρών και των μυστικών 
χειριστών όπως Charles A. Siringo. Ένας εγγενής και
προηγούμενος κάουμπου! του Τέξας, Siringo κινήθηκε προς το 
Σικάγο το 1886, όπου η από πρώτο χέρι παρατήρηση της 
σύγκρουσης εργασίας της πόλης (που απέδωσε στον ξένο αναρχισμό) 
τον κίνησε για να ενώσει το Pinkertons. 0 με την 
αντιπροσωπεία αφότου υπονόμευσε τη δημοσίευση των 
απομνημονευμάτων κάουμποϋ' του, Siringo δημοσίευσε δύο κακό 
Isms: Το Pinkertonism και ο αναρχισμός, μια αποκάλυψη 
εξιστορούν κατά γράμμα των μεθόδων Pinkerton και της 
εξαπάτησης. Φρουρώντας τη φήμη της, η αντιπροσωπεία 
Pinkerton πέτυχε στην καταστολή του βιβλίου. Οι χειριστές
αγόρασαν επάνω όλα τα αντίγραφα διαθέσιμα στα περίπτερα 
εφημερίδων και μια δικαστική απόφαση δήμευσε τα πιάτα του 
βιβλίου. Στην ακόλουθη μετάβαση από δύο κακό Isms, 
Siringo (που, ακόμα και όταν αλλοτριωμένος από το 
Pinkertons, δεν παρουσίασε ποτέ οποιαδήποτε συμπόνοια για τη 
μετακίνηση εργασίας) περιέγραψε πώς διείσδυσε και υπονόμευσε τις
ενώσεις των ανθρακωρύχων στο βόρειο Idaho κατά τη διάρκεια της
1892 απεργίας Coeur d'Alene.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con 2.000 agentes activos y 30.000 reservas, las 
fuerzas de la agencia detective nacional de Pinkerton eran más 
grandes que el ejército derecho de la nación en el siglo de fines 
del siglo diecinueve. El Pinkertons proporcionó a los servicios
para la gerencia en conflictos de trabajo, incluyendo protectores 
armados y operarios secretos como Charles A. Siringo. El vaquero
nativo y anterior de un Tejas, Siringo se trasladó a Chicago en 1886,
donde la observación de primera mano del conflicto de trabajo de la 
ciudad (que él atribuyó al anarquismo no nativo) lo movió para 
ensamblar el Pinkertons. Enojado con la agencia después de que 
saboteara la publicación de sus memorias del vaquero, Siringo 
publicó dos el mal Isms: Pinkertonism y anarquismo, un 
chronicle que revela de los métodos de Pinkerton y engaño. 
Guardando su reputación, la agencia de Pinkerton tenida éxito 
en suprimir el libro. Los operarios comprados encima de todos 
copian disponible en los kioscos de periódicos y un orden judicial 
confiscó las placas del libro. En el paso siguiente a partir el
dos del mal Isms, Siringo (quién, iguala cuando está enajenada del 
Pinkertons, nunca visualizado cualquier condolencia para el movimiento
de trabajo) describió cómo él infiltró y minó las uniones de los 
mineros en Idaho norteño durante la huelga 1892 del d'Alene de Coeur.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086879</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105424</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/telling-secrets-out-of-school-siringo-on-the-pinkertons</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
