<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105492</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105492</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086676</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Not All Caucasians Are White: The Supreme Court Rejects Citizenship for Asian Indians</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nicht Alle Kaukasier Sind Weiß: Das 
Höchste Gericht weist Staatsbürgerschaft für asiatische Inder 
zurück</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Non Tous les Caucasiens Sont Blancs : La 
cour suprême rejette la citoyenneté pour les Indiens asiatiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Não Todos os Caucasians São Brancos: A 
corte suprema rejeita o citizenship para indians asian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Non Tutti i Caucasians Sono Bianchi: La 
Corte suprema rifiuta la cittadinanza per gli indiani asiatici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όχι όλοι οι Καυκάσιοι είναι λευκοί: Το ανώτατο
δικαστήριο απορρίπτει την υπηκοότητα για ασιατικούς Ινδούς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">No Todos los Caucásicos Son Blancos: El 
Tribunal Supremo rechaza la ciudadanía para los indios asiáticos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In its decision in the case of U.S.  v . Bhagat Singh Thind (1923), the Supreme Court deemed Asian Indians ineligible for citizenship because U.S. law allowed only free whites to become naturalized citizens. The court conceded that Indians were "Caucasians" and that anthropologists considered them to be of the same race as white Americans, but argued that "the average man knows perfectly well that there are unmistakable and profound differences." The  Thind  decision also led to successful efforts to denaturalize some who had previously become citizens. This represented a particular threat in California, where a 1913 law prohibited aliens ineligible for citizenship from owning or leasing land. Only in 1946 did Congress, which was beginning to recognize that India would soon be independent and a major world power, pass a new law that allowed Indians to become citizens and also established a small immigration quota. But major immigration to the United States from South Asia did not begin until after immigration laws were sharply revised in 1965.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In seiner Entscheidung im Fall von VEREINIGTEN 
STAATEN V. Bhagat Singh Thind (1923), das Höchste Gericht 
meinte asiatische Inder untauglich für Staatsbürgerschaft, weil 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Gesetz nur freies Weiß eingebürgerten Bürgern 
stehen ließ. Das Gericht gestand, daß Inder "Kaukasier" waren 
und daß Anthropologen sie betrachteten, vom gleichen Rennen wie 
weiße Amerikaner zu sein zu, aber argumentierte, daß "der 
durchschnittliche Mann tadellos Vertiefung kennt, daß es gibt 
unmißverständliche und profunde Unterschiede." Die Thind 
Entscheidung, die auch zu erfolgreiche Bemühungen geführt wird, 
denaturalize einige, die vorher gewordene Bürger hatten. Dieses
stellte eine bestimmte Drohung in Kalifornien dar, in dem ein Gesetz 
1913 die Ausländer verbot, die für Staatsbürgerschaft von 
besitzendem oder mietendem Land untauglich sind. Nur in 1946 tat
Kongreß, der anfing, zu erkennen, daß Indien bald unabhängig und 
eine Hauptweltenergie sein würde, verabschieden ein neues Gesetz, das
Indern erlaubte, Bürgern zu stehen und auch eine kleine 
Immigrationquote herstellte. Aber Hauptimmigration in die 
Vereinigten Staaten von Südasien fing nicht bis an, nachdem 
Immigrationgesetze scharf 1965 verbessert wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans sa décision dans le cas des ETATS-UNIS v. 
Bhagat Singh Thind (1923), la cour suprême a considéré les 
Indiens asiatiques inéligibles pour la citoyenneté parce que la loi 
des ETATS-UNIS a permis seulement à des blancs libres de aller bien 
aux citoyens naturalisés. La cour a concédé que les Indiens 
étaient des "Caucasiens" et que les anthropologues les ont 
considérés être de la même course que les Américains blancs, mais
a argué du fait que "l'homme moyen connaît parfaitement le puits 
qu'il y a des différences indubitables et profondes." La 
décision de Thind également menée aux efforts réussis denaturalize
qui ont eu les citoyens précédemment devenus. Ceci a 
représenté une menace particulière en Californie, où une loi 1913 
a interdit des étrangers inéligibles pour la citoyenneté de la 
terre de possession ou de location. Seulement dans 1946 a fait 
le congrès, qui commençait à identifier que l'Inde serait bientôt 
indépendante et une puissance importante du monde, passent une 
nouvelle loi qui a permis à des Indiens de aller bien à des citoyens
et a également établi une petite quote-part d'immigration. 
Mais l'immigration principale vers les Etats-Unis d'Asie 
Du sud n'a pas commencé jusqu'à ce qu'après que des lois 
d'immigration aient été brusquement mises à jour en 1965.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em sua decisão no exemplo de ESTADOS UNIDOS v. 
Bhagat Singh Thind (1923), a corte suprema julgou indians asian 
inelegíveis para o citizenship porque a lei de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
permitiu que somente os brancos livres assentassem bem em cidadãos 
naturalizados. A corte conceded que os indians eram "caucasians"
e que os antropólogos os consideraram ser da mesma raça que os 
americanos brancos, mas discutiu que "o homem médio sabe 
perfeitamente o poço que há umas diferenças unmistakable e 
profundas." A decisão de Thind conduzida também aos esforços 
bem sucedidos denaturalize alguns que tiveram cidadãos previamente 
tornados. Isto representou uma ameaça particular em 
Califórnia, onde uma lei 1913 proibiu os estrangeiros inelegíveis 
para o citizenship da terra possuindo ou de aluguel. Somente em 
1946 fêz o congress, que estava começando a reconhecer que India 
seria logo independente e uma potência principal do mundo, passam uma
lei nova que permitisse que os indians se transformassem cidadãos e 
estabelecesse também um quota pequeno do immigration. Mas o 
immigration principal aos estados unidos de 3sul da Ásia não 
começou até que depois que as leis do immigration foram revisadas 
agudamente em 1965.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella relativa decisione nel caso degli STATI 
UNITI v. Bhagat Singh Thind (1923), la Corte suprema ha ritenuto
gli indiani asiatici ineleggibili per la cittadinanza perché la legge
degli STATI UNITI ha permesso che soltanto i bianchi liberi stessero 
bene ai cittadini naturalizzati. La corte ha concesso che gli 
indiani erano "caucasians" e che gli antropologi li hanno considerati 
essere della stessa corsa degli Americani bianchi, ma ha sostenuto che
"l'uomo medio conosce perfettamente il pozzo che ci sono differenze 
inequivocabili e profonde." La decisione di Thind anche condotta
agli sforzi riusciti denaturalize alcuni che abbiano avuti cittadini 
precedentemente diventati. Ciò ha rappresentato una minaccia 
particolare nella California, in cui una legge 1913 ha proibito gli 
stranieri ineleggibili per la cittadinanza da terra possedente o di 
leasing. Soltanto in 1946 ha fatto il congresso, che stava 
cominciando a riconoscere che l'India presto sarebbe indipendente e 
un'potenza importante del mondo, approvano una nuova legge che ha 
permesso che gli indiani diventassero cittadini ed egualmente che ha 
stabilito una piccola quota di immigrazione. Ma l'immigrazione 
principale al unito Non dichiara da Asia del Sud non ha 
cominciato fino a che dopo che le leggi di immigrazione siano state 
modificate acutamente in 1965.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην απόφασή του στην περίπτωση των ΗΠΑ β. Το 
Bhagat Singh Thind (1923), το ανώτατο δικαστήριο έκρινε
ασιατικούς Ινδούς μη εκλέξιμους για την υπηκοότητα επειδή ο 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ νόμος επέτρεψε μόνο στα ελεύθερα λευκά για να γίνει
πολιτογραφημένοι πολίτες. Το δικαστήριο παραδέχθηκε ότι 
Ινδοί ήταν "Καυκάσιοι" και ότι οι ανθρωπολόγοι τους θεώρησαν της
ίδιας φυλής με λευκούς Αμερικανούς, αλλά υποστήριξε ότι "το 
μέσο άτομο ξέρει τέλεια καλά ότι υπάρχουν καταφανείς και 
βαθιές διαφορές." Η απόφαση Thind που οδηγείται επίσης 
στις επιτυχείς προσπάθειες μερικές που είχαν γίνει προηγουμένως 
πολίτες. Αυτό αντιπροσώπευσε μια ιδιαίτερη απειλή σε 
Καλιφόρνια, όπου ένας νόμος του 1913 απαγόρευσε τους 
αλλοδαπούς μη εκλέξιμους για την υπηκοότητα από την ιδιοκτησία ή
τη μίσθωση του εδάφους. Μόνο το 1946 έκανε το συνέδριο, 
που άρχιζε να αναγνωρίζει ότι η Ινδία θα ήταν σύντομα 
ανεξάρτητη και μια σημαντική παγκόσμια δύναμη, να περάσει έναν 
νέο νόμο ότι Ινδοί για να γίνει πολίτες και καθιέρωσε επίσης 
μια μικρή ποσόστωση μετανάστευσης. Αλλά σημαντική 
μετανάστευση Πολιτεία από τη Νότια Ασία δεν άρχισε μέχρι 
αναθεωρήθηκαν αισθητά οι νόμοι μετανάστευσης το 1965.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En su decisión en el caso de ESTADOS UNIDOS v. 
Bhagat Singh Thind (1923), el Tribunal Supremo juzgaba a indios 
asiáticos inelegibles para la ciudadanía porque la ley de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS permitió que solamente sintieran bien los blancos libres a 
ciudadanos naturalizados. La corte concedió que los indios eran
"caucásicos" y que los antropólogos los consideraban estar de la 
misma raza que los americanos blancos, pero discutió que "el hombre 
medio sepa perfectamente el receptor de papel que hay diferencias 
inequívocas y profundas." La decisión de Thind también 
conducida a los esfuerzos acertados denaturalize a algunos que tenían
ciudadanos previamente convertidos. Esto representó una amenaza
determinada en California, en donde una ley 1913 prohibió a 
extranjeros inelegibles para la ciudadanía de pista que poseía o de 
renta. Solamente en 1946 hizo a congreso, que comenzaba a 
reconocer que la India pronto sería independiente y una potencia 
importante del mundo, aprueban una nueva ley que permitió que los 
indios hicieran ciudadanos y también estableció un contingente 
pequeño de la inmigración. Pero la inmigración importante a 
los Estados Unidos de Asia del Sur no comenzó hasta que después de 
que los leyes de la inmigración fueran revisados sostenidamente en 
1965.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086676</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105492</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/not-all-caucasians-are-white-the-supreme-court-rejects-citizenship-for-asian-indians</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
