<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/213609569</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>213609569</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206535</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology of Energy Balance: Calorie Intake and Physical Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie der Energie-Balance: 
Kalorie-Einlaß und körperliche Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie de bilan énergétique :
Prise de calorie et activité physique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia do contrapeso de energia: 
Entrada do calorie e atividade física</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia del bilancio energetico: 
Presa di caloria ed attività fisica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία της ενεργειακής ισορροπίας: 
Λήψη θερμίδας και σωματική δραστηριότητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología del balance energético: 
Producto de la caloría y actividad física</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps us strive toward energy balance. Lessons and activities reveal what energy is, how our bodies use it, how we spend our time, how serving sizes on food labels compare with the amounts of food we eat, and how many calories are associated with various foods. Students analyze data and design experiments to learn how genetics, food availability, and exercise affect weight changes in mice.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">hilft uns, in Richtung zur Energiebalance sich zu 
bemühen. Lektionen und Aktivitäten decken auf, was Energie 
ist, wie unsere Körper sie verwenden, wie wir unsere Zeit verbringen,
wie dienende Größen auf Nahrungsmittelkennsätzen mit den Mengen der
Nahrung vergleichen, essen wir, und wieviele Kalorien auf verschiedene
Nahrungsmittel beziehen. Kursteilnehmer analysieren Daten- und 
Designexperimente, um zu erlernen, wie Genetik, 
Nahrungsmittelverwendbarkeit und Übung Gewichtänderungen in den 
Mäusen beeinflussen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">nous aide à tâcher vers le bilan énergétique. 
Les leçons et les activités indiquent ce qu'est l'énergie, 
comment nos corps l'utilisent, comment nous passons notre temps, 
comment les tailles servantes sur des étiquettes de nourriture 
rivalisent avec les quantités de nourriture nous mangeons, et combien
de calories sont associées à de diverses nourritures. Les 
étudiants analysent des expériences de données et de conception 
pour apprendre comment la génétique, la disponibilité de 
nourriture, et l'exercice affectent des changements de poids des 
souris.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ajuda-nos strive para o contrapeso de energia. 
As lições e as atividades revelam o que a energia é, como 
nossos corpos o usam, como nós gastamos nosso tempo, como os tamanhos
servindo em etiquetas do alimento comparam com as quantidades de 
alimento nós comemos, e quantos calories são associados com os 
vários alimentos. Os estudantes analisam experiências dos 
dados e do projeto para aprender como os genetics, a disponibilidade 
do alimento, e o exercício afetam mudanças do peso nos ratos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">li aiuta a sforzarsi verso il bilancio energetico.
Le lezioni e le attività rivelano che cosa l'energia è, come i
nostri corpi lo usano, come spendiamo il nostro tempo, come i 
formati serventi sulle etichette dell'alimento paragonano agli importi
di alimento mangiamo e quante calorie sono associate con i vari 
alimenti. Gli allievi analizzano gli esperimenti di disegno e di
dati per imparare come la genetica, la disponibilità dell'alimento e 
l'esercitazione interessano i cambiamenti del peso in mouse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μας βοηθά να προσπαθήσουμε προς την ενεργειακή 
ισορροπία. Τα μαθήματα και οι δραστηριότητες αποκαλύπτουν 
ποια ενέργεια είναι, πώς οι οργανισμοί μας το χρησιμοποιούν, πώς
ξοδεύουμε το χρόνο μας, πώς τα εξυπηρετώντας μεγέθη στις 
ετικέτες τροφίμων συγκρίνουν με τα ποσά τροφίμων τρώμε, και 
πόσες θερμίδες συνδέονται με τα διάφορα τρόφιμα. Οι 
σπουδαστές αναλύουν τα πειράματα στοιχείων και σχεδίου για να 
μάθουν πώς η γενετική, η διαθεσιμότητα τροφίμων, και η άσκηση 
έχουν επιπτώσεις στις αλλαγές βάρους στα ποντίκια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">nos ayuda a esforzarse hacia balance energético. 
Las lecciones y las actividades revelan cuáles es la energía, 
cómo nuestros cuerpos lo utilizan, cómo pasamos nuestro tiempo, 
cómo las tallas que sirven en escrituras de la etiqueta del alimento 
comparan con las cantidades de alimento comemos, y cuántas calorías 
se asocian a los varios alimentos. Los estudiantes analizan 
experimentos de los datos y del diseño para aprender cómo las 
genéticas, la disponibilidad del alimento, y el ejercicio afectan 
cambios del peso en ratones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206535</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>213609569</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/science-and-technology-of-energy-balance-calorie-intake-and-physical-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
