<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103408</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103408</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212642</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Microbial Genome Program: Organisms in the Program: Complete and in Progress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Mikrobengenom-Programm: Organismen im 
Programm: Komplett und in Bewegung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Programme Microbien de Génome : 
Organizations dans le programme : Complet et en marche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Programa Microbial Do Genome: Organismos 
no programa: Completo e em andamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Programma Microbico Del Genome: Organismi
nel programma: Completo ed in progresso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μικροβιακό πρόγραμμα γονιδιώματος: Οργανισμοί
στο πρόγραμμα: Πλήρης και υπό εξέλιξη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Programa Microbiano Del Genoma: 
Organismos en el programa: Completo y en marcha</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website houses The Microbial Genome Program, genomic sequence data of bacteria studied by the U.S. Department of Energy (DOE). Microbes of interest are those involved in carbon sequestration, nitrification, energy production, bioremediation, metal reduction, cellulose degradation, biotechnology and applied microbiology, and microbial consortia. Microbes of interest are those involved in carbon sequestration, nitrification, energy production, bioremediation, metal reduction, cellulose degradation, biotechnology and applied microbiology, and microbial consortia. Links to other DOE research and interests can be found in the margins of the home page.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site bringt das Mikrobengenom-Programm, 
genomic Reihenfolge Daten des Bakteriums unter, das durch die 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Abteilung von Energie (DAMHIRSCHKUH) studiert wird.
Mikroben des Interesses sind die, die in Carbonabsonderung, 
Nitrierung, Energieproduktion, bioremediation, Metallverkleinerung, 
Zelluloseverminderung, Biotechnologie und angewendete Mikrobiologie 
und Mikrobenvereinigungen mit einbezogen werden. Mikroben des 
Interesses sind die, die in Carbonabsonderung, Nitrierung, 
Energieproduktion, bioremediation, Metallverkleinerung, 
Zelluloseverminderung, Biotechnologie und angewendete Mikrobiologie 
und Mikrobenvereinigungen mit einbezogen werden. Links zu 
anderer DAMHIRSCHKUH-Forschung und Interessen können in den 
Seitenrändern des Home Page gefunden werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web loge le programme microbien de 
génome, données genomic d'ordre des bactéries étudiées par le 
ministère de l'énergie des ETATS-UNIS (DAINE). Les microbes 
d'intérêt sont ceux impliqués dans la séquestration de carbone, la
nitrification, la production énergétique, le bioremediation, la 
réduction en métal, la dégradation de cellulose, la biotechnologie 
et la microbiologie appliquée, et les consortiums microbiens. 
Les microbes d'intérêt sont ceux impliqués dans la 
séquestration de carbone, la nitrification, la production 
énergétique, le bioremediation, la réduction en métal, la 
dégradation de cellulose, la biotechnologie et la microbiologie 
appliquée, et les consortiums microbiens. Des liens à l'autre 
recherche de DAINE et les intérêts peuvent être trouvés dans les 
marges du Home Page.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site abriga o programa microbial do 
genome, dados genomic da seqüência das bactérias estudadas pelo 
departamento de ESTADOS UNIDOS de energia (CORÇA). Os 
micróbios do interesse são aqueles envolvidos no sequestration do 
carbono, o nitrification, a produção de energia, o bioremediation, a
redução do metal, a degradação da celulose, o biotechnology e 
microbiology aplicado, e consortia microbial. Os micróbios do 
interesse são aqueles envolvidos no sequestration do carbono, o 
nitrification, a produção de energia, o bioremediation, a redução 
do metal, a degradação da celulose, o biotechnology e microbiology 
aplicado, e consortia microbial. As ligações à outra pesquisa
da CORÇA e os interesses podem ser encontrados nas margens do Home 
Page.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site alloggia il programma microbico 
del genome, dati genomic di sequenza dei batteri studiati dal 
Dipartimento per l'energia degli STATI UNITI (DAINA). I microbi 
di interesse sono quelli coinvolgere nel sequestro del carbonio, 
nitrificazione, produzione di energia, bioremediation, riduzione del 
metallo, degradazione della cellulosa, la biotecnologia e 
microbiologia applicata e consorzi microbici. I microbi di 
interesse sono quelli coinvolgere nel sequestro del carbonio, 
nitrificazione, produzione di energia, bioremediation, riduzione del 
metallo, degradazione della cellulosa, la biotecnologia e 
microbiologia applicata e consorzi microbici. I collegamenti 
all'altra ricerca della DAINA e gli interessi possono essere trovati 
nei margini del Home Page.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος στεγάζει το μικροβιακό πρόγραμμα 
γονιδιώματος, genomic στοιχεία ακολουθίας των βακτηριδίων που 
μελετώνται από το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ τμήμα ενέργειας (DOE). _ 
μικρόβιο ενδιαφέρον είμαι εκείνος περι:λαμβάνω άνθρακας 
απομάκρυνση, νιτροποίηση, ενέργεια παραγωγή, βιοθεραπεία, 
μέταλλο μείωση, κυτταρίνη υποβάθμιση, βιοτεχνολογία και εφαρμόζω
μικροβιολογία, και μικροβιακός κοινοπραξία. _ μικρόβιο 
ενδιαφέρον είμαι εκείνος περι:λαμβάνω άνθρακας απομάκρυνση, 
νιτροποίηση, ενέργεια παραγωγή, βιοθεραπεία, μέταλλο μείωση, 
κυτταρίνη υποβάθμιση, βιοτεχνολογία και εφαρμόζω μικροβιολογία, 
και μικροβιακός κοινοπραξία. Οι συνδέσεις με άλλη έρευνα 
DOE και τα ενδιαφέροντα μπορούν να βρεθούν στα περιθώρια της 
αρχικής σελίδας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site contiene el programa microbiano del 
Genoma, datos genomic de la secuencia de las bacterias estudiadas 
por el Ministerio de ESTADOS UNIDOS de Energía (GAMA). Los 
microbios del interés son ésos implicados en el secuestro del 
carbón, nitrificación, producción energética, bioremediation, 
reducción del metal, degradación de la celulosa, biotecnología y 
microbiología aplicada, y los consorcios microbianos. Los 
microbios del interés son ésos implicados en el secuestro del 
carbón, nitrificación, producción energética, bioremediation, 
reducción del metal, degradación de la celulosa, biotecnología y 
microbiología aplicada, y los consorcios microbianos. Las 
conexiones a la otra investigación de la GAMA y los intereses se 
pueden encontrar en los márgenes del Home Page.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:U.S. DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY MICROBIAL GENOME PROGRAM
FN:U.S. DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY MICROBIAL GENOME PROGRAM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DOEGENOMES.ORG
FN:DOEGENOMES.ORG
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212642</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103408</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-microbial-genome-program-organisms-in-the-program-complete-and-in-progress</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
