<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106008</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106008</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205775</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sir Anthony Van Dyck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sir Anthony Van Dyck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Monsieur Anthony Van Dyck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Senhor Anthony Camionete Dyck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sir Anthony Van Dyck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Sir Anthony Van Dyck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sir Anthony Van Dyck</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">shows paintings and descriptions of the National Gallery of Art's holdings of the famous Flemish painter. According to the Gallery, With elaborate settings, symbolic accessories, and suggestions of movement, Van Dyck made his models seem at once grand and alive, inaugurating a style of formal portraiture that is still emulated today.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erscheinenanstriche und Beschreibungen der 
nationalen Galerie der Holdings der kunst des berühmten flämischen 
Malers. Entsprechend der Galerie mit durchdachten Einstellungen,
symbolischen Zusatzgeräten und Vorschlägen der Bewegung, ließ Van 
Dyck seine Modelle großartig und lebendig sofort scheinen und 
eröffnete eine Art des formalen portraiture, das noch heute emuliert 
wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">peintures d'expositions et descriptions de la 
galerie nationale des possessions de l'art du peintre flamand 
célèbre. Selon la galerie, avec les configurations raffinées,
les accessoires symboliques, et les suggestions du mouvement, Van Dyck
a fait ses modèles sembler immédiatement grands et vivants, 
inaugurant un modèle de l'art du portrait formel qui est encore émulé 
aujourd'hui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">pinturas das mostras e descrições da galeria 
nacional de terras arrendadas da arte do pintor flemish famoso. 
De acordo com a galeria, com ajustes elaborados, os acessórios 
simbólicos, e as sugestões do movimento, Camionete Dyck fêz seus 
modelos parecer em uma vez que grande e vivo, inaugurating um estilo 
do portraiture formal que é emulado ainda hoje.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">pitture di esposizioni e descrizioni della 
galleria nazionale delle azioni dell'arte del pittore fiammingo 
famoso. Secondo la galleria, con le regolazioni elaborate, gli 
accessori simbolici ed i suggerimenti di movimento, Van Dyck ha fatto 
i suoi modelli sembrare immediatamente grandi e vivi, inaugurando uno 
stile del portraiture convenzionale che ancora è emulato oggi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εμφανίζει τα έργα ζωγραφικής και περιγραφές της 
εθνικής στοάς των μετοχών της τέχνης του διάσημου φλαμανδικού 
ζωγράφου. Σύμφωνα με τη στοά, με τις επιμελημένες τιμές των
παραμέτρων, τα συμβολικά εξαρτήματα, και τις προτάσεις της 
μετακίνησης, Van Dyck έκανε τα μοντέλα του να φανούν αμέσως
μεγάλα και ζωντανά, εγκαινιάζοντας ένα ύφος του επίσημου 
πορτρέτου που εξομοιώνεται ακόμα σήμερα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">pinturas de las demostraciones y descripciones de 
la galería nacional de las tenencias del arte del pintor flamenco 
famoso. Según la galería, con las configuraciones elaboradas, 
los accesorios simbólicos, y las sugerencias del movimiento, Van Dyck
hizo que sus modelos se parecen inmediatamente magníficos y vivos, 
inaugurando un estilo del portraiture formal que todavía se emula 
hoy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205775</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106008</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sir-anthony-van-dyck</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
