<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105574</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105574</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207101</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sleep, Sleep Disorders, and Biological Rhythms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schlaf, Schlaf-Störungen und biologische 
Rhythmen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sommeil, désordres de sommeil, et rythmes 
biologiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sono, disorders do sono, e ritmos biológicos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sonno, disordini di sonno e ritmi biologici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ύπνος, αναταραχές ύπνου, και βιολογικοί ρυθμοί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sueño, desórdenes del sueño, y ritmos 
biológicos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students understand basic scientific principles related to the nature and function of sleep and its effects on human health. Lessons focus on the biology of sleep and its relationship to health, sleep states and the dynamic nature of sleep, biological clocks, sleep hygiene and disorders, and sleep loss and consequences.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer verstehen die grundlegenden 
wissenschaftlichen Grundregeln, die auf der Natur und die Funktion des
Schlafes und seine Effekte auf menschliche Gesundheit in Verbindung 
gestanden werden. Lektionen konzentrieren auf die Biologie des 
Schlafes und sein Verhältnis zur Gesundheit, Schlafzustände und die 
dynamische Natur des Schlafes, biologische Uhren, Schlafhygiene und 
-störungen und Schlafverlust und -konsequenzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les étudiants d'aides comprennent des principes 
scientifiques de base liés à la nature et la fonction du sommeil et 
ses effets sur la santé humaine. Les leçons se concentrent sur
la biologie du sommeil et son rapport avec la santé, les états de 
sommeil et la nature dynamique du sommeil, les horloges biologiques, 
l'hygiène et les désordres de sommeil, et la perte et les 
conséquences de sommeil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os estudantes das ajudas compreendem os 
princípios científicos básicos relacionados à natureza e a 
função do sono e seus efeitos na saúde humana. As lições 
focalizam na biologia do sono e seu relacionamento à saúde, os 
estados do sono e a natureza dinâmica do sono, pulsos de disparo 
biológicos, higiene e disorders do sono, e perda e conseqüências do
sono.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli allievi di aiuti capiscono i principii 
scientifici fondamentali relativi alla natura e la funzione di sonno 
ed i relativi effetti su salute umana. Le lezioni mettono a 
fuoco sulla biologia di sonno ed il relativo rapporto a salute, sonno 
dichiara e la natura dinamica di sonno, orologi biologici, 
l'igiene e disordini di sonno e perdita e conseguenze di sonno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν τις βασικές 
επιστημονικές αρχές σχετικές με τη φύση και τη λειτουργία του 
ύπνου και τα αποτελέσματά του στην ανθρώπινη υγεία. Τα 
μαθήματα εστιάζουν στη βιολογία του ύπνου και της σχέσης του στην
υγεία, τις καταστάσεις ύπνου και τη δυναμική φύση του ύπνου, τα 
βιολογικά ρολόγια, την υγιεινή και τις αναταραχές ύπνου, και την 
απώλεια και τις συνέπειες ύπνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los estudiantes de las ayudas entienden los 
principios científicos básicos relacionados con la naturaleza y la 
función del sueño y sus efectos sobre salud humana. Las 
lecciones se centran en la biología del sueño y su lazo a la salud, 
los estados del sueño y la naturaleza dinámica del sueño, los 
relojes biológicos, higiene y los desórdenes del sueño, y pérdida 
y las consecuencias del sueño.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207101</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105574</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sleep-sleep-disorders-and-biological-rhythms</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
