<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108078</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108078</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087231</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"When We Worked on Shares, We Couldn't Make Nothing": Henry Blake Talks About Sharecropping after the Civil War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"als wir auf Anteilen arbeiteten, könnten wir 
nicht nichts bilden": Henry Blake befaßt sich mit Sharecropping
nach dem Bürgerkrieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"quand nous avons travaillé aux parts, nous ne 
pourrions pas ne faire rien" : Henry Blake parle du métayage 
après la guerre civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"quando nós trabalhamos em partes, nós não 
poderíamos não fazer nada": O Henry Blake fala sobre o 
sharecropping após a guerra civil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"quando abbiamo lavorato alle parti, non potremmo 
non fare niente": Colloqui di Blake di henry circa mezzadria 
dopo la guerra civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όταν εργαστήκαμε στις μετοχές, δεν θα μπορούσαμε να 
κάνουμε τίποτα": Θ*Χενρυ Blake Talks About 
Sharecropping μετά από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cuando trabajamos en las partes, no podríamos 
hacer nada": El Henrio Blake habla de aparcería después de la 
guerra civil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In some ways, emancipation and Reconstruction broke the power of white southern planters over their labor force. Freedpeople negotiated with planters over how the land would be cultivated and how they would be compensated. African-American families worked small plots independently, sometimes obtaining land for cash or, more commonly, for a fixed share of the year's crop; this latter practice was known as sharecropping. By 1870, sharecropping was the dominant means by which African Americans could gain access to land in the South. Still, freedpeople desired independent proprietorship. In this interview, African-American farmer Henry Blake recalls how black land ownership became an elusive goal as unequal power relations between white and black hardened and the Ku Klux Klan's terrorist campaigns increased. Blake's narrative and many others were recorded during an ambitious New Deal (1936-38) program of interviews with ex-slaves. Despite unfamiliar interviewers and distant memories, these first person accounts are an unparalleled resource.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Irgendwie brachen Emanzipation und Rekonstruktion 
die Energie der weißen südlichen Pflanzer über ihren 
Arbeitskräften. Freedpeople vermittelte mit 
Pflanzerüberschuß, wie das Land kultiviert würde und wie sie 
ausgeglichen würden. Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Familien 
bearbeiteten kleine Plots unabhängig und manchmal erreichten Land 
für Bargeld oder häufiger für einen örtlich festgelegten Anteil 
des Getreides des Jahres; diese letzte Praxis bekannt als 
Sharecropping. Bis zum 1870 war Sharecropping die dominierenden 
Mittel, durch die afrikanische Amerikaner Zutritt erhalten konnten, um
im Süden zu landen. Noch wünschte freedpeople unabhängigen 
Eigentumsrecht. dieses Interviews erhöhten sich 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Landwirt Henry Blake Rückrufe, wie 
schwarzer Landbesitz ein schwer bestimmbares Ziel als ungleiche 
Energie Relationen zwischen Weiß wurde und Schwarzes sich verhärtete
und das Ku Klux Klans Terroristdie kampagnen. Darstellung und 
viele andere Blakes wurden während eines ehrgeizigen (1936-38) 
Programms des neuen Abkommens von Interviews mit Exsklaven 
gespeichert. Trotz der nicht vertrauten Interviewer und der 
entfernten Speicher sind diese ersten Personkonten ein 
unvergleichliches Hilfsmittel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par certains côtés, l'émancipation et la 
reconstruction ont cassé la puissance des planteurs méridionaux 
blancs au-dessus de leur main-d'oeuvre. Freedpeople était en 
pourparlers avec l'excédent de planteurs comment la terre serait 
cultivée et comment elles seraient compensées. Les familles 
afro-américaines ont travaillé de petits traçages indépendamment, 
parfois obtenant la terre pour l'argent comptant ou, généralement, 
pour une part fixe de la collecte de l'année ; cette dernière 
pratique a été connue comme métayage. D'ici 1870, le 
métayage était les moyens dominants par lesquels les Américains 
africains pourraient accéder pour débarquer dans les Sud. 
Toujours, le freedpeople a désiré la propriété 
indépendante. Dans cette entrevue, les rappels afro-américains de 
Blake d'Henry de fermier comme la propriété terrienne noire est 
devenue un but évasif en tant que relations inégales de puissance 
entre le blanc et le noir a durci et les campagnes de terroriste de Ku
Klux le Klan ont augmenté. Le récit et beaucoup d'autres de 
Blake ont été enregistrés pendant des 1936-38) programmes ambitieux
de nouvelle affaire (des entrevues avec des ex-esclaves. En 
dépit des interviewers peu familiers et des mémoires éloignées, 
ces premiers comptes de personne sont une ressource inégalée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em algumas maneiras, o emancipation e o 
reconstruction quebraram a potência dos plantadores do sul brancos 
sobre sua força labor. Freedpeople negociou com o excesso dos 
plantadores como a terra seria cultivada e como seriam compensados. 
As famílias Africano-Americanas trabalharam lotes pequenos 
independentemente, às vezes obtendo a terra para o dinheiro ou, mais 
geralmente, para uma parte fixa da colheita do ano; esta última
prática foi sabida como o sharecropping. Por 1870, o 
sharecropping era os meios dominantes por que os americanos africanos 
poderiam ganhar o acesso à terra no sul. Ainda, o freedpeople 
desejou o proprietorship independente. Nesta entrevista, as 
recordações Africano-Americanas de Blake do Henry do fazendeiro como
a posse de terra preta se transformou um objetivo elusive como 
relações desiguais da potência entre o branco e o preto se 
endureceu e as campanhas do terrorista de Ku Klux o Klan aumentaram. 
Muita outra de Blake a narrativa e foram gravadas durante uns 
1936-38) programas ambicioso do negócio novo (das entrevistas com 
ex-escravos. Apesar dos interviewers estranhos e das memórias 
distantes, estes primeiros clientes da pessoa são um recurso 
unparalleled.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per alcuni versi, l'emancipazione e la 
ricostruzione hanno rotto l'potenza delle piantatrici del sud bianche 
sopra la loro forza di lavoro. Freedpeople ha negoziato con 
l'eccedenza delle piantatrici come la terra si coltiverebbe e come 
sarebbero compensate. Le famiglie Africano-Americane hanno 
lavorato indipendentemente i piccoli diagrammi, a volte ottenendo la 
terra per contanti o, più conunemente, per una parte fissa del 
raccolto dell'anno; questa pratica posteriore è stata 
conosciuta come mezzadria. Entro 1870, la mezzadria era i mezzi 
dominanti da cui gli Americani africani potrebbero accedere per 
atterrare nel sud. Eppure, il freedpeople ha voluto la 
proprietà indipendente. di questa intervista, i richiami 
Africano-Americani di Blake di henry del coltivatore come la 
proprietà terriera nera si è transformata in in un obiettivo evasivo
come rapporti disuguali di potenza fra il bianco ed il nero si è 
indurito e le campagne del terrorista di Ku Klux il Klan sono 
aumentato. La descrizione e molti altre del Blake sono state 
registrate durante i 1936-38) programmi ambizioso di nuovo affare 
(delle interviste con gli ex-schiavi. Malgrado gli 
intervistatori non pratici e le memorie distanti, questi primi clienti
della persona sono una risorsa senza pari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με κάποιους τρόπους, η χειραφέτηση και η 
αναδημιουργία έσπασαν τη δύναμη των λευκών νότιων καλλιεργητών 
πέρα από το εργατικό δυναμικό τους. Το Freedpeople 
διαπραγματεύτηκε με τους καλλιεργητές πέρα από το πώς το έδαφος 
θα καλλιεργούταν και το πώς θα αντισταθμίζονταν. 
Αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά οι οικογένειες απασχολήθηκαν στις 
μικρές πλοκές ανεξάρτητα, λαμβάνοντας μερικές φορές το έδαφος 
για τα μετρητά ή, συχνότερα, για ένα σταθερό μερίδιο της 
συγκομιδής του έτους  αυτή η τελευταία πρακτική ήταν 
γνωστή ως sharecropping. Από 1870, sharecropping 
ήταν ο κυρίαρχος τρόπος με τον οποίο αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί θα 
μπορούσαν να αποκτήσουν πρόσβαση στο έδαφος στο νότο. 
Ακόμα, freedpeople επιθυμητή ανεξάρτητη ιδιοκτησία. 
Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη, ο αφρικανικός-αμερικανικός αγρότης
Henry Blake υπενθυμίζει πώς η μαύρη ιδιοκτησία εδάφους 
έγινε ένας αόριστος στόχος ως άνισες σχέσεις δύναμης μεταξύ 
άσπρου και του Μαύρου σκλήραινε και οι τρομοκρατικές εκστρατείες 
Ku Klux Klan αυξήθηκαν. Το αφήγημα του Blake και 
πολλά άλλα καταγράφηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια ενός φιλόδοξου νέου 
προγράμματος διαπραγμάτευσης (1936-38) των συνεντεύξεων με τους 
πρώην-σκλάβους. Παρά τους άγνωστους ερευνητές και τις 
απόμακρες μνήμες, αυτοί οι πρώτοι απολογισμοί προσώπων είναι 
ένα ασύγκριτο στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Algunas maneras, la emancipación y la 
reconstrucción adaptaron la potencia de los plantadores meridionales 
blancos sobre su mano de obra. Freedpeople negoció con el 
excedente de los plantadores cómo la pista sería cultivada y cómo 
serían compensadas. Las familias Africano-Americanas trabajaron
diagramas pequeños independientemente, a veces obteniendo la pista 
para el efectivo o, más comunmente, para una parte fija de la cosecha
del año; esta última práctica era conocida como aparcería. 
Antes de 1870, la aparcería era los medios dominantes por los 
cuales los americanos africanos podrían acceder para aterrizar en el 
sur. No obstante, el freedpeople deseó propiedad independiente. 
De esta entrevista, memorias Africano-Americanas de Blake del 
Henrio del granjero cómo la propiedad de terreno negra se convirtió 
en una meta evasiva como relaciones desiguales de la potencia entre el
blanco y el negro endureció y las campañas del terrorista de Ku Klux
el Klan aumentaron. La narrativa y muchos otras de Blake fueron 
registradas durante 1936-38) programas ambicioso del nuevo reparto (de
entrevistas con los ex-esclavos. A pesar de entrevistadores 
desconocedores y memorias distantes, estas primeras cuentas de la 
persona son un recurso sin par.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087231</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108078</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/when-we-worked-on-shares-we-couldnt-make-nothing-henry-blake-talks-about-sharecropping-after-the-civil-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
