<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106026</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106026</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087338</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Show of Support: Farmers Feed Homestead Strikers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Erscheinen des Supports: 
Landwirt-Zufuhr-Gehöft-Schlaggeräte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une exposition de support : Butées de Ferme
d'Alimentation de Fermiers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma mostra da sustentação: Grevistas Do 
Homestead Da Alimentação Dos Fazendeiros</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un'esposizione di supporto: Percussori Della
Fattoria Dell'Alimentazione Dei Coltivatori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια επίδειξη της υποστήριξης: Οι αγρότες 
ταϊ'ζουν τους απεργούς αγροτικών σπιτιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una demostración de la ayuda: Huelguistas 
De la Granja De la Alimentación De los Granjeros</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1892 the possibility of a Labor-Populist alliance circulated. Populist orators like Mary Lease sought to build ties between the Farmer's Alliance and the labor movement by mobilizing farmers to send wheat and corn to striking workers at Carnegie's Homestead steel mill outside Pittsburgh. Despite the support for such an alliance among many in the labor movement, American Federation of Labor leader Samuel Gompers opposed such political action. Gompers insured that the A.F.L maintained, in his words, "a masterly inactivity" on political involvements. In this appeal to Kansas farmers, published as a letter to the editor in the Topeka  Advocate , Lease attacked the "misrepresentations" of those who claimed that farmers did not understand and sympathize with workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In 1892 verteilte die Möglichkeit eines 
BearbeitenVolksbündnisses. Volksredner wie Mary Miete suchten, 
Gleichheit zwischen dem Bündnis des Landwirts und der 
Arbeiterbewegung durch mobilisierende Landwirte aufzubauen, um Weizen 
und Mais am Gehöft-Stahltausendstel äußeres Pittsburgh zu schicken 
auffallenden Arbeitern Carnegies. Trotz des Supports für solch 
ein Bündnis unter vielen in der Arbeiterbewegung, setzte 
amerikanische Vereinigung des Gewerkschaftsführers Samuel Gompers 
solcher politischer Tätigkeit entgegen. Gompers versicherte, 
daß das A.F.L, in seinen Wörtern, "eine Vorlagen- Untätigkeit" auf 
politischen Miteinbeziehungen beibehielt. In diesem Anklang an 
die Kansas Landwirte, veröffentlicht, da ein Leserbrief im Topeka 
Fürsprecher, angegriffen den "Misrepresentations" von denen mieten, 
die behaupteten, daß Landwirte nicht mit Arbeitern verstanden und 
sympathisierten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1892 la possibilité d'une alliance 
Travailler-Populiste a circulé. Les orateurs populistes comme 
le bail de Mary ont recherché à construire des cravates entre 
l'alliance du fermier et le mouvement de travail par les fermiers de 
mobilisation pour envoyer le blé et le maïs aux ouvriers saisissants
à l'aciérie Pittsburgh extérieur de la ferme de Carnegie's. 
En dépit du soutien d'une telle alliance parmi beaucoup dans le
mouvement de travail, la fédération américaine du dirigeant 
syndical Samuel Gompers s'est opposée à un tel action politique. 
Gompers a assuré que l'A.F.L a mis à jour, dans ses mots, 
"magistralement une inactivité" sur des participations politiques. 
Dans cet appel aux fermiers du Kansas, édités car une lettre 
à l'éditeur dans l'avocat de Topeka, louent attaqué les "fausses 
déclarations" de ceux qui ont réclamé que les fermiers n'ont pas 
compris et n'ont pas sympathisé avec des ouvriers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1892 a possibilidade de um alliance 
Trabalh-labor-Populist circulou. Os orators populist como o 
aluguer de Mary procuraram construir laços entre o alliance do 
fazendeiro e o movimento labor por fazendeiros mobilizing para emitir 
o trigo e o milho aos trabalhadores impressionantes no moinho de aço 
Pittsburgh exterior do homestead de Carnegie. Apesar da 
sustentação para tal alliance entre muitos no movimento labor, o 
federation americano do líder labor Samuel Gompers opôs tal ação 
política. Gompers segurou que o A.F.L manteve, em suas 
palavras, "mestra um inactivity" em participações políticas. 
Nesta apelação aos fazendeiros de Kansas, publicados porque 
uma letra ao editor no advogado do Topeka, aluga atacado os 
"misrepresentations" daqueles que reivindicaram que os fazendeiros 
não compreenderam e não sympathize com os trabalhadores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1892 la possibilità di alleanza di 
lavoro-populist ha circolato. I orators populistici come il 
contratto d'affitto della Mary hanno cercato di costruire i legami fra
l'alleanza del coltivatore ed il movimento di lavoro dai coltivatori 
di mobilitazione per trasmettere il frumento ed il cereale agli operai
notevoli all'acciaieria Pittsburgh esterna della fattoria del 
Carnegie. Malgrado il sostegno una tal alleanza fra molti nel 
movimento di lavoro, la federazione americana del capo 
Di lavoro Samuel Gompers ha opposto tale azione politica. 
Gompers ha assicurato che il A.F.L ha effettuato matrice, nelle 
sue parole, "un inactivity" sulle partecipazioni politiche. In 
questo appello ai coltivatori del Kansas, pubblicati poichè una 
lettera all'editore nel fautore de Topeka, affitta attacato "le 
dichiarazioni false" di coloro che ha sostenuto che i coltivatori non 
hanno capito e non sympathize con gli operai.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1892 η δυνατότητα μιας εργασία-λαϊκιστικής 
συμμαχίας που κυκλοφορούν. Οι λαϊκιστικοί ομιλητές όπως 
Mary Lease επιδίωξαν να χτίσουν τους δεσμούς μεταξύ της 
συμμαχίας του αγρότη και της μετακίνησης εργασίας με να 
κινητοποιήσουν τους αγρότες για να στείλουν το σίτο και το 
καλαμπόκι στους απεργούς εργαζομένους στο μύλο χάλυβα αγροτικών 
σπιτιών Carnegie έξω από το Πίτσμπουργκ. Παρά την 
υποστήριξη για μια τέτοια συμμαχία μεταξύ πολλών στη μετακίνηση 
εργασίας, η αμερικανική ομοσπονδία του ηγέτη Samuel Gompers 
εργασίας αντέταξε τέτοια πολιτική ενέργεια. Το Gompers 
ασφάλισε ότι το A.F.L διατήρησε, στις λέξεις του, "μια 
masterly αδράνεια" στις πολιτικές συμμετοχές. Σε αυτήν 
την έκκληση στους αγρότες του Κάνσας, που δημοσιεύθηκε ως 
επιστολή στον επεξεργαστή στο συνήγορο Topeka, η μίσθωση 
επιτέθηκε στις "διαστρευλώσεισ" εκείνοι που υποστήριξαν ότι οι 
αγρότες δεν κατάλαβαν και συμμερίζονται τους εργαζομένους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1892 la posibilidad de una alianza 
Trabajar-Populista circuló. Los oradores populistas como el 
arriendo de Maria intentaron construir lazos entre la alianza del 
granjero y el movimiento de trabajo por los granjeros de movilización
para enviar trigo y maíz a los trabajadores llamativos en el molino 
de acero Pittsburgh exterior de la granja de Carnegie. A pesar 
de la ayuda para tal alianza entre muchos en el movimiento de trabajo,
la federación americana del arranque de cinta de trabajo Samuel 
Gompers opuso tal acción política. Gompers aseguró que el 
A.F.L mantuvo, en sus palabras, "principal una inactividad" en 
implicaciones políticas. En esta súplica a los granjeros de 
Kansas, publicados pues una carta al editor en el abogado del Topeka, 
arrienda atacado las "malas representaciones" de los que demandaron 
que los granjeros no entendían y no se compadecieron de los 
trabajadores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087338</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106026</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-show-of-support-farmers-feed-homestead-strikers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
