<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107792</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107792</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086193</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Get on the Ground and We Will Kick Your Head In": A Reporter Tells of Terrorism in Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"erhalten Sie aus den Grund und wir treten Ihren 
Kopf in": Ein Reporter erklärt vom Terrorismus in Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"obtenez sur la terre et nous donnerons un coup de
pied votre tête dans" : Un journaliste raconte le terrorisme en
Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"comece na terra e nós retrocederemos sua cabeça
em": Um repórter diz do terrorismo em Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ottenga sulla terra e daremo dei calci alla 
vostra testa in": Un Reporter dice a di terrorismo 
nell'Alabama</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πάρτε στο έδαφος και θα κλωτσήσουμε το κεφάλι σασ": 
Ένας δημοσιογράφος λέει της τρομοκρατίας στην Αλαμπάμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"consiga en la tierra y golpearemos su cabeza con 
el pie en": Un reportero dice de terrorismo en Alabama</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Between 1882 and 1964, nearly five thousand people died from lynching, the majority African-American. The 1890s witnessed the worst period of lynching in U.S. history. The grim statistical record almost certainly understates the story. Many lynchings were not recorded outside their immediate locality, and pure numbers do not convey the brutality of lynching. Lynchings, often witnessed by large crowds of white onlookers, were the most extreme form of Southern white control over the African-American population, regularly meted out against African Americans who had been falsely charged with crimes but in fact were achieving a level of political or economic autonomy that whites found unacceptable. Lynching was especially prevalent in areas of low population density, recent increase in black population, and high rates of transiency, where strangers feared one another and whites judged legitimate law enforcement weak. As the following testimony by a Birmingham, Alabama, newspaper reporter to a 1949 House subcommittee shows, acts of violence by vigilante groups in the South were directed not only toward blacks. The virulently anti-Catholic, anti-Semitic, and anti-foreigner Ku Klux Klan of the 20th century violently attempted to impose its code of morality on men, women, and children who violated their beliefs of community norms.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zwischen 1882 und 1964 starben fast fünf tausend 
Leute am Lynchen, die Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Majorität. Das 
1890s zeugte die falschste Periode des Lynchens in der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Geschichte. Der grimmige statistische Satz understates 
fast zweifellos die Geschichte. Viele lynchings wurden nicht 
außerhalb ihrer sofortigen Stelle gespeichert, und reine Zahlen 
übermitteln nicht die Brutalitäten des Lynchens. Lynchings, 
häufig gezeugt von den großen Massen der weißen Zuschauer, waren 
das extremste Formular der südlichen weißen Steuerung über der 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Bevölkerung, regelmäßig ausgeteilt 
heraus gegen afrikanische Amerikaner, die falsch mit Verbrechen 
aufgeladen worden waren, aber tatsächlich erzielten eine Stufe der 
politischen oder ökonomischen Autonomie, daß Weiß nicht annehmbar 
fand. Das Lynchen war in den Bereichen der niedrigen 
Bevölkerung Dichte, neue Zunahme der schwarzen Bevölkerung besonders
überwiegend, und hohe Kinetik von transiency, in dem Fremde ein 
anderes ein und Weiß fürchteten, beurteilten gesetzmaßige 
Gesetzdurchführung schwach. Wie das folgende Zeugnis durch ein 
Birmingham, Alabama, Zeitungsreporter zu Erscheinen einer 1949 
Hausunterausschusses, Gewaltakte durch vigilante Gruppen im Süden 
nicht nur in Richtung zu den Schwarzen verwiesen wurden. Das 
giftig Anti-Katholische, das anti-Semitic und Anti-Ausländer Ku Klux 
Klan des 20. Jahrhunderts versuchten heftig, seinen Code des 
Sittlichkeitsgefühls Männern, Frauen und Kindern aufzuerlegen, die 
ihren Glauben der Gemeinschaftsnormen verletzten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entre 1882 et 1964, presque cinq mille personnes 
sont mortes de lyncher, l'Afro-Américain de majorité. Le 1890s 
était témoin de la plus mauvaise période de lyncher dans l'histoire
des ETATS-UNIS. L'enregistrement statistique sinistre minimise 
presque certainement l'histoire. Beaucoup de lynchings n'ont pas
été enregistrés en dehors de leur localité immédiate, et les 
nombres purs ne donnent pas la brutalité de lyncher. Lynchings,
souvent été témoin par de grandes foules des spectateurs blancs, 
étaient la forme la plus extrême du contrôle blanc méridional de 
la population afro-américaine, régulièrement distribuée dehors contre
les Américains africains qui avaient été faussement chargés des 
crimes mais en fait réalisaient un niveau d'autonomie politique ou 
économique que les blancs ont trouvé inacceptable. Lyncher 
était particulièrement répandu dans les zones de la basse densité 
de population, augmentation récente de population noire, et les 
cadences élevées du transiency, où les étrangers ont craint un un 
autre et des blancs ont jugé l'application de loi légitime faible. 
Comme le témoignage suivant par Birmingham, Alabama, 
journaliste de journal à 1949 expositions d'un sous-comité de 
Chambre, actes de violence par des groupes de surveillant dans les 
Sud ont été dirigés non seulement vers des noirs. 
Violemment l'anti-Catholique, l'anti-sémitique, et anti-Étranger 
Ku Klux Klan du 20ème siècle ont violemment essayé d'imposer son 
code de la moralité aux hommes, aux femmes, et aux enfants qui ont 
violé leur croyance des normes de la communauté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entre 1882 e 1964, quase cinco mil povos morreram 
de lynching, maioria Africano-Americana. O 1890s testemunhou o 
período o mais mau de lynching no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS. O 
registro estatístico grim suaviza quase certamente a história. 
Muitos lynchings não foram gravados fora de seu locality 
imediato, e os números puros não fazem saber ao brutality de 
lynching. Lynchings, testemunhado frequentemente por multidões 
grandes dos espectadores brancos, era o formulário o mais extremo do 
controle branco do sul sobre a população Africano-Americana, meted 
regularmente para fora de encontro aos americanos africanos que tinham
sido carregados falsa com os crimes mas no fato conseguiam um nível 
da autonomia política ou econômica que os brancos encontraram 
inaceitável. Lynching era especial prevalent nas áreas da 
densidade de população baixa, aumento recente na população preta, 
e as taxas elevadas do transiency, onde os desconhecido temeram um 
outro e brancos julgaram o enforcement de lei legitimate fraco. 
Como o seguinte testimony por um Birmingham, Alabama, repórter 
de jornal mostras a 1949 de uma subcomissão da casa, atos de 
violência por grupos do vigilante no sul foi dirigido não somente 
para pretos. O virulently anti-anti-Catholic, o anti-Semitic, e 
anti-estrangeiro Ku Klux Klan do 20o século tentaram violentamente 
impo seu código do morality em homens, em mulheres, e em crianças 
que violated sua opinião de normas da comunidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fra 1882 e 1964, quasi cinque mila genti sono 
morto dal lynching, la maggioranza Africano-Americana. Il 1890s 
ha testimoniato il periodo più difettoso di lynching nella storia 
degli STATI UNITI. Il record statistico torvo quasi certamente 
minimizza la storia. Molti lynchings non sono stati registrati 
fuori della loro località immediata ed i numeri puri non trasportano 
il brutality di lynching. Lynchings, testimoniato spesso dalle 
grandi folle dei onlookers bianchi, era la forma più estrema di 
controllo bianco del sud sopra la popolazione Africano-Americana, 
meted regolarmente fuori contro gli Americani africani che erano stati
caricati erroneamente dei crimini ma in effetti stava realizzando un 
livello di autonomia politica o economica che i bianchi hanno trovato 
inaccettabile. Lynching era particolarmente prevalente nelle 
zone di densità demografica bassa, aumento recente in popolazione di 
colore e gli alti tassi del transiency, dove gli sconosciuti hanno 
temuto uno un altro ed i bianchi hanno giudicato l'applicazione di 
legge legittima debole. Come la seguente testimonianza da 
Birmingham, Alabama, reporter del giornale esposizioni a 1949 del 
sottocomitato della Camera, atti della violenza dai gruppi del 
vigilante nel sud è stata diretta non soltanto verso i neri. 
Violentemente il anti-Cattolico, il anti-Semitic ed 
anti-straniero Ku Klux Klan del ventesimo secolo hanno tentato 
violentemente di imporre il relativo codice della moralità agli 
uomini, alle donne ed ai bambini che hanno violato la loro credenza 
delle norme della Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταξύ 1882 και 1964, σχεδόν πέντε χιλιάες 
άνθρωποι πέθαναν από το λυντσάρισμα, η πλειοψηφία 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός. Το 1890s βεβαίωσε τη χειρότερη 
περίοδο λυντσαρίσματος στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉ ιστορία. Το απαίσιο
στατιστικό αρχείο σχεδόν βεβαίως μειώνει την ιστορία. 
Πολλά λυντσαρίσματα δεν καταγράφηκαν έξω από την άμεση 
τοποθεσία τους, και οι καθαροί αριθμοί δεν μεταβιβάζουν τη 
βιαιότητα του λυντσαρίσματος. Τα λυντσαρίσματα, που 
βεβαιώθηκαν συχνά από τα μεγάλα πλήθη των λευκών θεατών, ήταν 
η πιό ακραία μορφή του νότιου άσπρου ελέγχου του 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού πληθυσμού, τακτικά έξω ενάντια σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς που ήταν χρεωμένων ψευδώς με τα 
εγκλήματα αλλά στην πραγματικότητα επετύγχαναν ένα επίπεδο 
πολιτικής ή οικονομικής αυτονομίας ότι λευκά που βρέθηκαν 
απαράδεκτα. Το λυντσάρισμα ήταν ιδιαίτερα επικρατόν στους 
τομείς της χαμηλής πυκνότητας πληθυσμών, της πρόσφατης αύξησης 
στο μαύρο πληθυσμό, και των υψηλών ποσοστών transiency, όπου 
ξένοι φοβισμένος που ένας άλλος και τα λευκά έκριναν τη 
νόμιμη επιβολή νόμου αδύνατη. Σαν ακόλουθη κατάθεση από 
ένα Μπέρμιγχαμ, Αλαμπάμα, ο δημοσιογράφος εφημερίδων σε μια 
υποεπιτροπή σπιτιών του 1949 εμφανίζει, ενεργεί της βίας από 
τις ομάδες vigilante στο νότο κατευθύνθηκε όχι μόνο προς τους 
Μαύρους. Virulently ο αντι-καθολικός, αντισημιτικός, και 
ο αντι-αλλοδαπός Ku Klux Klan του 20ού αιώνα προσπάθησε 
βίαια να επιβάλει τον κώδικα ηθικής του στους άνδρες, τις 
γυναίκες, και τα παιδιά που παραβίασαν τις πεποιθήσεις κοινοτικών
κανόνων τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entre 1882 y 1964, casi cinco mil personas 
murieron de lynching, la mayoría Africano-Americana. El 1890s 
atestiguó el período peor de lynching en la historia de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. El expediente estadístico severo minimisa casi 
ciertamente la historia. Muchos lynchings no fueron registrados 
fuera de su lugar inmediato, y los números puros no transportan la 
brutalidad de lynching. Lynchings, atestiguado a menudo por las 
muchedumbres grandes de los onlookers blancos, era la forma más 
extrema de control blanco meridional sobre la población 
Africano-Americana, meted regularmente hacia fuera contra los 
americanos africanos que habían sido cargados falso con crímenes 
pero en hecho alcanzaban un nivel de la autonomía política o 
económica que los blancos encontraron inaceptable. El lynching 
era especialmente frecuente en áreas de la densidad demogr'afica 
baja, aumento reciente en la población negra, y los altos índices 
del transiency, donde los extranjeros temieron uno otro y blancos 
juzgaron la aplicación de ley legítima débil. Como el 
testimonio siguiente por una Birmingham, Alabama, reportero 
demostraciones a 1949 de un subcomité de la casa, actos de la 
violencia por los grupos del vigilante en el sur fue dirigido no 
solamente hacia negros. El virulento contra-Cato'lico, el 
anti-Semitic, y contra-extranjero Ku Klux Klan del vigésimo siglo 
procuraron violentamente imponer su código de la moralidad ante 
hombres, mujeres, y los niños que violaron su creencia de las normas 
de la comunidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086193</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107792</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/get-on-the-ground-and-we-will-kick-your-head-in-a-reporter-tells-of-terrorism-in-alabama</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
