<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105174</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105174</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209880</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Line </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ligne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Linha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Riga</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γραμμή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Línea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the definition of a line. The applet presents two points and a line that passes through them extending to infinity in both directions. As the points a re dragged the line moves but it is never possible to reveal a line end. See also the entries for line segment and ray. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Definition einer Zeile zeigen. Der applet 
stellt zwei Punkte und eine Zeile dar, die durch sie ausdehnend auf 
Unbegrenztheit in beiden Richtungen überschreitet. Da die 
Punkte ein Re die Zeile Bewegungen aber schleppten, es ist nie 
möglich, eine Zeile Ende aufzudecken. Sehen Sie auch die 
Einträge für Strich und Strahl. Applet kann zum vollen 
Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert
werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf 
es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek 
ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent la définition d'une ligne. L'applet présente 
deux points et une ligne qui traverse eux étendant à l'infini dans 
les deux directions. Car les points un Re ont traîné la ligne 
mouvements mais il n'est jamais possible d'indiquer une ligne 
extrémité. Voyez également les entrées pour la ligne segment
et rayon. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein 
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem a definição de uma linha. O applet apresenta dois 
pontos e uma linha que passe através deles que estendem à infinidade
em ambos os sentidos. Porque os pontos um re arrastaram a linha 
movimentos mas é nunca possível revelar uma linha extremidade. 
Veja também as entradas para a linha segmento e raio. O 
applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um 
projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, 
estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou
na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este 
recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook da 
geometria da referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano la definizione di una riga. Il applet presenta due 
punti e una riga che attraversa loro che estendere all'infinità in 
entrambi i sensi. Poichè i punti un Re hanno trascinato la riga
movimenti ma non è mai possibile rivelare una riga estremità. 
Veda inoltre le entrate per la riga segmento e raggio. Il 
applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con 
un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, 
allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o 
nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa 
risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della 
geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τον καθορισμό μιας γραμμής. Το applet 
παρουσιάζει δύο σημεία και μια γραμμή που περνά μέσω τους που 
επεκτείνονται στο άπειρο και στις δύο κατευθύνσεις. 
Δεδομένου ότι τα σημεία ένα Πε έσεραν τη γραμμή κινούνται
αλλά δεν είναι ποτέ δυνατό να αποκαλυφθεί ένα τέλος γραμμών. 
Δείτε επίσης τις καταχωρήσεις γιατί η γραμμή 
τέμνει και ακτίνα. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο 
πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. 
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran la definición de una línea. El applet presenta dos 
puntas y una línea que pase a través de ellas que extienden al 
infinito en ambas direcciones. Pues las puntas un re arrastraron
la línea movimientos pero nunca es posible revelar una línea 
extremo. Vea también las entradas para la línea segmento y 
rayo. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla 
completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El 
uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso 
otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin 
la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un componente del 
proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la geometría de la 
referencia abierta de la matemáticas en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209880</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105174</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/line</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
