<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107219</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107219</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207205</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Westward by Sea: A Maritime Perspective on American Expansion, 1820-1890</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach Westen durch Sea: Eine Seeperspektive 
auf amerikanischer Expansion, 1820-1890</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À l'ouest par Sea : Une perspective 
maritime sur l'expansion américaine, 1820-1890</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para o oeste por Mar: Um perspective 
marítimo na expansão americana, 1820-1890</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verso ovest da Sea: Una prospettiva 
marittima su espansione americana, 1820-1890</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δυτικά θαλασσίως: Μια θαλάσσια προοπτική στην 
αμερικανική επέκταση, 1820-1890</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hacia el oeste por Sea: Una perspectiva 
marítimo en la extensión americana, 1820-1890</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents letters, business papers, photos, maps, ship logbooks, and narratives that can help students understand the story of American's travel by sea to settle California, Alaska, Hawaii, Texas, and the Pacific Northwest. Themes illustrated by these materials, selected from Mystic Seaport's collection, include whaling, life at sea, the California Gold Rush, and native populations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Zeichen, Geschäftspapiere, Fotos, Karten, 
Schiff Maschinenbordbücher dar, und Darstellungen, die können, 
Kursteilnehmern helfen, die Geschichte des Spielraums des Amerikaners 
durch Meer zu verstehen, um Kalifornien, Alaska, Hawaii, Texas und den
pazifischen Nordwesten zu vereinbaren. Die Themen, die durch 
diese Materialien, ausgewählt von der Ansammlung des mystischen 
Seehafens veranschaulicht werden, enthalten Whaling, das Leben am 
Meer, die Kalifornien Goldanstürme und die einheimischen 
Bevölkerungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente des lettres, papiers d'affaires, photos,
cartes, carnets de bateau, et les récits qui peuvent aider des 
étudiants à comprendre l'histoire du voyage de l'Américain par la 
mer pour arranger la Californie, l'Alaska, Hawaï, le Texas, et le 
nord-ouest Pacifique. Les thèmes illustrés par ces matériaux,
choisis parmi la collection du port maritime mystique, incluent la 
pêche à la baleine, la vie en mer, les précipitations d'or de la 
Californie, et les populations indigènes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta letras, papéis de negócio, fotos, 
mapas, registros do navio, e as narrativas que podem para ajudar a 
estudantes compreender a história do curso do americano pelo mar para
estabelecir Califórnia, Alaska, Havaí, Texas, e o noroeste 
pacífico. Os temas ilustrados por estes materiais, selecionados
da coleção do seaport mystic, incluem a baleação, a vida no mar, 
as arremetidas do ouro de Califórnia, e populações nativas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta le lettere, le carte d'ufficio, le foto, 
i programmi, libri macchina della nave e descrizioni che possono 
aiutare gli allievi a capire la storia della corsa dell'americano dal 
mare per depositare California, l'Alaska, l'Hawai, il Texas ed il 
nord-ovest pacifico. I temi illustrati da questi materiali, 
scelti dall'accumulazione del porto marittimo mystic, includono la 
caccia alla balena, la vita in mare, gli sbalzi dell'oro della 
California e le popolazioni autoctone.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις επιστολές, τις επιχειρησιακές 
εργασίες, τις φωτογραφίες, τους χάρτες, τα ημερολόγια σκαφών, και
τα αφηγήματα που μπορούν να βοηθήσουν τους σπουδαστές να 
καταλάβουν την ιστορία του ταξιδιού Αμερικανού θαλασσίως για να 
εγκαταστήσουν Καλιφόρνια, την Αλάσκα, τη Χαβάη, το Τέξας, και τα 
ειρηνικά βορειοδυτικά. Τα θέματα που εμφανίζονται σε αυτά 
τα υλικά, που επιλέγονται από τη συλλογή του απόκρυφου θαλάσσιου
λιμένα, περιλαμβάνουν το κυνήγι φάλαινας, τη ζωή εν πλω, τη 
χρυσή βιασύνη Καλιφόρνιας, και τους εγγενείς πληθυσμούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta las cartas, documentos comerciales, 
fotos, correspondencias, diarios de operación de la nave, y las 
narrativas que pueden ayudar a estudiantes a entender la historia del 
recorrido del americano por el mar para colocar California, Alaska, 
Hawaii, Tejas, y el noroeste pacífico. Los temas ilustrados por
estos materiales, seleccionados de la colección del puerto místico, 
incluyen a pesca de ballenas, a vida en el mar, a las acometidas del 
oro de California, y a poblaciones indígenas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207205</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107219</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/westward-by-sea-a-maritime-perspective-on-american-expansion-1820-1890</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
