<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Certain Fundamental Truths": The AFL Protests Unemployment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Bestimmte Grundlegende Wahrheiten": Das AFL
Protestiert Arbeitslosigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Certaines Vérités Fondamentales" : L'AFL 
Proteste Le Chômage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Determinadas Verdades Fundamentais": O AFL 
Protesta O Desemprego</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Determinate Verità Fondamentali": Il AFL 
Protesta La Disoccupazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ορισμένο θεμελιώδες Truths": Το AFL 
διαμαρτύρεται την ανεργία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ciertas Verdades Fundamentales": El AFL 
Protesta El Desempleo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The spreading economic depression of 1893 stirred the American Federation of Labor (AFL), which was sometimes guilty of focusing primarily on the needs of its own members, to call for broad measures that would benefit all working people. The AFL urged the unemployed to hold mass demonstrations. The federation also organized "federal labor unions" of the jobless. New York's organized labor movement also protested, as seen in this September 1893 appeal signed by local and national labor leaders, including Samuel Gompers. Although the resolution primarily called on the city to provide "immediate relief and public employment," it also suggested that the state and federal governments should provide for the unemployed. This claim was part of a long-term shift in which working people and others came to see the needs of the jobless as more than a local obligation (in the manner of traditional poor relief). Only with the New Deal of the 1930s were such demands realized.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die ausgebreitete Wirtschaftskrise von 1893 
rührte die amerikanische Vereinigung der Arbeit (AFL), das vom 
Konzentrieren hauptsächlich auf die Notwendigkeiten seiner eigenen 
Bauteile manchmal schuldig war, um ausgedehnte Masse zu verlangen, die
alle Arbeitsleute fördern würden. Das AFL drängte die 
Arbeitslosen, Massendemonstrationen anzuhalten. Die Vereinigung 
organisierte auch "föderativarbeiterverbände" vom arbeitslosen. 
New York organisierte Arbeiterbewegung protestierte auch, wie in
diesen September 1893 Anklang gesehen, der von den lokalen und 
nationalen Gewerkschaftsführern, einschließlich Samuel Gompers 
unterzeichnet wurde. Obgleich die Zerlegung hauptsächlich um 
die Stadt ersuchte, um "sofortig Entlastung und Beschäftigung im 
öffentlichen Dienst zur Verfügung zu stellen," schlug sie auch vor, 
daß der Zustand und die Bundesregierungen für die Arbeitslosen 
sorgen sollten. Dieser Anspruch war ein Teil einer langfristigen
Schicht, in der Arbeitsleute und andere kamen, die Notwendigkeiten vom
arbeitslosen wie zu sehen mehr als eine lokale Verpflichtung (in der 
Weise der traditionellen schlechten Entlastung). Nur mit dem 
neuen Abkommen der dreißiger Jahre waren solche verwirklichte 
Nachfragen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La dépression économique de propagation de 1893 
a remué la fédération américaine du travail (AFL), qui était 
parfois coupable de se concentrer principalement sur les besoins de 
ses propres membres, pour nécessiter les larges mesures qui 
bénéficieraient toutes les personnes travaillantes. L'AFL a 
invité les chômeurs à tenir des démonstrations de masse. La 
fédération a également organisé "les syndicats fédéraux" du sans
emploi. Le mouvement de travail organisé de New York a 
également protesté, comme vu dans cet appel de septembre 1893 signé
par les dirigeants syndicaux locaux et nationaux, y compris Samuel 
Gompers. Bien que la résolution ait principalement invité la 
ville pour fournir "le soulagement immédiat et l'emploi public," il a
également suggéré que l'état et les gouvernements fédéraux 
devraient prévoir les chômeurs. Cette réclamation faisait 
partie d'un décalage à long terme dans lequel les personnes 
travaillantes et d'autres sont venues pour voir les besoins du sans 
emploi comme davantage qu'un engagement local (de la façon du 
soulagement faible traditionnel). Seulement avec la nouvelle 
affaire des années 30 étaient de telles demandes réalisées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O depression econômico espalhando de 1893 agitou 
o federation americano do trabalho (AFL), que era às vezes culpado de
focalizar primeiramente nas necessidades de seus próprios membros, 
para chamar-se para as medidas largas que beneficiariam todos os povos
trabalhando. O AFL incitou os desempregados prender 
demonstrações maciças. O federation organizou também 
"uniões labor federais" do jobless. O movimento labor 
organizado de New York protestou também, como visto nesta apelação 
de setembro 1893 assinada por líderes labor locais e nacionais, 
including Samuel Gompers. Embora a definição convidasse 
primeiramente a cidade para fornecer "o relevo imediato e o emprego 
público," sugeriu também que o estado e os governos federais devem 
fornecer para os desempregados. Esta reivindicação era parte 
de uma SHIFT a longo prazo em que os povos trabalhando e outros vieram
ver as necessidades do jobless como mais do que uma obrigação local 
(na maneira do relevo deficiente tradicional). Somente com o 
negócio novo dos 1930s eram tais demandas realizadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La depressione economica di diffusione di 1893 ha 
mescolato la federazione americana del Lavoro (AFL), che era a 
volte colpevole di focalizzazione soprattutto sui bisogni dei relativi
propri membri, per richiedere le vaste misure che avvantaggerebbero 
tutta la gente lavorante. Il AFL ha invitato i disoccupati a 
tenere le dimostrazioni totali. La federazione egualmente ha 
organizzato "i sindacati di lavoro federali" del senza lavoro. 
Il movimento di lavoro organizzato de New York egualmente ha 
protestato, come visto in questo appello di settembre 1893 firmato dai
capi di lavoro locali e nazionali, compreso Samuel Gompers. 
Anche se la risoluzione soprattutto ha invitato la città per 
fornire "il rilievo immediato e l'occupazione pubblica," egualmente ha
suggerito che il dichiarare ed i governi federali dovrebbero prevedere
i disoccupati. Questo reclamo faceva parte di uno spostamento di
lunga durata in cui la gente lavorante ed altre sono venuto vedere i 
bisogni del senza lavoro come più di un obbligo locale (nel modo di 
povero rilievo tradizionale). Soltanto con il nuovo affare 
dei 1930s erano tali richieste realizzate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαδίδοντας οικονομική ύφεση 1893 ανακάτωσε την 
αμερικανική ομοσπονδία της εργασίας (AFL), που ήταν μερικές 
φορές ένοχη να εστιάσει πρώτιστα στις ανάγκες των μελών της, για
να απαιτήσει τα ευρέα μέτρα που θα ωφελούσαν όλους τους 
εργαζόμενους ανθρώπους. Το AFL ώθησε τους ανέργους για να
πραγματοποιήσει τις μαζικές επιδείξεις. Η ομοσπονδία 
οργάνωσε επίσης τα "ομοσπονδιακά εργατικά συνδικάτα" των 
ανέργων. Οργανωμένη μετακίνηση εργασίας της Νέας Υόρκης 
που διαμαρτύρεται επίσης, όπως βλέπει σε αυτήν την 
έκκληση Σεπτεμβρίου 1893 που υπογράφεται από τους τοπικούς και
εθνικούς ηγέτες εργασίας, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του Samuel 
Gompers. Αν και το ψήφισμα κάλεσε πρώτιστα στην πόλη για 
να παρέχει τη "άμεση ανακούφιση και τη δημόσια απασχόληση," 
επίσης πρότεινε ότι το κράτος και οι ομοσπονδιακές κυβερνήσεις 
πρέπει να προβλέψουν για τους ανέργους. Αυτή η αξίωση ήταν
μέρος μιας μακροπρόθεσμης μετατόπισης στην οποία οι λειτουργώντας
άνθρωποι και άλλες ήρθαν να δουν τις ανάγκες των 
ανέργων όπως περισσότερο από μια τοπική υποχρέωση (με τον τρόπο
της παραδοσιακής φτωχής ανακούφισης). Μόνο με τη νέα 
διαπραγμάτευση της δεκαετίας του '30 τέτοιες απαιτήσεις 
πραγματοποιήθηκαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La depresión económica que se separaba de 1893 
revolvió la federación americana del trabajo (AFL), que era a veces 
culpable de centrarse sobre todo en las necesidades de sus propios 
miembros, para llamar para las amplias medidas que beneficiarían a 
toda la gente de trabajo. El AFL impulsó a parados celebrar 
demostraciones totales. La federación también ordenó 
"sindicatos federales" del desempleado. El movimiento de trabajo
ordenado de Nueva York también protestó, según lo considerado en 
esta súplica de septiembre 1893 firmada por los arranques de cinta de
trabajo locales y nacionales, incluyendo Samuel Gompers. Aunque 
la resolución invitó sobre todo la ciudad para proporcionar a la 
"relevación inmediata y al empleo público," también sugirió que el
estado y los gobiernos federales previeran los parados. Esta 
demanda era parte de una rotación a largo plazo en la cual la gente 
de trabajo y otras vinieron ver las necesidades del desempleado como 
más que una obligación local (de la manera de la relevación pobre 
tradicional). Solamente con el nuevo reparto de los años 30 
estaban tales demandas observadas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103664</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/certain-fundamental-truths-the-afl-protests-unemployment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
