<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106091</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106091</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211656</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Principles and Standards in School Mathematics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grundregeln und Standards in der 
Schule-Mathematik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Principes et normes dans des mathématiques 
d'école</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Princípios e padrões na matemática da escola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Principii e standard nella matematica della 
scuola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχές και πρότυπα στα σχολικά μαθηματικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Principios y estándares en matemáticas de la 
escuela</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Principles and Standards for School Mathematics describes a future in which all students have access to rigorous, high-quality mathematics instruction, including four years of high school mathematics. Principles and Standards for School Mathematics has four major components. First, the Principles for school mathematics reflect basic perspectives on which educators should base decisions that affect school mathematics. These Principles establish a foundation for school mathematics programs by considering the broad issues of equity, curriculum, teaching, learning, assessment, and technology. Users can access all chapters of the book as well as information on the Standards 2000 Project, additional resources, electronic lesson examples and appendices.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grundregeln und Standards für Schule-Mathematik 
beschreibt eine Zukunft, in der alle Kursteilnehmer Zugriff zur 
rigorosen, hochwertigen Mathematikanweisung haben, einschließlich 
vier Jahre High School Mathematik. Grundregeln und Standards 
für Schule-Mathematik hat vier Hauptbestandteile. Zuerst 
reflektieren die Grundregeln für Schulemathematik grundlegende 
Perspektiven, auf denen Erzieher Entscheidungen gründen sollten, die 
Schulemathematik beeinflussen. Diese Grundregeln stellen eine 
Grundlage für Schulemathematikprogramme her, indem sie die 
ausgedehnten Ausgaben von Billigkeit, von Lehrplan, von Unterricht, 
von Lernen, von Einschätzung und von Technologie betrachten. 
Benutzer können auf alle Kapitel des Buches sowie Informationen
über die Standards 2000 zugreifen sich projizieren, zusätzliche 
Betriebsmittel, elektronische Lektionbeispiele und Anhänge.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les principes et les normes pour des 
mathématiques d'école décrit un futur l'où tous les étudiants ont
accès à l'instruction rigoureuse et de haute qualité de 
mathématiques, y compris quatre ans de mathématiques de lycée. 
Les principes et les normes pour des mathématiques d'école a 
quatre composants principaux. D'abord, les principes pour des 
mathématiques d'école reflètent les perspectives de base sur 
lesquelles les éducateurs devraient baser les décisions qui 
affectent des mathématiques d'école. Ces principes 
établissent une base pour des programmes de mathématiques d'école 
en considérant les larges questions des capitaux propres, du 
programme d'études, de l'enseignement, de l'étude, de l'évaluation,
et de la technologie. Les utilisateurs peuvent accéder à tous 
les chapitres du livre aussi bien que l'information sur les normes 
2000 projettent, les ressources supplémentaires, les exemples 
électroniques de leçon et les annexes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os princípios e os padrões para a matemática da
escola descrevem um futuro em que todos os estudantes têm o acesso à
instrução rigorous, de alta qualidade da matemática, including 
quatro anos da matemática da High School. Os princípios e os 
padrões para a matemática da escola têm quatro componentes 
principais. Primeiramente, os princípios para a matemática da 
escola refletem os perspectives básicos em que os educadores devem 
basear as decisões que afetam a matemática da escola. Estes 
princípios estabelecem uma fundação para programas da matemática 
da escola considerando as introduções largas da equidade, do 
curriculum, do ensino, da aprendizagem, da avaliação, e da 
tecnologia. Os usuários podem alcançar todos os capítulos do 
livro as.well.as a informação nos padrões 2000 projetam-se, 
recursos adicionais, exemplos eletrônicos da lição e apêndices.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I principii e gli standard per la matematica della
scuola descrive un futuro in où tutti gli allievi hanno accesso ad 
istruzione rigorosa e di alta qualità di matematica, compreso quattro
anni della matematica della High School. I principii e gli 
standard per la matematica della scuola ha quattro componenti 
importanti. In primo luogo, i principii per la matematica della 
scuola riflettono le prospettive di base su cui gli educatori 
dovrebbero basare le decisioni che interessano la matematica della 
scuola. Questi principii stabiliscono un fondamento per i 
programmi di matematica della scuola considerando le vaste emissioni 
dell'equità, del programma di studi, dell'insegnamento, imparare, 
della valutazione e della tecnologia. Gli utenti possono 
accedere a tutti i capitoli del libro così come le informazioni sugli
standard 2000 si proiettano, risorse supplementari, esempi elettronici
di lezione ed appendici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αρχές και τα πρότυπα για τα σχολικά μαθηματικά 
περιγράφουν το μέλλον στο οποίο όλοι οι σπουδαστές έχουν 
πρόσβαση στην αυστηρή, υψηλής ποιότητας οδηγία μαθηματικών, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων τεσσάρων ετών μαθηματικών γυμνασίου. Οι
αρχές και τα πρότυπα για τα σχολικά μαθηματικά έχουν τέσσερα 
σημαντικά συστατικά. Κατ' αρχάς, οι αρχές για τα σχολικά 
μαθηματικά απεικονίζουν τις βασικές προοπτικές στις οποίες οι 
εκπαιδευτικοί πρέπει να βασίσουν τις αποφάσεις που έχουν 
επιπτώσεις στα σχολικά μαθηματικά. Αυτές οι αρχές 
καθιερώνουν ένα ίδρυμα για τα προγράμματα σχολικών μαθηματικών 
με την εξέταση των ευρέων ζητημάτων της δικαιοσύνης, του 
προγράμματος σπουδών, της διδασκαλίας, της εκμάθησης, της 
αξιολόγησης, και της τεχνολογίας. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να 
έχουν πρόσβαση σε όλα τα κεφάλαια του βιβλίου καθώς επίσης και 
των πληροφοριών για το πρόγραμμα προτύπων το 2000, τα πρόσθετα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, τα ηλεκτρονικά παραδείγματα μαθήματος και 
τα παραρτήματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los principios y los estándares para las 
matemáticas de la escuela describen un futuro en el cual todos los 
estudiantes tengan acceso a la instrucción rigurosa, de alta calidad 
de las matemáticas, incluyendo cuatro años de matemáticas de la 
High School secundaria. Los principios y los estándares para 
las matemáticas de la escuela tienen cuatro componentes importantes. 
Primero, los principios para las matemáticas de la escuela 
reflejan las perspectivas básicas en las cuales los educadores deben 
basar las decisiones que afectan matemáticas de la escuela. 
Estos principios establecen una fundación para los programas de
las matemáticas de la escuela considerando las amplias aplicaciones 
la equidad, el plan de estudios, la enseñanza, aprender, el gravamen,
y la tecnología. Los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a todos 
los capítulos del libro así como la información sobre los 
estándares 2000 proyectan, los recursos adicionales, los ejemplos 
electrónicos de la lección y los apéndices.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211656</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106091</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/principles-and-standards-in-school-mathematics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
