<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106037</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106037</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Are Not the Degraded Race You Would Make Us": Norman Asing Challenges Chinese Immigration Restrictions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir sind nicht das verminderte Rennen, das Sie 
uns" bilden würden: Normannisches Asing Fordert Chinesische 
Einwanderungsbeschränkungen Heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous ne sommes pas la course dégradée que vous
nous feriez" : Asing Normand Défie des Restrictions 
d'Immigration Chinoises</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós não somos a raça que degradada você nos 
faria": Asing Normando Desafia Limitações De Immigration 
Chinesas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non siamo la corsa che degradata li abbiate 
fatti": Asing Normanno Sfida Le Limitazioni Di Immigrazione 
Cinesi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν είμαστε η υποβιβασμένη φυλή που θα μας κάνατε": 
Ο Norman Asing προκαλεί τους κινεζικούς περιορισμούς 
μετανάστευσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no somos la raza degradada que usted nos 
haría": Asing Normando Desafía Restricciones De Inmigración 
Chinas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">California had a few thousand Chinese immigrants in 1850. By 1852, the number swelled to 20,000, constituting almost a quarter of California's work force. Chinese who toiled in mines and worked as shopkeepers were welcomed, even recruited, at first. But nativist sentiment to curtail Chinese immigration grew as the number of immigrants increased. John Bigler, the state's first Governor, called for immigration restriction in 1852, citing Chinese immigrants' inability to assimilate as European immigrants had. Norman Asing, a restaurant owner and leader in San Francisco's Chinese community, assailed the governor for his anti-Chinese stance and utilized the rhetoric of the Declaration of Independence and the U.S. Constitution against Bigler's claims of the danger of Chinese immigration. But Asing's argument also embraced some of the era's racist assumptions about African Americans and Native Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalifornien hatte einige tausend chinesische 
Immigranten 1850. Bis zum 1852 schwoll die Zahl bis 20.000 und 
fast setzte ein Viertel Kraft Arbeit Kaliforniens fest. Chinese,
der in den Gruben und gearbeitet abplagte, während 
Ladenbesitzer begrüßt wurden, sogar eingezogen, zuerst. Aber 
das nativist Gefühl, zum der chinesischen Immigration zu beschränken
wuchs, während die Zahl Immigranten sich erhöhte. John Bigler,
erster Regler des Zustandes, verlangt Einwanderungsbeschränkung 1852,
Unfähigkeit der chinesischen Immigranten zitierend anzupassen, wie 
europäische Immigranten hatten. Normannisches Asing, ein 
Gaststätteinhaber und Führer San Franciscos in der chinesischen 
Gemeinschaft, griffen den Regler für seine Anti-Chinesische Position 
an und verwendeten die Rhetorik der Unabhängigkeitserklärung und die
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit gegen Ansprüche Biglers der Gefahr 
der chinesischen Immigration. Aber Argument Asings umfaßte auch
einige der rassistischen Annahmen der Ära über afrikanische 
Amerikaner und gebürtige Amerikaner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Californie a eu quelques mille immigrés 
chinois en 1850. D'ici 1852, le nombre a gonflé à 20.000, 
constituant presque un quart de main-d'oeuvre de la Californie. 
Chinois qui travaille fort dans les mines et travaillé comme 
des commerçants ont été accueillis, même recruté, d'abord. 
Mais le sentiment nativiste pour raccourcir l'immigration 
chinoise s'est développé à mesure que le nombre d'immigrés 
augmentait. John Bigler, le premier gouverneur de l'état, 
nécessité la restriction d'immigration en 1852, citant l'incapacité
des immigrés chinois d'assimiler comme les immigrés européens ont 
eu. Asing normand, un propriétaire de restaurant et l'amorce 
dans la communauté chinoise de San Francisco, ont envahi le 
gouverneur pour sa position anti-Chinoise et ont utilisé la 
rhétorique de la déclaration de l'indépendance et la constitution 
des ETATS-UNIS contre les réclamations de Bigler du danger de 
l'immigration chinoise. Mais l'argument d'Asing a également 
embrassé certaines des prétentions racistes de l'ère au sujet des 
Américains africains et des Américains indigènes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Califórnia teve alguns mil immigrants chineses 
em 1850. Por 1852, o número inchou a 20.000, constituindo quase
um quarto da força de trabalho de Califórnia. Chinês que 
labuta nas minas e trabalhado como os shopkeepers foram dados 
boas-vindas, recrutado mesmo, no início. Mas o sentiment 
nativist para curtail o immigration chinês cresceu enquanto o número
dos immigrants aumentou. John Bigler, primeiro regulador do 
estado, chamado para a limitação de immigration em 1852, citing a 
inabilidade dos immigrants' chineses assimilate como os immigrants 
europeus tiveram. Asing normando, um proprietário do 
restaurante e o líder na comunidade chinesa do San Francisco, 
assailed o regulador para seu stance anti-Chinês e utilizaram o 
rhetoric da declaração de independência e o constitution de ESTADOS
UNIDOS de encontro às reivindicações de Bigler do perigo do 
immigration chinês. Mas o argumento de Asing embraced também 
algumas das suposições racist da era sobre americanos africanos e 
americanos nativos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La California ha avuta alcuni mille immigranti 
cinesi in 1850. Entro 1852, il numero ha gonfiato a 20.000,
costituendo quasi un quarto della forza di lavoro della California. 
Cinese che lavora duramente in miniere e lavorato come i 
commercianti sono stati accolti favorevolmente, persino reclutato, 
inizialmente. Ma il sentimento nativist per accorciare 
l'immigrazione cinese si è sviluppato mentre il numero di 
immigranti è aumentato. John Bigler, il primo regolatore di 
dichiarare, richiesto la limitazione di immigrazione in 1852, citando
incapacità cinese degli immigranti di assimilare come gli 
immigranti europei hanno avuti. Asing normanno, un proprietario 
del ristorante ed il capo nella Comunità cinese de San 
Francisco, hanno assalito il regolatore per la sua posizione di 
anti-cinese ed hanno utilizzato la retorica della dichiarazione di 
indipendenza e la costituzione degli STATI UNITI contro i reclami del 
Bigler del pericolo dell'immigrazione cinese. Ma 
l'argomento del Asing egualmente ha abbracciato alcuni dei presupposti
razzisti dell'era circa gli Americani africani e gli Americani natali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καλιφόρνια είχε μερικές χιλιάες κινεζικούς 
μετανάστες το 1850. Από 1852, ο αριθμός πρήστηκε σε 
20.000, αποτελώντας σχεδόν ένα τέταρτο του εργατικού 
δυναμικού Καλιφόρνιας. Κινέζικα που κοπίασαν στα ορυχεία 
και εργάστηκαν καθώς οι καταστηματάρχες καλωσορίστηκαν, ακόμη και
στρατολογημένος, πρώτα. Αλλά το συναίσθημα nativist για 
να περιορίσει την κινεζική μετανάστευση αυξήθηκε καθώς ο αριθμός
μεταναστών αυξήθηκε. Θ*Ιοχν Bigler, ο κρατικός πρώτος 
κυβερνήτης, απαίτησε τον περιορισμό μετανάστευσης το 1852, 
αναφέροντας την ανικανότητα των κινεζικών μεταναστών να 
αφομοιώσει καθώς οι ευρωπαϊκοί μετανάστες είχαν. Ο 
Norman Asing, ένας ιδιοκτήτης εστιατορίων και ένας ηγέτης 
στην κινεζική κοινότητα του Σαν Φρανσίσκο, επιτέθηκαν τον 
κυβερνήτη για την αντι-κινεζική θέση του και χρησιμοποίησαν τη 
ρητορική της Διακήρυξης της ανεξαρτησίας και του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ 
συντάγματος ενάντια στις αξιώσεις Bigler του κινδύνου της 
κινεζικής μετανάστευσης. Αλλά το όρισμα Asing αγκαλίασε 
επίσης μερικών από τις ρατσιστικές υποθέσεις της εποχής για 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς και εγγενείς Αμερικανούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">California tenía algunos mil inmigrantes chinos 
en 1850. Antes de 1852, el número se hinchó a 20.000, 
constituyendo casi un cuarto de la fuerza de trabajo de California. 
Chino que trabaja en minas y trabajado como dieron la bienvenida
los comerciantes, incluso reclutado, al principio. Pero el 
sentimiento nativista para acortar la inmigración china creció 
mientras que el número de inmigrantes aumentó. Juan Bigler, 
primer gobernador del estado, llamado para la restricción de 
inmigración en 1852, citando la inhabilidad de los inmigrantes chinos
de asimilar como los inmigrantes europeos tenían. Asing 
normando, un propietario del restaurante y el arranque de cinta en la 
comunidad china de San Francisco, invadieron el gobernador para su 
postura contra-China y utilizaron el retórico del declaración de la 
independencia y la constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS contra las demandas
de Bigler del peligro de la inmigración china. Pero el 
argumento de Asing también abrazó algunas de las asunciones racist 
de la era sobre americanos africanos y americanos nativos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106037</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-are-not-the-degraded-race-you-would-make-us-norman-asing-challenges-chinese-immigration-restrictions</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
