<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102926</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102926</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206429</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Constitution Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale Beschaffenheit-Mitte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre National de Constitution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro Nacional Do Constitution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro Nazionale Di Costituzione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικό κέντρο συνταγμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro Nacional De la Constitución</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">includes lessons on the Declaration of Independence, Bill of Rights, electoral process, executive branch, separation of powers, war making, freedom of speech, Founding Fathers, and suffrage. Teaching with Current Events features news stories related to the Constitution, discussion starters for current events, and differing perspectives by commentators and elected officials.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schließt Lektionen der 
Unabhängigkeitserklärung, Verfassung, der Wahlprozess-, Exekutive, 
Trennung von Energien ein, dem bildenden Krieg, Freiheit Rede, 
Gründung der Väter und des Stimmrechts. Unterricht mit 
aktuellen Fällen kennzeichnet die Nachrichten Geschichten, die auf 
der Beschaffenheit, den Diskussion Startern für aktuelle Fälle und 
den unterscheidenen Perspektiven von den Kommentatoren und von 
gewählten Beamten in Verbindung gestanden werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">inclut des leçons sur la déclaration de 
l'indépendance, la déclaration des droits, le branchement de 
processus et exécutif électoral, la séparation des puissances, la 
guerre faisant, la liberté de pères de la parole, de fondation, et 
de suffrage. L'enseignement avec des événements actuels 
comporte des histoires de nouvelles liées à la constitution, aux 
démarreurs de discussion pour des événements actuels, et aux 
perspectives différentes par des commentateurs et des fonctionnaires 
élus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">inclui lições na declaração de independência,
na conta de direitas, na filial electoral do processo, a executiva, na
separação das potências, na guerra que fazem, na liberdade de pais 
do discurso, fundar, e de suffrage. O ensino com eventos atuais 
caracteriza as histórias da notícia relacionadas ao constitution, 
aos acionadores de partida da discussão para eventos atuais, e aos 
perspectives diferindo por comentadores e por oficiais eleitos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">include le lezioni sulla dichiarazione di 
indipendenza, sulla fattura dei diritti, sul ramo esecutivo 
elettorale, di processo, sulla separazione delle potenzi, sulla guerra
che fanno, sulla libertà dei padri fondare, di discorso e del 
suffrage. L'insegnamento con gli eventi correnti caratterizza le
storia di notizie relative alla costituzione, ai dispositivi 
d'avviamento di discussione per gli eventi correnti ed alle 
prospettive differenti dai commentatori e dai funzionari scelti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει τα μαθήματα στη Διακήρυξη της 
ανεξαρτησίας, Bill των δικαιωμάτων, της εκλογικής διαδικασίας, 
του εκτελεστικού κλάδου, του χωρισμού των δυνάμεων, του πολέμου 
που κάνουν, της ελευθερίας της ομιλίας, των ιδρύοντας πατέρων, 
και της ψήφου. Η διδασκαλία με τα παρόντα γεγονότα 
χαρακτηρίζει τις ιστορίες ειδήσεων αφορούσε το σύνταγμα, τους 
εκκινητές συζήτησης για τα παρόντα γεγονότα, και τις διαφορετικές
προοπτικές από τους σχολιαστές και εξέλεξε τους ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incluye lecciones en el declaración de la 
independencia, la cuenta de las derechas, la ramificación electoral 
del proceso, ejecutiva, la separación de potencias, la guerra que 
hace, la libertad de los padres del discurso, de la fundación, y del 
sufragio. La enseñanza con sucesos actuales ofrece las 
historias de las noticias relacionadas con la constitución, los 
arrancadores de la discusión para los sucesos actuales, y las 
perspectivas que diferencian por los comentaristas y los funcionarios 
elegidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206429</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102926</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-constitution-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
