<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105658</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105658</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206946</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reservation Controversies: Then and Now</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reservierung Kontroversen: Dann und jetzt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Polémiques de Réservation : Puis et 
maintenant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Controvérsias Do Reservation: Então e 
agora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Polemiche Di Prenotazione: Allora ed ora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαμάχες επιφύλαξης: Κατόπιν και τώρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Controversias De la Reservación: Entonces y
ahora</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is built around two scenarios that help students understand issues related to American Indian reservations. Under one scenario, set in 1973, the student plays the role of agent for a Comanche Indian reservation. Under a contemporary scenario, the student is cast as a new congressional intern who has received a letter from the his congresswoman asking for help on issues related to casinos on reservations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">wird um zwei Drehbücher aufgebaut, die 
Kursteilnehmern helfen, die Ausgaben zu verstehen, die auf 
indianischen Reservierungen in Verbindung gestanden werden. 
Unter einem Drehbuch stellen Sie 1973, der Kursteilnehmer spielt
die Rolle des Mittels für eine Komanche-Inderreservierung ein. 
Unter einem zeitgenössischen Drehbuch wird der Kursteilnehmer 
geworfen, wie ein neuer Kongreßinternierter, der einen Brief vom 
seinem Kongreßabgeordneten erhalten hat, das um Hilfe auf Ausgaben 
bittet, auf Kasinos auf Reservierungen in Verbindung stand.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est construit autour de deux scénarios qui aident
des étudiants à comprendre des issues liées aux réservations 
indiennes. Au-dessous de un scénario, placez en 1973, 
l'étudiant joue le rôle de l'agent pour une réservation d'Indien de
Comanche. Sous un scénario contemporain, l'étudiant est moulé
comme un nouvel interne congressionnel qui a reçu une lettre de la sa
membre du Congrès demandant l'aide sur des questions a rapporté aux 
casinos sur des réservations.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é construído em torno de dois scenarios que 
ajudam a estudantes compreender as edições relacionadas aos 
reservations indian americanos. Sob um scenario, ajuste em 1973,
o estudante joga o papel do agente para um reservation do indian do 
comanche. Sob um scenario contemporary, o estudante é moldado 
como um interno congressional novo que receba uma letra de seu 
congresswoman que pede ajuda em edições se relacionou aos casinos em
reservations.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è costruito intorno a due piani d'azione che 
aiutano gli allievi a capire le edizioni relative alle prenotazioni 
indiane americane. Sotto un piano d'azione, regolisi in 1973, 
l'allievo svolge il ruolo dell'agente per una prenotazione 
dell'indiano del comanche. Sotto un piano d'azione 
contemporaneo, l'allievo è lanciato come un nuovo interno 
congressuale che ha ricevuto una lettera dal suo congresswoman che 
chiede l'aiuto sulle edizioni ha riferito ai casinos sulle 
prenotazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χτίζεται γύρω από δύο σενάρια που βοηθούν τους 
σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν τα ζητήματα σχετικά με τις αμερικανικές 
ινδικές επιφυλάξεις. Κάτω από ένα σενάριο, που τίθεται το
1973, ο σπουδαστής διαδραματίζει το ρόλο του πράκτορα για μια 
ινδική επιφύλαξη Comanche. Κάτω από ένα σύγχρονο 
σενάριο, ο σπουδαστής πετιέται ως νέος του Κογκρέσου οικότροφος 
που έχει λάβει μια επιστολή από τη congresswoman ζήτησή του 
τις οδηγίες στα ζητήματα σχετικά με τις χαρτοπαικτικές λέσχες 
στις επιφυλάξεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">se construye alrededor de dos decorados que ayuden
a estudiantes a entender las ediciones relacionadas con las 
reservaciones indias americanas. Bajo un decorado, fije en 1973,
el estudiante desempeña el papel del agente para una reservación del
indio del comanche. Bajo decorado contemporáneo, echan al 
estudiante como un nuevo interno del congreso que ha recibido una 
letra del su congresswoman que pedía ayuda en ediciones se relacionó
con los casinos en reservaciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206946</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105658</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/reservation-controversies-then-and-now</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
