<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104550</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104550</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209786</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reflex Angle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reflexwinkel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Angle Réflexe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ângulo Reflexo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Angolo Riflesso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανακλαστική γωνία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ángulo Reflejo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate reflex angles (greater than 180 deg). The applet presents an angle (initially reflex) that the user can adjust by dragging the end points of the line segments forming the angle. As it changes it shows the angle measure and a message that indicate which type of angle it is. There a software 'detents' that make it easy capture exact angles such as 90 degrees and 180 degrees The message and angle measures can be turned off to facilitate classroom discussion. The text on the page has links to other pages defining each angle type in depth. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die Reflexwinkel zeigen (grösser als 180 Grad). Der 
applet stellt einen Winkel dar (zuerst Reflex) den der Benutzer 
justieren kann, indem er die Ende Punkte von die Striche schleppt, die
den Winkel bilden. Während er ändert, zeigt er das Winkelmaß 
und eine Meldung, die anzeigen, welcher Typ des Winkels es ist. 
Dort Software ', die es können der Rasten einer einfachen 
Sicherung genauen Winkel wie 90 Grad bilden und 180 Grad die Meldung 
und Winkelmasse abgestellt werden, um Klassenzimmerdiskussion zu 
erleichtern. Der Text auf der Seite hat Links zu anderen Seiten,
die jeden eingehenden Winkeltypen definieren. Applet kann zum 
vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les angles réflexes (180 degrés plus grands que). 
L'applet présente un angle (au commencement réflexe) que 
l'utilisateur peut ajuster en traînant les points finals de la ligne 
segments formant l'angle. Pendant qu'il change il montre la 
mesure d'angle et un message qui indiquent quel type d'angle c'est. 
Là logiciel exact facile des 'qui lui font détentes la d'un 
saisie des angles tels que 90 degrés et 180 degrés les mesures de 
message et d'angle peuvent être arrêtés pour faciliter la 
discussion de salle de classe. Le texte à la page a des liens 
à d'autres pages définissant chaque type d'angle détaillé. 
L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem os ângulos reflexos (mais extremamente de 180 graus). 
O applet apresenta um ângulo (inicialmente reflex) que o 
usuário possa ajustar arrastando os pontos de extremidade da linha 
segmentos que dão forma ao ângulo. Enquanto muda mostra a 
medida do ângulo e uma mensagem que indique que tipo de ângulo é. 
Lá software exato de um fácil ' que lhe fazem os reténs a 
captação ângulos tais como 90 graus e 180 graus as medidas da 
mensagem e do ângulo podem ser desligados para facilitar a discussão
da sala de aula. O texto na página tem as ligações a outras 
páginas que definem cada ângulo para datilografar dentro a 
profundidade. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela 
cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de 
uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o 
web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano gli angoli riflessi (più notevolmente di 180 gradi). 
Il applet presenta un angolo (inizialmente riflesso) che 
l'utente può registrare trascinando i punti finali della riga 
segmenti che formano l'angolo. Mentre cambia mostra la misura di
angolo e un messaggio che indica quale tipo di angolo è. Là 
software esatto del facile 'che gli rendono i denti d'arresto il 
bloccaggio angoli quali 90 gradi e 180 gradi le misure di angolo e del
messaggio possono essere spenti per facilitare la discussione 
dell'aula. Il testo alla pagina ha collegamenti ad altre pagine 
che definiscono ogni tipo di angolo approfondito. Il applet può
essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un 
proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo 
può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella 
libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è 
un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τις ανακλαστικές γωνίες (μεγαλύτερες από 180 
βαθμούς). Το applet παρουσιάζει μια γωνία (αρχικά 
ανακλαστική) που ο χρήστης μπορεί να ρυθμίσει με το σύρσιμο των 
σημείων τελών των τμημάτων μνήμης γραμμών που διαμορφώνουν τη 
γωνία. Δεδομένου ότι αλλάζει εμφανίζει το μέτρο γωνίας 
και ένα μήνυμα που προσδιορίζουν ποιος τύπος γωνίας είναι. 
Εκεί ένα λογισμικό "ανασχετικές συσκευέσ" που το καθιστά 
εύκολο να συλλάβει τις ακριβείς γωνίες όπως 90 βαθμοί και 
180 βαθμοί τα μέτρα μηνυμάτων και γωνίας μπορεί να κλειθεί 
για να διευκολύνει τη συζήτηση τάξεων. Το κείμενο στη 
σελίδα έχει τις συνδέσεις με άλλες σελίδες καθορίζοντας κάθε 
τύπο γωνίας σε βάθος. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο
πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. 
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran los ángulos reflejos (mayor de 180 grados). El 
applet presenta un ángulo (inicialmente reflejo) que el utilizador 
pueda ajustar arrastrando los puntos finales de la línea segmentos 
que forman el ángulo. Mientras que cambia muestra la medida del
ángulo y un mensaje que indique qué tipo de ángulo es. Allí 
software exacto de un fácil las ' que le hacen muescas captura los 
ángulos tales como 90 grados y 180 grados las medidas del mensaje y 
del ángulo se pueden dar vuelta apagado para facilitar la discusión 
de la sala de clase. El texto en la paginación tiene conexiones
a otras paginaciones que definen cada ángulo para pulsar adentro 
profundidad. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209786</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104550</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/reflex-angle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
