<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106007</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106007</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209798</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Arc </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bogen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arc</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Arco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τόξο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Arco</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of an arc. The applet shows a circle with part of it highlighted to identify the arc. Each endpoint of the arc can be dragged to resize it. The web page ahs definitions and links to the properties of an arc. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept eines Bogens zeigen. Der applet stellt
dar, daß ein Kreis mit Teil von ihm markierte, um den Bogen zu 
kennzeichnen. Jeder Endpunkt des Bogens kann geschleppt werden, 
um ihn die Größe neu zu bestimmen. Die Webseite ahs 
Definitionen und die Links zu den Eigenschaften eines Bogens. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept d'un arc. L'applet montre que un 
cercle avec une partie de lui a mis en valeur pour identifier l'arc. 
Chaque point final de l'arc peut être traîné pour le remettre
à la côte. Les définitions et les liens d'ahs de page Web 
aux propriétés d'un arc. L'applet peut être agrandi à la 
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito de um arco. O applet mostra que um 
círculo com parte dele destacou para identificar o arco. Cada 
endpoint do arco pode ser arrastado para resize o. As 
definições e as ligações dos ahs do Web page às propriedades de 
um arco. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto di un arco. Il applet mostra che un 
cerchio con la parte di esso ha evidenziato per identificare l'arco. 
Ogni punto finale dell'arco può essere trascinato per 
ridimensionarlo. Le definizioni ed i collegamenti dei ahs di Web
page alle proprietà di un arco. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια ενός τόξου. Το applet εμφανίζει
έναν κύκλο με μέρος από το που τονίζεται για να προσδιορίσει το 
τόξο. Κάθε σημείο τέλους του τόξου μπορεί να σέρθεί για 
να το επαναταξινομήσει. Οι ορισμοί και οι συνδέσεις 
ιστοσελίδας ahs με τις ιδιότητες ενός τόξου. Το Applet
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto de un arco. El applet muestra que un 
círculo con la parte de él destacó para identificar el arco. 
Cada punto final del arco se puede arrastrar para volverlo a 
clasificar según el tamaño. Las definiciones y las conexiones 
de los ahs del Web page a las características de un arco. El 
applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el 
uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la
sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier 
web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida.
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209798</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106007</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/arc</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
