<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108300</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108300</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212688</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Plow that Broke the Plains</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Pflug, der die Ebenen brach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La charrue qui a cassé les plaines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O arado que quebrou as planícies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'aratro che ha rotto le pianure</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το άροτρο που έσπασε τις πεδιάδες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El arado que rompió los llanos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This thirties era US Government film from Kansas State University chronicles the boom and bust agriculture on the High Plains. The first section of the film is devoted to the establishment of mechanized agriculture and how it contributed to crop productivity gains. The final section of the film recounts bleak dust bowl conditions, including the migration of displaced farmers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser dreißiger Jahre Ära US Regierung Film von
der Kansas Landesuniversität zeichnet die Hochkonjunktur- und 
Büstelandwirtschaft auf den hohen Ebenen auf. Das erste Kapitel
des Filmes wird der Einrichtung der mechanisierten Landwirtschaft 
gewidmet und wie es zu den Getreideproduktivitätgewinnen beitrug. 
Das abschließende Kapitel des Filmes zählt kahle 
Trockengebietbedingungen, einschließlich das Umsiedeln verlegte 
Landwirte nach.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce film de gouvernement des USA d'ère d'années 
'30 d'université de l'Etat du Kansas fait la chronique de 
l'agriculture de perche et de buste sur les hautes plaines. La 
première section du film est consacrée à l'établissement de 
l'agriculture mécanisée et comment elle a contribué aux gains de 
productivité de collecte. La section finale du film raconte des
conditions mornes de cuvette de poussière, y compris le transfert des
fermiers déplacés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta película do governo dos E. U. da era dos 
thirties da universidade de estado de Kansas chronicles a agricultura 
do crescimento e do busto nas planícies elevadas. A primeira 
seção da película é devotada ao estabelecimento da agricultura 
mechanized e como contribuiu aos ganhos da produtividade da colheita. 
A seção final da película recounts condições bleak da bacia
de poeira, including a migração de fazendeiros deslocados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa pellicola di governo degli Stati Uniti di 
era di thirties da Kansas Dichiara i chronicles 
dell'università l'agricoltura del busto e dell'asta sulle alte 
pianure. La prima sezione della pellicola è dedicata 
all'istituzione dell'agricoltura meccanizzata e come ha contribuito ai
guadagni di rendimento del raccolto. La sezione finale della 
pellicola racconta i termini brulli della ciotola di polvere, compreso
l'espansione dei coltivatori spostati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ταινία αμερικανικής κυβέρνησης εποχής 
δεκαετιών του '30 από το κρατικό πανεπιστήμιο του Κάνσας 
εξιστορεί κατά γράμμα το βραχίονα και τη γεωργία αποτυχιών στις 
υψηλές πεδιάδες. Το πρώτο τμήμα της ταινίας αφιερώνεται 
στην καθιέρωση της μηχανοποιημένης γεωργίας και πώς συνέβαλε στα 
κέρδη παραγωγικότητας συγκομιδών. Το τελικό τμήμα της 
ταινίας εξιστορεί τους ψυχρούς όρους κύπελλων σκόνης, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της μετανάστευσης των μετατοπισμένων αγροτών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta película del gobierno de los E.E.U.U. de la 
era de los años 30 de la universidad de estado de Kansas chronicles 
la agricultura del auge y del busto en los llanos altos. La 
primera sección de la película se dedica al establecimiento de la 
agricultura mecanizada y cómo contribuyó a los aumentos de la 
productividad de la cosecha. La sección final de la película 
contó de nuevo condiciones tristes del tazón de fuente de polvo, 
incluyendo la migración de granjeros desplazados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212688</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108300</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-plow-that-broke-the-plains</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
