<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105762</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105762</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086824</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Shew Yourselves to be Freemen": Herman Husband and the North Carolina Regulators, 1769</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Shew, um Ehrenbürger zu sein": Herman 
Ehemann und die Nord-Carolina Regler, 1769</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"shew pour être des citoyens d'honneur" : 
Mari de Herman et les régulateurs du nord de la Caroline, 
1769</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"shew para ser freemen": Marido de Herman e 
os reguladores de North.carolina, 1769</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"shew per essere freemen": Marito di Herman 
ed i regolatori del North.carolina, 1769</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Shew οι ίδιοι για να είναι ελεύθεροι πολίτεσ": 
Θ*Χερμαν Husband και οι ρυθμιστές της βόρειας Καρολίνας, 
1769</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"shew para ser freemen": Marido y los 
reguladores de Carolina del Norte, 1769 de Herman</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the decade preceding the American Revolution, settlers spilling into new inland settlements created increased social conflict along with economic opportunity. Those living in the backcountry demanded better political representation in the colonial government, as well as government action to remove Indians from those inland areas. The North Carolina Regulator movement of farmers, tenants, and laborers challenged the government in the 1760s; they accused the coastal elite of corruption and monopolization of government offices. Often settlers found land speculators had already claimed the best lands. Herman Husband, the author of this tract, was the most prominent agitator in the regulator movement. A man of great contradictions, he held land grants of over 8000 acres yet also advanced new democratic ideas in his writings. In this pamphlet he challenged the undemocratic basis of Carolina's government and urged his fellow backcountry residents to vote out their corrupt representatives.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Dekade, welche die amerikanische Umdrehung 
vorangeht, erstellten die Siedleren, die in neue inländische 
Regelungen verschüttet werden, erhöhte Sozial$überschneidung 
zusammen mit ökonomischer Gelegenheit. Die, die in der 
backcountry verlangten besseren politischen Darstellung in der 
Kolonialregierung, sowie Regierung Tätigkeit leben, um Inder von 
jenen inländischen Bereichen zu löschen. Die Nord-Carolina 
Reglerbewegung der Landwirte, der Pächter und der Arbeiter forderte 
die Regierung im 1760s heraus; sie beschuldigten die 
Küstenauslese von der Korruption und monopolization von den 
Regierungsstellen. Häufig fanden Siedleren Landspekulantn 
hatten behauptet bereits die besten Länder. Herman Ehemann, der
Autor dieser Fläche, war der vorstehendste Quirl in der 
Reglerbewegung. Ein Mann der großen Widersprüche, hielt er an,
Landbewilligungen von über 8000 Morgen dennoch rückte auch neue 
demokratische Ideen in seinen Schreiben vor. In dieser 
Flugschrift forderte er die undemocratic Grundlage von Regierung 
Carolinas heraus und drängte seine Mitbackcountry Bewohner, aus ihren
verdorbenen Repräsentanten zu wählen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans la décennie précédant la révolution 
américaine, les colons se renversant dans de nouveaux règlements 
intérieurs ont créé le conflit social accru avec l'occasion 
économique. Ceux vivant dans la représentation politique 
meilleure exigée backcountry dans le gouvernement colonial, aussi 
bien que l'action de gouvernement pour retirer des Indiens de ces 
zones intérieures. Le mouvement du nord de régulateur de 
la Caroline des fermiers, des locataires, et des travailleurs a 
défié le gouvernement dans le 1760s ; ils accusent l'élite 
côtière de la corruption et le monopolization des bureaux de 
gouvernement. Souvent les colons ont trouvé des spéculateurs 
de terre avaient déjà réclamé les meilleures terres. Le mari
de Herman, l'auteur de cette région, était l'agitateur le plus en 
avant dans le mouvement de régulateur. Un homme de grandes 
contradictions, il a tenu des concessions de terre de plus de 8000 
acres pourtant a également avancé de nouvelles idées démocratiques
dans ses écritures. En cette brochure il a défié la base 
antidémocratique du gouvernement de la Caroline et a invité ses 
résidants backcountry de camarade à voter hors de leurs 
représentants altérés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na década que precede a volta americana, os 
settlers que derramam em estabelecimentos inland novos criaram o 
conflito social aumentado junto com a oportunidade econômica. 
Aqueles que vivem na respresentação política melhor exijida 
backcountry no governo colonial, as.well.as a ação do governo para 
remover os indians daquelas áreas inland. O movimento do 
regulador de North.carolina dos fazendeiros, dos tenants, e dos 
laborers desafiou o governo no 1760s; acusam o elite litoral do 
corruption e o monopolization de escritórios de governo. 
Frequentemente os settlers encontraram speculators da terra 
tinham reivindicado já as mais melhores terras. O marido de 
Herman, autor deste intervalo, era o agitador o mais proeminente no 
movimento do regulador. Um homem de contradictions grandes, 
prendeu concessões da terra sobre de 8000 acres contudo avançou 
também idéias democráticas novas em suas escritas. Neste 
panfleto desafiou a base undemocratic do governo de Carolina e incitou
seus residentes backcountry do companheiro votar para fora de seus 
representantes corrupt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella decade che precede la rivoluzione americana,
i settlers che si rovesciano nei nuovi stabilimenti interni hanno 
creato il conflitto sociale aumentato con l'occasione economica. 
Quelli che vivono nella rappresentazione politica migliore 
richiesta backcountry nel governo coloniale, così come l'azione di 
governo per rimuovere gli indiani da quelle zone interne. Il 
movimento del regolatore del North.carolina dei coltivatori, degli 
inquilini e dei lavoratori ha sfidato il governo nel 1760s; 
accusano l'elite litoranea della corruzione ed il monopolization
dei servizi governativi. I settlers hanno trovato spesso gli 
speculatori della terra già avevano esatto le terre migliori. 
Il marito di Herman, l'autore di questo tratto, era l'agitatore 
più prominente nel movimento del regolatore. Un uomo delle 
contraddizioni grandi, ha tenuto le concessioni della terra oltre di 
8000 acri tuttavia egualmente ha avanzato le nuove idee democratiche 
nelle sue scritture. In questo opuscolo ha sfidato la base 
undemocratic del governo della Carolina ed ha invitato i suoi 
residenti backcountry del collega a votare verso l'esterno i loro 
rappresentanti corrotti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δεκαετία που προηγείται της αμερικανικής 
επανάστασης, οι άποικοι που ανατρέπουν στις νέες εσωτερικές 
τακτοποιήσεις δημιούργησαν την αυξανόμενη κοινωνική σύγκρουση 
μαζί με την οικονομική ευκαιρία. Εκείνοι που ζουν στη 
backcountry απαιτημένη καλύτερη πολιτική αντιπροσώπευση στην 
αποικιακή κυβέρνηση, καθώς επίσης και την κυβερνητική ενέργεια 
να απομακρυθούν Ινδοί από εκείνες τις εσωτερικές περιοχές. 
Η κυκλοφορία ρυθμιστών της βόρειας Καρολίνας των αγροτών, 
των μισθωτών, και των laborers προκάλεσε την κυβέρνηση στο 
1760s  κατηγόρησαν την παράκτια ελίτ για τη δωροδοκία και
το monopolization των κυβερνητικών γραφείων. Συχνά οι 
άποικοι βρήκαν οι παίκτες χρηματιστηρίου ότι εδάφους είχαν 
απαιτήσει ήδη τα καλύτερα εδάφη. Ο Herman Husband, ο 
συντάκτης αυτού του κομματιού, ήταν ο πιό προεξέχων ταραχοποιός
στη μετακίνηση ρυθμιστών. Ένα άτομο των μεγάλων 
αντιφάσεων, κράτησε οι επιχορηγήσεις ότι εδάφους πάνω από 
8000 στρεμμάτων ακόμα επίσης προώθησαν τις νέες δημοκρατικές 
ιδέες στις γραφές του. Σε αυτό το τεύχος προκάλεσε τη μη 
δημοκρατική βάση της κυβέρνησης της Καρολίνας και ώθησε τους 
συντροφικούς backcountry κατοίκους του για να ψηφίσει έξω τους 
διεφθαρμένους αντιπροσώπους τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la década que precedía la revolución 
americana, los colonos que se derramaban en nuevos establecimientos 
interiores crearon conflicto social creciente junto con oportunidad 
económica. Ésos que viven en la representación política 
mejor exigida backcountry en el gobierno colonial, así como la 
acción del gobierno para quitar a indios de esas áreas interiores. 
El movimiento del regulador de Carolina del Norte de granjeros, 
de arrendatarios, y de trabajadores desafió el gobierno en el 1760s; 
acusan la élite costera de la corrupción y el monopolization 
de oficinas gubernamentales. Los colonos encontraron a menudo a 
especuladores de la pista habían demandado ya las mejores pistas. 
El marido de Herman, el autor de esta zona, era el mezclador 
más prominente del movimiento del regulador. Un hombre de 
grandes contradicciones, él llevó a cabo concesiones de la pista 
sobre de 8000 acres con todo también avanzó nuevas ideas 
democráticas en sus escrituras. En este folleto él desafió la
base undemocratic del gobierno de Carolina e impulsó a sus residentes
backcountry del compañero votar fuera de sus representantes 
corruptos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086824</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105762</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shew-yourselves-to-be-freemen-herman-husband-and-the-north-carolina-regulators-1769</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
