<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103498</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103498</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087391</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"An Independent Destiny for America": Charles A. Lindbergh on Isolationism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein unabhängiges Schicksal für Amerika": 
Charles A. Lindbergh auf Isolationismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un destin indépendant pour l'Amérique" : 
Charles A. Lindbergh sur l'Isolationnisme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um destiny independente para América": 
Charles A. Lindbergh em Isolationism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un destino indipendente per l'America": 
Charles A. Lindbergh su Isolationism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα ανεξάρτητο πεπρωμένο για την Αμερική": 
Θ*Θχαρλες A. Lindbergh στον απομονωτισμό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un destino Independiente para América": 
Charles A. Lindbergh en Aislacionismo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The interwar peace movement was arguably the largest mass movement of the 1920s and 1930s, a mobilization often overlooked in the wake of the broad popular consensus that ultimately supported the U.S. involvement in World War II. The destruction wrought in World War I (known in the 1920s and 1930s as the "Great War") and the cynical nationalist politics of the Versailles Treaty had left Americans disillusioned with the Wilsonian crusade to save the world for democracy. Senate investigations of war profiteering and shady dealings in the World War I munitions industry both expressed and deepened widespread skepticism about wars of ideals. On the right wing of the antiwar movement, Charles A. Lindbergh, popular hero of American aviation, was a champion of diehard isolationism and a prominent member of the America-First Committee, organized in September 1940. In this 1941 speech, he drew on a time-honored theme of American exceptionalism as he urged his listeners to avoid entanglements with Europe.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die interwar Friedensbewegung war diskutierbar 
die größte Massenbewegung der zwanziger Jahre und der dreißiger 
Jahre, eine Mobilisierung, die häufig unmittelbar nach der 
ausgedehnten populären Übereinstimmung übersehen wurde, die 
schließlich die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Miteinbeziehung im Zweiten 
Weltkrieg unterstützte. Die Zerstörung, die im Ersten 
Weltkrieg wrought sind (bekannt in den zwanziger Jahren und in den 
dreißiger Jahren als der "große Krieg") und die zynische 
nationalistische Politik des Versailles Vertrags hatten die linken 
Amerikaner, die mit dem Wilsonian Kreuzzug ernüchtert wurden, um die 
Welt für Demokratie zu sichern. Senatuntersuchungen von Krieg 
Profiteering und schattige Umgang in der Erster Weltkrieg 
Munitionsindustrie drückten aus und vertieften weitverbreitete 
Skepsis über Kriege von Idealen. Auf dem rechten Flügel der 
Antikriegsbewegung, war Charles A. Lindbergh, populärer Held der 
amerikanischen Luftfahrt, ein Meister des diehard Isolationismus und 
ein vorstehendes Bauteil des Amerika-Ersten Ausschusses, organisiert 
im September 1940. In dieser Rede 1941 zeichnete er auf ein 
altehrwürdiges Thema des amerikanischen exceptionalism, während er 
seine Zuhörer drängte, Verwicklungen mit Europa zu vermeiden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement de paix d'entre-deux guerres était 
discutablement le plus grand mouvement de masse des années 20 et des 
années 30, une mobilisation souvent négligée à la suite du large 
consensus populaire qui a finalement supporté l'intervention des 
ETATS-UNIS dans la deuxième guerre mondiale. La destruction 
travaillée dans la Première Guerre Mondiale (connue dans les années
20 et les années 30 comme "grande guerre") et la politique 
nationaliste cynique du Traité de Versailles ont eu les Américains 
gauches désillusionnés avec la croisade de Wilsonian pour 
sauvegarder le monde pour la démocratie. Les investigations de 
sénat sur le mercantilisme de guerre et les rapport d'affaires 
ombreuses dans l'industrie de munitions de Première Guerre Mondiale 
ont exprimé et ont approfondi le scepticisme répandu au sujet des 
guerres des idéaux. Sur l'aile droite du mouvement pacifiste, 
Charles A. Lindbergh, héros populaire d'aviation américaine, était 
un champion d'isolationnisme tenace et un membre en avant du 
l'Amérique-Premier Comité, organisé en septembre 1940. Dans 
ce discours 1941, il a dessiné sur un thème consacré 
d'exceptionalism américain pendant qu'il invitait ses auditeurs à 
éviter des enchevêtrements avec l'Europe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento interwar da paz era arguably o 
movimento maciço o maior dos 1920s e dos 1930s, um mobilization 
negligenciado frequentemente na vigília do consenso popular largo que
suportou finalmente a participação de ESTADOS UNIDOS na segunda 
guerra mundial. A destruição feita no world.war.i (sabido nos 
1920s e nos 1930s como "a guerra grande") e a política nacionalista 
cínica do tratado de Versalhes tiveram os americanos esquerdos 
disillusioned com o crusade de Wilsonian para conservar o mundo para a
democracia. As investigações do senate do profiteering da 
guerra e as transações shady na indústria dos munitions do 
world.war.i  expressaram e aprofundaram skepticism difundido sobre 
guerras dos ideals. Na asa direita do movimento antiwar, Charles
A. Lindbergh, herói popular da aviação americana, era um campeão 
do isolationism do diehard e um membro proeminente do 
América-Primeiro comitê, organizado em setembro 1940. Neste 
discurso 1941, desenhou em um tema time-honored do exceptionalism 
americano enquanto incitou seus ouvintes evitar entanglements com 
Europa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento interwar di pace era discutibilmente
il più grande movimento totale degli anni 20 e dei 1930s, una 
mobilizzazione trascurata spesso come conseguenza di vasto consenso 
popolare che infine ha sostenuto la partecipazione degli STATI UNITI 
alla seconda guerra mondiale. La distruzione modellata nel 
world.war.i (conosciuto negli anni 20 e nei 1930s come "la guerra 
grande") e la politica nazionalista cinica del Trattato de Versailles 
hanno avute Americani di sinistra disillusi con il crusade di 
Wilsonian per salvare il mondo per la democrazia. Le indagini 
del senato sull'affarismo di guerra ed i rapporti d'affari ombreggiati
nell'industria dei munitions di world.war.i sia hanno espresso che 
approfondito lo scetticismo diffuso circa le guerre degli ideali. 
Sull'ala di destra del movimento pacifista, Charles A. 
Lindbergh, hero popolare di aeronautica americana, era un campione del
isolationism di diehard e un membro prominente del America-Primo 
comitato, organizzato nel mese di settembre del 1940. In questo 
discorso 1941, ha dissipato su un tema consacrato del exceptionalism 
americano mentre ha invitato i suoi ascoltatori a evitare gli intrichi
con Europa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μετακίνηση ειρήνης μεσοπολέμου ήταν αμφισβητήσιμα η
μεγαλύτερη μαζική μετακίνηση της δεκαετίας του '20 και της 
δεκαετίας του '30, μια κινητοποίηση που αγνοήθηκε συχνά αμέσως 
μετά την ευρεία δημοφιλή συναίνεση που υποστήριξε τελικά την 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ συμμετοχή στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Η καταστροφή
επεξεργασμένη στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι (γνωστό στη δεκαετία του 
'20 και τη δεκαετία του '30 ως "μεγάλος πόλεμοσ") και η κυνική 
εθνικιστική πολιτική της Συνθήκης των Βερσαλλιών είχαν αφήσει 
Αμερικανούς απογοήτεψαν με τη σταυροφορία Wilsonian για να 
σώσουν τον κόσμο για τη δημοκρατία. Οι έρευνες Συγκλήτου 
για πολεμικό profiteering και τις σκιερές συναλλαγές στον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι βιομηχανία πυρομαχικών και εξέφρασαν και 
εμβάθυναν το διαδεδομένο σκεπτικισμό για τους πολέμους των 
ιδανικών. Στη δεξιά της αντιπολεμικής μετακίνησης, 
Charles A. Lindbergh, δημοφιλής ήρωας της αμερικανικής 
αεροπορίας, ήταν πρωτοπόρος του αδιάλλακτου απομονωτισμού και 
ένα προεξέχον μέλος της Αμερική-πρώτης Επιτροπής, που 
οργανώθηκε τον Σεπτέμβριο του 1940. Σε αυτήν την ομιλία 
του 1941, επέσυρε την προσοχή σε ένα time-honored θέμα του 
αμερικανικού exceptionalism δεδομένου ότι ώθησε τους ακροατές 
του για να αποφύγει τις εμπλοκές με την Ευρώπη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento interwar de la paz era discutible 
el movimiento total más grande de los años 20 y de los años 30, una
movilización pasada por alto a menudo en la estela del amplio 
consenso popular que utilizó en última instancia la implicación de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en la Segunda Guerra Mundial. La destrucción 
labrada en la Primera Guerra Mundial (sabida en los años 20 y los 
años 30 como la "gran guerra") y la política nacionalista cínica 
del tratado de Versalles tenían americanos izquierdos desilusionados 
con la cruzada de Wilsonian para salvar el mundo para la 
democracia. Las investigaciones del senado del mercantilismo de 
la guerra y las reparticiones sombrías en la industria de las 
municiones de la Primera Guerra Mundial expresaron y profundizaron 
escepticismo extenso sobre guerras de ideales. En el ala derecha
del movimiento pacifista, Charles A. Lindbergh, héroe popular de la 
aviación americana, era un campeón del aislacionismo del diehard y un 
miembro prominente del Ame'rica-Primer comité, ordenado en septiembre
de 1940. En este discurso 1941, él trazó en un tema consagrado
del exceptionalism americano mientras que él impulsó a sus módulos 
de escucha evitar los enredos con Europa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087391</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103498</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-independent-destiny-for-america-charles-a-lindbergh-on-isolationism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
