<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106596</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106596</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086132</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Everything Here is  New  But the Forests": Englishman Thomas Woodcock Travels to Niagara on the Erie Canal, 1836.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"alles hier ist neu aber die Wälder": 
Engländer-Thomas Waldschnepfe reist zu Niagara auf dem Erie 
Kanal, 1836.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"tout ici est nouvelle mais les forêts" : 
l'Anglais Thomas Woodcock voyage à Niagara sur le canal 
d'Erie, 1836.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"tudo aqui é nova mas as florestas": O 
inglês Thomas Woodcock viaja a Niagara no canal de erie, 1836.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tutto qui è nuovo ma le foreste": 
L'inglese Thomas Woodcock viaggia a Niagara sul canale di Erie, 
1836.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όλα είναι εδώ νέα αλλά τα δάση": Αγγλος 
Thomas Woodcock Travels σε Niagara στο κανάλι του 
Erie, 1836.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"todo aquí es nuevo pero los bosques": El 
inglés Thomas Woodcock viaja a Niagara en el canal de Erie, 1836.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Engraver Thomas Woodcock was born in Manchester, England in 1805 and emigrated to the United States in 1830. In 1836 he took a trip to Niagara Falls, traveling north from Manhattan up the Hudson river and west on the Erie Canal. Niagara Falls was a favorite destination for tourists in the 1830s, made possible in part by the completion of the Erie Canal in 1825. The trip was popularized by authors like Basil Hall, whose 1829  Travels in North America in the Years 1827 and '28  Woodcock mentions several times here. Woodcock's narrative is noteworthy less for his appreciation of the natural wonders of the falls than for his shrewd appraisal of business practices in western New York. This selection from his private journal begins on the Erie Canal with his trip from Schenectady to Utica by packet boat.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Engraver Thomas Waldschnepfe wurde in Manchester, 
England 1805 getragen und ausgewandert in die Vereinigten Staaten 
1830. 1836 nahm er eine Reise zu den Niagara Falls und reiste 
nördlich von Manhattan herauf den Hudson Fluß und vom Westen auf dem
Erie Kanal. Niagara Falls waren eine Lieblingszieleinheit für 
Touristen im 1830s, ermöglicht im Teil durch die Beendigung des Erie 
Kanals 1825. Die Reise wurde von den Autoren wie Basilikum Hall 
popularisiert, dessen 1829 Spielräume in Nordamerika in den 
Erwähnungen der Jahre 1827 und der Waldschnepfe '28 mehrmals hier. 
Waldschnepfedarstellung ist weniger für seine Anerkennung der 
natürlichen Wunder der Fälle als für seine raffinierte Schätzung 
der Geschäftsverfahren in Westnew York bemerkenswert. Diese 
Auswahl von seinem privaten Journal fängt auf dem Erie Kanal mit 
seiner Reise von Schenectady zu Utica durch Paketboot an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le graveur Thomas Woodcock a été soutenu à 
Manchester, Angleterre en 1805 et émigré aux Etats-Unis en 1830. 
En 1836 il a pris un voyage aux automnes de Niagara, voyageant 
au nord de Manhattan vers le haut du fleuve de Hudson et d'ouest sur 
le canal d'Erie. Les automnes de Niagara étaient une 
destination préférée pour des touristes dans le 1830s, possible en 
partie par l'accomplissement du canal d'Erie en 1825. Le voyage 
a été popularisé par des auteurs comme le basilic Hall, dont les 
1829 voyages en Amérique du nord pendant les années 1827 et des
mentions de '28 Woodcock plusieurs fois ici. Le récit de 
Woodcock est remarquable moins pour son appréciation des 
merveilles normales des chutes que pour sa évaluation judicieuse des 
procédures de gestion à New York occidental. Cette sélection 
à partir de son journal privé commence sur le canal d'Erie par son 
voyage de Schenectady à Utica en le bateau de paquet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Engraver Thomas Woodcock foi carregado em Manchester, 
Inglaterra em 1805 e emigrated aos estados unidos em 1830. Em 
1836 fêz exame de um desengate às quedas de niagara, viajando para o
norte de Manhattan acima do rio de Hudson e de oeste no canal de erie.
As quedas de niagara eram um destino favorito para turistas no 
1830s, feito possível na parte pela conclusão do canal de erie em 
1825. O desengate popularized por autores como o basil Salão, 
cujos 1829 cursos em America do Norte nos anos 1827 e em mentions de 
'28 Woodcock diversas vezes aqui. A narrativa de Woodcock é 
noteworthy mais menos para sua apreciação das maravilhas naturais 
das quedas do que para seu appraisal shrewd de práticas de negócio 
em New York ocidental. Esta seleção de seu jornal confidencial
começa no canal de erie com seu desengate de Schenectady a Utica pelo
barco do pacote.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Engraver Thomas Woodcock è stato sopportato a Manchester,
Inghilterra in 1805 ed emigrato al unito Dichiara in 1830. 
In 1836 ha preso un viaggio alle cadute di niagara, mobili a 
nord da Manhattan sul fiume di Hudson e dall'ovest sul canale di Erie.
Le cadute di niagara erano una destinazione favorita per i 
turisti nel 1830s, permessa in parte dal completamento del canale di 
Erie in 1825. Il viaggio si è diffuso dagli autori come 
basilico Corridoio, di cui 1829 corse in America del Nord fra anni 
1827 e le menzioni di '28 Woodcock parecchie volte qui. La 
descrizione del Woodcock è considerevole più di meno per il suo 
apprezzamento dei wonders naturali delle cadute che per la sua 
valutazione sagace delle pratiche di affari a New York occidentale. 
Questa selezione dal suo giornale riservato comincia sul canale 
di Erie con il suo viaggio da Schenectady a Utica in crogiolo di 
pacchetto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Engraver Thomas Woodcock γεννήθηκε στο 
Μάντσεστερ, Αγγλία το 1805 και μεταναστεύω στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες το 1830. Το 1836 πήρε ένα ταξίδι στις 
πτώσεις Niagara, που ταξιδεύουν το Βορρά από το Μανχάτταν 
επάνω ο ποταμός Hudson και η δύση στο κανάλι του Erie. 
Οι πτώσεις Niagara ήταν ένας αγαπημένος προορισμός για 
τους τουρίστες στο 1830s, που έγινε πιθανός εν μέρει από την 
ολοκλήρωση του καναλιού του Erie το 1825. Το ταξίδι 
διαδόθηκε από τους συντάκτες όπως την αίθουσα βασιλικού, της 
οποίας 1829 ταξίδια στη Βόρεια Αμερική στα έτη 1827 και 
'28 η μπεκάτσα αναφέρει αρκετές φορές εδώ. Το αφήγημα 
της μπεκάτσας είναι αξιοσημείωτο λιγότεροι για την εκτίμησή του 
του φυσικού αναρωτιέται των πτώσεων απ'ό,τι για την πονηρή 
αξιολόγηση επιχειρησιακών πρακτικών του στη δυτική Νέα Υόρκη. 
Αυτή η επιλογή από το ιδιωτικό περιοδικό του αρχίζει στο 
κανάλι του Erie με το ταξίδι του από Schenectady σε Utica 
με τη βάρκα πακέτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Engraver Thomas Woodcock fue llevado en Manchester, 
Inglaterra en 1805 y emigró a los Estados Unidos en 1830. 
En 1836 él llevó un viaje las caídas de niagara, viajando al 
norte de Manhattan encima del río de Hudson y del oeste en el canal 
de Erie. Las caídas de niagara eran una destinación preferida 
para los turistas en el 1830s, hecha posible en parte por la 
terminación del canal de Erie en 1825. El viaje fue 
popularizado por los autores como la albahaca Pasillo, que 1829 
recorridos en Norteamérica en los años 1827 y las menciones de '28 
Woodcock varias veces aquí. La narrativa de Woodcock es 
significativa menos para su aprecio de las maravillas naturales de las
caídas que para su valoración astuta de las prácticas de 
negocio en Nueva York occidental. Esta selección de su diario 
privado comienza por el canal de Erie con su viaje de Schenectady a 
Utica en barco del paquete.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086132</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106596</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/everything-here-is-new-but-the-forests-englishman-thomas-woodcock-travels-to-niagara-on-the-erie-canal-1836</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
