<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108722</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108722</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086138</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Explore and Discover Observing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschen Sie und entdecken Sie das Beobachten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorez et découvrez observer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explore e descubra observar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplori e scopra l'osservazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ερευνήστε και ανακαλύψτε την παρατήρηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explore y descubra la observación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Find an Asteroid, Comet or Other Moving Solar System Object. Follow the motions of known solar system objects. Search to discover new ones. There are countless asteroids and comets orbiting the Sun. Plenty for everyone to track and map. All are interesting. Some astronomers are searching for ones that are in Near Earth Orbit and other astronomers search for dim ones way out by the orbits of Pluto and beyond.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Finden Sie einen Planetoid, Kometen oder andere 
bewegliche Solarsystem Nachricht. Folgen Sie den Bewegungen der 
bekannten Solarsystem Nachrichten. Suchen Sie, um Neue zu 
entdecken. Es gibt unzählige Planetoide und die Kometen, die 
das Sonne-viel in Umlauf bringen, damit jeder aufspürt und abbildet. 
Alle sind interessant. Einige Astronomen suchen nach 
einen, die in der nahen Masse Bahn sind und andere Astronomen nach den
schwachen Ausweg durch die Bahnen von Pluto und jenseits suchen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Trouvez un asteroïde, la comète ou tout autre 
objet mobile de système solaire. Suivez les mouvements des 
objets connus de système solaire. Recherchez pour découvrir 
des neufs. Il y a les asteroïdes innombrables et les comètes 
satellisant l'abondance du soleil pour que chacun dépiste et pour 
trace. Tous sont intéressants. Quelques astronomes 
recherchent ceux qui sont dans l'orbite proche de la terre et d'autres
astronomes recherchent les faibles la sortie par les orbites de Pluton
et là-bas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Encontre um asteroid, o cometa ou o outro objeto 
movente do sistema solar. Siga os movimentos de objetos sabidos 
do sistema solar. Procurare para descobrir novos. Há 
asteroids incontáveis e cometas que orbitam a abundância do sol para
que todos siga e trace. Todos são interessantes. Alguns 
astrónomos estão procurarando por que estão na órbita próxima da 
terra e outros astrónomos procuraram por o não ofuscantes a maneira 
para fora pelas órbitas de Pluto e além.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Trovi un asteroide, la cometa o l'altro oggetto 
commovente del sistema solare. Segua i movimenti degli oggetti 
conosciuti del sistema solare. Cerchi per scoprire i nuovi. 
Ci sono asteroidi countless e comete che orbitano intorno 
all'abbondanza del sole affinchè tutto rintraccino e per tracciare. 
Tutti sono interessanti. Alcuni astronomi stanno cercando 
ones che siano nell'orbita vicina della terra ed altri astronomi 
cercano quei fiochi l'uscita dalle orbite di Pluto e di là.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βρείτε asteroid, τον κομήτη ή άλλο κινούμενο 
αντικείμενο ηλιακών συστημάτων. Ακολουθήστε τις κινήσεις 
των γνωστών αντικειμένων ηλιακών συστημάτων. Αναζήτηση για 
να ανακαλύψει νέες. Υπάρχουν αμέτρητοι asteroids και 
κομήτες που βάζουν την αφθονία ήλιων για την καθεμία σε τροχιά 
στη διαδρομή και το χάρτη. Όλοι είναι ενδιαφέροντες. 
Μερικοί αστρονόμοι ψάχνουν για τους αυτούς που είναι στην 
κοντινή γήινη τροχιά και άλλη αναζήτηση αστρονόμων της αμυδρής 
εξόδου αυτών από τις τροχιές pluto και πέρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encuentre el asteroide, el cometa o el otro objeto
móvil de la Sistema Solar. Siga los movimientos de los objetos 
sabidos de la Sistema Solar. Busque para descubrir nuevos. 
Hay asteroides incontables y cometas que mueven en órbita 
alrededor de la abundancia del sol para que cada uno siga y asocie. 
Todos son interesantes. Algunos astrónomos están 
buscando para unos que estén en órbita cercana de la tierra y otros 
astrónomos buscan para los déviles salida por las órbitas de Pluto 
y más allá.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086138</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108722</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/explore-and-discover-observing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
