<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106412</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106412</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206595</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Camp Chase Confederate Cemetery</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lager-Verfolgung-Verbündet-Kirchhof</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cimetière de Confédéré De Chasse de Camp</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cemetery Do Confederado Da Perseguição Do 
Acampamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cimitero Del Confederato Di Inseguimento 
Dell'Accampamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ομόσπονδο νεκροταφείο αυλακώματος στρατόπεδων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cementerio Del Confederato De la Persecución Del
Campo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of Camp Chase, one of the largest prisoner-of-war camps for Confederate soldiers during the Civil War. Located on the western outskirts of Columbus, Ohio, the camp -- now a cemetery for Confederate soldiers -- played a key role in the evolution of federal policy on marking Confederate graves.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte von Lager-Verfolgung, 
eins der größten Kriegsgefangenlager für verbündete Soldaten 
während des Bürgerkrieges, der auf dem westlichen Randgebiet von
Columbus, Ohio, das Lager gelegen ist -- jetzt ein Kirchhof für 
verbündete Soldaten -- spielte eine Schlüsselrolle in der Geschichte
von Bundespolitik auf Markierung Verbündetgräbern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire de la chasse de camp, un des plus 
grands camps de prisonnier de guerre pour les soldats confédérés 
pendant la guerre civile située sur les périphéries occidentales de
Columbus, Ohio, le camp -- maintenant un cimetière pour les soldats 
confédérés -- a joué un rôle principal dans l'évolution de la 
politique fédérale sur des tombes de confédéré d'inscription.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história da perseguição do acampamento, 
um dos acampamentos os maiores do prisioneiro de guerra para soldados 
confederate durante a guerra civil situada nos outskirts ocidentais de
Columbo, Ohio, o acampamento -- agora um cemetery para soldados 
confederate -- jogou um papel chave na evolução da política federal
em sepulturas do confederado do marking.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia dell'inseguimento 
dell'accampamento, uno di più grandi accampamenti del prigioniero di 
guerra per i soldati confederati durante la guerra civile situata sui 
outskirts occidentali di Columbus, Ohio, l'accampamento -- ora un 
cimitero per i soldati confederati -- ha svolto un ruolo chiave nello 
sviluppo della politica federale sulle tombe del confederato della 
marcatura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία του αυλακώματος στρατόπεδων, ένα 
από τα μεγαλύτερα στρατόπεδα αιχμαλώτων πολέμου για τους 
ομόσπονδους στρατιώτες κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου πολέμου. 
Τοποθετημένο στα δυτικά περίχωρα του Columbus, Οχάιο, το 
στρατόπεδο -- τώρα ένα νεκροταφείο για τους ομόσπονδους 
στρατιώτες -- διαδραμάτισε έναν βασικό ρόλο στην εξέλιξη της 
ομοσπονδιακής πολιτικής για το χαρακτηρισμό των ομόσπονδων τάφων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia de la persecución del campo, 
uno de los campos más grandes del prisionero de guerra para los 
soldados confederados durante la guerra civil situada en las 
cercanías occidentales de Columbus, Ohio, el campo -- ahora un 
cementerio para los soldados confederados -- desempeñó un papel 
dominante en la evolución de la política federal en sepulcros del 
confederato de la marca.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206595</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106412</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/camp-chase-confederate-cemetery</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
