<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107877</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107877</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087572</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Survey of ICTs in Education in Africa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Übersicht von ICTs in der Ausbildung in Afrika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude d'ICTs dans l'éducation en Afrique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exame de ICTs na instrução em África</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Indagine di ICTs nella formazione in Africa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Έρευνα ICTs στην εκπαίδευση στην Αφρική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encuesta de ICTs en la educación en África</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Information for Development Program is taking the initiative to assess the state of ICT applications in education in Africa and has contracted with the Commonwealth of Learning to undertake a survey that will address the following general questions for all countries on the African continent: How are ICTs currently being used in the education sector in Africa, and what are the strategies and policies related to this use? What are the common challenges and constraints faced by African countries in this area? What is actually happening on the ground, and to what extent are donors involved?</string>
          </description>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">Africa</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Informationen für Entwicklungsprogramm nehmen
die Initiative, um den Zustand der ICT Anwendungen in der Ausbildung 
in Afrika festzusetzen und haben mit dem Commonwealth des Lernens, 
sich eine Übersicht aufzunehmen Vertrag abgeschlossen, die die 
folgenden allgemeinen Fragen für alle Länder auf dem afrikanischen 
Kontinent adressiert: Wie werden ICTs aktuell im Ausbildung 
Sektor in Afrika verwendet, und was ist die Strategien und die 
Politik, die auf diesem Gebrauch in Verbindung gestanden werden? 
Was sind die geläufigen Herausforderungen und die Begrenzungen,
die durch afrikanische Länder in diesem Bereich gegenübergestellt 
werden? Was geschieht wirklich aus den Grund und in welchem 
Ausmass werden Spender mit.einbezogen?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'information pour le programme de développement 
prend l'initiative pour évaluer l'état d'applications d'ICT dans 
l'éducation en Afrique et s'est contractée avec le Commonwealth de 
l'étude pour entreprendre une étude qui adressera les questions 
générales suivantes pour tous les pays sur le continent africain : 
Comment ICTs sont-elles actuel sont-ils utilisés dans le 
secteur d'éducation en Afrique, et que les stratégies et les 
politiques liées à cette utilisation ? Quels sont les défis 
et les contraintes communs faits face par les pays africains dans 
cette zone ? Que se produit réellement sur la terre, et dans 
quelle mesure des donateurs est impliqué ?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A informação para o programa de desenvolvimento 
está fazendo exame da iniciativa para avaliar o estado de 
aplicações de ICT na instrução em África e contraiu-se com a 
comunidade da aprendizagem empreender um exame que se dirija às 
seguintes perguntas gerais para todos os países no continente 
africano: Como ICTs atualmente estão sendo usados no setor da 
instrução em África, e que são as estratégias e as políticas 
relacionadas a este uso? Que são os desafios e os confinamentes
comuns enfrentados por países africanos nesta área? Que estão
acontecendo realmente na terra, e a os que extensão os doadores são 
envolvidos?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le informazioni per il programma di sviluppo 
stanno prendendo l'iniziativa per valutare il dichiarare delle 
applicazioni di ICT nella formazione in Africa e si sono contratte con
il commonwealth di imparare intraprendere un'indagine che rivolgere le
seguenti domande generali per tutti i paesi sul continente africano: 
Come ICTs attualmente stanno usandi nel settore di formazione in
Africa e che cosa sono le strategie e le politiche relative a questo 
uso? Che cosa sono le sfide ed i vincoli comuni affrontati dai 
paesi africani in questa zona? Che cosa realmente sta accadendo 
sulla terra ed in che misura donatori è coinvolto?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι πληροφορίες για το πρόγραμμα ανάπτυξης παίρνουν την
πρωτοβουλία να αξιολογηθεί η κατάσταση των εφαρμογών ICT στην 
εκπαίδευση στην Αφρική και έχουν συμβληθεί με την Κοινοπολιτεία 
της εκμάθησης να αναλαμβάνεται μια έρευνα που θα εξετάσει τις 
ακόλουθες γενικές ερωτήσεις για όλες τις χώρες στην αφρικανική 
ήπειρο: Πώς είναι ICTs που χρησιμοποιούνται αυτήν την 
περίοδο στον τομέα της εκπαίδευσης στην Αφρική, και ποιες είναι 
οι στρατηγικές και οι πολιτικές σχετικές με αυτήν την χρήση; 
Ποιες είναι οι κοινοί προκλήσεις και οι περιορισμοί που 
αντιμετωπίζονται από τις της Αφρικής χώρες σε αυτήν την περιοχή;
Τι συμβαίνει πραγματικά στο έδαφος, και μέχρι ποιό σημείο 
οι χορηγοί αναμιγνύονται;</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La información para el programa de desarrollo 
está tomando la iniciativa para evaluar el estado de las aplicaciones
de ICT en la educación en África y ha contraído con la Commonwealth
de aprender emprender una encuesta que trate las preguntas generales 
siguientes para todos los países en el continente africano: 
¿Cómo ICTs actualmente se están utilizando en el sector de la 
educación en África, y cuál son las estrategias y las políticas 
relacionadas con este uso? ¿Cuáles son los desafíos y los 
apremios comunes hechos frente por los países africanos en esta 
área? ¿Qué está sucediendo realmente en la tierra, y en qué 
medida los donantes están implicados?</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087572</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107877</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/icts-in-africa</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
