<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108746</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108746</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086362</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">James Haughton on Racism in the House of Labor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">James Haughton auf Rassismus im Haus der Arbeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">James Haughton sur le racisme dans la Chambre
du travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">James Haughton no racism na casa do trabalho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">James Haughton su razzismo nella Camera del 
Lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">James Haughton στο ρατσισμό στη Βουλή της 
εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">James Haughton en racismo en la casa del trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As the Civil Rights movement began to dismantle formal racial segregation, African-American union activists such as James Houghton sought to integrate the workplace by challenging racial segregation in industrial unions. Houghton was active in the Negro American Labor Council, founded in 1960, before Cold War fears of communist infiltration disbanded the organization. Frustrated by what he saw as a lack of militancy to combat discrimination within the labor movement, Houghton founded the Harlem Unemployment Center, which later became Harlem Fight Back, to challenge racial discrimination in the skilled building trades. The organization played an important role in creating equal employment opportunity programs, increasing minority hiring at construction sites, and forcing unions to open their membership rolls.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während die Zivilrechtbewegung anfing, formale 
rassische Abtrennung abzubauen, suchten Afrikanisch-Amerikanische 
Anschlußaktivisten wie James Houghton, den Arbeitsplatz durch 
schwierige rassische Abtrennung in den Industriegewerkschaften zu 
integrieren. Houghton war im Schwarze-Amerikaner-Arbeit Rat 
aktiv, gegründet 1960, bevor Furcht des kalten Krieges vor 
kommunistischer Infiltration die Organisation auflöste. 
Frustriert durch was er als Mangel an Militancy sah, um 
Unterscheidung innerhalb der Arbeiterbewegung zu bekämpfen, gründete
Houghton die Harlem Arbeitslosigkeit Mitte, die später Harlem Kampf 
zurück wurde, um rassische Unterscheidung im erfahrenen Baugewerbe 
herauszufordern. Die Organisation spielte eine wichtige Rolle, 
wenn sie die gleichen Beschäftigungsmöglichkeitprogramme erstellte 
und die Minorität erhöhte, die an den Baustellen anstellt, und das 
Erzwingen der Anschlüße, um ihre Mitgliedschaft zu öffnen rollt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que le mouvement de droits civiques 
commençait à démanteler la ségrégation raciale formelle, les 
activistes afro-américains des syndicats tels que James Houghton ont
recherché à intégrer le lieu de travail par ségrégation raciale 
provocante dans les syndicats ouvriers. Houghton était en 
activité au Conseil de travail d'Américain de nègre, fondé en 
1960, avant que les craintes de guerre froide de l'infiltration 
communiste aient congédié l'organisation. Frustré par ce 
qu'il a vu comme manque de militantisme pour combattre la 
discrimination dans le mouvement de travail, Houghton a fondé le 
centre du chômage de Harlem, qui plus tard est devenu combat de 
Harlem en arrière, pour défier la discrimination raciale dans 
les industries du bâtiment habiles. L'organisation a joué un 
rôle important en créant des programmes égaux d'offre d'emploi, 
augmentant la minorité louant aux chantiers de construction, et 
forcer des syndicats pour ouvrir leur adhésion roule.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto o movimento das direitas civis começou a
desmontar o segregation racial formal, as activistas 
Africano-Americanas da união tais como James Houghton procuraram 
integrar o workplace por segregation racial challenging em uniões 
industriais. Houghton foi ativo no conselho do trabalho do 
americano do negro, fundado em 1960, antes que os medos da guerra fria
do infiltration comunista disbanded a organização. Frustrado 
por o que viu como uma falta do militancy para combater a 
discriminação dentro do movimento labor, Houghton fundou o centro do
desemprego de Harlem, que se transformou mais tarde luta de Harlem 
para trás, para desafiar a discriminação racial nos comércios de 
edifício hábeis. A organização jogou um papel importante em 
criar os programas iguais da oportunidade de emprego, aumentando o 
minority que emprega em locais de construção, e forçar uniões para
abrir sua sociedade rola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre il movimento di diritti civili ha 
cominciato a smantellare la segregazione razziale convenzionale, gli 
attivisti Africano-Americani del sindacato quale James Houghton 
hanno cercato di integrare il posto di lavoro dalla segregazione 
razziale challenging in sindacati industriali. Houghton era 
attivo nel Consiglio Di lavoro americano del negro, fondato in 1960,
prima che i timori di guerra fredda di infiltrazione comunista 
disperdessero l'organizzazione. Frustrato da che cosa ha visto 
come mancanza di militanza per combattere la distinzione 
all'interno del movimento di lavoro, Houghton ha fondato il centro 
di disoccupazione di Harlem, che più successivamente si è 
transformato in in lotta di Harlem indietro, per sfidare la 
distinzione razziale nei nei commerci di costruzione esperti. 
L'organizzazione ha svolto un ruolo importante nella creazione 
dei programmi uguali di possibilità d'impiego, aumentanti la 
minoranza che assume ai cantieri e forzare i sindacati per aprire il 
loro insieme dei membri rotola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι η μετακίνηση αστικών δικαιωμάτων 
άρχισε να αποσυναρμολογεί τον επίσημο φυλετικό διαχωρισμό, τα 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά ενεργά στελέχη ένωσης όπως james 
Houghton επιδίωξαν να ενσωματώσουν τον εργασιακό χώρο με την 
πρόκληση του φυλετικού διαχωρισμού στις βιομηχανικές ενώσεις. 
Το Houghton δραστηριοποιήθηκε στο αμερικανικό Συμβούλιο 
εργασίας νέγρων, που ιδρύθηκε το 1960, προτού να απολύσουν οι 
φόβοι ψυχρού πολέμου της κομμουνιστικής διήθησης την οργάνωση. 
Ματαιωμένος από αυτό που εβλέίδε ως έλλειψη 
μαχητικότητας για να καταπολεμήσει τη διάκριση μέσα στη 
μετακίνηση εργασίας, Houghton ίδρυσε το κέντρο ανεργίας 
Harlem, που έγινε αργότερα πλάτη πάλης Harlem, για να 
προκαλέσει τη φυλετική διάκριση στα ειδικευμένα εμπόρια 
οικοδόμησης. Η οργάνωση διαδραμάτισε έναν σημαντικό ρόλο 
στη δημιουργία των ίσων προγραμμάτων ευκαιρίας απασχόλησης, την 
αύξηση της μίσθωσης μειονότητας επί των τόπων κατασκευής, και 
τον καταναγκασμό των ενώσεων για να ανοίξει τους ρόλους ιδιότητας
μέλους τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que el movimiento de las derechas civiles
comenzó a desmontar la segregación racial formal, los activistas 
Africano-Americanos de la unión tales como James Houghton intentaron 
integrar el lugar de trabajo por la segregación racial desafiadora en
uniones industriales. Houghton era activo en el consejo del 
trabajo del americano del negro, fundado en 1960, antes de que los 
miedos de la guerra fría de la infiltración comunista disolvieran la
organización. Frustrado por lo que él vio como carencia de la 
militancia para combatir la discriminación dentro del movimiento de 
trabajo, Houghton fundó el centro del desempleo de Harlem, que se 
convirtió en más adelante lucha de Harlem detrás, para desafiar la 
discriminación racial en los comercios de edificio expertos. La
organización desempeñó un papel importante en crear los programas 
iguales de la posibilidad de empleo, aumentando a la minoría que 
empleaba en los emplazamientos de la obra, y forzar uniones para abrir
su calidad de miembro rueda.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086362</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108746</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/james-haughton-on-racism-in-the-house-of-labor</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
