<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105831</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105831</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212839</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Toxic and Harmful Algal Blooms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Giftige und schädliche Algenblüte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fleurs d'algues toxiques et nocives</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Flores algal tóxicas e prejudiciais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fioriture d'alghe tossiche e nocive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τοξικές και επιβλαβείς φυκώδεις ανθίσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Floraciones algal tóxicas y dañosas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Primarily through the use of engaging graphics, this resource outlines where Toxic and Harmful Algal Blooms (HABs) occur in U.S. waters. It also addresses the differences between toxic and non-toxic HABs, which organisms in the food web are affected, how specific toxins work and the symptoms associated with them, and the causative phytoplankton species.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hauptsächlich durch den Gebrauch von Engagieren 
der Graphiken, wässert umreißen dieses Hilfsmittels, in denen 
giftige und schädliche Algenblüte (HABs) in VEREINIGTEN STAATEN 
auftritt. Es adressiert auch die Unterschiede zwischen giftigem 
und ungiftigem HABs, das organismen im Nahrungsmittelweb beeinflußt 
werden, wie spezifische Giftstoffe und die Symptome arbeiten, die mit 
ihnen verbunden sind und die begründende Phytoplanktonsorte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Principalement par l'utilisation d'engager des 
graphiques, les contours de cette ressource où les fleurs d'algues 
toxiques et nocives (HABs) se produisent aux ETATS-UNIS arrose. 
Il adresse également les différences entre toxique et HABs 
non-toxique, que des organizations dans le Web de nourriture sont 
affecté, comment les toxines spécifiques fonctionnent et les 
symptômes liés à eux, et les espèces causatives de 
phytoplancton.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Primeiramente com o uso de acoplar gráficos, os 
esboços deste recurso onde as flores algal tóxicas e prejudiciais 
(HABs) ocorrem em ESTADOS UNIDOS molham. Dirige-se também às 
diferenças entre tóxico e HABs non-toxic, que os organismos no Web 
do alimento são afetados, como os toxins específicos trabalham e os 
sintomas associados com ele, e a espécie causative do phytoplankton.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Soprattutto con l'uso di aggancio dei grafici, 
profili di queste risorse in cui le fioriture d'alghe tossiche e 
nocive (HABs) si presentano negli STATI UNITI innaffia. 
Egualmente richiama le differenze fra tossico e HABs non 
tossico, che gli organismi nel Web dell'alimento sono influenzati, 
come le tossine specifiche funzionano ed i sintomi connessi con loro e
la specie causativa del fitoplancton.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρώτιστα μέσω της χρήσης της γραφικής παράστασης 
δέσμευσης, αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς περιγράφει όπου οι 
τοξικές και επιβλαβείς φυκώδεις ανθίσεις (HABs) εμφανίζονται 
στα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ ύδατα. Εξετάζει επίσης τις διαφορές μεταξύ
τοξικού και μη τοξικού HABs, στο οποίο οι οργανισμοί στον Ιστό
τροφίμων επηρεάζονται, πώς οι συγκεκριμένες τοξίνες λειτουργούν 
και τα συμπτώματα που συνδέονται με τους, και τα αιτιολογικά είδη 
φυτοπλαγκτόντων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sobre todo con el uso de contratar gráficos, los 
contornos de este recurso donde las floraciones algal tóxicas y 
dañosas (HABs) ocurren en ESTADOS UNIDOS riegan. También trata
las diferencias entre tóxico y HABs no tóxico, que los organismos en
el Web del alimento se afectan, cómo las toxinas específicas 
trabajan y los síntomas asociados a él, y la especie causativa del 
phytoplankton.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BIGELOW LABORATORY
FN:BIGELOW LABORATORY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212839</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105831</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/toxic-and-harmful-algal-blooms</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
