<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106300</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106300</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203992</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Transfert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Migração</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Espansione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετανάστευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Migración</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Every year millions of monarch butterflies manage to find their way from hatching grounds in North America to wintering grounds in Mexico. These butterflies log up to 2,000 miles to arrive at their destination: a few fir tree-covered ridge tops in Mexico that none have ever been to. How do these lovely lepidoptera know where to go? How do other species migrate? What are modern threats to migrating species?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Millionen jedes Jahres Monarchbasisrecheneinheiten
handhaben, ihre Methode vom Ausbrüten des Bodens in Nordamerika zu 
wintering Boden in Mexiko zu finden. Diese Basisrecheneinheiten 
protokollieren bis 2.000 Meilen, um in ihrer Zieleinheit anzukommen: 
einig Baum-bedeckte Tanne Kanteoberseiten in Mexiko, das keine 
überhaupt nach gewesen sind. Wie dieses wissen reizendes 
lepidoptera, wohin man geht? Wie ziehen andere Sorten fort? 
Was sind moderne Drohungen zu den Fortziehensorten?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les millions de chaque année de papillons de 
monarque parviennent à trouver leur chemin de hacher des raisons en 
Amérique du nord aux au sol de hivernage au Mexique. Ces 
papillons enregistrent jusqu'à 2.000 milles pour arriver à leur 
destination : quelque le sapin arbre-a couvert des dessus 
d'arête au Mexique au lequel aucun n'a jamais été. Comment 
ces le beau lepidoptera savent-ils où aller ? Comment d'autres 
espèces passent-elles ? Quelles sont des menaces modernes 
aux espèces de passer ?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os milhões de cada ano de borboletas do monarch 
controlam encontrar sua maneira de chocar terras em America do Norte 
às terras wintering em México. Estas borboletas registram até
2.000 milhas para chegar em seu destino: algum o abeto 
árvore-cobriu altos do cume em México a que nenhuns foram sempre. 
Como este o lepidoptera encantador sabe aonde ir? Como 
outras espécies migram? Que são ameaças modernas às 
espécies migrar?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Milioni di ogni anno di farfalle del monarca 
riescono a trovare la loro direzione dalla covata dei motivi in 
America del Nord ai motivi wintering nel Messico. Queste 
farfalle annotano fino a 2.000 miglia per arrivare alla loro 
destinazione: alcun l'abete albero-ha coperto le parti superiori
della cresta nel Messico a che nessun sono stati mai. Come 
questo lepidoptera bello conosce dove andare? Come altre specie 
migrano? Che cosa sono minacce moderne alle specie di 
migrazione?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα εκατομμύρια κάθε έτους των πεταλούδων μοναρχών 
κατορθώνουν να βρούν τον τρόπο τους από την εκκόλαψη των λόγων 
στη Βόρεια Αμερική στους λόγους διαχείμασης στο Μεξικό. 
Αυτές οι πεταλούδες καταγράφουν μέχρι 2.000 μίλια για να
φθάσουν στον προορισμό τους: μερικές δέντρο-καλυμμένες 
έλατο κορυφές κορυφογραμμών στο Μεξικό ότι κανένα δεν ήταν 
πάντα. Πώς αυτά τα καλά λεπιδόπτερα ξέρουν πού να πάνε; 
Πώς άλλα είδη μεταναστεύουν; Τι είναι σύγχρονες 
απειλές στα μεταναστεύοντας είδη;</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Millones de cada año de mariposas del monarca 
manejan encontrar su manera de tramar los argumentos en Norteamérica 
a los argumentos wintering en México. Estas mariposas registran
hasta 2.000 millas para llegar su destinación: algún el abeto 
a'rbol-cubrio' tapas del canto en México a el cual ninguno ha estado 
siempre. ¿Cómo este el lepidoptera encantador sabe adónde ir? 
¿Cómo otras especies emigran? ¿Cuáles son amenazas 
modernas a las especies de la migración?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID TENENBAUM
FN:DAVID TENENBAUM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203992</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106300</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/migration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
