<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103218</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103218</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205515</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Beginner's Modern Greek Module 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Modernes Griechisches Modul 1 Des Anfängers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Module Grec Moderne 1 Du Débutant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Módulo Grego Moderno 1 Do Novato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modulo Greco Moderno 1 Del Principiante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενότητα 1 των σύγχρονων ελληνικών αρχαρίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Módulo Griego Moderno 1 Del Principiante</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This module is intended to help revise and test your knowledge of basic Modern Greek. There is a 10-page detailed presentation of the language areas under study. Common vocabulary, basic grammar and useful phrases are presented in easily learnt tabular form. The quiz section of the module includes 3 levels, the first of which tests knowledge of Modern Greek script and pronunciation (the alphabet). This is followed by a vocabulary trainer which helps you learn about 100 words. The vocabulary trainer is constantly refilled randomly, so it can be played again and again. Finally there is a revision level. Achievement is tracked over time in detail, providing long term motivation. Please note that you will need version 1.3.5 or higher of the Qedoc Quiz Player to view Greek letters properly.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Modul soll helfen, Ihr Wissen des 
grundlegenden modernen Griechen zu verbessern und zu prüfen. Es
gibt eine 10-page genau geschilderte Darstellung der Sprachenbereiche 
unter Studie. Geläufiger Wortschatz, grundlegende Grammatik und
nützliche Phrasen werden in leicht erlernter tabellarischer Form 
dargestellt. Das Quizkapitel des Moduls schließt 3 Stufen, die 
erste ein, welches Testwissens des modernen griechischen Indexes und 
des Aussprache (das Alphabet). Dieses wird von einem 
Wortschatzkursleiter gefolgt, dem Hilfen Sie ungefähr 100 Wörter 
erlernen. Der Wortschatzkursleiter wird ständig nach dem zufall
wieder gefüllt, also kann er immer wieder gespielt werden. 
Schließlich es gibt eine Änderungstufe. Ausführung wird
über Zeit im Detail aufgespürt und stellt langen Bezeichnung 
Beweggrund zur Verfügung. Beachten Sie bitte, daß Sie Version 
1.3.5 oder höheres des Qedoc Quiz-Spielers benötigen, griechische 
Zeichen richtig anzusehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module est destiné pour aider à mettre à 
jour et tester votre connaissance de Grec moderne de base. Il y 
a une présentation détaillée par 10-page des zones de langage à 
l'étude. Le vocabulaire commun, la grammaire de base et les 
expressions utiles sont présentés sous la forme tabulaire facilement
apprise. La section de jeu du module inclut 3 niveaux, le 
premier de quelle connaissance d'essais de séquence type et de 
prononciation grecques modernes (l'alphabet). Ceci est suivi 
d'un entraîneur de vocabulaire que les aides vous apprennent environ 
100 mots. L'entraîneur de vocabulaire est constamment rempli 
aléatoirement, ainsi il peut être joué à plusieurs reprises. 
Enfin il y a un niveau de révision. L'accomplissement est
dépisté avec le temps en détail, fournissant la motivation à long 
terme. Veuillez noter que vous aurez besoin de version 1.3.5 ou 
plus haut du joueur de jeu de Qedoc pour visualiser les lettres 
grecques correctement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo é pretendido ajudar revisar e testar
seu conhecimento do grego moderno básico. Há uma 
apresentação detalhada 10-page das áreas da língua sob o estudo. 
O vocabulário comum, a gramática básica e as frases úteis 
são apresentados no formulário tabular fàcilmente aprendido. 
A seção do quiz do módulo inclui 3 níveis, os primeiros de 
que conhecimento dos testes do certificado e da pronunciação gregos 
modernos (o alfabeto). Isto é seguido por um instrutor do 
vocabulário que as ajudas você aprendam aproximadamente 100 
palavras. O instrutor do vocabulário é reenchido 
constantemente aleatòria, assim que pode ser jogado repetidas vezes. 
Finalmente há um nível da revisão. A realização é 
seguida sobre o tempo em detalhe, fornecendo o motivation a longo 
prazo. Anote por favor que você necessitará a versão 1.3.5 ou
mais elevado do jogador do quiz de Qedoc ver corretamente as letras 
gregas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo è inteso per contribuire a 
modificare e verificare la vostra conoscenza di Greco moderno di base.
Ci è una presentazione dettagliata 10-page delle zone di 
linguaggio allo studio. Il vocabolario comune, la grammatica di 
base e le frasi utili sono presentati nella forma tabulare facilmente 
imparata. La sezione di quiz del modulo include 3 livelli, i 
primi di quale conoscenza delle prove dello scritto e della pronuncia 
greci moderni (l'alfabeto). Ciò è seguita da un addestratore 
di vocabolario che gli aiuti voi imparano circa 100 parole. 
L'addestratore di vocabolario è riempito costantemente a caso, 
in modo da può essere giocato diverse volte. Infine ci è un 
livello di revisione. Il successo è rintracciato 
dettagliatamente col tempo, fornendo la motivazione di lunga durata. 
Noti prego che avrete bisogno delle versioni 1.3.5 o più alto 
del giocatore di quiz di Qedoc di osservare correttamente le lettere 
greche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα προορίζεται να βοηθήσει να αναθεωρήσει
και να εξετάσει τη γνώση των βασικών σύγχρονων ελληνικών σας. 
Υπάρχει μια λεπτομερής 10-σελίδα παρουσίαση των γλωσσικών 
τομέων κάτω από τη μελέτη. Το κοινό λεξιλόγιο, η βασική 
γραμματική και οι χρήσιμες φράσεις παρουσιάζονται με εύκολα 
μαθημένη συνοπτική μορφή. Το τμήμα διαγωνισμοου γνώσεων της
ενότητας περιλαμβάνει 3 επίπεδα, το πρώτο των οποίων εξετάζει τη
γνώση του αρχείου εντολών και προφοράς των σύγχρονων ελληνικών 
(το αλφάβητο). Αυτό ακολουθείται από έναν εκπαιδευτή 
λεξιλογίου που σας βοηθά να μάθετε περίπου 100 λέξεις. Ο
εκπαιδευτής λεξιλογίου ξαναγεμίζεται συνεχώς τυχαία, έτσι 
μπορεί να παιχτεί επανειλημμένως. Τελικά υπάρχει ένα 
επίπεδο αναθεώρησης. Το επίτευγμα ακολουθείται κατά τη 
διάρκεια του χρόνου λεπτομερώς, που παρέχει το μακροπρόθεσμο 
κίνητρο. Παρακαλώ σημειώστε ότι θα χρειαστείτε την έκδοση 
1.3.5 ή υψηλότερος του φορέα διαγωνισμοου γνώσεων Qedoc στις
ελληνικές επιστολές όψης κατάλληλα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo se piensa para ayudar a revisar y a 
probar su conocimiento del Griego moderno básico. Hay una 
presentación detallada 10-page de las áreas del lenguaje bajo 
estudio. El vocabulario común, la gramática básica y las 
frases útiles se presentan en forma tabular fácilmente aprendida. 
La sección del concurso del módulo incluye 3 niveles, los 
primeros de qué conocimiento de las pruebas de la escritura y de la 
pronunciación griegas modernas (el alfabeto). Esto es seguida 
por un amaestrador del vocabulario que las ayudas usted aprendan cerca
de 100 palabras. El amaestrador del vocabulario se rellena 
constantemente aleatoriamente, así que puede ser jugado repetidas 
veces. Finalmente hay un nivel de la revisión. El logro 
se sigue en un cierto plazo detalladamente, proporcionando a la 
motivación a largo plazo. Observe por favor que usted 
necesitará la versión 1.3.5 o más alto del jugador del concurso de 
Qedoc visión las cartas griegas correctamente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVE GREEN
FN:DAVE GREEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205515</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103218</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/beginners-modern-greek-module-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
