<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107538</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107538</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209908</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Regular Polygon </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Regelmäßiges Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Polygone Régulier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Polygon Regular</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poligono Normale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κανονικό πολύγωνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Polígono Regular</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate regular polygons. The applet presents a regular hexagon initially. The user can drag any vertex, which causes all the others to move in such a way as to keep the polygon regular. There are buttons to change the number of sides from 3 to 99. The apothem and circumradius are shown and continuously updated as you drag Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die regelmäßige Polygone zeigen. Der applet stellt 
ein regelmäßiges Hexagon zuerst dar. Der Benutzer kann jeden 
möglichen Gipfel schleppen, der alle andere veranläßt, in solch 
eine Methode hinsichtlich des Unterhaltes das regelmäßige Polygon zu
verschieben. Es gibt die Tasten, zum der Zahl Seiten von 3 bis 
99 zu ändern. Das apothem und das circumradius werden gezeigt 
und ununterbrochen aktualisierter, während Sie schleppen, applet kann
zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les polygones réguliers. L'applet présente un 
hexagone régulier au commencement. L'utilisateur peut traîner 
n'importe quel sommet, qui fait déplacer tous les autres de façon à
maintenir le polygone régulier. Il y a des boutons pour changer
le nombre de côtés de 3 en 99. L'apothem et le circumradius 
sont montrés et pendant que vous traînez l'applet sans interruption 
à jour peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage 
avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après utilisation 
dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de 
n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem polygons regulares. O applet apresenta um hexágono 
regular inicialmente. O usuário pode arrastar todo o vertex, 
que fizer com que todo o outro mova em tal maneira a respeito do 
sustento o polygon regular. Há teclas para mudar o número dos 
lados de 3 a 99. O apothem e o circumradius são mostrados e 
enquanto você arrasta o applet continuamente atualizado pode ser 
ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala 
de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode 
alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca 
com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um 
componente do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da 
referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano i poligoni normali. Il applet presenta inizialmente 
un esagono normale. L'utente può trascinare tutto il vertice, 
che induce tutti gli altri a muoversi in modo da mantenere il poligono
normale. Ci sono tasti per cambiare il numero di lati da 3 a 99.
Il apothem ed il circumradius sono indicati e mentre vi 
trascinate il applet continuamente aggiornato può essere ingrandito 
al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. 
La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora 
da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio 
attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del 
progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto
di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τα κανονικά πολύγωνα. Το applet παρουσιάζει
κανονικό hexagon αρχικά. Ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει 
οποιοδήποτε vertex, το οποίο αναγκάζει όλων άλλων για να 
κινηθεί με τέτοιο τρόπο ώστε να κρατηθεί το πολύγωνο κανονικό. 
Υπάρχουν κουμπιά για να αλλάξουν τον αριθμό πλευρών από 3 
έως 99. Το apothem και το circumradius εμφανίζονται 
και ενημερωμένος συνεχώς καθώς σέρνετε Applet μπορεί να 
διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran polígonos regulares. El applet presenta un hexágono
regular inicialmente. El utilizador puede arrastrar cualquier 
cima, que haga todos los otras mover de tal manera en cuanto a 
mantiene el polígono regular. Hay botones para cambiar el 
número de caras a partir del 3 a 99. Se muestran el apothem y 
el circumradius y como usted arrastra el applet continuamente puesto 
al día se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el 
uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la
sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier 
web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida.
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209908</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107538</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/regular-polygon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
