<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106842</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106842</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086919</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Colonies Reduced."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Kolonien Verringert."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Les Colonies Réduites."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"As Colônias Reduzidas."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Le Colonie Ridotte."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι αποικίες που μειώνονται."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Las Colonias Reducidas."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This 1767 engraving, published in Great Britain and attributed to Benjamin Franklin, warned of the consequences of alienating the colonies through enforcement of the Stamp Act. The act was a 1765 attempt by Parliament to increase revenue from the colonies to pay for troops and colonial administration, and it required colonists to purchase stamps for many documents and printed items, such as land titles, contracts, playing cards, books, newspapers, and advertisements. Because it affected almost everyone, the act provoked widespread hostility. The cartoon depicts Britannia, surrounded by her amputated limbsmarked Virginia, Pennsylvania, New York, and New Englandas she contemplates the decline of her empire. Franklin, who was in England representing the colonists' claims, arranged to have the image printed on cards that he distributed to members of Parliament.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Stich 1767, veröffentlicht in Großbritannien und 
Benjamin Franklin zugeschrieben, warnte von den Konsequenzen des 
Entfremdens der Kolonien durch Durchführung der Stempel-Tat. 
Die Tat war ein Versuch 1765 durch das Parlament, Einkommen von 
den Kolonien auf Bezahlung für Truppen und Kolonialleitung zu 
erhöhen, und sie benötigte Kolonisten, Stempel für viele Dokumente 
zu kaufen und druckte Einzelteile, wie Grundbesitzrechte, die 
Verträge und spielte Karten, Bücher, Zeitungen und Reklameanzeigen. 
Weil sie fast jeder beeinflußte, erregte die Tat 
weitverbreitete Feindseligkeit. Die Karikatur stellt Britannia 
bildlich dar, umgeben von ihr amputierte limbsmarked Virginia, 
Pennsylvania, New York und neues Englandas, die sie die Abnahme ihres 
Reiches erwägt. Franklin, der in England war, das die 
Ansprüche der Kolonisten darstellt, ordnete, das Bild zu haben, das 
auf Karten gedruckt wurde, die er auf Parlamentsmitglieder verteilte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette gravure 1767, éditée en Grande-Bretagne et 
attribuée à Benjamin Franklin, a averti des conséquences d'aliéner
les colonies par l'application de l'acte de timbre. L'acte 
était une tentative 1765 par le Parlement d'augmenter le revenu des 
colonies au salaire pour les troupes et la gestion coloniale, et il a 
exigé des colons d'acheter des timbres pour beaucoup de documents et 
a imprimé des éléments, tels que des titres de bien-fonds, des 
contrats, jouant des cartes, des livres, des journaux, et des 
annonces. Puisqu'il a affecté presque chacun, l'acte a 
provoqué l'hostilité répandue. Le dessin animé dépeint 
Britannia, entouré par elle a amputé limbsmarked la Virginie, la 
Pennsylvanie, New York, et nouvel Englandas qu'elle contemple le 
déclin de son empire. Franklin, qui était en Angleterre 
représentant les réclamations des colons, s'est chargé d'avoir 
l'image imprimée sur les cartes qu'il a distribuées aux 
parlementaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este engraving 1767, publicado em Grâ Bretanha e 
atribuído a Benjamin Franklin, advertiu das conseqüências de 
alienating as colônias com o enforcement do ato do selo. O ato 
era uma tentativa 1765 pelo parliament de aumentar o rendimento das 
colônias ao pagamento para tropas e a administração colonial, e 
requereu colonos comprar selos para muitos originais e imprimiu 
artigos, tais como títulos de terra, contratos, jogando cartões, 
livros, jornais, e propagandas. Porque afetou quase todos, o ato
provocou hostilidade difundida. O cartoon descreve Britannia, 
cercado por ela amputou limbsmarked Virgínia, Pensilvânia, New York,
e Englandas que novo contempla o declínio de seu império. 
Franklin, que estava em Inglaterra que representa as 
reivindicações dos colonos, arranjou para ter a imagem impressa nos 
cartões que distribuiu aos membros de parliament.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa incisione 1767, pubblicata in Gran Bretagna ed 
attribuita a Benjamin Franklin, ha avvertito delle conseguenze di 
alienazione delle colonie con applicazione della Legge del bollo. 
L'atto era un tentativo 1765 dal Parlamento di aumentare il 
reddito dalle colonie a paga per le truppe e la gestione coloniale ed 
ha richiesto ai colonizzatori di comprare i bolli per molti documenti 
ed ha stampato gli articoli, quali i titoli di terra, i contratti, 
giocanti le schedi, i libri, i giornali e le pubblicità. 
Poiché ha interessato quasi tutto, l'atto ha provocato 
l'ostilità diffusa. Il fumetto descrive Britannia, circondato 
da lei amputated limbsmarked la Virginia, la Pensilvania, New York e 
nuovo Englandas che contempla il declino del suo impero. 
Franklin, che era in Inghilterra che rappresenta i reclami dei 
colonizzatori, ha organizzato avere l'immagine stampata sulle schedi 
che ha distribuito ai parlamentari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η χάραξη 1767, που δημοσιεύεται στη Μεγάλη 
Βρετανία και που αποδίδεται σε Benjamin Franklin, που 
προειδοποιείται για τις συνέπειες της αλλοτρίωσης των αποικιών 
μέσω της επιβολής του νόμου γραμματοσήμων. Η πράξη ήταν 
μια προσπάθεια 1765 από το Κοινοβούλιο να αυξηθεί το εισόδημα 
από τις αποικίες για να πληρώσει για τα στρατεύματα και την 
αποικιακή διοίκηση, και απαίτησε τους αποίκους για να αγοράσει τα
γραμματόσημα για πολλά έγγραφα και τύπωσε τα αντικείμενα, όπως 
οι τίτλοι εδάφους, οι συμβάσεις, οι κάρτες παιχνιδιού, τα 
βιβλία, οι εφημερίδες, και οι διαφημίσεις. Επειδή είχε 
επιπτώσεις σχεδόν σε του καθενός, η πράξη προκάλεσε τη 
διαδεδομένη εχθρότητα. Τα κινούμενα σχέδια απεικονίζουν 
Britannia, από την που ακρωτηριάστηκε η Βιρτζίνια, η 
Πενσυλβανία, η Νέα Υόρκη, και νέο Englandas που συλλογίζεται 
την πτώση της αυτοκρατορίας της. Το Franklin, που ήταν 
στην Αγγλία που αντιπροσωπεύει τις αξιώσεις των αποίκων, κανόνισε
να τυπώσει την εικόνα στις κάρτες που διένειμε στα μέλη του 
Κοινοβουλίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este grabado 1767, publicado en Gran Bretaña y atribuido 
a Benjamin Franklin, advirtió de las consecuencias de enajenar a las 
colonias con la aplicación del acto del sello. El acto era una 
tentativa 1765 del parlamento de aumentar el rédito de las colonias a
la paga para las tropas y la administración colonial, y requirió a 
colonos comprar los sellos para muchos documentos e imprimió items, 
tales como títulos de pista, los contratos, jugando tarjetas, los 
libros, los periódicos, y los anuncios. Porque afectó casi 
cada uno, el acto provocó hostilidad extensa. La historieta 
representa Britannia, rodeado por ella amputó limbsmarked Virginia, 
Pennsylvania, Nueva York, y Englandas nuevo que ella comtempla la 
declinación de su imperio. Franklin, que estaba en Inglaterra 
que representaba las demandas de los colonos, arregló tener la imagen
impresa en las tarjetas que él distribuyó a los miembros del 
parlamento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086919</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106842</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-colonies-reduced</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
