<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105225</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105225</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203206</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hudson River PCBs Superfund Site</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Site Des Hudson Fluss-PCBs Superfund</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Site du Fleuve PCBs Superfund de Hudson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Local Do Rio PCBs Superfund De Hudson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luogo Del Fiume PCBs Superfund Di Hudson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοχή Superfund ποταμών PCBs Hudson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sitio Del Río PCBs Superfund De Hudson</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site is the EPA's home page for the PCB contamination of the Hudson River by the General Electric Company and the ongoing remediation efforts by the EPA. The site features information and news about the project background and design, progress-to-date, community involvement, and a gallery of maps, photographs and videos of the project site and activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site ist das Home Page des EPAs für die PWB
Verschmutzung des Hudson Flusses durch die General- Electricfirma und 
die fortwährenden Remediationbemühungen durch das EPA. Die 
Situationsmerkmale Informationen und Nachrichten über den 
Projekthintergrund und -design, Weiterkommen-zudatum, 
Gemeinschaftsmiteinbeziehung und eine Galerie der Karten, der 
Fotographien und der videos der Projektsites und -aktivitäten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site est le Home Page de l'EPA pour la 
contamination de carte du fleuve de Hudson par la compagnie de General
Electric et les efforts continus de remédiation par l'EPA. Les 
dispositifs de site l'information et nouvelles au sujet du fond et la 
conception de projet, progresser-à-date, participation de la 
communauté, et une galerie des cartes, des photographies et des 
videos du site et des activités de projet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local é o Home Page do EPA para a 
contaminação do PWB do rio de Hudson pela companhia elétrica geral 
e pelos esforços ongoing da remediação pelo EPA. As 
características de local informação e notícia sobre o fundo e o 
projeto do projeto, progrid-à-data, participação da comunidade, e 
uma galeria dos mapas, das fotografias e dos videos do local e das 
atividades do projeto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo è il Home Page del EPA per la 
contaminazione del PWB del fiume di Hudson dall'azienda della General 
Electric e dagli sforzi continui di remediation dal EPA. Le 
caratteristiche di luogo le informazioni e notizie circa i precedenti 
ed il disegno di progetto, progred-$$$-DATA, partecipazione della 
Comunità e una galleria dei programmi, delle fotografie e dei videos 
del luogo e delle attività di progetto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή είναι η αρχική σελίδα του EPA για 
τη μόλυνση PCB του ποταμού Hudson από τη γενική ηλεκτρική 
επιχείρηση και των τρεχουσών προσπαθειών επανόρθωσης από το 
EPA. Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις πληροφορίες και τις 
ειδήσεις για το υπόβαθρο και το σχεδιασμό προγράμματος, την 
πρόοδος-$$$-ΗΜΕΡΟΜΗΝΊΑ, την κοινοτική συμμετοχή, και μια στοά των
χαρτών, των φωτογραφιών και των βίντεο της περιοχής και των 
δραστηριοτήτων προγράμματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio es el Home Page del EPA para la 
contaminación del PWB del río de Hudson por la compañía de general
electric y los esfuerzos en curso de la remediación por el EPA. 
Las características de sitio información y noticias sobre el 
fondo y el diseño del proyecto, progresar-a-fecha, implicación de la
comunidad, y una galería de correspondencias, de fotografías y de 
videos del sitio y de las actividades del proyecto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203206</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105225</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hudson-river-pcbs-superfund-site</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
