<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107875</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107875</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086473</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Migrants.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wanderer.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Migrants.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Emigrantes.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Migranti.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετανάστες.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nómadas.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Not all farm families who became migrants during the Great Depression did so because of drought, and not all went to California. Many families lost their land when agricultural prices dropped, and the mechanization of agriculture left many agricultural laborers without work. These members of a South Texas family, photographed by the Farm Security Administration's Dorothea Lange in August 1936, were traveling to the Arkansas Delta to pick cotton.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nicht alle Bauernhoffamilien, die Wanderern während des 
großen Tiefstands standen, taten so wegen der Dürre und nicht aller 
gingen zu Kalifornien. Viele Familien verloren ihr Land, als 
landwirtschaftliche Preise fielen, und die Mechanisierung der 
Landwirtschaft nach links viele landwirtschaftliche Arbeiter ohne 
Arbeit. Diese Bauteile einer Südtexas Familie, fotografiert 
durch das Dorothea Lange der Bauernhof-Sicherheit Leitung im August 
1936, reisten zum Arkansas Dreieck zur Auswahlbaumwolle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Non toutes les familles de ferme qui sont allées bien à 
des migrants pendant la grande dépression ont fait ainsi en raison de
la sécheresse, et pas de toutes sont allées à la Californie. 
Beaucoup de familles ont détruit leur terre quand les prix 
agricoles ont chuté, et la mécanisation de l'agriculture à gauche 
beaucoup de travailleurs agricoles sans travail. Ces membres 
d'une famille du sud du Texas, photographiés par le Dorothea 
Lange de la gestion de sécurité de ferme en août 1936, voyageaient 
au delta de l'Arkansas au coton de sélection.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Não todas as famílias da fazenda que assentaram bem em 
emigrantes durante o depression grande fizeram assim por causa da 
seca, e não de todas foram a Califórnia. Muitas famílias 
perderam sua terra quando os preços agriculturais deixaram cair, e o 
mechanization da agricultura à esquerda muitos laborers agriculturais
sem trabalho. Estes membros de uma família sul de Texas, 
fotografados pelo Dorothea Lange da administração da segurança da 
fazenda em agosto 1936, estavam viajando ao delta de Arkansas ao 
algodão da picareta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Non tutte le famiglie dell'azienda agricola che hanno 
stato bene ai migranti durante la depressione grande hanno fatto così
a causa della siccità e non di tutta sono andato alla California. 
Molte famiglie hanno perso la loro terra quando i prezzi 
agricoli sono caduto e la meccanizzazione dell'agricoltura a sinistra 
molti lavoratori agricoli senza lavoro. Questi membri di una 
famiglia del sud del Texas, fotografati dal Dorothea Lange 
dell'azienda agricola della gestione di sicurezza nel mese di agosto 
del 1936, stavano viaggiando al delta dell'Arkansas al cotone del 
selezionamento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όχι όλες οι αγροτικές οικογένειες που έγιναν 
μετανάστες κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης 
έκαναν έτσι λόγω της ξηρασίας, και δεν πήγαν όλοι σε 
Καλιφόρνια. Πολλές οικογένειες έχασαν το έδαφός τους όταν
άφησαν τις γεωργικές τιμές που έπεσαν, και η μηχανοποίηση της 
γεωργίας πολλά γεωργικά laborers χωρίς εργασία. Αυτά τα
μέλη μιας οικογένειας του νότιου Τέξας, που φωτογραφίστηκαν από 
το Dorothea Lange της διοίκησης αγροτικής ασφάλειας τον 
Αύγουστο του 1936, ταξίδευαν στο δέλτα του Αρκάνσας για να 
επιλέξουν το βαμβάκι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">No todas las familias de la granja que sintieron bien a 
nómadas durante la gran depresión hicieron tan debido a sequía, y 
no toda fueron a California. Muchas familias perdieron su pista 
cuando los precios agrícolas cayeron, y la mecanización de la 
agricultura a la izquierda muchos trabajadores agrícolas sin trabajo.
Estos miembros de una familia del sur de Tejas, fotografiados 
por el Dorothea Lange de la granja de la administración de la 
seguridad en agosto de 1936, viajaban al delta de Arkansas al algodón
de la selección.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086473</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107875</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/migrants</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
