<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103291</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103291</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209853</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Constructing a tangent to a circle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Konstruieren einer Tangente zu einem Kreis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Construction d'une tangente à un cercle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Construindo um tangent a um círculo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Costruzione della tangente ad un cerchio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατασκευή μιας εφαπτομένης σε έναν κύκλο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Construir una tangente a un círculo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate how to construct a tangent to a cicrle at a given point on the circle, using compass and straightedge. It starts with the given circle and point, and in an animation that can run without stopping or single stepped, shows how to construct the tangent line through that point. The text on the page contains written step-by-step instructions that can be printed. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die zeigen, wie man eine Tangente zu einem cicrle an einem 
gegebenen Punkt auf dem Kreis mit Kompaß und Lineal konstruiert. 
Er beginnt mit dem gegebenen Kreis und dem Punkt und in einer 
Animation, die, ohne kann zu stoppen, laufen oder single getreten, 
Erscheinen, wie man die Tangentezeile durch diesen Punkt konstruiert. 
Der Text auf der Seite enthält geschriebene schrittweisee 
Anweisungen, die gedruckt werden können. Applet kann zum vollen
Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert
werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf 
es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek 
ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent comment construire une tangente à un cicrle à un 
point donné sur le cercle, à l'aide de la boussole et de la règle. 
Il commence par le cercle et le point donnés, et dans une 
animation qui peut fonctionner sans s'arrêter ou choisir fait un pas,
expositions comment construire la ligne de tangente par ce point. 
Le texte à la page contient les instructions pas à pas 
écrites qui peuvent être imprimées. L'applet peut être 
agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur 
de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de 
classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem como construir um tangent a um cicrle em um ponto dado no 
círculo, usando o compasso e o straightedge. Começa com o 
círculo e o ponto dados, e em um animation que possa funcionar sem 
parar ou escolhir pisado, mostras como construir a linha do tangent 
através desse ponto. O texto na página contem as instruções 
passo a passo escritas que podem ser imprimidas. O applet pode 
ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da 
sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode 
alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca 
com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um 
componente do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da 
referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano come costruire una tangente ad un cicrle ad un dato punto 
sul cerchio, per mezzo della bussola e dello straightedge. 
Comincia con il dati cerchio e punto ed in una animazione che 
può funzionare senza arrestarsi o scegliere fatto un passo, 
esposizioni come costruire la riga di tangente attraverso quel punto. 
Il testo alla pagina contiene le istruzioni graduali scritte che
possono essere stampate. Il applet può essere ingrandito al 
formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν πώς να κατασκευάσουν μια εφαπτομένη σε ένα 
cicrle σε ένα δεδομένο σημείο στον κύκλο, χρησιμοποιώντας την 
πυξίδα και straightedge. Αρχίζει με το δεδομένους κύκλο 
και το σημείο, και σε μια ζωτικότητα που μπορεί να τρέξει χωρίς 
την παύση ή ενιαίο περπατημένο, επιδεικνύει πώς να κατασκευάσει
τη γραμμή εφαπτομένης μέσω εκείνου του σημείου. Το κείμενο
στη σελίδα περιέχει τις γραπτές βαθμιαίες οδηγίες που μπορούν να
τυπωθούν. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran cómo construir una tangente a un cicrle en una punta dada 
en el círculo, usando el compás y la regla. Comienza con el 
círculo y la punta dados, y en una animación que pueda ejecutarse 
sin parar o escoger caminado, demostraciones cómo construir la línea
de la tangente a través de esa punta. El texto en la 
paginación contiene las instrucciones paso a paso escritas que pueden
ser impresas. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209853</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103291</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/constructing-a-tangent-to-a-circle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
