<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105614</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105614</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Virtual Cell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Virtuelle Zelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cellule Virtuelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pilha Virtual</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cellula Virtuale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικονικό κύτταρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Célula Virtual</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Virtual Cell is an online video game developed by the World-Wide Web Instructional Committee at North Dakota State University. The players take control of a tiny virtual submarine that explores plant and animal cells from the inside! Players learn about organelles, respiration, and photosynthesis. The game requires a fast Internet connection and a Java-enabled browser.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Virtuelle Zelle ist ein Onlinevideospiel, das vom 
weltweites Web-anweisenden Ausschuß an der North Dakota 
Landesuniversität entwickelt wird. Die Spieler nehmen Steuerung
eines kleinen virtuellen Unterseeboots, das Betriebs- und Tierzellen 
vom Innere erforscht! Spieler erlernen über Organellen, Atmung 
und Fotosynthese. Das Spiel benötigt einen schnellen 
Internet-Anschluß und eine Java-aktivierte Datenbanksuchroutine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La cellule virtuelle est un jeu vidéo en ligne 
développé par le Comité d'instruction de Web mondial à 
l'université de l'Etat du nord du Dakota. Les joueurs 
prennent la commande d'un sous-marin virtuel minuscule qui explore des
cellules d'usine et d'animal de l'intérieur ! Les joueurs se 
renseignent sur des organelles, la respiration, et la photosynthèse. 
Le jeu exige une connexion rapide d'Internet et un navigateur 
Java-permis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A pilha virtual é um jogo video em linha 
desenvolvido pelo comitê instrutivo do Web world-Wide na universidade
de estado de dakota norte. Os jogadores fazem exame do controle 
de um submarino virtual minúsculo que explore pilhas da planta e do 
animal do interior! Os jogadores aprendem sobre os organelles, a
respiração, e a fotossíntese. O jogo requer uma conexão 
rápida do Internet e um browser Java-permitido.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La cellula virtuale è un video gioco in linea 
sviluppato dal Web che in tutto il mondo il comitato didattico al 
Dakota del Nord Dichiara l'università. I giocatori 
prendono il controllo di un sommergibile virtuale molto piccolo che 
esplora le cellule dell'animale e della pianta dalla parte interna! 
I giocatori imparano circa gli organelli, la respirazione e la 
fotosintesi. Il gioco richiede un collegamento veloce del 
Internet e un browser Java-permesso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εικονικό κύτταρο είναι ένα σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
τηλεοπτικό παιχνίδι που αναπτύσσεται από την εκπαιδευτική 
Επιτροπή World Wide Web στο κρατικό πανεπιστήμιο της 
βόρειας Ντακότας. Οι φορείς παίρνουν τον έλεγχο ενός 
μικροσκοπικού εικονικού υποβρυχίου που εξερευνά τις εγκαταστάσεις
και τα ζωικά κύτταρα από το εσωτερικό! Οι φορείς μαθαίνουν
για organelles, την αναπνοή, και τη φωτοσύνθεση. Το 
παιχνίδι απαιτεί μια γρήγορη σύνδεση με το Διαδίκτυο και έναν 
Ιάβα- ξεφυλλιστή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La célula virtual es un juego video en línea 
desarrollado por el comité educacional del Web mundial en la 
universidad de estado de Dakota del Norte. ¡Los jugadores toman 
control de un submarino virtual minúsculo que explore las células de
la planta y del animal del interior! Los jugadores aprenden 
sobre los organelles, la respiración, y la fotosíntesis. El 
juego requiere una conexión rápida del Internet y un browser 
Java-permitido.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105614</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/virtual-cell</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
