<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202614</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Facial Studies Through Creation of a Face Jug</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gesichtsbehandlung-Studien durch Kreation eines 
Gesicht Krugs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Études de massage facial par la création d'une 
cruche de visage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estudos do facial através da criação de um 
jarro da cara</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi del facial attraverso la creazione di una 
brocca della faccia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Του προσώπου μελέτες μέσω της δημιουργίας μιας 
κανάτας προσώπου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estudios del facial a través de la creación de 
un jarro de la cara</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students study the anatomy of a face and use what they have learned about rendering faces and three dimensional objects to create thumbnail sketches of expressive faces on jugs. They learn to blend values to create the illusion of volume in both facial features and clay jugs. Three dimensional understanding is reinforced by adding expressive facial features to coiled clay jugs. Earth Science is integrated through the study of clay. Social Sciences in integrated through the study of face jugs found as far back in Social Sciences as Pre-Columbian times. Artistic meaning is explored through facial expression and the psychological implications of color. They look at examples of face jugs. They learn about types of clay. They learn to roll clay coils and create a jug using coil construction. They score, slip and blend facial features to the jug. They choose either underglaze decoration followed by a clear glaze coating or colored glaze decoration applied after bisque firing as a finish.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer studieren die Anatomie eines 
Gesichtes und verwenden, was sie über die Übertragung der Gesichter 
und der dreidimensionalen Nachrichten, um thumbnail Skizzen der 
ausdrucksvollen Gesichter auf Krügen zu erstellen erlernt haben. 
Sie erlernen, Werte zu mischen, um die Illusion des 
Datenträgers in den Gesichtsmerkmalen und in den Lehmkrügen zu 
erstellen. Dreidimensionales Verständnis wird durch das 
Hinzufügen der ausdrucksvollen Gesichtsmerkmale aufgerollten 
Lehmkrügen verstärkt. Geowissenschaft wird durch die Studie 
des Lehms integriert. Sozialwissenschaften integrierten innen 
durch die Studie Gesicht Krüge der gefundenen so weiten Rückseite in
den Sozialwissenschaften wie Vor-Kolumbianische Zeiten. 
Künstlerische Bedeutung wird durch Gesichtsausdruck und die 
psychologischen Implikationen der Farbe erforscht. Sie 
betrachten Beispiele der Gesicht Krüge. Sie erlernen über 
Typen des Lehms. Sie erlernen, Lehmspulen zu rollen und einen 
Krug mit Spule Aufbau herzustellen. Sie zählen, gleiten und 
mischen Gesichtsmerkmale zum Krug. Sie wählen jede underglaze 
Dekoration, die von einer freien Glasurschicht gefolgt werden oder die
farbige Glasurdekoration, die nach Fischcremesuppezündung als Ende 
angewendet wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants étudient l'anatomie d'un visage et
utilisent ce qu'ils se sont renseignés sur rendre des visages et des 
objets tridimensionnels pour créer des croquis minuscules des visages 
expressifs sur des cruches. Ils apprennent à mélanger des 
valeurs pour créer l'illusion du volume dans les dispositifs faciaux 
et des cruches d'argile. L'arrangement tridimensionnel est 
renforcé en ajoutant les dispositifs faciaux expressifs aux cruches 
enroulées d'argile. La science de la terre est intégrée par 
l'étude de l'argile. Les sciences sociales ont dedans intégré
par l'étude du  aussi lointain trouvé par cruches de visage en 
sciences sociales que des périodes Pré-Colombiennes. La 
signification artistique est explorée par l'expression faciale et les
implications psychologiques de couleur. Elles regardent des 
exemples des cruches de visage. Ils se renseignent sur des types
d'argile. Ils apprennent à rouler des enroulements d'argile et 
à créer une cruche en utilisant la construction d'enroulement. 
Ils marquent, glissent et mélangent les dispositifs faciaux 
dans la cruche. Ils choisissent l'une ou l'autre décoration 
d'underglaze suivie d'un enduit clair de lustre ou décoration 
colorée de lustre appliquée après la mise à feu de bisque comme 
finition.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes estudam o anatomy de uma cara e 
usam-se o que aprenderam sobre render as caras e objetos 
tridimensionais para criar esboços do thumbnail das caras expressive 
em jarros. Aprendem misturar valores para criar o illusion do 
volume  em características facial e em jarros da argila. A 
compreensão tridimensional é reforçada adicionando características
facial expressive aos jarros coiled da argila. A ciência de 
terra é integrada com o estudo da argila. As ciências sociais 
integraram dentro com o estudo da parte traseira tão distante 
encontrada jarros da cara em ciências sociais quanto épocas 
Pre-pre-Columbian. O meaning artístico é explorado com a 
expressão facial e as implicações psicológicas da cor. Olham
exemplos de jarros da cara. Aprendem sobre tipos de argila. 
Aprendem rolar bobinas da argila e criar um jarro usando a 
construção da bobina. Marcam, deslizam e misturam 
características facial ao jarro. Escolhem uma ou outra 
decoração do underglaze seguida por um revestimento desobstruído do
esmalte ou a decoração colorida do esmalte aplicada após o 
despedimento do bisque como um revestimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi studiano l'anatomia di una faccia ed 
usano che cosa hanno imparato circa la rappresentazione le facce e 
degli oggetti tridimensionali per creare gli abbozzi del thumbnail 
delle facce espressive sulle brocche. Imparano mescolare i 
valori per creare l'illusione di volume in sia caratteristiche 
facciali che brocche dell'argilla. La comprensione 
tridimensionale è rinforzata aggiungendo le caratteristiche facciali 
espressive alle brocche arrotolate dell'argilla. Le scienze 
della terra sono integrate con lo studio di argilla. Le scienze 
sociali dentro hanno integrato con lo studio sulla parte posteriore 
lontana trovata brocche della faccia nelle scienze sociali quanto i 
periodi Pre-Colombiani. Il significato artistico è esplorato 
con l'espressione facciale e le implicazioni psicologiche di colore. 
Guardano gli esempi delle brocche della faccia. Imparano 
circa i tipi di argille. Imparano rotolare le bobine 
dell'argilla e creare una brocca usando la costruzione della bobina. 
Notano, slittano e mescolano le caratteristiche facciali alla 
brocca. Scelgono la una o la altra decorazione del underglaze 
seguita da un rivestimento libero della glassa o la decorazione 
colorata della glassa applicata dopo infornamento del bisque come 
rivestimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές μελετούν την ανατομία ενός προσώπου και
μιας χρήσης τι έχουν μάθει για την απόδοση προσώπων και τριών 
διαστατικών αντικειμένων για να δημιουργήσουν τα σκίτσα νυχιών 
του αντίχειρα των εκφραστικών προσώπων στις κανάτες. 
Μαθαίνουν να συνδυάζουν τις τιμές για να δημιουργήσουν την 
παραίσθηση της έντασης του ήχου και στα του προσώπου 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα και στις κανάτες αργίλου. Η 
διαστατική κατανόηση τρία ενισχύεται με την προσθήκη των 
εκφραστικών του προσώπου χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων στις 
κουλουριασμένες κανάτες αργίλου. Η γήινη επιστήμη είναι 
ενσωματωμένη μέσω της μελέτης του αργίλου. Κοινωνικές 
επιστήμες ενσωματωμένος μέσω της μελέτης των κανατών προσώπου 
που βρίσκεται τόσο μακριά πίσω στις κοινωνικές επιστήμες όσο 
και τους pre-Columbian χρόνους. Η καλλιτεχνική έννοια 
εξερευνιέται μέσω της του προσώπου έκφρασης και των ψυχολογικών 
επιπτώσεων του χρώματος. Εξετάζουν τα παραδείγματα των 
κανατών προσώπου. Μαθαίνουν για τους τύπους αργίλων. 
Μαθαίνουν να κυλούν τα πηνία αργίλου και να δημιουργούν μια
κανάτα χρησιμοποιώντας την κατασκευή πηνίων. Σημειώνουν, 
γλιστρούν και συνδυάζουν τα του προσώπου χαρακτηριστικά 
γνωρίσματα στην κανάτα. Επιλέγουν είτε underglaze τη 
διακόσμηση που ακολουθείται από ένα σαφές επίστρωμα λούστρου 
είτε τη χρωματισμένη διακόσμηση λούστρου που εφαρμόζεται μετά 
από την πυρκαγιά σούπας με θαλασσινά ως τέρμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes estudian la anatomía de una cara 
y utilizan lo que han aprendido sobre la representación de caras y de
objetos tridimensionales para crear bosquejos del thumbnail de caras 
expresivas en los jarros. Aprenden mezclar valores para crear la
ilusión del volumen en características faciales y jarros de la 
arcilla. La comprensión tridimensional es reforzada agregando 
características faciales expresivas a los jarros en espiral de la 
arcilla. La geología se integra con el estudio de la arcilla. 
Las ciencias sociales adentro integraron con el estudio de la 
parte posteriora tan lejana encontrada los jarros de la cara en 
ciencias sociales como épocas Pre-Colombinas. El significado 
artístico se explora con la expresión facial y las implicaciones 
psicologicas del color. Miran ejemplos de los jarros de la cara.
Aprenden sobre tipos de arcilla. Aprenden rodar bobinas de
la arcilla y crear un jarro usando la construcción de la bobina. 
Anotan, deslizan y mezclan características faciales al jarro. 
Eligen cualquier decoración del underglaze seguida por una capa
clara del esmalte o la decoración coloreada del esmalte aplicada 
después de la despedida del bisque como final.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LORI SHEPLEY
FN:LORI SHEPLEY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MELISSA THIBAULT
FN:MELISSA THIBAULT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NELLE HAYES
FN:NELLE HAYES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202614</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104423</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/facial-studies-through-creation-of-a-face-jug</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
