<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103036</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103036</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212213</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Space Sense</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Platz-Richtung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sens de l'Espace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sentido Do Espaço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Senso Dello Spazio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαστημική αίσθηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sentido Del Espacio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Space Sense is a game developed as part of the Windows to the Universe project. Players learn about the planets, galaxies and the universe by answering questions. Every question they answer correctly will boost their rocket toward its destination-leaving the Earth's atmosphere. Each question contains a 'Life Line' button for helpful clues and an 'Open a Link' button that will take users to web page that has information about the question.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Platz-Richtung ist ein Spiel, das als Teil Windows
zum Universumprojekt entwickelt wird. Spieler erlernen über die
Planeten, die Galaxien und das Universum, indem sie Fragen 
beantworten. Jede Frage, die sie richtig beantworten, lädt ihre
Rakete in Richtung zu seinem Zieleinheit-Lassen der Atmosphäre der 
Masse auf. Jede Frage enthält ' Lebensader ' Taste für 
nützliche Anhaltspunkte und eine Taste ' öffnen Sie eines Links ', 
die Benutzer zur Webseite nimmt, die Informationen über die Frage 
hat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le sens de l'espace est un jeu développé en tant
qu'élément de Windows au projet d'univers. Les joueurs se 
renseignent sur les planètes, les galaxies et l'univers en répondant
à des questions. Chaque question qu'ils répondent correctement
amplifiera leur fusée vers son destination-abandon de l'atmosphère 
de la terre. Chaque question contient la 'ligne de vie 'bouton 
pour des indices utiles et un bouton 'ouvrez lien 'qui portera des 
utilisateurs à la page Web qui a des informations sur la question.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O sentido do espaço é um jogo desenvolvido como 
a parte de Windows ao projeto do universo. Os jogadores aprendem
sobre os planetas, galáxias e o universo respondendo a perguntas. 
Cada pergunta que respondem corretamente impulsionará seu 
foguete para sua destino-partida da atmosfera da terra. Cada 
pergunta contem ' a linha de vida ' tecla para indícios úteis e ' 
abra uma tecla de uma ligação ' que faça exame de usuários ao Web 
page que tem a informação sobre a pergunta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il senso dello spazio è un gioco sviluppato come 
componente di Windows al progetto dell'universo. I giocatori 
imparano circa i pianeti, le galassie e l'universo rispondendo alle 
domande. Ogni domanda che rispondono a amplificherà 
correttamente il loro razzo verso relativo destinazione-lasciare 
l'atmosfera della terra. Ogni domanda contiene 'riga di vita 
'tasto per gli indizii utili e 'apra un tasto di collegamento 'che 
prenderà gli utenti al Web page che ha informazioni sulla domanda.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διαστημική αίσθηση είναι ένα παιχνίδι που 
αναπτύσσεται ως τμήμα των Windows στο πρόγραμμα κόσμου. 
Οι φορείς μαθαίνουν για τους πλανήτες, τους γαλαξίες και τον
κόσμο με την απάντηση των ερωτήσεων. Κάθε ερώτηση που 
απαντούν σωστά θα ωθήσει τον πύραυλό τους προς την 
προορισμός-αναχώρησή της η γήινη ατμόσφαιρα. Κάθε ερώτηση
περιέχει ένα κουμπί "γραμμών ζωήσ" για τις χρήσιμες ενδείξεις 
και "ανοικτός κουμπί συνδέσεων" που θα πάρει τους χρήστες 
ιστοσελίδας που έχει τις πληροφορίες για την ερώτηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El sentido del espacio es un juego desarrollado 
como parte de Windows al proyecto del universo. Los jugadores 
aprenden sobre los planetas, las galaxias y el universo contestando a 
preguntas. Cada pregunta que contestan alzará correctamente su 
cohete hacia su destinacio'n-dejar la atmósfera de la tierra. 
Cada pregunta contiene la ' línea de vida ' botón para las 
pistas provechosas y ' abra un botón de una conexión ' que lleve a 
utilizadores al Web page que tiene información sobre la pregunta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212213</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103036</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/space-sense</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
