<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104317</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104317</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209883</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Locus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ort</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lieu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Locus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luogo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεωμετρικός τόπος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lugar geométrico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet that illustrate the concept of locus. The applet shows a model of the plane populated with a large number of points on a grid. Those points equidistant form a point are highlighted, forming a circle in this case. The user can drag the point and drag the distance, showing the circle moving and changing size. The text page has a description of the locus concept and links to other loci - a straight line and an ellipse. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, die 
das Konzept des Ortes veranschaulichen. Der applet zeigt ein 
Modell der Fläche, die mit vielen Punkten auf einem Rasterfeld 
bevölkert wird. Das äquidistante Formular jener Punkte ein 
Punkt werden markiert und in diesem Fall bilden einen Kreis. Der
Benutzer kann den Punkt schleppen und den Abstand schleppen und die 
bewegende und ändernde Größe des Kreises zeigen. Die 
Textseite hat eine Beschreibung des Ortkonzeptes und -links zu anderen
Orten - eine gerade Gerade und ein Ellipse. Applet kann zum 
vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif qui 
illustrent le concept du lieu. L'applet montre un modèle de 
l'avion peuplé avec un grand nombre de points sur une grille. 
La forme équidistante de ces points par point sont mises en 
valeur, formant un cercle dans ce cas-ci. L'utilisateur peut 
traîner le point et traîner la distance, montrant la taille en 
mouvement et changeante de cercle. La page des textes a une 
description du concept et des liens de lieu à d'autres lieux - une 
ligne droite et une ellipse. L'applet peut être agrandi à la 
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que ilustrem o
conceito do locus. O applet mostra um modelo do plano povoado 
com um grande número pontos em uma grade. O formulário 
equidistante daqueles pontos um o ponto é destacado, dando forma a um
círculo neste caso. O usuário pode arrastar o ponto e arrastar
a distância, mostrando o tamanho móvel e em mudança do círculo. 
A página do texto tem uma descrição do conceito e das 
ligações do locus a outros loci - uma linha reta e um ellipse. 
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che 
illustrano il concetto del luogo. Il applet mostra un modello 
dell'aereo popolato con tantissimi punti su una griglia. La 
forma equidistanta di quei punti un punto è evidenziata, formante un 
cerchio in questo caso. L'utente può trascinare il punto e 
trascinare la distanza, mostrante il formato muoventesi e cambiante 
del cerchio. La pagina del testo ha una descrizione del concetto
e dei collegamenti di luogo ad altri luoghi - una linea retta e un 
ellisse. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo 
pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione
nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel 
paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. 
Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del 
manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που επεξηγούν 
την έννοια του γεωμετρικού τόπου. Το applet εμφανίζει 
ένα μοντέλο του αεροπλάνου που εποικείται με έναν μεγάλο αριθμό
σημείων σε ένα πλέγμα. Η εξ ίσου απέχουσα μορφή εκείνων 
των σημείων ένα σημείο τονίζεται, διαμορφώνοντας έναν κύκλο σε 
αυτήν την περίπτωση. Ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει το σημείο 
και να σέρει την απόσταση, που εμφανίζει κινούμενο και 
μεταβαλλόμενο μέγεθος των κύκλων. Η σελίδα κειμένων έχει 
μια περιγραφή της έννοιας και των συνδέσεων γεωμετρικού τόπου με 
άλλους γεωμετρικούς τόπους - μια ευθεία γραμμή και μια έλλειψη. 
Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης
για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση 
στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que ilustran 
el concepto del lugar geométrico. El applet muestra un modelo 
del plano poblado con una gran cantidad de puntas en una rejilla. 
La forma equidistante de esas puntas a la punta se destaca, 
formando un círculo en este caso. El utilizador puede arrastrar
la punta y arrastrar la distancia, mostrando la talla de mudanza y que
cambia del círculo. La paginación del texto tiene una 
descripción del concepto y de las conexiones del lugar geométrico a 
otros lugares geométricos - una línea recta y una elipse. El 
applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el 
uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la
sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier 
web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida.
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209883</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104317</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/locus</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
