<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106483</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106483</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206440</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Coffee Break</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kaffeepause</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pause-café</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ruptura De Café</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Intervallo per il caffè</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διάλειμμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Descanso para tomar café</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a collection of short reports on recent biological discoveries. Each report is about 400 words, and is based on a discovery recently published peer-reviewed literature. It incorporates interactive tutorials that show how bioinformatics tools are used as a part of the research process. Past topics include how salmonella gains entry into human cells, new clues on Alzheimer's pathology, how living organisms tune in to the time of day, and many more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Ansammlung kurze Berichte über neue 
biologische Entdeckungen. Jeder Report ist ungefähr 400 Wörter
und basiert auf einer erschienenen Gleich-wiederholten Literatur der 
Entdeckung vor kurzem. Er enthält interaktive Tutorials, die 
zeigen, wie bioinformatics Hilfsmittel als Teil des Forschung 
Prozesses benutzt werden. Hinter Themen enthalten Sie, wie 
Salmonellen Eintrag in menschliche Zellen, in neue Anhaltspunkte auf 
Pathologie Alzheimers, wie lebende organismen innen zur Zeit justieren
und in viel mehr gewinnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une collection d'états courts sur des 
découvertes biologiques récentes. Chaque état est environ 400
mots, et est basé sur une littérature pair-passée en revue 
récemment éditée de découverte. Il incorpore les cours 
d'instruction interactifs qui montrent comment des outils de 
bioinformatics sont utilisés comme partie du procédé de recherches.
Après des sujets incluez comment la salmonelle gagne l'entrée 
dans les cellules humaines, les nouveaux indices sur la pathologie 
d'Alzheimer, comment la matière organique accorde dedans à l'heure, 
et beaucoup plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma coleção de relatórios curtos em 
descobertas biológicas recentes. Cada relatório é 
aproximadamente 400 palavras, e é baseado em uma literatura 
par-revista recentemente publicada da descoberta. Incorpora os 
tutorials interativos que mostram como as ferramentas do 
bioinformatics são usadas como uma parte do processo da pesquisa. 
Após tópicos inclua como o salmonella ganha a entrada em 
pilhas humanas, em indícios novos no pathology de Alzheimer, como os 
organismos vivos ajustam dentro à hora, e em muito mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una collezione di rapporti corti sulle scoperte
biologiche recenti. Ogni rapporto è circa 400 parole ed è 
basato su una letteratura pari-rivista recentemente pubblicata di 
scoperta. Comprende le lezioni private interattive che mostrano 
come gli strumenti di bioinformatics sono utilizzati come parte del 
processo di ricerca. Oltre i soggetti includa come la salmonella
guadagna l'entrata nelle cellule umane, nei nuovi indizii su patologia
del Alzheimer, come gli organismi viventi sintonizzano dentro all'ora 
ed in molto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια συλλογή των σύντομων εκθέσεων σχετικά με 
τις πρόσφατες βιολογικές ανακαλύψεις. Κάθε έκθεση είναι 
περίπου 400 λέξεις, και είναι βασισμένη σε μια 
όμοιος-αναθεωρημένη λογοτεχνία ανακαλύψεων πρόσφατα 
δημοσιευμένη. Ενσωματώνει τα διαλογικά σεμινάρια που 
επιδεικνύουν πώς τα εργαλεία βιοπληροφορικής χρησιμοποιούνται ως 
μέρος της ερευνητικής διαδικασίας. Τα προηγούμενα θέματα 
περιλαμβάνουν πώς η σαλμονέλα κερδίζει την είσοδο μέσα σε τα 
ανθρώπινα κύτταρα, νέες ενδείξεις στην παθολογία του 
Alzheimer, πώς οι οργανισμοί διαβίωσης συντονίζουν μέσα στο 
χρόνο της ημέρας, και πολύ περισσότερους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una colección de informes cortos sobre 
descubrimientos biológicos recientes. Cada informe es cerca de 
400 palabras, y se basa en una literatura par-repasada recientemente 
publicada del descubrimiento. Incorpora las guías interactivas 
que muestran cómo las herramientas del bioinformatics se utilizan 
como parte del proceso de la investigación. Más allá de 
asuntos incluya cómo la salmonela gana la entrada en las células 
humanas, las nuevas pistas en la patología de Alzheimer, cómo los 
organismos vivos templan adentro a la hora, y muchos más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206440</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106483</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/coffee-break</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
