<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105740</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105740</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086687</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"On the Night When the Levee Broke": William Cobb Remembers the 1927 Mississippi Flood</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"auf der Nacht, als der Levee" brach: 
William Cobb erinnert sich die an Mississippi Flut 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la nuit où la levée s'est cassée" : 
William Cobb se rappelle l'inondation 1927 du Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"na noite em que o levee quebrou": William 
Cobb recorda a inundação 1927 de Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sulla notte in cui il levee si è rotto": 
William Cobb si ricorda dell'inondazione 1927 del Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Στη νύχτα όταν έσπασε το ανάχωμα": Θ*Ωηλληαμ 
Cobb Remembers η πλημμύρα του Μισισιπή του 1927</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"en la noche en que el dique se rompió": 
Guillermo Cobb recuerda la inundación 1927 de Mississippi</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In spring 1927 it started raining in the Upper Midwest and, according to one observer, "it just never did stop." Torrential rains quickly filled the Mississippi's dozens of tributaries. On April 21, the supposedly impregnable levee system, maintained since 1879 by the Mississippi River Commission, sprang two leaks, or "crevasses" as they are known. Within days the Mississippi River levee system sustained forty more major crevasses in Arkansas, Mississippi, and Louisiana, unleashing a natural disaster that had no precedent in the long history of human interaction with the Mississippi River. William Cobb, who, in 1927 was a young boy living on his family's farm near Pendleton, Arkansas, recalled for historian Pete Daniel the crevasse that opened on April 21 in the levee near his family's house, a few miles from the Arkansas River.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Frühjahr 1927 fing er an, im oberen 
Mittelwesten zu regnen und, nach Ansicht eines Beobachters, "er gerade
nie stoppte." Reißende Regen füllten schnell die Dutzende des 
Mississippis von Steuerbaren. An April 21, entsprang das 
angenommen unumstößliche Leveesystem, beibehalten seit 1879 von der 
Mississippi Fluss-Kommission, zwei Leckstellen oder 
"Gletscherspalten", wie sie bekannt. Innerhalb der Tage 
unterstützte das Mississippi Fluß Leveesystem vierzig 
hauptsächlichgletscherspalten in Arkansas, in Mississippi und in 
Louisiana, unleashing eine Naturkatastrophe, die keinen Präzedenzfall
in der langen Geschichte der menschlichen Interaktion mit dem 
Mississippi Fluß hatte. William Cobb, den, 1927 ein junger 
Junge war, der auf Bauernhof seiner Familie nahe Pendleton, Arkansas 
lebt, für Historiker Peter Daniel die Gletscherspalte, die an April 
21 im Levee nahe Haus seiner Familie, sich öffnete einige Meilen 
wieder aufgerufen vom Arkansas Fluß.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Au printemps 1927 il a commencé à pleuvoir dans 
le Midwest supérieur et, selon un observateur, "il juste ne s'est 
jamais arrêté." Les pluies torrentielles ont rapidement rempli
douzaines du Mississippi de tributaires. Avril 21, le système 
censément irréfutable de levée, mis à jour depuis 1879 par la 
Commission de fleuve du Mississippi, a jailli deux fuites, ou 
"crevasses" comme elles sont connues. Dans des jours le 
système de levée de fleuve du Mississippi a soutenu quarante 
crevasses plus principales en Arkansas, au Mississippi, et en 
Louisiane, lâchant un désastre normal qui n'a eu aucun précédent 
dans la longue histoire de l'interaction humaine avec le fleuve du 
Mississippi. William Cobb, que, en 1927 était un jeune garçon 
vivant à la ferme de sa famille près de Pendleton, Arkansas, 
rappelé pour l'historien Peter Daniel la crevasse qui s'est 
ouverte avril 21 dans la levée près de la maison de sa famille, 
quelques milles du fleuve de l'Arkansas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na mola 1927 começou chover no Midwest superior 
e, de acordo com um observador, "apenas nunca parou." As chuvas 
torrential encheram rapidamente as dúzias do Mississippi dos 
tributários. Abril em 21, o sistema suposta impregnable do 
levee, mantido desde 1879 pelo commission do rio de Mississippi, 
saltou dois escapes, ou "crevasses" como são sabidos. Dentro 
dos dias o sistema do levee do rio de Mississippi sustentou quarenta 
crevasses mais principais em Arkansas, em Mississippi, e em Louisiana,
desencadeando um disastre natural que não tivesse nenhum precedent no
history longo da interação humana com o rio de Mississippi. 
William Cobb, que, em 1927 estava um menino novo que vive na 
fazenda perto de Pendleton, Arkansas da sua família, recordado para o
historian Pete Daniel o crevasse que abriu abril em 21 no levee perto 
da casa da sua família, algumas milhas do rio de Arkansas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In primavera 1927 ha cominciato piovere nel 
Midwest superiore e, secondo un osservatore, "non si è arrestato 
appena mai." Le pioggie torrential hanno riempito rapidamente le
dozzine del Mississippi dei tributari. Il 21 aprile, il sistema 
presunto impregnable del levee, effettuato dal 1879 dalla Commissione 
del fiume del Mississippi, ha balzato due perdite, o "crevasses" come 
sono conosciute. Nei giorni il sistema del levee del fiume del 
Mississippi ha sostenuto quaranta crevasses più importanti 
nell'Arkansas, nel Mississippi ed in Luisiana, liberante un disastro 
naturale che non ha avuto precedente nella storia lunga di interazione
umana con il fiume del Mississippi. William Cobb, che, in 1927 
era un ragazzo giovane che vive sul podere vicino a Pendleton, 
Arkansas della sua famiglia, ricordato per lo storico Pete Daniel il 
crevasse che si è aperto il 21 aprile nel levee vicino alla casa 
della sua famiglia, alcune miglia dal fiume dell'Arkansas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Την άνοιξη του 1927 άρχισε ανώτερο midwest και, 
σύμφωνα με έναν παρατηρητή, "ακριβώς δεν σταμάτησε ποτέ." 
Οι χειμαρρώδεις βροχές γέμισαν γρήγορα τις δωδεκάδες του 
Μισισιπή των υποτελών εθνών. Στις 21 Απριλίου, το 
υποθετικά impregnable σύστημα αναχωμάτων, διατήρησε από 
1879 από την Επιτροπή ποταμών του Μισισιπή, αναπήδησε δύο 
διαρροές, ή "crevasses" δεδομένου ότι είναι γνωστές. 
Εντός ημερών το σύστημα αναχωμάτων ποταμών του Μισισιπή 
στήριξε σαράντα πιό σημαντικά crevasses στο Αρκάνσας, το 
Μισισιπή, και τη Λουιζιάνα, που εξαπολύει μια φυσική καταστροφή 
που δεν είχε κανένα προηγούμενο στη μακροχρόνια ιστορία της 
ανθρώπινης αλληλεπίδρασης με τον ποταμό του Μισισιπή. 
Θ*Ωηλληαμ Cobb, που, το 1927 ήταν ένα νέο αγόρι που 
ζει στο αγρόκτημα της οικογένειάς του κοντά σε Pendleton, 
Αρκάνσας, που υπενθυμίζεται για τον ιστορικό pete Daniel το 
crevasse που άνοιξε στις 21 Απριλίου στο ανάχωμα κοντά στο 
σπίτι της οικογένειάς του, μερικά μίλια από τον ποταμό του 
Αρκάνσας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el resorte 1927 comenzó a llover en el Cercano
oeste superior y, según un observador, "nunca acaba de parar." 
Las lluvias torrenciales llenaron rápidamente las docenas del 
Mississippi de tributarios. De abril el 21, el sistema supuesto 
impregnable del dique, mantenido desde 1879 por la Comisión del río 
de Mississippi, soltó dos escapes, o las "hendiduras" como se saben. 
Dentro de días el sistema del dique del río de Mississippi 
sostuvo cuarenta hendiduras más importantes en Arkansas, Mississippi,
y Luisiana, destraillando un desastre natural que no tenía ningún 
precedente en la historia larga de la interacción humana con el río 
de Mississippi. Guillermo Cobb, que, en 1927 estaba un muchacho 
joven que vivía en la granja cerca de Pendleton, Arkansas de su 
familia, recordado para el historiador Pete Daniel la hendidura que se
abrió 21 de abril en el dique cerca de la casa de su familia, 
algunas millas del río de Arkansas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086687</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105740</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/on-the-night-when-the-levee-broke-william-cobb-remembers-the-1927-mississippi-flood</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
