<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087178</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">" We Are Not Slaves": Female Shoe and Textile Workers in Marblehead, Massachusetts, 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Sind Nicht Sklaven": Weibliche 
Schuh-und Textilarbeiter in Marblehead, Massachusetts, 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Ne sommes pas des Esclaves" : Ouvriers
féminins de chaussure et de textile dans Marblehead, le 
Massachusetts, 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Não somos Escravos": Trabalhadores 
fêmeas em Marblehead, Massachusetts da sapata e do textile, 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non siamo Schiavi": Operai femminili in 
Marblehead, Massachusetts, 1860 della tessile e del pattino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν είμαστε σκλάβοι": Παπούτσι θηλυκών και 
υφαντικοί εργαζόμενοι σε Marblehead, Μασαχουσέτη, 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No somos Esclavos": Trabajadores femeninos 
en Marblehead, Massachusetts, 1860 del zapato y del textil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On George Washington's birthday, 1860, the largest industrial strike to date in the United States started in Lynn, Massachusetts, a coastal town north of Boston. The efforts of the Lynn strikers encouraged shoe and textile workers--including many women--in the nearby town of Marblehead. In Marblehead, as in Lynn, workers invoked the republican values of the American revolution to press their cause. Carrying banners proclaiming "we are not slaves," they referred both to the rhetorical slavery employed by revolutionary leaders and to the real slave system that would collapse in the imminent Civil War. The  New York Times  reporter who wrote this article, however, was less interested in the historical resonance of the events he witnessed than he was in the loss of revenue to Lynn merchants, the novelty of women gathering in public, and having a good time with his Boston colleagues.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf George Washingtons Geburtstag 1860, der 
größte industrielle Schlag bis jetzt in den Vereinigten Staaten 
begonnen in Lynn, Massachusetts, ein Küstenstadtnorden von Boston. 
Die Bemühungen der Lynn Schlaggeräte angeregten Schuh- und 
Textilarbeiter -- einschließlich viele Frauen -- in der nahe 
gelegenen Stadt von Marblehead. In Marblehead wie in Lynn, 
Arbeiter rief die republikanischen Werte der amerikanischen Umdrehung 
hervor, um ihre Ursache zu betätigen. Die tragenden 
proklamierenden Fahnen "wir sind nicht Sklaven," verwiesen sie auf die
rhetorische Sklaverei, die von den revolutionären Führern eingesetzt
wurde und auf das reale Untersystem, das im unmittelbar drohenden 
Bürgerkrieg einstürzen würde. Das New York setzt Zeit 
Reporters, der diesen Artikel schrieb, jedoch an der historischen 
Resonanz der Fälle weniger interessiert war, die, er zeugte, als er 
war im Verlust des Einkommens zu den Lynn Kaufleuten, die Neuheit der 
Frauen fest, die in der Öffentlichkeit erfassen und eine gute Zeit 
mit seinen Boston Kollegen haben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sur l'anniversaire de George Washington, 1860,
la plus grande grève industrielle jusqu'ici aux Etats-Unis commencés
dans Lynn, le Massachusetts, un nord côtier de ville de Boston. 
Les efforts des ouvriers de chaussure encouragés par butées et
de textile de Lynn -- comprenant beaucoup de femmes -- dans la ville 
voisine de Marblehead. Dans Marblehead, comme dans Lynn, 
ouvriers a appelé les valeurs républicaines de la révolution 
américaine pour appuyer leur cause. Les drapeaux portants 
proclamant "nous ne sommes pas des esclaves," elles se sont 
référées à l'esclavage rhétorique utilisé par les amorces 
révolutionnaires et au vrai système slave qui s'effondrerait 
dans la guerre civile imminente. New York chronomètre le 
journaliste qui a écrit cet article, cependant, était moins 
intéressé par la résonance historique des événements qu'il était
témoin qu'il était dans la perte du revenu aux négociants de Lynn, 
la nouveauté des femmes se réunissant l'en public, et ayant un bon 
temps avec ses collègues de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No aniversário de George Washington, 1860, a 
batida industrial a maior à data nos estados unidos começados em 
Lynn, Massachusetts, um norte litoral da cidade de Boston. Os 
esforços dos trabalhadores incentivados grevistas da sapata e do 
textile de Lynn -- including muitas mulheres -- na cidade próxima de 
Marblehead. Em Marblehead, como em Lynn, trabalhadores invocou 
os valores republicanos da volta americana para pressionar sua causa. 
As bandeiras carregando que proclamam "nós não somos 
escravos," consultaram  ao slavery rhetorical empregado por líderes 
revolucionários e ao sistema slave real que desmoronaria na guerra 
civil imminent. A New York cronometra o repórter que escreveu 
este artigo, entretanto, estava mais menos interessado no resonance 
histórico dos eventos que testemunhou do que ele estava na perda do 
rendimento aos comerciantes de Lynn, o novelty das mulheres que 
recolhem no público, e tendo uma estadia boa com seus colegas de 
Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sul compleanno di George Washington, 1860, il più
grande colpo industriale fin qui in unito Dichiara cominciato 
in Lynn, Massachusetts, un nord litoraneo della città di Boston. 
Gli sforzi dei percussori di Lynn hanno consigliato agli operai 
della tessile e del pattino -- compreso molte donne -- alla nella 
città vicina di Marblehead. In Marblehead, come in Lynn, operai
ha invocato i valori repubblicani della rivoluzione americana per 
premere la loro causa. Bandiere trasportanti che affermano "non 
siamo schiavi," si sono riferiti sia allo slavery retorico impiegato 
dai capi rivoluzionari che al sistema slave reale che 
sprofonderebbe nella guerra civile imminente. New York 
cronometra il reporter che ha scritto questo articolo, tuttavia, 
era meno interessato nella risonanza storica degli eventi che ha 
testimoniato che lui era nella perdita di reddito ai commercianti di 
Lynn, la novità delle donne che riuniscono in pubblico e 
divertentesi con i suoi colleghe de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στα γενέθλια George Ουάσιγκτον, 1860, η 
μεγαλύτερη βιομηχανική απεργία μέχρι σήμερα στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες αρχίζω σε Lynn, Μασαχουσέτη, μια παράκτια πόλη 
βόρεια της Βοστώνης. Οι προσπάθειες των απεργών Lynn 
ενθάρρυναν το παπούτσι και τους υφαντικούς εργαζομένους -- 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων πολλών γυναικών -- στην κοντινή πόλη 
Marblehead. Σε Marblehead, όπως σε Lynn, οι 
εργαζόμενοι κάλεσαν τις δημοκρατικές τιμές της αμερικανικής 
επανάστασης για να πατήσουν την αιτία τους. Φέρνοντας 
εμβλήματα που πιστοποιούν "δεν είμαστε σκλάβοι," αναφέρθηκαν και 
στη ρητορική σκλαβιά που υιοθετήθηκε από τους επαναστατικούς 
ηγέτες και στο πραγματικό σύστημα σκλάβων που θα κατέρρεε στον 
επικείμενο εμφύλιο πόλεμο. Ο δημοσιογράφος New York 
Times που έγραψε αυτό το άρθρο, εντούτοις, ενδιαφέρθηκε 
λιγότερο για την ιστορική αντήχηση των γεγονότων που βεβαίωσε 
από ήταν στην απώλεια εισοδήματος Lynn στους εμπόρους, η 
καινοτομία των γυναικών που συλλέγουν στο κοινό, και που έχουν 
έναν καλό χρόνο με τους συναδέλφους της Βοστώνης του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el cumpleaños de George Washington, 1860, la 
huelga industrial más grande hasta la fecha de los Estados Unidos 
comenzados en Lynn, Massachusetts, un norte costero de la ciudad de 
Boston. Los esfuerzos de los trabajadores alentadores 
huelguistas del zapato y del textil de Lynn -- incluyendo muchas 
mujeres -- en la ciudad próxima de Marblehead. En Marblehead, 
como en Lynn, trabajadores invocó los valores republicanos de la 
revolución americana para presionar su causa. Las banderas que 
llevan que proclaman "no somos esclavos," se refirieron a la 
esclavitud retórica empleada por los arranques de cinta 
revolucionarios y al sistema auxiliar verdadero que se derrumbaría en
la guerra civil inminente. La Nueva York mide el tiempo del 
reportero que escribió este artículo, sin embargo, estaba menos 
interesado en la resonancia histórica de los acontecimientos que él 
atestiguó que él estaba en la pérdida del rédito a los 
comerciantes de Lynn, la novedad de las mujeres que recolectan en 
público, y teniendo un buen rato con sus colegas de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087178</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103861</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-are-not-slaves-female-shoe-and-textile-workers-in-marblehead-massachusetts-1860</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
