<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105304</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105304</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206662</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Future State</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zukünftiger Zustand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Futur État</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estado Futuro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il futuro Dichiara</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μελλοντικό κράτος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estado Futuro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the U.S. State Department's website for youth. It offers lesson plans on terrorism, Vietnam, and the Cuban Missile Crisis and information about more than 50 international issues. Careers Representing America, games, and Meet the Secretary of State are among the features. Links are provided for learning about current events, geography, and the environment.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Web site der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Zustand-Abteilung für Jugend. Sie bietet Lektionpläne auf 
Terrorismus, Vietnam und die kubanische Flugkrise und -informationen 
über mehr als 50 internationale Ausgaben an. Die Karrieren, die
Amerika, Spiele darstellen, und treffen den Staatssekretär gehören 
zu den Merkmalen. Links werden für das Lernen über aktuelle 
Fälle, Geographie und die Umgebung zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le site Web du service d'état des ETATS-UNIS 
pour la jeunesse. Il offre des plans de leçon sur le 
terrorisme, le Vietnam, et la crise et les informations cubaines de 
missile sur plus de 50 issues internationales. Les carrières 
représentant l'Amérique, jeux, et rencontrent le secrétaire d'état
sont parmi les dispositifs. Des liens sont donnés pour se 
renseigner sur des événements actuels, la géographie, et 
l'environnement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o Web site do departamento do estado de ESTADOS
UNIDOS para a juventude. Oferece plantas da lição no 
terrorismo, o Vietnam, e a crise e a informação cuban do míssil 
sobre mais de 50 edições internacionais. As carreiras que 
representam América, jogos, e encontram-se com a secretária de 
estado são entre as características. As ligações são 
fornecidas aprendendo sobre eventos atuais, geografia, e o ambiente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il Web site degli STATI UNITI State Department per la
gioventù. Offre i programmi di lezione su terrorismo, il 
Vietnam e la crisi e le informazioni cuban del missile su più di 50 
edizioni internazionali. Le carriere che rappresentano 
l'America, giochi e vengono a contatto della segretaria di 
Dichiarano sono fra le caratteristiche. I collegamenti sono
forniti per imparare circa gli eventi correnti, la geografia e 
l'ambiente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ο ιστοχώρος του υπουργείου ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ 
εξωτερικών για τη νεολαία. Προσφέρει τα σχέδια μαθήματος 
για την τρομοκρατία, το Βιετνάμ, και την κουβανικές κρίση και τις 
πληροφορίες βλημάτων για περισσότερα από 50 διεθνή ζητήματα. 
Οι σταδιοδρομίες που αντιπροσωπεύουν την Αμερική, παιχνίδια,
και συναντούν το γραμματέα του κράτους είναι μεταξύ των 
χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων. Οι συνδέσεις παρέχονται για την
εκμάθηση για τα παρόντα γεγονότα, τη γεωγραφία, και το 
περιβάλλον.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el Web site de ESTADOS UNIDOS del departamento 
del estado para la juventud. Ofrece planes de la lección en 
terrorismo, Vietnam, y la crisis y la información cubanos del misil 
sobre más de 50 ediciones internacionales. Las carreras que 
representan América, juegos, y satisfacen a secretaria del estado 
están entre las características. Las conexiones se 
proporcionan para aprender sobre sucesos actuales, la geografía, y el
ambiente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206662</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105304</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/future-state</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
