<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103029</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103029</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087327</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Person Like Me, Oppress'd By Dame Fortune, Need Not Care Where He Goes": The "Infortunate" William Moraley Tries His Luck in America, 1729.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Eine Person Mögen Mich, Oppress'd Durch Dame 
Fortune, Braucht, Nicht Sich Zu interessieren, Wo Er" Geht: Das 
"Infortunate" William Moraley versucht sein Glück in Amerika, 1729.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Une Personne M'aiment, Oppress'd Par Dame Fortune,
N'a pas besoin de s'inquiéter Où Il Va" : L'"Infortunate" 
William Moraley essaye sa chance en Amérique, 1729.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Uma Pessoa Gosta De Me, Oppress'd Pelo Dame 
Fortuna, Não necessita Importar-se Onde Vai": O "Infortunate" 
William Moraley tenta sua sorte em América, 1729.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Una Persona Lo gradisce, Oppress'd Dal Dame 
Fortune, Non deve Preoccuparsi Dove Va": "il Infortunate" 
William Moraley prova la sua fortuna in America, 1729.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα πρόσωπο όπως με, Oppress'd από την κυρία 
Fortune, δεν χρειάζεται την προσοχή όπου πηγαίνει": Το 
"Infortunate" William Moraley Tries His Luck στην 
Αμερική, 1729.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Una Persona Tiene gusto De Mí, Oppress'd De Dama 
Fortune, No necesita Cuidar Donde Él Va": El "Infortunate" 
Guillermo Moraley intenta su suerte en América, 1729.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many travelers made their way to Philadelphia and the Mid-Atlantic colonies in the eighteenth century in search of economic opportunity, but not all experienced the fabulous success of Benjamin Franklin. William Moraley, born in 1699 into a modest artisanal family, was more typical. Economic cycles were often critical in determining migration patterns; approximately 73,000 people left for the British colonies in the1730s, twice the average of earlier in the century (17,000 arrived in Philadelphia). Like half of all European emigrants to North America in the eighteenth-century, Moraley faced grim conditions at home. After the death of his father, a journeyman clockmaker, Moraley possessed scarce resources and was imprisoned for debt. The thirty-year-old Moraley bound himself for five years as a servant in the British North American colonies. He titled his picaresque account of life in Britain and America  The Infortunate: The Voyage and Adventures of William Moraley, an Indentured Servant .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Reisende bildeten Philadelphia und den 
Mittler-Atlantischen Kolonien im achtzehnten Jahrhundert ihre Methode 
auf der Suche nach ökonomischer Gelegenheit, aber nicht alle erfuhren
den fabelhaften Erfolg von Benjamin Franklin. William Moraley, 
getragen 1699 in eine bescheidene artisanal Familie, war typischer. 
Ökonomische Schleifen waren häufig kritisch, wenn sie 
Migration Muster feststellten; ungefähr 73.000 Leute verließen
für die britischen Kolonien in the1730s, zweimal der Durchschnitt 
früh innen vom Jahrhundert (17.000 angekommen in Philadelphia). 
Wie Hälfte aller europäischen Emigranten nach Nordamerika im 
Achtzehntjahrhundert, stellte Moraley grimmige Bedingungen zu Hause 
gegenüber. Nach dem Tod seines Vaters, wurden ein Facharbeiter 
clockmaker, Moraley besessene knappe Betriebsmittel und für Schuld 
eingesperrt. Das dreißig-Jahr-alte Moraley springen sich für 
fünf Jahre als Bedienstetes in den britischen nordamerikanischen 
Kolonien. Er betitelte sein picaresque Konto des Lebens in 
Großbritannien und in Amerika das Infortunate: Die Reise und 
die Abenteuer von William Moraley, ein Indentured Bediensteter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup de voyageurs ont fait leur chemin vers 
Philadelphie et les colonies Mi-Atlantiques au dix-huitième siècle à 
la recherche de l'occasion économique, mais pas tous ont éprouvé le
succès fabuleux de Benjamin Franklin. William Moraley, soutenu 
en 1699 dans une famille modeste d'artisanal, était plus typique. 
Les cycles économiques étaient souvent critiques en 
déterminant des configurations de transfert ; approximativement
73.000 personnes sont parties pour les colonies britanniques dans 
the1730s, deux fois la moyenne plus tôt dedans du siècle (17.000 
arrivés à Philadelphie). Comme la moitié de tous les 
émigrants européens vers l'Amérique du nord en 
dix-huitième-siècle, Moraley a fait face à des conditions sinistres
à la maison. Après la mort de son père, un horloger de 
compagnon, des ressources rares possédées par Moraley et ont été 
emprisonnés pour la dette. Le trente-année-vieux Moraley se 
bondissent pendant cinq années en tant que domestique dans les 
colonies américaines du nord britanniques. Il a intitulé 
son compte de picaresque de la vie en Grande-Bretagne et en Amérique 
l'Infortunate : Le voyage et les aventures de William Moraley, 
un domestique d'Indentured.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos viajantes fizeram sua maneira a Filadélfia e às 
colônias Mid-mid-Atlantic no décimo oitavo século na busca da 
oportunidade econômica, mas não todos experimentaram o sucesso 
fabulous de Benjamin Franklin. William Moraley, carregado em 
1699 em uma família modesta do artisanal, era mais típico. Os 
ciclos econômicos eram frequentemente críticos em determinar testes 
padrões da migração; aproximadamente 73.000 povos sairam para
as colônias britânicas em the1730s, duas vezes a média mais cedo 
dentro do século (17.000 chegados em Filadélfia). Como a 
metade de todos os emigrants europeus a America do Norte no 
décimo-século, Moraley enfrentou circunstâncias grim na HOME. 
Após a morte de seu pai, um clockmaker do journeyman, uns 
recursos escassos possuídos Moraley e imprisoned para o débito. 
O Moraley trinta-ano-velho limita-se por cinco anos como um 
empregado nas colônias norte-americanas britânicas. Intitulou 
seu cliente do picaresque da vida em Grâ Bretanha e em América o 
Infortunate: A viagem e as aventuras de William Moraley, um 
empregado de Indentured.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti viaggiatori hanno fatto il loro modo a Filadelfia ed
alle colonie Metà di-Atlantiche nel diciottesimo secolo alla ricerca 
dell'occasione economica, ma non tutti hanno avvertito il successo 
fabulous di Benjamin Franklin. William Moraley, sopportato in 
1699 in una famiglia modesta di artisanal, era più tipico. I 
cicli economici erano spesso critici nella determinazione dei modelli 
di espansione; circa 73.000 genti hanno andato per le colonie 
britanniche in the1730s, due volte la media presto dentro del secolo 
(17.000 arrivati a Filadelfia). Come la metà di tutti gli 
emigranti europei in America del Nord nel diciottesimo-secolo, Moraley
ha affrontato le circostanze torve nel paese. Dopo la morte del 
suo padre, un clockmaker dell'operaio qualificato, lle risorse 
limitate possedute Moraley ed erano incarcerati per il debito. Il
trenta-anno-vecchio Moraley si limita per cinque anni come servo nelle
colonie nordamericane britanniche. Ha intitolato il suo cliente 
del picaresque di vita in Gran-Bretagna ed in America il Infortunate: 
Il viaggio e le avventure di William Moraley, un servo di 
Indentured.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί ταξιδιώτες έκαναν τον τρόπο τους στη 
Φιλαδέλφεια και τις μέσος-ατλαντικές αποικίες στο δέκατο όγδοο 
αιώνα σε αναζήτηση της οικονομικής ευκαιρίας, αλλά δεν δοκίμασαν
όλοι τη μυθική επιτυχία Benjamin Franklin. Θ*Ωηλληαμ 
Moraley, γεννημένο το 1699 σε μια μέτρια χειρωνακτική 
οικογένεια, ήταν πιό χαρακτηριστικός. Οι οικονομικοί 
κύκλοι ήταν συχνά κρίσιμοι στον καθορισμό των προτύπων 
μετανάστευσης  περίπου 73.000 άνθρωποι έφυγαν για τις 
βρετανικές αποικίες σε the1730s, δύο φορές ο μέσος όρος 
νωρίτερα στον αιώνα (17.000 έφθασαν στη Φιλαδέλφεια). 
Όπως τους μισούς από όλους τους ευρωπαϊκούς μετανάστες 
στη Βόρεια Αμερική στο δέκατος-αιώνα, Moraley αντιμετώπισε 
τους απαίσιους όρους στο σπίτι. Μετά από το θάνατο του 
πατέρα του, ένας ρολογάς τεχνιτών, Moraley κατείχε τα λιγοστά
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και φυλακίστηκε για το χρέος. Το 
τριάντα-χρονών Moraley δεσμεύθηκε για πέντε έτη ως 
υπάλληλο στις βρετανικές βορειοαμερικανικές αποικίες. Αυτός
με τον τίτλο ο πικαρέσκ απολογισμός ζωής του στη Μεγάλη Βρετανία
και την Αμερική το Infortunate: Το ταξίδι και οι 
περιπέτειες William Moraley, ένας υπάλληλος Indentured.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchas hojas de ruta (traveler) hicieron su manera a 
Philadelphia y a las colonias Mediados de-Atla'nticas en el décimo 
octavo siglo en búsqueda de la oportunidad económica, pero no todas 
experimentaron el éxito fabuloso de Benjamin Franklin. 
Guillermo Moraley, llevado en 1699 en una familia modesta del 
artisanal, era más típico. Los ciclos económicos eran a 
menudo críticos en la determinación de modelos de la migración; 
aproximadamente 73.000 personas se fueron para las colonias 
británicas en the1730s, dos veces el promedio anterior adentro del 
siglo (17.000 llegados en Philadelphia). Como la mitad de todos 
los emigrantes europeos a Norteamérica en el de'cimo octavo-siglo, 
Moraley hizo frente a condiciones severas en el país. Después 
de la muerte de su padre, un clockmaker del oficial, los recursos 
escasos poseídos Moraley y fueron encarcelados para la deuda. 
El treinta-año-viejo Moraley se limita por cinco años como 
criado en las colonias norteamericanas británicas. Él tituló 
su cuenta del picaresque de la vida en Gran Bretaña y América el 
Infortunate: El viaje y las aventuras de Guillermo Moraley, 
criado de Indentured.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087327</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103029</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-person-like-me-oppressd-by-dame-fortune-need-not-care-where-he-goes-the-infortunate-william-moraley-tries-his-luck-in-america-1729</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
