<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108607</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108607</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086410</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Letters to the Editor about Alan Paton's 1954 Article " The Negro in America Today"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leserbriefe über Alan Patons Artikel 1954 "der 
Schwarze in Amerika heute"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lettres à l'éditeur au sujet de l'article 1954 
d'Alan Paton "le nègre en Amérique aujourd'hui"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Letras ao editor sobre o artigo 1954 de Alan Paton 
"o negro em América hoje"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lettere all'editore circa l'articolo 1954 di Alan 
Paton "il negro in America oggi"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστολές στον επεξεργαστή για το άρθρο του 1954 του
Alan Paton's "ο νέγρος στην Αμερική σήμερα"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cartas al editor sobre el artículo 1954 de Alan 
Paton "el negro en América hoy"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Alan Paton's first novel, Cry, the Beloved Country (1948), communicated the tragic dimensions of South Africa's system of apartheid to a world audience. In 1954, Paton was asked by Collier's magazine to observe and interview Americans about this country's system of racial segregation. In the first of two articles, Paton reported on race relations in Washington, D.C. and in the Deep South around the time that the Supreme Court declared that segregated " separate but equal" public schools were unconstitutional in its landmark Brown v. Board of Education ruling. The following letters to the editor express a range of reactions to the Court' s decision and to Paton' s undisguised support for the ongoing " war against segregation."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alan Patons erster Roman, Schrei, geliebte Country
(1948), teilte die tragischen Maße von System Südafrikas von 
Apartheid zu einem Weltpublikum mit. 1954 wurde Paton durch 
Zeitschrift Colliers gebeten, Amerikaner über System dieses Landes 
der rassischen Abtrennung zu beobachten und zu interviewen. Im 
ersten von zwei Artikeln, berichtete Paton über Rennenrelationen in 
Washington, Gleichstrom und im tiefen Süden um die Zeit, der das 
Höchste Gericht erklärte, daß getrennte "unterschiedliche aber 
gleiche" allgemeine Schulen in seinem Brett des Grenzstein Braun-V. 
Ausbildung des Anordnens verfassungswidrig waren. Die folgenden 
Leserbriefe drücken eine Strecke der Reaktionen zum Gericht ' s 
Entscheidung aus und zu Paton ' undisguised s Support für den 
fortwährenden "Krieg gegen Abtrennung."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le premier roman d'Alan Paton, cri, Country
aimé (1948), a communiqué les dimensions tragiques du système 
Du sud de l'Afrique de la ségrégation à une assistance du 
monde. En 1954, Paton a été invité par le magazine de 
Collier à observer et interviewer des Américains au sujet du 
système de ce pays de la ségrégation raciale. Dans le premier
de deux articles, Paton a rendu compte des relations inter-raciales à
Washington, C.C et dans les Sud profonds autour du temps que 
la cour suprême a déclaré que les écoles d'Etat "séparées mais 
égales" isolées étaient inconstitutionnelles dans son panneau du 
brun v. de borne limite de régner d'éducation. Les lettres 
suivantes à l'éditeur expriment un intervalle des réactions au 
soutien de manifeste de s à Paton de cour 'décision de s et 'de la
"guerre continue contre la ségrégation."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A primeira novela de Alan Paton, grito, País 
beloved (1948), comunicou as dimensões trágicas do sistema de 
África do Sul do apartheid a uma audiência do mundo. Em 1954, 
Paton foi pedido pelo compartimento de Collier para observar e 
entrevistar americanos sobre o sistema deste país do segregation 
racial. No primeiro de dois artigos, Paton relatou nas 
relações de raça em Washington, C.C. e no sul profundo em torno do 
tempo que a corte suprema declarou que as escolas públicas "separadas
mas iguais" segregadas eram unconstitutional em sua placa do marrom v.
do marco de governar da instrução. As seguintes letras ao 
editor expressam uma escala das reações à corte ' decisão de s e a
Paton ' s undisguised a sustentação para a "guerra ongoing de 
encontro ao segregation."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il primo romanzo di Alan Paton, Grida, 
il Country caro (1948), ha comunicato le dimensioni tragiche del 
sistema della Sudafrica di segregazione ad un pubblico del mondo. 
In 1954, Paton è stato chiesto dallo scomparto del Collier di 
osservare ed intervistare gli Americani circa il sistema di questo 
paese della segregazione razziale. Nel primo di due articoli, 
Paton ha segnalato sui rapporti di corsa in Washington, DC e nel sud 
profondo intorno al tempo che la Corte suprema ha dichiarato che le 
"public school" "separate ma uguali" segregate erano inconstituzionali
nel relativo Bordo di colore marrone v. del limite di 
regolamento di formazione. Le lettere seguenti all'editore 
esprimono una gamma di reazioni alla corte 'decisione di s ed a Paton 
'la s undisguised il sostegno "la guerra continua contro la 
segregazione."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρώτο μυθιστόρημα του Alan Paton's, κραυγή, η 
αγαπημένη χώρα (1948), διαβίβασε τις τραγικές διαστάσεις του 
συστήματος της Νότιας Αφρικής του απαρτχάιντ σε ένα παγκόσμιο 
ακροατήριο. Το 1954, Paton κλήθηκε από το περιοδικό 
του ανθρακωρύχου να παρατηρήσει και να πάρει συνέντευξη από 
Αμερικανούς για το σύστημα αυτής της χώρας του φυλετικού 
διαχωρισμού. Στο πρώτο δύο άρθρων, Paton υπέβαλε έκθεση
σχετικά με τις φυλετικές σχέσεις στην Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ 
και στο βαθύ νότο γύρω από το χρόνο ότι το ανώτατο δικαστήριο 
δήλωσε ότι τα διαχωρισμένα "χωριστά αλλά ίσα" δημόσια σχολεία 
ήταν αντισυνταγματικά στο ορόσημό του Brown V. Board 
απόφασης εκπαίδευσης. Οι ακόλουθες επιστολές στον 
επεξεργαστή εκφράζουν μια σειρά των αντιδράσεων στην απόφαση 
δικαστηρίου "s και στην απροκάλυπτη υποστήριξη Paton" s 
για τον τρέχοντα "πόλεμο ενάντια στο διαχωρισμό."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La primera novela de Alan Paton, grito, Country 
querido (1948), comunicó las dimensiones trágicas del sistema de 
Suráfrica del apartheid a una audiencia del mundo. En 1954, 
Paton fue pedido por el compartimiento de Collier observar y 
entrevistarse con a americanos sobre el sistema de este país de la 
segregación racial. En el primer de dos artículos, Paton 
señaló sobre las relaciones de raza en Washington, C.C. y en el sur 
profundo alrededor del tiempo que el Tribunal Supremo declaró que las
escuelas públicas "separadas pero iguales" segregadas eran 
inconstitucionales en su tarjeta del marrón v. de la señal de la 
decisión de la educación. Las cartas siguientes al editor 
expresan un rango de reacciones a la corte ' decisión de s y a Paton 
' s undisguised la ayuda para la "guerra en curso contra la 
segregación."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086410</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108607</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/letters-to-the-editor-about-alan-patons-1954-article-the-negro-in-america-today</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
