<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104901</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104901</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200582</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Audio Interview with Dr. Carol Stoker about MARTE and the Rio Tinto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Audiointerview mit Dr. Carol Stoker über MARTE 
und das Rio Tinto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entrevue sonore avec Dr. Carol Stoker au sujet de 
MARTE et de Rio Tinto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entrevista audio com Dr. Carol Stoker sobre MARTE 
e o Rio Tinto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Intervista audio con il Dott. Carol Stoker circa 
MARTE e Rio Tinto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηχητική συνέντευξη με το Δρ Carol Stoker για 
MARTE και το Ρίο Tinto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entrevista audio con el Dr. Carol Stoker sobre 
MARTE y la Río Tinto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features links to broadcast quality audio files and transcripts from an interview with Dr. Carol Stoker about the Mars Analog Research and Technology Experiment (MARTE) which is to take place near the Rio Tinto in Spain. Interview topics include the MARTE expedition, the definition of an extremophile, the significance of the color and pH of Rio Tinto, equipment for the MARTE experiment, the possibility of a Mars drilling mission, and the resemblance of Rio Tinto geochemistry to that of Mars.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale bindet, um 
Qualitätsaudiodateien und Abschriften von einem Interview mit Dr. 
Carol Stoker zu übertragen über das Mars analoge Forschung und 
Technologie-Experiment (MARTE) das nahe dem Rio Tinto in Spanien 
stattfinden soll. Interviewthemen schließen die MARTE 
Expedition, die Definition von einem extremophile, die Stichhaltigkeit
der Farbe und des pH von Rio Tinto, Ausrüstung für das MARTE 
Experiment, die Möglichkeit einer Mars bohrenmission und die 
Ähnlichkeit von Rio Tinto Geochemie zu der von Mars ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dispositifs de ce site joint pour annoncer les
fichiers et les transcriptions sonores de qualité d'une entrevue avec
Dr. Carol Stoker au sujet de l'expérience analogique de recherches et
de technologie de Mars (MARTE) qui doit avoir lieu près de Rio Tinto 
en Espagne. Les sujets d'entrevue incluent l'expédition de 
MARTE, la définition d'un extremophile, la signification de la 
couleur et du pH de Rio Tinto, matériel pour l'expérience de MARTE, 
la possibilité d'une mission de forage de Mars, et la ressemblance de
la géochimie de Rio Tinto à celle de Mars.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As características deste local ligam para 
transmitir limas e transcripts audio da qualidade de uma entrevista 
com Dr. Carol Stoker sobre a experiência análoga da pesquisa e da 
tecnologia de Marte (MARTE) que deve ocorrer perto do Rio Tinto em 
Spain. Os tópicos da entrevista incluem a expedição de MARTE,
a definição de um extremophile, o significado da cor e do pH de Rio 
Tinto, equipamento para a experiência de MARTE, a possibilidade de 
uma missão perfurando de Marte, e a semelhança do geochemistry de 
Rio Tinto àquela de Marte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo si collega per 
trasmettere per radio gli archivi e le trascrizioni audio di qualità 
da un'intervista con il Dott. Carol Stoker circa l'esperimento analog 
di ricerca e di tecnologia del Marte (MARTE) che deve avvenire vicino 
a Rio Tinto in Spagna. I soggetti di intervista includono la 
spedizione di MARTE, la definizione di un extremophile, l'importanza 
del colore e del pH di Rio Tinto, apparecchiatura per l'esperimento di
MARTE, la possibilità di missione perforante del Marte e la 
rassomiglianza della geochimica de Rio Tinto a quella di Marte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις συνδέσεις για να 
μεταδώσει ραδιοφωνικά τα ποιοτικά ηχητικά αρχεία και τα 
αντίγραφα από μια συνέντευξη με το Δρ Carol Stoker για το 
πείραμα αναλογικό ερευνητικό και τεχνολογίας του Αρη (MARTE) 
που είναι να πραγματοποιηθεί κοντά στο Ρίο Tinto στην Ισπανία.
Τα θέματα συνέντευξης περιλαμβάνουν την αποστολή MARTE, 
τον καθορισμό ενός extremophile, τη σημασία του χρώματος και το
pH του Ρίο Tinto, εξοπλισμός για το πείραμα MARTE, τη 
δυνατότητα μιας αποστολής διάτρυσης του Αρη, και την ομοιότητα 
της γεωχημείας του Ρίο Tinto σε αυτή του Αρη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las características de este sitio conectan para 
difundir ficheros y transcripciones audio de la calidad de una 
entrevista con el Dr. Carol Stoker sobre el experimento analogico de 
la investigación y de la tecnología de Marte (MARTE) que es ocurrir 
cerca de la Río Tinto en España. Los asuntos de la entrevista 
incluyen la expedición de MARTE, la definición de un extremophile, 
la significación del color y del pH de Río Tinto, equipo para el 
experimento de MARTE, la posibilidad de una misión que perfora de 
Marte, y la semejanza de la geoquímica de Río Tinto a la de Marte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CAROL STOKER
FN:CAROL STOKER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NASA AMES RESEARCH CENTER PUBLIC AFFAIRS DIVISION
FN:NASA AMES RESEARCH CENTER PUBLIC AFFAIRS DIVISION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200582</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104901</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/audio-interview-with-dr-carol-stoker-about-marte-and-the-rio-tinto</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
