<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108579</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108579</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086278</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Didn't Know Anything About Voting:" Fannie Lou Hamer On The Mississippi Voter Registration Campaign</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Wußte Nicht Nichts Über Das Wählen:" 
Fannie Lou Hamer Auf Der Mississippi 
Wähler-Registrierung-Kampagne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Je N'ai su Rien Au sujet du Vote :" Fannie 
Lou Hamer Sur La Campagne d'Enregistrement D'Électeur du Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Não soube Qualquer coisa Sobre Votar:" 
Fannie Lou Hamer Na Campanha Do Registo Do Eleitor De 
Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non ho conosciuto Nulla Circa Il Voto:" 
Fannie Lou Hamer Sulla Campagna Di Registro Dell'Elettore Del 
Mississippi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν ήξερα τίποτα για την ψηφοφορία:" Fannie 
Lou Hamer στην εκστρατεία εγγραφής ψηφοφόρων του Μισισιπή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No sabía Cualquier cosa Sobre La Votación:" 
Fannie Lou Hamer En La Campaña Del Registro Del Votante De 
Mississippi</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Fannie Lou Hamer, the last of 20 children and a Mississippi tenant farmer, leapt to national prominence during the 1964 Democratic National Convention, when she eloquently challenged Mississippi's segregated Democratic primary on national television. In 1962, she had become a leader of the African-American voting rights movement in Mississippi that culminated in 1964's Freedom Summer. Forced off her land when her landlord demanded that she take her name off the voter registration list, Hamer was repeatedly jailed and beaten during her voting rights activities. "The only thing they could do to me was kill me," Hamer said, "and it seemed like they'd been trying to do that a little bit at a time ever since I could remember."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fannie Lou Hamer, das Letzte von 20 Kindern und 
von Mississippi Pachtbauern, gesprungen zum nationalen Vorsprung 
während demokratischen des Nationalkonvent1964, als sie redegewandt 
Mississippis getrenntes demokratisches Primär auf nationalem 
Fernsehen herausforderte. 1962 war sie ein Führer der 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Bewegung der wählenden Rechte in 
Mississippi geworden, das im Freiheit 1964's Sommer kulminierte. 
Erzwungen weg von ihrem Land, als ihr Hauswirt verlangte, daß 
sie ihren Namen die Wählerregistrierungliste entfernt, wurde Hamer 
wiederholt während ihrer Aktivitäten der wählenden Rechte 
gefangengesetzt und geschlagen. "die einzige Sache, die sie mich
antun konnten, war Abbruch ich," gesagtes Hamer, "und es schien, wie 
sie versuchend, das ein wenig hintereinander zu tun wurden, seitdem 
ich mich erinnern könnte."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fannie Lou Hamer, le bout de 20 enfants et d'un 
exploitant-locataire du Mississippi, sauté à la proéminence 
nationale pendant la convention 1964 nationale démocratique, quand 
elle a par éloquence défié primaire démocratique isolé du 
Mississippi à la télévision nationale. En 1962, elle était 
devenue une amorce du mouvement afro-américain de droit de vote au 
Mississippi qui a abouti à l'été de la liberté 1964's. 
Forcé outre de sa terre quand son propriétaire a exigé 
qu'elle prennent son nom outre de la liste d'enregistrement 
d'électeur, Hamer a été à plusieurs reprises emprisonné et battu 
pendant ses activités de droit de vote. "la seule chose 
qu'elles pourraient faire à moi était mise à mort je," Hamer dit, 
"et lui a semblé comme elles  essayant de faire cela un peu à la 
fois depuis que je pourrais me rappeler."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fannie Lou Hamer, o último de 20 crianças e de 
um fazendeiro de tenant de Mississippi, pulado ao prominence nacional 
durante a convenção 1964 nacional democrática, quando desafiou 
eloquently preliminar democrático segregado de Mississippi na 
televisão nacional. Em 1962, tinha-se transformado um líder do
movimento Africano-Americano das direitas votando em Mississippi que 
culminou no verão da liberdade 1964's. Forçado fora de sua 
terra quando seu landlord exijiu que faz exame de seu nome fora da 
lista do registo do eleitor, Hamer jailed e foi batido repetidamente 
durante suas atividades das direitas votando. "a única coisa 
que poderiam me fazer era matança mim," Hamer dito, "e ele pareceu 
como  tentando fazer que um bit pequeno em um momento sempre desde que
eu poderia recordar."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fannie Lou Hamer, l'ultimo di 20 bambini e di un 
affittuario del Mississippi, saltato alla protuberanza nazionale 
durante la convenzione nazionale democratica 1964, quando eloquente ha
sfidato primario democratico segregato del Mississippi sulla 
televisione nazionale. In 1962, era diventato un capo del
movimento Africano-Americano di diritti di voto nel Mississippi che ha
culminato nell'estate di libertà 1964's. Forzato fuori della 
sua terra quando il suo proprietario ha richiesto che prende il suo 
nome fuori della lista di registro dell'elettore, Hamer ripetutamente 
è stato imprigionato e battuto stato durante le sue attività di 
diritti di voto. "l'unica cosa che potrebbero fare a me era 
uccisione me," Hamer detto, "ed esso ha sembrato come provando a fare 
che un bit piccolo alla volta da quando potrei ricordarsi di."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Fannie Lou Hamer, ο τελευταίος 20 παιδιών 
και ενός αγρότη μισθωτών του Μισισιπή, πήδησε στην εθνική 
προεξοχή κατά τη διάρκεια της δημοκρατικής εθνικής Συνθήκης του 
1964, όταν προκάλεσε εύγλωττα διαχωρισμένο δημοκρατικό αρχικό
του Μισισιπή στην εθνική τηλεόραση. Το 1962, είχε γίνει 
ηγέτης της αφρικανικός-αμερικανικής μετακίνησης δικαιωμάτων 
ψήφου στο Μισισιπή που κατέληξε το καλοκαίρι ελευθερίας 
1964's. Αναγκασμένο από το έδαφός της όταν απαίτησε ο 
ιδιοκτήτης της να βγάλει το όνομά της από τον κατάλογο εγγραφής
ψηφοφόρων, Hamer φυλακίστηκε επανειλημμένα και κτυπήθηκε κατά 
τη διάρκεια των δραστηριοτήτων δικαιωμάτων ψήφου της. "Το 
μόνο πράγμα που θα μπορούσαν να κάνουν σε με ήταν θανάτωση 
εγώ," Hamer εν λόγω, "και φάνηκε όπως το they'd επιδιγμένος
για να κάνει αυτού λίγο σε έναν χρόνο από τότε που μπόρεσα να 
θυμηθώ."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fannie Lou Hamer, el último de 20 niños y de un 
granjero de arrendatario de Mississippi, saltado a la prominencia 
nacional durante la convención nacional democrática 1964, cuando 
ella elocuente desafió primario democrático segregada de Mississippi
en la televisión nacional. En 1962, ella había hecho un 
arranque de cinta del movimiento Africano-Americano de los derechos al
voto en Mississippi que culminó en verano de la libertad 1964's. 
Forzado de su pista cuando su propietario exigió que ella toma 
su nombre de la lista del registro del votante, Hamer fue encarcelado 
y batido en varias ocasiones durante sus actividades de los derechos 
al voto. "la única cosa que podrían hacer a mí era matanza 
yo," Hamer dicho, "y él se parecía como  intentando hacer eso un 
poco al mismo tiempo desde entonces podría recordar."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086278</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108579</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-didnt-know-anything-about-voting-fannie-lou-hamer-on-the-mississippi-voter-registration-campaign</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
