<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107207</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107207</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211554</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Phases of the Moon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Phasen des Mondes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Phases de la lune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fases da lua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fasi della luna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φάσεις του φεγγαριού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fases de la luna</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This exercise has students use a simple physical model of the Earth, sun, and moon to understand why the moon changes phases from the perspective of Earthly observers. Students hold up balls representing the moon in a room with a single light source (representing the sun). As they turn relative to the sun, holding the "moon" out in front of them, they will see changes in how much of the side that they can see is lit. At the same time, they can check and see that overall, half of the "moon" is lit no matter what position it is in relative to them. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Übung läßt Kursteilnehmer ein einfaches 
körperliches Modell der Masse, der Sonne und des Mondes benutzen, um 
zu verstehen, warum der Mond Phasen von der Perspektive der Earthly 
Beobachter ändert. Kursteilnehmer halten die Kugeln, die den 
Mond in einem Raum mit einer einzelnen Lichtquelle darstellen (die 
Sonne darstellend). Da sie im Verhältnis zu der Sonne sich 
drehen, den "Mond" heraus vor ihnen anhalten, sehen sie, daß 
Änderungen in, wieviel der Seite ist, die sie sehen können, 
beleuchteten. Gleichzeitig können sie überprüfen und sehen 
das wird Gesamtes, Hälfte des "Mondes" beleuchtet, egal was Position 
es innen sie relative.to ist. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite 
können Benutzer auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung,
Kontext für Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und 
Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen 
zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice fait employer à des étudiants un 
modèle physique simple de la terre, du soleil, et de la lune pour 
comprendre pourquoi la lune change des phases de la perspective des 
observateurs terrestres. Les étudiants supportent des boules 
représentant la lune dans une chambre avec une source lumineuse 
simple (représentant le soleil). Car ils tournent relativement 
au soleil, tenant la "lune" dehors devant eux, ils verront que des 
changements de combien du côté qu'ils peuvent voir coûte s'est 
allumé. En même temps, ils peuvent contrôler et voir cela la 
combinaison, moitié de la "lune" est allumée n'importe ce que la 
position il est dedans relative ils. À cette page de point de 
départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations sur les 
buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités 
d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, 
les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício manda estudantes usar um modelo 
físico simples da terra, do sol, e da lua compreender porque a lua 
muda fases do perspective de observadores earthly. Os estudantes
mantêm levantadas as esferas que representam a lua em um quarto com 
uma única fonte clara (que representa o sol). Porque giram 
relativo ao sol, prendendo a "lua" para fora na frente deles, verão 
que mudanças em quanto do lado que podem ver é iluminou-se. Ao
mesmo tempo, podem verificar e para ver isso o macacão, metade da 
"lua" é iluminado não importa o que a posição ele é dentro 
relative.to eles. Nesta página do ponto começar, os usuários 
podem alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do 
exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os 
materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as referências e os 
tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione fa usare agli allievi un 
modello fisico semplice della terra, del sole e della luna per capire 
perchè la luna cambia le fasi dalla prospettiva degli osservatori 
earthly. Gli allievi sostengono le sfere che rappresentano la 
luna in una stanza con una singola fonte di luce (che rappresenta il 
sole). Poichè girano riguardante il sole, tenuta "la luna"
fuori davanti loro, vedranno che cambiamenti in quanto del lato che 
possono vedere è si è illuminato. Allo stesso tempo, possono 
controllare e vedere quello il camice, metà "della luna" è 
illuminato qualunque cosa la posizione esso sia dentro relativa loro. 
A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono 
accedere alle informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti 
dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di istruzione, di uso note 
e, i materiali didattici, le idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i 
soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η άσκηση έχει τους σπουδαστές να χρησιμοποιήσουν
ένα απλό φυσικό μοντέλο της γης, του ήλιου, και του φεγγαριού 
για να καταλάβει γιατί το φεγγάρι αλλάζει τις φάσεις από την 
προοπτική των γείηνων παρατηρητών. Οι σπουδαστές κρατούν 
ψηλά τις σφαίρες που αντιπροσωπεύουν το φεγγάρι σε ένα δωμάτιο 
με μια ενιαία πηγή φωτός (που αντιπροσωπεύει τον ήλιο). 
Καθώς γυρίζουν σχετικά με τον ήλιο, κρατώντας το "φεγγάρι"
έξω μπροστά από τους, θα δουν τις αλλαγές σε πόσο της
πλευράς που μπορούν να δουν ανάβει. Συγχρόνως, 
μπορούν να ελέγξουν και να δουν αυτού συνολικά, το 
μισό από το "φεγγάρι" ανάβει η του οποίου θέση είναι σχετικά 
με τους. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν 
να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της
άσκησης, πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες 
διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις 
αναφορές και τα θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio hace que los estudiantes utilicen 
un modelo físico simple de la tierra, del sol, y de la luna para 
entender porqué la luna cambia fases de la perspectiva de 
observadores terrenales. Los estudiantes soportan las bolas que 
representan la luna en un cuarto con una sola fuente de luz (que 
representa el sol). Pues dan vuelta concerniente al sol, 
sosteniendo la "luna" hacia fuera delante de ellos, verán que los 
cambios en cuánto de la cara que pueden ver es se encendió. En
el mismo tiempo, pueden controlar y ver eso se enciende el 
guardapolvo, mitad de la "luna" no importa qué la posición él es 
adentro en relación con ellos. En esta paginación del punto de
partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre 
las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades 
del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las
ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REBECCA TEED
FN:REBECCA TEED
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211554</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107207</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/phases-of-the-moon-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
