<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107419</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107419</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086839</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Society note from Moscow."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Gesellschaftanmerkung von Moskau."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"note de société de Moscou."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">da "nota sociedade de Moscow."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"nota della società da Mosca."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σημείωση κοινωνίας από τη Μόσχα."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"nota de la sociedad de Moscú."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In November 1917 the second phase of the Russian revolution unfolded, as communists led by V. I. Lenin took power. Although deeply disturbing to President Woodrow Wilson and other western leaders, the Bolsheviks promised a far-reaching social transformation that appealed to downtrodden peoples around the world. This cartoon was one of a series by Alfred Freuh in the radical weekly  Good Morning  that celebrated the Bolshevik Revolution's impact on Russia's aristocracy: Count Parasitsky will not occupy his palatial residence in the mountains this summer</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im November 1917 britt die zweite Phase der russischen 
Umdrehung, als Kommunisten aus, die von V geführt wurden. I. 
Lenin nahm Energie. Obgleich tief, störend zum Präsidenten 
Woodrow Wilson und andere westliche Führer, versprachen die 
Bolschewike eine weitreichende Sozialtransformation, die downtrodden 
Völkern um die Welt gefiel. Diese Karikatur war eine einer 
Serie durch Alfred Freuh im radikalen wöchentlichen guten Morgen, der
die Auswirkung der Bolschewik-Umdrehung auf Aristokratie Rußlands 
feierte: Zählimpuls Parasitsky besetzt nicht seinen palatial 
Wohnsitz in den Bergen dieser Sommer</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En novembre 1917 la deuxième phase de la révolution 
russe a dévoilé, comme communistes menés par V. I. Lenin a 
pris la puissance. Bien que profondément troublant au 
Président Woodrow Wilson et d'autres amorces occidentales, les 
bolchéviques ont promis une transformation sociale de grande 
envergure qui a fait appel aux peuples piétinés autour du monde. 
Ce dessin animé était un d'une série par Alfred Freuh en 
bonjour hebdomadaire radical qui a célébré l'impact de la 
révolution de bolchévique sur l'aristocratie de la Russie : Le
compte Parasitsky n'occupera pas sa résidence somptueuse dans les 
montagnes cet été</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em novembro 1917 a segunda fase da volta russian unfolded,
como os comunistas conduzidos por V. I. Lenin fêz exame da 
potência. Embora profundamente perturbando ao presidente 
Woodrow Wilson e outros líderes ocidentais, os bolsheviks prometeram 
uma transformação social far-reaching que apelasse aos povos 
downtrodden em torno do mundo. Este cartoon era uma de uma 
série por Alfred Freuh na manhã boa semanal radical que comemorou o 
impacto da volta do bolshevik no aristocracy de Rússia: A 
contagem Parasitsky não ocupará sua residência palatial nas 
montanhas este verão</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In novembre 1917 la seconda fase della rivoluzione russa 
ha spiegato, come comunisti condotti da V. I. Lenin ha preso 
l'potenza. Anche se profondamente disturbandosi al presidente 
Woodrow Wilson ed altri capi occidentali, i bolsheviks hanno 
promesso una trasformazione sociale ampia che ha fatto appello alla 
gente downtrodden intorno al mondo. Questo fumetto era uno di 
una serie da Alfred Freuh nella buona mattina settimanale radicale che
ha celebrato l'effetto della rivoluzione del bolshevik sul aristocracy
della Russia: Il conteggio Parasitsky non occuperà la sua 
residenza palatial nelle montagne questa estate</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Νοέμβριο του 1917 η δεύτερη φάση της ρωσικής 
επανάστασης που ξετυλίγεται, ως κομμουνιστές που οδηγούνται από 
το Β. Ι. Λένιν πήρε τη δύναμη. Αν και βαθειά 
ενοχλητικό στον Πρόεδρο Woodrow Wilson και άλλους δυτικούς 
ηγέτες, το Bolsheviks υποσχέθηκε έναν εκτεταμένο κοινωνικό 
μετασχηματισμό που απευθύνθηκε στους τσαλαπατημένους λαούς σε όλο
τον κόσμο. Αυτά τα κινούμενα σχέδια ήταν μια από μια 
σειρά από τον Alfred Freuh τη ριζική εβδομαδιαία καλημέρα 
που γιόρτασε τον αντίκτυπο της μπολσεβικικής επανάστασης στην 
αριστοκρατία της Ρωσίας: Η αρίθμηση Parasitsky δεν θα 
καταλάβει την ανακτορική κατοικία του στα βουνά αυτό το 
καλοκαίρι</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En noviembre 1917 la segunda fase de la revolución rusa 
reveló, como comunistas conducidos por V. I. Lenin tomó 
potencia. Aunque profundamente disturbaron a presidente Woodrow 
Wilson y otros arranques de cinta occidentales, los bolsheviks 
prometieron una transformación social de gran envergadura que abrogó
a la gente pisoteada alrededor del mundo. Esta historieta era 
una de una serie de Alfred Freuh por la buena mañana semanal radical 
que celebró el impacto de la revolución del bolshevik en la 
aristocracia de Rusia: La cuenta Parasitsky no ocupará su 
residencia palatial en las montañas este verano</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086839</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107419</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/society-note-from-moscow</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
