<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105433</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105433</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205799</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Nineteenth Century in Print: the Making of America in Books and Periodicals</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das 19.jahrhundert im Druck: das Bilden von 
Amerika in den Büchern und in den Zeitschriften</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le dix-neuvième siècle dans la copie : la 
fabrication de l'Amérique en livres et périodiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O décimo nono século na cópia: fazer de 
América nos livros e nos periodicals</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il diciannovesimo secolo in stampa: fare 
dell'America in libri e periodici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο δέκατος έννατος αιώνας στην τυπωμένη ύλη: η 
παραγωγή της Αμερικής στα βιβλία και τα περιοδικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El diecinueveavo siglo en la impresión: la 
fabricación de América en libros y periódicos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents digitized books and periodicals published in the U.S. during the 19th century. The collection includes 23 popular magazines and more than 1,500 books that illuminate themes central to American life in the mid- to late 19th century, including the Civil War, slavery and abolition, religion, education, self-help and self-improvement, travel and westward expansion, and poetry.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschenke digitalisierte Bücher und Zeitschriften
veröffentlichten in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN während des 19. 
Jahrhunderts. Die Ansammlung enthält 23 populäre Zeitschriften
und mehr als 1.500 Bücher, die die Themen belichten, die zur 
amerikanischen Lebensdauer im mittleren zum des späten 19. 
jahrhunderts Jahrhundert, einschließlich den Bürgerkrieg, die 
Sklaverei und die Aufhebung, die Religion, die Ausbildung, der 
Self-help und die Selbst-Verbesserung, der Spielraum und die nach 
Westen gerichtete Expansion zentral sind, und Poesie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les livres et les périodiques numérisés par 
présents ont édité aux ETATS-UNIS pendant le 19ème siècle. 
La collection inclut 23 magasins populaires et plus de 1.500 
livres qui illuminent des thèmes centraux à la vie américaine dans 
le mi à la fin du 19me siècle, y compris la guerre civile, 
l'esclavage et l'abolition, la religion, l'éducation, le 
art de l'auto-portrait-help et le art de l'auto-portrait-improvement, le voyage et l'expansion 
à l'ouest, et poésie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os livros e os periodicals digitados presentes 
publicaram nos ESTADOS UNIDOS durante o 1ø século. A coleção
inclui 23 compartimentos populares e mais de 1.500 livros que iluminam
os temas centrais à vida americana no mid- ao 1ø século atrasado, 
including a guerra civil, o slavery e o abolition, a religião, a 
instrução, o self-help e a self-melhoria, o curso e a expansão na 
direcção ocidental, e poesia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i libri ed i periodici dati valori numerici a 
presenti hanno pubblicato negli STATI UNITI durante il diciannovesimo 
secolo. L'accumulazione include 23 scomparti popolari e più di 
1.500 libro che illuminano i temi centrali a vita americana nel metà 
di al fine del 19esimo secolo, compresi la guerra civile, lo slavery e
l'abolizione, la religione, la formazione, il self-help ed il 
auto-miglioramento, la corsa e l'espansione westward e la poesia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τα μεταλλαγμένα βιβλία και τα περιοδικά 
που δημοσιεύονται στις ΗΠΑ κατά τη διάρκεια του 19$ου αιώνα. 
Η συλλογή περιλαμβάνει 23 δημοφιλή περιοδικά και 
περισσότερα από 1.500 βιβλία που φωτίζουν τα θέματα κεντρικά 
στην αμερικανική ζωή στο μέσο - στο 19$ο αργά αιώνα, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου του εμφύλιου πολέμου, της σκλαβιάς και της 
κατάργησης, της θρησκείας, της εκπαίδευσης, της αυτοβοήθειας και 
της μόνος-βελτίωσης, του ταξιδιού και της δυτικής επέκτασης, και 
της ποίησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los libros y los periódicos digitalizados los 
presentes publicaron en los ESTADOS UNIDOS durante el diecinueveavo 
siglo. La colección incluye 23 compartimientos populares y más
de 1.500 libros que iluminen los temas centrales a la vida americana 
al mediados de a la a fines del siglo XIX, incluyendo la guerra civil,
la esclavitud y la abolición, la religión, la educación, el 
esfuerzo personal y la uno mismo-mejora, el recorrido y la extensión 
que va hacia el oeste, y poesía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205799</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105433</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-nineteenth-century-in-print-the-making-of-america-in-books-and-periodicals</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
