<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108438</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108438</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101440</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Petri Dish Circus (MWV12)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Petrischale Zirkus (MWV12)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cirque de Boîte de Pétri (MWV12)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Circus Do Prato De Petri (MWV12)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Circus Della Capsula di Petri (MWV12)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Petri τσίρκο πιάτων (MWV12)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Circo Del Plato De Petri (MWV12)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">See the history of microbiology in nine scenes of gags, burlesque, drollery and song. Produced by Active Cultures, the vernacular theater of Maryland, Petri Dish Circus is a play based off of the classic non-fiction novel Microbe Hunters by Paul Henry de Kruif. Much like the original book first published in 1926 that describes 12 historical milestones in science, Active Cultures reenacts "the daring-do of Louis Pasteur in his Parisian lab, the Scotch fortitude of Ronald Ross as he travels through disease-stricken Africa, and the melancholy saga of Walter Reed as he battles Yellow Jack in Cuba" - all with a healthy dose of humor. In this episode, we interview Mary Resing, artistic director for Active Cultures, who talks about Microbe Hunters as inspiration for theater and her whimsical, and slightly pointed, approach to the portrayal of women featured in de Kruif's work. Excerpts from the actual performance are also featured.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sehen Sie die Geschichte von Mikrobiologie in neun
Szenen des Gags, der Burleske, des Drollery und des Lieds. 
Produziert durch Active Cultures, ist das vernacular Theater von
Maryland, Petrischale Zirkus ein Spiel, das weg von den 
klassischen Nichterfindung Roman Mikrobe Jägern von Paul Henry de 
Kruif gegründet wird. Ganz wie das ursprüngliche Buch, das 
zuerst 1926, das beschreibt 12 historische Meilensteine in der 
Wissenschaft, die aktiven Kulturen reenacts "von Louis Pasteur in 
seinem Pariser Labor, von der schottischen Kraft von Ronald Ross, 
während er reist durch Krankheit-getroffenes Afrika, und von der 
melancholischen Saga des Walter Schilfs während verwegen- 
er veröffentlicht wird, Schlachten gelber Jack in Kuba" - aller mit 
einer gesunden Dosis der Stimmung. In dieser Episode interviewen
wir Mary Resing, künstlerischer Direktor für aktive Kulturen, der 
mit Mikrobe Jägern während Inspiration für Theater und ihr 
whimsical sich befaßt, und etwas gezeigt, Annäherung auf die 
Schilderung der Frauen, die de Kruifs in der Arbeit gekennzeichnet 
werden. Excerpts von der Ist-Leistung werden auch 
gekennzeichnet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voyez l'histoire de la microbiologie dans neuf 
scènes de bâillon, de burlesque, de drôlerie et de chanson. 
Produit par Active Cultures, le théâtre vernaculaire du 
Maryland, cirque de boîte de Pétri Est un jeu basé hors fonction 
des chasseurs classiques de microbe de roman de non-fiction par Paul 
Henry de Kruif. Tout comme le livre initial d'abord édité en 
1926 qui décrit 12 étapes importantes historiques dans la science, 
reenacts actifs de cultures "audacieux- de Louis Pasteur dans son 
laboratoire parisien, du courage écossais de Ronald Ross pendant
qu'il voyage par l'Afrique maladie-frappée, et de la saga 
mélancolique du roseau de Walter pendant qu'il les batailles Jack 
jaune au Cuba" - tout avec une dose saine d'humeur. Dans cet 
épisode, nous interviewons Mary Resing, le directeur artistique pour 
les cultures actives, qui parle des chasseurs de microbe pendant 
qu'inspiration pour le théâtre et son lunatique, et légèrement 
dirigé, approche à la représentation des femmes décrites en 
travail de de Kruif's. Des extraits de l'exécution réelle sont
également décrits.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Veja o history do microbiology em nove cenas da 
mordaça, do burlesque, da brincadeira e da canção. Produzido 
por Ativo Cultura, o teatro vernacular de Maryland, circus do prato de
petri é um jogo baseado fora dos caçadores clássicos do micróbio 
da novela do non-non-fiction por Paul Henry de Kruif. Bem como o
livro original publicado primeiramente em 1926 que descreve 12 marcos 
miliários históricos na ciência, nos reenacts ativos das culturas 
"audaz- de Louis Pasteur em seu laboratório parisian, do fortitude 
scotch de Ronald Ross enquanto viaja através de África 
doença-golpeada, e do saga melancólico da lingüeta de Walter 
enquanto as batalhas Jack amarelo em Cuba" - tudo com um dose 
saudável do humor. Neste episode, nós entrevistamos Mary 
Resing, o diretor artístico para culturas ativas, que fala sobre 
caçadores do micróbio enquanto inspiração para o teatro e o seu 
whimsical, e apontado ligeiramente, aproximação ao portrayal das 
mulheres caracterizadas no trabalho de de Kruif. Os excerpts do 
desempenho real são caracterizados também.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Veda la storia di microbiologia in nove scene del 
bavaglio, del burlesque, del drollery e della canzone. Prodotto 
da Active Cultures, il teatro vernacolare di Maryland, circus della 
capsula di Petri È un gioco basato fuori dei cacciatori classici del 
microbo del romanzo di non-romanzo da Paul Henry de Kruif. Tanto
come il libro originale in primo luogo pubblicato in 1926 che descrive
12 pietre storiche nella scienza, nei reenacts attivi delle colture 
"daring- di Louis Pasteur nel suo laboratorio parigino, del fortitude 
scozzese di Ronald Ross mentre attraversa through l'Africa 
malattia-impressionante e del saga malinconico della canna di Walter 
mentre battaglie Jack giallo in Cuba" - tutto con una dose sana di 
umore. In questo episodio, intervistiamo Mary Resing, direttore 
artistico per le colture attive, che colloqui circa i cacciatori 
del microbo come ispirazione per il teatro ed il suo whimsical ed 
indicato un po', metodo alla rappresentazione delle donne descritte 
nel lavoro del de Kruif. I brani dalle prestazioni reali 
egualmente sono descritti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δείτε την ιστορία της μικροβιολογίας σε 
εννέα σκηνές των φιμωμάτων, παρωδίακος, drollery και του 
τραγουδιού. Παραχθέν από τους ενεργούς πολιτισμούς, το 
ιδιωματικό θέατρο της Μέρυλαντ, petri τσίρκο πιάτων είναι 
ένα παιχνίδι που βασίζεται μακριά των κλασικών non-fiction 
νέων κυνηγών μικροβίων από Paul Henry δε Kruif. Σαν
το αρχικό βιβλίο που δημοσιεύεται πρώτα το 1926 που περιγράφει
12 ιστορικά κύρια σημεία στην επιστήμη, οι ενεργοί πολιτισμοί
reenacts "τολμώ-κάνουν του Louis Pasteur στο παρισινό 
εργαστήριό του, σκωτσέζικο fortitude του Ronald Ross 
καθώς ταξιδεύει μέσω της ασθένεια-κτυπημένης Αφρικής, και του 
μελαγχολικού μακριού περιπετειώδους μυθιστορήματος walter 
Reed δεδομένου ότι μάχεται τον κίτρινο Jack στην Κούβα" - 
όλοι με μια υγιή δόση του χιούμορ. Σε αυτό το επεισόδιο, 
παίρνουμε συνέντευξη από Mary Resing, καλλιτεχνικός 
σκηνοθέτης για τους ενεργούς πολιτισμούς, που μιλά για τους 
κυνηγούς μικροβίων ως έμπνευση για το θέατρο και την ιδιότροπα, 
και ελαφρώς δειγμένος, προσέγγιση στην απεικόνιση των γυναικών 
που χαρακτηρίζονται στην εργασία de Kruif's. Τα 
αποσπάσματα από την πραγματική απόδοση χαρακτηρίζονται επίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vea la historia de la microbiología en nueve 
escenas de la mordaza, del burlesque, de la payasada y de la canción.
Producido por Active Cultures, el teatro vernáculo de Maryland,
circo del plato de petri es un juego basado apagado de los cazadores 
clásicos del microbio de la novela de la no-ficcio'n por Paul Henry 
de Kruif. Como el libro original primero publicado en 1926 que 
describa 12 jalones históricos en ciencia, los reenacts activos de 
las culturas "atrevido- de Louis Pasteur en su laboratorio parisiense,
de la fortaleza de ánimo escocesa de Ronald Ross como él viaja a través de 
África enfermedad-pulso, y de la saga melancólica de la caña 
de Walter mientras que él las batallas Gato amarillo en Cuba" - todo 
con una dosis sana del humor. En este episodio, nos 
entrevistamos con a Maria Resing, el director artístico para las 
culturas activas, que habla de cazadores del microbio mientras que 
inspiración para el teatro y su whimsical, y señalado levemente, 
acercamiento a la representación de las mujeres ofrecidas en el 
trabajo de de Kruif. Los extractos del funcionamiento real 
también se ofrecen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MICROBEWORLD
FN:MICROBEWORLD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101440</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108438</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/petri-dish-circus-mwv12</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
