<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103327</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103327</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201194</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Deep Sea Vents Harbor Earth's Hottest Animal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tiefes Meer Lüftet Heißestes Tier Der 
Hafen-Masse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Mer Profonde Exhale l'Animal Le plus chaud de 
la Terre de Port</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Mar Profundo Exala O Animal O mais quente Da 
Terra Do Porto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Mare Profondo Scarica L'Animale Più caldo 
Della Terra Del Porto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καυτότερο ζώο της μεγάλης θαλασσίων βαθών γης 
διεξόδων λιμενικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Mar Profundo Expresa El Animal Más caliente De
la Tierra Del Puerto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This University of Delaware interactive web page combines text, images, video, and audio clips to describe the Pompeii worm (Alvinella pompejana), the most heat tolerant animal on Earth. Features of this site include: a 3-D visual which allows users to manipulate and view the organism from all angles, a video that shows the worm feeding on bacteria in its habitat, and audio clips that enhance images of the worm and its hydrothermal vent community.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Universität Delaware der interaktiven 
Webseite kombiniert Text, Bilder, Bildschirm, und die Audioclips, zum 
der Pompeji Endlosschraube (Alvinella pompejana) zu beschreiben, die 
die meisten erhitzen tolerantes Tier auf Masse. Merkmale dieser 
Sites schließen ein: eine Sichtbarmachung 3-D, die Benutzern 
erlaubt, den Organismus von allen Winkeln, von einem Bildschirm, der 
die Endlosschraube, die auf Bakterium zeigt in seinem Lebensraum 
einzieht und von den Audioclips zu manipulieren und anzusehen, die 
Bilder der Endlosschraube und seiner hydrothermalen 
Entlüftungsöffnung Gemeinschaft erhöhen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette université de page Web interactive du 
Delaware combine le texte, images, vidéo, et les clips sonores pour 
décrire le ver de Pompeii (pompejana d'Alvinella), les la plupart 
chauffent l'animal tolérant sur terre. Les dispositifs de ce 
site incluent : un visuel 3-D qui permet à des utilisateurs de 
manipuler et visualiser l'organization de tous les angles, d'un vidéo
qui montre le ver alimentant sur des bactéries dans son habitat, et 
des clips sonores qui mettent en valeur des images du ver et de son 
communauté hydrothermique d'évent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta universidade do Web page interativo de 
Delaware combina o texto, imagens, vídeo, e os grampos audio para 
descrever o sem-fim de Pompeii (pompejana de Alvinella), o a maioria 
aquecem o animal tolerante na terra. As características deste 
local incluem: um visual 3-D que permita que os usuários 
manipulem e v o organismo de todos os ângulos, de um vídeo que 
mostre o sem-fim que alimenta nas bactérias em seu habitat, e dos 
grampos audio que realçam imagens do sem-fim e de sua comunidade 
hydrothermal do respiradouro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa università di Web page interattivo del 
Delaware unisce il testo, le immagini, video e le clip audio per 
descrivere la vite senza fine de Pompeii (pompejana di Alvinella), il 
la maggior parte riscaldano l'animale tollerante su terra. Le 
caratteristiche di questo luogo includono: una rappresentazione 
3-D che permette che gli utenti maneggino ed osservino l'organismo da 
tutti gli angoli, da un video che mostra la vite senza fine che si 
alimenta sui batteri nel relativo habitat e dalle clip audio che 
aumentano le immagini della vite senza fine e della relativa Comunità
idrotermale dello sfiato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το πανεπιστήμιο διαλογική ιστοσελίδας του 
Delaware συνδυάζει το κείμενο, εικόνες, βίντεο, και οι 
ηχητικοί συνδετήρες για να περιγράψουν το σκουλήκι της Πομπηίας 
(pompejana Alvinella), οι περισσότεροι θερμαίνουν το ανεκτικό
ζώο στη γη. Τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα αυτής της περιοχής
περιλαμβάνουν: τρισδιάστατος ένας οπτικός που επιτρέπει 
στους χρήστες για να χειριστεί και να εμφανίσει τον οργανισμό από
όλες τις γωνίες, ένα βίντεο που εμφανίζουν το σκουλήκι που 
ταϊ'ζει με τα βακτηρίδια στο βιότοπό του, και τους ηχητικούς 
συνδετήρες που ενισχύουν τις εικόνες του σκουληκιού και της 
κοινότητας υδροθερμικών διεξόδων του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta universidad del Web page interactivo de 
Delaware combina el texto, imágenes, vídeo, y los clips audio para 
describir el gusano de Pompeii (pompejana de Alvinella), el la 
mayoría calientan el animal tolerante en la tierra. Las 
características de este sitio incluyen: una representación 
visual 3-D que permite que los utilizadores manipulen y que visión el
organismo de todos los ángulos, de un vídeo que muestre el gusano 
que alimenta en bacterias en su habitat, y de los clips audio que 
realzan las imágenes del gusano y de su comunidad hidrotérmica del 
respiradero.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MISSION TO THE ABYSS
FN:MISSION TO THE ABYSS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNIVERSITY OF DELAWARE GRADUATE COLLEGE OF MARINE STUDIES
FN:UNIVERSITY OF DELAWARE GRADUATE COLLEGE OF MARINE STUDIES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201194</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103327</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/deep-sea-vents-harbor-earths-hottest-animal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
