<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106775</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106775</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206712</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Online Academy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Onlineakademie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Académie En ligne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Academy Em linha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'Accademia In linea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σε απευθείας σύνδεση ακαδημία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Academia En línea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1999-2000 the Anacostia Community Museum renovated its facility to focus on the collection, storage and study of artifacts. This on-line academy is presented as part of the museum's recommitment to identify, study, preserve, and collect African American historical materials. 

The Online Academy highlights artifacts, scholars, collectors, and preservers of African American history. Features include the inventor of the multiple effect vacuum process for producing sugar, the first identified African American toolmaker, the autobiography of an African American cowboy, and Zora Neale Hurston's first novel.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In 1999-2000 erneuerte das Anacostia 
Gemeinschaftsmuseum seinen Teildienst, um auf die Ansammlung, die 
Speicherung und die Studie der Kunstprodukte zu konzentrieren. 
Diese Onlineakademie wird als Teil des recommitment des Museums 
dargestellt, um afrikanische amerikanische historische Materialien zu 
kennzeichnen, zu studieren, zu konservieren und zu sammeln. Die 
Onlineakademie markiert Kunstprodukte, Gelehrte, Sammler und Retter 
der afrikanischen amerikanischen Geschichte. Merkmale enthalten 
den Erfinder des mehrfachen Effektvakuumprozesses für das Produzieren
des Zuckers, der zuerst gekennzeichnete afrikanische amerikanische 
Toolmaker, die Autobiographie eines afrikanischen amerikanischen 
Cowboys und Zora Neale Hurstons des ersten Romans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1999-2000 le musée de la Communauté 
d'Anacostia a rénové son dextérité pour se concentrer sur la 
collection, la mémoire et l'étude des objets façonnés. Cette
académie en ligne est présentée en tant qu'élément du 
recommitment du musée pour identifier, étudier, préserver, et 
rassembler les matériaux historiques américains africains. 
L'académie en ligne met en valeur des objets façonnés, des 
disciples, des collecteurs, et des conservateurs de l'histoire 
américaine africaine. Les dispositifs incluent l'inventeur du 
procédé multiple de vide d'effet pour produire le sucre, l'outilleur
américain africain d'abord identifié, l'autobiographie d'un cowboy 
américain africain, et roman de Zora Neale Hurston du premier.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1999-2000 o museu da comunidade de Anacostia 
renovated sua facilidade para focalizar na coleção, no armazenamento
e no estudo dos artifacts. Este academy em linha é apresentado 
como a parte do recommitment do museu para identificar, estudar, 
preservar, e coletar materiais históricos americanos africanos. 
O academy em linha destaca artifacts, scholars, coletores, e 
preservers do history americano africano. As características 
incluem o inventor do processo múltiplo do vácuo do efeito para 
produzir o açúcar, toolmaker americano africano primeiramente 
identificado, o autobiography de um vaqueiro americano africano, e 
novela de Zora Neale Hurston da primeira.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1999-2000 il museo della Comunità di Anacostia
ha rinnovato la relativa funzione per mettere a fuoco 
sull'accumulazione, sulla memoria e sullo studio sui manufatti. 
Questa accademia in linea è presentata come componente del 
recommitment del museo per identificare, studiare, conservare e 
raccogliere i materiali storici americani africani. 
L'Accademia in linea evidenzia i manufatti, gli eruditi, i 
collettori ed i preservers di storia americana africana. Le 
caratteristiche includono l'inventore del procedimento multiplo di 
vuoto di effetto per produrre lo zucchero, il toolmaker americano 
africano in primo luogo identificato, il autobiography di un cowboy 
americano africano e romanzo di Zora Neale Hurston del primo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1999-2000 το κοινοτικό μουσείο Anacostia 
ανακαίνισε τη δυνατότητά του για να εστιάσει στη συλλογή, την 
αποθήκευση και τη μελέτη των χειροποίητων αντικειμένων. 
Αυτή η σε απευθείας σύνδεση ακαδημία παρουσιάζεται ως 
τμήμα recommitment του μουσείου που προσδιορίζει, που μελετά, 
που συντηρεί, και που συλλέγει τα αφρικανικά αμερικανικά ιστορικά
υλικά. Η σε απευθείας σύνδεση ακαδημία δίνει έμφαση στα 
χειροποίητα αντικείμενα, τους μελετητές, τους συλλέκτες, και τα 
συντηρητικά της αφρικανικής αμερικανικής ιστορίας. Τα 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα περιλαμβάνουν τον εφευρέτη της 
πολλαπλάσιας κενής διαδικασίας επίδρασης για τη ζάχαρη, το πρώτο
προσδιορισμένο αφρικανικό αμερικανικό toolmaker, την 
αυτοβιογραφία ενός αφρικανικού αμερικανικού κάουμποϋ, και το 
πρώτο μυθιστόρημα της Zora Neale Hurston's.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1999-2000 el museo de la comunidad de Anacostia
renovó su recurso para centrarse en la colección, el almacenaje y el
estudio de artefactos. Presentan esta academia en línea como 
parte del recommitment del museo para identificar, para estudiar, para
preservar, y para recoger los materiales históricos americanos 
africanos. La academia en línea destaca a los artefactos, a los
eruditos, a los colectores, y a preservers de la historia americana 
africana. Las características incluyen a inventor del proceso 
múltiple del vacío del efecto para producir el azúcar, el toolmaker
americano africano primero identificado, la autobiografía de un 
vaquero americano africano, y novela de Zora Neale Hurston de la 
primera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206712</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106775</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-online-academy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
