<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103935</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103935</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212137</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Slinky and Waves</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schleichend und Wellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Furtif et vagues</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Slinky e ondas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Slinky ed onde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κρυψίνους και κύματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Slinky y ondas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Slinky and Wave exercise is an interactive lecture that explains how to use a Slinky to demonstrate motion of P- and S-waves, wave reflection and standing waves. The demonstration is designed for use in an introductory geoscience course where wave properties are important such as geology, oceanography, or atmospheric sciences. The site includes teaching materials on P- and S-waves, standing waves and seismic waves. Also outlined in the site are teaching tips, assessment information and additional references. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die schleichende und Welle Übung ist ein 
interaktiver Vortrag, der erklärt, wie man ein schleichendes 
verwendet, um Bewegung von p zu demonstrieren und, Welle Reflexion 
S-wellenartig bewegt und Stellung wellenartig bewegt. Die 
Demonstration ist für Gebrauch in einem einleitenden geoscience Kurs 
bestimmt, in dem Welle Eigenschaften wie Geologie, Ozeanographie oder 
atmosphärische Wissenschaften wichtig sind. Die Site schließt 
Lehrmittel auf p ein und S-bewegt wellenartig und steht Wellen und 
seismische Wellen. Auch umrissen in der Site unterrichten 
Spitzen, Einschätzung Informationen und zusätzliche Referenzen. 
Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'exercice Furtif et de vague est une 
conférence interactive qui explique comment employer un Furtif 
pour démontrer le mouvement du p et S-ondule, réflexion de vague et 
la position ondule. La démonstration est conçue pour l'usage 
dans un cours préliminaire de geoscience où les propriétés de 
vague sont importantes comme la géologie, l'océanographie, ou les 
sciences atmosphériques. Le site inclut le matériel didactique
sur le p et S-ondule, tenant des vagues et des vagues séismiques. 
En outre tracé les grandes lignes dans le site enseignent des 
extrémités, l'information d'évaluation et des références 
supplémentaires. Cette activité fait partie de la collection 
de point de départ : http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O exercício slinky e da onda é um lecture 
interativo que explique como usar um slinky demonstrar o movimento do 
p e S-acene, reflexão da onda e a posição acene. A 
demonstração é projetada para o uso em um curso introdutório do 
geoscience onde as propriedades da onda sejam importantes como a 
geologia, o oceanography, ou ciências atmosféricas. O local 
inclui materiais de ensino no p e S-acena, estando ondas e ondas 
seismic. Esboçado também no local estão ensinando pontas, 
informação da avaliação e referências adicionais. Esta 
atividade é parte da coleção do ponto começar: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'esercitazione dell'onda e slinky è una 
conferenza interattiva che spiega come usare uno slinky per dimostrare
il movimento della p e S-fluttua, riflessione dell'onda e la 
condizione fluttua. La dimostrazione è progettata per uso in un
corso introduttivo di geoscience dove le proprietà dell'onda sono 
importanti quali la geologia, l'oceanografia, o le scienze 
atmosferiche. Il luogo include i materiali didattici sulla p e 
S-fluttua, levandosi in piedi le onde e le onde sismiche. 
Inoltre descritto nel luogo stanno insegnando le punte, le 
informazioni di valutazione ed i riferimenti supplementari. 
Questa attività fa parte dell'accumulazione del punto di 
partenza: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κρυψίνους και άσκηση κυμάτων είναι μια διαλογική 
διάλεξη που εξηγεί πώς να χρησιμοποιήσει έναν κρυψίνους για να 
καταδείξει την κίνηση του π - και των s-kyma'twn, της 
αντανάκλασης κυμάτων και των μόνιμων κυμάτων. Η επίδειξη 
σχεδιάζεται για τη χρήση σε μια εισαγωγική σειρά μαθημάτων 
geoscience όπου οι ιδιότητες κυμάτων είναι σημαντικές όπως η 
γεωλογία, η ωκεανογραφία, ή οι ατμοσφαιρικές επιστήμες. Η 
περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά στο π - και τα 
s-ky'mata, τα μόνιμα κύματα και τα σεισμικά κύματα. 
Επίσης περιγραμμένος στην περιοχή διδάσκει τις συμβουλές, 
τις πληροφορίες αξιολόγησης και τις πρόσθετες αναφορές. 
Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ejercicio slinky y de la onda es una 
conferencia interactiva que explica cómo utilizar un slinky para 
demostrar el movimiento del p y S-agita, reflexión de la onda y la 
situación agita. La demostración se diseña para el uso en un 
curso introductorio del geoscience donde están importantes las 
características de la onda por ejemplo la geología, la 
oceanografía, o ciencias atmosféricas. El sitio incluye los 
materiales didácticos en el p y S-agita, estando paradas ondas y 
ondas sísmicas. También contorneado en el sitio están 
enseñando extremidades, la información del gravamen y referencias 
adicionales. Esta actividad es parte de la colección del punto 
de partida: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MACKAY
FN:ROBERT MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212137</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103935</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/slinky-and-waves</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
