<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103526</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103526</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rhombus area formula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rhombusbereich Formel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Formule de région de losange</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fórmula da área do rhombus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Formula di zona del rhombus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τύπος περιοχής ρόμβων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fórmula del área del rombo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet showing the ways to calculate the area of a rhombus. The user can drag the vertices of the rhombus and the other points change automatically to ensure it remains a rhombus. A grid inside the shape allows students to estimate the area visually, then check against the actual computed area. The text on the page gives three different ways to calculate the area with a formula for each. The applet uses one of the methods to compute the area in real time, so it changes as the rhombus is reshaped with the mouse. A companion page is http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombus.html showing the definition and properties of a rhombus Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, welche 
die Methoden zeigen, den Bereich eines Rhombus zu errechnen. Der
Benutzer kann die Gipfel des Rhombus und der anderen Punktänderung 
automatisch schleppen, um ihm einen Rhombus des Remains 
sicherzustellen. Ein Rasterfeld innerhalb der Form erlaubt 
Kursteilnehmern, den Bereich sichtlich zu schätzen, dann überprüft 
gegen den tatsächlichen Berechnungs- Bereich. Der Text auf der 
Seite gibt drei unterschiedliche Möglichkeiten, den Bereich mit einer
Formel für jedes zu errechnen. Der applet verwendet eine der 
Methoden, um den Bereich in der Istzeit zu berechnen, also ändert er,
während der Rhombus mit der Maus umgestaltet wird. Eine 
Begleiterseite ist darstellendes 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombus.html, daß die Definition und die 
Eigenschaften eines Rhombus applet zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch
mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden können. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif montrant 
les voies de calculer la zone d'un losange. L'utilisateur 
peut traîner les sommets du losange et de l'autre changement de 
points automatiquement pour lui assurer un losange des restes. 
Une grille à l'intérieur de la forme permet à des étudiants 
d'estimer la zone visuellement, puis contrôle contre la zone 
calculée réelle. Le texte à la page donne trois voies 
différentes de calculer la zone avec une formule pour chacun. 
L'applet emploie une des méthodes pour calculer la zone en 
temps réel, ainsi il change pendant que le losange est 
restructuré avec la souris. Une page de compagnon est 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombus.html montrant que la définition et
les propriétés d'un applet de losange peuvent être agrandies à
la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que mostram as 
maneiras calcular a área de um rhombus. O usuário pode 
arrastar os vertices do rhombus e da outra mudança dos pontos 
automaticamente para assegurar-lhe um rhombus do remains. Uma 
grade dentro da forma permite que os estudantes estimem a área 
visualmente, a seguir verifica-os de encontro à área computada real.
O texto na página dá três maneiras diferentes calcular a 
área com uma fórmula para cada um. O applet usa um dos 
métodos computar a área no tempo real, assim que muda enquanto o 
rhombus reshaped com o rato. Uma página do companheiro é 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombus.html que mostra que a definição e
as propriedades de um applet do rhombus podem ser ampliadas ao tamanho
de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O 
depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez 
de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de 
uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che mostrano i
modi calcolare la zona di un rhombus. L'utente può trascinare 
automaticamente i vertici del rhombus e dell'altro cambiamento dei 
punti per accertargli un rhombus del remains. Una griglia 
all'interno della figura permette che gli allievi valutino visivamente
la zona, quindi che controlla contro la zona computata reale. Il
testo alla pagina dà tre modi differenti calcolare la zona con una 
formula per ciascuno. Il applet usa uno dei metodi per computare
la zona in tempo reale, in modo da cambia mentre il rhombus è 
rimodellato con il mouse. Una pagina del compagno è 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombus.html che mostra che la definizione 
e le proprietà di un applet del rhombus possono essere ingrandite al 
formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που εμφανίζουν
τους τρόπους να υπολογιστεί η περιοχή ενός ρόμβου. Ο 
χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει vertices του ρόμβου και τα άλλα 
σημεία αλλάζουν αυτόματα για να εξασφαλίσουν ότι παραμένει ένας
ρόμβος. Ένα πλέγμα μέσα στη μορφή επιτρέπει στους 
σπουδαστές για να υπολογίσει την περιοχή οπτικά, κατόπιν έλεγχος
ενάντια στην πραγματική υπολογισμένη περιοχή. Το κείμενο 
στη σελίδα δίνει τρεις διαφορετικούς τρόπους να υπολογιστεί η 
περιοχή με έναν τύπο για κάθε έναν. Το applet 
χρησιμοποιεί μιας από τις μεθόδους για να υπολογίσει την περιοχή 
στον πραγματικό χρόνο, έτσι αλλάζει όπως ο ρόμβος 
αναδιαμορφώνεται με το ποντίκι. Μια σελίδα συντρόφων είναι 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombus.html εμφανίζοντας τον 
καθορισμό και οι ιδιότητες ενός ρόμβου Applet μπορούν να 
διευρυνθούν στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que muestran 
las maneras de calcular el área de un rombo. El utilizador 
puede arrastrar las cimas del rombo y del otro cambio de las puntas 
automáticamente para asegurarle un rombo del restos. Una 
rejilla dentro de la dimensión de una variable permite que los 
estudiantes estimen el área visualmente, después controla contra el 
área computada real. El texto en la paginación da tres 
diversas maneras de calcular el área con un fórmula para cada uno. 
El applet utiliza uno de los métodos para computar el área en 
tiempo real, así que cambia mientras que el rombo se restructura con 
el ratón. Una paginación del compañero es 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombus.html que muestra que la definición
y las características de un applet del rombo se pueden agrandar a la 
talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala 
de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede
tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209920</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103526</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rhombus-area-formula</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
