<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106517</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106517</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206779</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Revolutionary War: Morristown National Historic Park</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanischer Revolutionärer Krieg: 
Morristown Nationaler Historischer Park</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Guerre Révolutionnaire Américaine : Parc 
Historique National de Morristown</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Guerra Revolucionária Americana: Parque 
Historic Nacional De Morristown</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Guerra Rivoluzionaria Americana: Parco 
Storico Nazionale Di Morristown</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικός επαναστατικός πόλεμος: Εθνικό 
ιστορικό πάρκο Morristown</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guerra Revolucionaria Americana: Parque 
Histórico Nacional De Morristown</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes the mansion and environs where General Washington and his aides were headquartered for 200 days. It was here in the Ford Mansion that he met with officers, scouts, spies, statesmen, and foreign diplomats. His troops -- the Continental Army of over 10,000 soldiers -- were encamped on the windswept hills and farmland nearby, where they built a log-house city of more than 1,000 structures. Washington had selected this site in Morristown, NJ, for strategic reasons.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt die Villa und die Umgebung, in der 
Vertrag Generals Washington und seiner Adjutanten für 200 Tage gehabt
wurden. Er war hier in der Ford Villa, die er Offiziere, 
Pfadfinder, Spione, Staatsmänner und fremde Diplomaten traf. 
Seine Truppen -- die kontinentale Armee von über 10.000 
Soldaten -- wurden auf den windswept Hügeln und dem Ackerland in der 
Nähe gelagert, wo sie eine Protokoll-Haus Stadt von mehr als 1.000 
Strukturen aufbauten. Washington hatte diese Site in Morristown,
NJ, für strategische Gründe ausgewählt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit le manoir et les environs où le Général
Washington et ses aides ont été siégés pendant 200 jours. Il
était ici dans le manoir de Ford qu'il a rencontré des officiers, 
des scouts, des espions, des hommes d'État, et des diplomates 
étrangers. Ses troupes -- l'armée continentale de plus de 
10.000 soldats -- ont été campées sur les collines et les champs 
balayés par le vent tout près, où elles ont construit une ville de 
logarithme-maison de plus de 1.000 structures. Washington avait 
choisi ce site dans Morristown, NJ, pour des raisons stratégiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve o mansion e os environs onde o general 
Washington e seus aides foi sediado por 200 dias. Estava aqui no
mansion de Ford que se encontrou com com oficiais, scouts, espiões, 
statesmen, e os diplomatas extrangeiros. Suas tropas -- 
exército continental sobre de 10.000 soldados -- encamped nos montes 
e na terra do windswept próximo, onde construíram uma cidade da 
registro-casa de mais de 1.000 estruturas. Washington tinha 
selecionado este local em Morristown, NJ, para razões estratégicas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive il mansion e gli environ dove il General 
Washington ed i suoi aiutanti è stato acquartierato per 200 
giorni. Era qui nel mansion del Ford che ha incontrato gli 
ufficiali, gli esploratori, le spie, gli statisti ed i diplomatici 
stranieri. Le sue truppe -- l'esercito continentale oltre di 
10.000 soldati -- encamped sulle colline e sul terreno coltivabile del
windswept qui vicino, dove hanno costruito una città della libro 
macchina-casa di più di 1.000 struttura. Washington aveva 
selezionato questo luogo in Morristown, NJ, per i motivi strategici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει το μέγαρο και περιβάλλει όπου ο στρατηγός 
Washington και οι βοηθοί του ήταν με κεντρικά γραφεία για 
200 ημέρες. Ήταν εδώ στο μέγαρο διάβασης ότι 
συναντήθηκε με τους ανώτερους υπαλλήλους, τις ανιχνεύσεις, τους 
κατασκόπους, τους πολιτικούς, και τους ξένους διπλωμάτες. Τα
στρατεύματά του -- ο ηπειρωτικός στρατός πάνω από 10.000 
στρατιωτών -- ήταν στους ανεμοδαρμένους λόφους και το 
καλλιεργήσιμο έδαφος εδώ κοντά, όπου έχτισαν μια πόλη 
κούτσουρο-σπιτιών περισσότερων από 1.000 δομών. Η 
Ουάσιγκτον είχε επιλέξει αυτήν την περιοχή σε Morristown, 
NJ, για στρατηγικούς λόγους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe la mansión y los alrededores donde 
establecieron jefatura al general Washington y sus ayudantes por 200 
días. Estaba aquí en la mansión de Ford que él resolvió con
los oficiales, los exploradores, los espías, los estadistas, y los 
diplomatas no nativos. Sus tropas -- el ejército continental 
sobre de 10.000 soldados -- encamped en las colinas y las tierras de 
labrantío del windswept cerca, donde construyeron una ciudad de la 
registro-casa de más de 1.000 estructuras. Washington había 
seleccionado este sitio en Morristown, NJ, por razones estratégicas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206779</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106517</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-revolutionary-war-morristown-national-historic-park</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
