<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107813</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107813</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203297</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">I'm Watching You 24/7</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ich Überwache Sie 24/7</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Je Vous observe 24/7</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Eu Estou prestando-lhe atenção 24/7</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sto guardandoli 24/7</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σας προσέχω 24/7</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Le estoy mirando 24/7</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The post-Renaissance world saw the nation-state mature and confront the issue of how to control the lives of its citizens. Two models of political organization, democratic and authoritarian, gradually developed. During the twentieth century, as some nations granted individuals and groups more and more rights, ideology and modern technology enabled authoritarian governments to gain ever more control, until community interest dominated the individual and totalitarianism was born. Although Nazi Germany and the Soviet Union have passed into history and there are cracks in the total control of the People's Republic of China, North Korea still retains all of the characteristics of totalitarianism. Still technically at war with the United Nations Forces, it poses a threat to the world at large with its developing nuclear program. At the same time it continues to threaten its perceived enemies. Very few foreigners have been able to visit and record life in the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (the official name of North Korea), and the nation remains largely unknown to outsiders. This lesson will begin with an introductory activity that draws on students' prior knowledge to discuss, 'How does a society create social and political order?' After brainstorming the characteristics of totalitarianism, the class will be divided into groups to locate historical examples and create a Document Based Question to share with their classmates. Students will next examine excerpts from the WIDE ANGLE film 'A State of Mind' (2003) to see how the characteristics of totalitarian societies still operate today in North Korea. As a culminating activity, students will analyze editorials on North Korea's nuclear program from newspapers around the world, formulate their own opinions, and write a Letter to the Editor of their local newspaper.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Pfosten-Renaissance Welt sah den fälligen 
Nation-Zustand und konfrontiert die Ausgabe von, wie man die Leben 
seiner Bürger steuert. Zwei Modelle politische Organisation, 
demokratisch und autoritär, stufenweise entwickelt. Während 
des zwanzigsten Jahrhunderts als einige Nationen, die Einzelpersonen 
und die Gruppen immer mehr Rechte bewilligt wurden, aktivierten 
Ideologie und moderne Technologie autoritäre Regierungen, mehr 
Steuerung überhaupt zu gewinnen, bis Gemeinschaftsinteresse die 
Einzelperson beherrschte und Totalitarismus getragen wurde. 
Obgleich Nazi Deutschland und der Sowjet-Anschluß in Geschichte
überschritten haben und es Sprünge in der Gesamtsteuerung der 
Volksrepublik China gibt, behält Nordkorea noch alle Eigenschaften 
des Totalitarismus bei. Noch technisch am Krieg mit den Nationen
Kräften, wirft es eine Drohung zur Welt an großem mit seinem sich 
entwickelnden Kernprogramm auf. Gleichzeitig fährt es fort, 
seine wahrgenommenen Feinde zu bedrohen. Sehr haben wenige 
Ausländer gekonnt, das Leben in der demokratischen Volksrepublik von 
Korea (der amtliche Name von Nordkorea) zu besuchen und zu speichern, 
und die Nation bleibt Außenseitern groß unbekannt. Diese 
Lektion fängt mit einer einleitenden Aktivität, die auf vorheriges 
Wissen der Kursteilnehmer zeichnet, um zu behandeln, ' an, wie tut 
eine Gesellschaft erstellen Sozial- und politische Ordnung?' 
Nach Geistesstörung werden die Eigenschaften des 
Totalitarismus, die Kategorie in Gruppen geteilt, um historische 
Beispiele zu lokalisieren und eine Dokument gegründete Frage zu 
erstellen, um mit ihren Mitschülern zu teilen. Kursteilnehmer 
überprüfen zunächst Excerpts vom Weitwinkelfilm ' ein 
Geisteszustand ' (2003) um zu sehen wie die Eigenschaften der 
totalitären Gesellschaften noch heute in Nordkorea funktionieren. 
Als kulminierende Aktivität analysieren Kursteilnehmer 
Leitartikel auf Nordkoreas Kernprogramm von den Zeitungen um die Welt,
formulieren ihre eigenen Meinungen und schreiben einen Leserbrief 
ihrer lokalen Zeitung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le monde de la poteau-Renaissance a vu le 
nation-état mûr et confronte l'issue de la façon contrôler les 
vies de ses citoyens. Deux modèles d'organisation politique, 
démocratique et autoritaire, graduellement développée. 
Pendant le vingtième siècle, en tant que quelques nations 
accordées des individus et groupes de plus en plus droites, 
l'idéologie et la technologie moderne ont permis à des gouvernements
autoritaires de gagner jamais plus de commande, jusqu'à ce que 
l'intérêt de communauté ait dominé l'individu et le totalitarisme a 
été soutenu. Bien que l'Allemagne Nazie et Union Soviétique 
aient passé dans l'histoire et il y a des fissures dans toute la 
commande de la République populaire de Chine, la Corée du nord 
maintient toujours toutes les caractéristiques de totalitarisme. 
Toujours techniquement à la guerre avec les forces des Nations 
Unies, elle constitue une menace au monde dans son ensemble avec son 
programme nucléaire se développant. En même temps elle 
continue à menacer ses ennemis perçus. Très peu d'étrangers 
ont pu visiter et enregistrer la vie en République populaire 
démocratique de la Corée (le nom officiel de la Corée 
du nord), et la nation demeure en grande partie inconnue aux 
étrangers. Cette leçon commencera par une activité 
préliminaire qui dessine sur la connaissance antérieure des 
étudiants pour discuter, 'comment fait une société créent la 
commande sociale et politique?' Après séance de réflexion les
caractéristiques du totalitarisme, la classe seront divisées en 
groupes pour localiser des exemples historiques et pour créer une 
question basée par document pour partager avec leurs camarades de 
classe. Les étudiants examineront ensuite des extraits du film 
GRAND-ANGULAIRE 'un état d'esprit '(2003) pour voir comment les 
caractéristiques des sociétés totalitaires fonctionnent toujours 
aujourd'hui en Corée du nord. Comme activité culminante, 
les étudiants analyseront des éditoriaux sur le programme nucléaire
du nord de la Corée des journaux autour du monde, formuleront 
leurs propres avis, et écriront une lettre à l'éditeur de leur 
journal local.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O mundo do borne-Renascimento viu o nação-estado
maduro e confronta a introdução de como controlar as vidas de seus 
cidadãos. Dois modelos da organização política, democrático
e authoritarian, desenvolvida gradualmente. Durante o vigésimo 
século, como algumas nações concedidas indivíduos e grupos mais e 
mais direitas, o ideology e a tecnologia moderna permitiram governos 
authoritarian de ganhar sempre mais controle, até que o interesse de 
comunidade dominou o indivíduo e o totalitarianism fosse carregado. 
Embora Germany nazi e a Soviete-união passem no history e haja 
rachaduras no controle total da República Popular da China, Coreia 
norte retem ainda todas as características do totalitarianism. 
Ainda tècnica na guerra com as forças unidas das nações, 
poses uma ameaça ao mundo em grande com seu programa nuclear 
tornando-se. Ao mesmo tempo continua a ameaçar seus inimigos 
percebidos. Muito poucos estrangeiros puderam  visitar e gravar 
a vida na república de pessoa democrática de Coreia (o nome oficial 
de Coreia norte), e a nação remanesce pela maior parte desconhecida 
aos outsiders. Esta lição começará com uma atividade 
introdutória que desenhe no conhecimento prévio dos estudantes para 
discutir, ' como faz uma sociedade críam a ordem social e política?'
Após o brainstorming as características do totalitarianism, a 
classe serão divididas em grupos para encontrar exemplos históricos 
e para criar uma pergunta baseada original para compartilhar com seus 
classmates. Os estudantes examinarão em seguida excerpts do 
ÂNGULO LARGO filmam ' um estado de mente ' (2003) para ver como as 
características de sociedades totalitarian se operam ainda hoje em 
Coreia norte. Como uma atividade culminando, os estudantes 
analisarão editorials no programa nuclear norte de Coreia dos jornais
em torno do mundo, formularão suas próprias opiniões, e escreverão
uma letra ao editor de seu jornal local.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il mondo di alberino-Rinascita ha visto il 
nation-dichiarare maturo e confronta l'emissione di come gestire le vite
dei relativi cittadini. Due modelli dell'organizzazione 
politica, democratico ed autoritario, sviluppata gradualmente. 
Durante il ventesimo secolo, come alcune nazioni assegnate gli 
individui e gruppi più e più diritti, l'ideologia e la tecnologia 
moderna hanno permesso ai governi autoritari di guadagnare mai più 
controllo, fino a che l'interesse di Comunità non dominasse 
l'individuo ed il totalitarianism fosse sopportato. Anche se la 
Germania Nazista e l'Soviet-unione hanno passato in storia e ci 
sono crepe nel controllo totale della Repubblica popolare cinese, il 
Korea di Nord ancora mantiene tutte le caratteristiche del 
totalitarianism. Ancora tecnicamente alla guerra con le forze 
delle Nazioni Unite, propone una minaccia al mondo nel suo insieme con
il relativo programma nucleare di sviluppo. Allo stesso tempo 
continua a minacciare i relativi nemici percepiti. Molto pochi 
stranieri hanno potuti visitare e registrare la vita in Repubblica 
popolare democratica della Corea (il nome ufficiale del Korea di Nord) e 
la nazione rimane in gran parte sconosciuta agli stranieri. 
Questa lezione comincerà con un'attività introduttiva che 
dissipa su conoscenza anteriore degli allievi per discutere, 'come fa 
una società creano l'ordine sociale e politico?' Dopo 
"brainstorming" le caratteristiche del totalitarianism, il codice 
categoria saranno divise nei gruppi per individuare gli esempi storici
e per creare una domanda basata documento per ripartirsi con i loro 
classmates. Gli allievi dopo esamineranno i brani dalla 
pellicola GRANDANGOLARE 'un Dichiarare della mente '(2003) per vedere 
come le caratteristiche delle società totalitarian ancora funzionano 
oggi nel Korea di Nord. Come attività di culminazione, gli 
allievi analizzeranno gli editoriali sul programma nucleare del 
Korea di Nord dai giornali intorno al mondo, formuleranno i loro propri 
pareri e scriveranno una lettera all'editore del loro giornale locale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο κόσμος μετα-αναγέννησης εβλέίδε το έθνος 
κράτος ώριμο και αντιμετωπίζει το ζήτημα για το πώς να ελέγξει 
τις ζωές των πολιτών του. Δύο μοντέλα της πολιτικής 
οργάνωσης, δημοκρατικός και αυταρχικός, αναπτύχθηκαν βαθμιαία. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια του εικοστού αιώνα, ως μερικά έθνη 
χορήγησε στα άτομα και στις ομάδες όλο και περισσότερες 
δικαιώματα, ιδεολογία και σύγχρονες τεχνολογία αυταρχικές 
κυβερνήσεις για να κερδίσει πάντα περισσότερο έλεγχο, έως ότου 
εξουσίασε το συμφέρον της Κοινότητας το άτομο και ο 
ολοκληρωτισμός γεννήθηκε. Αν και η ναζιστική Γερμανία και η 
Σοβιετική Ένωση έχουν περάσει στην ιστορία και υπάρχουν ρωγμές 
στο συνολικό έλεγχο της Λαϊκής Δημοκρατίας της Κίνας, η βόρεια 
Κορέα διατηρεί ακόμα όλα τα χαρακτηριστικά του ολοκληρωτισμού. 
Ακόμα τεχνικά στον πόλεμο με τις δυνάμεις Ηνωμένων Εθνών, 
αποτελεί απειλή για τον κόσμο σε μεγάλο με το αναπτυσσόμενο 
πυρηνικό πρόγραμμά της. Συγχρόνως συνεχίζει να απειλεί 
τους αντιληπτούς εχθρούς του. Πολύ λίγοι αλλοδαποί ήταν σε
θέση να επισκεφτούν και να καταγράψουν τη ζωή στη δημοκρατική 
Λαϊκή Δημοκρατία της Κορέας (το επίσημο όνομα της βόρειας 
Κορέας), και το έθνος παραμένει κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος άγνωστο 
στους ξένους. Αυτό το μάθημα θα αρχίσει με μια εισαγωγική 
δραστηριότητα που επισύρει την προσοχή προγενέστερη γνώση των 
σπουδαστών "που συζητά," πώς μια κοινωνία δημιουργεί την 
κοινωνική και πολιτική τάξη;" Μετά από το 
"brainstorming" τα χαρακτηριστικά του ολοκληρωτισμού, η κλάση θα
διαιρεθούν σε ομάδες για να εντοπίσουν τα ιστορικά παραδείγματα 
και να δημιουργήσουν μια βασισμένη στο έγγραφο ερώτηση που 
μοιράζεται με τους συμμαθητές τους. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
εξετάσουν έπειτα τα αποσπάσματα από την ταινία WIDE.ANGLE 
"ένα κράτος του μυαλού" (2003) για να δουν πώς τα 
χαρακτηριστικά των ολοκληρωτικών κοινωνιών λειτουργούν ακόμα 
σήμερα στη βόρεια Κορέα. Σαν καταλήγοντας δραστηριότητα, οι
σπουδαστές θα αναλύσουν τα κύρια άρθρα στο πυρηνικό πρόγραμμα 
της βόρειας Κορέας από τις εφημερίδες σε όλο τον κόσμο, θα 
διατυπώσουν τις απόψεις τους, και θα γράψουν μια επιστολή στον 
επεξεργαστή της τοπικής εφημερίδας τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El mundo del poste-Renacimiento vio el 
nacio'n-estado maduro y enfrenta la aplicación cómo controlar las 
vidas de sus ciudadanos. Dos modelos de organización política,
democrático y autoritario, desarrollada gradualmente. Durante 
el vigésimo siglo, como algunas naciones concedidas individuos y los 
grupos más y las más derechas, la ideología y la tecnología 
moderna permitieron a gobiernos autoritarios ganar siempre más 
control, hasta que el interés de comunidad dominó a individuo y el 
totalitarianism fue llevado. Aunque Alemania nazi y la 
Soviet-unio'n han pasado en historia y hay grietas en el control total
de la República Popular de China, Corea del norte todavía conserva 
todas las características del totalitarianism. Aún técnico en
la guerra con las fuerzas de Naciones Unidas, plantea una amenaza al 
mundo en grande con su programa nuclear que se convierte. En el 
mismo tiempo continúa amenazando a sus enemigos percibidos. Muy
pocos extranjeros han podido visitar y registrar vida en la república
popular democrática de Corea (el nombre oficial de Corea del norte), 
y la nación sigue siendo en gran parte desconocida a los forasteros. 
Esta lección comenzará con una actividad introductoria que 
trace en el conocimiento anterior de los estudiantes para discutir, ' 
cómo hace a sociedad crean orden social y política?' Después 
de la reunión de reflexión las características del totalitarianism,
la clase serán divididas en grupos para localizar ejemplos 
históricos y para crear una pregunta basada documento para compartir 
con sus classmates. Los estudiantes examinarán después 
extractos de la película GRANANGULAR ' un estado de la mente ' (2003)
para ver cómo las características de sociedades totalitarias 
todavía funcionan hoy en Corea del norte. Como actividad que 
culmina, los estudiantes analizarán los editoriales en el programa 
nuclear del norte de Corea de los periódicos alrededor del mundo, 
formularán sus propias opiniones, y escribirán una letra al editor 
de su periódico local.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MIRLA MORRISON
FN:MIRLA MORRISON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203297</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107813</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/im-watching-you-24-7</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
