<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973903</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Secondary School Science Electronic Library for Africa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sekundärschule-Wissenschaft elektronische 
Bibliothek für Afrika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bibliothèque électronique de la Science d'école
secondaire pour l'Afrique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biblioteca eletrônica da ciência da escola 
secundária para África</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Libreria elettronica di scienza della scuola 
secondaria per l'Africa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηλεκτρονική βιβλιοθήκη επιστήμης δευτεροβάθμιας 
εκπαίδευσης για την Αφρική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biblioteca electrónica de la ciencia de la 
escuela secundaria para África</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This science electronic library features lesson plans by topic, methodology and grade, as well as articles and sample test questions and FAQ for science teachers of secondary school students. The lessons have been gathered from various sources and sites. They are appropriate for teaching in Africa. The lessons can be used by teacher trainers as models of exciting and creative teaching. The lessons may also be revised and modified. The methodologies may be useful for teacher trainers and applicable to a variety of subjects.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">Africa</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Wissenschaft elektronische Bibliothek 
kennzeichnet Lektionpläne durch Thema, Methodenlehre und Grad, sowie 
Artikel und Beispieltestfragen und FAQ für Wissenschaft Lehrer der 
Sekundärschulekursteilnehmer. Die Lektionen sind von den 
verschiedenen Quellen und von den Sites erfaßt worden. Sie sind
für das Unterrichten in Afrika angebracht. Die Lektionen 
können von den Lehrerkursleitern als Modelle des aufregenden und 
kreativen Unterrichts verwendet werden. Die Lektionen können 
auch verbessert werden und geändert werden. Die Methodenlehren 
können auf eine Vielzahl der Themen nützlich für Lehrerkursleiter 
und anwendbar sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette bibliothèque électronique de la science 
comporte des plans de leçon par sujet, méthodologie et catégorie, 
comme des articles et des questions d'essai témoin et le FAQ pour des
professeurs de la science des étudiants d'école secondaire. 
Les leçons ont été recueillies de diverses sources et de 
sites. Elles sont appropriées pour enseigner en Afrique. 
Les leçons peuvent être employées par des entraîneurs de 
professeur comme modèles de l'enseignement passionnant et créateur. 
Les leçons peuvent également être mises à jour et 
modifiées. Les méthodologies peuvent être utiles pour des 
entraîneurs de professeur et applicables à une variété de sujets.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta biblioteca eletrônica da ciência 
caracteriza plantas da lição pelo tópico, a metodologia e a classe,
assim como artigos e perguntas do teste da amostra e FAQ para 
professores da ciência de estudantes da escola secundária. As 
lições foram recolhidas das várias fontes e dos locais. São 
apropriada para ensinar em África. As lições podem ser usadas
por instrutores do professor como modelos de ensino emocionante e 
creativo. As lições podem também ser revisadas e modificado. 
As metodologias podem ser úteis para instrutores do professor e
aplicáveis a uma variedade dos assuntos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa libreria elettronica di scienza 
caratterizza i programmi di lezione dal soggetto, la metodologia e 
grado, come pure gli articoli e le domande della prova del campione ed
il FAQ per gli insegnanti di scienza degli allievi della scuola 
secondaria. Le lezioni sono state riunite dalle varie 
sorgenti e dai luoghi. Sono adatte per l'istruzione in Africa. 
Le lezioni possono essere usate dagli addestratori 
dell'insegnante come modelli di insegnamento emozionante e creativo. 
Le lezioni possono anche essere modificate e modificate. 
Le metodologie possono essere utili per gli addestratori 
dell'insegnante ed applicabili ad una varietà di oggetti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ηλεκτρονική βιβλιοθήκη επιστήμης χαρακτηρίζει 
τα σχέδια μαθήματος από το θέμα, τη μεθοδολογία και το βαθμό, 
καθώς επίσης και τα άρθρα και τις ερωτήσεις εξέτασης δειγμάτων 
και FAQ για τους καθηγητές θετικών επιστημών των σπουδαστών 
δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης. Τα μαθήματα έχουν μαζευτεί από
τις διάφορες πηγές και τις περιοχές. Είναι κατάλληλοι για 
τη διδασκαλία στην Αφρική. Τα μαθήματα μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν από τους εκπαιδευτές δασκάλων ως μοντέλα της 
διέγερσης και της δημιουργικής διδασκαλίας. Τα μαθήματα 
μπορούν επίσης να αναθεωρηθούν και να τροποποιηθούν. Οι 
μεθοδολογίες μπορούν να ισχύσουν χρήσιμες για τους εκπαιδευτές 
δασκάλων και σε ποικίλα θέματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta biblioteca electrónica de la ciencia ofrece 
planes de la lección por asunto, metodología y grado, tan bien como 
los artículos y las preguntas de la prueba de la muestra y el FAQ 
para los profesores de la ciencia de los estudiantes de la escuela 
secundaria. Las lecciones se han recolectado de varias fuentes y
de sitios. Son apropiadas para enseñar en África. Las 
lecciones se pueden utilizar por los amaestradores del profesor como 
modelos de la enseñanza emocionante y creativa. Las lecciones 
pueden también ser revisadas y ser modificadas. Las 
metodologías pueden ser útiles para los amaestradores del profesor y
aplicables a una variedad de temas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973903</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105861</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/secondary-school-science-electronic-library-for-africa</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
