<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107203</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107203</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087210</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Was Jus' Turned Out Like a Lot of Cattle": Fountain Hughes Recalls His Life in Slavery and Freedom, Baltimore, 1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir waren Jus', das wie eine Menge Vieh" 
ausgefallen wurde: Brunnen-Hughes Rückrufe seine Lebensdauer in
Slavery und in Freedom, Baltimore, 1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous étions Jus avéré comme beaucoup de 
bétail" : Rappels de Hughes de fontaine sa vie en Slavery et 
Freedom, Baltimore, 1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós éramos Jus' girado para fora como muitos do
gado": Recordações de Hughes da fonte sua vida em Slavery e em
Liberdade, Baltimore, 1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Eravamo Jus Risultato Come I Bestiami 
Molto": Richiami del Hughes della fontana la sua vita in 
Slavery ed in Freedom, Baltimora, 1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ήμαστε Jus που βγάλθηκε όπως πολλά βοοειδή": 
Πηγή Hughes Recalls His Life στη σκλαβιά και την 
ελευθερία, Βαλτιμόρη, 1944</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"éramos Jus resultado como muchos de ganados": 
Memorias de Hughes de la fuente su vida en Slavery y Freedom, 
Baltimore, 1944</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Fountain Hughes was born a slave in 1848 in Charlottesville, Virginia. In 1944 (or 1949) he was interviewed in Baltimore by Hermond Norwood, a representative of the Library of Congress's Archive of Folk Song. The Federal Writer's Project, a Depression-era program, had initiated the government's effort to capture the memories of the, by then, very elderly former slaves. Hughes recalled not only life under slavery but also the difficulties many slaves faced in making the transition to freedom in an antagonistic white society that worked hard to impede their efforts. Conditions for the Hughes family under freedom were materially not much better than they had been under slavery. In this interview Hughes recalled how his widowed mother supported her family by binding, or contracting, her children out to work. Still, Hughes asserted, he far preferred freedom to slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Brunnen Hughes wurde ein Sklave 1848 in 
Charlottesville, Virginia getragen. 1944 (oder 1949) wurde er in
Baltimore von Hermond Norwood, ein Repräsentant der Bibliothek des 
Archivs des Kongresses von Volkslied interviewt. Das 
BundesProjekt des verfassers, ein Tiefstand-Ära Programm, hatte die 
Bemühung der Regierung initialisiert, die Speicher von bis dahin zu 
erfassen sehr ältere ehemalige Sklaven. Hughes erinnerte an das
nicht nur Leben unter Sklaverei, aber auch die Schwierigkeiten, die 
viele Sklaven gegenüberstellten, wenn sie den Übergang zur Freiheit 
in einer entgegenwirkenden weißen Gesellschaft bildeten, die stark 
arbeitete, um ihre Bemühungen zu behindern. Bedingungen für 
die Hughes Familie unter Freiheit waren materiell nicht viel besser, 
als sie unter Sklaverei gewesen waren. In diesem Interview rief 
Hughes wieder auf, wie seiner Mutter unterstützte ihre Familie 
widowed, indem er heraus band, oder, ihre Kinder, um zu arbeiten 
Vertrag abschloß. Noch erklärter Hughes, bevorzugte er weit 
Freiheit gegenüber Sklaverei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La fontaine Hughes a été soutenue un slave
en 1848 dans Charlottesville, la Virginie. En 1944 (ou 1949) il 
a été interviewé à Baltimore par Hermond Norwood, un représentant
de la bibliothèque des archives du congrès de la chanson 
folklorique. Le projet de l'auteur fédéral, un programme de 
Dépression-ère, avait lancé l'effort du gouvernement de capturer 
les mémoires du, d'ici là, d'anciens esclaves très vieux. 
Hughes a rappelé non seulement la vie sous l'esclavage mais 
également les difficultés que beaucoup d'esclaves ont faites face en
faisant la transition à la liberté dans une société blanche 
antagonique qui a travaillé dur pour empêcher leurs efforts. 
Les conditions pour la famille de Hughes sous la liberté 
n'étaient matériellement pas bien mieux qu'elles avaient été sous 
l'esclavage. Dans cette entrevue Hughes s'est rappelé comment 
sa mère veuve a supporté sa famille en liant, ou 
sous-traitant, ses enfants pour travailler. Toujours, Hughes 
affirmé, il a loin préféré la liberté à l'esclavage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A fonte Hughes foi carregada um escravo em 1848 em
Charlottesville, Virgínia. Em 1944 (ou em 1949) foi 
entrevistado em Baltimore por Hermond Norwood, um representante da 
biblioteca do arquivo do congress da canção popular. O projeto
do escritor federal, um programa da Depression-era, tinha iniciado o 
esforço do governo capturar as memórias do, perto então, escravos 
anteriores muito idosos. Hughes recordou não somente a vida sob
o slavery mas também as dificuldades que muitos escravos enfrentaram 
em fazer a transição à liberdade em uma sociedade branca 
antagonistic que trabalhasse duramente para impedir seus esforços. 
As condições para a família de Hughes sob a liberdade não 
eram materialmente muito mais melhor do que tinham estado sob o 
slavery. Nesta entrevista Hughes recordou como his widowed a 
matriz suportou sua família ligando, ou se contraindo, suas crianças
para fora para trabalhar. Ainda, Hughes afirmado, preferiu 
distante a liberdade ao slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La fontana Hughes è stata sopportata uno schiavo 
in 1848 in Charlottesville, la Virginia. In 1944 (o in 1949) è 
stato intervistato a Baltimora da Hermond Norwood, un rappresentante 
della libreria dell'archivio del congresso della canzone piega. 
Il progetto del produttore federale, un programma di 
Depressione-era, aveva iniziato lo sforzo del governo bloccare le 
memorie del, per allora, schiavi precedenti molto anziani. 
Hughes ha ricordato non soltanto la vita sotto slavery ma anche 
le difficoltà che molti schiavi hanno affrontato nel fare la 
transizione alla libertà in una società bianca antagonistica che ha 
lavorato duro per impedire i loro sforzi. I termini per la 
famiglia del Hughes sotto la libertà non erano materialmente molto 
più meglio di erano stati sotto slavery. In questa intervista 
Hughes ha ricordato come suo widowed la madre ha sostenuto la sua 
famiglia legandosi, o subappaltando, i suoi bambini per funzionare. 
Eppure, Hughes asserito, lontano ha preferito la libertà a 
slavery.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πηγή Hughes γεννήθηκε ένας σκλάβος το 1848 σε 
Charlottesville, Βιρτζίνια. Το 1944 (ή το 1949) 
πέρασε από συνέντευξη στη Βαλτιμόρη από Hermond Norwood, 
ένας αντιπρόσωπος του αρχείου βιβλιοθήκης του συνεδρίου του 
λαϊκού τραγουδιού. Το έργο του ομοσπονδιακού συγγραφέα, 
ένα πρόγραμμα κατάθλιψη-εποχής, είχε αρχίσει την κυβερνητική 
προσπάθεια να συλληφθούν οι μνήμες, έως τότε, πολύ ηλικιωμένοι 
προηγούμενοι σκλάβοι. Ο Hughes υπενθύμισε όχι μόνο τη 
ζωή κάτω από τη σκλαβιά αλλά και τις δυσκολίες πολλοί σκλάβοι 
που αντιμετωπίστηκαν στην παραγωγή της μετάβασης στην ελευθερία σε
μια ανταγωνιστική λευκιά κοινωνία που δούλεψε σκληρά για να 
εμποδίσει τις προσπάθειές τους. Οι όροι για την οικογένεια 
του Hughes κάτω από την ελευθερία δεν ήταν υλικά πολύ 
καλύτεροι από ήταν κάτω από τη σκλαβιά. Σε αυτήν την 
συνέντευξη ο Hughes υπενθύμισε πώς η χηρευάμενη μητέρα του 
υποστήριξε την οικογένειά της με τη δέσμευση, ή την εργολαβία, 
τα παιδιά της να εργαστεί έξω. Ακόμα, ο Hughes βεβαίωσε,
προτίμησε μακριά την ελευθερία από τη σκλαβιά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La fuente Hughes fue llevada un esclavo en 1848 en
Charlottesville, Virginia. En 1944 (o 1949) él fue entrevistado
con en Baltimore por Hermond Norwood, representante de la biblioteca 
del archivo del congreso de la canción popular. El proyecto del
programa de escritura federal, un programa de la Depresio'n-era, 
había iniciado el esfuerzo del gobierno de capturar las memorias del,
para entonces, los esclavos anteriores muy mayores. Hughes 
recordó no solamente vida bajo esclavitud pero también las 
dificultades que muchos esclavos hicieron frente en la fabricación de
la transición a la libertad en una sociedad blanca antagónica que 
trabajó difícilmente para impedir sus esfuerzos. Las 
condiciones para la familia de Hughes bajo libertad no estaban 
materialmente mucho mejor que habían estado bajo esclavitud. En
esta entrevista Hughes recordó cómo el suyo widowed a madre utilizó
a su familia atando, o contrayendo, sus niños hacia fuera para 
trabajar. No obstante, Hughes afirmado, él prefirió lejos la 
libertad a la esclavitud.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087210</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107203</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-was-jus-turned-out-like-a-lot-of-cattle-fountain-hughes-recalls-his-life-in-slavery-and-freedom-baltimore-1944</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
