<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106190</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106190</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206334</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Floyd Bennett Field: Naval Aviation's Home in Brooklyn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Floyd Bennett Fangen auf: 
Marineluftfahrt Haupt in Brooklyn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zone de Floyd Bennett : Aviation 
navale à la maison à Brooklyn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Campo De Floyd Bennett: Aviação naval home
em Brooklyn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Campo Di Floyd Bennett: Aeronautica navale 
domestica a Brooklyn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πεδίο Bennett Floyd: "Οικία" της ναυτικής 
αεροπορίας στο Μπρούκλιν</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Campo De Floyd Bennett: Aviación naval 
casera en Brooklyn</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts the role of this airport in aviation history and World War II. In 1931, it was among the most advanced airports in the world. From it, early aviators launched pioneering and round-the-world flights during the 1930s. After the Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor, its duties as Naval Air Station New York grew rapidly. During the 1942 U-Boat offensive, it provided air cover for ship convoys embarking from New York.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt die Rolle dieses Flughafens in der 
Luftfahrt Geschichte und dem Zweiten Weltkrieg nach. 1931 
gehörte sie zu den hochentwickeltesten Flughäfen in der Welt. 
Von ihr stießen frühe Flieger Vorangehen und Rund-dweltflüge 
während der dreißiger Jahre aus. Nach dem japanischen Angriff 
auf Pearl Harbor, wuchsen seine Aufgaben als Marineflughafen New York 
schnell. Während der U-Boot Offensive 1942 stellte es 
Luftabdeckung für die Schiff Konvois zur Verfügung, die von New York
sich einschiffen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte le rôle de cet aéroport dans l'histoire 
et la deuxième guerre mondiale d'aviation. En 1931, elle était
parmi les aéroports les plus avançés au monde. D'elle, les 
premiers aviateurs ont lancé des vols de frayer un chemin et de 
rond-le-monde pendant les années 30. Après l'attaque japonaise
sur le port de perle, ses fonctions en tant qu'aéroport naval New 
York se sont développées rapidement. Pendant l'offensive 1942 
d'U-Bateau, il a fourni la couverture d'air pour des convois de bateau
s'embarquant de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts o papel deste aeroporto no history e na 
segunda guerra mundial da aviação. Em 1931, era entre os 
aeroportos os mais avançados no mundo. Dela, os aviadores 
adiantados lançaram vôos abrir caminho e de redondo-$$$-MUNDO 
durante os 1930s. Após o ataque japonês no porto de pérola, 
seus deveres como a estação de ar naval New York cresceram 
ràpidamente. Durante a ofensiva 1942 do U-Barco, forneceu a 
tampa do ar para os combóios do navio que embarking de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta il ruolo di questo aeroporto nella storia
e nella seconda guerra mondiale di aeronautica. In 1931, era fra
gli aeroporti più avanzati nel mondo. Da esso, i aviators in 
anticipo hanno lanciato i voli del rotondo-$$$-MONDO e di pionierismo 
durante i 1930s. Dopo l'attacco giapponese al porto di perla, le
relative funzioni come stazione di aria navale New York si sono 
sviluppate velocemente. Durante l'offensiva 1942 della U-Barca, 
ha fornito la copertura dell'aria per i convogli della nave che si 
imbarcano da New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί το ρόλο αυτού του αερολιμένα στην ιστορία 
και τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ αεροπορίας. Το 1931, ήταν 
μεταξύ των πιό προηγμένων αερολιμένων στον κόσμο. Από το, 
οι πρώτοι αεροπόροι προώθησαν τις πτήσεις εξερεύνησης και 
στρογγυλός-ο-κόσμων κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '30. 
Μετά από την ιαπωνική επίθεση στο λιμάνι μαργαριταριών, τα
καθήκοντά του ως ναυτικός σταθμός Νέα Υόρκη αέρα αυξήθηκαν 
γρήγορα. Κατά τη διάρκεια της επίθεσης u-varkw'n του 
1942, παρείχε την κάλυψη αέρα για τις συνοδείες σκαφών που 
επιβιβάζονται από τη Νέα Υόρκη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo el papel de este aeropuerto en 
historia y la Segunda Guerra Mundial de la aviación. En 1931, 
estaba entre los aeropuertos más avanzados del mundo. De ella, 
los aviadores tempranos lanzaron vuelos el iniciar y del 
redondo-$$$-MUNDO durante los años 30. Después del ataque 
japonés contra puerto de perla, sus deberes como estación de aire 
naval Nueva York crecieron rápidamente. Durante la ofensiva 
1942 del U-Barco, proporcionó a la cubierta del aire para los 
convoyes de la nave que se embarcaban de Nueva York.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206334</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106190</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/floyd-bennett-field-naval-aviations-home-in-brooklyn</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
