<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106120</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106120</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086180</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"From a Child I Was Fond of Reading": Benjamin Franklin Becomes a Printer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"von einem Kind war ich in Messwert" vernarrt: 
Benjamin Franklin wird ein Drucker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"d'un enfant j'étais fanatique de la lecture" : 
Benjamin Franklin devient une imprimante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"de uma criança eu era afeiçoado da leitura": 
Benjamin Franklin transforma-se uma impressora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"da un bambino provenivo affettuoso di lettura": 
Benjamin Franklin diventa una stampante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Από ένα παιδί αγάπησα της ανάγνωσησ": 
Θ*Ψενιαμην Franklin Becomes ένας εκτυπωτής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"de un niño era encariñado con la lectura": 
Benjamin Franklin hace impresora</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">College education was rare in colonial America, mostly intended for young men entering the ministry. Artisans learned the skills and secrets of their trade through an apprenticeship to a master as Benjamin Franklin related in this excerpt about his education as a craftsman from his famous autobiography. After their service they became journeymen, hired for a time while they saved to open a workshop of their own. Franklin's father, with seventeen children, had to plan carefully in order to secure a niche for his youngest child, Benjamin. Printers stood near the top of the mechanical arts because the trade required literacy. Printers, clustered in the port cities, often formed a network of interrelated families; Benjamin's brother James was a master before him. Benjamin quickly learned the printing trade and ventured out into independent activities. Armed with his valuable training and a penchant for independence, he never finished his term of service and instead moved on to ply his trade in Philadelphia and London.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hochschulbildung war in Kolonialamerika selten, 
meistens bestimmt für die jungen Männer, die das Ministerium 
eintragen. Handwerker erlernten die Fähigkeiten und die 
Geheimnisse ihres Handels durch eine Lehre zu einem Meister als 
Benjamin Franklin, der in diesem Excerpt über seine Ausbildung als 
Handwerker von seiner berühmten Autobiographie in Verbindung 
gestanden wurde. Nachdem ihr Service sie den Facharbeitern 
stand, angestellt während einer Zeit, während sie sicherten, um eine
Werkstatt von ihren Selbst zu öffnen. Vater Franklins, mit 
siebzehn Kindern, mußte sorgfältig planen, um eine Nische für sein 
jüngstes Kind, Benjamin zu sichern. Drucker standen nahe der 
Oberseite der mechanischen künste weil der benötigte 
Geschäftsbildungsgrad. Die Drucker, gebündelt in den 
Portstädte, bildeten häufig ein Netz der zusammenhängend Familien; 
Bruder James Benjamins war ein Meister vor ihm. Benjamin 
erlernte schnell den druckenhandel und riskierte heraus in 
unabhängige Aktivitäten. Bewaffnet mit seinem wertvollen 
Training und einem Hang für Unabhängigkeit, beendete er nie seine 
Bezeichnung des Services und zog anstatt an um, um seinen Handel in 
Philadelphia und in London auszuüben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'éducation d'université était rare en 
Amérique coloniale, la plupart du temps destinée à de jeunes hommes
écrivant le ministère. Les artisans ont appris les 
qualifications et les secrets de leur commerce par un apprentissage à
un maître comme Benjamin Franklin associé dans cet extrait au sujet 
de son éducation en tant qu'artisan de sa autobiographie célèbre. 
Après que leur service ils soit allé bien à des compagnons, 
loués pendant un certain temps tandis qu'ils économisaient pour 
ouvrir un atelier de leurs propres. Le père de Franklin's, avec
dix-sept enfants, a dû projeter soigneusement afin de fixer une place
pour son enfant plus en bas âge, Benjamin. Les imprimantes se 
sont tenues près du dessus des arts mécaniques parce que 
l'instruction exigée commerciale. Les imprimantes, groupées 
dans les villes gauches, ont souvent formé un réseau des familles en
corrélation ; Le frère James de Benjamin était un 
maître avant lui. Benjamin a rapidement appris le commerce 
d'impression et a osé dehors dans des activités indépendantes. 
Armé avec sa formation valable et un penchant pour 
l'indépendance, il n'a jamais terminé sa limite de service et à la 
place s'est déplacé en fonction pour manier ses échanges à 
Philadelphie et à Londres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A instrução de faculdade era rara em América 
colonial, pretendida na maior parte para os homens novos que 
incorporam o ministry. Os artisans aprenderam as habilidades e 
os segredos de seu comércio com um apprenticeship a um mestre como 
Benjamin Franklin relacionado neste excerpt sobre sua instrução como
um artesão de seu autobiography famoso. Depois que seu serviço
eles assentou bem nos journeymen, empregados por um momento quando 
conservaram para abrir uma oficina do seus próprios. O pai de 
Franklin, com dezessete crianças, teve que planear com cuidado a fim 
fixar um niche para sua criança mais nova, Benjamin. As 
impressoras estiveram perto do alto das artes mecânicas porque o 
literacy requerido de comércio. As impressoras, aglomeradas nas
cidades portuárias, deram forma frequentemente a uma rede de 
famílias relacionadas; O irmão James de Benjamin era um mestre
antes dele. Benjamin aprendeu rapidamente o comércio imprimindo
e arriscou-se para fora em atividades independentes. Armado com 
seu treinamento valioso e um penchant para a independência, nunca 
terminou seu termo de serviço e moveu-se preferivelmente sobre para 
dobrar seu comércio em Filadélfia e em Londres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La formazione di università era rara in America 
coloniale, principalmente destinata ai giovani che entrano nel 
ministero. Gli artigianale hanno imparato le abilità ed i 
segreti del loro commercio con un apprendistato ad un supervisore come
Benjamin Franklin riguardante in questo brano circa la sua 
formazione come artigiano dal suo autobiography famoso. Dopo che
il loro servizio stia bene agli operai qualificati, assunti per un 
certo tempo mentre hanno risparmiato per aprire un workshop dei loro 
propri. Il padre del Franklin, con diciassette bambini, ha 
dovuto progettare con attenzione per fissare un posticino per il suo 
bambino più in giovane età, Benjamin. Le stampanti si sono 
levate in piedi vicino alla parte superiore delle arti meccaniche 
perché il literacy richiesto commerciale. Le stampanti, 
ragruppate nelle città port, hanno formato spesso una rete delle 
famiglie correlate; Il fratello James di Benjamin era un 
supervisore prima che di lui Benjamin ha imparato rapidamente il 
commercio di stampa e si è avventurato fuori nelle attività 
indipendenti. Munito con il suo addestramento importante e un 
penchant per indipendenza, mai ha rifinito il suo termine di servizio 
e preferibilmente non si è mosso sopra per maneggiare il suo 
commercio a Filadelfia e Londra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εκπαίδευση κολλεγίου ήταν σπάνια στην αποικιακή 
Αμερική, συνήθως προοριζόμενη για τους νεαρούς άνδρες που 
εισάγουν το υπουργείο. Το Artisans έμαθε τις δεξιότητες 
και τα μυστικά του εμπορίου τους μέσω μιας μαθητείας σε έναν 
κύριο όπως Benjamin Franklin αφορούσε σε αυτό το απόσπασμα 
για την εκπαίδευσή του ως βιοτέχνης από τη διάσημη αυτοβιογραφία
του. Μετά από την υπηρεσία τους έγιναν τεχνίτες, που 
μισθώθηκαν για έναν χρόνο ενώ έσωσαν για να ανοίξουν ένα δικό 
τους εργαστήριο. Ο πατέρας του Franklin, με δεκαεπτά 
παιδιά, έπρεπε να προγραμματίσει προσεκτικά προκειμένου να 
εξασφαλιστεί μια θέση για το πιό μικρό παιδί του, Benjamin. 
Εκτυπωτές που στέκονται κοντά στην κορυφή των μηχανικών 
τεχνών επειδή το εμπόριο απαίτησε τη βασική εκπαίδευση. Οι
εκτυπωτές, που συγκεντρώθηκαν στις πόλεις λιμένων, διαμόρφωσαν 
συχνά ένα δίκτυο των αλληλένδετων οικογενειών  Ο αδελφός 
james Benjamin ήταν κύριος ενώπιον του. Θ*Ψενιαμην 
έμαθε γρήγορα το εμπόριο εκτύπωσης και αποτόλμησε έξω στις 
ανεξάρτητες δραστηριότητες. Οπλισμένος με την πολύτιμη 
κατάρτισή του και μια τάση για την ανεξαρτησία, δεν τελείωσε 
ποτέ τον όρο υπηρεσίας του και κινήθηκε αντ' αυτού για να 
χειριστεί το εμπόριό του στη Φιλαδέλφεια και το Λονδίνο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La educación universitaria era rara en América 
colonial, prevista sobre todo para los hombres jóvenes que 
incorporaban el ministerio. Los artesanos aprendieron las 
habilidades y los secretos de su comercio con un aprendizaje a un amo 
como Benjamin Franklin relacionado en este extracto sobre su 
educación como artesano de su autobiografía famosa. Después 
de que sintió bien su servicio ellos a oficiales, empleados por una 
época mientras que salvaron para abrir un taller sus el propios. 
El padre de Franklin, con diecisiete niños, tuvo que planear 
cuidadosamente para asegurar un lugar para su niño más joven, 
Benjamin. Las impresoras estaban paradas cerca de la tapa de los
artes mecánicos porque la instrucción requerida comercial. Las
impresoras, arracimadas en las ciudades portuarias, formaron a menudo 
una red de familias correlacionadas; El hermano James de 
Benjamin era un amo antes de él. Benjamin aprendió 
rápidamente el comercio de impresión y aventuró hacia fuera en 
actividades independientes. Armado con su entrenamiento valioso y 
una inclinación para la independencia, él nunca acabó su término del
servicio y en lugar de otro se movió encendido para manejar su 
comercio en Philadelphia y Londres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086180</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106120</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/from-a-child-i-was-fond-of-reading-benjamin-franklin-becomes-a-printer</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
