<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102919</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102919</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206789</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Glidden's Patent Application for Barbed Wire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Patentanfrage Gliddens für Stacheldraht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Demande du brevet de Glidden pour le barbelé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aplicação de patente de Glidden para o arame 
farpado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Richiesta di brevetto del Glidden per filo 
spinato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αίτηση διπλώματος ευρεσιτεχνίας Glidden για το 
οδοντωτό καλώδιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aplicación de patente de Glidden para el alambre 
de púas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents the drawing and description that helped Joseph Glidden, a farmer from De Kalb, Illinois, win a patent for barbed wire in 1874. Glidden's design remains today the most familiar style of barbed wire. This site also examines the considerable impact of barbed wire on the economy, society, and politics in the West.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt die Zeichnung dar und Beschreibung, die 
Joseph Glidden half, ein Landwirt von De Kalb, Illinois, gewinnen ein 
Patent für Stacheldraht 1874. Design Gliddens bleibt heute die 
vertrauteste Art des Stacheldrahts. Diese Site überprüft auch 
die beträchtliche Auswirkung des Stacheldrahts auf die Wirtschaft, 
die Gesellschaft und die Politik im Westen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente le schéma et la description qui a aidé
Joseph Glidden, un fermier de de Kalb, l'Illinois, gagnent un brevet 
pour le barbelé en 1874. La conception de Glidden demeure 
aujourd'hui le modèle le plus familier du barbelé. Ce site 
examine également l'impact considérable du barbelé sur l'économie,
la société, et la politique dans l'ouest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta o desenho e a descrição que ajudou a 
Joseph Glidden, um fazendeiro de De Kalb, Illinois, ganha uma patente 
para o arame farpado em 1874. O projeto de Glidden remanesce 
hoje o estilo o mais familiar do arame farpado. Este local 
examina também o impacto considerável do arame farpado na economia, 
na sociedade, e na política no oeste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta l'illustrazione e la descrizione che ha 
aiutato Joseph Glidden, un coltivatore da De Kalb, l'Illinois, vince 
un brevetto per filo spinato in 1874. Il disegno del Glidden 
rimane oggi lo stile più esperto di filo spinato. Questo luogo 
egualmente esamina l'effetto considerevole di filo spinato 
sull'economia, sulla società e sulla politica nell'ovest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει το σχέδιο και η περιγραφή που βοήθησε 
Joseph Glidden, ένας αγρότης από de Kalb, Ιλλινόις, 
κερδίζει ένα δίπλωμα ευρεσιτεχνίας για το οδοντωτό καλώδιο σε 
1874, σχέδιο Glidden παραμένει σήμερα το πιό γνωστό ύφος 
του οδοντωτού καλωδίου. Αυτή η περιοχή εξετάζει επίσης τον
ιδιαίτερο αντίκτυπο του οδοντωτού καλωδίου στην οικονομία, την 
κοινωνία, και την πολιτική στη δύση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta el gráfico y la descripción que ayudó 
a José Glidden, granjero de De Kalb, Illinois, gana una patente para 
el alambre de púas en 1874. El diseño de Glidden sigue siendo 
hoy el estilo más familiar del alambre de púas. Este sitio 
también examina el impacto considerable del alambre de púas en la 
economía, la sociedad, y la política en el oeste.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206789</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102919</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/gliddens-patent-application-for-barbed-wire</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
