<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105238</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105238</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213191</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Windows Into Wonderland - Yellowstone Electronic Field Trips</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Windows In Märchenland - Elektronisches 
Yellowstone Fangen Reisen auf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Windows En Le Pays des merveilles - Voyages de 
Zone Électroniques de Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Windows No Wonderland - Desengates De Campo 
Eletrônicos De Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Windows In Wonderland - Viaggi Di Campo 
Elettronici Di Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ωηνδοως στη χώρα των θαυμάτων - ηλεκτρονικά ταξίδια 
πεδίων Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Windows En El País de las maravillas - Disparos 
al campo Electrónicos De Yellowstone</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site contains slide shows and virtual field trips of Yellowstone National Park. There are several slide shows to chose from, including wolves of Yellowstone, bear research, fire ecology, the history of Yellowstone and the influence of art on Yellowstone Park. Each program features slides containing text and photographs. There is also an orientation slide show about the National Park system. More virtual field trips will be added in the future. This resource is part of the Biocomplexity collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site enthält Diavorführungen und virtuell 
fangen Sie Reisen von Yellowstone Nationalpark auf. Es
gibt einige Diavorführungen zu wählte von, einschließlich Wölfe 
von Yellowstone, von Bär Forschung, von Feuerökologie, von 
Geschichte von Yellowstone und von Einfluß der kunst auf Yellowstone 
Park. Jedes Programm kennzeichnet die Plättchen, die Text und 
Fotographien enthalten. Es gibt auch eine Lagebestimmung 
Diavorführung über das Nationalparksystem. Virtueller 
fangen Sie Reisen wird hinzugefügt zukünftig auf. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der Biocomplexity Ansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site contient des projections de diapositives 
et des voyages de zone virtuels de parc national de Yellowstone. 
Il y a plusieurs projections de diapositives à a choisi de, y 
compris des loups de Yellowstone, de recherche d'ours, d'écologie du 
feu, de l'histoire de Yellowstone et de l'influence de l'art sur le 
parc de Yellowstone. Chaque programme comporte des glissières 
contenant le texte et les photographies. Il y a également une 
projection de diapositives d'orientation au sujet du système de parc 
national. Des voyages de zone plus virtuels seront ajoutés à 
l'avenir. Cette ressource fait partie de la collection 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local contem mostras de corrediça e 
desengates de campo virtuais do parque nacional de Yellowstone. 
Há diversas mostras de corrediça a escolheu de, including 
lobos de Yellowstone, de pesquisa do urso, de ecology do fogo, do 
history de Yellowstone e da influência da arte no parque de 
Yellowstone. Cada programa caracteriza as corrediças que 
contêm o texto e as fotografias. Há também uma mostra de 
corrediça da orientação sobre o sistema do parque nacional. 
Uns desengates de campo mais virtuais serão adicionados no 
futuro. Este recurso é parte da coleção 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo contiene le proiezioni di diapositive
ed i viaggi di campo virtuali del parco nazionale di Yellowstone. 
Ci sono parecchie proiezioni di diapositive a hanno scelto da, 
compreso i lupi di Yellowstone, di ricerca dell'orso, dell'ecologia 
del fuoco, della storia di Yellowstone e dell'influenza dell'arte sul 
parco di Yellowstone. Ogni programma caratterizza gli scorrevoli
che contengono il testo e le fotografie. Ci è egualmente una 
proiezione di diapositive di orientamento circa il sistema del parco 
nazionale. I viaggi di campo più virtuali saranno aggiunti in 
avvenire. Questa risorsa fa parte dell'accumulazione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ di Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει τις επιδείξεις φωτογραφικών 
διαφανειών και τα εικονικά ταξίδια πεδίων του εθνικού πάρκου 
Yellowstone. Υπάρχουν διάφορες επιδείξεις φωτογραφικών 
διαφανειών επέλεξαν από, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των λύκων 
Yellowstone, την έρευνα αρκούδων, την οικολογία πυρκαγιάς, την 
ιστορία Yellowstone και την επιρροή της τέχνης στο πάρκο 
Yellowstone. Κάθε πρόγραμμα χαρακτηρίζει τις φωτογραφικές
διαφάνειες που περιέχουν το κείμενο και τις φωτογραφίες. 
Υπάρχει επίσης μια επίδειξη φωτογραφικών διαφανειών 
προσανατολισμού για το εθνικό σύστημα πάρκων. Περισσότερα 
εικονικά ταξίδια πεδίων θα προστεθούν στο μέλλον. Αυτό το 
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος της Biocomplexity συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio contiene demostraciones de diapositiva 
y disparos al campo virtuales del parque nacional de Yellowstone. 
Hay varias demostraciones de diapositiva a eligió de, 
incluyendo lobos de Yellowstone, de la investigación del oso, de la 
ecología del fuego, de la historia de Yellowstone y de la influencia 
del arte en el parque de Yellowstone. Cada programa ofrece las 
diapositivas que contienen el texto y las fotografías. Hay 
también una demostración de diapositiva de la orientación sobre el 
sistema del parque nacional. Disparos al campo más virtuales 
serán agregados en el futuro. Este recurso es parte de la 
colección http://serc.carleton.edu/biocomplexity/ de Biocomplexity</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213191</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105238</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/windows-into-wonderland-yellowstone-electronic-field-trips</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
