<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103374</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103374</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086076</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Digital History</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Digital Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire de Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History De Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia Di Digital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψηφιακή ιστορία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia De Digital</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is an educational and non-commercial site designed specifically for history teachers and their students.  The materials included in the Digital History website are original works, government records, works for which copyright permission has expired, works reprinted with permission, or works believed to be within the fair use protection of the copyright laws.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist eine pädagogische und nicht 
gewerbliche Site, die spezifisch für Geschichte Lehrer und ihre 
Kursteilnehmer konzipiert ist. Die Materialien, die in der 
Digital Geschichte Web site eingeschlossen sind, sind ursprüngliche 
Arbeiten, Regierung speichert, arbeitet für welche copyrighterlaubnis
abgelaufen ist, die Arbeiten, die mit Erlaubnis neugedruckt werden, 
oder die Arbeiten, die geglaubt werden, um innerhalb des angemessenen 
Gebrauchschutzes der Urheberrechtsgesetze zu sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un site éducatif et non-commercial conçu 
spécifiquement pour des professeurs d'histoire et leurs étudiants. 
Les matériaux inclus dans le site Web d'histoire de Digital 
sont les travaux initiaux, le gouvernement enregistre, travaille pour 
quelle permission de copyright a expiré, des travaux réimprimés 
avec la permission, ou des travaux pensés pour être dans la 
protection juste d'utilisation des lois de copyright.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um local educacional e non-commercial 
projetado especificamente para professores do history e seus 
estudantes. Os materiais incluídos no Web site do history de 
Digital são trabalhos originais, o governo gravam, trabalham para que
permissão do copyright expirou, os trabalhos reprinted com 
permissão, ou os trabalhos acreditados para estar dentro da 
proteção justa do uso das leis de copyright.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un luogo educativo e non commerciale 
progettato specificamente per gli insegnanti di storia ed i loro 
allievi. I materiali inclusi nel Web site di storia di Digital 
sono impianti originali, governo registra, funziona per quale permesso
del copyright ha espirato, impianti ristampati con permesso, o 
impianti creduti per essere all'interno della protezione giusta di uso
delle leggi di copyright.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι μια εκπαιδευτική και μη εμπορική περιοχή 
που σχεδιάζεται συγκεκριμένα για τους δασκάλους ιστορίας και τους 
σπουδαστές τους. Τα υλικά που περιλαμβάνονται στον ψηφιακό 
ιστοχώρο ιστορίας είναι αρχικές εργασίες, κυβερνητικά αρχεία, 
εργασίες για τις οποίες η δικαιοδοσία πνευματικών δικαιωμάτων 
έχει λήξει, οι εργασίες ανατυπωμένος με τη δικαιοδοσία, ή οι 
εργασίες που θεωρούνται μέσα στη δίκαιη προστασία χρήσης των 
νόμων πνευματικών δικαιωμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es un sitio educativo y no comercial 
diseñado específicamente para los profesores de la historia y sus 
estudiantes. Los materiales incluidos en el Web site de la 
historia de Digital son trabajos originales, el gobierno registran, 
trabajan para ha expirado qué permiso del copyright, los trabajos 
reimpresos con el permiso, o los trabajos creídos para estar dentro 
de la protección justa del uso de los leyes de copyright.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNKNOWN
FN:UNKNOWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086076</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Varies per item</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103374</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/digital-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
