<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108400</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108400</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086044</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Cotton Belt Blues": Lizzie Miles's Blues Song</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Baumwollriemen-Blau": Blau-Lied Der Lizzie 
Meilen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Bleus de Ceinture de Coton" : Chanson des 
Bleus des Milles de Lizzie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Do "Azuis Da Correia Algodão": Canção Dos
Azuis Das Milhas De Lizzie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Azzurri Della Cinghia Del Cotone": Canzone 
Degli Azzurri Delle Miglia Di Lizzie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μπλε ζωνών βαμβακιού": Τραγούδι μπλε των μιλίων
Lizzie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Azul De la Correa Del Algodón": Canción 
De los Azul De las Millas De Lizzie</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The "Great Migration" of the second two decades of the 20th century (the teens and twenties) reshaped northern cities--roughly 70,000 southern blacks settled in Chicago alone. Many used the city only as a temporary destination, moving to other cities in the North and West. During these years New York's black population grew from 91,709 to 152,467; Detroit's from 5,741 to 40,878; and Philadelphia's from 84,459 to 134,229. Northern newspapers, word of mouth, and letters sent home by earlier migrants all contributed to the anticipation black southerners felt about opportunities for a new life in the North. Once they had settled in northern cities, however, many newcomers responded more ambivalently to their new surroundings in the face of northern-style racism, cold weather, high prices, crime, and loneliness.Some African-American blues musicians used their songs to describe the migrants' reactions to their new homes. Lizzie Miles's "Cotton Belt Blues," recorded in 1923, expressed yearning for a former southern home.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die "große Migration" der zweiten zwei Dekaden 
des 20. Jahrhunderts (die Teens und die Zwanziger Jahre) gestaltete 
Nordstädte -- ungefähr 70.000 südliche Schwarze um, die in Chicago 
alleine vereinbart wurden. Viele benutzten die Stadt nur als 
temporäre auf andere Städte bewogen und West Zieleinheit, im Norden.
Während dieses der Jahre New York wuchs schwarze Bevölkerung 
von 91.709 bis 152.467; Detroits von 5.741 bis 40.878; und
Philadelphias von 84.459 bis 134.229. Nordzeitungen, Wort der 
Öffnung und Zeichen sendeten Haus durch die früheren Wanderer, die 
ganz zu den Erwartung Schwarzes southerners beigetragen wurden, die 
über Gelegenheiten für eine neue Lebensdauer im Norden geglaubt 
wurden. Sobald sie in den Nordstädte jedoch vereinbart hatten 
reagierten viele Neulinge ambivalently auf ihre neuen Umlagerungen 
angesichts des Nord-Art Rassismus, kaltes Wetter, hohe Preise, 
Verbrechen, und loneliness.Some verwendeten Afrikanisch-Amerikanische 
Blaumusiker ihre Liede, um die Reaktionen der Wanderer zu ihren neuen 
Häusern zu beschreiben. RIEMEN-Blau der Lizzie Meilen 
"Baumwoll," speicherte 1923, ausgedrückter Yearning für ein 
ehemaliges südliches Haus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le "grand transfert" des deux deuxièmes 
décennies du 20ème siècle (les années de l'adolescence et les 
années '20) a restructuré les villes nordiques -- approximativement 
70.000 noirs méridionaux arrangés en seule Chicago. Beaucoup 
ont utilisé la ville seulement comme destination provisoire, se 
déplaçant à d'autres villes dans le nord et occidentale. 
Pendant la population noire de ce des années New York a accru 
de 91.709 à 152.467 ; Detroit de 5.741 à 40.878 ; et 
Philadelphie de 84.459 à 134.229. Les journaux nordiques, le 
mot de la bouche, et les lettres ont envoyé la maison par de premiers
migrants tout contribués aux habitants du sud de noir d'anticipation 
sentis au sujet des occasions pendant une nouvelle vie dans le 
nord. Une fois qu'ils avaient arrangé dans les villes 
nordiques, cependant, beaucoup de nouveaux venus ont répondu plus 
ambivalently à leurs nouveaux environnements face au racisme de 
nordique-modèle, le froid survivent à, des prix élevés, crime,
et les musiciens afro-américains de bleus de loneliness.Some avaient 
l'habitude leurs chansons pour décrire les réactions des migrants à
leurs nouvelles maisons. Bleus de ceinture du coton des milles 
de Lizzie les "," ont enregistré en 1923, désir exprimé d'une 
ancienne maison méridionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a migração grande" das segundas duas décadas 
do 20o século (os teens e os twenties) reshaped cidades do norte -- 
aproximadamente 70.000 pretos do sul estabelecidos em Chicago sozinho.
Muitos usaram a cidade somente como um destino provisório, 
movendo-se para outras cidades no norte e ocidental. Durante a 
população preta desta anos New York cresceu  91.709 a 152.467; 
Detroit de 5.741 a 40.878; e Filadélfia de 84.459 a 
134.229. Os jornais do norte, a palavra da boca, e as letras 
emitiram a HOME por uns emigrantes mais adiantados contribuídos toda 
aos southerners do preto da antecipação sentidos sobre oportunidades
por uma vida nova no norte. Uma vez que se tinham estabelecido 
em cidades do norte, entretanto, muitos newcomers responderam mais 
ambivalently a seus arredors novos na cara do racism do do 
norte-estilo, tempo frio, preços elevados, crime, e os músicos 
Africano-Americanos dos azuis de loneliness.Some usaram suas canções
descrever as reações dos emigrantes a suas HOME novas. Os 
azuis da correia algodão das milhas de Lizzie do "," gravaram em 
1923, anseio expressado para uma HOME do sul anterior.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'espansione grande" delle seconde due decadi del
ventesimo secolo (gli anni dell'adolescenza e gli anni '20) ha 
rimodellato le città nordiche -- approssimativamente 70.000 neri del 
sud depositati in Chicago da solo. Molti hanno usato la città 
soltanto come destinazione provvisoria, muoventesi verso altre città 
nel nord ed ad ovest. Durante la popolazione di colore de questa
gli anni New York ha sviluppato 91.709 - 152.467; Detroit da 
5.741 a 40.878; e Filadelfia da 84.459 a 134.229. I 
giornali nordici, la parola della bocca e le lettere trasmesse a sede 
dai migranti più in anticipo interamente contribuiti ai southerners 
di nero di anticipazione hanno ritenuto circa le occasioni per una 
nuova vita nel nord. Una volta che si fossero depositati in 
città nordiche, tuttavia, molti nuovi venuti hanno risposto più 
ambivalently ai loro nuovi dintorni di fronte al razzismo di 
nordico-stile, il tempo freddo, i prezzi elevati, crimine ed i 
musicisti Africano-Americani degli azzurri di loneliness.Some hanno 
usato le loro canzoni per descrivere le reazioni dei migranti alle 
loro nuove sedi. Gli azzurri della cinghia del cotone delle 
miglia di Lizzie "," hanno registrato in 1923, yearning espresso per 
una sede del sud precedente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η "μεγάλη μετανάστευση" των δεύτερων δύο δεκαετιών 
των αναδιαμορφωμένων βόρειων πόλεων του 20ού αιώνα (τα teens 
και οι δεκαετίες του '20) -- κατά προσέγγιση 70.000 νότιοι 
Μαύροι που εγκαθίστανται στο Σικάγο μόνο. Πολλοί 
χρησιμοποίησαν την πόλη μόνο ως προσωρινό προορισμό, που 
κινείται προς άλλες πόλεις στο Βορρά και τη δύση. Κατά τη 
διάρκεια αυτού του του Μαύρου της Νέας Υόρκης ετών ο πληθυσμός 
αυξήθηκε από 91.709 έως 152.467  Ντητρόιτ από 
5.741 έως 40.878  και η Φιλαδέλφεια από 84.459 έως 
134,229. τις βόρειες εφημερίδες, τη λέξη του στόματος, και τις 
επιστολές που στάλησαν κατ' οίκον από τους πιό πρώτους 
μετανάστες όλοι συνέβαλε στους μαύρους νοτίους αναμονής που 
έγιναν αισθητούς για τις ευκαιρίες για μια νέα ζωή στο Βορρά. 
Μόλις εγκαταστήσουν στις βόρειες πόλεις, εντούτοις, πολλοί
νεοφερμένοι αποκρίθηκαν pjo' αμψηβαλεντλυ στα νέα περίχωρά 
τους παρά το ρατσισμό βόρειος-ύφους, τον κρύο καιρό, τις υψηλές
τιμές, το έγκλημα, και τη μοναξιά Μερικοί 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί μουσικοί μπλε χρησιμοποίησαν τα 
τραγούδια τους για να περιγράψουν τις αντιδράσεις των μεταναστών 
στα νέα σπίτια τους. Μπλε ζωνών βαμβακιού των μιλίων 
Lizzie τα "," καταγραμμένος το 1923, εξέφρασαν το επιθυμητό 
για ένα προηγούμενο νότιο σπίτι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La "gran migración" de las segundas dos décadas 
del vigésimo siglo (las adolescencias y los años 20) restructuró 
las ciudades norteñas -- áspero 70.000 negros meridionales colocados
en Chicago solamente. Muchos utilizaron la ciudad solamente como
destinación temporal, moviéndose a otras ciudades en el norte y del 
oeste. Durante la población negra de esta años Nueva York 
creció a partir el 91.709 a 152.467; Detroit a partir del 5.741
a 40.878; y Philadelphia a partir del 84.459 a 134.229. 
Los periódicos norteños, la palabra de la boca, y las cartas 
enviaron el hogar de nómadas anteriores contribuidos todo a los 
southerners del negro de la anticipación sentidos sobre las 
oportunidades por una nueva vida en el norte. Una vez que 
hubieran colocado en ciudades norteñas, sin embargo, muchos recién 
llegado respondieron ma's ambivalently a sus nuevos alrededores en la 
cara del racismo del norteño-estilo, tiempo frío, precios altos 
elevados, crimen, y los músicos Africano-Americanos de los azul de 
loneliness.Some utilizaron sus canciones para describir las reacciones
de los nómadas a sus nuevos hogares. Azul de la correa del 
algodón de las millas de Lizzie los "," registraron en 1923, deseo 
vivo expresado para un hogar meridional anterior.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086044</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108400</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cotton-belt-blues-lizzie-miless-blues-song</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
