<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107801</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107801</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087213</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Wee made Good speed along": Boston Businesswoman Sarah Knight Travels From Kingston to New London, 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"kleine gebildete gute Geschwindigkeit entlang": 
Boston Geschäftsfrau Sarah Ritter reist von Kingston nach neues
London, 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"bonne vitesse faite petite le long de" : Le 
chevalier de Sarah de Femme d'affaires de Boston voyage de Kingston à 
nouvelle Londres, 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"velocidade boa feita pequenina ao longo": O
knight de Sarah do businesswoman de Boston viaja de Kingston a Londres
nova, 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"buona velocità fatta piccolissima lungo": 
Il cavaliere di Sarah del businesswoman de Boston viaggia da 
Kingston a nuova Londra, 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Wee γίνοντη καλή ταχύτητα κατά μήκοσ": 
Ταξίδια ιπποτών της Βοστώνης Businesswoman Sarah από 
το Κίνγκστον στο νέο Λονδίνο, 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"buena velocidad hecha wee a lo largo": El 
caballero de Sarah del businesswoman de Boston viaja de Kingston a 
Londres nuevo, 1704</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In October 1704, Sarah Kemble Knight set off on what would be a five month journey, by herself, from her home in Boston to New York and back again. Madam Knight, as she was called, was an unusually independent woman for her time. During her husband's lifetime she supported herself and her family by running a shop, teaching handwriting to children, copying legal documents, and taking in boarders. After his death she continued to do very well for herself, buying and selling land and keeping an inn. In this section of the journal she kept of her trip, Knight described what it was like to travel on horseback, accompanied by a mail carrier and other travelers, from Kingston, Rhode Island, to New London, Connecticut. Her frank humor and often bigoted descriptions of people she met, anxiety about river crossings, displeasure with the rough inns she stayed in, and habit of turning experience into poetry were all expressed here.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Oktober 1704, Sarah Kemble stellte Ritter weg 
auf ein, was eine fünf Monat Reise by.herself von ihrem Haus in 
Boston zu New York und zur Rückseite wieder sein würde. Frau 
Knight, da sie angerufen wurde, war eine ungewöhnlich unabhängige 
Frau während ihrer Zeit. Während der Lebenszeit ihres Ehemanns
unterstützte sich sie und ihre Familie, indem sie ein System laufen 
ließ und den Kindern Handschrift, kopierende gesetzliche Dokumente 
und das Nehmen in den Kostgängern unterrichtete. Nachdem sein 
Tod, den sie fortfuhr, für sehr gut zu tun und kaufte und verkauft 
Land und hält ein Gasthaus. , begleitet von einer Postträger 
und von anderen Reisenden, von Kingston, Rhode-Insel, nach neues 
London, Connecticut an zu Pferde reisen sollte in diesem Kapitel des 
Journals hielt sie von ihrer Reise, beschrieb Ritter, was es wie. 
Ihre aufrichtige Stimmung und bigoted häufig Beschreibungen der
Leute, die sie traf, Angst um Flußüberfahrten, Verdruß mit den 
rauhen Gasthäusern sie innen blieb, und alle Gewohnheit der 
drehenerfahrung in Poesie wurden hier ausgedrückt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En octobre 1704, le chevalier de Sarah Kemble a 
placé hors fonction sur ce qui serait un voyage de cinq mois, toute 
seule, de sa maison à Boston à New York et à dos encore. 
Madame Knight, car elle s'est appelée, était une femme 
exceptionnellement indépendante pendant son temps. Pendant la 
vie de son mari elle s'est supportée et sa famille en dirigeant un 
système, enseignant l'écriture aux enfants, les documents juridiques
copiants, et la prise dans les internes. Après que sa mort 
qu'elle a continué à faire très bien pour elle-même, achetant et 
vendant la terre et gardant une auberge. Dans cette section du 
journal elle a gardé de son voyage, le chevalier a décrit comme ce 
qu'il devait voyager à cheval, accompagné d'un porteur de courrier 
et d'autres voyageurs, de Kingston, île de Rhode, à nouvelle Londres, 
le Connecticut. Ses descriptions franches d'humeur et souvent de
fanatique des personnes qu'elle a rencontrées, inquiétude au sujet 
des croisements de fleuve, mécontentement avec les auberges rugueuses
elle est restées dedans, et l'habitude d'une expérience de rotation 
dans la poésie toute ont été exprimées ici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em outubro 1704, o knight de Sarah Kemble 
ajustou-se fora em o que seria uma viagem de cinco meses, por herself,
de sua HOME em Boston a New York e a parte traseira outra vez. A
senhora Knight, porque foi chamada, era uma mulher raramente 
independente por seu tempo. Durante a vida do seu marido 
suportou-se e sua família funcionando uma loja, ensinando o 
handwriting às crianças, originais legais de copi, e fazer exame nos
boarders. Depois que sua morte que continuou a fazer muito bem 
para herself, comprando e vendendo a terra e mantendo um inn. 
Nesta seção do jornal manteve-se de seu desengate, o knight 
descreveu o que devia como viajar sobre horseback, acompanhado por um 
portador do correio e por outros viajantes, de Kingston, console de 
Rhode, a Londres nova, Connecticut. Seu humor frank e bigoted 
frequentemente as descrições dos povos que se encontrou com, 
ansiedade sobre cruzamentos do rio, displeasure com os inns ásperos 
permaneceu dentro, e o hábito da experiência de giro na poesia todo 
foi expressado aqui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mese di ottobre del 1704, il cavaliere di 
Sarah Kemble si è regolato fuori su che cosa sarebbe ancora un 
viaggio di cinque mesi, da sè, dalla sua sede a Boston a New York ed 
alla parte posteriore. La signora Knight, poichè è stata 
chiamata, era una donna insolitamente indipendente per il suo tempo. 
Durante il corso della vita del suo marito si è sostenuta e la 
sua famiglia dirigendo un negozio, insegnando la scrittura a mano ai 
bambini, i documenti giuridici di copiatura e la presa nei boarders. 
Dopo che la sua morte che ha continuato a fare molto bene per 
sè, comprando e vendendo terra e mantenendo una locanda. In 
questa sezione del giornale ha mantenuto del suo viaggio, il cavaliere
ha descritto che cosa doveva come viaggiare a cavallo sopra, 
accompagnato da un elemento portante della posta e da altri 
viaggiatori, da Kingston, Rhode-isola, a nuova Londra, Connecticut. 
Il suo umore franco e bigoted spesso le descrizioni della gente 
che ha venuto a contatto di, l'ansia circa gli incroci del fiume, 
fastidio con le locande di massima ha rimasto dentro e l'abitudine di 
esperienza di rotazione nella poesia tutta è stata espressa qui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Οκτώβριο του 1704, ο ιππότης Sarah Kemble 
έθεσε μακριά σε αυτό που θα ήταν ένα ταξίδι πέντε μήνα, μόνη 
της, από το σπίτι της στη Βοστώνη στη Νέα Υόρκη και την πλάτη 
πάλι. Η κυρία Knight, καθώς κλήθηκε, ήταν 
κατ'ασυνήθιστο τρόπο ανεξάρτητη γυναίκα για το χρόνο της. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια της διάρκειας ζωής του συζύγου της 
υποστηρίχθηκε και την οικογένειά της με το τρέξιμο ενός 
καταστήματος, τη διδασκαλία της γραφής στα παιδιά, την αντιγραφή 
των νομικών εγγράφων, και τη λήψη στους οικότροφους. Μετά 
από το θάνατό του συνέχισε να κάνει πολύ καλά για την, την 
αγορά και πωλώντας έδαφος και την κράτηση ενός πανδοχείου. 
Σε αυτό το τμήμα του περιοδικού κράτησε του ταξιδιού της, 
ιππότης που περιγράφηκε τι επρόκειτο όπως να ταξιδεψει στην πλάτη
αλόγου, που συνοδεύθηκε από έναν μεταφορέα ταχυδρομείου και 
άλλους ταξιδιώτες, από το Κίνγκστον, Ρόδος, στο νέο Λονδίνο, το
Κοννέκτικατ. Το ειλικρινές χιούμορ και οι συχνά φανατικές 
περιγραφές ανθρώπων της συναντήθηκε, ανησυχία για τις 
διασταυρώσεις ποταμών, δυσαρέσκεια με τα τραχιά πανδοχεία που 
έμεινε μέσα, και η συνήθεια της μετατροπής της εμπειρίας σε 
ποίηση όλες εκφράστηκε εδώ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En octubre de 1704, el caballero de Sarah Kemble 
fijó apagado en cuál sería un viaje de cinco meses, por se, de su 
hogar en Boston a Nueva York y a la parte posteriora otra vez. 
Señora Knight, pues le llamaron, era una mujer inusualmente 
independiente por su tiempo. Durante el curso de la vida de su 
marido ella se utilizó y a su familia ejecutando un departamento, 
enseñando cursivo a los niños, documentos jurídicos de copiado, y 
tomar en huéspedes. Después de que su muerte que ella 
continuó haciendo muy bien para se, comprando y vendiendo pista y 
guardando un mesón. En esta sección del diario ella guardó de
su viaje, el caballero describió como cuál debía viajar encendido a
caballo, acompañado por un portador del correo y otras hojas de ruta 
(traveler), de Kingston, Rhode-isla, a Londres nuevo, Connecticut. 
Su humor franco y bigoted a menudo las descripciones de la gente
que ella satisfizo, ansiedad sobre travesías del río, descontento 
con los mesones ásperos ella permanecía adentro, y el hábito de la 
experiencia que daba vuelta en poesía todo fue expresado aquí.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087213</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107801</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/wee-made-good-speed-along-boston-businesswoman-sarah-knight-travels-from-kingston-to-new-london-1704</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
