<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106606</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106606</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200474</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AP Calculus AB II</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AP Kalkül AB II</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Calcul Ab II de AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cálculo Ab II do Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Calcolo Ab II di Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπολογισμός αβ ΙΙ AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cálculo Ab II del Ap</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to the NROC Advanced Placement (AP) Calculus AB course. This curriculum covers all of the material outlined by the College Board as necessary to prepare students to pass the AP Calculus AB exam. This course is divided into two semesters and is designed to acquaint you with calculus principles such as derivatives, integrals, limits, approximation, and applications and modeling. During this course you will gain experience in the use of calculus methods and learn how calculus methods may be applied to practical applications.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zum NROC rückte Plazierung (AP) Kurs 
des Kalküls AB vor. Dieser Lehrplan umfaßt die ganze Material,
das durch das Hochschulgremium wie benötigt, Kursteilnehmer 
vorzubereiten, die Prüfung des AP Kalküls zu führen AB umrissen 
wird. Dieser Kurs ist in zwei Semester geteilt und ist 
konzipiert, um Sie mit Kalkülgrundregeln wie Ableitungen, Integrale, 
Begrenzungen, Näherungswert und Anwendungen und Formung mitzuteilen. 
Während dieses Kurses gewinnen Sie Erfahrung im Gebrauch von 
Kalkülmethoden und erlernen, wie Kalkülmethoden an den praktischen 
Anwendungen angewendet werden können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La bienvenue au NROC a avancé le cours du calcul 
ab du placement (AP). Ce programme d'études couvre tout le 
matériel tracé les grandes lignes par le conseil d'université selon
les besoins pour préparer des étudiants passer l'examen du calcul ab
de AP. Ce cours est divisé en deux semestres et est conçu pour
vous mettre au courant des principes de calcul tels que des dérivés,
des intégrales, des limites, approximation, et des applications et 
modeler. Pendant ce cours vous acquerrez l'expérience de 
l'utilisation des méthodes de calcul et apprendrez comment des 
méthodes de calcul peuvent être appliquées aux applications 
pratiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A boa vinda ao NROC avançou o curso do AB do 
cálculo da colocação (AP). Este curriculum cobre todo o 
material esboçado pela placa de faculdade como necessário preparar 
estudantes para passar o exam do AB do cálculo do AP. Este 
curso é dividido em dois semesters e projetado familiarizá-lo com os
princípios do cálculo tais como derivatives, integrais, limites, 
aproximação, e aplicações e modelar. Durante este curso 
você ganhará a experiência no uso de métodos do cálculo e 
aprenderá como os métodos do cálculo podem ser aplicados às 
aplicações práticas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il benvenuto al NROC ha avanzato il corso di 
calcolo ab di disposizione (AP). Questo programma di studi 
tratta tutto il materiale descritto dal Bordo dell'università 
come necessario preparare gli allievi per passare il exam di calcolo 
ab di AP. Questo corso è diviso in due semestri ed è destinato
per informarlo dei principii di calcolo quali i derivati, integrali, 
limiti, approssimazione ed applicazioni e modellare. Durante 
questo corso guadagnerete l'esperienza di uso dei metodi di calcolo ed
imparerete come i metodi di calcolo possono essere applicati alle 
applicazioni pratiche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στην προηγμένη NROC σειρά μαθημάτων 
υπολογισμού αβ τοποθέτησης (AP). Αυτό το πρόγραμμα 
σπουδών καλύπτει όλο το υλικό που περιγράφεται από τον πίνακα 
κολλεγίου για να προετοιμάσει ανάλογα με τις ανάγκες τους 
σπουδαστές για να περάσει το διαγωνισμό υπολογισμού αβ AP. 
Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων διαιρείται σε δύο εξάμηνα και 
σχεδιάζεται για να σας εξοικειώσει με τις αρχές υπολογισμού όπως 
τα παράγωγα, τα ολοκληρώματα, τα όρια, η προσέγγιση, και οι 
εφαρμογές και η διαμόρφωση. Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της 
σειράς μαθημάτων θα αποκτήσετε την εμπειρία στη χρήση των 
μεθόδων υπολογισμού και θα μάθετε πώς οι μέθοδοι υπολογισμού 
μπορούν να εφαρμοστούν στις πρακτικές εφαρμογές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La recepción al NROC avanzó curso del AB del 
cálculo de la colocación (AP). Este plan de estudios cubre 
todo el material contorneado por la tarjeta de universidad como 
necesaria para preparar a estudiantes para aprobar el examen del AB 
del cálculo del AP. Este curso se divide en dos semestres y se 
diseña para conocerle de principios del cálculo tales como 
derivados, los integrales, los límites, aproximación, y las 
aplicaciones y el modelar. Durante este curso usted ganará 
experiencia en el uso de los métodos del cálculo y aprenderá cómo 
los métodos del cálculo se pueden aplicar a las aplicaciones 
prácticas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
FN:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200474</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106606</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ap-calculus-abii</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
