<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107943</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087063</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Truth about Haiti: An NAACP Investigation"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Wahrheit über Haiti: Eine NAACP 
Untersuchung "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la vérité au sujet du Haïti : Une 
Recherche de NAACP "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a verdade sobre Haiti: Uma Investigação de
NAACP "</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"verità circa l'Haiti: Una Ricerca di NAACP 
"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η αλήθεια για την Αϊτή: Μια έρευνα NAACP 
"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la verdad sobre Haití: Una Investigación 
de NAACP "</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">U.S. marines occupied Haiti from 1915 to 1934. By 1919, Haitian Charlemagne Pralte had organized more than a thousand  cacos , or armed guerrillas, to militarily oppose the marine occupation. The marines responded to the resistance with a counterinsurgency campaign that razed villages, killed thousands of Haitians, and destroyed the livelihoods of even more. American organizations such as the NAACP opposed the U.S. occupation of Haiti. They sent delegations that investigated conditions and protested the blatant racism and imperialism of U.S. policy in Haiti in the early 20th century. An article from 1920, by NAACP leader James Weldon Johnson, countered the standard justifications for U.S. occupation of Haiti.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinen besetzten Haiti von 1915
bis 1934. Bis zum 1919 hatte haitianischer Karl der Große 
Pralte mehr als tausend cacos oder bewaffnete Bandenkämpfer 
organisiert, um der Marinebesetzung militärisch entgegenzusetzen. 
Die Marinen reagierten auf den Widerstand mit einer 
Gegenaufstandkampagne, die Dörfer razed, Tausenden Haitianer beendete
und die Lebensunterhalt von sogar mehr zerstörte. Amerikanische
Organisationen wie das NAACP setzten der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Besetzung 
von Haiti entgegen. Sie sendeten Delegationen, die Bedingungen 
nachforschten und den krassen Rassismus und den Imperialismus von 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Politik in Haiti im frühen 20. Jahrhundert 
protestierten. Ein Artikel von 1920, durch NAACP Führer James 
Weldon Johnson, widersprach den Standardrechtfertigungen für 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Besetzung von Haiti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les soldats de marine des ETATS-UNIS ont occupé 
le Haïti de 1915 à 1934. D'ici 1919, Charlemagne haïtien 
Pralte avait organisé plus que mille cacos, ou les guérilleros 
armés, pour s'opposer militairement au métier marin. Les 
soldats de marine ont répondu à la résistance avec une campagne de 
contre-insurrection qui a rasé des villages, a détruit 
des milliers de haïtiens, et a détruit les vies d'encore plus. 
Les organismes américains tels que le NAACP se sont opposés au
métier des ETATS-UNIS du Haïti. Ils ont envoyé les 
délégations qui ont étudié des conditions et ont protesté le 
racisme et l'impérialisme flagrants de la politique des ETATS-UNIS au
Haïti en début du 20ème siècle. Un article de 1920, par 
l'amorce James Weldon Johnson de NAACP, a paré les 
justifications standard pour le métier des ETATS-UNIS du Haïti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocuparam 
Haiti de 1915 a 1934. Por 1919, Charlemagne haitian Pralte tinha
organizado mais do que mil cacos, ou guerrillas armados, para opôr 
militar a ocupação marinha. Os fuzileiros navais responderam 
à resistência com uma campanha do counterinsurgency que razed vilas,
matasse milhares dos haitians, e destruísse os meios de subsistência
de mesmo mais. As organizações americanas tais como o NAACP 
opuseram a ocupação de ESTADOS UNIDOS de Haiti. Emitiram os 
delegations que investigaram circunstâncias e protestaram o racism e 
o imperialism blatant da política de ESTADOS UNIDOS em Haiti no 20o 
século adiantado. Um artigo de 1920, pelo líder James Weldon 
Johnson de NAACP, opôs as justificações padrão para a ocupação 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS de Haiti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I fanti di marina degli STATI UNITI hanno occupato 
l'Haiti da 1915 a 1934. Entro 1919, Charlemagne haitian Pralte 
aveva organizzato più di mille cacos, o i guerriglieri muniti, per 
opporre militarmente l'occupazione marina. I fanti di marina 
hanno risposto alla resistenza con una campagna del counterinsurgency 
che razed i villaggi, ha ucciso i migliaia dei haitians ed ha 
distrutto le vite di ancor più. Le organizzazioni 
americane quale il NAACP hanno opposto l'occupazione degli STATI UNITI
dell'Haiti. Hanno trasmesso le delegazioni che hanno studiato le
circostanze ed hanno protestato il razzismo e l'imperialismo blatant 
della politica degli STATI UNITI in Haiti nell'inizio del 20esimo 
secolo. Un articolo da 1920, dal capo James Weldon 
Johnson del NAACP, ha ricambiato le giustificazioni standard per 
l'occupazione degli STATI UNITI dell'Haiti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ΗΠΑ κατειλημμένη ναυτικά Αϊτή από το 1915 ως το 
1934. Μέχρι το 1919, αϊτινό Charlemagne Pralte 
είχε οργανώσει περισσότερα από χίλια cacos, ή τους 
οπλισμένους αντάρτες, για να αντιτάξει στρατιωτικά το θαλάσσιο 
επάγγελμα. Τα ναυτικά αποκρίθηκαν στην αντίσταση με μια 
εκστρατεία αντιεξέγερσης που τα χωριά, σκότωσε χιλιάδες 
Αϊτινοί, και κατέστρεψε τα livelihoods ακόμη και περισσότερο. 
Οι αμερικανικές οργανώσεις όπως το NAACP αντέταξαν το 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ επάγγελμα της Αϊτής. Έστειλαν τις 
αντιπροσωπείες που ερεύνησαν τους όρους και διαμαρτυρήθηκαν τον 
κραυγαλέους ρατσισμό και τον ιμπεριαλισμό της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ 
πολιτικής στην Αϊτή στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα. Ένα άρθρο
από το 1920, από NAACP τον ηγέτη james Weldon 
Johnson, αντιμετώπισε τις πρότυπες δικαιολογίες για το 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ επάγγελμα της Αϊτής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los infantes de marina de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocuparon 
Haití a partir de 1915 a 1934. Antes de 1919, Charlemagne 
haitiano Pralte había ordenado más que mil cacos, o a guerrillas 
armados, para oponer militar la ocupación marina. Los infantes 
de marina respondieron a la resistencia con una campaña del 
counterinsurgency que razed aldeas, mató a millares de haitianos, y
destruyó los sustentos de aún más. Las organizaciones 
americanas tales como el NAACP opusieron la ocupación de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS de Haití. Enviaron a delegaciones que investigaron 
condiciones y protestaron el racismo y el imperialismo evidentes de la
política de ESTADOS UNIDOS en Haití en el vigésimo siglo temprano. 
Un artículo a partir de 1920, por el arranque de cinta James 
Weldon Johnson de NAACP, contradijo las alineaciones estándares para 
la ocupación de ESTADOS UNIDOS de Haití.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087063</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107943</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-truth-about-haiti-an-naacp-investigation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
