<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103141</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103141</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087087</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Their Extraordinary Great Labor": Roger Williams Observes Indian Customs and Language, 1643</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ihre Außerordentliche Große Arbeit": Roger
Williams beobachtet indische Gewohnheiten und Sprache, 1643</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Leur Grand Travail Extraordinaire" : Roger 
Williams observe les coutumes et la langue indiennes, 1643</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Seu Trabalho Grande Extraordinário": Roger 
Williams observa os costumes e a língua indian, 1643</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Loro Lavoro Grande Straordinario": 
Roger Williams osserva le abitudini ed il linguaggio indiani, 
1643</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η "εξαιρετική μεγάλη εργασία τουσ": Θ*Ρογερ 
Williams Observes Indian Customs και γλώσσα, 1643</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Su Gran Trabajo Extraordinario": Roger 
Williams observa los costumbres y el lenguaje indios, 1643</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">European observers generally commented critically upon the leading role of Indian women in work. Roger Williams proved an exception. The minister, once head of the Salem church, was expelled from the Massachusetts Bay colony in 1635 for questioning the Puritan leadership. He helped found the colony of Rhode Island around Narragansett Bay on land purchased from the Narragansett people to the south, with whom he and the colony maintained generally good relations. He spent much of his life trying to understand the Indians 'customs and language, and published some of his sympathetic observations in his 1643 book  Key into the Language of America  where he offered a glossary of Algonquian words that revealed much about Indian life. Williams also criticized certain colonial practices, such as the occupation of Indian lands by Europeans, and advocated the separation of church and state and individual freedom in other writings.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Europäische Beobachter kommentierten im 
Allgemeinen kritisch nach der führenden Rolle der indischen Frauen in
der Arbeit. Roger Williams prüfte eine Ausnahme. Der 
Minister, einmal Kopf der Salem Kirche, wurde von der Massachusetts 
Buchtkolonie 1635 für das Ausfragen der puritanischen Führung 
weggetrieben. Er half fand die Kolonie von Rhode-Insel um 
Narragansett Bucht auf dem Land, das von den Narragansett Leuten zum 
Süden gekauft wurde, mit dem er und die Kolonie im Allgemeinen gute 
Relationen beibehielten. Er verbrachte viel seiner Lebensdauer, 
die versucht, Gewohnheiten und Sprache zu verstehen der Inder ' und 
veröffentlichte einige seiner sympatischen Beobachtungen in seiner 
1643 Buch Taste in die Sprache von Amerika, in dem er ein Glossar der 
Algonquian Wörter anbot, die viel über indische Lebensdauer 
aufdeckten. Williams auch kritisierte bestimmte Kolonialpraxis, 
wie die Besetzung der indischen Länder durch Europäer und 
befürwortet der Trennung der Kirche und des Zustandes und einzelner 
Freiheit in anderen Schreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les observateurs européens généralement ont 
commenté en critique sur le principal rôle des femmes indiennes dans
le travail. Roger Williams a montré une exception. Le 
ministre, une fois chef de l'église de Salem, a été expulsé de la 
colonie de compartiment du Massachusetts en 1635 pour remettre en 
cause la conduite puritaine. Il a aidé a trouvé la colonie 
d'île de Rhode autour du compartiment de Narragansett sur la terre 
achetée des personnes de Narragansett aux sud, avec qui lui 
et la colonie ont mis à jour des relations de bien général. 
Il a passé beaucoup de sa vie essayant coutumes et langue de 
comprendre Indiens des ', et a édité certaines de ses observations 
sympathiques dans sa clé de 1643 livres dans le langage de 
l'Amérique où il a offert un glossaire des mots d'Algonquian qui ont
indiqué beaucoup au sujet de la vie indienne. Pratiques en 
matière coloniales également critiquées de Williams certaines, 
telles que le métier des terres indiennes par Européen, et 
préconisé la séparation de l'église et de l'état et liberté 
individuelle dans d'autres écritures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os observadores europeus comentaram geralmente 
crìticamente em cima do papel principal de mulheres indian no 
trabalho. Roger Williams provou uma exceção. O ministro,
uma vez cabeça da igreja de Salem, foi expelido da colônia da baía 
de Massachusetts em 1635 para questionar a liderança puritan. 
Ajudou encontrou a colônia do console de Rhode em torno da 
baía de Narragansett na terra comprada dos povos de Narragansett ao 
sul, com quem e a colônia mantiveram relações geralmente boas. 
Gastou muita de sua vida que tenta compreender costumes e 
língua dos indians ', e publicou algumas de suas observações 
sympathetic em sua chave de 1643 livros na língua de América onde 
ofereceu um glossário das palavras de Algonquian que revelaram muito 
sobre a vida indian. Práticas coloniais também criticadas de 
Williams determinadas, tais como a ocupação de terras indian por 
Europeu, e advogado a separação da igreja e do estado e liberdade 
individual em outras escritas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli osservatori europei osservazione generale 
criticamente sul ruolo principale delle donne indiane nel lavoro. 
Roger Williams ha dimostrato un'eccezione. Il ministro,
una volta testa della chiesa de Salem, è stato espulso dalla colonia 
della baia del Massachusetts in 1635 per mettere in discussione la 
direzione puritan. Ha aiutato ha trovato la colonia 
dell'Rhode-isola intorno alla baia di Narragansett su terra comprata 
dalla gente di Narragansett al sud, con quale lui e la colonia hanno 
effettuato i rapporti generalmente buoni. Ha speso 
molta della sua vita che prova a capire abitudini e linguaggio degli 
indiani 'ed ha pubblicato alcune delle sue osservazioni simpatiche nel
suo tasto dei 1643 libri nel linguaggio dell'America in cui ha offerto
un glossario delle parole di Algonquian che hanno rivelato molto circa
vita indiana. Pratiche coloniali anche criticate del Williams 
determinate, quale l'occupazione delle terre indiane da Europeo e 
sostenuto la separazione della chiesa e dichiarano e libertà 
individuale in altre scritture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ευρωπαϊκοί παρατηρητές σχολίασαν γενικά αυστηρά 
επάνω στον κύριο ρόλο των ινδικών γυναικών στην εργασία. Ο
Roger Williams απέδειξε μια εξαίρεση. Ο υπουργός, μιά 
φορά επικεφαλής της εκκλησίας του Σάλεμ, αποβλήθηκε από την 
αποικία κόλπων της Μασαχουσέτης το 1635 για την επερώτηση της 
πουριτανής ηγεσίας. Βοήθησε να βρεί την αποικία της Ρόδου 
γύρω από τον κόλπο Narragansett στο έδαφος που αγοράστηκε από
τους ανθρώπους Narragansett στο νότο, με τον οποίο αυτός και η 
αποικία διατήρησαν τις γενικά καλές σχέσεις. Πέρασε ένα 
μεγάλο μέρος της ζωής του που προσπαθεί τελωνείο και γλώσσα να 
καταλάβει των Ινδών ", και δημοσίευσε μερικές από τις 
συμπονετικές παρατηρήσεις του σε 1643 του κρατά το πλήκτρο σε 
γλώσσα της Αμερικής όπου πρόσφερε ένα γλωσσάρι των λέξεων 
Algonquian που αποκάλυψε πολύ για την ινδική ζωή. Ο 
Ουίλιαμς επέκρινε επίσης ορισμένες αποικιακές πρακτικές, όπως 
το επάγγελμα των ινδικών εδαφών από τους Ευρωπαίους, και 
υποστήριξε το χωρισμό της εκκλησίας και του κράτους και τη 
μεμονωμένη ελευθερία σε άλλες γραφές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los observadores europeos comentaron generalmente 
críticamente sobre el papel principal de mujeres indias en trabajo. 
Roger Williams probó una anomalía. Expelieron al 
ministro, una vez jefe de la iglesia de Salem, de la colonia de la 
bahía de Massachusetts en 1635 para preguntar la dirección puritan. 
Él ayudó encontró a colonia de la Rhode-isla alrededor de la 
bahía de Narragansett en la pista comprada de la gente de 
Narragansett al sur, con el cual él y la colonia mantuvieron 
relaciones generalmente buenas. Él pasó mucha de su vida que 
intentaba entender costumbres y lenguaje a los indios los ', y 
publicó algunas de sus observaciones comprensivas en su clave de 1643
libros en el lenguaje de América en donde él ofreció un glosario de
las palabras de Algonquian que revelaron mucho sobre vida india. 
Prácticas coloniales también criticadas de Williams ciertas, 
tales como la ocupación de pistas indias de europeo, y abogado la 
separación de la iglesia y del estado y libertad individual en otras 
escrituras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087087</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103141</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/their-extraordinary-great-labor-roger-williams-observes-indian-customs-and-language-1643</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
