<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106205</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106205</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973948</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Physics Games: Microscopes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Physik-Spiele: Mikroskope</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Physique : Microscopes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Física: Microscópios</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Fisica: Microscopii</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια φυσικής: Μικροσκόπια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Física: Microscopios</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! Zernike invented the phase-contrast microscope, Ruska developed the electron microscope, and Binnig and Rohrer invented the scanning tunneling microscope. All have been awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics. Here, you can learn more about these different microscopes and what the scientist studies with them. You can also try the techniques of Nobel Prize Laureates by yourself in our microscope simulators.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Zernike erfand Phase-kontrastieren Mikroskop, entwickelte Ruska 
das Elektronenmikroskop, und Binnig und Rohrer erfanden das 
Abtastungeinen Tunnel anlegen Mikroskop. Alle sind den 
Nobelpreis in der Physik zugesprochen worden. Hier können Sie 
mehr über diese unterschiedlichen Mikroskope erlernen und was der 
Wissenschaftler mit ihnen studiert. Sie können die Techniken 
der Nobelpreis-Laureaten durch selbst in unseren Mikroskopsimulatoren 
auch versuchen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Zernike a
inventé phase-contrastent le microscope, Ruska a développé le 
microscope électronique, et Binnig et Rohrer ont inventé le 
microscope de perçage d'un tunnel de lecture. Tous ont été 
attribués le prix Nobel dans la physique. Ici, vous pouvez 
apprendre plus au sujet de ces différents microscopes et ce que le 
scientifique étudie avec eux. Vous pouvez également essayer 
les techniques des lauréats de prix Nobel par vous-même dans des nos
simulateurs de microscope.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Zernike
inventou fase-contrasta o microscópio, Ruska desenvolveu o 
microscópio de elétron, e Binnig e Rohrer inventaram o microscópio 
tunneling da exploração. Todos foram concedidos o prêmio de 
nobel na física. Aqui, você pode aprender mais sobre estes 
microscópios diferentes e o que o cientista estuda com eles. 
Você pode também tentar as técnicas de laureates do prêmio 
de nobel por yourself em nossos simuladores do microscópio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Zernike ha inventato 
fase-contrappone il microscopio, Ruska ha sviluppato il microscopio 
elettronico e Binnig e Rohrer hanno inventato il microscopio di 
traforo di esame. Tutti hanno ricevuto il premio Nobel nella 
fisica. Qui, potete imparare più circa questi microscopii 
differenti e che cosa lo scienziato studia con loro. Potete 
anche provare le tecniche dei laureates del premio Nobel da lei in 
nostri simulatori del microscopio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Το 
Zernike έφηυρε το μικροσκόπιο φάση-αντίθεσης, Ruska 
ανέπτυξε το ηλεκτρονικό μικροσκόπιο, και Binnig και Rohrer 
έφηυραν το ανοίγοντας μικροσκόπιο ανίχνευσης. Όλοι έχουν 
απονεμηθεί το βραβείο Νόμπελ στη φυσική. Εδώ, μπορείτε να 
μάθετε περισσότερων για αυτά τα διαφορετικά μικροσκόπια και τι ο 
επιστήμονας μελετά με τα. Μπορείτε επίσης να δοκιμάσετε τις
τεχνικές δαφνοστεφών βραβείων Νόμπελ από σας στους προσομοιωτές 
μικροσκοπίων μας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Zernike 
inventó fase-pone en contraste el microscopio, Ruska desarrolló el 
microscopio electrónico, y Binnig y Rohrer inventaron el microscopio 
el hacer un túnel de la exploración. Todos se han concedido el
premio Nobel en la física. Aquí, usted puede aprender más 
sobre estos diversos microscopios y qué el científico estudia con 
ellos. Usted puede también intentar las técnicas de los 
laureados del premio Nobel de se en nuestros simuladores del 
microscopio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973948</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106205</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/physics-games-microscopes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
