<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107698</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107698</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087102</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"They That Are Born There Talk Good English": Hugh Jones Describes Virginia's Slave Society, 1724</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie, Die Dort Geboren Sind, Sprechen Gutes 
Englisch": Hugh Jones Beschreibt Virginias Sklavengesellschaft, 
1724</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ils Qui Naissent Là Parlent Le Bon Anglais" : 
Hugh Jones Décrit La Société Slave de la 
Virginie, 1724</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Que São carregados Lá Falam O Inglês Bom": 
Hugh Jones Descreve A Sociedade Slave De Virgínia, 1724</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Che Sono sopportati Là Comunicano Il Buon 
Inglese": Hugh Jones Descrive La Società Slave Della Virginia, 
1724</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Που γεννιούνται εκεί μιλούν τα καλά αγγλικά": 
Κοινωνία σκλάβων του Hugh Jones Describes Βιρτζίνια,
1724</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Que Nacen Allí Hablan Buen Inglés": Hugh 
Jones Describe A Sociedad Auxiliar De Virginia, 1724</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Slavery and a society based on slave labor were well established in the Chesapeake region by the third decade of the 18th century. Hugh Jones described the beginnings of African-American culture as slavery spread in the Chesapeake. Virginia's slave population grew from 3,000 in 1680 to 13,000 in 1700. It further expanded to 27,000 by 1720. Despite Jones's rosy picture, he effectively depicted the enslaved population's contact with whites, the growth of a smaller group that spoke English, and the emergence of strong kinship bonds facilitated by a naturally increasing population, a first in the New World. Hugh Jones arrived from England and served as a minister in Jamestown and professor of mathematics at William and Mary. He authored  The Present State of Virginia  (1724) where he described the distinctive form of society emerging in Virginia of large and small landowners, poor white laborers, and enslaved Africans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sklaverei und eine Gesellschaft, die auf 
Sklavenarbeit basierte, waren in der Chesapeakeregion bis zum der 
dritten Dekade des 18. Jahrhunderts gut eingerichtet. Hugh Jones
beschrieb die Anfänge der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Kultur, während
Sklaverei im Chesapeake verbritt. Virginias Sklavenbevölkerung 
wuchs von 3.000 1680 bis 13.000 1700. Es erweiterte weiter bis 
27.000 bis zum 1720. Trotz Jones der rosigen Abbildung stellte 
er effektiv den versklavten Kontakt der Bevölkerung mit Weiß, das 
Wachstum einer kleineren Gruppe, die Englisch sprach, und das 
Hervortreten der starken Verwandtschaftbindungen bildlich dar, die von
einer natürlich zunehmenden Bevölkerung, eine erste in der neuen 
Welt erleichtert wurden. Hugh Jones kam von England an und 
diente als Minister in Jamestown und Professor von Mathematik bei 
William und bei Mary. Er schrieb den aktuellen Stand von 
Virginia (1724) wo er das unterscheidende Formular der Gesellschaft 
auftauchend in Virginia der großen und kleinen Grundbesitzer 
beschrieb, versklavten arme weiße Arbeiter und Afrikaner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'esclavage et une société basée sur le travail
slave étaient bien établis dans la région de chesapeake par 
la troisième décennie du 18ème siècle. Hugh Jones a 
décrit les débuts de la culture afro-américaine pendant que 
l'esclavage s'étendait dans le chesapeake. La population 
slave de la Virginie s'est développée de 3.000 en 1680 à 
13.000 de 1700. Elle a plus loin augmenté à 27.000 d'ici 1720.
En dépit de l'image attrayante de Jones, il a pertinemment 
dépeint le contact de la population asservie avec des blancs, la 
croissance d'un plus petit groupe qui a parlé anglais, et 
l'apparition des obligations fortes de parenté facilitées par une 
population naturellement croissante, une première au nouveau monde. 
Hugh Jones est arrivé d'Angleterre et a servi de 
ministre dans Jamestown et de professeur des mathématiques chez 
William et Mary. Il a écrit l'état actuel de la Virginie 
(1724) où il a décrit la forme distinctive de la société 
émergeant en Virginie de grands et petits propriétaires fonciers, 
les pauvres travailleurs blancs, et ont asservi des Africains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O slavery e uma sociedade baseada no trabalho 
slave foram estabelecidos bem na região do chesapeake pela terceira 
década do 18o século. Hugh Jones descreveu os começos da 
cultura Africano-Americana enquanto o slavery espalhou no chesapeake. 
A população slave de Virgínia cresceu de 3.000 em 1680 a 
13.000 em 1700. Expandiu mais mais a 27.000 por 1720. 
Apesar do retrato rosy de Jones, descreveu eficazmente o contato
da população enslaved com brancos, o crescimento de um grupo menor 
que falasse o inglês, e o emergence das ligações fortes do kinship 
facilitadas por uma população naturalmente crescente, uma primeira 
no mundo novo. Hugh Jones chegou de Inglaterra e serviu como um 
ministro em Jamestown e o professor da matemática em William e em 
Mary. Foi o autor do estado atual de Virgínia (1724) onde 
descreveu o formulário distintivo da sociedade que emerge em 
Virgínia de latifundiários grandes e pequenos, os laborers brancos 
deficientes, e enslaved africanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo slavery e una società basata sul lavoro 
slave erano affermati nella regione del chesapeake entro la terza 
decade del diciottesimo secolo. Hugh Jones ha descritto gli 
inizii di coltura Africano-Americana mentre lo slavery si è sparso 
nel chesapeake. La popolazione slave della Virginia si è 
sviluppata da 3.000 in 1680 - 13.000 di 1700. Più ulteriormente
si è espansa a 27.000 entro 1720. Malgrado l'immagine 
ottimistica del Jones, ha descritto efficacemente il contatto della 
popolazione asservita con i bianchi, lo sviluppo di più piccolo 
gruppo che ha parlato inglese e l'emersione dei legami forti del 
kinship facilitati da una popolazione naturalmente aumentante, una 
prima nel nuovo mondo. Hugh Jones è arrivato dall'Inghilterra 
ed ha servito da ministro in Jamestown e professore della 
matematica a William ed a Mary. Ha creato il presente 
Dichiara della Virginia (1724) dove ha descritto la forma 
distintiva della società che emerge nella Virginia di grandi e 
piccoli latifondisti, i poveri lavoratori bianchi ed hanno 
asservito gli Africani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σκλαβιά και μια κοινωνία βασισμένη στην εργασία 
σκλάβων καθιερώθηκαν καλά στη chesapeake περιοχή μέχρι την 
τρίτη δεκαετία του 18$ου αιώνα. Ο Hugh Jones 
περιέγραψε τις αρχές του αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού πολιτισμού ως 
σκλαβιά που διαδόθηκε chesapeake. Ο πληθυσμός σκλάβων της
Βιρτζίνια αυξήθηκε από 3.000 το 1680 σε 13.000 το 1700.
Επεκτάθηκε περαιτέρω σε 27.000 από 1720, Παρά τη
ροδοειδή εικόνα Jones, απεικόνισε αποτελεσματικά την 
υποδουλωμένη επαφή του πληθυσμού με τα λευκά, η αύξηση μιας 
μικρότερης ομάδας που μίλησε τα αγγλικά, και την εμφάνιση των 
ισχυρών δεσμών συγγένειας που διευκολύνθηκαν από έναν φυσικά 
αυξανόμενο πληθυσμό, ένας πρώτος στο νέο κόσμο. Ο Hugh 
Jones έφθασε από την Αγγλία και εχρησίμευσε ως έναν υπουργό 
σε Jamestown και ο καθηγητής των μαθηματικών σε William και 
Mary. Η παρούσα κατάσταση της Βιρτζίνια (1724) όπου 
περιέγραψε τη διακριτική μορφή της κοινωνίας που προκύπτει στη 
Βιρτζίνια των μεγάλων και μικρών landowners, φτωχά λευκά 
laborers, και υποδούλωσε Αφρικανούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La esclavitud y una sociedad basada en trabajo 
auxiliar eran establecidas en la región del chesapeake por la tercera
década del décimo octavo siglo. Hugh Jones describió los 
principios de la cultura Africano-Americana mientras que la esclavitud
se separó en el chesapeake. La población auxiliar de Virginia 
creció a partir del 3.000 en 1680 a 13.000 de 1700. Se amplió 
más lejos a 27.000 antes de 1720. A pesar de el cuadro 
atractivo de Jones, él representó con eficacia el contacto de la 
población esclavizada con blancos, el crecimiento de un grupo más 
pequeño que habló inglés, y la aparición de los enlaces fuertes 
del parentesco facilitados por una población naturalmente de aumento,
una primera en el mundo nuevo. Hugh Jones llegó de Inglaterra y
sirvió como un ministro en Jamestown y profesor de las matemáticas 
en Guillermo y Maria. Él fue autor del estado actual de 
Virginia (1724) donde él describió la forma distintiva de sociedad 
que emergía en Virginia de terratenientes grandes y pequeños, los 
trabajadores blancos pobres, y esclavizaron a africanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087102</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107698</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/they-that-are-born-there-talk-good-english-hugh-jones-describes-virginias-slave-society-1724</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
