<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106790</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106790</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086686</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Oh Yeah?: Herbert Hoover Predicts Prosperity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">OH- Yeah?: Herbert Staubsauger Sagt 
Wohlstand Voraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Oh Ouais ? : l'Aspirateur d'Herbert Prévoit
La Prospérité</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Oh Yeah?: O Hoover De Herbert Prediz A 
Prosperidade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'OH Yeah?: Il Hoover Del Herbert Predice La
Prosperità</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">OH ναι;: Θ*Χερψερτ Hoover Predicts 
Prosperity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Oh Sí?: La Aspiradora De Herberto Predice 
Prosperidad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On the morning of October 24, 1929 ("Black Thursday"), billions of dollars in stock value were wiped out before lunch. Prices recovered somewhat that afternoon, but the Great Crash was underway. The next day President Herbert Hoover counseled reassurance, but as stock prices continued to plummet Hoover's reassurances rang increasingly hollow. The president's efforts to reassure the public did not stop, in part as he tried to convince voters that his policies were bringing recovery. In 1932, Edward Angly published a short book filled with optimistic forecasts about the economy offered by Hoover and his associates. The sarcastic title,  Oh Yeah? , reflected his contempt for political leaders who did not seem to know what was happening to the country. These 17 quotations from or about Herbert Hoover proved that he was a poor prophet of the hard times ahead.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf dem Morgen von Oktober 24, 1929 ("schwarzer 
Donnerstag"), Milliarden Dollar im auf lagerwert wurden heraus vor dem
Mittagessen abgewischt. Preise stellten ein wenig diesen 
Nachmittag wieder her, aber der große Systemabsturz war unterwegs. 
Der am nächsten Tag Präsident Herbert Hoover riet 
Versicherung, aber, während die Aktienpreise, die fortgesetzt wurden,
um abzusinken Versicherungen des Staubsaugers, in zunehmendem Maße 
hohles schellten. Die Bemühungen des Präsidenten, der 
Öffentlichkeit zu versicheren stoppten, nicht im Teil, während er 
versuchte, Wähler zu überzeugen, daß seine politischen Richtlinien 
Wiederanlauf holten. 1932 veröffentlichte Edward Angly ein 
kurzes Buch, das mit optimistischen Prognosen über die Wirtschaft 
gefüllt wurde, die von Hoover angeboten wurde und seins verbindet. 
Der sarkastische Name, OH- Yeah? , reflektiert seiner 
Verachtung für politische Führer, die nicht schienen, zu wissen, was
dem Land geschah. Diese 17 Preisangabe oder über vom Herbert 
Staubsauger prüfte, daß er ein armer Prophet der harten Zeiten voran
war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matin octobre de 24, 1929 ("jeudi noir"), 
milliards de dollars en valeur courante ont été éliminés avant le 
déjeuner. Les prix ont récupéré en quelque sorte cet 
après-midi, mais la grande panne totale était en cours. Le 
jour suivant le Président Herbert Hoover a conseillé la 
réassurance, mais pendant que les cours des actions d'actions 
continués pour descendre les réassurances de l'aspirateur sonnaient 
de plus en plus creux. Les efforts du président de rassurer le 
public ne se sont pas arrêtés, en partie pendant qu'il essayait de 
convaincre des électeurs que ses politiques apportaient la reprise. 
En 1932, Edouard Angly a édité un livre court rempli de 
prévisions optimistes au sujet de l'économie offerte par Hoover et 
sien s'associe. Le titre sarcastique, OH ouais ? , 
reflété son mépris pour les amorces politiques qui n'ont pas 
semblé savoir ce qui arrivait au pays. Ces 17 citations ou au 
sujet d'aspirateur d'Herbert ont montré qu'il était un pauvre 
prophète des périodes difficiles en avant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na manhã outubro de 24, 1929 ("quinta-feira 
preta"), billions dos dólares no valor conservado em estoque foram 
limpados para fora antes do lunch. Os preços recuperaram um 
tanto essa tarde, mas o ruído elétrico grande era underway. No
dia seguinte o presidente Herbert Hoover aconselhou o reassurance, mas
enquanto os preços conservados em estoque continuados a plummet 
reassurances do hoover soaram cada vez mais oco. Os esforços do
presidente tranquilizar o público não pararam, na parte enquanto 
tentou convencer eleitores que suas políticas traziam a 
recuperação. Em 1932, Edward Angly publicou um livro curto 
enchido com as previsões optimistic sobre a economia oferecida por 
Hoover e his assocía. O título sarcastic, Oh yeah? , 
refletido seu contempt para os líderes políticos que não pareceram 
saber o que estava acontecendo ao país. Estas 17 citações ou 
sobre do hoover de Herbert provaram que era um prophet deficiente dos 
tempos duros adiante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sulla mattina de 24 ottobre 1929 ("giovedì 
nero"), miliardi dei dollari nel valore di riserva sono stati 
eliminati prima di pranzare. I prezzi hanno recuperato piuttosto
quel pomeriggio, ma l'arresto grande era in corso. Il giorno 
seguente il presidente Herbert Hoover ha consigliato la 
riassicurazione, ma mentre i prezzi di riserva continuati per 
discendere riassicurazioni del hoover hanno squillato sempre più 
vuoto. Gli sforzi del presidente riassicurare il pubblico non si
sono arrestati, in parte mentre ha provato a convincere gli elettori 
che le sue politiche stavano portando il recupero. In 1932, 
Edward Angly ha pubblicato un libro corto riempito di previsioni 
ottimiste circa l'economia offerta da Hoover e suo si associa. 
Il titolo sarcastic, OH yeah? , riflesso il suo contempt 
per i capi politici che non hanno sembrato conoscere che cosa 
stava accadendo al paese. Queste 17 citazioni da o circa il 
hoover del Herbert hanno dimostrato che era un povero prophet dei 
tempi duri avanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο πρωί της 24ης Οκτωβρίου ..1929 ("μαύρη 
Πέμπτη"), τα δισεκατομμύρια των δολαρίων στην αξία αποθεμάτων 
σκουπίστηκαν έξω πριν από το μεσημεριανό. Οι τιμές που 
ανακτήθηκαν κάπως εκείνο το απόγευμα, αλλά η μεγάλη συντριβή 
ήταν εν εξελίξει. Η επόμενη ημέρα ο Πρόεδρος Herbert 
Hoover συμβούλευσε τη διαβεβαίωση, αλλά δεδομένου ότι οι 
τιμές αποθεμάτων συνέχισαν να πέφτουν κατακόρυφα οι 
διαβεβαιώσεις Hoover χτύπησαν όλο και περισσότερο κοίλο. 
Οι προσπάθειες του Προέδρου να καθησυχάσει το κοινό δεν 
σταμάτησαν, εν μέρει δεδομένου ότι προσπάθησε να πείσει τους 
ψηφοφόρους ότι οι πολιτικές του έφερναν την αποκατάσταση. 
Το 1932, ο Edward Angly δημοσίευσε ένα κοντό βιβλίο
που γέμισαν με τις αισιόδοξες προβλέψεις για την οικονομία που 
προσφέρθηκε από Hoover και τους συνεταίρους του. Ο 
σαρκαστικός τίτλος, OH ναι; , απεικόνισε την περιφρόνησή
του για τους πολιτικούς ηγέτες που δεν φάνηκαν να ξέρουν τι 
συνέβαινε στη χώρα. Αυτές οι 17 αναφορές από ή για 
Herbert Hoover απέδειξαν ότι ήταν φτωχός προφήτης των 
σκληρών χρόνων μπροστά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la mañana del de octubre 24 de 1929 ("jueves 
negro"), mil millones de dólares en el valor común fueron limpiados 
hacia fuera antes de almorzar. Los precios recuperaron algo esa 
tarde, pero la gran caída estaba en curso. El presidente 
Herberto Hoover aconsejó el día siguiente reaseguro, pero como los 
precios comunes continuados para caer a plomo los reaseguros de la 
aspiradora sonaron cada vez más hueco. Los esfuerzos del 
presidente de tranquilizar al público no pararon, en parte mientras 
que él intentó convencer a votantes de que sus políticas trajeran 
la recuperación. En 1932, Edward Angly publicó un libro corto 
llenado de pronósticos optimistas sobre la economía ofrecida por 
Hoover y el suyo se asocia. ¿El título sarcástico, Oh sí? 
, reflejado su desprecio para los arranques de cinta políticos 
que no se parecían saber qué sucedía al país. Estas 17 citas
o sobre de la aspiradora de Herberto probaron que él era un profeta 
pobre de los tiempos duros a continuación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086686</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106790</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/oh-yeah-herbert-hoover-predicts-prosperity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
