<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104371</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104371</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209896</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Apothem of a Regular Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Apothem eines regelmäßigen Polygons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Apothem d'un polygone régulier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Apothem de um polygon regular</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Apothem di un poligono normale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Apothem ενός κανονικού πολυγώνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Apothem de un polígono regular</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the apothem of a regular polygon. The applet shows a regular polygon where the user can alter the number of sides and resize it by dragging any vertex. At all times, the apothem (line from center to a midpoint of a side) is drawn and it's length shown. The text on the page shows two formulae for calculating the apothem, depending on what you are give to start. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das apothem eines regelmäßigen Polygons zeigen. 
Der applet zeigt einem regelmäßigen Polygon, wo der Benutzer 
die Zahl Seiten ändern und sie die Größe neu bestimmen kann, indem 
er jeden möglichen Gipfel schleppt. Ständig ist das apothem 
(Zeile von der Mitte zu einem Mittelpunkt einer Seite) gezogen und es 
ist die gezeigte Länge. Der Text auf der Seite zeigt zwei 
Formeln für die Berechnung des apothem, abhängig von, was Sie das 
Geben sind, zum zu beginnen. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang 
für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent l'apothem d'un polygone régulier. L'applet 
montre à un polygone régulier où l'utilisateur peut modifier le 
nombre de côtés et le remettre à la côte en traînant n'importe 
quel sommet. À tout moment, l'apothem (ligne de centre à un 
point médian d'un côté) est tiré et lui est longueur montrée. 
Le texte à la page montre deux formules pour calculer 
l'apothem, selon ce que vous êtes élasticité à commencer. 
L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o apothem de um polygon regular. O applet mostra a um
polygon regular onde o usuário pode alterar o número dos lados e 
resize o arrastando todo o vertex. Em todas as vezes, o apothem 
(linha do centro a um ponto médio de um lado) é drawn e ele está a 
um comprimento mostrado. O texto na página mostra duas 
fórmulas para calcular o apothem, dependendo de o que você é 
elasticidade a começar. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho 
de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O 
depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez 
de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de 
uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il apothem di un poligono normale. Il applet mostra 
ad un poligono normale dove l'utente può alterare il numero di lati e
ridimensionarlo trascinando tutto il vertice. Sempre, il apothem
(riga dal centro ad un punto mediano di un lato) è tirato ed esso è 
lunghezza indicata. Il testo alla pagina mostra due formule per 
la calcolazione del apothem, secondo che cosa siete give da 
cominciare. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di 
schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν το apothem ενός κανονικού πολυγώνου. Το 
applet εμφανίζει κανονικό πολύγωνο όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να 
αλλάξει τον αριθμό πλευρών και να τον επαναταξινομήσει με το 
σύρσιμο οποιουδήποτε vertex. Πάντα, το apothem (γραμμή
από το κέντρο σε ένα μεσαίο σημείο μιας πλευράς) σύρεται και 
είναι μήκος που εμφανίζεται. Το κείμενο στη σελίδα 
εμφανίζει δύο τύπους για τον υπολογισμό του apothem, ανάλογα 
με αυτό που είστε δίνετε στην έναρξη. Το Applet μπορεί 
να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el apothem de un polígono regular. El applet muestra
a polígono regular donde el utilizador puede alterar el número de 
caras y volverlo a clasificar según el tamaño arrastrando cualquier 
cima. Siempre, el apothem (línea del centro a un punto mediano 
de una cara) es exhausto y él es longitud mostrada. El texto en
la paginación muestra dos fórmulas para calcular el apothem, 
dependiendo de cuál usted es elasticidad a comenzar. El applet 
se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con 
un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209896</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104371</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/apothem-of-a-regular-polygon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
