<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107279</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107279</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207131</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Journeys West</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reisen West</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voyages Occidentaux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Viagens Ocidentais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Viaggi Ad ovest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δύση ταξιδιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Viajes Del oeste</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students examine the motivations of people who traveled west during the 1800s, as well as the conditions they encountered, the conflicts between settlers and native people, and policies of the federal government. Students interpret first person narratives and choose a role for in-depth study -- a gold miner, fur trader, pioneer family, Native American, or explorer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer überprüfen die 
Beweggründe der Leute, die nach Westen während des 1800s reisten, 
sowie die Bedingungen, die sie antrafen, die $überschneidungen 
zwischen Siedleren und gebürtigen Leuten und politischen Richtlinien 
der Bundesregierung. Kursteilnehmer deuten erste 
Persondarstellungen und wählen eine Rolle für eingehende Studie -- 
ein Goldbergmann, ein Pelzhändler, eine Pionierfamilie, ein 
gebürtiger Amerikaner oder einen Forscher.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les étudiants d'aides examinent les motivations 
des personnes qui ont voyagé à l'ouest pendant le 1800s, comme les 
conditions qu'ils ont rencontrées, les conflits entre les colons et 
les indigènes, et les politiques du gouvernement fédéral. Les
étudiants interprètent les premiers récits de personne et 
choisissent un rôle pour l'étude appronfondie -- un mineur d'or, un 
commerçant de fourrure, une famille pionnière, un Américain 
indigène, ou un explorateur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os estudantes das ajudas examinam os motivations 
dos povos que viajaram para o oeste durante o 1800s, assim como as 
circunstâncias que encontraram, os conflitos entre settlers e povos 
nativos, e políticas do governo federal. Os estudantes 
interpretam primeiras narrativas da pessoa e escolhem um papel para o 
estudo in-depth -- um mineiro do ouro, um comerciante da pele, uma 
família pioneira, um americano nativo, ou um explorador.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli allievi di aiuti esaminano le motivazioni 
della gente che ha viaggiato verso ovest durante il 1800s, come pure 
le circostanze che hanno incontrato, i conflitti fra i settlers e le 
popolazioni autoctone e le politiche del governo federale. Gli 
allievi interpretano le prime descrizioni della persona e scelgono un 
ruolo per lo studio approfondito -- un minatore dell'oro, un 
commerciante della pelliccia, una famiglia pionieristica, un americano
natale, o un esploratore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να εξετάσουν τα κίνητρα των 
ανθρώπων που ταξίδεψαν τη δύση κατά τη διάρκεια του 1800s, 
καθώς επίσης και των όρων που αντιμετώπισαν, οι συγκρούσεις 
μεταξύ των αποίκων και των εγγενών ανθρώπων, και πολιτικές της 
ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης. Οι σπουδαστές ερμηνεύουν τα πρώτα
αφηγήματα προσώπων και επιλέγουν έναν ρόλο για τη σε βάθος 
μελέτη -- ένας χρυσή ανθρακωρύχος, ένας έμπορος γουνών, μια 
οικογένεια πρωτοπόρων, ένας εγγενής Αμερικανός, ή ένας 
εξερευνητής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los estudiantes de las ayudas examinan las 
motivaciones de la gente que viajó al oeste durante el 1800s, tan 
bien como las condiciones que encontraron, los conflictos entre los 
colonos y los indígenas, y las políticas del gobierno federal. 
Los estudiantes interpretan las primeras narrativas de la 
persona y eligen un papel del estudio profundizado -- un minero del 
oro, un comerciante de la piel, una familia pionera, un americano 
nativo, o explorador.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207131</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107279</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/journeys-west</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
