<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106070</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106070</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086147</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Facts . . . Are the Only Arsenal": Information and the  War Cyclopedia  in World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Tatsachen. . . Sind das einzige
Arsenal ": Informationen und der Krieg Cyclopedia im Ersten 
Weltkrieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"faits. . . Sont le seul arsenal
": L'information et la guerre Cyclopedia dans la Première 
Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"fatos. . . É o único arsenal 
": Informação e a guerra Cyclopedia no world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"fatti. . . È l'unico arsenale 
": Le informazioni e la guerra Cyclopedia nel world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γεγονότα. .. Είναι το μόνο οπλοστάσιο ": 
Πληροφορίες και ο πόλεμος Cyclopedia στον παγκόσμιο 
πόλεμο Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"hechos. . . Es el único 
arsenal ": Información y la guerra Cyclopedia en Primera Guerra
Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When the United States entered World War I in 1917, many Americans viciously attacked the loyalty of German Americans, attacks that were in some ways supported by the federal government. President Woodrow Wilson sponsored a campaign to reverse the German influence on American academia, and an effort to erase favorable depictions of Germany from the nation's textbooks resulted in the  War Cyclopedia ,written by a number of distinguished historians. In this 325-page reference handbook, "the attempt to portray propaganda as scholarship reached its fullest expression," writes historian Carol Gruber. The Committee on Public Information (CPI), the government's official propaganda agency during the first world war, printed more than eight hundred thousand copies for use in American schools.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als die Vereinigten Staaten den Ersten Weltkrieg 
1917 eintrugen, nahmen viele Amerikaner viciously die Loyalität der 
deutschen Amerikaner, Angriffe in Angriff, die irgendwie durch die 
Bundesregierung unterstützt wurden. Präsident Woodrow Wilson 
förderte eine Kampagne, um den deutschen Einfluß auf amerikanische 
Akademie aufzuheben, und eine Bemühung, vorteilhafte Beschreibungen 
von Deutschland von den Lehrbüchern der Nation zu löschen ergab den 
Krieg Cyclopedia, geschrieben durch eine Anzahl von bemerkenswerten 
Historikern. In diesem Handbuch des Bezugs 325-page "der 
Versuch, Propaganda zu schildern, da Gelehrsamkeit seinen vollsten 
Ausdruck erreichte," schreibt Historiker Lied Gruber. Der 
Ausschuß für allgemeine Informationen (CPI), die 
Regierungsbeamt-Propagandaagentur während des ersten Weltkrieges, 
druckte mehr als acht hundert tausend Exemplare für Gebrauch in den 
amerikanischen Schulen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand les Etats-Unis ont écrit la Première 
Guerre Mondiale en 1917, beaucoup d'Américains ont viciously attaqué
la fidélité des Américains allemands, les attaques qui par certains
côtés ont été supportées par le gouvernement fédéral. Le 
Président Woodrow Wilson a commandité une campagne pour renverser 
l'influence allemande sur le milieu universitaire américain, et un 
effort d'effacer des descriptions favorables de l'Allemagne des 
manuels de la nation a eu comme conséquence la guerre Cyclopedia, 
écrit par un certain nombre d'historiens distingués. En ce 
manuel de la référence 325-page, "la tentative de dépeindre la 
propagande car la bourse a atteint sa plus pleine expression," écrit 
la hymne de louange Gruber d'historien. Le comité de 
l'information publique (CPI), l'agence de propagande du fonctionnaire 
de gouvernement pendant la première guerre mondiale, a imprimé plus 
d'huit cents mille copies pour l'usage dans les écoles américaines.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando os estados unidos incorporaram o 
world.war.i a 1917, muitos americanos atacaram viciously a lealdade de
americanos alemães, os ataques que estavam em algumas maneiras 
suportadas pelo governo federal. O presidente Woodrow Wilson 
patrocinou uma campanha para inverter a influência alemão no 
academia americano, e um esforço apagar depictions favoráveis de 
Germany dos textbooks da nação resultou na guerra Cyclopedia, 
escrito por um número distintos de historians. Neste manual da 
referência 325-page, "a tentativa de portray o propaganda porque o 
scholarship alcançou sua expressão mais cheia," escreve o carol 
Gruber do historian. O comitê na informação pública (CPI), a
agência do propaganda do oficial de governo durante a primeira guerra
de mundo, imprimiu mais de oito cem mil cópias para o uso em escolas 
americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando unito Dichiara il world.war.i 
inserito in 1917, molti Americani viciously hanno attacato la lealtà 
degli Americani tedeschi, attacchi che per alcuni versi sono stati 
sostenuti dal governo federale. Il presidente Woodrow Wilson ha 
patrocinato una campagna per invertire l'influenza tedesca 
sull'accademia americana e uno sforzo cancellare i depictions 
favorevoli della Germania dai manuali della nazione ha provocato la 
guerra Cyclopedia, scritto da un certo numero di storici distinti. 
In questo manuale di riferimento 325-page, "il tentativo di 
ritrarre la propaganda poichè la borsa ha raggiunto la relativa 
espressione più completa," scrive il carol Gruber dello storico. 
Il comitato delle informazioni pubbliche (caratteri per 
pollice), l'agenzia di propaganda del funzionario del governo durante 
la prima guerra mondiale, ha stampato più di ottocento mila copie per
uso in scuole americane.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες εισήγαγαν τον παγκόσμιο 
πόλεμο Ι το 1917, πολλοί Αμερικανοί επιτέθηκαν viciously 
στην πίστη γερμανικών Αμερικανών, επιθέσεις που με κάποιους 
τρόπους υποστηρίζω από την ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση. Ο 
Πρόεδρος Woodrow Wilson υποστήριξε μια εκστρατεία για να 
αντιστρέψει τη γερμανική επιρροή στον αμερικανικό ακαδημαϊκό 
κόσμο, και μια προσπάθεια να σβηθούν τα ευνοϊκά depictions της
Γερμανίας από τα εγχειρίδια του έθνους οδήγησε στον πόλεμο 
Cyclopedia, που γράφτηκε από διάφορους διακεκριμένους 
ιστορικούς. Σε αυτό το εγχειρίδιο αναφοράς 325-σελίδων, "η 
προσπάθεια να απεικονιστεί η προπαγάνδα ως υποτροφία που 
επιτυγχάνεται την πληρέστερη έκφρασή της," γράφει τον ιστορικό 
Carol Gruber. Η Επιτροπή των δημόσιων πληροφοριών 
(ΔΤΚ), η αντιπροσωπεία κυβερνητικής επίσημη προπαγάνδας κατά τη 
διάρκεια του πρώτου παγκόσμιου πολέμου, τύπωσε περισσότερα από 
οκτακόσιες χιλιάες αντίγραφα για τη χρήση στα αμερικανικά 
σχολεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando los Estados Unidos incorporaron Primera 
Guerra Mundial a 1917, muchos americanos viciously atacaron la lealtad
de americanos alemanes, los ataques que estaban de algunas maneras 
utilizadas por el gobierno federal. Presidente Woodrow Wilson 
patrocinó una campaña para invertir la influencia alemana en la 
academia americana, y un esfuerzo de borrar pinturas favorables de 
Alemania de los libros de textos de la nación dio lugar a la guerra 
Cyclopedia, escrito por un número de historiadores distinguidos. 
En este manual de la referencia 325-page, "la tentativa de 
retratar propaganda como la beca alcanzó su expresión más 
completa," escribe el carol Gruber del historiador. El comité 
sobre la información pública (CPI), la agencia de la propaganda del 
oficial del gobierno durante la primera guerra mundial, imprimió más
de ocho cientos mil copias para el uso en escuelas americanas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086147</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106070</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/facts-are-the-only-arsenal-information-and-the-war-cyclopedia-in-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
