<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107374</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107374</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974012</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Feeding Minds Fighting Hunger Curriculum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Einziehen Kümmert Sich, Hunger-Lehrplan Zu 
kämpfen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Alimentation S'occupe de combattre Le Programme 
d'études de Faim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alimentar Ocupa-se Lutar O Curriculum Da Fome</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programma di studi D'Alimentazione Di Fame Di 
Combattimento Di Menti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σίτιση απασχολεί το πρόγραμμα σπουδών πείνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Alimentación Importa El Luchar De Plan de 
estudios Del Hambre</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Feeding Minds Fighting Hunger is designed to help equip and encourage teachers, students and young people all over the world to actively participate in creating a world free from hunger. You will find lesson modules for teachers, resources and activities for young people and an interactive forum for exchanging information and experiences around the world. Armed with knowledge and motivated to take action, we can all play an important role in ending hunger. Join us in making hunger history.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Business</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>ar</language>
          <language>zh</language>
          <language>fr</language>
          <language>it</language>
          <language>pt</language>
          <language>ru</language>
          <language>es</language>
          <language>sw</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einziehend kümmert sich, Hunger zu kämpfen ist 
konzipiert zu helfen ausrüsten und anregen Lehrer, Kursteilnehmer und
junge Leute auf der ganzen Erde, aktiv teilzunehmen, an, eine Welt 
frei herzustellen vom Hunger. Sie finden Lektionmodule für 
Lehrer, Betriebsmittel und Aktivitäten für junge Leute und ein 
interaktives Forum für das Austauschen von von Informationen und 
Erfahrungen um die Welt. Bewaffnet mit Wissen und motiviert, um 
Maßnahmen zu ergreifen, können wir alles Spiel eine wichtige Rolle 
im Endehunger. Verbinden Sie uns, wenn Sie Hungergeschichte 
bilden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Alimentant s'occupe de combattre la faim est 
conçu pour aider équipent et encouragent des professeurs, des 
étudiants et des jeunes partout dans le monde à participer 
activement à créer un monde librement de la faim. Vous 
trouverez des modules de leçon pour des professeurs, des ressources 
et des activités pour des jeunes et un forum interactif pour permuter
l'information et des expériences autour du monde. Armé avec la
connaissance et motivé pour agir, nous pouvons tout jouer un rôle 
important dans la faim de fin. Joignez-nous en faisant 
l'histoire de faim.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alimentando ocupa-se lutar a fome é projetado 
ajudar equipam e incentivam professores, estudantes e povos novos toda
sobre o mundo participar ativamente em criar um mundo livre da fome. 
Você encontrará os módulos da lição para professores, 
recursos e atividades para povos novos e um forum interativo para 
trocar a informação e experiências em torno do mundo. Armado 
com o conhecimento e motivated para fazer exame da ação, nós 
podemos todo o jogo um papel importante na fome do ending. 
Junte-nos em fazer o history da fome.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le menti d'alimentazione la fame di Combattimento 
che è destinata per aiutare dotano e consigliano agli insegnanti, 
agli allievi ed ai giovani dappertutto attivamente partecipare a 
creare un mondo liberamente da fame. Troverete i moduli di 
lezione per gli insegnanti, risorse ed attività per i giovani e una 
tribuna interattiva per lo scambio delle informazioni ed esperienze 
intorno al mondo. Munito con conoscenza e motivato per agire, 
possiamo tutto il gioco un ruolo importante nella fame di conclusione.
Uniscali nel fare la storia di fame.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σίτιση απασχολεί την πείνα έχει ως σκοπό να 
βοηθήσει να εξοπλίσει και να ενθαρρύνει τους δασκάλους, τους 
σπουδαστές και τους νέους σε όλο τον κόσμο για να συμμετέχει 
ενεργά στη δημιουργία ενός κόσμου απαλλαγμένου από την πείνα. 
Θα βρείτε τις ενότητες μαθήματος για τους δασκάλους, τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και τις δραστηριότητες για τους νέους και 
ένα διαλογικό φόρουμ για την ανταλλαγή των πληροφοριών και την 
εμπειρία σε όλο τον κόσμο. Οπλισμένοι με τη γνώση και 
παρακινημένοι για να λάβουν μέτρα, μπορούμε όλοι να 
διαδραματίσουμε έναν σημαντικό ρόλο στο τελείωμα της πείνας. 
Μας ενώστε στην παραγωγή της ιστορίας πείνας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alimentando importa el luchar de hambre se diseña
ayudar equipan y animan a profesores, a estudiantes y a gente joven 
todo sobre el mundo que participen activamente en crear un mundo 
libremente de hambre. Usted encontrará los módulos de la 
lección para los profesores, los recursos y las actividades para la 
gente joven y un foro interactivo para intercambiar la información y 
las experiencias alrededor del mundo. Armado con conocimiento y 
motivado para tomar la acción, podemos todo el juego un papel 
importante en hambre del conclusión. Ensámblenos en la 
fabricación de historia del hambre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschäft</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Affaires</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Negócio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Commercio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιχείρηση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Negocio</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974012</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107374</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/feeding-minds-fighting-hunger-curriculum</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
