<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105763</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105763</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203290</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Igneous Rocks Tour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eruptivgestein-Tour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Excursion de Roches Plutoniques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Excursão Das Rochas Igneous</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giro Delle Rocce eruttive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γύρος πύρινων βράχων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Viaje De las Rocas Ígneas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This module is designed to allow students to learn about igneous rocks at their own speed using images of hand samples and rock outcrops in their natural settings. Topics covered include the common igneous rock types, igneous textures, and intrusive rock bodies. Each topic has instructive text and several images. The site also features a self-quiz with 17 questions about 12 hand sample pictures. This site provides useful reference material suitable for high school or introductory college students. This resource is part of the Teaching Petrology collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Modul ist konzipiert, um Kursteilnehmern zu
erlauben, über Eruptivgesteine mit ihrer eigenen Geschwindigkeit mit 
Bildern der Handproben und des Felsenzutageliegens in ihren 
natürlichen Einstellungen zu erlernen. Die umfaßten Themen 
schließen die geläufigen Eruptivgesteintypen, die 
Eruptivbeschaffenheiten und aufdringlichen die Felsenkörper ein. 
Jedes Thema hat lehrreichen Text und einige Bilder. Die 
Site kennzeichnet auch einen Selbst-Quiz mit 17 Fragen über 12 
Handbeispielabbildungen. Diese Site stellt das nützliche 
Bezugsmaterial zur Verfügung, das für High School oder einleitende 
Studenten verwendbar ist. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der 
unterrichtenden Petrologyansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module est conçu pour permettre à des 
étudiants de se renseigner sur les roches plutoniques à leur propre 
vitesse en utilisant des images des échantillons de main et des 
affleurements rocheux dans leurs configurations normales. Les 
sujets couverts incluent les types communs de roche plutonique, les 
textures ignées, et les corps intrusifs de roche. Chaque sujet 
a le texte instructif et plusieurs images. Le site comporte 
également un art de l'auto-portrait-quiz avec 17 questions environ 12 images 
témoin de main. Ce site fournit la documentation de référence
utile appropriée pour le lycée ou les étudiants d'université 
préliminaires. Cette ressource fait partie de la collection 
d'enseignement 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html de 
petrology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo é projetado permitir que os 
estudantes aprendam sobre rochas igneous em sua própria velocidade 
usando imagens de amostras da mão e de outcrops de rocha em seus 
ajustes naturais. Os tópicos cobertos incluem os tipos comuns 
da rocha igneous, as texturas igneous, e os corpos intrusive da rocha.
Cada tópico tem o texto instructive e as diversas imagens. 
O local caracteriza também um self-self-quiz com 17 perguntas 
aproximadamente 12 retratos da amostra da mão. Este local 
fornece o material de referência útil apropriado para a High School 
ou estudantes de faculdade introdutórios. Este recurso é parte
da coleção ensinando 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html da 
petrologia</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo è destinato per permettere che gli 
allievi imparino circa le rocce eruttive alla loro propria velocità 
usando le immagini dei campioni della mano e degli affioramenti 
rocciosi nelle loro regolazioni naturali. I soggetti coperti 
includono i tipi comuni della roccia eruttiva, le strutture ignee ed i
corpi intrusivi della roccia. Ogni soggetto ha il testo 
istruttivo e parecchie immagini. Il luogo egualmente 
caratterizza un auto-quiz con 17 domande circa 12 immagini del 
campione della mano. Questo luogo fornisce il materiale di 
riferimento utile adatto per la High School o gli allievi di 
università introduttivi. Questa risorsa fa parte 
dell'accumulazione d'istruzione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html di 
petrology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα έχει ως σκοπό να επιτρέψει στους 
σπουδαστές για να μάθει για τους πύρινους βράχους με την 
ταχύτητά τους χρησιμοποιώντας τις εικόνες των δειγμάτων χεριών 
και των επανθίσεων βράχου στις φυσικές τιμές των παραμέτρων τους.
Τα θέματα που καλύπτονται περιλαμβάνουν τους κοινούς τύπους
πύρινου βράχου, τις πύρινες συστάσεις, και τους παρεισφρητικούς 
οργανισμούς βράχου. Κάθε θέμα έχει το διδακτικό κείμενο 
και διάφορες εικόνες. Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει επίσης έναν 
μόνος-διαγωνισμό γνώσεων με 17 ερωτήσεις για 12 εικόνες 
δειγμάτων χεριών. Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει το χρήσιμο υλικό
αναφοράς κατάλληλο για το γυμνάσιο ή τους εισαγωγικούς 
σπουδαστές κολλεγίων. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι 
μέρος της συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html 
πετρολογίας διδασκαλίας</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo se diseña para permitir que los 
estudiantes aprendan sobre rocas ígneas a su propia velocidad usando 
imágenes de las muestras de la mano y de los afloramientos de roca en
sus configuraciones naturales. Los asuntos cubiertos incluyen 
los tipos comunes de la roca ígnea, las texturas ígneas, y los 
cuerpos intrusos de la roca. Cada asunto tiene el texto 
instructivo y varias imágenes. El sitio también ofrece un uno 
mismo-concurso con 17 preguntas cerca de 12 cuadros de la muestra de 
la mano. Este sitio proporciona al material de referencia útil 
conveniente para la High School secundaria o los estudiantes de 
universidad introductorios. Este recurso es parte de la 
colección de enseñanza 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html de la 
petrología</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203290</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105763</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/igneous-rocks-tour</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
