<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104959</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104959</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206810</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kingston, New York: A National Register of Historic Places Travel Itinerary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kingston, New York: Eine Einwohnermeldeliste
des historischen Platz-Spielraum-Reisewegs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Kingston, New York : Un registre national 
d'itinéraire historique de voyage d'endroits</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Kingston, New York: Um registo nacional do 
itinerary historic do curso dos lugares</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Kingston, New York: Un registro nazionale 
dell'itinerario storico di corsa dei posti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κίνγκστον, Νέα Υόρκη: Ένας εθνικός κατάλογος 
της ιστορικής περιήγησης ταξιδιού θέσεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Kingston, Nueva York: Un registro nacional 
del itinerario histórico del recorrido de los lugares</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores Kingston's over 300 years of history using 24 historic places that recall past eras when settlers and Native Americans warily shared its plains, proud Revolutionaries and angry British armies walked its narrow streets and when coal, limestone and even patent medicines flowed along its canals. The Dutch established Kingston 1652 and it became an active participant in the American Revolution and a major river-port during New York's 19th-century canal and steamboat era.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht Kingstons über 300 Jahren Geschichte 
mit 24 historischen Plätzen, die hinter Ären, als Siedleren und 
gebürtige Amerikaner warily seine Ebenen teilten, stolze 
Revolutionäre wiederaufrufen und verärgerte britische Armeen gingen 
seine schmalen Straßen und als Kohle, Kalkstein und sogar 
Patentmedizin entlang seine Kanäle flossen. Die Holländer 
stellten Kingston 1652 her und es wurde ein aktiver Teilnehmer an die 
amerikanische Umdrehung und ein HauptFluss-kanal während der Kanal- 
und steamboatära 19th-century New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore Kingston sur 300 ans d'histoire en 
utilisant 24 endroits historiques qui se rappellent après des ères 
quand les colons et les Américains indigènes ont warily partagé ses
plaines, les révolutionnaires fiers et les armées britanniques 
fâchées ont marché ses rues étroites et où le charbon, la pierre 
à chaux et même les spécialités pharmaceutiques ont coulé le long
de ses canaux. Le Néerlandais a établi Kingston 1652 et c'est 
devenu un participant actif à la révolution américaine et un 
fleuve-port important pendant l'ère de canal et de bateau à vapeur du 
19th-century de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora Kingston sobre 300 anos do history usando 
24 lugares historic que recordam após as eras quando os settlers e os
americanos nativos compartilharam warily de suas planícies, 
revolucionários orgulhosos e os exércitos britânicos irritados 
andaram suas ruas estreitas e em que o carvão, a pedra calcária e 
mesmo as medicinas de patente fluíram ao longo de seus canais. 
O dutch estabeleceu Kingston 1652 e transformou-se um 
participant ativo na volta americana e uma rio-porta principal durante
a era do canal e do steamboat de 19th-century de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora Kingston in 300 anni di storia usando 24 
posti storici che ricordano oltre le ere quando i settlers e gli 
Americani natali warily hanno ripartito le relative pianure, 
rivoluzionari fieri e gli eserciti britannici arrabbiati hanno 
camminato le relative vie strette ed in cui il carbone, il calcare e 
perfino le medicine di brevetto hanno fluito lungo i relativi canali. 
Il dutch ha stabilito Kingston 1652 e si è transformato in in 
un partecipante attivo alla rivoluzione americana ed in una 
fiume-porta importante durante l'era del canale e dello steamboat di 
19th-century de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά 300 έτη του Κίνγκστον πάνω από ιστορίας 
χρησιμοποιώντας 24 ιστορικές θέσεις που υπενθυμίζουν τις 
προηγούμενες εποχές όταν μοιράστηκαν warily οι άποικοι και 
εγγενείς Αμερικανοί τις πεδιάδες του, υπερήφανο Revolutionaries
και οι ι βρετανικοί στρατοί περπάτησαν τις στενές οδούς του και 
όταν έρευσαν ο άνθρακας, ο ασβεστόλιθος και ακόμη και τα φάρμακα
διπλωμάτων ευρεσιτεχνίας κατά μήκος των καναλιών του. Οι 
Ολλανδοί καθιέρωσαν το Κίνγκστον 1652 και έγινε ενεργός 
συμμετέχων στην αμερικανική επανάσταση και ένας σημαντικός 
ποταμός-λιμένας κατά τη διάρκεια της εποχής καναλιών και 
ατμοπλοίων 19$ος-αιώνα της Νέας Υόρκης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora Kingston sobre 300 años de historia 
usando 24 lugares históricos que recuerden más allá de las eras 
cuando los colonos y los americanos nativos warily compartieron sus 
llanos, los revolucionarios orgullosos y los ejércitos británicos 
enojados recorrieron sus calles estrechas y en que el carbón, la 
piedra caliza e incluso los específicos fluyeron a lo largo de sus 
canales. El holandés estableció Kingston 1652 y se convirtió 
en un participante activo en la revolución americana y un ri'o-acceso
importante durante la era del canal y del steamboat de 19th-century de
Nueva York.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206810</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104959</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/kingston-new-york-a-national-register-of-historic-places-travel-itinerary</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
