<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108171</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108171</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973939</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Pavlov's Dog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Hund Pavlovs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Le Chien de Pavlov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Cão De Pavlov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Cane Del Pavlov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Σκυλί Pavlov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Perro De Pavlov</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! In this game, you will find out if you can train a dog to drool on command! Ivan Pavlov's description on how animals (and humans) can be trained to respond in a certain way to a particular stimulus, has drawn a tremendous amount of interest ever since he first presented his findings. His work paved the way for a new and objective method of studying animal and human behavior.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
In diesem Spiel finden Sie heraus, wenn Sie einen Hund ausbilden
können, um auf Befehl zu geifern! Ivan Pavlovs Beschreibung 
auf, wie Tiere (und Menschen) ausgebildet werden können, um in einer 
bestimmten Methode auf einen bestimmten Auslöseimpuls zu reagieren, 
hat eine enorme Zinshöhe gezeichnet, seitdem er zuerst seine 
Entdeckungen darstellte. Seine Arbeit pflasterte die Methode 
für eine neue und objektive Methode des Studierens des Tier- und 
menschlichen Verhaltens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Dans ce 
jeu, vous découvrirez si vous pouvez former un chien pour radoter sur
la commande ! La description d'Ivan Pavlov sur la façon dont 
des animaux (et les humains) peuvent être formés pour répondre 
d'une certaine voie à un stimulus particulier, a dessiné un taux 
d'intérêt énorme jamais depuis qu'il a présenté la première fois
ses résultats. Son travail a préparé le terrain pour une 
nouvelle et objective méthode d'étudier le comportement animal et 
humain.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Neste 
jogo, você encontrará para fora se você puder treinar um cão para 
drool no comando! A descrição de Ivan Pavlov em como os 
animais (e os seres humanos) podem ser treinados para responder em uma
determinada maneira a um stimulus particular, desenhou uma quantidade 
de interesse tremenda sempre desde que apresentou primeiramente seus 
findings. Seu trabalho pavimentou a maneira para um método novo
e objetivo de estudar o comportamento animal e humano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! In questo gioco, scoprirete se
potete addestrare un cane per drool sul comando! La descrizione 
di Ivan Pavlov su come gli animali (ed esseri umani) possono essere 
addestrati per rispondere in un determinato modo ad uno stimolo 
particolare, ha dissipato una quantità tremenda di interesse da 
quando in primo luogo ha presentato i suoi risultati. Il suo 
lavoro ha aperto la strada per un nuovo e metodo obiettivo di studiare
il comportamento animale ed umano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Σε 
αυτό το παιχνίδι, θα ανακαλύψετε εάν μπορείτε να εκπαιδεύσετε 
ένα σκυλί στο drool στην εντολή! Η περιγραφή Pavlov 
Ivan στον τρόπο με τον οποίο τα ζώα (και άνθρωποι) μπορούν να 
εκπαιδευθούν για να αποκριθούν με έναν ορισμένο τρόπο σε ένα 
ιδιαίτερο ερέθισμα, έχει σύρει ένα τεράστιο ποσό ενδιαφέροντος
από τότε που παρουσίασε αρχικά τα συμπεράσματά του. Η 
εργασία του προετοιμάζω το έδαφος για μια νέα και αντικειμενική 
μέθοδο τη ζωική και ανθρώπινη συμπεριφορά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! ¡En este
juego, usted descubrirá si usted puede entrenar a un perro para drool
en comando! La descripción de Ivan Pavlov en cómo los animales
(y los seres humanos) pueden ser entrenados para responder de cierta 
manera a un estímulo determinado, ha trazado una enorme cantidad de 
interés desde entonces él primero presentara sus resultados. 
Su trabajo pavimentó la manera para un nuevo y objetivo método
de estudiar el comportamiento animal y humano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973939</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108171</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-pavlov-s-dog</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
