<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104887</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104887</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087294</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A. F. of L. Delegates.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">A. F. von L. Delegates.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">A. F. de L. Delegates.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A. F. de L. Delegar.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A. F. di L. Delegates.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Α. Φ. Λ. Delegates.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A. F. de L. Delegates.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Faced with stiff business opposition, a conservative political climate, hostile courts, and declining membership, leaders of the American Federeration of Labor (AFL) grew increasingly cautious during the 1920s. Labor radicals viewed AFL leaders as overpaid, self-interested functionaries uninterested in organizing unorganized workers into unions. A cartoon by William Gropper published in the Communist Yiddish newspaper  Freiheit  (and reprinted in English in the  New Masses ) caricatures delegates to a 1926 AFL convention in Atlantic City. Well</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gegenübergestellt mit steifer Geschäft Opposition, einem
konservativen politischen Klima, feindlichen Gerichten und abfallender
Mitgliedschaft, wuchsen Führer des Amerikaners Federeration der 
Arbeit (AFL) während der zwanziger Jahre Arbeitsradikale gesehenen 
AFL Führer wie overpaid, die self-interested Beamten in zunehmendem 
Maße vorsichtig, die uninterested sind, beim Organisieren unorganized
Arbeiter in Anschlüße. Eine Karikatur durch William Gropper 
veröffentlichte in den kommunistischen Yiddish Zeitung Freiheit (und 
neugedruckt auf englisch in den neuen Massen) Karikaturdelegierten zu 
einer 1926 AFL Versammlung in Atlantic City. Vertiefung</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Confronté à l'opposition raide d'affaires, à un climat 
politique conservateur, aux cours hostiles, et à l'adhésion en 
baisse, les amorces de l'Américain Federeration du travail (AFL) se 
sont développées de plus en plus prudentes pendant les amorces 
visualisées par radicaux de travail des années 20 AFL comme ont 
sur-payé, des fonctionnaires de art de l'auto-portrait-interested indifférents en 
organisant les ouvriers mal organisés en syndicats. Un dessin 
animé par William Gropper a édité dans les délégués communistes 
de caricatures de Freiheit de journal de Yiddish (et réimprimé en 
anglais dans les nouvelles masses) à une convention de 1926 AFL à 
Atlantic City. Puits</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enfrentado com oposição dura do negócio, um clima 
político conservador, cortes hostis, e sociedade declinando, os 
líderes do americano Federeration do trabalho (AFL) cresceram cada 
vez mais cautelosos durante os líderes vistos dos 1920s. radicais 
labor AFL como overpaid, os functionaries self-interested uninterested
em organizar unorganized trabalhadores em uniões. Um cartoon 
por William Gropper publicou nos delegados comunistas dos caricatures 
de Freiheit do jornal de Yiddish (e reprinted em inglês nas massas 
novas) a uma convenção de 1926 AFL na cidade atlantic. Poço</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Affrontato ad opposizione rigida di affari, ad un clima 
politico conservatore, alle corti ostili ed all'insieme dei membri 
declinante, i capi del Federeration americano del Lavoro 
(AFL) si sono sviluppati sempre più prudenti durante i capi 
osservati radicali Di lavoro degli anni 20 AFL come overpaid, 
functionaries self-interested uninterested nell'organizzazione 
unorganized gli operai nei sindacati. Un fumetto da William 
Gropper ha pubblicato nei delegati comunisti dei caricatures di 
Freiheit del giornale di Yiddish (e ristampato in inglese nelle nuove 
masse) ad una convenzione di 1926 AFL a Atlantic City. Pozzo</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αντιμέτωποι με τη δύσκαμπτη επιχειρησιακή αντίθεση, 
ένα συντηρητικό πολιτικό κλίμα, εχθρικά δικαστήρια, και μια 
μειωμένος ιδιότητα μέλους, οι ηγέτες του αμερικανικού 
Federeration της εργασίας (AFL) έγιναν όλο και περισσότερο 
προσεκτικοί κατά τη διάρκεια των εμφανισμένων ριζοσπάστες ηγετών
AFL εργασίας της δεκαετίας του '20 όπως υπερπληρώνονται, 
μόνος-ενδιαφερόμενοι αξιωματούχοι αδιάφοροι στην οργάνωση των 
ανοργάνωτων εργαζομένων στις ενώσεις. Κινούμενα σχέδια από
William Gropper δημοσίευσαν στις κομμουνιστικές γίντις 
καρικατούρες Freiheit εφημερίδων (και ανατυπωμένος στα αγγλικά 
στις νέες μάζες) τους εκπροσώπους σε μια σύμβαση AFL του 
1926 στην Ατλάντικ Σίτυ. Καλά</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hecho frente con la oposición derecha del negocio, un 
clima político conservador, las cortes hostiles, y calidad de miembro
que declinaba, los arranques de cinta del americano Federeration del 
trabajo (AFL) crecieron cada vez más cautelosos durante los arranques
de cinta vistos los radicales de trabajo de los años 20 AFL como 
pagaron en exceso, los functionaries self-interested desinteresados en
la ordenación unorganized a trabajadores en uniones. Una 
historieta de Guillermo Gropper publicó en los delegados comunistas 
de los caricatures de Freiheit del periódico de Yiddish (y reimpreso 
en inglés en las nuevas masas) a una convención de 1926 AFL en 
Atlantic City. Receptor de papel</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087294</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104887</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-f-of-l-delegates</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
