<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206578</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lincoln/Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lincoln/Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lincoln/Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lincoln/Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lincoln/Net</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λίνκολν/δίκτυο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lincoln/Net</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents writings, speeches, and materials from Abraham Lincoln's years in Illinois (1830-1861). Biographical materials look at Lincoln's boyhood, Indian wars, the Whig Party, the Mexican War, the Republican Party, and the 1859-61 campaign. Themes include economic development, frontier settlement, racial attitudes, politics, religion and culture, and social relations of the era. Lesson plans focus on the Lincoln-Douglas debates, anti-slavery movement, Black Hawk War, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Schreiben, Reden und Materialien Abraham 
Lincolns von den Jahren in Illinois dar (1830-1861). 
Biographische Materialien betrachten Knabenalter Lincolns, 
indische Kriege, die Whig-Partei, den mexikanischen Krieg, die
Republikanische Partei und die Kampagne 1859-61. Themen schließen 
ökonomische Entwicklung, Grenzregelung, rassische Haltung, Politik, 
Religion und Kultur und Sozialrelationen der Ära ein. Lektion 
plant Fokus auf den Lincoln-Douglas Debatten, der Anti-Sklaverei 
Bewegung, schwarzen dem Falke-Krieg und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente des écritures, des discours, et des 
matériaux des années d'Abraham Lincoln en Illinois (1830-1861). 
Les matériaux biographiques regardent la jeunesse de Lincoln, 
les guerres indiennes, la partie de libéral, la guerre mexicaine, la 
partie républicaine, et la campagne 1859-61. Les thèmes 
incluent le développement économique, le règlement de frontière, 
les attitudes raciales, la politique, la religion et la culture, et 
les relations sociales de l'ère. La leçon projette le foyer 
sur les discussions de Lincoln-Douglas, le mouvement d'anti-esclavage,
la guerre noire de faucon, et les plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta escritas, discursos, e materiais dos 
anos de Abraham Lincoln em Illinois (1830-1861). Os materiais 
biographical olham o boyhood de Lincoln, guerras indian, o partido de 
whig, a guerra mexicana, o partido republicano, e a campanha 1859-61. 
Os temas incluem o desenvolvimento econômico, o posto 
avançado, atitudes raciais, política, religião e cultura, e 
relações sociais da era. A lição planeia o foco nos debates 
de Lincoln-Douglas, no movimento do anti-anti-slavery, na guerra preta
do falcão, e no mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta le scritture, i discorsi ed i materiali 
dagli anni di Abraham Lincoln nell'Illinois (1830-1861). I 
materiali biographical guardano il boyhood de Lincoln, le guerre 
indiane, il partito di whig, la guerra messicana, il partito 
Repubblicano e la campagna 1859-61. I temi includono lo sviluppo 
economico, stabilimento di frontiera, atteggiamenti razziali, 
politica, religione e coltura e rapporti sociali dell'era. La 
lezione progetta il fuoco sui dibattiti della Lincoln-Douglas, sul 
movimento di anti-anti-slavery, sulla guerra nera del hawk e sui più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις γραφές, τις ομιλίες, και τα υλικά από
τα έτη του Abraham Λίνκολν στο Ιλλινόις (1830-1861). Τα
βιογραφικά υλικά εξετάζουν την παιδική ηλικία του Λίνκολν, τους 
ινδικούς πολέμους, το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος Whig, το μεξικάνικο 
πόλεμο, το δημοκρατικό κόμμα, και την εκστρατεία 1859-61. 
Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν την οικονομική ανάπτυξη, τη 
συνοριακή τακτοποίηση, τις φυλετικές τοποθετήσεις, την πολιτική, 
τη θρησκεία και τον πολιτισμό, και τις κοινωνικές σχέσεις της 
εποχής. Τα σχέδια μαθήματος εστιάζουν στις 
Λίνκολν-Ντάγκλας συζητήσεις, ενάντια στη δουλεία μετακίνηση, 
μαύρος πόλεμος γερακιών, και περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta escrituras, discursos, y los materiales a
partir de los años de Abraham Lincoln en Illinois (1830-1861). 
Los materiales biográficos miran la adolescencia de Lincoln, las 
guerras indias, el partido de whig, la guerra mexicana, el partido 
republicano, y la campaña 1859-61. Los temas incluyen el 
desarrollo económico, establecimiento de frontera, las actitudes 
raciales, política, religión y cultura, y las relaciones sociales de
la era. La lección planea el foco en los discusiones de 
Lincoln-Douglas, el movimiento de la contra-esclavitud, la guerra 
negra del halcón, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206578</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107864</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lincoln-net</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
