<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104789</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104789</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206630</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Smithsonian National Zoological Park</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Smithsonian Nationaler Zoologischer Park</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Parc Zoologique National Smithsonien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Parque Zoological Nacional Smithsonian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parco Zoologico Nazionale Smithsonian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σμιθσονιτικό εθνικό ζωολογικό πάρκο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Parque Zoológico Nacional Smithsonian</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides fact sheets and photos for many of the 2,400 mammals, birds, reptiles and amphibians, fish, and invertebrates at the National Zoo and the Zoo's Conservation and Research Center. Learn about cheetahs, flamingos, hummingbirds, elephants, gorillas, pandas, snakes, butterflies, and many more animals, including the nearly one-fifth of the 400 species at the Zoo that are endangered or threatened.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Tatsache Blätter und Fotos für viele der 
2.400 Säugetiere, der Vögel, der Reptilien und der Amphibien, der 
Fische und der wirbellosen Tiere am nationalen Zoo und am 
Zoo-Erhaltung und Forschungszentrum zur Verfügung. 
Erlernen Sie über cheetahs, flamingos, Kolibris, Elefanten, 
Gorillas, Pandas, Schlangen, Basisrecheneinheiten und viel mehr Tiere,
einschließlich das fast ein Fünftel der 400 Sorten am 
Zoo, die gefährdet oder bedroht werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des feuilles et des photos de fait pour 
plusieurs des 2.400 mammifères, oiseaux, reptiles et amphibies, 
poissons, et invertébrés au zoo national et au centre de l'économie
et des recherches du zoo. Renseignez-vous sur les cheetahs, 
flamingos, colibris, éléphants, gorilles, pandas, serpents, 
papillons, et beaucoup plus d'animaux, y compris presque l'un 
cinquième des 400 espèces au zoo qui sont mises en danger ou 
menacées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece folhas e fotos do fato para muitos dos 
2.400 mamíferos, pássaros, répteis e anfíbios, peixes, e 
invertebrados no jardim zoológico nacional e no centro do 
conservation e de pesquisa do jardim zoológico. Aprenda sobre 
os cheetahs, flamingos, hummingbirds, elefantes, gorillas, pandas, 
serpentes, borboletas, e muitos mais animais, including as quase um 
quinto das 400 espécies no jardim zoológico que são postas em 
perigo ou ameaçadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce i fogli e foto di fatto per molti dei 
2.400 mammiferi, uccelli, rettili ed anfibi, pesci ed invertebrati al 
giardino zoologico nazionale ed al centro di conservazione e di 
ricerca del giardino zoologico. Impari circa i cheetahs, 
flamingos, hummingbirds, elefanti, gorillas, pandas, serpenti, 
farfalle e molti altri animali, compreso quasi l'un quinto delle 400 
specie al giardino zoologico che sono messe o minacciate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα ενημερωτικά δελτία και τις φωτογραφίες για 
πολλά από τα 2.400 θηλαστικά, τα πουλιά, τα ερπετά και τα 
αμφίβια, τα ψάρια, και τα ασπόνδυλα στον εθνικό ζωολογικό κήπο 
και το κέντρο συντήρησης και ερευνητικοου του ζωολογικού κήπου. 
Μάθετε για τα cheetahs, φλαμίγκο, κολίβρια, ελέφαντες, 
γορίλλες, pandas, φίδια, πεταλούδες, και πολλά περισσότερα 
ζώα, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του σχεδόν ενός πέμπτου των 400 
ειδών στο ζωολογικό κήπο που είναι διακυβευμένα ή απειλητικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a las hojas y las fotos del hecho para
muchos de los 2.400 mamíferos, pájaros, reptiles y anfibios, 
pescados, e invertebrados en el parque zoológico nacional y el centro
de la conservación y de investigación del parque zoológico. 
Aprenda sobre los cheetahs, flamingos, hummingbirds, elefantes, 
gorilas, pandas, serpientes, mariposas, y muchos más animales, 
incluyendo el casi un quinto de las 400 especies en el parque 
zoológico se ponen en peligro o se amenazan que.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206630</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104789</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/smithsonian-national-zoological-park</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
