<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102869</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102869</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086876</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"[T]ests have shown . . . that our three average men are equal."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"[ T]ests haben dargestellt. . . 
daß unsere drei durchschnittlichen Männer sind gleich."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"[ T]ests ont montré. . . que 
nos trois hommes moyens sont égaux."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"[ T]ests mostrou. . . que 
nossos três homens médios são iguais."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"[ T]ests ha indicato. . . che i
nostri tre uomini medii sono uguali."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"[ T]ests έχει εμφανίσει. .. ότι 
τρία μέσα άτομά μας είναι ίσα."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"[ T]ests ha mostrado. . . que 
nuestros tres hombres medios son iguales."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By the mid-twentieth century, the movement of African Americans from farms to cities, along with their participation in World War II industries and union organizing, spawned the origins of the modern civil rights movement. Although conflict between white and black workers continued, many African Americans faced continued discrimination with a new sense of self-confidence and militancy, based on their identities as equal workers, soldiers, and citizens. This frame from  Brotherhood of Man , an animated short produced by United Productions of America, a studio created by former Walt Disney animators, for the United Automobile Workers' 1946 interracial organizing drive.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum dem mittler-zwanzigsten Jahrhundert laichte die 
Bewegung der afrikanischen Amerikaner von Bauernhöfe zu Städte, 
zusammen mit ihrer Teilnahme an den Weltkriegindustrien und Anschluß 
organisierend, die Ursprung der modernen Zivilrechtbewegung. 
Obgleich $überschneidung zwischen den weißen und schwarzen 
Arbeitern fortfuhr, stellten viele afrikanische Amerikaner anhaltende 
Unterscheidung mit einer neuen Richtung des Selbstvertrauens und des 
Militancy gegenüber, basiert auf ihren Identitäten als gleiche 
Arbeiter, Soldaten und Bürger. Dieses Feld von der Bruderschaft
des Mannes, ein lebhafter Kurzschluß produzierte durch vereinigte 
Produktionen von Amerika, ein Studio, das von den ehemaligen Walt 
Disney Trickzeichnern, für das vereinigten interracial organisierende
Laufwerk der Automobil-Arbeiter 1946 hergestellt wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par le mi-vingtième siècle, le mouvement des Américains
africains des fermes aux villes, avec leur participation aux 
industries de la deuxième guerre mondiale et union organisant, a 
engendré les origines du mouvement moderne de droits civiques. 
Bien que le conflit entre les ouvriers blancs et noirs ait 
continué, beaucoup d'Américains africains ont fait face à la 
discrimination continue avec un nouveau sens de art de l'auto-portrait-confidence et
de militantisme, basé sur leurs identités en tant que les ouvriers, 
les soldats, et citoyens égaux. Cette trame de confrérie de 
l'homme, un short animé a produit par des productions unies de 
l'Amérique, un studio créé par d'anciens animateurs de Walt Disney, 
pour le lecteur d'organisation interracial des ouvriers unis 1946 
d'automobile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pelo mid-vigésimo século, o movimento dos americanos 
africanos das fazendas às cidades, junto com sua participação em 
indústrias da segunda guerra mundial e união organizando, spawned as
origens do movimento moderno das direitas civis. Embora o 
conflito entre os trabalhadores brancos e pretos continuasse, muitos 
americanos africanos enfrentaram a discriminação continuada com um 
sentido novo do self-confidence e do militancy, baseado em suas 
identidades como trabalhadores, soldados, e cidadãos iguais. 
Este frame do brotherhood do homem, um short animated produziu 
por produções unidas de América, um estúdio criado por 
realizadores de desenhos animados anteriores de Walt Disney, para a 
movimentação organizando interracial dos trabalhadores unidos 1946 
do automóvel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro il metà di-ventesimo secolo, il movimento degli 
Americani africani dai poderi alle città, con la loro partecipazione 
alle industrie della seconda guerra mondiale e l'unione organizzanti, 
ha deposto le uova le origini del movimento moderno di diritti civili.
Anche se il conflitto fra gli operai bianchi e neri è 
continuato, molti Americani africani affrontati hanno continuato la 
distinzione con un nuovo senso della sicurezza di sè e della 
militanza, basato sulle loro identità come gli operai, i soldati e 
cittadini uguali. Questa struttura da fratellanza dell'uomo, uno
short animato ha prodotto dalle produzioni unite dell'America, un 
studio creato dagli ex animatori del Walt Disney, per l'azionamento 
d'organizzazione interracial degli operai uniti 1946 dell'automobile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέχρι το μέσος-εικοστό αιώνα, η κυκλοφορία 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών από τα αγροκτήματα στις πόλεις, μαζί με 
τη συμμετοχή τους στις βιομηχανίες παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ και την 
ένωση που οργανώνει, ωοτόκησε την προέλευση της σύγχρονης 
μετακίνησης αστικών δικαιωμάτων. Αν και η σύγκρουση μεταξύ 
των λευκών και μαύρων εργαζομένων συνεχίστηκε, πολλοί 
αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί αντιμετώπισαν τη συνεχή διάκριση με μια 
νέα αίσθηση της αυτοπεποίθησης και της μαχητικότητας, βασισμένη 
στις ταυτότητές τους ως ίσοι εργαζόμενοι, στρατιώτες, και 
πολίτες. Αυτό το πλαίσιο από την αδελφοσύνη του ατόμου, 
ζωντανεμμένο παραχθείς απότομα από τις ενωμένες παραγωγές της 
Αμερικής, ένα στούντιο που δημιουργείται από τους προηγούμενους 
εμψυχωτές Walt Disney, για την των ενωμένων αυτοκινητικών 
εργαζομένων κίνηση οργάνωσης του 1946 διαφυλετική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por el mediados de-vige'simo siglo, el movimiento de los 
americanos africanos de granjas a las ciudades, junto con su 
participación en industrias de la Segunda Guerra Mundial y la unión 
ordenando, spawn/generó los orígenes del movimiento moderno de las 
derechas civiles. Aunque el conflicto entre los trabajadores 
blancos y negros continuó, muchos americanos africanos hicieron 
frente a la discriminación continuada con un nuevo sentido de la 
confianza en sí mismo y de la militancia, basado en sus identidades 
como trabajadores, soldados, y ciudadanos iguales. Este marco de
la fraternidad del hombre, un cortocircuito animado produjo por 
producciones unidas de América, un estudio creado por los animadores 
anteriores de Walt Disney, para el mecanismo impulsor de ordenación 
interracial de los trabajadores unidos 1946 del automóvil.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086876</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102869</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/t-ests-have-shown-that-our-three-average-men-are-equal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
