<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103598</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103598</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086171</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Forty-Two Cents an Hour" for Twelve to Fourteen Hours a Day: George Milkulvich Describes Work in the Clairton Mills after World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Forty-Two Cents ein Stunde" für zwölf bis 
vierzehn Stunden pro Tag: George Milkulvich beschreibt Arbeit in
den Clairton Tausendsteln nach dem Ersten Weltkrieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"cents de Forty-Two par heure" pendant douze à 
quatorze heures par jour : George Milkulvich décrit le 
travail dans les moulins de Clairton après la Première Guerre 
Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">de "centavos Forty-Two um a hora" por doze a 
quatorze horas um dia: George Milkulvich descreve o trabalho nos
moinhos de Clairton após o world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"centesimi di Forty-Two un l'ora" per dodici - 
quattordici ore al giorno: George Milkulvich descrive il lavoro 
nei laminatoi di Clairton dopo il world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σαράντα δύο σεντ μια ώρα" για δώδεκα έως 
δεκατέσσερις ώρες ημερησίως: Θ*Γεοργε Milkulvich 
Describes Work στους μύλους Clairton μετά από τον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"centavos de Forty-Two por hora" por doce a 
catorce horas un día: George Milkulvich describe el trabajo en 
los molinos de Clairton después de la Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the dramatic 1919 steel strike, 350,000 workers walked off their jobs and crippled the industry. The U.S. Senate Committee on Education and Labor set out to investigate the strike while it was still in progress. In his testimony before the committee, George Milkulvich, an immigrant from the Croatian region of Dalmatia (along the eastern shore of the Adriatic Sea), gave a straightforward explanation of what he was striking for--"better treatment."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im drastischen 1919 Stahlschlag gingen 350.000 
Arbeiter weg von ihren Jobs und verkrüppelten die Industrie. 
Der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senat-Ausschuß für Ausbildung und 
Arbeit legte dar, um den Schlag nachzuforschen, während er noch in 
Bewegung war. Anschlug für, in seinem Zeugnis vor dem 
Ausschuß, gab George Milkulvich, ein Immigrant von der kroatischen 
Region von Dalmatia (entlang dem östlichen Ufer des adriatischen 
Meeres), eine direkte Erklärung von, was er -- "bessere Behandlung."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les 1919 grèves en acier excessive, 350.000 
ouvriers ont marché outre de leurs travaux et ont estropié 
l'industrie. Le comité de sénat des ETATS-UNIS de l'éducation
et du travail s'est mis à étudier la grève tandis qu'elle était 
encore en marche. Dans son témoignage devant le comité, 
George Milkulvich, un immigré de la région croate de Dalmatia 
(le long du rivage oriental de la mer adriatique), a donné une 
explication franche pour de ce qu'il frappait -- un "meilleur 
traitement."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nas 1919 batidas de aço dramática, 350.000 
trabalhadores andaram fora de seus trabalhos e aleijaram a indústria.
O comitê do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na instrução e no 
trabalho ajustou-se para fora para investigar a batida quando era 
ainda em andamento. Em seu testimony antes do comitê, George 
Milkulvich, um immigrant da região croatian de Dalmatia (ao longo da 
costa oriental do mar adriático), deu uma explanação direta de o 
que estava golpeando para -- "o tratamento melhor."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nei 1919 colpi d'acciaio drammatico, 350.000 
operai hanno camminato fuori dei loro lavori ed hanno paralizzato 
l'industria. Il comitato del senato degli STATI UNITI di 
formazione e del Lavoro ha precisato per studiare il colpo mentre
era ancora in progresso. Nella sua testimonianza prima del 
comitato, George Milkulvich, un immigrante dalla regione croatian di 
Dalmatia (lungo il puntello orientale del mare adriatico), ha dato una
spiegazione diretta di che cosa stava colpendo per -- "trattamento 
migliore."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δραματική απεργία χάλυβα του 1919, 350.000 
εργαζόμενοι περπάτησαν από τις εργασίες τους και ακρωτηρίασαν τη 
βιομηχανία. Η Επιτροπή ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου της 
εκπαίδευσης και η εργασία καθόρισαν να ερευνήσουν την απεργία 
ενώ ήταν ακόμα υπό εξέλιξη. Στην κατάθεσή του ενώπιον 
της επιτροπής, George Milkulvich, ένας μετανάστης από την 
κροατική περιοχή της Δαλματίας (κατά μήκος της ανατολικής ακτής
της αδριατικής θάλασσας), έδωσε μια απλή εξήγηση αυτού που ήταν
εντυπωσιακός για -- "καλύτερη επεξεργασία."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En las 1919 huelgas de acero dramática, 350.000 
trabajadores recorrieron de sus trabajos y lisiaron la industria. 
El comité del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre la educación y el
trabajo precisó para investigar la huelga mientras que todavía 
estaba en marcha. En su testimonio ante el comité, George 
Milkulvich, inmigrante de la región croata de Dalmatia (a lo 
largo de la orilla del este del mar adriático), dio una explicación 
directa para de lo que él pulso -- un "tratamiento mejor."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086171</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103598</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/forty-two-cents-an-hour-for-twelve-to-fourteen-hours-a-day-george-milkulvich-describes-work-in-the-clairton-mills-after-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
