<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103941</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103941</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Learning Styles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erlernenarten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Modèles D'Étude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estilos De Aprendizagem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Stili Imparanti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μορφές εκμάθησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estilos Que aprenden</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The aim of this lesson is to help students identify their personal learning styles so they can study and learn more effectively. It is the ninth lesson in the study skills series and it introduces adult learners to the concept of learning styles. Students will have an opportunity to reflect on different ways of learning and to validate different abilities and capabilities, both their own and those of others. The lessons are designed as a package with key skills reinforced in each subsequent lesson so that a study culture is developed over time. They can be delivered sequentially or used individually, as a whole or in part, to support other programs of study.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel dieser Lektion ist, Kursteilnehmern zu 
helfen, ihre persönlichen erlernenarten zu kennzeichnen, also können
sie effektiv studieren und erlernen. Es ist die 9. Lektion in 
der Studie Fähigkeiten Serie und es stellt Erwachsenanfänger zum 
Konzept der erlernenarten vor. Kursteilnehmer haben eine 
Gelegenheit, sich auf unterschiedlichen Methoden des Lernens zu 
reflektieren und unterschiedliche Fähigkeiten und Fähigkeiten zu 
validieren, ihre Selbst- und die von anderen. Die Lektionen sind
während ein Paket mit den Schlüsselfähigkeiten konzipiert, die in 
jeder folgenden Lektion verstärkt werden, damit eine Studie Kultur 
über Zeit entwickelt wird. Sie können sequentiell geliefert 
werden oder, als Ganzes oder im Teil einzeln benutzt werden, um andere
Programme der Studie zu unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cette leçon est d'aider des étudiants
à identifier leurs modèles d'étude personnels ainsi ils peuvent 
étudier et apprendre plus pertinemment. C'est la neuvième 
leçon de la série de qualifications d'étude et il présente des 
étudiants d'adulte au concept des modèles d'étude. Les 
étudiants auront une occasion de réfléchir sur différentes voies 
de l'étude et de valider différentes capacités et capacités, leurs
propres et ceux de d'autres. Les leçons sont conçues pendant 
qu'un module avec les qualifications principales renforcées dans 
chaque leçon ultérieure de sorte qu'une culture d'étude soit 
développée avec le temps. Elles peuvent être livrées 
séquentiellement ou employées individuellement, dans l'ensemble ou 
en partie, pour supporter d'autres programmes d'étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O alvo desta lição é ajudar a estudantes 
identificar seus estilos de aprendizagem pessoais assim que podem 
estudar e aprender mais eficazmente. É a nona lição na série
das habilidades do estudo e introduz learners do adulto ao conceito de
estilos de aprendizagem. Os estudantes terão uma oportunidade 
de refletir em maneiras diferentes da aprendizagem e de validar 
abilidades e potencialidades diferentes,  seus próprios e aqueles de 
outros. As lições são projetadas enquanto um pacote com as 
habilidades chaves reforçadas em cada lição subseqüente de modo 
que uma cultura do estudo esteja desenvolvida sobre o tempo. 
Podem ser entregados sequencialmente ou usado individualmente, 
ao todo ou na parte, suportar outros programas do estudo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo di questa lezione è aiutare gli allievi
ad identificare i loro stili imparanti personali in modo da possono 
studiare più efficacemente ed imparare. È la nona lezione in 
serie di abilità di studio ed introduce i principianti dell'adulto al
concetto degli stili imparanti. Gli allievi avranno un'occasione
riflettere sui modi differenti di imparare e convalidare le abilità e
le possibilità differenti, sia il loro propri che quelli di altri. 
Le lezioni sono progettate mentre un pacchetto con le abilità 
chiave di rinforzo in ogni lezione successiva in moda da sviluppare 
una coltura di studio col tempo. Possono essere trasportate in 
sequenza o essere usate individualmente, nell'insieme o in parte, per 
sostenere altri programmi dello studio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του μαθήματος είναι να ενισχυθούν οι 
σπουδαστές να προσδιορίσουν τις προσωπικές μορφές εκμάθησής τους
έτσι μπορούν να μελετήσουν και να μάθουν αποτελεσματικότερα. 
Είναι το ένατο μάθημα στη σειρά δεξιοτήτων μελέτης και 
εισάγει τους ενήλικους αρχαρίους στην έννοια της εκμάθησης των 
μορφών. Οι σπουδαστές θα έχουν μια ευκαιρία να απεικονίσουν
στους διαφορετικούς τρόπους και να επικυρώσουν τις διαφορετικές 
δυνατότητες και τις ικανότητες, και τους δικοί και εκείνοι άλλες.
Τα μαθήματα σχεδιάζονται ως συσκευασία με τις βασικές 
δεξιότητες που ενισχύονται σε κάθε επόμενο μάθημα έτσι ώστε 
ένας πολιτισμός μελέτης αναπτύσσεται κατά τη διάρκεια του 
χρόνου. Μπορούν να παραδοθούν διαδοχικά ή να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν χωριστά, συνολικά ή εν μέρει, για να 
υποστηρίξουν άλλα προγράμματα της μελέτης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La puntería de esta lección es ayudar a 
estudiantes a identificar sus estilos que aprenden personales así que
pueden estudiar y aprender más con eficacia. Es la novena 
lección en la serie de las habilidades del estudio e introduce a 
principiantes del adulto al concepto de estilos que aprenden. 
Los estudiantes tendrán una oportunidad de reflejar en diversas
maneras de aprender y de validar diversas capacidades y capacidades, 
sus el propios y los de otros. Se diseñan las lecciones 
mientras que un conjunto con las habilidades dominantes reforzadas en 
cada lección subsecuente para desarrollar una cultura del estudio en 
un cierto plazo. Pueden ser entregadas secuencialmente o ser 
utilizadas individualmente, en su totalidad o en parte, para utilizar 
otros programas del estudio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103941</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/learning-styles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
