<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103703</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103703</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207020</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Wright Brothers National Memorial: Site of the First Controlled Powered Flight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wright Bruder-Nationales Denkmal: Site des 
ersten gesteuerten angeschalteten Fluges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mémorial National de Frères de Wright : 
Site du premier vol actionné contrôlé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Memorial Nacional Dos Irmãos De Wright: 
Local do primeiro vôo powered controlado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Memoriale Nazionale Dei Fratelli Di Wright: 
Luogo del primo volo alimentato gestito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικό μνημείο αδελφών Wright: Περιοχή της 
πρώτης ελεγχόμενης τροφοδοτημένης πτήσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Monumento Nacional De los Hermanos De Wright: 
Sitio del primer vuelo accionado controlado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells how bicycle makers in Dayton, Ohio, launched the aviation age. After reading about the glider accident that killed Otto Lilienthal, Wilbur and Orville Wright spent four years designing flying machines in Dayton and testing them near Kitty Hawk. Maps and photos show their flying machines and living quarters on the windswept dunes of the Outer Banks where, on December 17, 1903, they made history.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt, wie Fahrradhersteller in Dayton, Ohio, 
das Luftfahrtalter ausstießen. Nach dem Ablesen über den 
Segelflugzeugunfall, daß beendeter Otto Lilienthal, Wilbur und 
Orville Wright vier Jahre verbrachten, die Fliegenmaschinen in Dayton 
konzipieren und sie nahe Kitty-Falken prüfen. Karten und Fotos 
zeigen ihre Fliegenmaschinen und lebenden Viertel auf den windswept 
Dünen der äußeren Bänke, in denen, an Dezember 17, 1903, sie 
Geschichte bildeten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit que les générateurs de bicyclette à Dayton,
Ohio, ont lancé l'âge d'aviation. Après avoir eu connaissance
de l'accident de planeur qu'Otto détruit Lilienthal, Wilbur et 
Orville Wright ont passé quatre ans concevant des machines de vol à 
Dayton et les testant près du faucon de Kitty. Les cartes 
et les photos montrent leurs machines de vol et quarts vivants sur les
dunes balayées par le vent des banques externes où, 17 décembre 1903, elles
ont fait l'histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz como os fabricantes da bicicleta em Dayton, 
Ohio, lançaram a idade da aviação. Após ter lido sobre o 
acidente do planador que Otto matado Lilienthal, Wilbur e Orville 
Wright gastaram quatro anos que projetam máquinas do vôo em Dayton e
que testam as perto do falcão do kitty. Os mapas e as fotos 
mostram seus máquinas do vôo e quartos vivos nas dunas do windswept 
dos bancos exteriores onde, dezembro em 17, 1903, fizeram o history.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a come i creatori della bicicletta a Dayton, 
Ohio, hanno lanciato l'età di aeronautica. Dopo la lettura 
sull'incidente dell'aliante che Otto ucciso Lilienthal, Wilbur ed 
Orville Wright hanno speso quattro anni che progettano le 
macchine di volo a Dayton e che le esaminano vicino al hawk del kitty.
I programmi e le foto mostrano le loro macchine di volo e quarti
viventi sulle dune del windswept della Banca esterna in cui, il 
17 dicembre 1903, hanno fatto la storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει πώς οι κατασκευαστές ποδηλάτων στο Νταίυτον, 
Οχάιο, προώθησαν την ηλικία αεροπορίας. Μετά από την 
ανάγνωση για το ατύχημα ανεμοπλάνων που σκότωσε Otto 
Lilienthal, Wilbur και Orville Wright πέρασαν τέσσερα 
έτη που σχεδιάζουν τις πετώντας μηχανές στο Νταίυτον και που 
εξετάζουν τις κοντά στο γεράκι γατακιών. Οι χάρτες και οι 
φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν τις πετώντας μηχανές και τέταρτα 
διαβίωσής τους στους ανεμοδαρμένους αμμόλοφους των εξωτερικών 
τραπεζών όπου, στις 17 Δεκεμβρίου ..1903, έκαναν την 
ιστορία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice cómo los fabricantes de la bicicleta en 
Dayton, Ohio, lanzaron la edad de la aviación. Después de leer
sobre el accidente del planeador que Otto matado Lilienthal, Wilbur y 
Orville Wright pasaron cuatro años que diseñaban las máquinas del 
vuelo en Dayton y que las probaban cerca del halcón del gatito. 
Las correspondencias y las fotos muestran sus máquinas del 
vuelo y cuartos vivos en las dunas del windswept de las baterías 
externas en donde, 17 de diciembre de 1903, hicieron historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207020</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103703</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/wright-brothers-national-memorial-site-of-the-first-controlled-powered-flight</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
