<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108337</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108337</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087105</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"This Is How It Was": An American Nurse in France During World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Dieses Ist, Wie Es" War: Eine amerikanische
Krankenschwester in Frankreich während des Ersten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"C'est Comment Il Était" : Une infirmière 
américaine en France pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Isto É Como Era": Uma enfermeira americana
em France durante o world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Questo È Come Era": Un'infermiera 
americana in Francia durante il world.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έτσι ήταν": Μια αμερικανική νοσοκόμα στη 
Γαλλία κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Éste Es Cómo Era": Una enfermera 
americana en Francia durante Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ellen N. La Motte was one of the first American nurses to serve in a French field hospital during World War I. The Backwash of War , a series of fourteen vignettes of a French field hospital, recounting her 1915 service in Belgium, was first published in fall 1916, before American entry into the world war. Once the United States had entered the war, La Motte's unsparing view of the devastation of war was suppressed by the pervasive national propaganda effort of the home front, and the publishers withdrew the book. Republished in 1934, the book found a new audience among Americans determined to avoid involvement in foreign wars. Included here is her introduction to the 1934 republication, which gave the book's publishing history, and one of the sketches.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ellen N. La Motte war eine der ersten 
amerikanischen Krankenschwestern, zum auf Franzosen zu dienen 
auffangen Krankenhaus während des Ersten Weltkrieges. 
Der Wellengang des Krieges, eine Reihe von vierzehn vignettes 
Franzosen fangen das Krankenhaus auf und zählen ihren 
Service 1915 in Belgien nach, wurde veröffentlicht zuerst in Fall 
1916, vor amerikanischem Eintrag in den Weltkrieg. Sobald die 
Vereinigten Staaten den Krieg eingetragen hatten, La Mottes wurde 
unsparing Ansicht der Verwüstung des Krieges durch die durchdringende
nationale Propagandabemühung der Hauptfrontseite unterdrückt, und 
die Verleger entnahmen das Buch. Neu aufgelegt 1934, fand das 
Buch ein neues Publikum unter den Amerikanern, die festgestellt 
wurden, um Miteinbeziehung in den Auslandskriegen zu vermeiden. 
Hier geschlossen ihre Einleitung bis die Neuauflage 1934, die 
die Verlags- Geschichte des Buches gab, und eine der Skizzen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ellen N. La Motte était l'une des premières 
infirmières américaines à servir dans un hôpital français de zone
pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale. Le remuement de la guerre,
une série de quatorze vignettes d'un hôpital français de zone, 
racontant son service 1915 en Belgique, a été édité la première 
fois dans la chute 1916, avant entrée américaine dans la guerre 
mondiale. Une fois que les Etats-Unis avaient écrit la guerre, 
la vue libérale de Motte de La de la dévastation de la guerre a 
été supprimée par l'effort national dominant de propagande de 
l'avant à la maison, et les éditeurs ont retiré le livre. 
Republié en 1934, le livre a trouvé une nouvelle assistance 
parmi des Américains déterminés pour éviter la participation dans 
des guerres étrangères. Incluse ici est son introduction à 
l'nouvelle édition 1934, qui a donné l'histoire d'édition du livre,
et à un des croquis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ellen N. La Motte era uma das primeiras 
enfermeiras americanas a servir em um hospital francês do campo 
durante o world.war.i. O backwash da guerra, uma série de 
quatorze vignettes de um hospital francês do campo, recounting seu 
serviço 1915 em Bélgica, foi publicado primeiramente na queda 1916, 
antes da entrada americana na guerra de mundo. Uma vez que os 
estados unidos tinham incorporado a guerra, a vista unsparing de Motte
do la do devastation da guerra foi suprimida pelo esforço nacional 
pervasive do propaganda da parte dianteira home, e os publishers 
retiraram o livro. Republished em 1934, o livro encontrou uma 
audiência nova entre os americanos determinados evitar a 
participação em guerras extrangeiras. É incluída aqui sua 
introdução ao republication 1934, que deu o history publicando do 
livro, e a um dos esboços.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ellen N. La Motte era una delle prime infermiere 
americane da servire in un ospedale francese del campo durante il 
world.war.i. Il risucchio della guerra, una serie di quattordici
vignettes di un ospedale francese del campo, raccontanti il suo 
servizio 1915 nel Belgio, in primo luogo è stato pubblicato nella 
caduta 1916, prima dell'entrata americana nella guerra mondiale. 
Unito Dichiara una volta aveva entrato nella guerra, la 
vista unsparing del Motte della La della devastazione della guerra è 
stata soppressa dallo sforzo nazionale dominante di propaganda della 
parte anteriore domestica e gli editori hanno ritirato il libro. 
Republished in 1934, il libro ha trovato un nuovo pubblico fra 
gli Americani determinati per evitare la partecipazione alle guerre 
straniere. È inclusa qui la sua introduzione alla 
ripubblicazione 1934, che ha dato la storia di pubblicazione del libro
e ad uno degli abbozzi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Ellen N. La Motte ήταν μια από τις πρώτες
αμερικανικές νοσοκόμες που εξυπηρετούν σε ένα γαλλικό νοσοκομείο
πεδίων κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι. Το 
παλίνδρομο κύμα του πολέμου, μια σειρά δεκατεσσάρων σύντομων 
χρονογραφημάτων ενός γαλλικού νοσοκομείου πεδίων, που εξιστορούν
την υπηρεσία του 1915 της στο Βέλγιο, δημοσιεύθηκε αρχικά το 
φθινόπωρο του 1916, πριν από την αμερικανική είσοδο μέσα σε 
τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο. Μόλις εισαγάγουν οι Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες τον πόλεμο, η αδυσώπητη όψη Λα Motte της ερήμωσης 
του πολέμου καταστάλθηκε από κυρίαρχη εθνική προσπάθεια 
προπαγάνδας του βασικού μετώπου, και οι εκδότες απέσυραν το 
βιβλίο. Αναδημοσιευμένο το 1934, το βιβλίο βρήκε ότι 
ένα νέο ακροατήριο μεταξύ Αμερικανών αποφάσισε να αποφύγει τη 
συμμετοχή στους ξένους πολέμους. Συμπεριλαμβανόμενη εδώ 
είναι η εισαγωγή της στην αναδημοσίευση του 1934, η οποία 
έδωσε την ιστορία έκδοσης του βιβλίου, και ένα από τα σκίτσα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ellen N. La Motte era una de las primeras 
enfermeras americanas a servir en un hospital francés del campo 
durante Primera Guerra Mundial. La turbulencia de la guerra, una
serie de catorce vignettes de un hospital francés del campo, contando
de nuevo su servicio 1915 en Bélgica, primero fue publicada en la 
caída 1916, antes de la entrada americana en la guerra mundial. 
Una vez que los Estados Unidos hubieran incorporado la guerra, 
la opinión unsparing de Motte del la de la devastación de la guerra 
fue suprimida por el esfuerzo nacional penetrante de la propaganda del
frente casero, y los editores retiraron el libro. Republicado en
1934, el libro encontró a nueva audiencia entre los americanos 
determinados para evitar la implicación en guerras no nativas. 
Se incluye aquí su introducción a la nueva edición 1934, que 
dio la historia que publicaba del libro, y a uno de los bosquejos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087105</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108337</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/this-is-how-it-was-an-american-nurse-in-france-during-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
