<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/272565609</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>272565609</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209944</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Triangle circumcircle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dreieck circumcircle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Circumcircle de triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Circumcircle do triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Circumcircle del triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τρίγωνο circumcircle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Circumcircle del triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the properties of the circumcircle of a triangle. The applet shows a triangle where the user can drag the vertices to reshape it. The circumcircle (the circle that passes through all vertices) is continuously updated as the triangle is resized. The center of the circle (circumcenter) is shown along with the three side bisectors that define it. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Eigenschaften des circumcircle eines Dreiecks 
zeigen. Der applet zeigt einem Dreieck, wo der Benutzer die 
Gipfel schleppen kann, um ihn umzugestalten. Das circumcircle 
(der Kreis, das durch alle Gipfel überschreitet), wird ununterbrochen
aktualisiert, während das Dreieck die Größe neu bestimmt wird. 
Die Mitte des Kreises (circumcenter) wird zusammen mit den drei 
seitlichen bisectors gezeigt, die ihn definieren. Applet kann 
zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les propriétés du circumcircle d'une triangle. 
L'applet montre à une triangle où l'utilisateur peut traîner 
les sommets pour le restructurer. Le circumcircle (le cercle qui
traverse tous les sommets) est sans interruption mis à jour pendant 
que la triangle est remise à la côte. Le centre du cercle 
(circumcenter) est montré avec les trois bisectors latéraux qui le 
définissent. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein 
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem as propriedades do circumcircle de um triângulo. O 
applet mostra a um triângulo onde o usuário pode arrastar os 
vertices para reshape o. O circumcircle (o círculo que passa 
com todos os vertices) é atualizado continuamente enquanto o 
triângulo resized. O centro do círculo (circumcenter) é 
mostrado junto com os três bisectors laterais que o definem. O 
applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um 
projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, 
estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou
na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este 
recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook da 
geometria da referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano le proprietà del circumcircle di un triangolo. Il 
applet mostra ad un triangolo dove l'utente può trascinare i vertici 
per rimodellarlo. Il circumcircle (il cerchio che attraversa 
tutti i vertici) è aggiornato continuamente mentre il triangolo è 
ridimensionato. Il centro del cerchio (circumcenter) è indicato
con i tre bisectors laterali che lo definiscono. Il applet può 
essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un 
proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo 
può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella 
libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è 
un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τις ιδιότητες του circumcircle ενός τριγώνου. 
Το applet εμφανίζει ένα τρίγωνο όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί 
να σέρει vertices για να το αναδιαμορφώσει. Το 
circumcircle (ο κύκλος που περνά μέσω όλα vertices) 
ενημερώνεται συνεχώς καθώς το τρίγωνο επαναταξινομείται. Το
κέντρο του κύκλου (circumcenter) εμφανίζεται μαζί με τα τρία 
δευτερεύοντα bisectors που το καθορίζουν. Το Applet 
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran las características del circumcircle de un triángulo. 
El applet muestra a triángulo donde el utilizador puede 
arrastrar las cimas para restructurarlo. El circumcircle (el 
círculo que pasa con todas las cimas) se pone al día continuamente 
mientras que se vuelve a clasificar según el tamaño el triángulo. 
El centro del círculo (circumcenter) se muestra junto con los 
tres bisectors laterales que lo definen. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209944</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>272565609</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/triangle-circumcircle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
