<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108586</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108586</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Gospel According to Andrew: Carnegie's Hymn to Wealth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Evangelium entsprechend Andrew: 
Hymne Carnegies zur Fülle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'evangile selon Andrew : L'hymne de 
Carnegie's à la richesse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O gospel de acordo com Andrew: Hymn de 
Carnegie à riqueza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il gospel secondo Andrew: Hymn del Carnegie 
a ricchezza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Ευαγγέλιο σύμφωνα με τον Andrew: Ύμνος 
Carnegie στον πλούτο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Evangelio según Andrew: Himno de 
Carnegie a la abundancia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In his essay "Wealth," published in  North American Review  in 1889, the industrialist Andrew Carnegie argued that individual capitalists were duty bound to play a broader cultural and social role and thus improve the world. Some labor activists sharply differed with Carnegie's point-of-view and responded with essays of their own, such as the Pennsylvania trade unionists who protested Carnegie's gift of a library to the city of New Castle by pointing out that it had been built with the "sweat and blood of thousands of workers." Carnegie's essay, below, later became famous under the title "The Gospel of Wealth." (Click here to  hear  an audio version of an excerpt from that speech.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In seinem Versuch "Fülle," veröffentlichte in 
der nordamerikanischen Zusammenfassung 1889, argumentierte der 
Industrielle Andrew Carnegie, daß einzelne Kapitalisten 
pflichtgemäß waren, eine ausgedehntere kulturelle und Sozialrolle zu
spielen und die Welt folglich zu verbessern. Einige 
Arbeitsaktivisten unterschieden scharf sich mit Punkt-von-Ansicht 
Carnegies und reagierten mit Versuchen von ihren Selbst, wie den 
Pennsylvania Gewerkschaftlern, die Geschenk Carnegies einer Bibliothek
zur Stadt des neuen Schlosses protestierten, indem sie unterstrichen, 
daß sie war aufgebaut worden mit dem "Schweiß und dem Blut von 
Tausenden Arbeitern." Versuch Carnegies unten wurde später 
berühmt unter dem Namen "das Evangelium von Fülle." (klicken 
Sie hier, um eine Audioversion eines Excerpts von dieser Rede zu 
hören.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans son essai "richesse," a édité dans la revue
américaine du nord en 1889, l'industriel Andrew Carnegie a 
argué du fait que les différents capitalistes étaient contraints à
jouer un plus large rôle culturel et social et à améliorer ainsi le
monde. Quelques activistes de travail ont nettement différé 
avec la point-de-vue de Carnegie's et ont répondu avec des essais de 
leurs propres, tel que les syndicalistes de la Pennsylvanie qui ont 
protesté le cadeau de Carnegie's d'une bibliothèque à la ville du 
nouveau château en précisant qu'elle avait été construite avec la 
"sueur et le sang des milliers d'ouvriers." L'essai de 
Carnegie's, ci-dessous, plus tard est devenu célèbre sous le titre 
"l'evangile de la richesse." (Clic ici pour entendre une 
version sonore d'un extrait de ce discours.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em seu essay "riqueza," publicou na revisão 
norte-americana em 1889, o industrialista Andrew Carnegie discutiu que
os capitalistas individuais eram limite do dever para jogar um papel 
cultural e social mais largo e para melhorar assim o mundo. 
Algumas activistas labor diferiram agudamente com 
ponto-$$$-VISTA de Carnegie e responderam com essays do seus 
próprios, tais como os unionists de comércio de Pensilvânia que 
protestaram o presente de Carnegie de uma biblioteca à cidade do 
castelo novo indicando que tinha sido construída com o "suor e o 
sangue dos milhares dos trabalhadores." O essay de Carnegie, 
abaixo, tornou-se mais tarde famoso sob o título "o gospel da 
riqueza." (estale aqui para ouvir uma versão audio de um 
excerpt desse discurso.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel suo saggio "ricchezza," ha pubblicato nella 
revisione nordamericana in 1889, l'industriale Andrew Carnegie ha 
sostenuto che i diversi capitalisti erano impegnati a svolgere un più
vasto ruolo culturale e sociale ed a migliorare così il mondo. 
Alcuni attivisti di lavoro hanno differito da acutamente con
la punto-de-vista del Carnegie ed hanno risposto con i saggi dei loro 
propri, quali i sindacalisti della Pensilvania che hanno protestato il
regalo del Carnegie di una libreria alla città di nuovo castello 
precisando che era stata costruita con "il sudore e l'anima dei 
migliaia degli operai." Il saggio del Carnegie, sotto, più 
successivamente è diventato famoso sotto il titolo "il gospel di 
ricchezza." (scattisi qui per sentire una versione audio di un 
brano da quel discorso.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο δοκίμιό του "πλούτος," δημοσιευμένος στη 
βορειοαμερικανική αναθεώρηση το 1889, ο βιομήχανος Andrew 
Carnegie υποστήριξε ότι οι μεμονωμένοι κεφαλαιοκράτες ήταν 
καθήκον που δεσμεύθηκε να διαδραματίσει έναν ευρύτερο 
πολιτιστικό και κοινωνικό ρόλο και να βελτιώσει έτσι τον κόσμο. 
Μερικά ενεργά στελέχη εργασίας διέφεραν αισθητά με την 
άποψη Carnegie και αποκρίθηκαν με δικά τους τα δοκίμια, όπως 
οι συνδικαλιστές της Πενσυλβανίας που διαμαρτυρήθηκαν το δώρο 
Carnegie μιας βιβλιοθήκης στην πόλη του νέου Castle με την 
επισήμανση ότι ήταν χτισμένη με το "ιδρώτα και το αίμα χιλιάδων
εργαζόμενοι." Το δοκίμιο του Carnegie, κατωτέρω, έγινε 
αργότερα διάσημο υπό τον τίτλο "το Ευαγγέλιο του πλούτου." 
(Στιγμιαίο πάτημα για να ακούσει εδώ μια ηχητική έκδοση 
ενός αποσπάσματος από εκείνη την ομιλία.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En su ensayo "abundancia," publicó en la 
revisión norteamericana en 1889, el industrial Andrew Carnegie 
discutió que los capitalistas individuales fueran límite del deber 
para desempeñar un papel cultural y social más amplio y para mejorar
así el mundo. Algunos activistas de trabajo diferenciaron 
sostenidamente con la punta-de-vista de Carnegie y respondieron con 
ensayos sus el propios, tales como los unionistas comerciales de 
Pennsylvania que protestaron el regalo de Carnegie de una biblioteca a
la ciudad del castillo nuevo precisando que había sido construida con
el "sudor y la sangre de millares de trabajadores." El ensayo de
Carnegie, abajo, llegó a ser más adelante famoso bajo título "el 
Evangelio de la abundancia." (haga clic aquí para oír una 
versión audio de un extracto de ese discurso.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108586</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-gospel-according-to-andrew-carnegies-hymn-to-wealth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
