<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103616</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103616</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206727</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Martin Van Buren's "Return to the Soil"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Martin Van Burens "Rückkehr zum Boden"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Retour de Martin Van Buren's "au sol"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Retorno de Martin Camionete Buren "ao solo"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ritorno del Martin Van Buren "al terreno"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστροφή Martin Van Buren's "στο χώμα"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vuelta de Martin Van Buren "al suelo"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a curriculum-oriented site using the home, named Lindenwald, the eighth President moved to after his term in office to introduce a discussion of Van Buren and his times. The site contains photos and drawings of Lindenwald as well as discussions how Van Buren interacted with other political leaders of the day, like Andrew Jackson and John C. Calhoun. The site offers many questions and suggestions for student assignments.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Lehrplan-orientierte Site mit dem Haus, 
benannt Lindenwald, dem achten Präsidenten, der auf nach seine 
Bezeichnung im Büro verschoben wird, um eine Diskussion über Van 
Buren und seine Zeiten vorzustellen. Die Site enthält Fotos und
Zeichnungen von Lindenwald sowie Diskussionen, wie Van Buren auf 
andere politische Führer des Tages, wie Andrew Jackson und John C. 
Calhoun einwirkte. Die Site bietet viele Fragen und Vorschläge 
für Kursteilnehmeranweisungen an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un site programme d'études-orienté en 
utilisant la maison, nommée Lindenwald, le huitième président 
déplacé à après sa limite dans le bureau pour présenter une 
discussion de Van Buren et ses périodes. Le site contient des 
photos et des schémas de Lindenwald aussi bien que des discussions 
comment Van Buren a agi l'un sur l'autre avec d'autres amorces 
politiques du jour, comme Andrew Jackson et John C. Calhoun. Le 
site offre beaucoup de questions et suggestions pour des affectations 
d'étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um local curriculum-orientado usando a HOME, 
nomeada Lindenwald, o oitavo presidente movido para após seu termo no
escritório para introduzir uma discussão de Camionete Buren e suas 
épocas. O local contem fotos e desenhos de Lindenwald 
as.well.as discussões como Camionete Buren interagiu com outros 
líderes políticos do dia, como Andrew Jackson e John C. Calhoun. 
O local oferece muitas perguntas e sugestões para atribuições
do estudante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un luogo programma di studi-orientato usando la
sede, chiamata Lindenwald, l'ottavo presidente spostato verso dopo il 
suo termine in ufficio per introdurre una discussione su Van Buren ed 
i suoi periodi. Il luogo contiene le foto e le illustrazioni di 
Lindenwald così come le discussioni come Van Buren si è interagito 
con altri capi politici del giorno, come Andrew Jackson e John 
C. Calhoun. Il luogo offre molti domande e suggerimenti per le 
assegnazioni dell'allievo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια πρόγραμμα σπουδών-προσανατολισμένη στο 
περιοχή που χρησιμοποιεί το σπίτι, που ονομάζονται Lindenwald, 
τον όγδοο Πρόεδρο που κινείται προς μετά από τον όρο του στην 
αρχή για να εισαγάγει μια συζήτηση Van Buren και των χρόνων 
του. Η περιοχή περιέχει τις φωτογραφίες και τα σχέδια 
Lindenwald καθώς επίσης και των συζητήσεων πώς Van Buren 
αλληλεπίδρασε με άλλους πολιτικούς ηγέτες της ημέρας, όπως τον 
Andrew Τζάκσον και John C. Calhoun. Η περιοχή 
προσφέρει πολλές ερωτήσεις και προτάσεις για τις αναθέσεις 
σπουδαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un sitio plan de estudios-orientado usando al 
hogar, nombrado Lindenwald, al octavo presidente movido después de su
término en oficina para introducir una discusión de Van Buren y sus 
épocas. El sitio contiene las fotos y los gráficos de 
Lindenwald así como discusiones cómo Van Buren obró recíprocamente
con otros arranques de cinta políticos del día, como Andrew Jackson 
y Juan C. Calhoun. El sitio ofrece muchas preguntas y 
sugerencias para las asignaciones del estudiante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206727</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103616</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/martin-van-burens-return-to-the-soil</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
