<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105374</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105374</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087258</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"You Are the Un-Americans, and You Ought to be Ashamed of Yourselves": Paul Robeson Appears Before HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie sind die Un-Amerikaner, und Sie sollen über 
beschämt sein": Paul Robeson Erscheint Vor HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"vous êtes les Un-Américains, et vous devez avoir
honte de vous-mêmes" : Paul Robeson Apparaît Avant HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"você é os Un-Americanos, e você ought ser 
ashamed de yourselves": Paul Robeson Aparece Antes de HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"siete gli ONU-Americani e dovete essere ashamed di
voi": Paul Robeson Compare Prima di HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είστε οι Η.Ε-Αμερικανοί, και οφείλετε να είστε 
ντροπιασμένοι σασ": Θ*Παuλ Robeson Appears Before 
HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"usted es los Un-Americanos, y usted ought estar 
avergonzado de ustedes mismos": Paul Robeson Aparece Antes de 
HUAC</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many African-American witnesses subpoenaed to testify at the House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC) hearings in the 1950s were asked to denounce Paul Robeson (1888-1976) in order to obtain future employment. Robeson, an All-American football player and recipient of a Phi Beta Kappa key at Rutgers, received a law degree at Columbia. He became an internationally acclaimed concert performer and actor as well as a persuasive political speaker. In 1949, Robeson was the subject of controversy after newspapers reports of public statements that African Americans would not fight in "an imperialist war." In 1950, his passport was revoked. Several years later, Robeson refused to sign an affidavit stating that he was not a Communist and initiated an unsuccessful lawsuit. In the following testimony to a HUAC hearing, ostensibly convened to gain information regarding his passport suit, Robeson refused to answer questions concerning his political activities and lectured bigoted Committee members Gordon H. Scherer and Chairman Francis E.Walter about African-American history and civil rights. In 1958, the Supreme Court ruled that a citizen's right to travel could not be taken away without due process and Robeson' passport was returned.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Zeugen subpoenaed, 
um am Haus-Ausschuß für Un-Amerikanische Aktivitäten zu bezeugen 
(HUAC), das Hörfähigkeiten in den fünfziger Jahren denunzieren Paul
Robeson (1888-1976) um zukünftige Beschäftigung zu erreichen gebeten
wurden. Robeson, ein All-Amerikanischer Fußballspieler und 
Empfänger einer Phi Betakappa Taste bei Rutgers, empfingen einen 
Gesetzgrad bei Kolumbien. Er wurde ein international mit Beifall
begrüßter Konzertausführender und -schauspieler sowie einen 
überzeugenden politischen Lautsprecher. 1949 war Robeson das 
Thema der Kontroverse, nachdem Zeitungen Reports der allgemeinen 
Anweisungen, die afrikanische Amerikaner würden kämpfen nicht in 
"einem imperialist Krieg." 1950 wurde sein Paß widerrufen. 
Einige Jahre später, lehnte Robeson ab, ein Affidavit zu 
unterzeichnen, das angibt, daß er nicht ein Kommunist war und 
initialisiert einen erfolglosen Prozeß. Im folgenden Zeugnis zu
einer HUAC Hörfähigkeit, anscheinend zusammengekommen, um die 
Informationen betreffend sind seine Paßklage, um die Fragen 
abgelehntes und konferiertes Robeson bigoted zu gewinnen hinsichtlich 
sind seiner politischen Aktivitäten zu beantworten 
Ausschußmitgliedas Gordon H. Scherer und Vorsitzender Francis 
E.Walter über Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Geschichte und Zivilrechte. 
1958 ordnete das Höchste Gericht an, daß das Recht eines 
Bürgers zu reisen nicht ohne passenden Prozeß weggenommen werden 
könnte und Robeson ' Paß zurückgebracht wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup de témoins afro-américains ont cité pour 
témoigner au comité de Chambre des activités Un-Américaines (HUAC)
que des auditions dans les années 50 ont été demandées dénoncent 
Paul Robeson (1888-1976) afin d'obtenir le futur emploi. 
Robeson, un joueur Tout-Américain de football et le 
destinataire d'une bêta clé de Kappa de phi chez Rutgers, ont reçu 
un degré de loi chez Colombie. Il est devenu un interprète et 
un acteur internationalement acclamés de concert aussi bien qu'un 
orateur politique persuasif. En 1949, Robeson était le sujet de
la polémique après que des états de journaux des rapports publics 
que les Américains africains ne combattraient pas dans "une guerre 
impérialiste." En 1950, son passeport a été retiré. 
Plusieurs ans après, Robeson a refusé de signer une 
déclaration sous serment déclarant qu'il n'était pas un communiste 
et lance un procès non réussi. Dans le témoignage suivant à 
une audition de HUAC, en apparence assemblée pour gagner 
l'information concernant son costume de passeport, Robeson refusé 
pour répondre à des questions au sujet de ses activités politiques 
et a parlé des membres Gordon H. Scherer et Président Francis 
E.Walter du Comité de fanatique au sujet de l'histoire afro-américaine 
et des droits civiques. En 1958, la cour suprême a régné que 
le droit d'un citoyen de voyager ne pourrait pas être emporté sans 
processus dû et passeport de Robeson 'a été retourné.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitas testemunhas Africano-Americanas subpoenaed 
para testify no comitê da casa em atividades Un-Americanas (HUAC) que
os hearings nos 1950s foram pedidos denounce Paul Robeson (1888-1976) 
a fim obter o emprego futuro. Robeson, um jogador Todo-Americano
do football e o receptor de uma chave beta de Kappa da phi em Rutgers,
receberam um grau da lei em Colômbia. Transformou-se um 
performer e um ator internacional aclamados do concert as.well.as um 
altofalante político persuasive. Em 1949, Robeson era o assunto
da controvérsia depois que relatórios dos jornais das indicações 
públicas que os americanos africanos não lutariam "em uma guerra 
imperialist." Em 1950, seu passport foi revogado. Diversos
anos mais tarde, Robeson recusou assinar um affidavit que indica que 
não era um comunista e inicía um lawsuit mal sucedido. No 
seguinte testimony a um hearing de HUAC, reunido ostensibly para 
ganhar a informação a respeito de seu terno do passport, Robeson 
recusado responder às perguntas a respeito de suas atividades 
políticas e lectured bigoted membros de comitê Gordon H. Scherer e 
presidente Francis E.Walter sobre o history Africano-Americano e 
direitas civis. Em 1958, a corte suprema governou que a direita 
de um cidadão viajar não poderia ser removida sem processo devido e 
passport de Robeson ' estêve retornado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti testimoni Africano-Americani subpoenaed per 
testimoniare al comitato della Camera delle attività ONU-Americane 
(HUAC) che le udienze negli anni 50 sono state chieste denunciano Paul
Robeson (1888-1976) per ottenere l'occupazione futura. Robeson, 
un giocatore Tutto-Americano di gioco del calcio ed il destinatario di
beta tasto di Kappa di phi a Rutgers, hanno ricevuto un grado di legge
a Colombia. È diventato un esecutore e un attore 
internazionalmente applauditi di concerto così come un altoparlante 
politico convincente. In 1949, Robeson era l'argomento di 
polemica dopo che rapporti dei giornali delle istruzione pubbliche che
gli Americani africani non combatterebbero "in una guerra 
imperialist." In 1950, il suo passaporto è stato revocato. 
Parecchi anni più successivamente, Robeson ha rifiutato di 
firmare un affidavit che dichiara che non era un comunista ed 
inizia una causa infruttuosa. Nella seguente testimonianza ad 
un'udienza di HUAC, riunita apparentemente per ottenere le 
informazioni per quanto riguarda il suo vestito del passaporto, 
Robeson rifiutato per rispondere alle domande riguardo alle sue 
attività politiche e parlato bigoted i membri di comitato Gordon H. 
Scherer ed il presidente Francis E.Walter circa storia 
Africano-Americana ed i diritti civili. In 1958, la Corte 
suprema ha regolato che la destra del cittadino viaggiare non potrebbe
essere tolta senza processo dovuto e passaporto di Robeson 'è stato 
restituito.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί αφρικανικός-αμερικανικοί μάρτυρες που 
κλητεύθηκαν για να πιστοποιήσουν στην Επιτροπή Βουλών των 
αντιαμερικανικών ακροάσεων δραστηριοτήτων (HUAC) στη δεκαετία 
του '50 κλήθηκαν να καταγγείλουν Paul Robeson (1888-1976) 
προκειμένου να λάβουν τη μελλοντική απασχόληση. Το 
Robeson, ένας όλος-αμερικανικοί παίκτης ποδοσφαίρου και ένας 
παραλήπτης ενός phi βήτα πλήκτρου καπών σε Rutgers, έλαβαν
έναν βαθμό νόμου στην Κολούμπια. Έγινε διεθνώς 
επευφημημένος εκτελεστής και δράστης συναυλίας καθώς επίσης και 
πειστικός πολιτικός ομιλητής. Το 1949, Robeson 
αποτέλεσε το αντικείμενο της διαμάχης μετά από τις εκθέσεις 
εφημερίδων των δημόσιων δηλώσεων που αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί δεν 
θα πάλευαν "σε έναν ιμπεριαλιστικό πόλεμο." Το 1950, το 
διαβατήριό του ανακλήθηκε. Αρκετά έτη αργότερα, Robeson
αρνήθηκε να υπογράψει μια ένορκη κατάθεση δηλώνοντας ότι δεν 
ήταν κομμουνιστής και άρχισε μια ανεπιτυχή δίκη. Στην 
ακόλουθη κατάθεση σε μια ακρόαση HUAC, που συγκλήθηκε 
φαινομενικά για να λάβει τις πληροφορίες σχετικά με το κοστούμι 
διαβατηρίων του, Robeson αρνήθηκε να απαντήσει στις ερωτήσεις 
σχετικά με τις πολιτικές δραστηριότητές του και τα μιλημένα 
φανατικά μέλη Gordon Χ. Scherer και πρόεδρος Francis 
E.Walter Επιτροπής για την αφρικανικός-αμερικανική ιστορία και 
τα αστικά δικαιώματα. Το 1958, το ανώτατο δικαστήριο 
διέταξε ότι το δικαίωμα ενός πολίτη να ταξιδεψει δεν θα μπορούσε
να παρθεί μαζί χωρίς οφειλόμενη διαδικασία και "το διαβατήριο 
Robeson επιστράφηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos testigos Africano-Americanos citaron para 
atestiguar en el comité de la casa sobre actividades Un-Americanas 
(HUAC) que las audiencias en los años 50 fueron pedidas denunci a 
Paul Robeson (1888-1976) para obtener el empleo futuro. Robeson,
un jugador Todo-Americano del balompié y el recipiente de un clave 
beta de Kappa de la phi en Rutgers, recibieron un grado de la ley en 
Colombia. Él hizo un ejecutante y agente internacionalmente 
aclamados del concierto así como un altavoz político persuasivo. 
En 1949, Robeson era el tema de la controversia después de que 
los informes de los periódicos de las declaraciones públicas que los
americanos africanos no lucharían en "una guerra imperialista." 
En 1950, su pasaporte fue revocado. Varios años más 
adelante, Robeson rechazó firmar una declaración jurada que indicaba
que él no era un comunista e inició un pleito fracasado. En el
testimonio siguiente a una audiencia de HUAC, aparentemente convocada 
para ganar la información con respecto a su juego del pasaporte, 
Robeson rechazado para contestar a preguntas referentes a sus 
actividades políticas y dado una conferencia bigoted a miembros del 
comité Gordon H. Scherer y presidente Francis E.Walter sobre historia
Africano-Americana y las derechas civiles. En 1958, el Tribunal 
Supremo gobernó que la derecha de un ciudadano de viajar no se 
podría quitar sin proceso debido y pasaporte de Robeson ' fue vuelto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087258</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105374</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/you-are-the-un-americans-and-you-ought-to-be-ashamed-of-yourselves-paul-robeson-appears-before-huac</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
