<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105263</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105263</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205690</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reading Rockets: Launching Young Readers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leseraketen: Ausstoßende Junge Leser</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fusées de Lecture : Jeunes Lecteurs de 
Lancement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Foguetes Da Leitura: Leitores Novos 
Lançando-se</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Razzi Della Lettura: Lettori Giovani Di 
Lancio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πύραυλοι ανάγνωσης: Προωθώντας νέοι αναγνώστες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cohetes De la Lectura: Programas de lectura 
Jóvenes Que lanzan</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features easy-to-do parent tips, video clips and transcripts from interviews with some of the nation's foremost reading experts, motivational e-cards that grandparents and teachers can send to children, a forum for sharing suggestions, booklists, and answers to key questions. This website, which accompanies the PBS Reading Rockets television series.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale einfach-zu- Elternteilspitzen, 
videoclips und Abschriften von den Interviews mit einigen der 
vordersten experten der Nation Lese, MotivEkarten, die Großeltern und
Lehrer schicken können den Kindern, einem Forum für das Teilen von 
von Vorschlägen, den Bücherverzeichnissen und den Antworten, um 
Fragen zu befestigen. Diese Web site, die die PBS Leseraketen 
Fernsehenserie begleitet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les dispositifs facile-à- des extrémités de 
parent, des clips visuels et des transcriptions des entrevues avec 
certains des premiers experts en matière de la lecture de la nation, 
les e-cartes de motivation que les grand-pères et les professeurs 
peuvent envoyer aux enfants, à un forum pour partager des 
suggestions, aux listes des livres, et aux réponses pour introduire 
des questions. Ce site Web, qui accompagne la série de 
télévision de fusées de lecture de PBS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as características fácil-à- pontas do pai, os 
grampos video e os transcripts das entrevistas com os alguns dos 
peritos foremost da leitura da nação, os e-cartões motivational que
os grandparents e os professores podem emitir às crianças, a um 
forum para compartilhar de sugestões, aos booklists, e às respostas 
para fechar à chave perguntas. Este Web site, que acompanha a 
série da televisão dos foguetes da leitura de PBS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le caratteristiche facile-$$$- punte del genitore,
video clip e le trascrizioni dalle interviste con alcuni di primi 
esperti della lettura della nazione, e-schedi motivazionali che i 
grandparents e gli insegnanti possono trasmettere ai bambini, ad una 
tribuna per la compartecipazione dei suggerimenti, agli elenchi dei 
libri ed alle risposte per impostare le domande. Questo Web 
site, che accompagna la serie della televisione dei razzi della 
lettura di PBS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα εύκολος-$$$-ΚΑΝΟΥΝ τις 
άκρες γονέων, τους τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες και τα αντίγραφα από 
τις συνεντεύξεις με μερικούς από τους πρώτιστους εμπειρογνώμονες 
ανάγνωσης του έθνους, κινητήριες ε-κάρτες που οι παππούδες και 
γιαγιάδες και οι δάσκαλοι μπορούν να στείλουν στα παιδιά, ένα 
φόρουμ για τη διανομή των προτάσεων, των καταλόγων βιβλίων, και 
των απαντήσεων στις ερωτήσεις κλειδή. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος, ο 
οποίος συνοδεύει την τηλεοπτική σειρά πυραύλων ανάγνωσης PBS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las características fa'cil-a- las extremidades 
del padre, los clips video y las transcripciones de entrevistas con 
algunos de los primeros expertos de la lectura de la nación, las 
e-tarjetas de motivación que los abuelos y los profesores pueden 
enviar a niños, a un foro para compartir sugerencias, a listas de 
libros, y a respuestas para afinar preguntas. Este Web site, que
acompaña la serie de la televisión de los cohetes de la lectura de 
PBS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205690</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105263</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/reading-rockets-launching-young-readers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
