<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104635</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104635</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086377</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Just Doing Our Job, Ma'am: Defending the State Police</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unsere Arbeit Gerade Erledigen, Ma'am: 
Verteidigen der Zustand-Polizei</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faire Juste Notre Travail, Ma'am : Défendre
la police d'état</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Apenas Fazendo Nosso Trabalho, Ma'am: 
Defendendo as polícias do estado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Appena Fare Il Nostro Lavoro, Ma'am: 
Difendere la polizia di Dichiarare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακριβώς κάνοντας την εργασία μας, Ma'am: 
Υπεράσπιση της κρατικής αστυνομίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Apenas Hacer Nuestro Trabajo, Ma'am: 
Defender al policía del estado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Labor conflicts in Pennsylvania's coal mines and steel mills during the nineteenth and early-twentieth centuries were usually violent. In order to insure that they had the upper hand and to avoid relying on local police (who were sometimes sympathetic to strikers), mine and mill operators set up their own "Coal and Iron Police" as early as the 1870s. Public reaction against these private armies led the Pennsylvania legislature to create a Department of State Police as an ostensibly more neutral and highly-trained law enforcement body. But in the 1910 strike at Bethlehem Steel, the state police proved to be as pro-management as the Coal and Iron Police, and even more brutal. George F. Lumb, deputy superintendent of the newly minted State Police, appeared before the U.S. Commission on Industrial Relations in 1915 to defend the force's reputation against accusations that they tended to side automatically with management in labor disputes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeit $überschneidungen in den Kohlengruben 
Pennsylvanias und in den Stahltausendsteln während der 19. und 
früh-zwanzigsten Jahrhunderte waren normalerweise heftig. Um zu
versichern daß sie die obere Hand hatten und auf lokale Polizei (wer 
zu bauen vermeiden zu den Schlaggeräten manchmal sympatisch waren), 
führten Grube und die Tausendstelbediener, die herauf ihre Selbst 
"Kohle-und Eisen-Polizei" schon in der allgemeinen Reaktion 1870s. 
gegen diese privaten Armeen eingestellt wurden die Pennsylvania 
Gesetzgebung ein Außenministerium Polizei als anscheinend Null- und 
hoch-ausgebildeter Gesetzdurchführungkörper zu erstellen. Aber
im Schlag 1910 am Bethlehem Stahl, prüfte die Zustandpolizei, als 
Pro-Management als die Kohle-und Eisen-Polizei und sogar brutaleres zu
sein. George F. Lumb, Abgeordnetbetriebsleiter von minted eben 
die Zustand-Polizei, geerschienen, bevor die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN auf 
industriellen Beziehungen zwischen den Sozialpartnern 1915 
beauftragen, um das Renommee der Kraft gegen Anklagen zu verteidigen, 
die sie neigten, mit Management in den arbeitsrechtlichen 
Streitigkeiten automatisch mit Seiten zu versehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les conflits de travail dans les mines de houille 
de la Pennsylvanie et les aciéries pendant les dix-neuvième et 
tôt-vingtième siècles étaient habituellement violents. Afin 
d'assurer qu'elles ont eu le dessus et pour éviter de compter sur la 
police locale (qui étaient parfois sympathiques aux butées), la mine
et les opérateurs de moulin ont installé leurs propres "charbon et 
la police de fer" dès la réaction 1870s. publique contre ces armées
privées a mené la législature de la Pennsylvanie à créer un 
service de police d'état comme corps en apparence plus neutre et 
haut-qualifié d'application de loi. Mais dans la grève 1910 à
l'acier de Bethlehem, la police d'état s'est avérée être comme 
pro-gestion en tant que la police de charbon et de fer, et bien plus 
brutal. George F. Lumb, surveillant de député de la police
nouvellement monnayée d'état, est apparu avant que les 
ETATS-UNIS commissionnent sur des relations industrielles en 1915 pour
défendre la réputation de la force contre les accusations qu'ils ont
tendu à dégrossir automatiquement avec la gestion dans des conflits 
de travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os conflitos do trabalho em minas de carvão de 
Pensilvânia e nos moinhos de aço durante os décimos nonos e 
cedo-vigésimos séculos eram geralmente violentos. A fim 
segurar que teve a mão superior e para evitar de confiar em polícias
locais (quem eram às vezes sympathetic aos grevistas), a mina e os 
operadores do moinho ajustados acima do seus próprios de "polícias 
carvão e de ferro" assim que a reação 1870s. pública de encontro a
estes exércitos confidenciais conduziram à legislatura de 
Pensilvânia criar um departamento de polícias do estado como um 
corpo ostensibly mais neutro e elevado-treinado do enforcement de lei.
Mas na batida 1910 no aço de Bethlehem, as polícias do estado 
provaram ser como a pro-gerência como as polícias de carvão e de 
ferro, e mesmo mais brutal. George F. Lumb, superintendente do 
deputado do minted recentemente as polícias do estado, aparecidas 
antes que os ESTADOS UNIDOS comissão em relações industriais em 
1915 para defender a reputação da força de encontro aos accusations
que tenderam a tom o partido automaticamente da gerência em disputas 
labor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I conflitti di lavoro nelle miniere di 
carbone della Pensilvania ed in acciaierie durante i diciannovesimi e 
presto-ventesimi secoli erano solitamente violenti. Per 
assicurare che hanno avute la mano superiore ed evitare di contare 
sulla polizia locale (chi erano a volte simpatici ai percussori), la 
miniera e gli operatori del laminatoio installano il loro propri 
"carbone e la polizia del ferro" fin dal 1870s. che la reazione del 
pubblico contro questi eserciti riservati ha condotto la legislatura 
della Pensilvania creare un reparto di Dichiara la polizia come
corpo apparentemente più neutro ed alto-addestrato di applicazione di
legge. Ma nel colpo 1910 all'acciaio de Bethlehem, la polizia di
dichiarare è risultato essere come pro-gestione come la polizia del 
ferro e del carbone ed ancor più brutale. George F. Lumb, 
soprintendente del delegato del recentemente minted Dichiara la
polizia, comparsa prima che gli STATI UNITI Commissione sulle 
relazione industriali in 1915 per difendere la reputazione della forza
contro le accuse che hanno teso a parteggiare automaticamente 
per la gestione nelle dispute di lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συγκρούσεις εργασίας στα ορυχεία άνθρακα της 
Πενσυλβανίας και τους μύλους χάλυβα κατά τη διάρκεια των δέκατων
έννατων και πρόωρος-εικοστών αιώνων ήταν συνήθως βίαιες. 
Προκειμένου να ασφαλιστεί ότι είχαν το ανώτερο χέρι και 
για να αποφύγει στην τοπική αστυνομία (που ήταν μερικές φορές 
συμπονετική στους απεργούς), το ορυχείο και οι χειριστές μύλων 
ίδρυσαν το "άνθρακά τους και η αστυνομία σιδήρου" από τη 
1870s. δημόσια αντίδραση ενάντια σε αυτούς τους ιδιωτικούς 
στρατούς οδήγησε το νομοθετικό σώμα της Πενσυλβανίας για να 
δημιουργήσει ένα τμήμα κρατικής αστυνομίας ως φαινομενικά πιό 
ουδέτερο και ιδιαίτερα-εκπαιδευμένο σώμα επιβολής νόμου. 
Αλλά στην απεργία του 1910 στο χάλυβα της Βηθλεέμ, η 
κρατική αστυνομία αποδείχθηκε ως υπέρ-διαχείριση ως αστυνομία 
άνθρακα και σιδήρου, και ακόμα πιό βάναυσος. Θ*Γεοργε F.
Lumb, αναπληρωτής επιθεωρητής πρόσφατα η κρατική αστυνομία, 
εμφανίστηκε ενώπιον της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Επιτροπής στις εργασιακές 
σχέσεις το 1915 να υπερασπίζει τη φήμη της δύναμης ενάντια 
στις κατηγορίες που έτειναν στην πλευρά αυτόματα με τη διαχείριση
στις διαφωνίες εργασίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los conflictos del trabajo en las minas de carbón
de Pennsylvania y los molinos de acero durante los diecinueveavo y 
temprano-vige'simos siglos eran generalmente violentos. Para 
asegurar que tenían la mano superior y evitar de confiar en el 
policía local (quiénes eran a veces comprensivos a los huelguistas),
la mina y los operadores del molino fijados encima sus los propios 
"policía del carbón y del hierro" desde la reacción pública 1870s.
contra estos ejércitos privados condujeron a legislatura de 
Pennsylvania a crear un departamento del policía del estado como 
cuerpo aparentemente de más neutral y de alto-entrenado de la 
aplicación de ley. Pero en la huelga 1910 en el acero de 
Bethlehem, el policía del estado demostró estar como 
favorable-gerencia como el policía del carbón y del hierro, y aún 
más brutal. George F. Lumb, superintendente del diputado del 
minted nuevamente a policía del estado, aparecido antes de que los 
ESTADOS UNIDOS Comisión en relaciones laborales en 1915 para defender
la reputación de la fuerza contra las acusaciones que tendieron para 
echar a un lado automáticamente con la gerencia en conflictos de 
trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086377</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104635</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/just-doing-our-job-maam-defending-the-state-police</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
