<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103825</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103825</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211787</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Quahog Dissection</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Quahog Zerlegung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dissection de Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dissection De Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dissezione Di Quahog</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Quahog ανατομή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Disección De Quahog</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Rhode Island Sea Grant informational page presents a descriptive guide to Quahog (a type of hard-shell clam) dissections. The page accompanies students performing a Quahog dissection, using colorful images and highlighted vocabulary terms to illustrate special features. In addition to general anatomy, the reference includes informational sections about feeding &amp; digestion and respiration &amp; circulation. Linked terms direct users to related Sea Grant web pages.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Rhode-Insel Seegrant informatorische Seite 
stellt eine beschreibende Anleitung Quahog (ein Typ Hartshell Muschel)
zu den Zerlegungen dar. Die Seite begleitet die Kursteilnehmer, 
die eine Quahog Zerlegung mit bunten Bildern und markierten 
Wortschatzbezeichnungen, spezielle Merkmale zu veranschaulichen 
durchführen. Zusätzlich zur allgemeinen Anatomie schließt die
Referenz informatorische Kapitel über das Einziehen u. Verdauung und 
Atmung u. Zirkulation ein. Gebundene Bezeichnungen verweisen 
Benutzer auf in Verbindung stehende Seegrant Webseiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page informationnelle de Grant de mer 
d'île de Rhode présente un guide descriptif des dissections de Quahog
(un type de palourde de dur-interpréteur de commandes interactif). 
La page accompagne des étudiants exécutant une dissection de 
Quahog, en utilisant des images colorées et des limites mises en 
valeur de vocabulaire pour illustrer usages spéciaux. En plus 
de l'anatomie générale, la référence inclut les sections 
informationnelles au sujet de l'alimentation et la digestion et la 
respiration et la circulation. Les limites jointes dirigent des 
utilisateurs vers les pages Web relatives de Grant de mer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta página informativa de Grant do mar do 
console de Rhode apresenta uma guia descritiva aos dissections de 
Quahog (um tipo de moluscos do duro-escudo). A página acompanha
os estudantes que executam um dissection de Quahog, usando imagens 
coloridas e termos destacados do vocabulário ilustrar 
características especiais. Além ao anatomy geral, a 
referência inclui seções informativas sobre a alimentação &amp; a 
digestão e a respiração &amp; a circulação. Os termos ligados 
dirigem usuários aos Web pages relacionados de Grant do mar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa pagina informativa del Grant del mare 
dell'Rhode-isola presenta una guida descrittiva alle dissezioni di 
Quahog (un tipo di mollusco delle duro-coperture). La pagina 
accompagna gli allievi che realizzano una dissezione di Quahog, usando
le immagini colorful ed i termini evidenziati di vocabolario per 
illustrare le caratteristiche speciali. Oltre che l'anatomia 
generale, il riferimento include le sezioni informative circa 
l'alimentazione &amp; digestione e respirazione &amp; circolazione. I 
termini collegati dirigono gli utenti verso i Web pagi relativi del 
Grant del mare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενημερωτική σελίδα επιχορήγησης θάλασσας της 
Ρόδου παρουσιάζει έναν περιγραφικό οδηγό quahog (ένας τύπος 
μαλακίου σκληρός-κοχυλιών) στις ανατομές. Η σελίδα 
συνοδεύει τους σπουδαστές που εκτελούν μια quahog ανατομή, 
χρησιμοποιώντας τις ζωηρόχρωμες εικόνες και τους τονισμένους 
όρους λεξιλογίου για να επεξηγήσει τα ειδικά χαρακτηριστικά 
γνωρίσματα. Εκτός από τη γενική ανατομία, η αναφορά 
περιλαμβάνει τα ενημερωτικά τμήματα για τη σίτιση &amp; την πέψη και 
την αναπνοή &amp; την κυκλοφορία. Συνδεμένοι άμεσοι χρήστες 
όρων σχετικές ιστοσελίδας επιχορήγησης θάλασσας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta paginación informativa de Grant del mar de 
la Rhode-isla presenta una guía descriptiva a las disecciones de 
Quahog (un tipo de almeja del duro-shell). La paginación 
acompaña a estudiantes que realizan una disección de Quahog, usando 
imágenes coloridas y términos destacados del vocabulario para 
ilustrar características especiales. Además de la anatomía 
general, la referencia incluye secciones informativas sobre la 
alimentación y digestión y respiración y circulación. Los 
términos conectados dirigen a utilizadores a los Web pages 
relacionados de Grant del mar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RHODE ISLAND SEA GRANT
FN:RHODE ISLAND SEA GRANT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211787</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103825</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/quahog-dissection</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
