<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206439</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NIH Curriculum Supplement Series</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NIH Lehrplan-Ergänzung Serie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Série de Supplément de Programme d'études de 
NIH</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Série Do Suplemento Ao Curriculum de NIH</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Serie Di Supplemento Di Programma di studi di NIH</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σειρά συμπληρωμάτων προγράμματος σπουδών NIH</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Serie Del Suplemento Del Plan de estudios de NIH</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers web-based instructional modules based on cutting-edge scientific discoveries. Topics include cell biology and cancer, infectious diseases, human genetic variation, sleep disorders, neurobiology and addiction, chemicals and the environment, alcohol, the brain and hearing, the mouth and tooth decay. Most modules are for middle and high school. Each includes inquiry-based activities and extensive background materials. Each was field tested by teachers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebote Web-gründeten die anweisenden Module, 
die auf Ausschnitt-Rand wissenschaftlichen Entdeckungen basierten. 
Themen schließen Zelle Biologie und Krebs, ansteckende 
Krankheiten, menschliche genetische Variante, Schlafstörungen, 
Neurobiologie und Neigung, Chemikalien und die Umgebung, Spiritus, das
Gehirn und die Hörfähigkeit, die Öffnung und Zahnverfall ein. 
Die meisten Module sind für mittlere und High School. 
Jedes schließt Anfrage-gegründete Aktivitäten und 
umfangreiche Hintergrundmaterialien ein. Jedes war 
auffangen geprüft durch Lehrer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les offres Web-ont basé les modules d'instruction
basés sur des découvertes scientifiques de découpage-bord. 
Les sujets incluent la biologie et le cancer de cellules, les 
maladies infectieuses, la variation génétique humaine, les 
désordres de sommeil, la neurobiologie et le penchant, les produits 
chimiques et l'environnement, alcool, le cerveau et l'audition, la 
bouche et décomposition dentaire. La plupart des modules sont 
pour le lycée moyen et. Chacun inclut des activités 
enquête-basées et des matières de base étendues. Chacune 
était zone testée par des professeurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as ofertas Web-basearam os módulos instrutivos 
baseados em descobertas científicas da corte-borda. Os tópicos
incluem a biologia e o cancer da pilha, doenças infectious, 
variação genetic humana, disorders do sono, neurobiology e 
addiction, produtos químicos e o ambiente, álcool, o cérebro e o 
hearing, a boca e deterioração de dente. A maioria de módulos
são para a High School média e. Cada um inclui atividades 
inquérito-baseadas e materiais de fundo extensivos. Cada um era
campo testado por professores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le offerte Web-hanno basato i moduli didattici 
basati sulle scoperte scientifiche del taglio-bordo. I soggetti 
includono la biologia e cancro delle cellule, malattie contagiose, 
variazione genetica umana, disordini di sonno, la neurobiologia ed 
aggiunta, prodotti chimici e l'ambiente, alcool, il cervello e 
l'udienza, la bocca e carie dentaria. La maggior parte dei 
moduli sono per la High School centrale e. Ciascuno include le 
attività inchiesta-basate ed i vasti materiali di base. 
Ciascuno era campo esaminato dagli insegnanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βασισμένες στο WEB εκπαιδευτικές ενότητες προσφορών
βασισμένες στις επιστημονικές ανακαλύψεις τέμνων-ακρών. Τα 
θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τη βιολογία και τον καρκίνο κυττάρων, τις 
μολυσματικές ασθένειες, την ανθρώπινη γενετική παραλλαγή, τις 
αναταραχές ύπνου, τη νευροβιολογία και τον εθισμό, τις χημικές 
ουσίες και το περιβάλλον, το οινόπνευμα, τον εγκέφαλο και την 
ακρόαση, το στόμα και την αποσύνθεση δοντιών. Οι 
περισσότερες ενότητες είναι για τη μέση και το γυμνάσιο. 
Κάθε ένας περιλαμβάνει τις έρευνα-βασισμένες στο 
δραστηριότητες και τα εκτενή υλικά υποβάθρου. Κάθε ένα 
ήταν πεδίο που εξετάστηκε από τους δασκάλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las ofertas Web-basaron los módulos educacionales
basados en descubrimientos científicos del corte-borde. Los 
asuntos incluyen biología y cáncer de la célula, las enfermedades 
infecciosas, variación genética humana, los desórdenes del sueño, 
neurobiología y apego, los productos químicos y el ambiente, 
alcohol, el cerebro y la audiencia, la boca y caries. La 
mayoría de los módulos están para la High School media y 
secundaria. Cada uno incluye actividades pregunta-basadas y los 
materiales de base extensos. Cada uno era campo probado por los 
profesores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206439</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103679</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nih-curriculum-supplement-series</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
