<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103537</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103537</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087488</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Class Versus Gender: Catt Taps Middle-Class and Nativist Fears to Boost Women's Causes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kategorie Gegen Geschlecht: Catt klopft 
Mittler-Kategorie und Nativist-Furcht, um Ursachen der Frauen 
aufzuladen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Classe Contre Le Genre : Catt tape des 
craintes de Moyen-Classe et de nativiste pour amplifier les causes des
femmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Classe Contra O Gender: Catt bate medos da 
Médio-Classe e do nativist para impulsionar causas das mulheres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Codice categoria Contro Il Genere: Catt 
colpisce i timori leggermente del nativist e del Centrale-Codice 
categoria per amplificare le cause delle donne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κλάση εναντίον του γένους: Μεσαία τάξη βρυσών 
Catt και φόβοι Nativist για να ωθήσει τις αιτίες των 
γυναικών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Clase Contra Género: Catt golpea 
ligeramente miedos de la Medio-Clase y del nativista para alzar las 
causas de las mujeres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1890, two competing organizations working to gain the right to vote for women joined forces to form the National American Women Suffrage Association (NAWSA). NAWSA campaigned diligently for the vote in a variety of ways, but did not achieve success until the ratification of the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution in 1920. This prolonged struggle entangled female activists in other important political and moral issues that divided the nation along racial, ethnic, and class lines, and debates over the vote for women often took a divisive tone. Some white women suffrage leaders were willing to use class, ethnic, and racial arguments to bolster the case for granting white women the vote. In 1894 (a year of extraordinary class conflict that included the national Pullman and coal strikes), Carrie Chapman Catt addressed an Iowa suffrage gathering and maintained that women's suffrage was necessary to counter "the ignorant foreign vote" in American cities and protect the life and property of native-born Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1890 verbanden zwei konkurrierende Organisationen,
die arbeiten, um das Recht zu gewinnen, für Frauen zu wählen, 
Kräfte, um die nationale amerikanische Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung 
(NAWSA) zu bilden. NAWSA warb mit Sorgfalt für die Stimme in 
einer Vielzahl von Methoden, aber erzielte Erfolg bis die Bestätigung
der 19.änderung nicht zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit 1920. 
Dieser verlängerte Kampf verwickelte weibliche Aktivisten in 
anderen wichtigen politischen und moralischen Ausgaben, die die Nation
entlang rassischem teilten, ethnisch, und in Kategorie Zeilen, und 
Debatten über der Stimme für Frauen nahmen häufig einen teilenden 
Ton. Einige weiße Fraustimmrechtführer waren bereit, die 
Kategorie, ethnisch und die rassischen Argumente zu verwenden, um den 
Kasten für bewilligende weiße Frauen zu polstern die Stimme. 
1894 (ein Jahr der außerordentlichen Kategorie widersprechen, 
daß eingeschlossen die nationalen Pullman- und Kohleschläge), 
adressierte Carrie ambulanter Händler Catt eine Iowa 
Stimmrechtversammlung und behielt bei, daß Stimmrecht der Frauen 
notwendig war, um "der unwissenden fremden Stimme" in den 
amerikanischen Städte zu widersprechen und das Leben und die 
Eigenschaft der gebürtig-getragenen Amerikaner zu schützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1890, deux organismes de concurrence 
travaillant pour gagner la droite de voter pour des femmes ont joint 
des forces pour former l'association américaine nationale de suffrage
de femmes (NAWSA). NAWSA a fait campagne diligemment pour la 
voix par une multitude de moyens, mais n'a pas réalisé le succès 
jusqu'à la ratification du dix-neuvième amendement à la 
constitution des ETATS-UNIS en 1920. Cette lutte prolongée a 
empêtré les activistes féminins dans d'autres issues importantes 
qui ont divisé la nation le long de racial, ethnique, et lignes 
politiques et morales de classe, et les discussions au-dessus de la 
voix pour des femmes ont souvent pris une tonalité séparative. 
Quelques amorces blanches de suffrage de femmes étaient 
disposées à employer la classe, ethnique, et les arguments raciaux 
pour soutenir la caisse pour les femmes blanches d'octroi la voix. 
En 1894 (une année de classe extraordinaire sont en conflit 
qu'inclus les grèves nationales de pullman et de charbon), le 
colporteur Catt de Carrie a adressé une réunion de suffrage de 
l'Iowa et a mis à jour que le suffrage des femmes était nécessaire 
pour parer "la voix étrangère ignorante" dans les villes 
américaines et pour protéger la vie et la propriété des 
Américains indigène-soutenus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1890, duas organizações competindo que 
trabalham para ganhar a direita votar para mulheres juntaram forças 
para dar forma à associação americana nacional do suffrage das 
mulheres (NAWSA). NAWSA fêz campanha diligently para o voto em 
uma variedade das maneiras, mas não conseguiu o sucesso até o 
ratification da décima nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
em 1920. Este esforço prolongado entangled activistas fêmeas 
em outras edições importantes que dividiram a nação ao longo de 
racial, étnico, e linhas políticas e morais da classe, e os debates 
sobre o voto para mulheres fizeram exame frequentemente de um tom 
divisive. Alguns líderes brancos do suffrage das mulheres eram 
dispostos usar a classe, étnica, e argumentos raciais bolster a caixa
para mulheres brancas concedendo o voto. Em 1894 (um ano da 
classe extraordinária opõe que incluído as batidas nacionais do 
Pullman e do carvão), o chapman Catt de Carrie dirigiu-se a um 
recolhimento do suffrage de Iowa e manteve-se que o suffrage das 
mulheres era necessário para opôr "o voto extrangeiro ignorant" em 
cidades americanas e para proteger a vida e a propriedade de 
americanos nativo-carregados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1890, due organizzazioni competenti che 
lavorano per guadagnare la destra votare per le donne hanno unito le 
forze per formare l'associazione americana nazionale di suffrage delle
donne (NAWSA). NAWSA ha fatto una campagna diligente per il voto
in una varietà di modi, ma non ha realizzato il successo fino alla 
ratifica della diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI
UNITI in 1920. Questa lotta prolungata ha impigliato gli 
attivisti femminili in altre edizioni importanti che hanno diviso la
nazione lungo razziale, etnico e righe politiche e morali del codice 
categoria ed i dibattiti sopra il voto per le donne hanno preso spesso
un tono che divide. Alcuni capi bianchi di suffrage delle
donne erano disposti ad usare il codice categoria, etnico e gli 
argomenti razziali per sostenere la cassa per le donne bianche 
d'assegnazione il voto. In 1894 (un anno di codice categoria 
straordinario è in conflitto che incluso i colpi nazionali del 
carbone e del pullman), il chapman Catt di Carrie ha richiamato una 
riunione di suffrage dello Iowa ed ha effettuato che il suffrage 
delle donne era necessario da ricambiare "il voto straniero ignaro" in
città americane e da proteggere la vita e la proprietà degli 
Americani natale-sopportati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1890, δύο ανταγωνιστικές οργανώσεις εργαζόμενος 
για να κερδίσει το δικαίωμα να ψηφίσει για ενωμένες τις γυναίκες 
δυνάμεις να διαμορφώσει την εθνική αμερικανική ένωση ψήφου 
γυναικών (NAWSA). NAWSA έκανε εκστρατεία επιμελώς για
την ψηφοφορία με ποικίλους τρόπους, αλλά δεν επέτυχε την 
επιτυχία μέχρι την επικύρωση της δέκατης έννατης τροποποίησης 
στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΌ σύνταγμα το 1920. Αυτή η παρατεταμένη 
προσπάθεια έμπλεξε τα θηλυκά ενεργά στελέχη σε άλλα σημαντικά 
πολιτικά και ηθικά ζητήματα που διαίρεσαν το έθνος κατά μήκος 
φυλετικού, εθνικός, και οι γραμμές κλάσης, και οι συζητήσεις 
πέρα από την ψηφοφορία για τις γυναίκες πήραν συχνά έναν 
διαχωριστικό τόνο. Μερικοί λευκοί ηγέτες ψήφου γυναικών 
ήταν πρόθυμοι να χρησιμοποιήσουν τα εθνικών, και φυλετικών 
ορίσματα κλάσης, να υποστηρίξουν την περίπτωση για στις λευκές 
γυναίκες την ψηφοφορία. Το 1894 (ένα έτος εξαιρετικής 
σύγκρουσης κλάσης που περιέλαβε τις εθνικές απεργίες Pullman 
και άνθρακα), Carrie ο γυρολόγος Catt εξέτασε μια συλλογή 
ψήφου του Iowa και υποστήριξε ότι η ψήφος των γυναικών ήταν 
απαραίτητη για να αντιμετωπίσει "την ανίδεη ξένη ψηφοφορία" στις 
αμερικανικές πόλεις και να προστατεύσει τη ζωή και την ιδιοκτησία
εγγενής-γεννημένων Αμερικανών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1890, dos organizaciones competentes que 
trabajaban para ganar la derecha de votar por mujeres ensamblaron 
fuerzas para formar la asociación americana nacional del sufragio de 
las mujeres (NAWSA). NAWSA hizo campaña diligente para el voto 
en una variedad de maneras, pero no alcanzó éxito hasta la 
ratificación de la diecinueveavo enmienda a la constitución de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1920. Esta lucha prolongada enredó a 
activistas femeninos en otras ediciones importantes que dividieron la 
nación a lo largo de racial, étnico, y líneas políticas y morales 
de la clase, y los discusiones sobre el voto para las mujeres tomaron 
a menudo un tono divisivo. Algunos arranques de cinta blancos 
del sufragio de las mujeres estaban dispuestos a utilizar la clase, 
étnica, y argumentos raciales para alentar la caja para las mujeres 
blancas que concedían el voto. En 1894 (un año de la clase 
extraordinaria está en conflicto que incluido las huelgas nacionales 
del pullman y del carbón), el chapman Catt de Carrie trató una 
reunión del sufragio de Iowa y mantuvo que el sufragio de las mujeres
era necesario contradecir "el voto no nativo ignorante" en ciudades 
americanas y proteger la vida y la característica de americanos 
nativo-llevados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087488</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103537</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/class-versus-gender-catt-taps-middle-class-and-nativist-fears-to-boost-womens-causes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
