<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107896</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107896</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086874</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Swinton's Silver Lining: Taking Comfort in the 1892 Strikes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Swintons Silbernes Futter: Nehmen des 
Komforts in den 1892 Schlägen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Doublure Argentée de Swinton : Prise du 
confort dans les 1892 grèves</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Forro De prata De Swinton: Fazendo exame do 
conforto nas 1892 batidas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rivestimento D'argento Dello Swinton: Presa 
della comodità nei 1892 colpi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ασημένια επένδυση Swinton: Λήψη της άνεσης 
στις 1892 απεργίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Guarnición De plata De Swinton: Tomar 
comodidad en las 1892 huelgas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">To many in the labor movement, the year 1892 brought only a string of defeats, as labor editor John Swinton said in this speech to the December 1892 convention of the American Federation of Labor. But Swinton managed to rally union members with an optimistic message. Although defeated, the workers who struck at Homestead and elsewhere prevented further attacks on labor in other places. Swinton, a former abolitionist, drew an analogy from the North's ultimate victory in the Civil War.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zu vielen in der Arbeiterbewegung, holte das Jahr 
1892 der Dezember 1892 Vereinbarung der amerikanischen Vereinigung der
Arbeit nur eine Zeichenkette von Niederlagen, als Arbeitsherausgeber 
John Swinton, das in dieser Rede gesagt wurde. Aber Swinton 
handhatte, Anschlußbauteile mit einer optimistischen Meldung zu 
sammeln. Obgleich besiegt, die Arbeiter, die am Gehöft 
anschlugen und anderwohin verhinderte weitere Angriffe auf Arbeit in 
anderen Plätzen. Swinton, ein ehemaliges abolitionist, 
zeichnete eine Analogie vom entscheidenden Nordsieg im Bürgerkrieg.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À beaucoup dans le mouvement de travail, l'année
1892 a apporté seulement une chaîne de caractères des défaites, en
tant qu'éditeur de travail John Swinton dit dans ce discours à la 
convention de décembre 1892 de la fédération américaine du 
travail. Mais Swinton est parvenu à rassembler des travailleurs
syndiqués avec un message optimiste. Bien que défait, les 
ouvriers qui ont frappé à la ferme et autres attaques ailleurs 
empêchées sur le travail dans d'autres endroits. Swinton, un 
ancien abolitionniste, a tiré une analogie de la victoire finale des 
nord dans la guerre civile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A muitos no movimento labor, o ano 1892 trouxe 
somente uma corda das derrotas, como o editor labor John Swinton dito 
neste discurso à convenção de dezembro 1892 do federation americano
do trabalho. Mas Swinton controlou rally membros de união com 
uma mensagem optimistic. Embora derrotado, os trabalhadores que 
golpearam no homestead e ataques mais adicionais em outra parte 
impedidos no trabalho em outros lugares. Swinton, um 
abolitionist anterior, desenhou uma analogia da vitória final norte 
na guerra civil.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A molti nel movimento di lavoro, l'anno 1892 ha 
portato soltanto una serie di sconfitte, come editore di lavoro John 
Swinton detto in questo discorso alla convenzione di dicembre del 1892
della federazione americana del Lavoro. Ma Swinton è 
riuscito a radunare i membri del sindacato con un messaggio ottimista.
Anche se sconfitto, gli operai che hanno colpito alla fattoria 
ed ulteriori attacchi altrove evitati al lavoro in altri posti. 
Swinton, un abolitionist precedente, ha dissipato un'analogia 
dall'ultima vittoria del nord nella guerra civile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε πολλά στη μετακίνηση εργασίας, το έτος 1892 
έφερε μόνο μια συμβολοσειρά των ηττών, όπως ο επεξεργαστής 
John Swinton εργασίας είπε σε αυτήν την ομιλία έως τη 
σύμβαση Δεκεμβρίου 1892 της αμερικανικής ομοσπονδίας της 
εργασίας. Αλλά Swinton κατόρθωσε να συναθροίσει τα μέλη 
ένωσης με ένα αισιόδοξο μήνυμα. Αν και νικιέται, οι 
εργαζόμενοι που χτύπησαν στο αγροτικό σπίτι και απέτρεψαν αλλού 
τις περαιτέρω επιθέσεις στην εργασία σε ισχύ άλλες. Το 
Swinton, ένας προηγούμενος ρεφορμιστής, έσυρε μια αναλογία 
από τη βόρεια τελευταία νίκη στον εμφύλιο πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A muchos en el movimiento de trabajo, el año 1892
trajo solamente una cadena de derrotas, como editor de trabajo Juan 
Swinton dicho en este discurso a la convención de diciembre de 1892 
de la federación americana del trabajo. Pero Swinton manejó 
reunir a miembros de unión con un mensaje optimista. Aunque 
está derrotado, los trabajadores que pulso en la granja y ataques 
posteriores a otra parte prevenidos contra trabajo en otros lugares. 
Swinton, un abolitionist anterior, trazó una analogía de la 
última victoria del norte en la guerra civil.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086874</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107896</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/swintons-silver-lining-taking-comfort-in-the-1892-strikes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
