<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103423</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087324</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Mule Spinner Tells the U.S. Senate about Late 19th century Unemployment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Maultier-Spinner erklärt den VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Senat über des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert 
Arbeitslosigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un fileur de mule dit le sénat des ETATS-UNIS au 
sujet du fin du 19me chômage de siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um spinner da mula diz o senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
sobre o desemprego atrasado do 1ø século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un filatore del mulo dice al senato degli STATI 
UNITI circa fine del 19esimo disoccupazione di secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας κλώστης μουλαριών λέει την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ Σύγκλητο 
για του 19$ου αργά την ανεργία αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un hilandero de la mula dice el senado de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS sobre el desempleo de la a fines del siglo XIX</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Fall River, Massachusetts, mill worker Thomas O'Donnell (who had immigrated to the U.S. from England eleven years earlier) appeared before the U.S. Senate Committee on Education and Labor on October 18, 1883, to answer the panel's questions about working-class economic conditions. An unemployed mule spinner for more than half of the year, he described the introduction of new production methods at the Fall River, Massachusetts, textile factory where he worked as a mule spinner (a worker who tended the large yarn-making machines). These changes allowed the mill's owners to employ children, and they also left the mule spinner unemployed for much of the year. O'Donnell described the sharp decline in his family's living standards that followed and the ways they struggled to make ends meet.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fall-River, Massachusetts, Tausendstelarbeiter 
Thomas O'Donnell (wer in die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN von England elf Jahre
früher eingewandert hatte), schien bevor der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Senat-Ausschuß für Ausbildung und Arbeit an Oktober 18, 1883, die 
Fragen des Panels über Wirtschaftslage der Arbeiterklasse zu 
beantworten. Ein arbeitsloser Maultierspinner für mehr als 
Jahreshälfte, beschrieb er die Einleitung der neuen Produktion 
Methoden im Fall-River, Massachusetts, Textilfabrik, in dem er als 
Maultierspinner arbeitete (ein Arbeiter, der die großen 
Garn-bildenden Maschinen neigte). Diese Änderungen ließen die 
Inhaber des Tausendstels Kinder auch beschäftigen und sie nach links 
die Maultierspinnerarbeitslosen für viel des Jahres. O'Donnell 
beschrieb die scharfe Abnahme in lebenden Standards seiner Familie, 
die folgten und in den Methoden, die sie kämpften, um Enden treffen 
zu lassen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fall River, le Massachusetts, l'ouvrier Thomas 
o'Donnell (qui de moulin avait immigré aux ETATS-UNIS d'Angleterre 
onze ans plus tôt) a semblé avant que le comité de sénat des 
ETATS-UNIS de l'éducation et du travail 18 octobre 1883, répondre 
aux questions du panneau au sujet des états économiques de classe 
ouvrier. Un fileur sans emploi de mule pour plus que le 
semestre, il a décrit l'introduction de nouvelles méthodes de 
production à Fall River, le Massachusetts, usine de textile où il a 
travaillé en tant que fileur de mule (un ouvrier qui a tendu les 
grandes machines defabrication). Ces changements ont permis aux 
propriétaires du moulin d'employer des enfants, et à eux également 
à gauche les chômeurs de fileur de mule pour une grande partie de 
l'année. o'Donnell a décrit le déclin pointu dans les normes 
vivantes de sa famille qui ont suivi et les voies qu'elles ont lutté 
pour faire des extrémités rencontrer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O rio da queda, Massachusetts, o trabalhador 
Thomas O'Donnell do moinho (quem immigrated aos ESTADOS UNIDOS de 
Inglaterra onze anos mais adiantado) pareceu antes que o comitê do 
senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na instrução e no trabalho outubro em 18, 
1883, responder às perguntas do painel sobre condições econômicas 
do working-class. Um spinner unemployed da mula para mais do que
a metade do ano, descreveu a introdução de métodos de produção 
novos no rio da queda, Massachusetts, fábrica de textile onde 
trabalhou como um spinner da mula (um trabalhador que tendesse as 
máquinas fio-fazendo grandes). Estas mudanças permitiram que 
os proprietários do moinho empregassem crianças, e também à 
esquerda os desempregados do spinner da mula para muito do ano. 
O'Donnell descreveu o declínio afiado nos padrões vivos da sua
família que seguiram e nas maneiras que se esforçou para fazer 
extremidades se encontrar com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fall River, Massachusetts, operaio Thomas 
O'Donnell (chi del laminatoio immigrated negli STATI UNITI 
dall'Inghilterra undici anni più in anticipo) è sembrato prima del 
comitato del senato degli STATI UNITI di formazione e del Lavoro 
il 18 ottobre 1883, rispondere alle domande del pannello circa gli 
stati economici della classe operaia. Un filatore disoccupato 
del mulo per più del semestre, ha descritto l'introduzione di nuovi 
metodi di produzione a Fall River, Massachusetts, fabbrica della 
tessile in cui ha lavorato come filatore del mulo (un operaio che ha 
teso le grandi macchine filato-facenti). Questi cambiamenti 
hanno permesso che i proprietari del laminatoio impiegassero i bambini
e anche a sinistra i disoccupati del filatore del mulo per gran parte 
dell'anno. O'Donnell ha descritto il declino tagliente negli 
standard viventi della sua famiglia che sono seguito e nei modi che 
hanno lottato per fare le estremità venire a contatto di.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Φωλλ Ρίβερ, Μασαχουσέτη, εργαζόμενος Thomas 
O'Donnell μύλων (που είχε μεταναστεύσει στις ΗΠΑ από την 
Αγγλία ένδεκα έτη νωρίτερα) εμφανίστηκε ενώπιον της Επιτροπής 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉΣ Συγκλήτου της εκπαίδευσης και της εργασίας στις 18
Οκτωβρίου ..1883, να απαντά στις ερωτήσεις της επιτροπής για 
τους οικονομικούς όρους εργατικών τάξεων. Ένας άνεργος 
κλώστης μουλαριών για περισσότερο από το μισό από το έτος, 
περιέγραψε την εισαγωγή των νέων μεθόδων παραγωγής στο Φωλλ 
Ρίβερ, Μασαχουσέτη, υφαντικό εργοστάσιο όπου εργάστηκε ως 
κλώστης μουλαριών (ένας εργαζόμενος που έτεινε τις μεγάλες 
μηχανές νήμα-παραγωγής). Αυτές οι αλλαγές επέτρεψαν στους 
ιδιοκτήτες του μύλου για να απασχολήσουν τα παιδιά, και αυτές 
επίσης αριστερά οι άνεργοι κλωστών μουλαριών για ένα μεγάλο 
μέρος του έτους. Τα O'Donnell περιέγραψαν την αιχμηρή 
πτώση με το βιοτικό επίπεδο της οικογένειάς του που ακολούθησαν 
και τους τρόπους που αγωνίστηκαν να κάνουν τις άκρες να 
ανταποκριθούν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El río de la caída, Massachusetts, el trabajador
Thomas O'Donnell (quién del molino immigrated a los ESTADOS UNIDOS de
Inglaterra once años anterior) aparecía antes de que el comité del 
senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre la educación y el trabajo de octubre 
el 18 de 1883, contestar a las preguntas del panel sobre condiciones 
económicas de la clase obrera. Un hilandero parado de la mula 
para más que la mitad del año, él describió la introducción de 
los nuevos métodos de producción en el río de la caída, 
Massachusetts, fábrica del textil en donde él trabajó como 
hilandero de la mula (trabajador que tendió a las máquinas de 
hilado-fabricacio'n grandes). Estos cambios permitieron que los 
propietarios del molino emplearan a niños, y ellos también a la 
izquierda los parados del hilandero de la mula por mucho del año. 
O'Donnell describió la declinación sostenida en los 
estándares vivos de su familia que siguieron y las maneras que ella 
luchó para hacer que los extremos resuelven.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087324</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103423</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-mule-spinner-tells-the-u-s-senate-about-late-19th-century-unemployment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
