<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104126</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104126</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206936</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Library of Medicine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale Bibliothek von Medizin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bibliothèque nationale de médecine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biblioteca nacional da medicina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Libreria nazionale di medicina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική βιβλιοθήκη της ιατρικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biblioteca nacional de la medicina</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the entry point to the largest medical library in the world. Find answers to health questions, abstracts from 4300 biomedical journals, information about clinical research studies, a directory of health organizations, a catalog of books, journals, and audiovisuals in the NLM collections, a single web interface that searches multiple NLM retrieval systems, and additional information by subject.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Einsprungadresse zur größten 
medizinischen Bibliothek in der Welt. Entdeckungantworten zu den
Gesundheit Fragen, zu den Auszügen von 4300 biomedizinischen 
Journalen, zu den Informationen über klinische Forschung Studien, zu 
einem Verzeichnis der Gesundheit Organisationen, zu einem Katalog der 
Bücher, zu den Journalen und zu den audiovisuals in den NLM 
Ansammlungen, in einer einzelnen Web-Schnittstelle, die mehrfache NLM 
Informations-Retrievalsysteme sucht und in den zusätzlichen 
Informationen durch Thema.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le point d'entrée à la plus grande 
bibliothèque médicale dans le monde. Réponses de trouvaille 
aux questions de santé, aux résumés de 4300 journaux biomédicaux, 
aux informations sur des études cliniques de recherches, à un 
répertoire des organismes de santé, à un catalogue des livres, aux 
journaux, et aux audiovisuals dans les collections de NLM, une 
interface simple de Web qui recherche les systèmes de recherche 
multiples de NLM, et l'information supplémentaire par le sujet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o ponto de entrada à biblioteca médica a 
maior no mundo. Respostas do achado às perguntas de saúde, aos
sumários de 4300 jornais biomedical, à informação sobre estudos 
clínicos da pesquisa, a um diretório de organizações da saúde, a 
um catálogo dos livros, aos jornais, e aos audiovisuals nas 
coleções de NLM, em uma única relação do Web que procurare 
sistemas de recuperação múltiplos de NLM, e na informação 
adicional pelo assunto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il punto di entrata alla più grande libreria 
medica nel mondo. Risposte del ritrovamento ai problemi 
sanitari, agli estratti da 4300 pubblicazioni biomediche, alle 
informazioni sugli studi clinici di ricerca, ad un indice delle 
organizzazioni di salute, ad un catalogo dei libri, alle pubblicazioni
ed ai audiovisuals nelle collezioni di NLM, in una singola interfaccia
di Web che cerca i sistemi di ricerca dell'informazione multipli di 
NLM e nelle informazioni supplementari dall'oggetto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι το σημείο εισόδων στη μεγαλύτερη ιατρική 
βιβλιοθήκη στον κόσμο. Βρείτε τις απαντήσεις στις ερωτήσεις
υγείας, περιλήψεις από 4300 βιοϊατρικά περιοδικά, 
πληροφορίες για τις κλινικές ερευνητικές μελέτες, ένας κατάλογος
αρχείων των οργανώσεων υγείας, ένας κατάλογος των βιβλίων, των 
περιοδικών, και των audiovisuals στις NLM συλλογές, μια 
ενιαία διαπροσωπεία Ιστού που ψάχνει τα πολλαπλάσια συστήματα 
ανάκτησης NLM, και πρόσθετες πληροφορίες από το θέμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">está el punto de entrada a la biblioteca médica 
más grande del mundo. Respuestas del hallazgo a las preguntas 
de salud, a los extractos a partir de 4300 diarios biomédicos, a la 
información sobre estudios clínicos de la investigación, a un 
directorio de las organizaciones de la salud, a un catálogo de 
libros, a los diarios, y a los audiovisuals en las colecciones de NLM,
un solo interfaz del Web que busca sistemas de extracción múltiples 
de NLM, y la información adicional por el tema.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206936</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104126</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-library-of-medicine</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
