<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106942</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106942</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Word Has Just Been Received": Truman Speaks on the Railroad Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wort Ist Gerade" Empfangen worden: Truman 
spricht über den Eisenbahn-Schlag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le "Mot A été juste reçu" : Truman parle 
de la grève de chemin de fer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A "Palavra Foi recebida Apenas": Truman fala
na batida da estrada de ferro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Parola È stata ricevuta Appena": Truman
parla sul colpo della ferrovia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το Word παραλήφθηκε μόλισ": Το Truman μιλά
στην απεργία σιδηροδρόμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Acaba de Recibirse La "Palabra": Truman 
habla en la huelga del ferrocarril</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Unions that continued to press beyond the general labor settlements established in the auto and steel industries after World War II found themselves facing an additional and powerful adversary--the federal government. In the spring of 1946, both coal miners and railroad workers staged nationwide strikes. President Harry Truman decided that the unions had gone too far, and after the railroad workers rejected a settlement, he seized control of the railroads. Despite the government takeover, the workers continued with their strike plans. As a result, on May 24, 1946, Truman issued an ultimatum declaring that the government would operate the railroads and use the army as strikebreakers. When the deadline passed, Truman went before Congress to seek the power to deny seniority rights to strikers and to draft strikers into the armed forces. Just as Truman reached the climax of his speech, he received a note saying that the strike was "settled on the terms proposed by the President." After the congressional cheers died down, Truman proceeded with his prepared text.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anschlüße, die fortfuhren, sich über den 
allgemeinen Arbeitsregelungen hinaus zu betätigen, die in den Selbst-
und Stahlindustrien nach dem Zweiten Weltkrieg hergestellt wurden, 
fanden sich, einen zusätzlichen und leistungsfähigen Gegner 
gegenüberzustellen -- die Bundesregierung. Im Früjahr von 
1946, inszenierten Kohlebergmänner und Eisenbahnarbeiter allgemein 
Schläge. Präsident Harry Truman entschied, daß die 
Anschlüße zu weit gegangen waren, und nachdem die Eisenbahnarbeiter 
eine Regelung zurückwiesen, ergriff er Steuerung der Eisenbahnen. 
Trotz der Regierung Übernahme fuhren die Arbeiter mit ihren 
Schlagplänen fort. Infolgedessen an Mai 24, 1946, Truman gab 
einen Ultimatum heraus, der erklärt, daß die Regierung die 
Eisenbahnen laufen lassen und die Armee als Streikbrecher verwenden 
würde. Als der Stichtag überschritt, ging Truman bevor 
Kongreß, die Energie zu suchen, Alterrechte zu den Schlaggeräten und
zu den Entwurfschlaggeräten in die bewaffneten Kräfte zu verweigern.
Gerade da Truman den Höhepunkt seiner Rede erreichte, empfing 
er einen Anmerkung Saying, daß der Schlag "auf den Bezeichnungen 
vereinbart wurde, die vorgeschlagen wurden vom Präsidenten." 
Nachdem der Kongreßbeifall unten starb, fuhr Truman mit seinem 
vorbereiteten Text fort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les syndicats qui ont continué à appuyer au 
delà des règlements de travail généraux établis dans les 
industries automatiques et sidérurgiques après la deuxième guerre 
mondiale se sont trouvés faire face à un adversaire supplémentaire 
et puissant -- le gouvernement fédéral. Au printemps de 1946, 
les mineurs et les ouvriers de chemin de fer ont mis en scène des 
grèves dans tout le pays. Le Président Harry Truman a décidé
que les syndicats étaient allés trop loin, et après que les 
ouvriers de chemin de fer aient rejeté un règlement, il a saisi la 
commande des chemins de fer. En dépit du changement de 
gouvernement, les ouvriers ont continué leurs plans de grève. 
En conséquence, 24 mai 1946, Truman a émis un ultimatum 
déclarant que le gouvernement actionnerait les chemins de fer et 
utiliserait l'armée comme briseurs de grève. Quand la 
date-limite a passé, Truman est allé avant que le congrès 
rechercher la puissance de nier des juste d'ancienneté aux butées et
aux butées d'ébauche dans les forces armées. Juste comme 
Truman atteignait l'apogée de son discours, il a reçu une 
énonciation de note que la grève "a été réglée aux conditions 
proposées par le président." Après que les acclamations 
congressionnelles soient mortes vers le bas, Truman s'est poursuivi 
par son texte rédigé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As uniões que continuaram a pressionar além dos 
estabelecimentos labor gerais estabelecidos nas auto e indústrias de 
aço após a segunda guerra mundial encontraram-se enfrentar um 
adversário adicional e poderoso -- o governo federal. Na mola 
de 1946,  os mineiros de carvão e os trabalhadores da estrada de 
ferro encenaram batidas de âmbito nacional. O presidente Harry 
Truman decidiu-se que as uniões tinham ido demasiado distante, e 
depois que os trabalhadores da estrada de ferro rejeitaram um 
estabelecimento, apreendeu o controle das estradas de ferro. 
Apesar do takeover do governo, os trabalhadores continuaram com 
suas plantas da batida. Em conseqüência, maio em 24, 1946, 
Truman emitiu um ultimatum que declara que o governo operaria as 
estradas de ferro e usaria o exército como strikebreakers. 
Quando o fim do prazo passou, Truman foi antes que congress 
procurar a potência negar direitas da antigüidade aos grevistas e 
aos grevistas do esboço nas forças armadas. Apenas porque 
Truman alcançou o climax de seu discurso, recebeu um provérbio da 
nota que a batida "estêve estabelecida nos termos propostos pelo 
presidente." Depois que os cheers congressionais morreram para 
baixo, Truman proseguiu com seu texto preparado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I sindacati che hanno continuato a premere oltre 
gli stabilimenti di lavoro generali hanno stabilito nelle industrie 
siderurgiche automatiche e dopo la seconda guerra mondiale si sono 
scoperti che affrontano un avversario supplementare e potente -- il 
governo federale. Nella primavera di 1946, sia i minatori delle 
miniere di carbone che gli operai della ferrovia hanno organizzato i 
colpi nazionali. Il presidente Harry Truman ha deciso che i 
sindacati erano andato troppo lontano e dopo che gli operai della 
ferrovia rifiutassero uno stabilimento, ha grippato il controllo delle
ferrovie. Malgrado il cambio di gestione di governo, gli operai 
sono continuato con i loro programmi di colpo. Di conseguenza, 
maggio su 24, 1946, Truman ha pubblicato un ultimatum che dichiara che
il governo farebbe funzionare le ferrovie ed userebbe l'esercito come 
crumiri. Quando la scadenza ha passato, Truman è andato prima 
che congresso cercare l'potenza negare i diritti di anzianità ai 
percussori ed ai percussori della brutta copia nelle forze munite. 
Appena poichè Truman ha raggiunto il punto culminante del suo 
discorso, ha ricevuto un detto della nota che il colpo "è stato 
regolato alle condizioni proposte dal presidente." Dopo che le 
acclamazioni congressuali muoiano giù, Truman ha proceduto al suo 
testo redatto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώσεις που συνέχισαν να πατούν πέρα από τις γενικές
τακτοποιήσεις εργασίας που καθιερώθηκαν στο αυτοκίνητο και τις 
χαλυβουργίες αφότου βρέθηκε ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος ΙΙ έναν 
πρόσθετο και ισχυρό αντίπαλο -- η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση. 
Την άνοιξη του 1946, και οι ανθρακωρύχοι και οι 
εργαζόμενοι σιδηροδρόμου οργάνωσαν τις σε εθνικό επίπεδο 
απεργίες. Ο Πρόεδρος Harry Truman αποφάσισε ότι οι 
ενώσεις είχαν πάει πάρα πολύ μακριά, και αφότου απέρριψαν οι 
εργαζόμενοι σιδηροδρόμου μια τακτοποίηση, πήρε τον έλεγχο των 
σιδηροδρόμων. Παρά την κυβερνητική ανάληψη, οι εργαζόμενοι 
συνεχίστηκαν με τα σχέδια απεργίας τους. Κατά συνέπεια, σε 
Μάιος 24 ..1946, Truman εξέδωσε μια τελεγραφική 
δήλωση ότι η κυβέρνηση θα ενεργοποιούσε τους σιδηροδρόμους και θα
χρησιμοποιούσε το στρατό ως strikebreakers. Όταν η 
προθεσμία πέρασε, Truman πήγε πριν από το συνέδριο να 
επιδιώξει τη δύναμη να αμφισβητηθούν τα δικαιώματα αρχαιότητας 
στους απεργούς και στους απεργούς σχεδίων στις οπλισμένες 
δυνάμεις. Ακριβώς όπως Truman που επιτεύχθηκε το 
αποκορύφωμα της ομιλίας του, έλαβε μια σημείωση λέγοντας ότι η 
απεργία "εγκαταστάθηκε στους όρους που προτάθηκαν από τον 
Πρόεδρο." Αφότου πέθαναν κάτω οι του Κογκρέσου ευθυμίες, 
Truman συνέχισε με το έτοιμο κείμενό του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las uniones que continuaron presionando más allá
de los establecimientos de trabajo generales establecidos en las 
industrias auto y de acero después de la Segunda Guerra Mundial se 
encontraron el hacer frente de un adversario adicional y de gran 
alcance -- el gobierno federal. En el resorte de 1946, los 
mineros de carbón y los trabajadores del ferrocarril efectuaron 
huelgas a nivel nacional. Presidente Harry Truman decidía que 
habían ido las uniones demasiado lejos, y después de que los 
trabajadores del ferrocarril rechazaran un establecimiento, él 
agarró el control de los ferrocarriles. A pesar de la toma de 
posesión del gobierno, los trabajadores continuaron con sus planes de
la huelga. Consecuentemente, 24 de mayo de 1946, Truman 
publicó un ultimatum que declaraba que el gobierno funcionaría los 
ferrocarriles y utilizaría a ejército como rompehuelgas. 
Cuando el plazo pasó, Truman fue antes de que congreso a buscar
la potencia de negar las derechas de la precedencia a los huelguistas 
y a los huelguistas del bosquejo en las fuerzas armadas. Apenas 
pues Truman alcanzó el clímax de su discurso, él recibió un 
refrán de la nota que la huelga "fue colocada en los términos 
propuestos por el presidente." Después de que las aclamaciones 
del congreso murieran abajo, Truman procedió con su texto preparado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106942</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/word-has-just-been-received-truman-speaks-on-the-railroad-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
