<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105812</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105812</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200678</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bioluminescence: Living Light</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bioluminescence: Lebendes Licht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bioluminescence : Lumière Vivante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bioluminescence: Luz Viva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bioluminescence: Luce Vivente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βιολογική ακτινοβολία: Φως διαβίωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bioluminescence: Luz Viva</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This National Geographic lesson plan explores bioluminescent creatures and the underwater world in which they live. Using shoeboxes and black paint, students are directed to build a deep-sea model and inhabit it with fish made out of black construction paper. Students then use the model to describe how organisms use bioluminescence and learn about its use as camouflage. In addition to a detailed protocol, the lesson plan includes suggestions for assessments and links to additional information.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser nationale geographische Lektionplan 
erforscht bioluminescent Geschöpfe und die Unterwasserwelt, in denen 
sie leben. Mit shoeboxes und schwarzer Farbe werden 
Kursteilnehmer beauftragen, ein Tiefseemodell aufzubauen und es mit 
den Fischen zu bewohnen, die aus schwarzem Skizzenpapier heraus 
gebildet werden. Kursteilnehmer benutzen dann das Modell, um zu 
beschreiben, wie organismen bioluminescence verwenden und über seinen
Gebrauch als Tarnung erlernen. Zusätzlich zu einem 
ausführlichen Protokoll schließt der Lektionplan Vorschläge für 
Einschätzungen und Links zu den zusätzlichen Informationen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce plan géographique national de leçon explore 
les créatures bioluminescent et le monde sous-marin dans lesquels ils
vivent. En utilisant les shoeboxes et la peinture noire, des 
étudiants sont dirigés établir un modèle hauturier et l'habiter 
avec des poissons fabriqués à partir de le papier de construction 
noir. Les étudiants emploient alors le modèle pour décrire 
comment les organizations utilisent le bioluminescence et se 
renseignent sur son utilisation en tant que camouflage. En plus 
d'un protocole détaillé, le plan de leçon inclut des suggestions 
pour des évaluations et des liens à l'information supplémentaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta planta geográfica nacional da lição 
explora as criaturas bioluminescent e o mundo subaquático em que 
vivem. Usando shoeboxes e a pintura preta, os estudantes são 
dirigidos construir um modelo deep-sea e habitá-lo com os peixes 
feitos fora do papel de construção preto. Os estudantes usam 
então o modelo descrever como os organismos usam o bioluminescence e 
o aprendem sobre seu uso como camuflar. Além a um protocolo 
detalhado, a planta da lição inclui sugestões para avaliações e 
ligações à informação adicional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma geografico nazionale di lezione 
esplora le creature bioluminescent ed il mondo subacqueo in cui 
vivono. Usando gli shoeboxes e la vernice nera, gli allievi sono
diretti sviluppare un modello di alto mare ed abitarli con i pesci 
fatti dalla carta da costruzione nera. Gli allievi allora usano 
il modello per descrivere come gli organismi usano il bioluminescence 
ed imparano circa il relativo uso come camuffamento. Oltre che 
un protocollo dettagliato, il programma di lezione include i 
suggerimenti per le valutazioni ed i collegamenti alle informazioni 
supplementari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το εθνικό γεωγραφικό σχέδιο μαθήματος εξερευνά 
τα βιοφωτοβόλα πλάσματα και τον υποβρύχιο κόσμο στους οποίους 
ζουν. Χρησιμοποιώντας shoeboxes και το μαύρο χρώμα, 
σπουδαστές κατευθύνεται για να χτίσει ένα βαθύβιο μοντέλο και να
κατοικήσει σε το με τα ψάρια που γίνονται από το μαύρο έγγραφο 
κατασκευής. Οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν έπειτα το μοντέλο 
για να περιγράψουν πώς οι οργανισμοί χρησιμοποιούν τη βιολογική 
ακτινοβολία και μαθαίνουν για τη χρήση του ως κάλυψη. Εκτός
από ένα λεπτομερές πρωτόκολλο, το σχέδιο μαθήματος περιλαμβάνει
τις προτάσεις για τις αξιολογήσεις και τις συνδέσεις με τις 
πρόσθετες πληροφορίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan geográfico nacional de la lección 
explora las criaturas bioluminescent y el mundo subacuático en 
quienes viven. Usando shoeboxes y la pintura negra, ordenan a 
los estudiantes construir un modelo de alta mar y habitarlo con los 
pescados hechos fuera del papel de construcción negro. Los 
estudiantes entonces utilizan el modelo para describir cómo los 
organismos utilizan bioluminescence y aprenden sobre su uso como 
camuflaje. Además de un protocolo detallado, el plan de la 
lección incluye las sugerencias para los gravámenes y las conexiones
a la información adicional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC XPEDITIONS
FN:NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC XPEDITIONS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200678</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105812</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/bioluminescence-living-light</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
