<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102888</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102888</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207201</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Saratoga: The Tide Turns on the Frontier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Saratoga: Die Gezeiten schalten die 
Grenze ein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Saratoga : La marée allume la frontière</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Saratoga: A maré gira sobre a fronteira</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Saratoga: La marea accende la frontiera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Saratoga: Η παλίρροια ανοίγει τα σύνορα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Saratoga: La marea gira la frontera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Describes the two Battles of Saratoga. The two battles and surrender of the British in October of 1777 are often called the turning point of the American Revolution because they showed France that the ragtag Continental Army could win against Britain's well trained, disciplined troops. Within months (Feb. of 1778), France signed accords with Ben Franklin and other American envoys in Paris recognizing America's Declaration of Independence and pledging full military and financial support.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beschreibt die zwei Schlachten von Saratoga. 
Die zwei Schlachten und Auslieferung der Briten im Oktober von 
1777 werden häufig der Drehpunkt der amerikanischen Umdrehung 
benannt, weil sie Frankreich, daß das ragtag kontinentale Armee gegen
gut ausgebildetes Großbritannien gewinnen könnte, disziplinierte 
Truppen zeigten. Innerhalb der Monate (Feb. von 1778), 
unterzeichnete Frankreich Übereinstimmungen mit Ben Franklin und 
andere amerikanische Abgesandte in Paris, das 
Unabhängigkeitserklärung Amerikas erkennt und vollen militärischen 
und finanziellen Support verspricht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Décrit les deux batailles de Saratoga. Les 
deux batailles et redditions des Anglais en octobre de 1777 
s'appellent souvent le tournant de la révolution américaine parce 
qu'elles ont montré la France que le ragtag armée continentale 
pourrait gagner contre la Grande-Bretagne bien élevée, troupes 
disciplinées. Dans les mois (fév. de 1778), la France a signé
des ententes avec Ben Franklin et d'autres délégués américains à 
Paris identifiant la déclaration de l'Amérique de l'indépendance et
mettant en gage l'aide financière militaire et totale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Descreve as duas batalhas de Saratoga. As 
duas batalhas e rendições dos Ingleses em outubro de 1777 são 
chamadas frequentemente o ponto de giro da volta americana porque 
mostraram France que o ragtag exército continental poderia ganhar de 
encontro a Grâ Bretanha bem treinado, tropas disciplinadas. 
Dentro dos meses (fevereiro de 1778), France assinou acordos com
Ben Franklin e outros envoys americanos em Paris que reconhece a 
declaração de América de independência e que promete a 
sustentação militar e financeira cheia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Descrive le due battaglie di Saratoga. Le 
due battaglie e rese dei Britannici in ottobre di 1777 sono chiamate 
spesso la svolta della rivoluzione americana perché hanno mostrato la
Francia che il ragtag esercito continentale potrebbe vincere contro la
Gran-Bretagna ben educata, truppe disciplinate. Entro i mesi 
(febbraio di 1778), la Francia ha firmato gli accordi con Ben Franklin
ed altri envoys americani a Parigi che riconosce la dichiarazione 
dell'America di indipendenza e che impegna il contributo finanziario 
militare e completo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιγράφει τις δύο μάχες Saratoga. Οι δύο 
μάχες και η παράδοση των Βρετανών τον Οκτώβριο 1777 καλούνται 
συχνά κρίσιμη καμπή της αμερικανικής επανάστασης επειδή 
εμφάνισαν στη Γαλλία ότι το ragtag ηπειρωτικός στρατός θα 
μπορούσε να κερδίσει ενάντια της Μεγάλης Βρετανίας που 
εκπαιδεύθηκε καλά, πειθαρχημένα στρατεύματα. Μέσα στους 
μήνες (ο Φεβρ. 1778), υπογεγραμμένες η Γαλλία συμφωνίες με 
Ben Franklin και άλλα αμερικανικά envoys στο Παρίσι που 
αναγνωρίζει τη Διακήρυξη της Αμερικής της ανεξαρτησίας και που 
δεσμεύει την πλήρη στρατιωτική και οικονομική ενίσχυση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Describe las dos batallas de Saratoga. Las 
dos batallas y entregas de los Británicos en octubre de 1777 se 
llaman a menudo el momento crucial de la revolución americana porque 
mostraron Francia que el ragtag ejército continental podría ganar 
contra Gran Bretaña bien ensen$ada, tropas disciplinadas. 
Dentro de los meses (febrero de 1778), Francia firmó acordar 
con Ben Franklin y otros envoys americanos en París que reconocía el
declaración de la independencia de América y que prometía la ayuda 
militar y financiera completa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207201</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102888</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/saratoga-the-tide-turns-on-the-frontier</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
