<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105134</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105134</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087079</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Workers, Once Again, Seem to Have Fallen by the Wayside:" The Impact of September 11th on Airline Workers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Arbeiter scheinen noch einmal, durch das 
Wayside gefallen zu sein:" Die Auswirkung von September 11. auf 
Fluglinie Arbeiter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les ouvriers, de nouveau, semblent être tombés 
par le Bord de la route :" L'impact du 11 septembre sur des ouvriers 
de ligne aérienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"os trabalhadores, uma vez que outra vez, pareça 
ter caído pelo Wayside:" O impacto setembro de 11o em 
trabalhadores da linha aérea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"gli operai, ancora una volta, sembrano cadere dal
Wayside:" L'effetto del del 11 settembre sugli operai di linea 
aerea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι εργαζόμενοι, άλλη μια φορά, φαίνονται να πέφτουν 
από το κράσπεδο:" Ο αντίκτυπος της 11ης Σεπτεμβρίου στους 
εργαζομένους αερογραμμών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"los trabajadores, se parecen de nuevo haber 
caído por el Wayside:" El impacto del de septiembre 11 en 
trabajadores de la línea aérea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The economic impact of the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks on the World Trade Center most immediately affected workers in the airline and tourist industries. The airlines, like much of the U.S. economy, were already experiencing an economic slowdown after the boom years of the late 1990s. Within weeks of the attack, airlines laid off tens of thousands of workers and threatened to lay off more. President George W. Bush and the U.S. Congress quickly responded, offering $5 billion in cash grants and promising more. Earlier precedents, such as the $1.5 billion government bailout for the Chrylser Corporation in 1979-80, were based on the need to avoid severe job losses and economic turmoil, yet in the case of Chrysler nearly half of the hourly workers lost their jobs despite the bailout. In this interview, "Joshua DeVries," an airline employee, describes workers' reaction to the lay offs and government response.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die ökonomische Auswirkung des Septembers 11, 
2001 Terroristangriffe auf den betroffenen Arbeitern der 
Welthandel-Mitte sofort in der Fluglinie und in den Touristengewerben.
Die Fluglinien, wie viel der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Wirtschaft, 
erfuhren bereits eine ökonomische Verlangsamung nach den 
Hochkonjunkturjahren der späten neunziger Jahre innerhalb der Wochen 
des Angriffs, Fluglinien abgelegte 10 Tausenden Arbeiter und bedroht, 
um mehr abzulegen. Präsident George W. Bush und der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Kongreß reagierte schnell, bot $5 Milliarde in den 
Bargeldbewilligungen an und verspricht mehr. Frühere 
Präzedenzfälle, wie die Regierung $1.5 Milliarde Sicherheitsleistung
für Chrylser Corporation 1979-80, basierten auf der Notwendigkeit, 
strenge Jobverluste und ökonomischen Tumult zu vermeiden, dennoch im 
Fall Chrysler fast von der Hälfte der stündlichen Arbeiter verlor 
ihre Jobs trotz der Sicherheitsleistung. In diesem Interview 
"Joshua DeVries," ein Fluglinie Angestellter, beschreibt Reaktion der 
Arbeiter zu den Lage offs und zur Regierung Antwort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'impact économique septembre de 11, 2001 
attaques de terroriste sur les ouvriers le plus immédiatement 
affectés de centre commercial mondial dans la ligne aérienne et les 
industries du tourisme. Les lignes aériennes, comme une grande 
partie de l'économie des ETATS-UNIS, éprouvaient déjà un 
défilement ralenti économique après les années de perche des 
années 90 en retard. Dans des semaines de l'attaque, les lignes
aériennes ont congédié des dizaines de milliers d'ouvriers et ont 
menacé de congédier plus. Président George W. Bush et le
congrès des ETATS-UNIS a rapidement répondu, offrant $5 milliards 
dans des concessions d'argent comptant et promettant plus. Des 
précédents plus tôt, tels que le renflouement du gouvernement $1.5 
milliards pour Chrylser Corporation en 1979-80, ont été basés sur 
la nécessité d'éviter des pertes graves du travail et l'agitation 
économique, pourtant dans le cas de la moitié de Chrysler presque 
des ouvriers horaires a détruit leurs travaux en dépit du 
renflouement. Dans cette entrevue, "Joshua DeVries," un employé 
de ligne aérienne, décrit la réaction des ouvriers aux offs de 
configuration et à la réponse de gouvernement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O impacto econômico setembro do 11, 2001 ataques 
do terrorista nos trabalhadores o mais imediatamente afetados do 
centro de comércio de mundo na linha aérea e nas indústrias 
tourist. As linhas aéreas, como muita da economia de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS, experimentavam já um slowdown econômico após os anos do 
crescimento dos 1990s. atrasados dentro das semanas do ataque, linhas 
aéreas colocadas fora dos dez dos milhares dos trabalhadores e 
ameaçadas encontrar-se fora mais. O presidente George W. Bush e
congress de ESTADOS UNIDOS respondeu rapidamente, oferecendo $5 
bilhões em concessões do dinheiro e prometendo mais. Uns 
precedents mais adiantados, tais como o bailout do governo $1.5 
bilhões para o Chrylser Corporation em 1979-80, foram baseados na 
necessidade evitar perdas severas do trabalho e o turmoil econômico, 
contudo no exemplo da metade de Chrysler quase dos trabalhadores de 
hora em hora perdeu seus trabalhos apesar do bailout. Nesta 
entrevista, "Joshua DeVries," um empregado da linha aérea, descreve a
reação dos trabalhadores aos offs da configuração e à resposta do
governo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'effetto economico de 11 settembre 2001 attacchi 
del terrorista agli operai il più immediatamente affected del centro 
di commercio mondiale nella linea aerea e nelle industrie del turismo.
Le linee aeree, come gran parte dell'economia degli STATI UNITI,
già stavano avvertendo un rallentamento economico dopo gli anni 
dell'asta degli anni 90 tardi nelle settimane dell'attacco, dieci dei 
migliaia congedati linee aeree degli operai e minacciati per congedare
più. Il presidente George W. Bush ed il congresso degli STATI 
UNITI ha risposto rapidamente, offrendo $5 miliardo nelle concessioni 
dei contanti e promettendo più. I precedenti più iniziali, 
quale il bailout di governo $1.5 miliardo per il Chrylser Corporation 
in 1979-80, sono stati basati sulla necessità di evitare le perdite 
severe di lavoro e l'agitazione economica, tuttavia nel caso della 
metà della Chrysler quasi degli operai orari ha perso i loro lavori 
malgrado il bailout. In questa intervista, "Joshua DeVries," un 
impiegato di linea aerea, descrive la reazione degli operai ai offs di
disposizione ed alla risposta di governo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο οικονομικός αντίκτυπος της 11ης Σεπτεμβρίου 
τρομοκράτης ..2001 επιτίθεται στο κέντρο παγκόσμιου εμπορίου 
στους περισσότερους αμέσως επηρεασθέντες εργαζομένους στις 
βιομηχανίες αερογραμμών και τουριστών. Οι αερογραμμές, όπως
ένα μεγάλο μέρος της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ οικονομίας, δοκίμαζαν ήδη μια 
οικονομική επιβράδυνση μετά από τα έτη βραχιόνων της πρόσφατης 
δεκαετίας του '90 Εβδομάδες αργότερα της επίθεσης, οι 
αερογραμμές σταμάτησαν τις δεκάδες χιλιάδων εργαζόμενοι και 
απείλησαν να σταματήσουν περισσότερων. Ο Πρόεδρος George 
W. Bush και το ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ συνέδριο αποκρίθηκαν γρήγορα, 
προσφέροντας $5 δισεκατομμύρια στις επιχορηγήσεις μετρητών και 
ελπιδοφόρος περισσότερων. Τα προηγούμενα προηγούμενα, όπως 
η κυβερνητική εγκατάλειψη σκάφους $1,5 δισεκατομμυρίων για την 
εταιρία Chrylser το 1979-80, βασίστηκαν στην ανάγκη να 
αποφευχθούν οι αυστηρές απώλειες εργασίας και η οικονομική 
αναταραχή, όμως στην περίπτωση Chrysler σχεδόν οι μισοί από 
τους ωριαίους εργαζομένους έχασαν τις εργασίες τους παρά την 
εγκατάλειψη σκάφους. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη, "Joshua 
DeVries," ένας υπάλληλος αερογραμμών, περιγράφει την αντίδραση
των εργαζομένων στο λαϊκό offs και την κυβερνητική απάντηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El impacto económico del de septiembre 11 de 2001
ataques del terrorista contra los trabajadores lo más inmediatamente 
posible afectados del centro de comercio mundial de la línea aérea y
de las industrias turísticas. Las líneas aéreas, como mucha 
de la economía de ESTADOS UNIDOS, experimentaban ya un mecanismo de 
frenado de la velocidad de visualización en pantella económico 
después de los años del auge de los últimos años 90 dentro de las 
semanas del ataque, los diez despedidos líneas aéreas de millares de
trabajadores y amenazados para despedir más. Presidente George 
W. Bush y el congreso de ESTADOS UNIDOS respondió rápidamente, 
ofreciendo $5 mil millones en concesiones del efectivo y prometiendo 
más. Precedentes anteriores, tales como el desalojo urgente del
gobierno $1.5 mil millones para el Chrylser Corporation en 1979-80, 
fueron basados en la necesidad de evitar pérdidas severas del trabajo
y la agitación económica, con todo en el caso de la mitad de 
Chrysler de los trabajadores cada hora perdió casi sus trabajos a 
pesar de el desalojo urgente. En esta entrevista, "Joshua 
DeVries," un empleado de la línea aérea, describe la reacción de 
los trabajadores a los offs de la endecha y a la respuesta del 
gobierno.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087079</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105134</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-workers-once-again-seem-to-have-fallen-by-the-wayside-the-impact-of-september-11th-on-airline-workers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
