<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206528</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Exploration and Explorers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschung und Forscher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Exploration et explorateurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Exploração e exploradores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplorazione ed esploratori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξερεύνηση και εξερευνητές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Exploración y exploradores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at Europe's view of North America before and after Columbus, Martin Waldseemuller's 1507 map of the world, Diego Gutierrez's 1562 map of America, Spanish and Portuguese encounters in America, the Dutch in America, exploration and settlement of America from British and American points of view, Lewis and Clark, Henry Hudson, Jacques Cartier, and early images of the U.S.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf Ansicht Europas von Nordamerika vorher
und nachher Columbus, Martin Waldseemullers 1507 Karte der Welt, Diego
Gutierrezs 1562 Karte Amerika, des spanischem und Portugiesetreffens 
in Amerika, der Holländer in Amerika, der Erforschung und der 
Regelung von Amerika von den britischen und amerikanischen Punkten der
Ansicht, von Lewis und von Clark, Henry Hudson, Jacques Cartier und 
frühe Bilder von den US.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards à la vue de l'Europe de l'Amérique 
du nord avant et après Columbus, carte de Martin Waldseemuller 1507
du monde, carte de Diego Gutierrez 1562 de rencontre de l'Amérique, 
espagnole et du Portugais en Amérique, du Néerlandais en Amérique, 
d'exploration et de règlement de l'Amérique des points britanniques 
et américains de vue, du Lewis et du Clark, Henry Hudson, Jacques
Cartier, et images tôt des États-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares na vista de Europa de America do Norte 
before.and.after Columbo, mapa do mundo, mapa de Martin Waldseemuller 
1507 de Diego Gutierrez 1562 do encontro de América, espanhol e de 
português em América, do dutch em América, da exploração e do 
estabelecimento de América dos pontos britânicos e americanos da 
vista, do Lewis e do Clark, Henry Hudson, Jacques Cartier, e imagens 
adiantadas dos E. U..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi alla vista dell'Europa dell'America del 
Nord prima e dopo Columbus, programma del mondo, programma del Martin 
Waldseemuller 1507 di Diego Gutierrez 1562 dell'incontro spagnolo e 
del Portoghese dell'America, in America, del dutch in America, 
dell'esplorazione e dello stabilimento dell'America dai punti 
britannici ed americani della vista, da Lewis e da Clark, henry 
Hudson, Jacques Cartier ed immagini iniziali degli Stati Uniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την όψη της Ευρώπης της Βόρειας Αμερικής 
πριν και μετά από το Columbus, χάρτης 1507 Martin 
Waldseemuller's του κόσμου, χάρτης 1562 του Diego 
Gutierrez's της Αμερικής, ισπανικά και τα πορτογαλικά 
αντιμετωπίζουν στην Αμερική, τους Ολλανδούς στην Αμερική, την 
εξερεύνηση και την τακτοποίηση της Αμερικής από τις βρετανικές 
και αμερικανικές απόψεις, Lewis και clark, Henry Hudson,
Ζακ Cartier, και τις πρώτες εικόνες των ΗΠΑ</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en la opinión de Europa de Norteamérica
antes y después Columbus, correspondencia del mundo, correspondencia 
de Martin Waldseemuller 1507 de Diego Gutierrez 1562 del encuentro de 
América, español y del portugués en América, del holandés en 
América, de la exploración y del establecimiento de América de 
puntas británicas y americanas de la visión, de Lewis y de Clark, 
Henrio Hudson, Jacques Cartier, e imágenes tempranas de los E.E.U.U..</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206528</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108067</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/exploration-and-explorers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
