<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105184</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105184</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205401</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Shaken and Stirred: Scott Snibbe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerüttelt und gerührt: Scott Snibbe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Secoué et remué : Scott Snibbe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Agitado e agitado: Scott Snibbe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Agitato e mescolato: Scott Snibbe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τιναγμένος και ανακατωμένος: Scott Snibbe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sacudarido y revuelto: Scott Snibbe</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">SPARK follows Scott Snibbe at work on an installation piece Blow Up at the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts in San Francisco, and through his studio as he discusses his installation, interactive, and net art projects and some of the ideas underlying them. This Educator Guide is about the digital and new media art and the historic interplay between art and science and technology.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">FUNKEN folgt Scott Snibbe an der Arbeit über eine
Installation Stück Explosion in der Yerba Buena Mitte für die 
künste in San Francisco und durch sein Studio, während er seine 
Installation behandelt, interaktiv, und Nettokunstprojekte und einige 
der zugrundeliegenden Ideen sie. Diese Erzieher-Anleitung ist 
über die digitale und neue Mediakunst und die historische 
Wechselwirkung zwischen kunst und Wissenschaft und Technologie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'ÉTINCELLE suit Scott Snibbe au travail sur
une explosion de morceau d'installation au centre de Yerba Buena pour 
les arts dans San Francisco, et par son studio pendant qu'il discute 
son installation, interactive, et projets nets d'art et certaines des 
idées sous-tendantes elles. Ce guide d'éducateur est au sujet 
de l'art digital et nouvel de medias et de l'effet historique entre 
l'art et la science et la technologie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A FAÍSCA segue Scott Snibbe no trabalho em um 
sopro da parte da instalação acima no centro de Yerba Buena para as 
artes em San Francisco, e através de seu estúdio enquanto discute 
sua instalação, interativa, e os projetos líquidos da arte e os 
alguns das idéias subjacentes elas. Esta guia do educador é 
sobre a arte digital e nova dos media e o interplay historic entre a 
arte e a ciência e a tecnologia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La SCINTILLA segue Scott Snibbe sul lavoro su 
un'esplosione della parte dell'installazione al centro di Yerba Buena 
per le arti a San Francisco ed attraverso il suo studio mentre discute
la sua installazione, interattiva ed i progetti netti di arte ed 
alcuni delle idee di fondo loro. Questa guida dell'educatore 
è circa l'arte digitale e nuova di media e l'interazione storica fra 
l'arte e la scienza e tecnologia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ΣΠΙΝΘΗΡΑΣ ακολουθεί Scott Snibbe στην εργασία 
για ένα χτύπημα κομματιού εγκαταστάσεων επάνω στο κέντρο 
Yerba Buena για τις τέχνες στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο, και μέσω του 
στούντιό του δεδομένου ότι συζητά την εγκατάσταση, τα 
διαλογικά, και καθαρά προγράμματα τέχνης και μερικές του από τις
ιδέες που κρύβονται κάτω από τις. Αυτός ο οδηγός 
εκπαιδευτικών είναι για την ψηφιακή και νέα τέχνη μέσων και την 
ιστορική αλληλεπίδραση μεταξύ της τέχνης και της επιστήμης και 
της τεχνολογίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La CHISPA sigue Scott Snibbe en el trabajo sobre 
un soplo del pedazo de la instalación para arriba en el centro de 
Yerba Buena para los artes en San Francisco, y a través de su estudio
mientras que él discute su instalación, interactiva, y los proyectos
netos del arte y algunos de las ideas subyacentes ellas. Esta 
guía del educador está sobre el arte digital y nuevo de los media y 
la interacción histórica entre el arte y ciencia y tecnología.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205401</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105184</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/shaken-and-stirred-scott-snibbe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
