<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103809</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103809</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087171</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Warning Against the "Roman Catholic Party": Catholicism and the 1928 Election</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Warnen gegen die "römisch-katholische 
Partei": Katholizismus und die Wahl 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mettre en garde contre "la partie catholique" : 
Catholicisme et l'élection 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Advertir de encontro "ao partido do catholic 
roman": Catholicism e a eleição 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mettendo in guardia contro "il partito cattolico":
Catholicism e l'elezione 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προειδοποίηση ενάντια στο "ρωμαϊκό καθολικό 
συμβαλλόμενο μέροσ": Καθολικισμός και η εκλογή του 1928</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuidado contra el "partido católico": 
Catholicism y la elección 1928</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Democratic Presidential candidate Al Smith faced a vicious campaign of anti-Catholic innuendoes and slurs--both covert and overt--in the 1928 election. A widely distributed periodical called the  Fellowship Forum  declared that "The real issue in this campaign is PROTESTANT AMERICANISM VERSUS RUM AND ROMANISM." Anti-Catholicism was not confined to fringe groups. One of the most vocal opponents of a Catholic presence in American politics was Thomas J. Heflin, the junior senator from Alabama, who delivered some of his most vicious speeches on the floor of the Senate. Heflin's January 18, 1928, speech before his Senate colleagues blamed the defeat of 1924 Democratic presidential candidate John W. Davis on Roman Catholics ("Al Smith's crowd") who demanded--to Heflin's outrage--that the party denounce the Klan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Demokratisches Präsidentenanwärteral Smith 
stellte eine schändliche Kampagne der Anti-Katholischen Anspielungen 
und der slurs -- verborgen und offenkundig -- in der Wahl 1928 
gegenüber. Eine weit verteilte Zeitschrift benannte das 
Stipendium-Forum erklärte, daß "die reale Ausgabe in dieser Kampagne
ist PROTESTIERENDER AMERIKANISMUS GEGEN RUM UND ROMANISM." 
Anti-Katholizismus wurde nicht begrenzt, um Gruppen 
einzusäumen. Einer der vocal Konkurrenten einer katholischen 
Anwesenheit in der amerikanischen Politik war Thomas J. Heflin, der 
Juniorsenator von Alabama, das einige seiner schändlichsten Reden auf
dem Fußboden des Senats lieferte. Januar 18, 1928, Rede Heflins
vor seinen Senatkollegen tadelte die Niederlage 1924 demokratischen 
Präsidentenanwärters John W. Davis auf römischen Katholischen 
("Masse Al-Smith") die verlangten -- zum Verbrechen Heflins -- daß 
die Partei das Klan kündigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Al présidentiel démocratique Smith de candidat a
fait face à une campagne méchante des insinuations et des slurs 
anti-Catholiques -- secret et manifeste -- dans l'élection 1928. 
Un périodique largement distribué a appelé le forum de 
camaraderie a déclaré que "la vraie issue dans cette campagne est 
l'AMÉRICANISME PROTESTANT CONTRE LE RHUM ET LE ROMANISM." 
l'Anti-Catholicisme n'a pas été confiné pour fringer des 
groupes. Un des adversaires les plus vocaux d'une présence 
catholique dans la politique américaine était Thomas J. Heflin, 
sénateur junior d'Alabama, qui a fourni certains de ses discours plus
méchants sur le plancher du sénat. 18 janvier 1928, discours 
de Heflin avant ses collègues de sénat a blâmé la défaite 1924 du
candidat présidentiel démocratique John W. Davis sur les catholiques
romains ("la foule de Smith d'Al") qui ont exigé -- à l'outrage de 
Heflin -- que la partie dénoncent le Klan.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O al presidencial democrático Smith do candidato 
enfrentou uma campanha vicious de innuendoes e de slurs 
anti-anti-Catholic --  secreto e overt -- na eleição 1928. Um 
periodical extensamente distribuído chamou o forum do fellowship 
declarou que "a edição real nesta campanha é AMERICANISM PROTESTANT
CONTRA O RUM E O ROMANISM." O Anti-anti-Catholicism não foi 
confinado para franjar grupos. Um dos oponentes os mais vocais 
de uma presença catholic na política americana era Thomas J. Heflin,
senator júnior de Alabama, que entregou alguns de seus discursos mais
vicious no assoalho do senate. Janeiro 18 de Heflin, 1928, 
discurso antes de seus colegas do senate responsabilizou a derrota 
1924 do candidato presidencial democrático John W. Davis nos 
catholics roman (do "multidão de Smith al") que exijiram -- ao 
ultraje de Heflin -- que o partido denounce o Klan.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Al presidenziale democratico Smith del candidato 
ha affrontato una campagna viziosa dei innuendoes e degli slurs 
anti-Cattolici -- sia segreto che evidente -- nell'elezione 1928. 
Un periodico ampiamente distribuito ha chiamato la tribuna di 
fellowship ha dichiarato che "l'edizione reale in questa campagna è 
AMERICANISM PROTESTANTE CONTRO RUM E ROMANISM." Il 
Anti-anti-Catholicism non è stato limitato per guarnire i gruppi di 
frange. Uno degli avversari più vocali di una presenza 
cattolica nella politica americana era Thomas J. Heflin, il senatore 
minore dall'Alabama, che ha trasportato alcuni dei suoi discorsi più 
viziosi sul pavimento del senato. Gennaio 1928, discorso del 
Heflin 18 prima dei suoi colleghe del senato ha incolpato della 
sconfitta 1924 del candidato presidenziale democratico John W. Davis 
sui cattolici romani ("folla dello Smith di Al") che hanno richiesto 
-- all'oltraggio del Heflin -- che il partito denuncia il Klan.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το δημοκρατικό προεδρικό Al Smith υποψηφίων 
αντιμετώπισε μια κακοήθη εκστρατεία αντι-καθολικού innuendoes 
και slurs -- και συγκεκαλυμμένος και προφανής -- στην εκλογή του
1928. Ένα ευρέως διανεμημένο περιοδικό αποκαλούμενο 
φόρουμ υποτροφίας δήλωσε ότι "το πραγματικό ζήτημα σε αυτήν την
εκστρατεία είναι ΠΡΟΤΕΣΤΑΝΤΙΚΟ AMERICANISM ΕΝΑΝΤΊΟΝ του ΡΟΥΜΙΟΎ
ΚΑΙ ROMANISM." Ο αντι-καθολικισμός δεν περιορίστηκε στις 
ομάδες περιθωρίου. Ένας από τους πιό φωνητικούς 
αντιπάλους μιας καθολικής παρουσίας στην αμερικανική πολιτική 
ήταν ο Thomas Θ*ι. Heflin, ο κατώτερος γερουσιαστής από την 
Αλαμπάμα, η οποία παρέδωσε μερικές από τις πιό κακοήθεις 
ομιλίες του στο πάτωμα της Συγκλήτου. Ιανουαρίου ..1928, 
ομιλία του Heflin 18 ενώπιον των συναδέλφων Συγκλήτου του 
κατηγόρησε την ήττα του δημοκρατικού προεδρικού υποψηφίου John
W. Davis του 1924 στους ρωμαϊκούς Καθολικούς ("πλήθος 
Al Smith") που απαίτησαν -- στην προσβολή Heflin -- ότι το
συμβαλλόμενο μέρος καταγγέλλει το Klan.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El al presidencial democrático Smith del 
candidato hizo frente a una campaña viciosa de insinuacíones y de 
slurs contra-Cato'licos -- secreto y abierto -- en la elección 1928. 
Un periódico extensamente distribuido llamó el foro de la beca
declaró que "la edición verdadera en esta campaña es AMERICANISM 
PROTESTANTE CONTRA EL RON Y ROMANISM." El 
Contra-anti-Catholicism no fue confinado para franjar a grupos. 
Uno de los opositores más vocales de una presencia católica en
política americana era Thomas J. Heflin, el senador menor de Alabama,
que entregó algunos de sus discursos más viciosos en el suelo del 
senado. 18 de enero de 1928, discurso de Heflin antes de sus 
colegas del senado culpó la derrota 1924 del candidato presidencial 
democrático Juan W. Davis en los católicos romanos ("muchedumbre de 
Smith del al") que exigieron -- al ultraje de Heflin -- que el partido
denunci el Klan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087171</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103809</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/warning-against-the-roman-catholic-party-catholicism-and-the-1928-election</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
