<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108263</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108263</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086224</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hear Joe Louis Knock Out Max Schmeling: Black Sports Heroes in the Depression Era</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hören Sie Joe Louis, Maximales Schmeling Heraus 
Zu klopfen: Schwarzes Sports Helder in der Tiefstand-Ära</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entendez Joe Louis Assommer Schmeling Maximum : 
Le noir fôlatre des héros dans l'ère de dépression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ouça Joe Louis Bater Para fora Schmeling Máximo:
O preto ostenta heróis na era do depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Senta Joe Louis Buttare giù Schmeling Massimo: 
Il nero mette in mostra gli Eroi nell'era di depressione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακούστε Joe Louis Knock Out Max 
Schmeling: Μαύροι αθλητικοί ήρωες στην εποχή κατάθλιψης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Oiga A Joe Louis Golpear Hacia fuera Schmeling 
Máximo: El negro se divierte a héroes en la era de la 
depresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The rise to prominence in the 1930s of legendary black sports figures--the heavyweight boxing champion Joe Louis and the Olympic track and field star Jesse Owens--challenged the barriers that separated white and black American athletes and their fans. Louis's boxing prowess had excited black fans as early as 1934, and he quickly worked his way through the heavyweight ranks, dispatching white and black opponents alike with brutal efficiency. Louis's one defeat before attaining the title came at the hands of the German fighter and ex-champion Max Schmeling, who knocked Louis out in twelve rounds at Yankee Stadium in 1936. Two years later, Louis faced Schmeling in a rematch, this time not only with the championship belt on the line but bragging rights among nations lurching toward war. Louis knocked out Schmeling in two minutes and four seconds of the first round. The radio announcer's call of the fight, including the knockout punch, conveyed the drama, as did a postfight radio interview with the Champ.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anstieg zum Vorsprung in den dreißiger Jahren
der legendären schwarzen Sportabbildungen -- der heavyweight 
Verpackenmeister Joe Louis und die olympische Spur und 
fangen Sie Stern Jesse Owens auf -- forderte die Sperren 
heraus, die die weißen und schwarzen amerikanischen Athleten und ihre
Ventilatoren trennten. Verpackenfähigkeit Louiss hatte schwarze
Ventilatoren schon in 1934 aufgeregt, und er bearbeitete schnell seine
Methode durch die heavyweight Rank und gleich schickte die weißen und
schwarzen Konkurrenten mit brutaler Leistungsfähigkeit. Louiss 
eine Niederlage, bevor sie den Namen erreichte, kam an den Händen des
deutschen Kämpfers und des Exmeisters maximales Schmeling, die Louis 
heraus in zwölf Umläufen am Yankee Stadium 1936 klopften. Zwei
Jahre später, stellte Louis Schmeling in einem rematch, dieses mal 
nicht nur mit dem Meisterschaftriemen auf der Zeile gegenüber, aber 
das Prahlen berichtigt unter den Nationen, die in Richtung zum Krieg 
lurching sind. Louis klopfte heraus Schmeling in zwei Minuten 
und in vier Sekunden des ersten Umlaufes. Der RadioAufruf des 
ansagers des Kampfes, einschließlich den Knockoutlocher, 
übermittelte das Drama, wie ein postfight Radiointerview mit dem 
Champion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élévation à la proéminence dans les années 
30 des chiffres noirs légendaires de sports -- le champion Joe Louis 
de boxe de poids lourd et la piste et la zone olympiques 
tenez le premier rôle Jesse Owens -- a défié les barrières qui ont 
séparé les athlètes américains blancs et noirs et leurs 
ventilateurs. La prouesse de la boxe de Louis avait excité les 
ventilateurs noirs dès 1934, et il a rapidement travaillé sa voie 
par les rangs de poids lourd, acheminant les adversaires blancs et 
noirs de même avec l'efficacité brutale. Une défaite de Louis
avant d'atteindre le titre est venue aux mains du combattant et du 
l'ex-champion allemands Schmeling maximum, qui ont frappé Louis 
dehors dans douze séries au stade de Yankee en 1936. Deux ans 
après, Louis a fait face à Schmeling dans un rematch, cette fois non
seulement avec la ceinture de championnat sur la ligne mais la 
vantardise redresse parmi des nations vacillant vers la guerre. 
Louis a assommé Schmeling en deux minutes et quatre secondes du
premier rond. L'appel de l'annonceur par radio du combat, y 
compris le perforateur de coup de grâce, a donné le drame, de même 
que  une entrevue de radio de postfight avec le champion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A ascensão ao prominence nos 1930s de figuras 
pretas legendárias dos esportes -- campeão Joe Louis do boxing do 
heavyweight e a estrela olympic Jesse Owens da trilha e do campo -- 
desafiou as barreiras que separaram os atletas americanos brancos e 
pretos e os seus ventiladores. O prowess do boxing de Louis 
tinha excitado ventiladores pretos assim que 1934, e trabalhou 
rapidamente sua maneira através dos Rank do heavyweight, despachando 
os oponentes brancos e pretos igualmente com eficiência brutal. 
Uma derrota de Louis antes de alcançar o título veio nas mãos
do lutador e do ex-campeão alemães Schmeling máximo, que bateram 
Louis para fora em doze círculos no stadium de Yankee em 1936. 
Dois anos mais tarde, Louis enfrentou Schmeling em um rematch, 
esta vez não somente com a correia do championship na linha mas 
bragging endireita entre as nações que balançam para a guerra. 
Louis bateu para fora Schmeling em dois minutos e em quatro 
segundos do primeiro círculo. O atendimento do anunciador de 
rádio da luta, including o perfurador do knockout, fêz saber ao 
drama, como  uma entrevista do rádio do postfight com o champ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'aumento alla protuberanza nei 1930s delle figure
nere leggendarie di sport -- il campione Joe Louis di boxing del 
heavyweight e la stella olimpica Jesse Owens del campo e della pista 
-- ha sfidato le barriere che hanno separato gli atleti americani 
bianchi e neri ed i loro ventilatori. Il prowess di boxing del 
Louis aveva eccitato i ventilatori neri fin da 1934 ed ha lavorato 
rapidamente il suo modo attraverso la truppa del heavyweight, 
spedendo gli avversari bianchi e neri egualmente con il risparmio di 
temi brutale. Una sconfitta del Louis prima del raggiungimento 
del titolo è venuto alle mani del combattente e del ex-campione 
tedeschi Schmeling massimo, che hanno battuto Louis fuori in dodici 
tondi allo stadio di Yankee in 1936. Due anni più 
successivamente, Louis ha affrontato Schmeling in un rematch, questo 
volta non soltanto con la cinghia di campionato sulla riga ma vantarsi
radrizza fra le nazioni che sbandano verso la guerra. Louis ha 
buttato giù Schmeling in due minuti e quattro secondi del primo 
tondo. La chiamata del presentatore radiofonico della lotta, 
compreso il punzone di knockout, ha trasportato il dramma, come 
un'intervista della radio del postfight con il champ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η άνοδος στην προεξοχή στη δεκαετία του '30 των 
θρυλικών μαύρων αθλητικών αριθμών -- ο βαρέων βαρών 
εγκιβωτίζοντας πρωτοπόρος Joe Louis και το ολυμπιακό αστέρι 
Jesse Owens διαδρομής και πεδίων -- προκάλεσε τα εμπόδια που
χώρισαν τους λευκούς και μαύρους αμερικανικούς αθλητές και τους 
ανεμιστήρες τους. Η ανδρεία εγκιβωτισμού του Louis είχε 
διεγείρει τους μαύρους ανεμιστήρες από το 1934, και 
απασχολήθηκε γρήγορα στον τρόπο του μέσω των βαρέων βαρών 
τάξεων, που αποστέλλουν τους λευκούς και μαύρους αντιπάλους ίδια
με τη βάναυση αποδοτικότητα. Μια ήττα του Louis πρίν 
επιτυγχάνει τον τίτλο ήρθε στα χέρια του γερμανικών μαχητή και 
του πρώην-πρωτοπόρου ανώτατο Schmeling, οι οποίοι χτύπησαν το 
Louis έξω σε δώδεκα κύκλους στο στάδιο Αμερικανού σε 1936, 
Δύο έτη αργότερα, ο Louis αντιμετώπισε Schmeling σε 
ένα rematch, αυτή τη φορά όχι μόνο με τη ζώνη πρωταθλήματος 
στα δικαιώματα γραμμών αλλά καυχησιολογίας μεταξύ των εθνών που 
ταλαντεύονται προς τον πόλεμο. Ο Louis χτύπησε έξω 
Schmeling σε δύο λεπτά και τέσσερα δευτερόλεπτα του πρώτου 
κύκλου. Η κλήση του ραδιο αναγγέλλοντος της πάλης, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της knockout διάτρησης, μεταβίβασε το 
δράμα, όπως μια ραδιο συνέντευξη postfight με το Champ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La subida a la prominencia en los años 30 de las 
figuras negras legendarias de los deportes -- el campeón Joe Louis 
del boxeo del heavyweight y la estrella olímpica Jesse Owens de la 
pista y del campo -- desafió las barreras que separaron los atletas 
americanos blancos y negros y sus ventiladores. El valor del 
boxeo de Louis había excitado los ventiladores negros desde 1934, y 
él trabajó rápidamente su manera a través de las filas del 
heavyweight, enviando a opositores blancos y negros igualmente con 
eficacia brutal. Una derrota de Louis antes de lograr el título
vino en las manos del combatiente y del ex-campeo'n alemanes Schmeling
máximo, que golpearon Louis hacia fuera en doce redondos en el 
estadio de Yankee en 1936. Dos años más adelante, Louis hizo 
frente a Schmeling en un rematch, este vez no solamente con la correa 
del campeonato en la línea pero la jactancia endereza entre las 
naciones que guiñan hacia guerra. Louis golpeó hacia fuera 
Schmeling en dos minutos y cuatro segundos del primer redondo. 
La llamada del anunciador de radio de la lucha, incluyendo el 
sacador del golpe de gracia, transportó el drama, al igual que una 
entrevista de la radio del postfight con el champ.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086224</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108263</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hear-joe-louis-knock-out-max-schmeling-black-sports-heroes-in-the-depression-era</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
