<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/94590655</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>94590655</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204028</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mixed Reception Scenario</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mischaufnahme-Drehbuch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Scénario Mélangé De Réception</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Scenario Misturado Da Recepção</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Piano d'azione Mixed Di Ricezione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μικτό σενάριο λήψης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Decorado Mezclado De la Recepción</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This activity is set in a research group that is developing an antivenom for spider bites. In the opening scene, Nelson Pogline, a talented graduate student, dies unexpectedly at a university reception. As a detective, you must use chemistry concepts to determine if this was murder and if so, solve the case. You can interview suspects using Quicktime movies, investigate the crime scene for clues with Quicktime Virtual Reality images, and analyze the evidence from the crime lab. This activity requires basic knowledge of formula weight, stoichiometry, and the scientific method. Additional concepts that are discussed include molecular recognition, limiting reagents, and mass spectrometry.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Aktivität wird in eine Forschungsgruppe 
eingestellt, die ein Gegengift für Spinne Bissen entwickelt. In
der Öffnung Szene stirbt Nelson Pogline, ein begabter Schulabgänger,
unerwartet an einer Universitätsaufnahme. Als Detektiv müssen 
Sie Chemiekonzepte verwenden, um festzustellen, wenn dieses Mord war 
und wenn so, lösen den Fall. Sie können Verdächtige mit 
Quicktime Filmen, die Verbrechenszene nachforschen für Anhaltspunkte 
mit Quicktime virtuellen Wirklichkeit Bildern interviewen, und den 
Beweis vom Verbrechenlabor analysieren. Diese Aktivität 
benötigt grundlegendes Wissen des Formelgewichts, der Stöchiometrie 
und der wissenschaftlichen Methode. Zusätzliche Konzepte, die 
behandelt werden, schließen molekulare Anerkennung ein und begrenzen 
Reagenzien und Massenspektrometrie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité est placée dans un groupe de 
recherche qui développe un antivenin pour des morsures d'araignée. 
Dans la scène d'ouverture, le Nelson Pogline, un étudiant 
gradué doué, meurt inopinément à une réception d'université. 
En tant que détective, vous devez employer des concepts de 
chimie pour déterminer si c'était meurtre et si oui, résolvez le 
cas. Vous pouvez interviewer des suspects en utilisant des films
de Quicktime, étudier la scène de crime pour des indices avec des 
images virtuelles de réalité de Quicktime, et analyser l'évidence 
du laboratoire de crime. Cette activité exige la connaissance 
de base du poids de formule, de la stoechiométrie, et de la méthode 
scientifique. Les concepts supplémentaires qui sont discutés 
incluent l'identification moléculaire, limitant des réactifs, et la 
spectrométrie de masse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade é ajustada em um grupo de pesquisa
que esteja desenvolvendo um antivenom para mordidas da aranha. 
Na cena da abertura, Nelson Pogline, um estudante graduado 
talented, morre inesperada em uma recepção da universidade. 
Como um detetive, você deve usar conceitos do chemistry 
determinar se este for assassinato e se assim, resolve o caso. 
Você pode entrevistar suspeitos usando filmes de Quicktime, 
investigar a cena de crime para indícios com imagens virtuais da 
realidade de Quicktime, e analisar a evidência do laboratório do 
crime. Esta atividade requer o conhecimento básico do peso da 
fórmula, do stoichiometry, e do método científico. Os 
conceitos adicionais que são discutidos incluem o recognition 
molecular, limitando reagents, e o spectrometry maciço.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività è regolata in un gruppo di 
ricerca che sta sviluppando un antiveleno per i morsi del ragno. 
Nella scena di apertura, il Nelson Pogline, un allievo laureato 
di talento, muore inatteso ad una ricezione dell'università. 
Come detectivo, dovete usare i concetti di chimica per 
determinare se questo fosse omicidio ed in caso affermativo, risolvete
il caso. Potete intervistare i sospetti usando i film di 
Quicktime, studiare la scena di crimine per gli indizii con le 
immagini virtuali di realtà di Quicktime ed analizzare la prova dal 
laboratorio di crimine. Questa attività richiede la conoscenza 
di base del peso di formula, della stechiometria e del metodo 
scientifico. I concetti supplementari che sono discussi 
includono il riconoscimento molecolare, limitando i reagenti e la 
spettrometria totale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα τίθεται σε μια ερευνητική ομάδα 
που αναπτύσσει antivenom για τα δαγκώματα αραχνών. Στην 
ανοίγοντας σκηνή, το Nelson Pogline, ένας ταλαντούχος 
διαβαθμισμένος σπουδαστής, πεθαίνει απροσδόκητα σε μια 
πανεπιστημιακή λήψη. Σαν ιδιωτικό αστυνομικό, πρέπει να 
χρησιμοποιήσετε τις έννοιες χημείας για να καθορίσετε εάν αυτό 
ήταν δολοφονία και σε αυτή την περίπτωση, λύνετε την περίπτωση. 
Μπορείτε να πάρετε συνέντευξη από τους υπόπτους 
χρησιμοποιώντας τους κινηματογράφους Quicktime, να ερευνήσετε 
τον τόπο εγκλήματος για τις ενδείξεις με τις εικόνες εικονικής 
πραγματικότητας Quicktime, και να αναλύσετε τα στοιχεία από το 
εργαστήριο εγκλήματος. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα απαιτεί τη 
βασική γνώση του βάρους τύπου, της στοιχειομετρίας, και της 
επιστημονικής μεθόδου. Οι πρόσθετες έννοιες που συζητούνται
περιλαμβάνουν τη μοριακή αναγνώριση, που περιορίζει τα 
αντιδραστήρια, και τη μαζική φασματομετρία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad se fija en un grupo de 
investigación que esté desarrollando un antiveneno para las 
mordeduras de la araña. En la escena de la apertura, Nelson 
Pogline, estudiante graduado talentoso, muere inesperado en una 
recepción de la universidad. Como detective, usted debe 
utilizar conceptos de la química para determinar si éste era 
asesinato y si es así soluciona el caso. Usted puede 
entrevistarse con a sospechosos usando las películas de Quicktime, 
investigar la escena de crimen para las pistas con imágenes virtuales
de la realidad de Quicktime, y analizar la evidencia del laboratorio 
del crimen. Esta actividad requiere el conocimiento básico del 
peso del fórmula, del stoichiometry, y del método científico. 
Los conceptos adicionales se discuten que incluyen el 
reconocimiento molecular, limitando los reactivo, y spectrometry 
total.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CHEMISTRY COLLECTIVE
FN:CHEMISTRY COLLECTIVE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204028</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>94590655</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mixed-reception-scenario</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
