<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106779</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106779</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203555</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Journey to Planet Earth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reise nach Planet Masse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voyage à la terre de planète</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Viagem à terra do planeta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Viaggio alla terra del pianeta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ταξίδι στη γη πλανητών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Viaje a la tierra del planeta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features seven PBS programs from around the world that explore the delicate relationship between humans and the natural environment, and the necessity of achieving a balance between the two. Programs contain both text and video, as well as links to other information sources. In addition to the seven programs, the site also features a photo gallery, definitions and information about global ecosystems, and an interactive map that allows users to click on parts of the globe to view in-depth country profiles and read stories of ecological progress in those regions. The site provides useful educational resources to accompany the online material, including teachers' guides for lesson plans related to four of the programs and a companion website by Johns Hopkins University with lesson plans developed around global environmental change and human health. Easy navigation throughout the site makes it simple to access all of its features.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale sieben PBS Programme um 
von der Welt, die das empfindliche Verhältnis zwischen Menschen und 
der natürlichen Umgebung erforschen und die Notwendigkeit des 
Erzielens einer Balance zwischen den zwei. Programme enthalten 
Text und Bildschirm, sowie Links zu anderen Informationsquellen. 
Zusätzlich zu den sieben Programmen kennzeichnet die Site auch 
eine Fotogalerie, -definitionen und -informationen über globale 
Oekosysteme, und eine interaktive Karte, die Benutzern erlaubt, Teile 
der Kugel an zu klicken, um eingehendes Land anzusehen, erstellt ein 
Profil und las Geschichten des ökologischen Fortschritts in jenen 
Regionen. Die Site liefert nützliche pädagogische 
Betriebsmittel, um das Onlinematerial, einschließlich Anleitungen der
Lehrer für die Lektionpläne zu begleiten, die bis vier der Programme
und der Begleiterweb site durch Johns Hopkins Universität mit den 
Lektionplänen in Verbindung gestanden werden, die um globale 
Klimaänderung und menschliche Gesundheit entwickelt werden. 
Einfache Navigation in der Site bildet es einfach, alle auf 
seine Merkmale zuzugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs de ce site sept programmes de PBS de 
partout dans le monde qui explorent le rapport sensible entre les 
humains et l'environnement normal, et la nécessité de réaliser un 
équilibre entre les deux. Les programmes contiennent le texte 
et le vidéo, aussi bien que des liens à d'autres émetteurs 
d'informations. En plus des sept programmes, le site comporte 
également une galerie de photo, des définitions et des informations 
sur des écosystèmes globaux, et une carte interactive qui permet à 
des utilisateurs de cliquer sur des parties du globe pour 
visualiser des profils détaillés de pays et pour lire des histoires 
de progrès écologique dans ces régions. Le site fournit les 
ressources éducatives utiles pour accompagner le matériel en ligne, 
y compris les guides des professeurs pour des plans de leçon liés à
quatre des programmes et d'un site Web de compagnon par l'université 
de Johns Hopkins avec des plans de leçon développés autour du 
changement environnemental global et de la santé humaine. La 
navigation facile dans tout le site le rend simple pour accéder à 
tous ses dispositifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Características deste local sete programas de PBS
em torno do mundo que exploram o relacionamento delicado entre seres 
humanos e o ambiente natural, e a necessidade de conseguir um 
contrapeso entre os dois. Os programas contêm  o texto e o 
vídeo, as.well.as as ligações a outras fontes de informação. 
Além aos sete programas, o local caracteriza também uma 
galeria, definições e informação da foto sobre ecosystems globais,
e um mapa interativo que permita que os usuários estalem sobre partes
do globo para ver o país in-depth perfila e lê histórias do 
progresso ecological naquelas regiões. O local fornece recursos
educacionais úteis para acompanhar o material em linha, including 
guias dos professores para as plantas da lição relacionadas a quatro
dos programas e de um Web site do companheiro pela universidade de 
Johns Hopkins com as plantas da lição desenvolvidas em torno da 
mudança ambiental global e da saúde humana. A navegação 
fácil durante todo o local faz simples alcançar todas suas 
características.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo sette programmi di
PBS intorno al mondo che esplorano il rapporto fragile fra gli esseri 
umani e l'ambiente naturale e necessità di realizzare un equilibrio 
fra i due. I programmi contengono sia il testo che il video, 
così come i collegamenti ad altre sorgenti di informazioni. 
Oltre che i sette programmi, il luogo egualmente caratterizza 
una galleria, le definizioni e le informazioni della foto sugli 
ecosistemi globali e un programma interattivo che permette che gli 
utenti scattino sopra le parti del globo per osservare il paese 
approfondito profila e letto le storia di progresso ecologico in 
quelle regioni. Il luogo fornisce le risorse educative utili per
accompagnare il materiale in linea, compreso le guide degli insegnanti
per i programmi di lezione relativi a quattro dei programmi e di un 
Web site del compagno dall'università del Johns Hopkins con i 
programmi di lezione sviluppati intorno a cambiamento ambientale 
globale ed a salute umana. Il percorso facile durante il luogo 
lo rende semplice accedere a tutte le relative caratteristiche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει επτά προγράμματα PBS 
από σε όλο τον κόσμο που ερευνούν τη λεπτή σχέση μεταξύ των 
ανθρώπων και του φυσικού περιβάλλοντος, και την ανάγκη μια 
ισορροπία μεταξύ των δύο. Τα προγράμματα περιέχουν και το 
κείμενο και το βίντεο, καθώς επίσης και τις συνδέσεις με άλλες 
πηγές πληροφοριών. Εκτός από τα επτά προγράμματα, η 
περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει επίσης μια στοά φωτογραφιών, τους ορισμούς 
και τις πληροφορίες για τα σφαιρικά οικοσυστήματα, και έναν 
διαλογικό χάρτη που επιτρέπει στους χρήστες για να χτυπήσει στα 
μέρη της σφαίρας στα σε βάθος σχεδιαγράμματα χωρών όψης και να 
διαβάσει τις ιστορίες της οικολογικής προόδου σε εκείνες τις 
περιοχές. Η περιοχή παρέχει τα χρήσιμα εκπαιδευτικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς για να συνοδεύσει το σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
υλικό, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των οδηγών των δασκάλων για τα σχέδια 
μαθήματος σχετικά με τέσσερα από τα προγράμματα και έναν 
ιστοχώρο συντρόφων από Johns Hopkins το πανεπιστήμιο με τα 
σχέδια μαθήματος που αναπτύσσονται γύρω από τη σφαιρική 
περιβαλλοντική αλλαγή και την ανθρώπινη υγεία. Η εύκολη 
ναυσιπλοϊ'α σε όλη την περιοχή το καθιστά απλό να έχει πρόσβαση
τα σε όλα της χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de este sitio siete programas de 
PBS alrededor del mundo que exploran el lazo delicado entre los seres 
humanos y el ambiente natural, y la necesidad de alcanzar un 
equilibrio entre los dos. Los programas contienen el texto y el 
vídeo, así como conexiones a otras fuentes de información. 
Además de los siete programas, el sitio también ofrece una 
galería, definiciones y la información de la foto sobre ecosistemas 
globales, y una correspondencia interactiva que permite que los 
utilizadores hagan clic encendido las partes del globo para visión el
país profundizado perfila y leyó historias del progreso ecológico 
en esas regiones. El sitio proporciona a recursos educativos 
útiles para acompañar el material en línea, incluyendo las guías 
de los profesores para los planes de la lección relacionados con 
cuatro de los programas y de un Web site del compañero por la 
universidad de Johns Hopkins con los planes de la lección 
desarrollados alrededor de cambio ambiental global y de salud humana. 
La navegación fácil a través del sitio hace simple tener 
acceso a todas sus características.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203555</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106779</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/journey-to-planet-earth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
