<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087425</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Believe it or not</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Glauben Sie ihm oder nicht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Croyez-l'ou pas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Acredite-o ou não</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Credilo oppure no</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον θεωρήστε ή όχι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Créalo o no</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">At the close of the twentieth century, 93 percent of the U.S. population professed to believe in angels, 49 percent were sure that the federal government was hiding information about the existence of unidentified flying objects, and 25 percent thought they could communicate with the dead. Many Americans chose mystical options over the grimmer aspects of millennial life, but popular interest in the fantastic also signaled a love of creative fabrication dating back into U.S. history (linking, for example, the contemporary antics of the more outrageous tabloid press with the mid-nineteenth century showmanship of P. T. Barnum).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Am Abschluß des zwanzigsten Jahrhunderts, 
erklärten 93 Prozent der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Bevölkerung, an Engel zu
glauben, waren 49 Prozent sicher, daß die Bundesregierung 
Informationen über das Bestehen der nicht identifizierten 
Fliegennachrichten versteckte, und 25 Prozent dachten, daß sie die 
Toten verbundenSEIN konnten. Viele Amerikaner wählten mystische
Optionen über den grimmigeren Aspekten der millennial Lebensdauer, 
aber populäres Interesse am fantastischen auch signalisiert einer 
Liebe der kreativen Herstellung zurückgehend in die VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Geschichte (z.B. die zeitgenössischen Mätzchen der 
unverschämteren tabloid Presse mit dem mittler-19.jahrhundert 
showmanship von P. T. Barnum binden).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À l'issue du vingtième siècle, 93 pour cent de 
la population des ETATS-UNIS ont professé pour croire aux anges, 49 
pour cent étaient sûrs que le gouvernement fédéral cachait des 
informations sur l'existence des objets non identifiés de vol, et 25 
pour cent ont pensé qu'ils pourraient communiquer avec les morts. 
Beaucoup d'Américains ont choisi des options mystiques 
au-dessus des aspects plus sinistres de la vie millénaire, mais 
l'intérêt populaire dans le fantastique également signalé un amour
de la fabrication créatrice remontant dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS 
(joignant, par exemple, les singeries contemporaines de la presse 
tabloïd plus indigne avec le mi-dix-neuvième showmanship de 
siècle de P. T. Barnum).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No fim do vigésimo século, 93 por cento da 
população de ESTADOS UNIDOS professaram acreditar nos angels, 49 por
cento eram certos que o governo federal escondia a informação sobre 
a existência de objetos não identificados do vôo, e 25 por cento 
pensaram que poderiam se comunicar com os mortos. Muitos 
americanos escolheram opções mystical sobre os aspectos mais grimmer
da vida millennial, mas o interesse popular no fantástico sinalizado 
também um amor da fabricação creativa que data para trás no 
history de ESTADOS UNIDOS (que liga, para o exemplo, os antics 
contemporary da imprensa mais outrageous do tabloid com o mid-décimo 
nono showmanship do século de P. T. Barnum).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alla fine del ventesimo secolo, 93 per cento della
popolazione degli STATI UNITI hanno professato credere negli angeli, 
49 per cento erano sicuri che il governo federale stava nascondendo le
informazioni sull'esistenza degli oggetti non identificati di volo e 
25 per cento hanno pensato che potrebbero comunicare con i morti. 
Molti Americani hanno scelto le opzioni mystical sopra le 
funzioni più torve di vita millennial, ma l'interesse popolare nel 
fantastico anche segnalato un amore di montaggio creativo che data 
nuovamente dentro gli STATI UNITI la storia (che collega, per esempio,
i antics contemporanei della pressa più outrageous del tabloid con il
metà di-diciannovesimo showmanship di secolo di P. T. Barnum).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στον περίβολο του εικοστού αιώνα, 93 τοις εκατό του
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ πληθυσμού δήλωσαν φανερά να πιστεψουν στους αγγέλους,
49 τοις εκατό ήταν σίγουρα ότι η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση 
έκρυβε τις πληροφορίες για την ύπαρξη unidentified φλυηνγ 
οψιεθτς, και 25 τοις εκατό σκέφτηκαν ότι θα μπορούσαν να 
επικοινωνήσουν με τους νεκρούς. Πολλοί Αμερικανοί επέλεξαν 
τις μυστικές προαιρετικές δυνατότητες πέρα από τις πτυχές 
grimmer της χιλιετούς ζωής, αλλά το δημοφιλές ενδιαφέρον για 
το φανταστικό επεσήμανε επίσης μια αγάπη της δημιουργικής 
επεξεργασίας χρονολογώντας πίσω στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία 
(σύνδεση, παραδείγματος χάριν, το σύγχρονο antics του πιό 
προσβλητικού μικρού σχήματος Τύπου με το showmanship του 
μέσος-δέκατου έννατου αιώνα Σελ. Τ. Barnum).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el cierre del vigésimo siglo, 93 por ciento de
la población de ESTADOS UNIDOS profesaron creer en ángeles, 49 por 
ciento eran seguros que el gobierno federal ocultaba la información 
sobre la existencia de los objetos no identificados del vuelo, y 25 
por ciento pensaron que podrían comunicarse con los muertos. 
Muchos americanos eligieron opciones mystical sobre los aspectos
más severos de la vida millennial, pero interés popular en el 
fantástico también señalado un amor de la fabricación creativa que
fechaba nuevamente dentro de ESTADOS UNIDOS la historia (que conecta, 
por ejemplo, los antics contemporáneos de la prensa más indignante 
del tabloid con el mediados de-diecinueveavo showmanship del siglo de 
P. T. Barnum).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087425</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103820</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/believe-it-or-not</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
