<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107774</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107774</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212628</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Lifestyle Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Lebensstil Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Projet de Style de vie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Projeto Do Lifestyle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Di Lifestyle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα τρόπου ζωής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Proyecto De la Forma de vida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This innovative project offers a way for students to learn about environmental alternatives by modifying their own lifestyles. It is a three-week exercise for students to reduce their impact on the environment by changing the way in which they live from day to day. This website contains an article about the Lifestyle Project and all the materials needed to teach the project. Materials include a baseline quiz, worksheets, energy facts and figures, and an Excel spreadsheet for students to calculate their energy use. By participating in this project, students will gain first hand insights about energy conservation, water conservation and waste reduction.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses erfinderische Projekt bietet eine Methode 
an, damit Kursteilnehmer über Klimaalternativen erlernen, indem es 
ihre eigenen Lebensstile ändert. Es ist eine dreiwöchige 
Übung, damit Kursteilnehmer ihre Auswirkung auf die Umgebung 
verringern, indem es die Methode ändert, in der sie von täglichem 
leben. Diese Web site enthält einen Artikel über das 
Lebensstil Projekt und alle Materialien, das benötigt werden, um das 
Projekt zu unterrichten. Materialien schließen einen Grundlinie
Quiz, Bogen, Energietatsachen und -abbildungen und eine 
übertreffenkalkulationstabelle ein, damit Kursteilnehmer ihren 
Energiegebrauch errechnen. Indem sie an diesem Projekt 
teilnehmen, gewinnen Kursteilnehmer erste Handeinblicke über 
Energieerhaltung, Wassererhaltung und Vergeudung Verkleinerung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce projet innovateur offre une voie pour que les 
étudiants se renseignent sur des solutions de rechange 
environnementales en modifiant leurs propres styles de vie. 
C'est un exercice de trois semaines pour que les étudiants 
réduisent leur impact sur l'environnement en changeant la voie dont 
ils vivent de quotidien. Ce site Web contient un article 
concernant le projet de style de vie et tous matériaux requis pour 
enseigner le projet. Les matériaux incluent un jeu de ligne de 
base, des tableaux, des faits et des chiffres d'énergie, et un 
tableur d'exceler pour que les étudiants calculent leur utilisation 
d'énergie. En participant à ce projet, les étudiants 
gagneront des perspicacités de première main au sujet d'économie 
d'énergie, d'économie de l'eau et de réduction de perte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este projeto inovativo oferece uma maneira para 
que os estudantes aprendam sobre alternativas ambientais modificando 
seus próprios lifestyles. É um exercício three-week para que 
os estudantes reduzam seu impacto no ambiente mudando a maneira em que
vivem do dia ao dia. Este Web site contem um artigo sobre o 
projeto do lifestyle e todos os materiais necessitado ensinar o 
projeto. Os materiais incluem um quiz da linha de base, folhas, 
fatos e figuras da energia, e um spreadsheet do excel para que os 
estudantes calculem seu uso da energia. Participando neste 
projeto, os estudantes ganharão primeiras introspecções da mão 
sobre o conservation de energia, o conservation da água e a redução
do desperdício.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo progetto innovatore offre un modo affinchè
gli allievi impari circa le alternative ambientali modificando i loro 
propri lifestyles. È un'esercitazione di tre settimane 
affinchè gli allievi riduca il loro effetto sull'ambiente cambiando 
il modo in cui vivono da quotidiano. Questo Web site contiene un
articolo sul progetto di lifestyle e tutti i materiali stato 
necessario per insegnare il progetto. I materiali includono un 
quiz della linea di base, fogli di lavoro, fatti e figure di energia e
un foglio elettronico di supremazia affinchè gli allievi calcolino il
loro uso di energia. Partecipando a questo progetto, gli allievi
guadagneranno le prime comprensioni della mano circa risparmio 
energetico, conservazione dell'acqua e riduzione dello spreco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το καινοτόμο πρόγραμμα προσφέρει έναν τρόπο για
τους σπουδαστές να μάθουν για τις περιβαλλοντικές εναλλακτικές 
λύσεις με την τροποποίηση των τρόπων ζωής τους. Είναι μια 
τριών εβδομάδων άσκηση για τους σπουδαστές για να μειώσει τον 
αντίκτυπό τους στο περιβάλλον με την αλλαγή του τρόπου με τον 
οποίο ζουν από καθημερινό. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει ένα
άρθρο για το πρόγραμμα τρόπου ζωής και όλα τα υλικά που 
απαιτείται για να διδάξει το πρόγραμμα. Τα υλικά 
περιλαμβάνουν έναν διαγωνισμό γνώσεων βασικών γραμμών, τα φύλλα
εργασίας, τα ενεργειακούς γεγονότα και τους αριθμούς, και έναν 
υπολογισμό με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet) Excel για τους 
σπουδαστές για να υπολογίσουν την ενεργειακή χρήση τους. Με 
τη συμμετοχή σε αυτό το πρόγραμμα, οι σπουδαστές θα αποκτήσουν 
τις πρώτες επιγνώσεις χεριών για την ενεργειακή συντήρηση, τη 
συντήρηση ύδατος και τη μείωση αποβλήτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este proyecto innovador ofrece una manera para que
los estudiantes aprendan sobre alternativas ambientales modificando 
sus propias formas de vida. Es un ejercicio de tres semanas para
que los estudiantes reduzcan su impacto en el ambiente cambiando la 
manera de la cual viven de cotidiano. Este Web site contiene un 
artículo acerca del proyecto de la forma de vida y todos los 
materiales necesitado para enseñar el proyecto. Los materiales 
incluyen un concurso de la línea de fondo, las hojas de trabajo, los 
hechos y las figuras de la energía, y una hoja de balance del 
sobresalir para que los estudiantes calculen su uso de la energía. 
Participando en este proyecto, los estudiantes ganarán 
penetraciones de primera mano sobre la conservación de energía, la 
conservación del agua y la reducción de la basura.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KARIN KIRK
FN:KARIN KIRK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOHN THOMAS
FN:JOHN THOMAS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212628</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107774</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-lifestyle-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
