<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104701</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104701</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087004</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Negro Voter: Can He Elect a President?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Der Schwarze-Wähler: Kann er einen 
Präsidenten wählen?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"L'Électeur de Nègre : Peut il élire un 
président?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Eleitor Do Negro: Pode eleger um 
presidente?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"L'Elettore Del Negro: Può scegliere un 
presidente?"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο ψηφοφόρος νέγρων: Μπορεί να εκλέξει έναν 
Πρόεδρο;"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Votante Del Negro: Puede él elegir a un 
presidente?"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Journalist Theodore H. White received widespread acclaim for his "The Making of the President" series that analyzed election campaigns of the 1960s and 1970s. As White points out in the following  Collier's  article, African-American migration to Northern cities from the South made the black voter an important player in national politics by the mid-1950s. From 1910 to 1970, more than 6.5 million African Americans came North, with 3 million arriving in cities between 1940 and 1960. During the 1956 presidential campaign, Democratic Party candidate Adlai Stevenson attempted to win this black vote by voicing support for the 1954 Supreme Court decision  Brown  v.  Board of Education , outlawing segregated schools, a ruling incumbent President Dwight D. Eisenhower had refused to approve. Stevenson's appeal to black voters, however, was muted by his opposition to using Federal funds or troops to enforce desegregation, a position he adopted to avoid alienating southern voters. In addition, in the 1952 race, Stevenson had selected as his running mate a segregationist Senator from Alabama, John Sparkman. In October, African-American Congressman Adam Clayton Powell, Jr., announced his support of the President, and on election day, more than 60 percent of black voters also chose Eisenhower. This marked a shift in party allegiance by blacks who had voted overwhelmingly Democratic since the 1930s, when many changed from the party of Lincoln to support Franklin D. Roosevelt. Although Eisenhower's rout of Stevenson was attributed more to foreign affairs than domestic, the black vote continued to be a major factor in national politics.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Journalist Theodore H. White empfing weitverbreiteten 
Beifall für seins "das Bilden des Präsidenten" Serie, die 
Wahlkampagnen der sechziger Jahre und der siebziger Jahre analysierte.
Da Weiß im folgenden Artikel des Colliers unterstreicht, 
bildete Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Migration zu den Nordstädte vom 
Süden den schwarzen Wähler einen wichtigen Spieler in der nationalen
Politik bis zum den Mid-1950s. Von 1910 bis 1970, kamen mehr als
6.5 Million afrikanische Amerikaner nördlich, wenn 3 Million in den 
Städte ankommen, zwischen 1940 und 1960. Während der 
Präsidentenkampagne 1956 versuchte demokratischer Parteianwärter
Adlai Stevenson, diese schwarze Stimme zu gewinnen, indem er Support 
für das Brett Entscheidung des Höchsten Gerichts 1954 des Braun-V. 
der Ausbildung äußerte und getrennte Schulen, einen regierenden 
Amtsinhaber ächtete, den Präsident Dwight D. Eisenhower abgelehnt 
hatte zu genehmigen. Der Anklang Stevensons, zum der Wähler zu 
schwärzen war jedoch durch seine Opposition zum Verwenden der 
Staatspapiere oder der Truppen, um desegregation, eine Position zu 
erzwingen gedämpft, die er annahm, um südliche, Wähler zu 
entfremden zu vermeiden. Zusätzlich im Rennen 1952, hatte 
Stevenson als sein laufender Gehilfe einen segregationist Senator von 
Alabama, John Sparkman ausgewählt. Im Oktober verkündete 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanisches Kongreßabgeordnetes Adam Clayton Powell, 
jr., seinen Support des Präsidenten, und am Wahltag, wählten mehr 
als 60 Prozent schwarze Wähler auch Eisenhower. Dieses 
kennzeichnete eine Schicht in der Parteiuntertanentreue durch 
Schwarze, die überwältigend demokratisches seit den dreißiger 
Jahren gewählt hatten, als viele von der Partei von Lincoln 
zum Support Franklin D. Roosevelt änderten. Obgleich Rout 
Eisenhowers von Stevenson mehr zur Außenpolitik als Hausangestellt 
zugeschrieben wurde, fuhr die schwarze Stimme fort, ein Hauptfaktor in
der nationalen Politik zu sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le journaliste Theodore H. White a reçu l'acclamation 
répandue pour le sien "la fabrication la série de président" qui a 
analysé des campagnes d'élection des années 60 et des années 70. 
Car le blanc précise dans l'article suivant de Collier, le 
transfert afro-américain aux villes nordiques des Sud a fait à 
l'électeur noir un joueur important dans la politique nationale par 
le milieu des années 50. De 1910 à 1970, plus de 6.5 millions 
d'Américains africains sont venus nord, avec 3 millions 
arrivant dans les villes entre 1940 et 1960. Pendant la campagne
1956 présidentielle, le candidat Adlai Stevenson de parti 
démocratique a essayé de gagner cette voix noire en exprimant le 
soutien du conseil du brun v. de décision de la cour 1954 suprême de
l'éducation, proscrivant les écoles isolées, un candidat sortant 
régnant que le Président Dwight D. Eisenhower avait refusé 
d'approuver. L'appel de Stevenson pour noircir des électeurs, 
cependant, était amorti par son opposition à utiliser les fonds 
fédéraux ou les troupes pour imposer la déségrégation, une position 
qu'il a adopté pour éviter aliéner les électeurs méridionaux. 
En outre, dans la course 1952, Stevenson avait choisi en tant 
que son compagnon courant un sénateur ségrégationiste à partir de 
l'Alabama, John Sparkman. En octobre, le membre du Congrès 
afro-américain Adam Clayton Powell, Jr., a annoncé son 
support du président, et le jour d'élection, plus de 60 pour cent 
d'électeurs noirs ont également choisi Eisenhower. Ceci a 
marqué une variation dans l'allégeance de partie par les noirs qui 
avaient voté primordialement démocratique depuis les années 30, 
quand beaucoup ont changé de la partie de Lincoln en le support 
Franklin D. Roosevelt. Bien que la déroute d'Eisenhower de 
Stevenson ait été attribuée plus aux affaires étrangères que le 
domestique, la voix noire a continué à être un facteur important 
dans la politique nationale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O journalist Theodore H. Branco recebeu acclaim difundido 
para his "fazer a série do presidente" que analisou campanhas de 
eleição dos 1960s e dos 1970s. Porque o branco indica no 
artigo do seguinte collier, a migração Africano-Americana às 
cidades do norte do sul fêz ao eleitor preto um jogador importante na
política nacional pelos mid-1950s. 1910 a 1970, mais de 6.5 
milhão americanos africanos vieram para o norte, com os 3 milhões 
que chegam nas cidades entre 1940 e 1960. Durante a campanha 
1956 presidencial, o candidato Adlai Stevenson do partido democrático
tentou ganhar este voto preto exprimindo a sustentação para a placa 
do marrom v. da decisão da corte 1954 suprema da instrução, 
outlawing escolas segregadas, um encarregado que governando o 
presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower tinha recusado aprovar. A 
apelação de Stevenson para enegrecer eleitores, entretanto, era 
muted por sua oposição a usar fundos federais ou tropas reforçar o 
desegregation, uma posição que adotou para evitar de alienating 
eleitores do sul. Além, na raça 1952, Stevenson tinha 
selecionado como seu mate running um senator de Alabama, John Sparkman
do segregationist. Em outubro, o congressista Africano-Americano
Adam Clayton Powell, Jr., anunciou sua sustentação do presidente, e 
no dia de eleição, mais de 60 por cento de eleitores pretos 
escolheram também Eisenhower. Isto marcou uma SHIFT no 
allegiance do partido pelos pretos que tinham votado overwhelmingly 
democrático desde os 1930s, quando muitos mudaram do partido de 
Lincoln à sustentação Franklin D. Roosevelt. Embora o rout de
Eisenhower de Stevenson fosse atribuído mais aos casos extrangeiros 
do que o domestic, o voto preto continuou a ser um fator principal na 
política nacional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il giornalista Theodore H. White ha ricevuto 
l'acclamazione diffusa per suo "fare serie del presidente" che ha 
analizzato le campagne elettorali degli anni 60 e degli anni 70. 
Poichè il bianco precisa nell'articolo del seguente collier, 
l'espansione Africano-Americana alle città nordiche dal sud ha reso 
all'elettore nero un giocatore importante nella politica nazionale 
entro i mid-1950s. 1910 - 1970, più di 6.5 milione Americani 
africani sono venuto a nord, con 3 milioni che arrivano nelle città 
fra 1940 e 1960. Durante la campagna presidenziale 1956, il 
candidato Adlai Stevenson del partito democratico ha tentato di 
vincere questo voto nero esprimendo il sostegno il Bordo di 
colore marrone v. di decisione della Corte suprema 1954 di formazione,
proscrivente le scuole segregate, un incumbent che di regolamento il 
presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower aveva rifiutato di approvare. 
L'appello dello Stevenson per annerire gli elettori, tuttavia, 
era muted dalla sua opposizione a usando i fondi monetari federali o 
le truppe per fare rispettare il desegregation, una posizione che ha 
adottato per evitare di allontanare gli elettori del sud. In 
più, nella corsa 1952, Stevenson aveva selezionato come suo compagno 
corrente un senatore a partire dall'Alabama, John Sparkman di 
segregationist. In ottobre, il membro del Congresso 
Africano-Americano Adam Clayton Powell, Jr., ha annunciato il suo 
supporto del presidente ed il giorno di elezione, più di 60 per cento
degli elettori neri egualmente hanno scelto Eisenhower. Ciò ha 
contrassegnato una variazione nel allegiance del partito dai neri che 
avevano votato in modo schiacciante democratico dai 1930s, quando 
molti sono cambiato dal partito di Lincoln a supporto Franklin D. 
Roosevelt. Anche se la disfatta del Eisenhower di Stevenson 
è stata attribuita più agli affari esteri che il domestic, il voto 
nero ha continuato ad essere un fattore importante nella politica 
nazionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Journalist Theodore Χ. White έλαβε τη 
διαδεδομένη αναγνώριση για "η παραγωγή τη σειρά του Προέδρου του"
που ανέλυσε τις προεκλογικές εκστρατείες της δεκαετίας του '60 και
της δεκαετίας του '70. Όπως το λευκό επισημαίνει στο άρθρο 
του ακόλουθου ανθρακωρύχου, η αφρικανικός-αμερικανική 
μετανάστευση στις βόρειες πόλεις από το νότο έκανε το μαύρο 
ψηφοφόρο έναν σημαντικό φορέα στην εθνική πολιτική μέχρι τα 
μέσα τησδεκαετίας του '50. Από το 1910 ως το 1970, 
περισσότεροι από 6,5 εκατομμύριο αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί ήρθαν
βόρεια, με 3 εκατομμύρια φθάνοντας στις πόλεις μεταξύ 1940 και
1960, Κατά τη διάρκεια της προεδρικής εκστρατείας του 
1956, ο δημοκρατικός υποψήφιος Adlai Stevenson 
συμβαλλόμενου μέρους που προσπαθήθηκε για να κερδίσει αυτήν την 
μαύρη ψηφοφορία με την έκφραση της υποστήριξης για την απόφαση 
Brown V. Board ανώτατου δικαστηρίου του 1954 της 
εκπαίδευσης, που προγράφει τα διαχωρισμένα σχολεία, ένας 
κυβερνών κατέχων υπεύθυνη θέση Πρόεδρος Dwight D. 
Eisenhower είχε αρνηθεί να εγκρίνει. Την έκκληση του 
Stevenson στους μαύρους ψηφοφόρους, εντούτοις, από χαμήλωσε η 
αντίθεσή του στη χρησιμοποίηση των ομοσπονδιακών κεφαλαίων ή 
συγκεντρώνεται για να επιβάλει το διαχωρισμό, μια θέση που 
υιοθέτησε για να αποφύγει τους νότιους ψηφοφόρους. 
Επιπλέον, στη φυλή του 1952, Stevenson είχε επιλέξει 
ως τρέχοντας σύντροφό του έναν segregationist γερουσιαστή από
την Αλαμπάμα, John Sparkman. Τον Οκτώβριο, το 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικό μέλος του Κογκρέσσου Adam Clayton 
Powell, νεώτερος, ανήγγειλε την υποστήριξή του του Προέδρου, 
και την ημέρα εκλογής, περισσότερα από 60 τοις εκατό των 
μαύρων ψηφοφόρων επέλεξαν επίσης Eisenhower. Αυτό 
χαρακτήρισε μια μετατόπιση στην υποταγή συμβαλλόμενων μερών από 
τους Μαύρους που είχαν ψηφίσει συντριπτικά δημοκρατικό από τη 
δεκαετία του '30, όταν άλλαξαν πολλές από το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος
του Λίνκολν για να υποστηρίξουν Franklin Δ. Roosevelt. 
Αν και η κατατρόπωση Eisenhower Stevenson αποδόθηκε 
περισσότερο στις εξωτερικές υποθέσεις από εσωτερική, η μαύρη 
ψηφοφορία συνέχισε να είναι ένας σημαντικός παράγοντας στην 
εθνική πολιτική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El periodista Theodore H. White recibió la aclamación 
extensa para el suyo "la fabricación la serie del presidente" que 
analizaba las campañas lectorales de los años 60 y de los años 70. 
Pues el blanco precisa en el artículo del collier siguiente, la
migración Africano-Americana a las ciudades norteñas del sur hizo el
votante negro a jugador importante en política nacional por los 
mediados de los años cincuenta. A partir la 1910 a 1970, más 
de 6.5 millones de americanos africanos vinieron al norte, con 3 
millones llegando en ciudades entre 1940 y 1960. Durante la 
campaña presidencial 1956, el candidato Adlai Stevenson del partido 
democrático procuró ganar este voto negro expresando la ayuda para 
la tarjeta del marrón v. de la decisión del Tribunal Supremo 1954 de
la educación, proscribiendo las escuelas segregadas, titular 
predominante que presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower había rechazado 
aprobar. La súplica de Stevenson para ennegrecer a votantes, 
sin embargo, era silenciada por su oposición a usar fondos federales 
o a tropas para hacer cumplir el desegregation, una posición que él 
adoptó para evitar de enajenar a votantes meridionales. 
Además, en la raza 1952, Stevenson había seleccionado como su 
compañero corriente a senador de Alabama, Juan Sparkman del 
segregationist. En octubre, el miembro del Congreso 
Africano-Americano Adán Clayton Powell, Jr., anunció su ayuda del 
presidente, y el día de elección, más de 60 por ciento de votantes 
negros también eligieron Eisenhower. Esto marcó una rotación 
en lealtad del partido por los negros que habían votado de forma 
aplastante democrático desde los años 30, cuando muchos cambiaron 
del partido de Lincoln a la ayuda Franklin D. Roosevelt. Aunque 
la derrota de Eisenhower de Stevenson fue atribuida más a los asuntos
no nativos que domestic, el voto negro continuó siendo un factor 
importante en política nacional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087004</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104701</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-negro-voter-can-he-elect-a-president</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
