<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108651</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108651</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087173</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Are All Equally Free": New York City Workingmen Demand A Voice in the Revolutionary Struggle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Sind" Alles Gleichmäßig Freie: New 
York City Workingmen verlangen eine Stimme im revolutionären Kampf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Sommes Tout l'également Libres" : Les
ouvriers de New York City exigent une voix dans la lutte 
révolutionnaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Estamos Todo o Ingualmente Livres": Os
workingmen de New York City exigem uma voz no esforço 
revolucionário</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Siamo Tutto il Ugualmente Libero": I 
workingmen de New York City richiedono una voce nella lotta 
rivoluzionaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είμαστε όλοι εξίσου ελεύθεροι": Η πόλη 
Workingmen της Νέας Υόρκης απαιτεί μια φωνή στην επαναστατική 
προσπάθεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Estamos Todo el Igualmente Libres": Los 
workingmen de New York City exigen una voz en la lucha revolucionaria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The struggle against Great Britain in the years leading up to the War for Independence promoted an expansion of popular participation in politics. Popular pamphlets,urban demonstrations, and voluntary associations such as the Sons of Liberty gave voice to the sentiments of ordinary men and women. In May 1770 an anonymous author named "Brutus"--believed to be the New York City merchant and Son of Liberty Alexander McDougall--addressed his fellow citizens and urged them to reject the claims of leading merchants or "Mercantile Dons," as he labeled them, to decide unilaterally issues of great political and economic concern. Two years earlier, some merchants had organized boycotts against certain products imported from Great Britain (a strategy known as nonimportation) to resist British taxation measures aimed at the rebellious Americans. And these merchants regarded the decision to resume trade as their decision alone to make. But Brutus disagreed, and responded with this single-sheet broadside.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kampf gegen Großbritannien in den Jahren, die
bis zum Krieg für Unabhängigkeit führen, förderte eine Expansion 
der populären Teilnahme an der Politik. Populäre 
Flugschriften, städtische Demonstrationen und c4vereinigungen ohne 
eigene Rechtspersönlichkeit wie die Söhne der Freiheit gaben Stimme 
zu den Gefühlen der gewöhnlichen Männer und der Frauen. Im 
Mai 1770, das ein anonymer Autor "Brutus" -- geglaubt, um der New York
City Kaufmann und der Sohn der Freiheit Alexander McDougall zu sein --
sprach zu seinen Mitbürgern benannte und gedrängt ihnen, zum der 
Ansprüche der führenden Kaufleute zurückzuweisen oder 
"kaufmännisch zieht,", während er sie beschriftete an, um Ausgaben 
des großen politischen und ökonomischen Interesses einseitig zu 
entscheiden. Zwei Jahre früher, hatten einige Kaufleute 
Boykotts gegen bestimmte Produkte organisiert, die aus Großbritannien
importiert wurden (eine Strategie bekannt als nonimportation) um 
britischen Besteuerungmassen zu widerstehen anstrebten die rebellious 
Amerikaner. Und diese Kaufleute betrachteten die Entscheidung, 
um Handel als ihre Entscheidung alleine wieder aufzunehmen, um zu 
bilden. Aber BrutusWAR anderer Meinung und reagierte mit dieser 
Einzelformularbreitseite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La lutte contre la Grande-Bretagne en années 
amenant à la guerre pour l'indépendance a favorisé une expansion de
participation populaire à la politique. Les brochures 
populaires, les démonstrations urbaines, et les associations 
volontaires telles que les fils de la liberté ont donné la voix aux 
sentiments des hommes et des femmes ordinaires. En mai 1770 où 
un auteur anonyme a nommé "Brutus" -- pensé pour être le négociant
de New York City et le fils de la liberté Alexandre McDougall -- 
s'est adressé à ses citoyens de camarade et recommandé leur pour 
rejeter les réclamations des principaux négociants ou "marchand 
met," pendant qu'il les étiquetait, pour décider unilatéralement 
des issues de grand souci politique et économique. Deux ans de 
plus tôt, quelques négociants avaient organisé des boycotts contre 
certains produits importés de Grande-Bretagne (une stratégie connue 
sous le nom de nonimportation) pour résister à des mesures 
britanniques d'imposition ont visé les Américains rebelles. 
Et ces négociants ont considéré la décision pour reprendre 
le commerce en tant que leur seule décision pour faire. Mais 
Brutus était en désaccord, et a répondu avec ce flanc 
single-sheet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O esforço de encontro a Grâ Bretanha nos anos 
que conduzem à guerra para a independência promoveu uma expansão da
participação popular na política. Os panfletos populares, as 
demonstrações urbanas, e as associações voluntárias tais como os 
filhos da liberdade deram a voz aos sentiments de homens e de mulheres
ordinários. Em maio 1770 onde um autor anonymous nomeou 
"Brutus" -- acreditado para ser o comerciante de New York City e o 
filho da liberdade Alexander McDougall -- se dirigiu a seus cidadãos 
do companheiro e incitado lhes para rejeitar as reivindicações de 
comerciantes principais ou "mercantile dons," enquanto os etiquetou, 
para decidir unilaterally introduções do interesse político e 
econômico grande. Dois anos mais adiantado, alguns comerciantes
tinham organizado boycotts de encontro a determinados produtos 
importados de Grâ Bretanha (uma estratégia sabida como o 
nonimportation) para resistir medidas britânicas do taxation visaram 
os americanos rebellious. E estes comerciantes consideraram a 
decisão para recomeçar o comércio como sua decisão sozinho para 
fazer. Mas Brutus discordou, e respondeu com este broadside 
single-sheet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lotta contro la Gran Bretagna durante gli anni 
che portano alla guerra per indipendenza ha promosso un'espansione di 
partecipazione popolare alla politica. Gli opuscoli popolari, le
dimostrazioni urbane e le associazioni volontarie quali i figli della 
libertà hanno dato la voce ai sentimenti degli uomini e delle donne 
ordinari. Nel mese di maggio 1770 che un autore anonimo ha 
chiamato "Brutus" -- creduto per essere il commerciante de New York 
City ed il figlio di libertà Alexander McDougall -- ha parlato ai 
suoi cittadini del collega e li ha invitati a rifiutare i reclami dei 
commercianti principali o "mercantile indossa," mentre li ha 
identificati, per decidere unilateralmente le emissioni di 
preoccupazione politica ed economica grande. Più in anticipo 
due anni, alcuni commercianti avevano organizzato i boicottaggi contro
determinati prodotti importati dalla Gran Bretagna (una strategia 
conosciuta come il nonimportation) per resistere alle misure 
britanniche di tassa hanno puntato sugli Americani rebellious. E
questi commercianti hanno considerato la decisione per riprendere il 
commercio come loro decisione da solo per fare. Ma Brutus è non
stato d'accordo ed ha risposto con questo attacco single-sheet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αγώνας κατά της Μεγάλης Βρετανίας στα έτη που 
καταλήγουν στον πόλεμο για την ανεξαρτησία προώθησε μια επέκταση 
της δημοφιλούς συμμετοχής στην πολιτική. Τα δημοφιλή τεύχη,
οι αστικές επιδείξεις, και οι εθελοντικές ενώσεις όπως οι γιοι 
της ελευθερίας έδωσαν τη φωνή στα συναισθήματα των συνηθισμένων 
ανδρών και των γυναικών. Σε Μάιος 1770 ένας ανώνυμος
συντάκτης που ονομάστηκε "Brutus" -- θεωρημένος για να είναι ο 
έμπορος πόλεων της Νέας Υόρκης και ο γιος της ελευθερίας 
Αλέξανδρος McDougall -- απευθύνθηκε στους συντροφικούς πολίτες 
του και τους ώθησε για να απορρίψει τις αξιώσεις των κορυφαίων 
εμπόρων ή "εμπορικός φορά," δεδομένου ότι τους ονόμασε, για να 
αποφασίσει μονομερώς τα ζητήματα της μεγάλης πολιτικής και 
οικονομικής ανησυχίας. Δύο έτη νωρίτερα, μερικοί έμποροι 
είχαν οργανώσει τα μποϊκοταρίσματα ενάντια σε ορισμένα 
προϊόντα που εισήχθησαν από τη Μεγάλη Βρετανία (μια στρατηγική 
γνωστή ως nonimportation) για να αντισταθούν στα βρετανικά 
φορολογικά μέτρα που στόχευσαν στους επαναστατικούς Αμερικανούς. 
Και αυτοί οι έμποροι θεώρησαν την απόφαση να επαναλάβουν το
εμπόριο ως απόφασή τους να κάνουν μόνο. Αλλά Brutus 
διαφώνησε, και αποκρίθηκε με αυτό το single-sheet broadside.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La lucha contra Gran Bretaña en los años que 
conducían a la guerra para la independencia promovió una extensión 
de la participación popular en política. Los folletos 
populares, las demostraciones urbanas, y las asociaciones voluntarias 
tales como los hijos de la libertad dieron voz a los sentimientos de 
hombres y de mujeres ordinarios. En mayo de 1770 que un autor 
anónimo nombró "Brutus" -- creído para ser el comerciante de New 
York City y el hijo de la libertad Alexander McDougall -- se dirigió 
a sus ciudadanos del compañero e impulsado les para rechazar las 
demandas de comerciantes principales o "mercantil pone," como él los 
etiquetó, para decidir unilateral aplicaciones la gran preocupación 
política y económica. Dos años de anterior, algunos 
comerciantes habían ordenado boicoteos contra ciertos productos 
importados de Gran Bretaña (una estrategia conocida como 
nonimportation) para oponerse a medidas británicas de los impuestos 
tuvieron como objetivo a americanos rebellious. Y estos 
comerciantes miraron la decisión para reasumir comercio como su 
decisión solamente para hacer. Pero Brutus discrepó, y 
respondió con este costado single-sheet.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087173</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108651</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-are-all-equally-free-new-york-city-workingmen-demand-a-voice-in-the-revolutionary-struggle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
