<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104153</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104153</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086759</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Present at the Beginning of the Gold Rush: Journalist Edward Gould Buffum Pans Gold in California, 1848</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschenk am Anfang der Goldanstürme: 
Journalist Edward Gould Buffum verschiebt Gold in Kalifornien, 
1848</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Présent au début des précipitations d'or : 
Le journaliste Edouard Gould Buffum filtre l'or en 
Californie, 1848</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Presente no começo das arremetidas do ouro: 
O journalist Edward Gould Buffum garimpa o ouro em Califórnia, 
1848</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Presente all'inizio degli sbalzi dell'oro: 
Il giornalista Edward Gould Buffum fa una panoramica dell'oro 
nella California, 1848</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρόν στην αρχή της χρυσής βιασύνης: 
Δημοσιογράφος Edward Gould Buffum Pans Gold σε 
Καλιφόρνια, 1848</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presente al principio de las acometidas del oro: 
El periodista Edward Gould Buffum filtra el oro en California, 
1848</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Edward Gould Buffum (1820-1867) went to California in 1846 as a soldier in a New York regiment during the Mexican War. There, Buffum and his regiment helped wrest California from Mexico. After his discharge from the army, Buffum remained to pan gold in the area around John Sutter's sawmills where it had just been discovered. A journalist by profession, Buffum recorded his experiences in a book,  Six Months in the Gold Mines , from which this excerpt comes. He commented with wonder that men in the California gold mines earned one hundred dollars per day on average. To understand what a fortune this was, consider that women working as domestic servants in northeastern cities at this time earned between four and seven dollars per month.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Edward Gould Buffum (1820-1867) ging zu 
Kalifornien in 1846 als Soldat in einem New York Regiment während des
mexikanischen Krieges. Dort halfen Buffum und sein Regiment 
wrest Kalifornien von Mexiko. Nachdem seine Entladung von der 
Armee, Buffum blieb, Gold im Bereich um John Sutters Sägemühlen zu 
verschieben, in denen es gerade entdeckt worden war. Ein 
Journalist durch Beruf, Buffum speicherte seine Erfahrungen in einem 
Buch, sechs Monate in den Goldminen, von denen dieses Excerpt kommt. 
Er kommentierte mit Wunder, daß Männer in den Kalifornien 
Goldminen hundert Dollar pro Tag auf Durchschnitt erwarben. Um 
zu verstehen was ein Vermögen dieses war, betrachten Sie daß die 
Frauen, die als inländische Bedienstete in den nordöstlichen Städte
diesmal arbeiten, das zwischen vier und sieben Dollar pro Monat 
erworben wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Edouard Gould Buffum (1820-1867) est allé à
la Californie dans 1846 en tant que soldat dans un régiment de New 
York pendant la guerre mexicaine. Là, Buffum et son régiment 
ont aidé la Californie wrest du Mexique. Après que sa 
décharge de l'armée, Buffum soit demeurée pour filtrer l'or dans la
zone autour des scieries de John Sutter où on l'avait juste 
découvert. Un journaliste par profession, Buffum a enregistré 
ses expériences d'un livre, six mois dans les mines d'or, desquelles 
cet extrait vient. Il a commenté avec la merveille que les 
hommes dans les mines d'or de la Californie ont gagné cent dollars 
par jour en moyenne. Pour comprendre ce qu'était une fortune 
ceci, considérez que des femmes travaillant en tant que domestiques 
domestiques dans les villes du nord-est à ce moment gagné entre 
quatre et sept dollars par mois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Edward Gould Buffum (1820-1867) foi a Califórnia 
em 1846 como um soldado em um regiment de New York durante a guerra 
mexicana. Lá, Buffum e seu regiment ajudaram à Califórnia a 
mais wrest de México. Depois que sua descarga do exército, 
Buffum remanesceu garimpar o ouro na área em torno dos sawmills de 
John Sutter onde se tinha descoberto apenas. Um journalist pela 
profissão, Buffum gravou suas experiências em um livro, seis meses 
nas minas de ouro, de que este excerpt vem. Comentou com 
maravilha que os homens nas minas de ouro de Califórnia ganharam cem 
dólares por o dia na média. Para compreender o que uma fortuna
isto era, considere que as mulheres que trabalham como empregados 
domésticos em cidades do nordeste neste tempo ganho entre quatro e 
sete dólares por o mês.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Edward Gould Buffum (1820-1867) è andato alla 
California in 1846 come soldato in un regiment de New York durante la 
guerra messicana. Là, Buffum ed il suo regiment contribuiti a 
strappare California dal Messico. Dopo che il suo 
scarico dall'esercito, Buffum rimanga fare una panoramica dell'oro 
nella zona intorno alle segherie del John Sutter in cui era stato 
scoperto appena. Un giornalista dalla professione, Buffum ha 
registrato le sue esperienze di libro, sei mesi nelle miniere di oro, 
da cui questo brano viene. Ha commentato con wonder che gli 
uomini nelle miniere di oro della California hanno guadagnato cento 
dollari al giorno in media. Per capire che cosa una fortuna 
questo era, consideri che donne che lavorano come servi domestici in 
città di nordest attualmente guadagnato fra quattro e sette dollari 
al mese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Edward Gould Buffum (1820-1867) πήγε σε 
Καλιφόρνια το 1846 ως στρατιώτης σε ένα σύνταγμα της Νέας 
Υόρκης κατά τη διάρκεια του μεξικάνικου πολέμου. Εκεί, 
Buffum και το σύνταγμά του που ενισχύονται να αποσπάσει 
Καλιφόρνια από το Μεξικό. Μετά από την απαλλαγή του από 
το στρατό, Buffum παρέμεινε να φιλτραρίσει το χρυσό στην 
περιοχή γύρω από τα πριονιστήρια John Sutter's όπου ήταν 
ανακαλυμμενός ακριβώς. Ένας δημοσιογράφος από το 
επάγγελμα, Buffum κατέγραψε την εμπειρία του σε ένα βιβλίο, 
έξι μήνες στα χρυσά ορυχεία, από τα οποία αυτό το απόσπασμα 
προέρχεται. Σχολίασε με την κατάπληξη ότι τα άτομα στα 
χρυσά ορυχεία Καλιφόρνιας κέρδισαν εκατό δολάρια ανά ημέρα 
κατά μέσον όρο. Για να καταλάβετε ποια τύχη αυτό ήταν, 
θεωρήστε ότι γυναίκες που εργάζονται ως εσωτερικοί υπάλληλοι 
στις βορειοανατολικές πόλεις που κερδίζονται αυτή τη στιγμή 
μεταξύ τεσσάρων και επτά δολαρίων το μήνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Edward Gould Buffum (1820-1867) fue a California 
en 1846 como soldado en un regimiento de Nueva York durante la guerra 
mexicana. Allí, Buffum y su regimiento ayudaron a la California
ma's wrest de México. Después de que siguiera habiendo su 
descarga del ejército, Buffum filtrar el oro en el área alrededor de
las serrerías de Juan Sutter donde acababa de ser descubierto. 
Un periodista por la profesión, Buffum registró sus 
experiencias en un libro, seis meses en las minas de oro, de las 
cuales este extracto viene. Él comentó con maravilla que los 
hombres en las minas de oro de California ganaron cientos dólares por
día en promedio. Para entender cuál era una fortuna el, 
considere que las mujeres que trabajan como criados domésticos en 
ciudades del noreste en este tiempo ganado entre cuatro y siete 
dólares por mes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086759</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104153</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/present-at-the-beginning-of-the-gold-rush-journalist-edward-gould-buffum-pans-gold-in-california-1848</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
