<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105138</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105138</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Missed Manners: Wilson Lectures a Black Leader</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vermißte Weise: Wilson konferiert einen 
schwarzen Führer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Façons Manquées : Wilson parle une amorce 
noire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Maneiras Faltadas: Wilson lectures um líder
preto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modi Sig.na: Wilson parla un Capo 
nero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λειμμένοι τρόποι: Θ*Ωηλσον μιλά έναν μαύρο 
ηγέτη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Maneras Faltadas: Wilson da una conferencia 
a arranque de cinta negro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1912 Woodrow Wilson probably received more black votes than any previous Democratic presidential candidate, but his administration proved to be a bitter disappointment to African Americans. Black voters had abandoned William Howard Taft, Wilson's Republican predecessor, in part because he had appointed or retained a mere thirty-one black officeholders. But Wilson made only nine black appointments, and eight of these were Republican carryovers. Worse still, Wilson extended and defended segregation in the federal civil service. Black workers were forced to use inferior and segregated washrooms, and screens were set up to separate black and white workers in the same government offices. African Americans protested Wilson's policies. One of the most famous protest delegations was led in 1914 by Monroe Trotter, a Phi Beta Kappa graduate of Harvard and Boston newspaper editor. Wilson found Trotter's manner "insulting" and dismissed the delegation. The encounter made front-page news, and subsequent rallies protested Wilson's poor treatment of Trotter. But the segregation of the federal service continued.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1912 empfing Woodrow Wilson vermutlich schwärzere
Stimmen als jeder vorhergehende demokratische Präsidentenanwärter, 
aber seine Leitung, die eine bittere Enttäuschung zu den 
afrikanischen Amerikanern gewesen wurde. Schwarze Wähler hatten
William Howard Taft, Wilsons republikanischer Vorgänger, im Teil 
verlassen, weil er oder beibehaltenes bloße thirty-one schwarze 
Amtsträger ernannt hatte. Aber Wilson legte nur neun schwarze 
Zusammenkünfte fest, und acht von diesen waren republikanische 
Überträge. Falschere Stille, Wilson dehnte aus und verteidigte
Abtrennung im föderativstaatsdienst. Schwarze Arbeiter wurden 
erzwungen, die minderwertigen und getrennten Waschräume zu benutzen, 
und Bildschirme wurden bis zu den unterschiedlichen schwarzen und 
weißen Arbeitern in den gleichen Regierungsstellen eingestellt. 
Afrikanische Amerikaner protestierten politische Richtlinien 
Wilsons. Eine der berühmtesten Protestdelegationen wurde 1914 
durch Monroe Huf, ein Phi Betakappa Absolvent von Harvard und Boston 
Zeitungsverleger geführt. Wilson fand Weise des Hufes "zu 
beleidigen" und entließ die Delegation. Das Treffen, das 
front-page Nachrichten gebildet wurden, und die folgenden Sammlungen 
protestierten Wilsons schlechte Behandlung des Hufes. Aber die 
Abtrennung des Bundesservices fuhr fort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1912 Woodrow Wilson a probablement reçu des 
voix plus noires que n'importe quel candidat présidentiel 
démocratique précédent, mais sa gestion montrée être une 
déception amère aux Américains africains. Les électeurs 
noirs avaient abandonné William Howard Taft, le prédécesseur 
républicain de Wilson, en partie parce qu'il avait nommé ou maintenu
de seuls trente et un fonctionnaires noirs. Mais Wilson a pris 
seulement neuf rendez-vous noirs, et huit de ces derniers étaient des
transferts républicains. Un plus mauvais distillateur, Wilson a
étendu et a défendu la ségrégation dans la fonction publique 
fédérale. Des ouvriers noirs ont été forcés d'utiliser les 
salles de toilette inférieures et isolées, et des écrans ont été 
installés pour séparer les ouvriers noirs et blancs dans les mêmes 
bureaux de gouvernement. Les Américains africains ont protesté
les politiques de Wilson. Une des délégations de protestation 
les plus célèbres a été menée en 1914 par le trotteur de Monroe, 
un bêta diplômé de Kappa de phi éditeur de Harvard et de Boston de
journal. Wilson a trouvé la façon du trotteur "insulter" et a 
écarté la délégation. La rencontre faite les nouvelles en 
première page, et les rassemblements ultérieurs ont protesté le 
traitement faible de Wilson du trotteur. Mais la ségrégation 
du service fédéral a continué.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1912 Woodrow Wilson recebeu provavelmente uns 
votos mais pretos do que todo o candidato presidencial democrático 
precedente, mas uma sua administração provada ser um desapontamento 
amargo aos americanos africanos. Os eleitores pretos tinham 
abandonado William Howard Taft, predecessor republicano de Wilson, na 
parte porque tinha apontado ou retido meros trinta e uns officeholders
pretos. Mas Wilson fêz somente nove nomeações pretas, e oito 
destes eram extravasamentos republicanos. Um destilador mais 
mau, Wilson estendeu e defendeu o segregation no serviço civil 
federal. Os trabalhadores pretos foram forçados a usar 
washrooms inferior e segregados, e as telas foram ajustadas até 
trabalhadores pretos e brancos separados nos mesmos escritórios de 
governo. Os americanos africanos protestaram políticas de 
Wilson. Um dos delegations os mais famosos do protesto foi 
conduzido em 1914 pelo trotador de Monroe, um graduado beta de Kappa 
da phi editor de jornal de Harvard e de Boston. Wilson encontrou
a maneira do trotador "insultar" e demitiu o delegation. O 
encontro feito a notícia front-page, e os rallies subseqüentes 
protestaram o tratamento deficiente de Wilson do trotador. Mas o
segregation do serviço federal continuou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1912 Woodrow Wilson probabilmente ha ricevuto i
voti più neri che tutto il candidato presidenziale democratico 
precedente, ma la sua gestione dimostrata essere un disappunto amaro 
agli Americani africani. Gli elettori neri avevano abbandonato 
William Howard Taft, predecessore Repubblicano del Wilson, in parte 
perché aveva nominato o mantenuto trentuno officeholders nero puri. 
Ma Wilson ha fatto soltanto nove appuntamenti neri ed otto di 
questi erano residui Repubblicani. L'alambicco più difettoso, 
Wilson ha esteso e difeso la segregazione nell'amministrazione civile 
federale. Gli operai neri sono stati costretti ad usare le 
toilette inferiori e segregate e gli schermi sono stati installati per
separare gli operai neri e bianchi negli stessi servizi governativi. 
Gli Americani africani hanno protestato le politiche del Wilson.
Una delle delegazioni di protesta più famose è stata condotta 
in 1914 dal trotter de Monroe, un beta laureato di Kappa di phi 
editore di giornale de Boston e de Harvard. Wilson ha scoperto 
che il modo del trotter "insulta" e che ha allontanato la delegazione.
L'incontro reso a notizie del prima pagina ed i raduni successivi
hanno protestato il povero trattamento del Wilson del trotter. 
Ma la segregazione del servizio federale è continuato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1912 Woodrow Wilson έλαβε πιθανώς 
περισσότερες μαύρες ψηφοφορίες από οποιοδήποτε προηγούμενο 
δημοκρατικό προεδρικό υποψήφιο, αλλά η διοίκησή του αποδείχθηκε
μια πικρή απογοήτευση σε αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. Οι 
μαύροι ψηφοφόροι είχαν εγκαταλείψει William Howard Taft, 
δημοκρατικός προκάτοχος Wilson, εν μέρει επειδή είχε διορίσει
ή είχε διατηρήσει μόνους τριάντα έναν μαύρους υπαλλήλους. 
Αλλά Wilson έκανε μόνο εννέα μαύρους διορισμούς, και 
οκτώ από αυτούς ήταν δημοκρατικές μεταφορές. Χειρότερα 
ακόμα, Wilson επέκτεινε και υπεράσπισε το διαχωρισμό στην 
ομοσπονδιακή δημόσια υπηρεσία. Οι μαύροι εργαζόμενοι 
αναγκάστηκαν να χρησιμοποιήσουν κατώτερα και διαχωρισμένα 
washrooms, και οι οθόνες ιδρύθηκαν στους χωριστούς μαύρους και 
λευκούς εργαζομένους στα ίδια κυβερνητικά γραφεία. 
Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί διαμαρτυρήθηκαν τις πολιτικές 
Wilson. Μια από τις διασημότερες αντιπροσωπείες 
διαμαρτυρίας οδηγήθηκε το 1914 από το Μονρόε Trotter, έναν 
phi βήτα πτυχιούχο καπών του Χάρβαρντ και τον επεξεργαστή 
εφημερίδων της Βοστώνης. Θ*Ωηλσον βρήκε τον τρόπο Trotter
"" και απομάκρυνε την αντιπροσωπεία. Η σύγκρουση έκανε 
πρώτη σελίδα τις ειδήσεις, και οι επόμενες συναθροίσεις 
διαμαρτυρήθηκαν τη φτωχή επεξεργασία Wilson Trotter. 
Αλλά ο διαχωρισμός της ομοσπονδιακής υπηρεσίας συνεχίστηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1912 Woodrow Wilson recibió probablemente 
votos más negros que cualquier candidato presidencial democrático 
anterior, pero su administración demostrada ser una decepción amarga
a los americanos africanos. Los votantes negros habían 
abandonado Guillermo Howard Taft, precursor republicano de Wilson, en 
parte porque él había designado o conservado los treinta y uno 
officeholders negros meros. Pero Wilson concertó solamente 
nueve citas negras, y ocho de éstos eran adherencias al cilindro 
republicanas. El alambique peor, Wilson amplió y defendió la 
segregación en la función pública federal. Forzaron a los 
trabajadores negros utilizar servicios inferiores y segregados, y las 
pantallas fueron fijadas hasta trabajadores negros y blancos separados
en las mismas oficinas gubernamentales. Los americanos africanos
protestaron las políticas de Wilson. El trotón de Monroe 
condujo una de las delegaciones más famosas de la protesta en 1914, 
graduado beta de Kappa de la phi redactor de Harvard y de Boston. 
Wilson encontró la manera del trotón el "insultar" y despidió
a delegación. El encuentro hecho las noticias de la portado,
y las reuniones subsecuentes protestaron el tratamiento pobre de 
Wilson del trotón. Pero la segregación del servicio federal 
continuó.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105138</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/missed-manners-wilson-lectures-a-black-leader</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
