<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103299</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103299</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Call On You to Deliver Us From the Tyrant's Chain": Lowell Women Workers Campaign for a Ten Hour Workday</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir ersuchen um Sie, uns von der Kette des 
Tyrants zu liefern": Lowell Frau-Arbeiter werben während eines 
10 Stunde Arbeitstags</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous vous invitons à nous livrer de la chaîne 
des Tyrans" : Les ouvrières de femmes de Lowell font 
campagne pendant un jour ouvrable de Dix heures</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós convidamo-lo entregar-nos da corrente do 
Tyrant": Os trabalhadores das mulheres de Lowell fazem campanha 
por um workday de dez horas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"li invitiamo trasportarli dalla catena del 
Tyrant": Gli operai delle donne de Lowell fanno una campagna per
un workday di dieci ore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σας καλούμε για να μας παραδώσουμε από την αλυσίδα 
του τύραννου": Οι εργαζόμενοι γυναικών του Lowell κάνουν 
εκστρατεία για μια εργάσιμη ημέρα δέκα ώρας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"le invitamos a entregarnos del encadenamiento del
Tyrant": Los trabajadores de las mujeres de Lowell hacen 
campaña por un día laborable de diez horas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The burgeoning textile mills in Lowell, Massachusetts, brought increasing competition among the owners and declining conditions for the workers. In the 1830s the women working in the mills turned to economic protests and collective action; their "turn outs" or strikes proved unsuccessful in combating the wage cuts. In the 1840s mill workers turned to political organization as they mounted annual petition campaigns calling on the state legislature to limit the hours of labor within the mills. These campaigns reached their height in 1845 and 1846, when 2,000 and 5,000 operatives respectively signed petitions. to reduce the hours of labor in the mills. Women operatives organized the Lowell Female Labor Reform Association in 1845. An important part of the campaign was their periodical  The Voice of Industry . Another publication,  Factory Tracts , was part of their effort to expose conditions in the mills and advocate a ten hour day. Male mechanics and other workers in industrial communities joined the Lowell women operatives' campaign.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die sprießenden Textiltausendstel in Lowell, 
Massachusetts, zunehmenden Wettbewerb unter den Inhabern und dem 
Sinken geholt bedingt für die Arbeiter. Im 1830s die Frauen, 
die in den Tausendsteln gedreht zu den ökonomischen Protesten und zur
Kollektivtätigkeit arbeiten; ihr "Umdrehung Heraus" oder 
Schläge prüften erfolgloses, wenn sie die Lohnschnitte bekämpften. 
Im Tausendstel 1840s wendeten die Arbeiter an politische 
Organisation, während sie jährliche Petition Kampagnen um die 
Zustandgesetzgebung ersuchend, die Arbeitsstunden innerhalb der 
Tausendstel zu begrenzen einhingen. Diese Kampagnen erreichten 
ihre Höhe 1845 und 1846, als 2.000 und 5.000 Arbeiter beziehungsweise
Petitionen unterzeichneten. die Arbeitsstunden in den 
Tausendsteln verringern. Frauarbeiter organisierten die Lowell 
Frau-Arbeit Verbesserung-Verbindung 1845. Ein wichtiges Teil der
Kampagne war ihre Zeitschrift die Stimme der Industrie. Eine 
andere Publikation, Fabrik-Flächen, war ein Teil ihrer Bemühung, 
Bedingungen in den Tausendsteln herauszustellen und einen 10 Stunde 
Tag zu befürworten. Männliche Mechaniker und andere Arbeiter 
in den industriellen Gemeinschaften verbanden die Kampagne der Lowell 
Frau-Arbeiter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les moulins bourgeonnants de textile à Lowell, le
Massachusetts, apporté la concurrence croissante parmi les 
propriétaires et la réduction conditionne pour les ouvriers. 
Dans le 1830s les femmes travaillant dans les moulins tournés 
aux protestations économiques et à l'action collective ; leurs
"sorties de tour" ou grèves ont prouvé non réussi en combattant les
réductions de salaire. Dans le moulin 1840s les ouvriers se 
sont tournés vers l'organisation politique pendant qu'ils 
organisaient des campagnes annuelles de pétition invitant la 
législature d'état à limiter les heures du travail dans les 
moulins. Ces campagnes ont atteint leur taille en 1845 et 1846, 
quand 2.000 et 5.000 employés ont respectivement signé des 
pétitions. pour réduire les heures du travail dans les 
moulins. Les employés de femmes ont organisé l'association de 
réforme de travail de femelle de Lowell en 1845. Une partie 
importante de la campagne était leur périodique la voix de 
l'industrie. Une autre publication, régions d'usine, faisait 
partie de leur effort d'exposer des conditions dans les moulins et de 
préconiser un jour de dix heures. La mécanique mâle et 
d'autres ouvriers dans les communautés industrielles ont joint la 
campagne des employés de femmes de Lowell.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os moinhos burgeoning de textile em Lowell, 
Massachusetts, trazido a competição de aumento entre os 
proprietários e declinar condicionam para os trabalhadores. No 
1830s as mulheres que trabalham nos moinhos girados para protestos 
econômicos e a ação coletiva; suas da "saídas volta" ou as 
batidas provaram mal sucedido em combater os cortes de salário. 
No moinho 1840s os trabalhadores giraram para a organização 
política enquanto montaram campanhas anuais da petição que convidam
a legislatura de estado limitar as horas de trabalho dentro dos 
moinhos. Estas campanhas alcançaram sua altura em 1845 e em 
1846, quando 2.000 e 5.000 operatives assinaram respectivamente 
petições. para reduzir as horas de trabalho nos moinhos. 
Os operatives das mulheres organizaram a associação da reforma
do trabalho da fêmea de Lowell em 1845. Uma parte importante da
campanha era seu periodical a voz da indústria. Uma outra 
publicação, intervalos da fábrica, era parte de seu esforço expo 
condições nos moinhos e advogar um dia de dez horas. Os 
mecânicos masculinos e outros trabalhadores em comunidades 
industriais juntaram a campanha dos operatives' das mulheres de 
Lowell.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I laminatoi burgeoning della tessile a Lowell, 
Massachusetts, portato declinare ed i proprietari fra la concorrenza 
aumentare condiziona per gli operai. Nel 1830s le donne che 
lavorano nei laminatoi si sono girate verso le proteste economiche e 
l'azione collettiva; i loro "outs di girata" o i colpi hanno 
dimostrato infruttuoso nel combattimento dei tagli di stipendio. 
In laminatoio 1840s gli operai si sono girati verso 
l'organizzazione politica mentre hanno organizzato le campagne annuali
di petizione che invitano la legislatura di dichiarare limitare le ore
del lavoro all'interno dei laminatoi. Queste campagne hanno
raggiunto la loro altezza in 1845 ed in 1846, quando 2.000 e 5.000 
operatori hanno firmato rispettivamente le petizioni. per 
ridurre le ore del lavoro nei laminatoi. Gli operatori 
delle donne hanno organizzato l'associazione Di lavoro femminile di 
riforma de Lowell in 1845. Una parte importante della campagna 
era il loro periodico la voce di industria. Un'altra 
pubblicazione, tratti della fabbrica, faceva parte del loro sforzo 
esporre i termini nei laminatoi e sostenere un giorno di dieci ore. 
I meccanici maschii ed altri operai nelle Comunità industriali 
hanno unito la campagna de Lowell degli operatori delle donne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι να φυτρώσει υφαντικοί μύλοι στο Lowell, τη 
Μασαχουσέτη, που παρουσιάζεται τον αυξανόμενο ανταγωνισμό μεταξύ 
των ιδιοκτητών και τους μειωμένος όρους για τους εργαζομένους. 
Στο 1830s οι γυναίκες που εργάζονται στους μύλους που 
γυρίζουν στις οικονομικές διαμαρτυρίες και τη συλλογική ενέργεια 
"η στροφή τους outs" ή οι απεργίες αποδείχθηκε 
ανεπιτυχής στην καταπολέμηση των αποκοπών αμοιβών. Στο μύλο
1840s οι εργαζόμενοι γύρισαν στην πολιτική οργάνωση καθώς 
επικόλλησαν τις ετήσιες εκστρατείες αίτησης καλώντας το κρατικό 
νομοθετικό σώμα για να περιορίσουν τις ώρες της εργασίας μέσα 
στους μύλους. Αυτές οι εκστρατείες έφθασαν στο ύψος τους το
1845 και το 1846, όταν υπέγραψαν αντίστοιχα 2.000 και 
5.000 χειριστές τις αιτήσεις. για να μειώσουν τις ώρες 
της εργασίας στους μύλους. Οι χειριστές γυναικών οργάνωσαν 
τη θηλυκή ένωση μεταρρύθμισης εργασίας του Lowell το 1845. 
Ένα σημαντικό μέρος της εκστρατείας ήταν το περιοδικό τους
η φωνή της βιομηχανίας. Μια άλλη δημοσίευση, κομμάτια 
εργοστασίων, ήταν μέρος της προσπάθειάς τους να εκθέσουν τους 
όρους στους μύλους και να υποστηρίξουν ημερησίως δέκα ώρας. 
Οι μηχανικοί αρσενικών και άλλοι εργαζόμενοι στις 
βιομηχανικές κοινότητες ένωσαν την εκστρατεία των χειριστών 
γυναικών του Lowell.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los molinos burgeoning del textil en Lowell, 
Massachusetts, traído la creciente competencia entre los propietarios
y declinar condicionan para los trabajadores. En el 1830s las 
mujeres que trabajan en los molinos dados vuelta a las protestas 
económicas y a la acción colectiva; sus "salidas de la vuelta"
o las huelgas probaron fracasado en combatir los cortes de salario. 
En el molino 1840s los trabajadores dieron vuelta a la 
organización política mientras que montaron campañas anuales de la 
petición que invitaban a la legislatura de estado a limitar las horas
del trabajo dentro de los molinos. Estas campañas alcanzaron su
altura en 1845 y 1846, cuando 2.000 y 5.000 operarios firmaron 
respectivamente peticiones. para reducir las horas del trabajo 
en los molinos. Los operarios de las mujeres ordenaron la 
asociación de la reforma del trabajo de la hembra de Lowell en 1845. 
Una parte importante de la campaña era su periódico la voz de 
la industria. Otra publicación, zonas de la fábrica, era parte
de su esfuerzo de exponer condiciones en los molinos y de abogar un 
día de diez horas. Los mecánicos masculinos y otros 
trabajadores en comunidades industriales ensamblaron la campaña de 
Lowell de los operarios de las mujeres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103299</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-call-on-you-to-deliver-us-from-the-tyrants-chain-lowell-women-workers-campaign-for-a-ten-hour-workday</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
