<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086857</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Strange cargo.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkwürdige Ladung.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cargaison étrange.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Carga estranha.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Carico sconosciuto.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παράξενο φορτίο.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cargo extraño.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">To supply labor for the plantation economies of the Americas, Europeans forcibly removed roughly 12 million people from Africa between the 15th and the 19th centuries. These men, women, and children were marched from their homes to the coast and placed on "slavers" like the one pictured in this diagram from an 1808 report on the African slave trade. Designed to carry the largest number of people in the smallest possible space, these ships provided an indescribably horrible experience for the humans chained below decks. Roughly one in six slaves died at sea from disease, malnutrition, and suicide.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Um Arbeit für die Plantagewirtschaftssysteme des Amerikas
anzugeben, löschten Europäer gewaltsam ungefähr 12 Million Leute 
von Afrika zwischen das 15. und die 19. Jahrhunderte. Diese 
Männer, Frauen und Kinder wurden von ihren Häusern zur Küste 
gegrenzt und gelegt auf "slavers" wie das dargestellt worden in dieses
Diagramm von einem Bericht 1808 über den afrikanischen Sklave Handel.
Konzipierte, die größte Zahl Leuten im kleinsten möglichen 
Platz zu tragen, diese Schiffe zur Verfügung stellte eine 
unbeschreibbar schreckliche Erfahrung für die Menschen, die unter 
Plattformen angekettet wurden. Ungefähr ein in sechs Sklaven 
starb am Meer von der Krankheit, von der Unterernährung und vom 
Selbstmord.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour assurer le travail pour les économies de plantation 
des Amériques, Européens ont de force retiré approximativement 12 
millions de personnes de l'Afrique entre le 15ème et les 19èmes 
siècles. Ces hommes, femmes, et enfants ont été marchés de 
leurs maisons à la côte et placés sur des "slavers" comme celui 
décrites dans ce diagramme d'un état 1808 sur le commerce slave
africain. A conçu pour porter le plus grand nombre de personnes
dans le plus petit possible espace, ces bateaux a fourni une 
expérience indescriptible horrible pour les humains enchaînés 
au-dessous des paquets. Approximativement un dans six esclaves 
est mort en mer de la maladie, de malnutrition, et de suicide.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para fornecer o trabalho para as economias da plantação 
dos Americas, Europeus removeram forçosamente aproximadamente 12 
milhão povos de África entre o 1ö e os 1øs séculos. Estes 
homens, mulheres, e crianças foram marchados de suas HOME à costa e 
colocados em "slavers" como esse retratadas neste diagrama de um 
relatório 1808 no comércio africano do escravo. Projetou 
carregar o número o maior dos povos no espaço possível o menor, 
estes navios forneceu uma experiência indescribably horrible para os 
seres humanos acorrentados abaixo das plataformas. 
Aproximadamente um em seis escravos morreu no mar da doença, do
malnutrition, e do suicide.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per fornire il lavoro per le economie della 
piantagione dei Americas, Europei hanno rimosso con forza 
approssimativamente 12 milione di persone dall'Africa fra il 
quindicesimo ed i diciannovesimi secoli. Questi uomini, donne e 
bambini sono stati marciati dalle loro sedi al litorale e sono stati 
disposti "sugli slavers" come quello descritte in questo schema da un 
rapporto 1808 sul commercio africano dello schiavo. Ha 
progettato trasportare il più grande numero di gente nel più piccolo
spazio possibile, queste navi ha fornito un'esperienza indescribably 
horrible per gli esseri umani concatenati sotto le piattaforme. 
Approssimativamente uno in sei schiavi è morto in mare dalla 
malattia, dalla malnutrizione e dal suicide.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για να παρέχουν την εργασία για τις οικονομίες φυτειών
της Αμερικής, οι Ευρωπαίοι απομάκρυναν βίαια κατά προσέγγιση 
12 εκατομμύριο ανθρώπους από την Αφρική μεταξύ του 15$ου και 
τους 19$ους αιώνες. Αυτοί οι άνδρες, γυναίκες, και παιδιά 
βαδίστηκαν από τα σπίτια τους στην ακτή και τοποθετήθηκαν "στα 
slavers" όπως αυτό που απεικονίστηκε σε αυτό το διάγραμμα από
μια έκθεση 1808 σχετικά με το αφρικανικό εμπόριο σκλάβων. 
Σχεδιασμένα για να φέρουν το μεγαλύτερο αριθμό ανθρώπων στο
μικρότερο πιθανό διάστημα, αυτά τα πλοία παρείχαν μια 
απερίγραπτα φρικτή εμπειρία για τους ανθρώπους που αλυσοδέθηκαν 
κάτω από τα καταστρώματα. Κατά προσέγγιση το ένα σε έξι 
σκλάβους πέθανε εν πλω από την ασθένεια, τον υποσιτισμό, και την 
αυτοκτονία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para proveer el trabajo para las economías de la 
plantación de las Américas, europeos quitaron fuertemente a áspero 
12 millones de personas de de África entre el décimo quinto y los 
diecinueveavo siglos. Marcharon de sus hogares a la costa y 
fueron colocados a estos hombres, mujeres, y niños en "slavers" como 
el representados en este diagrama de un informe 1808 sobre el comercio
africano del esclavo. Diseñó llevar el número más grande de 
la gente en el espacio posible más pequeño, estas naves proporcionó
a una experiencia indescriptiblemente horrible para los seres humanos 
encadenados debajo de cubiertas. Áspero uno en seis esclavos 
murió en el mar de la enfermedad, de la desnutrición, y del 
suicidio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086857</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107872</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/strange-cargo</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
