<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104054</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104054</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086847</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Stalking the Stork": An Expose of Espionage in the Baby Clothes Industry</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", den Storch anpirschend": Ein Exposé von 
Spionage im Baby kleidet Industrie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"égrappant la cigogne" : Une exposition de 
l'espionnage dans le bébé vêtx l'industrie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"stalking a cegonha": Uma exposição do 
espionage no bebê veste a indústria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"inseguendo la cicogna": Una denunzia di 
spionaggio nel bambino copre l'industria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Καταδιώκοντας τον πελαργό": Μια έκθεση της 
κατασκοπείας στο μωρό ντύνει τη βιομηχανία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"acechando la cigüeña": Una exposición 
del espionaje en el bebé arropa industria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In addition to providing the public with an abundance of affordable consumer goods during the 20th century, the service sector of corporate America also began to invade and interfere with the private lives of many of its customers. Not content to advertise in print, radio, and television outlets, corporations and their investigative subsidiaries collected information in order to more efficiently target their products to interested buyers. (With the advent of the Internet, corporate consumer information gathering has grown even more sophisticated.) Just how much of an annoyance this could be to the average consumer was documented in the following article about maternity and baby products in the 1950s, the peak years of the "baby boom." During this period, the nation's birthrate rose substantially as economic security became more widespread and Americans on average got married earlier and had healthier children than before. The report described how friends, neighbors, delivery personnel, and laboratory technicians were all suspected of selling the names, addresses, and other vital statistics of prospective parents of "boomers" to marketers. By including men as advertising targets along with women, the author acknowledged a changing role for fathers in the "modern" family.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zusätzlich zum Versehen der Öffentlichkeit mit 
einem Überfluß an den erschwinglichen Verbrauchsgütern während des
20. Jahrhunderts, fing der Dienstleistungssektor von korporativem 
Amerika auch an, die privaten Leben von vielen seiner Kunden 
einzudringen und zu behinderen. Der nicht Inhalt, zum im Druck, 
Radio und Fernsehenanschlüsse, Korporationen und ihre 
Untersuchungstochtergesellschaften bekanntzumachen sammelte 
Informationen, um ihre Produkte zu interessierten Kunden 
leistungsfähiger zu zielen. (mit dem Aufkommen des Internets, 
ist korporative Verbraucherinformationen Versammlung. sogar hoch 
entwickelter gewachsen) Gerade wieviel einer Störung dieses zum
durchschnittlichen Verbraucher sein könnte, wurde dokumentiert im 
folgenden Artikel über Mutterschaft und in den Babyprodukten in den 
fünfziger Jahren, die Höchstjahre des "Babybooms." Während 
dieser Periode stieg die Geburtenrate der Nation im wesentlichen, 
während wirtschaftliche Sicherheit weitverbreiteter wurde und 
Amerikaner auf Durchschnitt früh heirieten und gesuendere Kinder als 
vorher hatten. Der Report beschrieb, wie Freunde, Nachbarn, 
Anlieferung Personal und Laboralle techniker vom Verkaufen der Namen, 
der Adressen und anderer lebenswichtiger Statistiken der zukünftigen 
Eltern von "boomers" zu den Marketingspezialisten vermutet wurden. 
Indem er Männer als Bekanntmachen der Ziele zusammen mit Frauen
enthielt, bestätigte der Autor eine ändernde Rolle für Väter in 
der "modernen" Familie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En plus de fournir au public une abondance de 
biens de consommation accessibles pendant le 20ème siècle, le 
secteur de service de l'Amérique de corporation a également 
commencé à envahir et gêner les vies privées de plusieurs de ses 
clients. Pas le contenu à annoncer dans la copie, la radio, et 
les sorties de télévision, les sociétés et leurs filiales 
investigatrices a rassemblé l'information afin de viser plus 
efficacement leurs produits aux acheteurs intéressés. (avec 
l'arrivée de l'Internet, le rassemblement de corporation de 
l'information du consommateur s'est développé bien plus 
sophistiqué.) Juste quelle quantité d'ennui ceci pourrait 
être au consommateur moyen a été documenté dans l'article suivant 
concernant la maternité et des produits de bébé dans les années 
50, les années record du "baby boom." Pendant cette période, 
le taux de naissance de la nation a monté sensiblement pendant que la
sécurité devenait plus répandue et les Américains en moyenne se 
mariaient  plus tôt et avaient des enfants plus sains qu'avant. 
L'état a décrit comment on a suspecté des amis, les voisins, 
le personnel de la livraison, et les techniciens de laboratoire tous 
de vendre les noms, des adresses, et d'autres statistiques 
essentielles des parents éventuels des "boomers" aux acheteurs. 
En incluant des hommes en tant que publicité des cibles avec 
des femmes, l'auteur a reconnu un rôle changeant pour des pères dans
la famille "moderne".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Além a fornecer o público com uma abundância de
bens de consumidor affordable durante o 20o século, o setor de 
serviço de América incorporada começou também a invadir e 
interferir com as vidas confidenciais de muitos de seus clientes. 
Não o índice a anunciar na cópia, o rádio, e as tomadas da 
televisão, os corporation e suas subsidiárias investigative coletou 
a informação a fim alvejar mais eficientemente seus produtos aos 
compradores interessados. (com o advent do Internet, o 
recolhimento incorporado da informação do consumidor cresceu mesmo 
mais sofisticado.) Apenas quanto de um annoyance este poderia 
ser ao consumidor médio foi documentado no seguinte artigo sobre a 
maternidade e em produtos do bebê nos 1950s, os anos peak de "do 
crescimento bebê." Durante este período, o birthrate da 
nação levantou-se substancialmente enquanto a segurança econômica 
se tornou mais difundida e os americanos na média começaram casados 
mais cedo e tiveram umas crianças mais saudáveis do que antes. 
O relatório descreveu como os amigos, os vizinhos, o pessoal da
entrega, e os técnicos de laboratório todos foram suspeitados de 
vender os nomes, endereços, e outros statistics vitais de pais em 
perspectiva de "boomers" aos comerciantes. Incluindo homens como
anunciar alvos junto com mulheres, o autor reconheceu um papel em 
mudança para pais na família "moderna".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Oltre che fornire al pubblico un'abbondanza delle 
merci di consumatore acquistabili durante il ventesimo secolo, il 
settore dei servizi dell'America corporativa egualmente ha cominciato 
ad invadere ed interferire con le vite riservate di molti dei relativi
clienti. Non il soddisfare da fare pubblicità a in stampa, 
radio e prese della televisione, società e le loro filiali 
investigative ha raccolto le informazioni per designare più 
efficientemente i loro prodotti come bersaglio ai compratori 
interessati. (con l'avvenimento del Internet, la riunione 
corporativa delle informazioni del consumatore si è sviluppata ancor 
più specializzata.) Appena quanto di un disturbo questo 
potrebbe essere al consumatore medio è stato documentato nel seguente
articolo su maternità e nei prodotti del bambino negli anni 50, gli 
anni peak "del"baby boom"." Durante questo periodo, il birthrate
della nazione è aumentato sostanzialmente mentre la sicurezza 
economica è diventato più diffusa e gli Americani in media hanno 
ottenuto sposati più presto ed hanno avuti bambini più sani che 
prima. Il rapporto ha descritto come gli amici, i vicinoi, i 
personali di consegna ed i tecnici di laboratorio tutti sono stati 
ritenuti sospetto di vendere i nomi, gli indirizzi ed altre 
statistiche vitali di futuri genitori "dei boomers" ai marketers. 
Includendo gli uomini come pubblicità degli obiettivi con le 
donne, l'autore ha riconosciuto un ruolo cambiante per i padri nella 
famiglia "moderna".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκτός από την παροχή του κοινού μια αφθονία προσιτών
καταναλωτικών αγαθών κατά τη διάρκεια του 20ού αιώνα, ο τομέας 
των υπηρεσιών της εταιρικής Αμερικής άρχισε επίσης να εισβάλλει 
και να παρεμποδίζει τις ιδιωτικές ζωές πολλοί από τους πελάτες 
του. Όχι ικανοποιήστε για να διαφημίσετε στην τυπωμένη ύλη,
το ραδιόφωνο, και τις τηλεοπτικές εξόδους, τις εταιρίες και τις 
εξεταστικές συλλεχθείσες υποκαταστήματα πληροφορίες τους 
προκειμένου να στοχευθούν αποτελεσματικότερα τα προϊόντα τους 
στους ενδιαφερόμενους αγοραστές. (Με την εμφάνιση του 
Διαδικτύου, η εταιρική συλλογή καταναλωτικών πληροφοριών έχει 
γίνει ακόμα περιπλοκότερη.) Ακριβώς πόσο μιας ενόχλησης 
που αυτό θα μπορούσε να είναι στο μέσο καταναλωτή τεκμηριώθηκε 
στο ακόλουθο άρθρο για τα προϊόντα μητρότητας και μωρών στη 
δεκαετία του '50, τα μέγιστα έτη του "βραχίονα μωρών." 
Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της περιόδου, ο ρυθμός γεννήσεων 
του έθνους αυξήθηκε ουσιαστικά καθώς η οικονομική ασφάλεια 
έγινε πιό διαδεδομένη και Αμερικανοί παντρεύτηκαν κατά μέσον 
όρο νωρίτερα και είχαν τα υγιέστερα παιδιά από πριν. Η 
έκθεση περιέγραψε πώς οι φίλοι, οι γείτονες, το προσωπικό 
παράδοσης, και οι εργαστηριακοί τεχνικοί όλοι υποψιάστηκαν της 
πώλησης των ονομάτων, των διευθύνσεων, και άλλων ζωτικής 
σημασίας στατιστικών των ενδεχόμενων γονέων "των boomers" στους
εμπόρους. Με τη συμπερίληψη των ανδρών ως διαφημίσεις των 
στόχων μαζί με τις γυναίκες, ο συντάκτης αναγνώρισε έναν 
μεταβαλλόμενο ρόλο για τους πατέρες στη "σύγχρονη" οικογένεια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Además de proveer del público una abundancia de 
bienes de consumo comprables durante el vigésimo siglo, el sector de 
servicio de América corporativa también comenzó a invadir y a 
interferir con las vidas privadas de muchos de sus clientes. No 
el contenido a anunciar en la impresión, radio, y los enchufes de la 
televisión, las corporaciones y sus subsidiarios investigadores 
recogió la información para apuntar más eficientemente sus 
productos a los compradores interesados. (con el advenimiento 
del Internet, la reunión corporativa de la información del 
consumidor ha crecido aún más sofisticada.) Apenas cuánto de 
una molestia éste podría ser al consumidor medio fue documentado en 
el artículo siguiente acerca de la maternidad y productos del bebé 
en los años 50, los años máximos del "baby boom." Durante 
este período, el índice de natalidad de la nación se levantó 
substancialmente mientras que la seguridad económica llegó a ser 
más extensa y los americanos en promedio consiguieron casados 
anterior y tenían niños más sanos que antes. El informe 
describió cómo sospecharon a los amigos, a los vecinos, al personal 
de la salida, y a los técnicos de laboratorio todos de vender los 
nombres, los direccionamientos, y la otra estadística vital de padres
anticipados de "boomers" a los vendedores. Incluyendo a hombres 
como publicidad de blancos junto con mujeres, el autor reconoció un 
papel que cambiaba de padres en la familia "moderna".</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086847</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104054</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/stalking-the-stork-an-expose-of-espionage-in-the-baby-clothes-industry</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
