<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105876</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105876</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211916</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Research Outdoorsmanship Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Forschung Outdoorsmanship Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Homepage d'Outdoorsmanship de Recherches</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Homepage De Outdoorsmanship Da Pesquisa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Homepage Di Outdoorsmanship Di Ricerca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχική σελίδα ερευνητικού Outdoorsmanship</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Homepage De Outdoorsmanship De la Investigación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website provides information about field trips. The site was written specifically for those participating is field research but information applies to wilderness camping and classroom field trips. The site 'aims to pass on some knowledge and skills necessary for the practice of safe field research by focusing on outdoorsmanship as it relates to outdoor research.'</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site liefert Informationen 
auffangen ungefähr Reisen. Die Site wurde spezifisch 
für teilnehmende die ist auffangen Forschung geschrieben, 
aber Informationen treffen auf die kampierende Wildnis zu und 
Klassenzimmer fangen Reisen auf. Die Site ' die Ziele, 
zum etwas Wissens weiterzuleiten und die Fähigkeiten, die für die 
Praxis des Safes notwendig sind, fangen Forschung auf, indem 
sie auf outdoorsmanship konzentrieren, wie es in Verbindung steht auf 
im Freienforschung.'</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web fournit des informations au sujet des 
voyages de zone. Le site a été écrit spécifiquement pour 
ceux participant est recherche de zone mais l'information s'applique 
aux voyages de zone de camper et de salle de classe de désert. 
Le site 'objectifs pour transmettre la quelques connaissance et 
qualifications nécessaires pour la pratique de la recherche de zone 
sûre en se concentrant sur l'outdoorsmanship comme il associe à la 
recherche extérieure.'</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site fornece a informação sobre 
desengates de campo. O local foi escrito especificamente para 
aqueles que participam é pesquisa de campo mas a informação 
aplica-se aos desengates de campo acampar e de sala de aula da região
selvagem. O local ' alvos para passar sobre alguns conhecimento 
e habilidades necessários para a prática da pesquisa de campo segura
focalizando no outdoorsmanship como se relaciona à pesquisa ao ar 
livre.'</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site fornisce le informazioni sui 
viaggi di campo. Il luogo è stato scritto specificamente per 
quelli che partecipano è indagine in loco ma le informazioni si 
applicano ai viaggi di campo di campeggio e dell'aula della selva. 
Il luogo 'obiettivi per passare sopra alcune conoscenza ed 
abilità necessarie per la pratica di indagine in loco sicuro mettendo
a fuoco sul outdoorsmanship come si riferisce a ricerca esterna.'</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για τα 
ταξίδια πεδίων. Η περιοχή γράφτηκε συγκεκριμένα για 
εκείνους που συμμετέχουν είναι έρευνα πεδίων αλλά οι 
πληροφορίες ισχύουν για τα ταξίδια πεδίων στρατοπέδευσης και 
τάξεων αγριοτήτων. Η περιοχή "στοχεύει να δώσει μερικές 
γνώση και δεξιότητες απαραίτητες για την πρακτική της ασφαλούς 
έρευνας πεδίων με την εστίαση στο outdoorsmanship όπως αφορά 
την υπαίθρια έρευνα."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site proporciona a la información sobre 
disparos al campo. El sitio fue escrito específicamente para 
ésos que participaban es investigación de campo pero la información
se aplica a los disparos al campo el acampar y de la sala de clase del
yermo. El sitio ' punterías para pasar encendido algún 
conocimiento y habilidades necesarios para la práctica de la 
investigación de campo segura centrándose en outdoorsmanship como se
relaciona con la investigación al aire libre.'</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REUBEN JOHNSON
FN:REUBEN JOHNSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211916</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105876</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/research-outdoorsmanship-homepage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
