<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107610</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107610</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087055</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Starving Time": John Smith Recounts the Early History of Jamestown, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Verhungernde Zeit": John Smith zählt 
die Frühgeschichte von Jamestown, 1609 nach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Temps Affamé" : John Smith raconte 
l'histoire des débuts de Jamestown, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Tempo Starving": John Smith recounts o 
history adiantado de Jamestown, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Tempo Affamato": John Smith racconta la 
storia remota di Jamestown, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο να λιμοκτονήσει χρόνοσ": Θ*Ιοχν Smith 
Recounts η πρόωρη ιστορία Jamestown, 1609</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Tiempo Muerto de hambre": Juan Smith 
contó de nuevo la historia temprana de Jamestown, 1609</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The organizers of the first English settlement at Jamestown, Virginia, in 1607 had visions of easy wealth and abundant plunder. The colonists, a group with little agricultural experience and weighted with gentry, instead found a swampy and disease-ridden site. The local Indians were unwilling to labor for them. Few survived the first difficult winters. Captain John Smith had been a soldier, explorer, and adventurer. With the colony in near chaos, he took over the government of the colony in 1608 and instituted a policy of rigid discipline and agricultural cultivation. When a gunpowder accident forced his return to England in 1608, the colonists faced a disastrous winter known as "starving time."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Organisatoren der ersten englischen Regelung 
bei Jamestown, Virginia, in 1607 hatten Anblicke der einfachen Fülle 
und der reichlich vorhandenen Plünderung. Die Kolonisten, eine 
Gruppe mit wenig landwirtschaftlicher Erfahrung und belastet mit 
niederen Adeln, swampy und Krankheit-gerittene stattdessen gefunden 
eine Site. Die lokalen Inder waren abgeneigt, für sie zu 
bearbeiten. Wenige überlebten die ersten schwierigen Winter. 
Kapitän John Smith war ein Soldat, ein Forscher und ein 
Abenteurer gewesen. Mit der Kolonie im nahen Chaos, übernahm er
die Regierung der Kolonie 1608 und leitete eine Politik der steifen 
Disziplin und der landwirtschaftlichen Bearbeitung ein. Als ein 
Schießpulverunfall seine Rückkehr nach England 1608 erzwang, 
stellten die Kolonisten einen verhängnisvollen Winter gegenüber, der
bekannt ist als "verhungernde Zeit."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les organisateurs du premier règlement anglais 
chez Jamestown, le Virginie, dans 1607 ont eu des visions de la 
richesse facile et du pillage abondant. Les colons, un groupe 
avec peu d'expérience agricole et pesés avec le gens de la haute 
société, au lieu de cela trouvés un site marécageux et 
maladie-monté. Les Indiens locaux étaient peu disposés à 
travailler pour eux. Peu ont survécu les premiers hivers 
difficiles. Capitaine John Smith avait été un soldat, un 
explorateur, et un aventurier. Avec la colonie dans le chaos 
proche, il a assuré le gouvernement de la colonie en 1608 et a 
institué une politique de discipline rigide et de culture agricole. 
Quand un accident de poudre a forcé son retour vers 
l'Angleterre en 1608, les colons ont fait face à un hiver désastreux
connu sous le nom de "temps affamé."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os organizers do primeiro estabelecimento inglês 
em Jamestown, Virgínia, em 1607 tiveram visões da riqueza fácil e 
da pilhagem abundante. Os colonos, um grupo com pouca 
experiência agricultural e tornados mais pesados com gentry, instead 
encontrados um local swampy e doença-montado. Os indians locais
eram unwilling trabalhar para eles. Poucos sobreviveram os 
primeiros invernos difíceis. O capitão John Smith tinha sido 
um soldado, um explorador, e um adventurer. Com a colônia no 
caos próximo, fêz exame sobre do governo da colônia em 1608 e 
instituiu uma política da disciplina rígida e do cultivation 
agricultural. Quando um acidente do gunpowder forçou seu 
retorno a Inglaterra em 1608, os colonos enfrentaram um inverno 
desastroso sabido como "tempo starving."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli organizzatori del primo stabilimento inglese a
Jamestown, la Virginia, in 1607 hanno avuti visioni di ricchezza 
facile e di plunder abbondante. I colonizzatori, un gruppo con 
poca esperienza agricola ed appesantiti con il gentry, invece trovati 
un luogo swampy e malattia-guidato. Gli indiani locali erano 
poco disposti al lavoro per loro. Pochi sono sopravvissuto 
i primi inverni difficili. Il capitano John Smith era stato un 
soldato, un esploratore e un adventurer. Con la colonia nel caos
vicino, ha assunto la direzione del governo della colonia in 1608 ed 
ha istituito una politica di disciplina rigida e di coltura agricola. 
Quando un incidente della polvere nera ha forzato il suo ritorno
in Inghilterra in 1608, i colonizzatori hanno affrontato un inverno 
disastroso conosciuto come "il tempo affamato."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι διοργανωτές της πρώτης αγγλικής τακτοποίησης σε 
Jamestown, Βιρτζίνια, το 1607 είχαν τα οράματα του εύκολου 
πλούτου και άφθονος να λεηλατήσουν. Οι άποικοι, μια ομάδα 
με λίγη γεωργική εμπειρία και ζυγισμένος με την ανώτερη τάξη, 
βρήκαν αντ' αυτού μια βαλτώδη και ασθένεια-οδηγημένη περιοχή. 
Οι τοπικοί Ινδοί ήταν απρόθυμοι στην εργασία για τους. 
Λίγοι επέζησαν των πρώτων δύσκολων χειμώνων. Ο 
καπετάνιος John Smith ήταν στρατιώτης, εξερευνητής, και 
τυχοδιώκτης. Με την αποικία στο κοντινό χάος, ανέλαβε την 
κυβέρνηση της αποικίας το 1608 και καθιέρωσε μια πολιτική της 
άκαμπτης πειθαρχίας και της γεωργικής καλλιέργειας. Όταν 
ένα ατύχημα πυρίτιδας ανάγκασε την επιστροφή του στην Αγγλία το 
1608, οι άποικοι αντιμέτωποι ένας καταστρεπτικός χειμώνας 
γνωστός όπως "να λιμοκτονήσει χρόνο."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los organizadores del primer establecimiento 
inglés en Jamestown, Virginia, en 1607 tenían visiones de la 
abundancia fácil y del pillaje abundante. Los colonos, un grupo
con poca experiencia agrícola y cargados con el gentry, en lugar 
encontrados un sitio swampy y enfermedad-montado. Los indios 
locales eran poco dispuestos trabajar para ellos. Pocos 
sobrevivieron los primeros inviernos difíciles. Capitán Juan 
Smith había sido soldado, explorador, y un aventurero. Con la 
colonia en caos cercano, él asumió el control el gobierno de la 
colonia en 1608 e instituyó una política de la disciplina rígida y 
de la cultivación agrícola. Cuando un accidente de la pólvora
forzó su vuelta a Inglaterra en 1608, los colonos hicieron frente a 
un invierno desastroso conocido como "tiempo muerto de hambre."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087055</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107610</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-starving-time-john-smith-recounts-the-early-history-of-jamestown-1609</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
