<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102897</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102897</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206550</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Women's History Resources</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Betriebsmittel Geschichte Der Frauen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ressources de l'Histoire des Femmes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recursos Do History Das Mulheres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risorse Di Storia Delle Donne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς ιστορίας γυναικών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recursos De la Historia De las Mujeres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">brings together the Library of Congress's resources on this topic. Learn about women who fought for right to vote, the first woman Supreme Court justice, women who served in war, and women in the performing arts. Read diary entries written by women before the American Revolution, during the Civil War, crossing the plains, on the frontier, and more. Use the American Women Gateway to do research in the field of women's history.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bringt die Bibliothek der Betriebsmittel des 
Kongresses auf diesem Thema zusammen. Erlernen Sie über Frauen,
die für Recht zu wählen kämpften, die erste Frau 
Gerichtgerechtigkeit, -frauen, die im Krieg dienten, und -frauen in 
den durchführenden künsten. Lesen Sie die Tagebucheinträge, 
die von den Frauen vor der amerikanischen Umdrehung, während des 
Bürgerkrieges geschrieben werden und die Ebenen kreuzen, auf der 
Grenze und mehr. Benutzen Sie die amerikanische Frau-Gateway, um
Forschung in auffangene der Geschichte der Frauen zu tun.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">rassemble la bibliothèque des ressources du 
congrès sur ce sujet. Renseignez-vous sur les femmes qui ont 
lutté pour le droit de voter, le premier juge, les femmes qui ont 
servi dans la guerre, et les femmes de cour suprême de femme dans les
arts d'exécution. Lisez les entrées d'agenda écrites par des 
femmes avant la révolution américaine, pendant la guerre civile, 
croisant les plaines, sur la frontière, et plus. Utilisez le 
Gateway américain de femmes pour faire la recherche dans le domaine 
de l'histoire des femmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">traz junto a biblioteca de recursos do congress 
neste tópico. Aprenda sobre as mulheres que lutaram pela 
direita votar, a primeira justiça, as mulheres que serviram na 
guerra, e as mulheres da corte suprema da mulher nas artes executando.
Leia as entradas do diário escritas por mulheres antes da volta
americana, durante a guerra civil, cruzando as planícies, na 
fronteira, e em mais. Use o Gateway americano das mulheres fazer
a pesquisa no campo do history das mulheres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">riunisce la libreria delle risorse del congresso 
su questo soggetto. Impari circa le donne che hanno combattuto 
per la destra votare, la prima giustizia, le donne che hanno servito 
nella guerra e le donne della Corte suprema della donna nelle arti 
d'effettuazione. Legga le entrate del diario scritte dalle donne
prima della rivoluzione americana, durante la guerra civile, 
attraversante le pianure, con frontiera e più. Utilizzi il 
Gateway americano delle donne per fare la ricerca nel campo di storia 
delle donne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">συγκεντρώνει τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς βιβλιοθήκης του 
συνεδρίου σε αυτό το θέμα. Μάθετε για τις γυναίκες που 
πάλεψαν για το δικαίωμα ψηφοφορίας, η πρώτη δικαιοσύνη ανώτατου 
δικαστηρίου γυναικών, γυναίκες που εξυπηρέτησαν στον πόλεμο, και 
τις γυναίκες στις τέχνες εκτέλεσης. Διαβάστε τις 
καταχωρήσεις ημερολογίων που γράφονται από τις γυναίκες πριν από
την αμερικανική επανάσταση, κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου 
πολέμου, που διασχίζει τις πεδιάδες, στα σύνορα, και 
περισσότεροι. Χρησιμοποιήστε την αμερικανική πύλη γυναικών 
για να κάνετε την έρευνα στον τομέα της ιστορίας των γυναικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">reúne la biblioteca de los recursos del congreso 
en este asunto. Aprenda sobre las mujeres que lucharon para la 
derecha de votar, la primera justicia, las mujeres que desempen'aron 
servicios en guerra, y las mujeres del Tribunal Supremo de la mujer en
los artes de ejecución. Lea las entradas del diario escritas 
por las mujeres antes de la revolución americana, durante la guerra 
civil, cruzando los llanos, en la frontera, y más. Utilice el 
Gateway americano de las mujeres para hacer la investigación en el 
campo de la historia de las mujeres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206550</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102897</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/womens-history-resources</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
