<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106964</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106964</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086791</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Rock Springs is Killed": White Reaction to the Rock Springs Riot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Felsen-Frühlinge wird" beendet: Weiße 
Reaktion auf den Felsen entspringt Aufstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">des "ressorts de roche est détruits" : La 
réaction blanche à la roche jaillit émeute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">da "as molas rocha são matadas": A reação 
branca à rocha salta motim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"le molle della roccia è uccisa": La 
reazione bianca alla roccia balza tumulto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι "ανοίξεις βράχου σκοτώνονται": Η άσπρη 
αντίδραση στο βράχο αναπηδά την ταραχή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">se matan los "resortes de la roca": La 
reacción blanca a la roca suelta alboroto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Even in the late nineteenth-century American West, a notably violent region, the violence directed against Chinese immigrants was shocking. The Union Pacific railroad employed 331 Chinese and 150 whites in their coal mine in Rock Springs, Wyoming. On September 2, 1885, Chinese and white miners, who were paid by the ton, had a dispute over who had the right to work in a particularly desirable area of the mine. White miners, members of the Knights of Labor, beat two Chinese miners and walked off their jobs. That evening the white miners, armed with rifles, rioted and burned down the Chinese quarter. No whites were prosecuted for the murder of twenty-eight Chinese and $150,000 in property damage, even though the identities of those responsible were widely known. Although U.S. Army troops had to provide protection before some of the Chinese could finally return to their burned-out homes in Rock Springs, some defiantly continued to work in the Union Pacific mines into the next century. This jingoistic editorial in the Rock Springs, Wyoming,  Independent , mourned the return of Chinese workers to the mining town the day after the riot.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sogar im spätes 19.-Jahrhundert amerikanischen 
Westen, entsetzte eine vornehmlich heftige Region, die 
Gewalttätigkeit, die gegen chinesische Immigranten verwiesen wurde. 
Die pazifische Eisenbahn des Anschlußes setzte 331 chinesische 
und 150 Weiß in ihrer Kohlengrube in den Felsen-Frühlingen, Wyoming 
ein. An September 2, 1885, chinesisches und weißen hatten die 
Bergmänner, die durch die Tonne gezahlt wurden, einen 
Debatteüberschuß, der das Recht hatte, in einem besonders 
wünschenswerten Bereich der Grube zu arbeiten. Weiße 
Bergmänner, Bauteile der Ritter der Arbeit, schlugen zwei chinesische
Bergmänner und gingen weg von ihren Jobs. Daß, die weißen 
Bergmänner glättend, bewaffnet mit Gewehren, randaliert und hinunter
das chinesische Viertel gebrannt. Kein Weiß wurde für den Mord
an achtundzwanzig chinesisch und an $150.000 in der 
Eigentumsbeschädigung verfolgt, obwohl die Identitäten von jenen 
verantwortlichen weit bekannt. Obgleich VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Armeetruppen Schutz zur Verfügung stellen mußten, bevor einiger des 
Chinesen zu ihren gebrannten-heraus Häusern in den Felsen-Frühlingen
schließlich zurückkommen könnte, fuhren einige defiantly fort, in 
den pazifischen Gruben des Anschlußes in das folgende Jahrhundert zu 
arbeiten. Dieser jingoistic Leitartikel im Felsen entspringt, 
Wyoming, Unabhängiges, beklagte die Rückkehr der chinesischen 
Arbeiter zur gewinnenstadt der Tag nach dem Aufstand.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Même vers la fin de l'ouest américain de 
dix-neuvième-siècle, une région notamment violente, la violence 
dirigée contre les immigrés chinois choquait. Le chemin de fer
Pacifique des syndicats a utilisé 331 chinois et 150 blancs dans leur
mine de houille en ressorts de roche, Wyoming. Septembre les 
mineurs de 2, 1885, chinois et blanc, qui ont été payés par la 
tonne, ont eu un excédent de conflit qui a eu le droit de travailler 
dans une zone particulièrement souhaitable de la mine. Les 
mineurs blancs, membres des chevaliers du travail, ont battu deux 
mineurs chinois et ont marché outre de leurs travaux. 
Qu'égaliser les mineurs blancs, armés avec fusille, 
ameuté et brûlé en bas du quart chinois. Aucun blanc n'a 
été poursuivi pour le meurtre de vingt-huit chinois et de $150.000 
dans des dégats matériels, quoique les identités de ces 
responsables aient été largement connues. Bien que les troupes
d'armée des ETATS-UNIS aient dû assurer la protection avant qu'une 
partie du Chinois pourrait finalement retourner à leurs maisons 
brûlées-dehors en ressorts de roche, les autres ont d'un air 
provoquant continué à travailler dans les mines Pacifiques des 
syndicats dans le siècle à venir. Cet éditorial jingoistic 
dans la roche jaillit, le Wyoming, indépendant, a pleuré le retour 
des ouvriers chinois à la ville d'extraction le jour après 
l'émeute.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mesmo no oeste americano de décimo-século 
atrasado, uma região notàvelmente violenta, a violência dirigida de
encontro aos immigrants chineses estava chocando-se. A estrada 
de ferro pacífica da união empregou 331 chineses e 150 brancos em 
sua mina de carvão nas molas da rocha, Wyoming. Em setembro os 
mineiros branco de 2, 1885, chinês e, que foram pagados pela 
tonelada, tiveram um excesso da disputa que tivesse a direita 
trabalhar em uma área particularmente desejável da mina. Os 
mineiros brancos, membros dos knights do trabalho, bateram dois 
mineiros chineses e andaram fora de seus trabalhos. Que 
nivelando os mineiros brancos, armados com os rifles, amotinados e 
queimados abaixo o quarto chinês. Nenhum branco prosecuted para
o assassinato de twenty-eight chinês e de $150.000 nos danos de 
propriedade, mesmo que as identidades daqueles responsáveis fossem 
sabidas extensamente. Embora as tropas do exército de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS tivessem que fornecer a proteção antes que algum do chinês 
poderia finalmente retornar a suas HOME queimadas-para fora nas molas 
da rocha, alguns continuaram defiantly a trabalhar nas minas 
pacíficas da união no século seguinte. Este editorial 
jingoistic na rocha salta, Wyoming, independent, mourned o retorno de 
trabalhadores chineses à cidade minando o dia após o motim.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche verso la fine dell'ovest americano di 
diciannovesimo-secolo, una regione considerevolmente violenta, la 
violenza diretta contro gli immigranti cinesi stava scuotendo. 
La ferrovia pacifica del sindacato ha impiegato 331 cinese 
ed i 150 bianchi nella loro miniera di carbone in molle della roccia, 
Wyoming. Settembri i minatori su bianco 2, 1885, cinese e, 
che sono stati pagati dalla tonnellata, hanno avuti un'eccedenza di 
disputa che ha avuta la destra lavorare in una zona particolarmente 
desiderabile della miniera. I minatori bianchi, membri dei 
cavalieri del Lavoro, hanno battuto due minatori cinesi ed 
hanno camminato fuori dei loro lavori. Che livellando i minatori
bianchi, muniti con i fucili, sollevati e bruciati giù il quarto 
cinese. Nessun bianco è stato proseguito per l'omicidio di 
ventotto cinese e di $150.000 nei danni materiali, anche se le 
identità di quei responsabili ampiamente sono state conosciute. 
Anche se le truppe dell'esercito degli STATI UNITI hanno dovuto 
assicurare la protezione prima che alcuno del cinese potrebbe 
infine ritornare alle loro sedi bruciate-fuori in molle della roccia, 
alcuni hanno continuato defiantly a funzionare nelle miniere pacifiche
del sindacato nel secolo venturo. Questo editoriale jingoistic 
nella roccia balza, il Wyoming, independent, si è addolorato il 
ritorno degli operai cinesi alla città estraente il giorno dopo 
il tumulto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακόμη και προς το τέλος της αμερικανικής δύσης 
δέκατος-αιώνα, μια ειδικότερα βίαια περιοχή, η βία που 
κατευθύνθηκε ενάντια στους κινεζικούς μετανάστες ήταν 
συγκλονίζοντας. Ο ειρηνικός σιδηρόδρομος ένωσης υιοθέτησε 
331 κινεζικό και 150 λευκά στο ορυχείο άνθρακά τους τις 
ανοίξεις βράχου, Wyoming. Στις 2 Σεπτεμβρίου ..1885, 
τους κινεζικούς και λευκούς ανθρακωρύχους, που πληρώθηκαν από τον
τόνο, είχε μια διαφωνία πέρα από ποιος είχε το δικαίωμα να 
εργαστεί σε μια ιδιαίτερα επιθυμητή περιοχή του ορυχείου. 
Οι λευκοί ανθρακωρύχοι, μέλη των ιπποτών της εργασίας, 
κτύπησαν δύο κινεζικούς ανθρακωρύχους και περπάτησαν από τις 
εργασίες τους. Εκείνο το βράδυ οι λευκοί ανθρακωρύχοι, που 
οπλίστηκαν με τα τουφέκια, στασίασαν και έκαψαν κάτω από το 
κινεζικό τέταρτο. Κανένα λευκό δεν διήχθη για τη δολοφονία
είκοσι οχτώ κινεζικά και $150.000 στη ζημία ιδιοκτησίας, 
ακόμα κι αν οι ταυτότητες των ατόμων ήταν ευρέως γνωστές. 
Αν και τα στρατεύματα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ στρατού έπρεπε να 
παρέχουν ότι η προστασία ενώπιον μερικών από τους Κινέζους θα 
μπορούσε τελικά να επιστρέψει στα καμένα σπίτια τους τις 
ανοίξεις βράχου, μερικές που συνεχίστηκαν προκλητικά για να 
εργάζονται στα ειρηνικά ορυχεία ένωσης στον επόμενο αιώνα. 
Αυτό το jingoistic κύριο άρθρο τις ανοίξεις βράχου, 
Wyoming, ανεξάρτητος, πένθησε την επιστροφή των κινεζικών 
εργαζομένων στην πόλη μεταλλείας η ημέρα μετά από την ταραχή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Incluso en el oeste americano del último 
diecinueveavo-siglo, una región notablemente violenta, la violencia 
dirigida contra inmigrantes chinos daba una sacudida eléctrica. 
El ferrocarril pacífico de la unión empleó 331 chinos y 150 
blancos en su mina de carbón en resortes de la roca, Wyoming. 
De septiembre los mineros el 2, 1885, chino y blanco, que fueron
pagados por la tonelada, tenían un excedente del conflicto que tenía
la derecha de trabajar en un área determinado deseable de la mina. 
Los mineros blancos, miembros de los caballeros del trabajo, 
batieron a dos mineros chinos y recorrieron de sus trabajos. Que
igualando a los mineros blancos, armados con los rifles, desenfrenados
y quemados abajo del cuarto chino. No se procesó ningunos 
blancos para el asesinato de veintiocho chino y $150.000 en daños 
materiales, aunque las identidades de esos responsables eran sabidas 
extensamente. Aunque las tropas del ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
tuvieron que proporcionar a la protección antes de que algo del chino
podría finalmente volver a sus hogares quemados-hacia fuera en 
resortes de la roca, algo continuó desafiantemente trabajando en las 
minas pacíficas de la unión en el siglo próximo. Este 
editorial jingoistic en la roca suelta, Wyoming, Independiente, estuvo de
luto la vuelta de trabajadores chinos a la ciudad que mina el día 
después del alboroto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086791</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106964</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/rock-springs-is-killed-white-reaction-to-the-rock-springs-riot</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
