<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106440</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106440</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087181</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We ask it; we demand it, and we intend to have it": Printer Albert R. Parsons Testifies before Congress about the Eight Hour Day</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir bitten um um es; wir verlangen es und 
wir beabsichtigen, es zu haben ": Drucker Albert R. Parsons 
Testifies vor Kongreß über den acht Stunde Tag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous la demandons ; nous l'exigeons, et 
nous avons l'intention de l'avoir ": Imprimante Albert R. 
Parsons Testifies devant le congrès au sujet du jour de huit heures</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós pedimo-la; nós exijimo-la, e nós 
pretendemos tê-la ": Impressora Albert R. Parsons Testifies 
antes do congress sobre o dia de oito horas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la chiediamo; la richiediamo ed intendiamo 
averli ": Stampante Albert R. Parsons Testifies prima del 
congresso circa il giorno di otto ore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τον ρωτάμε  τον απαιτούμε, και σκοπεύουμε να τον
έχουμε ": Printer Αλβέρτος Ρ. Parsons Testifies πριν
από το συνέδριο για την ημέρα οκτώ ώρας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la pedimos; la exigimos, y nos preponemos 
tenerla ": Impresora Albert R. Parsons Testifies antes del 
congreso sobre el día de ocho horas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With depression looming as a continual threat to the U.S. economy in the late-19th century, Americans debated how the government should respond to hard times--a question still unanswered today. At an 1878 Congressional hearing investigating "the causes of the general depression in labor and business," most witnesses took the position that government should not interfere with the workings of the "free market." But Texas-raised printer, socialist, and labor organizer Albert R. Parsons used his testimony to urge legislative intervention to cure the economic depression gripping the nation. In addition to calling for an eight-hour workday, Parsons challenged the notion that "freedom of contract" was possible "under our system of labor" and argued that the government should aid the people by loaning money to them, because "the people are simply borrowing money from themselves."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn der Tiefstand als kontinuierliche Drohung 
auftaucht, zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Wirtschaft im des späten 19. 
jahrhunderts Jahrhundert, debattierten Amerikaner, wie die Regierung 
auf harte Zeiten noch reagieren sollte -- eine Frage, die heute 
unbeantwortet ist. An einer Kongreßhörfähigkeit 1878, welche 
"die Ursachen des allgemeinen Tiefstands in der Arbeit und im 
Geschäft," nahmen die meisten nachforscht, Zeugen die Position, daß 
Regierung nicht die Funktionen des "freien Marktes behinderen sollte."
Aber Texas-angehobener Drucker, Sozialist und 
Gewerkschaftsorganisator Albert R. Parsons verwendeten sein Zeugnis, 
um gesetzgebende Intervention zu drängen, um die Wirtschaftskrise zu 
kurieren die Nation greifend. Zusätzlich zum Verlangen einen 
Achtstundenarbeitstag, forderten Pastoren den Begriff, der 
"Vertragsfreiheit unter unserem System der Arbeit" möglich "war" 
heraus und argumentierten, daß die Regierung den Leuten helfen 
sollte, indem sie Geld zu ihnen ausleiht, weil "die Leute borgen 
einfach Geld von selbst."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec la dépression apparaissant indistinctement 
comme menace continuelle à l'économie des ETATS-UNIS en fin du 19me 
siècle, les Américains ont discuté comment le gouvernement devrait 
répondre aux périodes difficiles -- une question encore sans 
réponse aujourd'hui. À une audition 1878 congressionnelle 
étudiant "les causes de la dépression générale dans le travail et 
les affaires," la plupart des témoins ont pris la position que le 
gouvernement ne devrait pas gêner les fonctionnements "du marché 
libre." Mais l'imprimante Texas-soulevée, le socialiste, et le 
propagandiste Albert R. Parsons avaient l'habitude son témoignage 
pour inviter l'intervention législative pour traiter la dépression 
économique saisissant la nation. En plus de nécessiter un jour
ouvrable de huit heures, les pasteurs ont défié la notion qui la 
"liberté de contrat" était possible "sous notre système de travail"
et ont argué du fait que le gouvernement devrait aider le peuple en 
prêtant l'argent à eux, parce que "le peuple emprunte simplement 
l'argent à eux-mêmes."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com o depression que aparece como uma ameaça 
contínua à economia de ESTADOS UNIDOS no século late-19th, os 
americanos debateram como o governo deve responder às épocas duras 
-- uma pergunta ainda não respondida hoje. Em um hearing 1878 
congressional que investiga "as causas do depression geral no trabalho
e no negócio," a maioria de testemunhas fizeram exame da posição 
que o governo não deve interferir com os funcionamentos "do mercado 
livre." Mas a impressora Texas-levantada, o socialist, e o 
organizer labor Albert R. Parsons usaram seu testimony incitar a 
intervenção legislativa para curar o depression econômico que 
prende a nação. Além à chamada por um workday eight-hour, os
parsons desafiaram a noção que a "liberdade de contrato" era 
possível "sob nosso sistema do trabalho" e discutiram que o governo 
deve ajudar aos povos emprestando o dinheiro a eles, porque "os povos 
estão pedindo simplesmente o dinheiro dse."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con la depressione che appare in lontananza come 
minaccia continua all'economia degli STATI UNITI nel fine del 19esimo 
secolo, gli Americani hanno dibattuto come il governo dovrebbe 
rispondere ancora ai periodi duri -- una domanda senza risposta oggi. 
Ad un'udienza congressuale 1878 che studia "le cause della 
depressione generale nel lavoro e nel commercio," la maggior 
parte dei testimoni hanno preso la posizione che il governo non 
dovrebbe interferire con i funzionamenti "del mercato libero." 
Ma la stampante Texas-alzata, il socialista e l'organizzatore 
di lavoro Albert R. Parsons hanno usato la sua testimonianza per 
invitare l'intervento legislativo per curare la depressione economica 
che afferra la nazione. Oltre che richiedere un workday di otto 
ore, i parsons hanno sfidato la nozione che "la libertà del 
contratto" era possibile "sotto il nostro sistema del lavoro" ed
hanno sostenuto che il governo dovrebbe aiutare la gente prestando i 
soldi a loro, perché "la gente sta prendendo in prestito 
semplicemente i soldi da se stesso."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την κατάθλιψη που εμφανίζεται ως συνεχής απειλή 
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ οικονομία στο late-19th αιώνα, Αμερικανοί 
συζήτησαν πώς η κυβέρνηση πρέπει να αποκριθεί στους σκληρούς 
χρόνους -- μια ερώτηση ακόμα αναπάντητη σήμερα. Σε μια του 
Κογκρέσου ακρόαση 1878 που ερευνά "τις αιτίες της γενικής 
κατάθλιψης στην εργασία και την επιχείρηση," οι περισσότεροι 
μάρτυρες υποστήριξαν τη θέση ότι η κυβέρνηση δεν πρέπει να 
παρεμποδίσει τα έργα της "ελεύθερης αγοράς." Αλλά ο 
Τέξας-αυξημένοι εκτυπωτής, ο σοσιαλιστής, και ο διοργανωτής 
Αλβέρτος R. Parsons εργασίας χρησιμοποίησαν την κατάθεσή 
του για να ωθήσουν τη νομοθετική επέμβαση για να θεραπεύσουν την 
οικονομική ύφεση πιάνοντας το έθνος. Εκτός από την 
απαίτηση μιας οκτώ ωρών εργάσιμης ημέρας, οι εφημέριοι 
προκάλεσαν την έννοια ότι "η ελευθερία της σύμβασησ" ήταν 
δυνατή "στο πλαίσιο του συστήματος εργασίας μασ" και υποστήριξε 
ότι η κυβέρνηση πρέπει να βοηθήσει τους ανθρώπους με τα χρήματα 
σε τους, επειδή "οι άνθρωποι δανείζονται απλά τα χρήματα από 
τους."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la depresión asomando como amenaza continua a
la economía de ESTADOS UNIDOS en el siglo de fines del siglo 
diecinueve, los americanos discutieron cómo el gobierno debe todavía
responder a las épocas duras -- una pregunta por contestar hoy. 
En una audiencia del congreso 1878 que investigaba "las causas 
de la depresión general en trabajo y negocio," la mayoría de los 
testigos tomaron la posición que el gobierno no debe interferir con 
los funcionamientos del "mercado libre." Pero la impresora 
Tejas-levantada, el socialista, y el organizador de trabajo Albert R. 
Parsons utilizaron su testimonio para impulsar la intervención 
legislativa para curar la depresión económica que apretaba la 
nación. Además de llamar por un día laborable de ocho horas, 
los parsons desafiaron la noción que la "libertad del contrato" era 
posible "bajo nuestro sistema del trabajo" y discutieron que el 
gobierno debe ayudar a la gente prestando el dinero a ellos, porque 
"la gente está pidiendo prestado simplemente el dinero de sí 
mismos."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087181</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106440</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-ask-it-we-demand-it-and-we-intend-to-have-it-printer-albert-r-parsons-testifies-before-congress-about-the-eight-hour-day</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
