<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105472</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105472</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206966</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">California As I Saw It: First-Person Narratives of California's Early Years, 1849-1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalifornien, Wie Ich Es Sah: Erst-Person 
Darstellungen von Kaliforniens frühen Jahren, 1849-1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Californie Comme Je L'ai vue : Récits de 
Premier-Personne des premières années de la Californie, 1849-1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Califórnia Como Eu A vi: Narrativas da 
Primeiro-Pessoa dos anos adiantados de Califórnia, 1849-1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">California Come La ho vista: Descrizioni 
della Primo-Persona dei primi anni della California, 1849-1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καλιφόρνια δεδομένου ότι Την εβλέίδα: 
Πρώτος-πρόσωπο αφηγήματα των στις αρχές ετών Καλιφόρνιας, 
1849-1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">California Como La vi: Narrativas de la 
Primero-Persona de los años de California, 1849-1900</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">consists of texts and illustrations of 190 works documenting California's history from the Gold Rush to the turn of the century. It captures the pioneer experience; encounters between Anglo-Americans and the diverse peoples who had preceded them; the transformation of the land by mining, ranching, agriculture, and urban development; the often-turbulent growth of communities and cities; and California's emergence as both a state and a place of uniquely American dreams.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">aus Texten und Abbildungen von 190 Arbeiten 
besteht das Dokumentieren von von Geschichte Kaliforniens von den 
Goldanstürmen zur Jahrhundertwende. Es erfaßt die 
Pioniererfahrung; Treffen zwischen Anglo-Amerikanern und den 
verschiedenen Völkern, die sie vorangegangen hatten; die 
Transformation des Landes durch das Bergbau, das Ranching, 
Landwirtschaft und städtische Entwicklung; das 
häufig-turbulente Wachstum der Gemeinschaften und der Städte; 
und Hervortreten Kaliforniens als Zustand und Ort der eindeutig 
amerikanischen Träume.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">se compose des textes et des illustrations de 190 
travaux documentant l'histoire de la Californie des précipitations 
d'or au tournant du siècle. Il capture l'expérience pionnière
; rencontre entre les Anglo-Américains et les peuples divers 
qui les avaient précédés ; la transformation de la terre par 
le mien, ranching, l'agriculture, et le développement urbain ; 
la croissance souvent-turbulente des communautés et des villes 
; et l'apparition de la Californie comme état et endroit des 
rêves seulement américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">consiste em textos e em ilustrações de 190 
trabalhos que documentam o history de Califórnia das arremetidas do 
ouro à volta do século. Captura a experiência pioneira; 
encontro entre os Anglo-Americanos e os povos diversos que os 
tinham precedido; a transformação da terra minar, ranching, 
por agricultura, e pelo desenvolvimento urbano; o crescimento 
frequentemente-often-turbulent das comunidades e das cidades; e 
emergence de Califórnia como  um estado e um lugar de sonhos 
excepcionalmente americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiste dei testi e delle illustrazioni di 190 
impianti che documentano la storia della California dagli sbalzi 
dell'oro alla girata del secolo. Blocca l'esperienza 
pionieristica; incontro fra gli Anglo-Americani e la gente varia
che li avevano preceduti; la trasformazione della terra 
estraendo, ranching, agricoltura e sviluppo urbano; lo sviluppo 
spesso-turbolento delle Comunità e delle città; ed emersione 
della California come sia un dichiarare che posto dei sogni unicamente
americani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποτελείται από τα κείμενα και τις απεικονίσεις 190
εργασιών τεκμηριώνοντας την ιστορία Καλιφόρνιας από τη χρυσή 
βιασύνη στη στροφή του αιώνα. Συλλαμβάνει την εμπειρία 
πρωτοπόρων  αντιμετωπίζει μεταξύ ανγλο-Αμερικανών και των 
διαφορετικών λαών που τους είχαν προηγηθεί  ο 
μετασχηματισμός του εδάφους από να εξαγάγει, τη διεύθυνση ενός 
αγροκτήματος, τη γεωργία, και την αστική ανάπτυξη  η 
συχνά-ταραχώδης αύξηση των κοινοτήτων και των πόλεων  και 
εμφάνιση Καλιφόρνιας και ως κατάσταση και ως θέση των μεμονωμένα 
αμερικανικών ονείρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">consiste en los textos y las ilustraciones de 190 
trabajos que documentan la historia de California de las acometidas 
del oro a la vuelta del siglo. Captura la experiencia pionera; 
encuentro entre los Anglo-Americanos y la gente diversa que los 
habían precedido; la transformación de la pista por minar, 
ranching, agricultura, y el desarrollo urbano; el crecimiento a 
menudo-turbulento de comunidades y de ciudades; y aparición de 
California como un estado y lugar de sueños únicamente americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206966</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105472</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/california-as-i-saw-it-first-person-narratives-of-californias-early-years-1849-1900</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
