<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104790</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104790</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202755</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Try to see it my way; I'll try to see it yours.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Versuchen Sie, sie zu sehen meine Methode; 
Ich versuche, sie zu sehen Ihr.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Essayez de le voir ma voie ; J'essayerai de 
la voir vôtre.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tente vê-lo minha maneira; Eu tentarei 
vê-la seu.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Provi a vederlo il mio modo; Proverò a 
vederlo il vostro.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προσπαθήστε να το δείτε ο τρόπος μου  
Θα προσπαθήσω να το δω δικοί σας.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Intente verlo mi manera; Intentaré verla el
tuyo.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson includes guided class discussion and a hands-on activity demonstrating the importance of clear communication in avoiding misunderstanding and conflict. Students use wooden blocks in a building activity that allows them to actually experience the difference in their own and another student's perception and understanding of verbal building instructions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion einschließt geführte Kategorie Diskussion 
und Blindeinschub eine Aktivität, die den Wert der freien 
Kommunikation zeigt, wenn sie Mißverständnis und $überschneidung 
vermeidet. Kursteilnehmer benutzen hölzerne Blöcke in einer 
Konjunktur im Bausektor, die sie den Unterschied bezüglich ihrer 
Selbst wirklich erfahren läßt und in der Vorstellung und im 
Verstehen eines anderen Kursteilnehmers der mündlichen 
Gebäudeanweisungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon inclut la discussion guidée de classe et une
activité à commande manuelle démontrant l'importance de 
transmission claire en évitant le malentendu et le conflit. Les
étudiants utilisent les blocs en bois dans une activité de bâtiment
qui leur permet d'éprouver réellement la différence dans leurs 
propres et la perception et l'arrangement d'un autre étudiant des 
instructions verbales de bâtiment.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição inclui a discussão guiada da classe e uma 
atividade hands-on que demonstra a importância de uma comunicação 
desobstruída em evitar o engano e o conflito. Os estudantes 
usam blocos de madeira em uma atividade de edifício que permita que 
experimentem realmente a diferença no seus próprios e na percepção
e na compreensão de um outro estudante de instruções verbais do 
edifício.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione include la discussione guidata del codice 
categoria e un'attività hands-on che dimostra l'importanza della 
comunicazione libera nel evitare il misunderstanding ed il conflitto. 
Gli allievi usano i blocchi di legno in un'attività di 
costruzione che li permette realmente di avvertire la differenza nei 
loro propri e nella percezione e nel capire di un altro allievo delle 
istruzioni verbali della costruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα περιλαμβάνει την καθοδηγημένη συζήτηση
κλάσης και μια εμπράγματη δραστηριότητα που καταδεικνύει τη 
σημασία της σαφούς επικοινωνίας στην αποφυγή της παρανόησης και 
της σύγκρουσης. Οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν τις ξύλινες 
ομάδες δεδομένων σε μια δραστηριότητα κτηρίου που επιτρέπει σε 
τις για να δοκιμάσει πραγματικά τη διαφορά δικοί τους και 
αντίληψη και κατανόηση ενός άλλου σπουδαστή των λεκτικών 
οδηγιών οικοδόμησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección incluye la discusión dirigida de la clase y
una actividad con manos que demuestra la importancia de la 
comunicación clara en evitar el malentendido y el conflicto. 
Los estudiantes utilizan bloques de madera en una actividad de 
edificio que permita que experimenten realmente la diferencia en sus 
el propios y la opinión y entender de otro estudiante de las 
instrucciones verbales del edificio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KAREN OSBORNE-ROWLAND
FN:KAREN OSBORNE-ROWLAND
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202755</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104790</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/try-to-see-it-my-way-ill-try-to-see-it-yours</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
