<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107405</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107405</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087408</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Art Within Reach": Federal Art Project Community Art Centers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Kunst Innerhalb Der Reichweite": 
Bundeskunst-Projekt-Gemeinschaftskunst-Mitten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Art Dans l'Extension" : Centres Fédéraux 
d'Art de la Communauté De Projet d'Art</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Arte Dentro Do Alcance": Centros Federais 
Da Arte Da Comunidade Do Projeto Da Arte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Arte All'interno Dell'Estensione": Centri 
Federali Di Arte Della Comunità Di Progetto Di Arte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τέχνη προσιτή": Ομοσπονδιακά τέχνης κέντρα 
τέχνης προγράμματος κοινοτικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Arte Dentro Del Alcance": Centros Federales
Del Arte De la Comunidad Del Proyecto Del Arte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">New Deal arts projects were guided by two novel assumptions: artists were workers and art was cultural labor worthy of government support. That commitment was demonstrated most dramatically in the Federal Art Project (FAP), a relief program for depression-era artists. Some painters and sculptors continued working in their studios with the assistance of relief checks and the occasional supervision of WPA administrators--their work was placed in libraries, schools, and other public buildings. FAP also sponsored hundreds of murals and sculptures designed for municipal buildings and public spaces. FAP's Community Art Centers worked to create new audiences for art by bringing art education and exhibitions to neighborhoods and communities with little access to galleries and museums. These essays by FAP employees Thaddeus Clapp and Lawrence A. Jones lauded programs that brought "art within reach" for people in Massachusetts and affirmed the democratic possibilities of a project that reached across class and racial lines in New Orleans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kunstprojekte des neuen Abkommens wurden durch 
zwei Romanannahmen geführt: Künstler waren Arbeiter und kunst 
war der Regierungsunterstützung kulturelles Arbeitsangemessenes. 
Diese Verpflichtung wurde drastisch im Bundeskunst-Projekt 
(FAP), ein Entlastung Programm für Tiefstand-Ära Künstler 
demonstriert. Einige Maler und Sculptors fuhren fort, in ihren 
Studios mit der Unterstützung der Entlastung Überprüfungen und der 
gelegentlichen Überwachung der WPA Verwalter zu arbeiten -- ihre 
Arbeit wurde in Bibliotheken, in Schulen und in andere allgemeine 
Gebäude gelegt. FAP auch geförderte Hunderte Wandbilder und 
Skulpturen konzipierten für städtische Gebäude und allgemeine 
Platz. Kunst-Mitten Gemeinschaft FAPs arbeiteten, um neue 
Publikum für kunst, indem sie kunstausbildung und -ausstellungen zu 
den Nachbarschaften und holten Gemeinschaften zu erstellen mit wenig 
Zugriff zu den Galerien und zu den Museen. Diese Versuche durch 
FAP Angestellte Thaddeus Clapp und Lawrence A. Jones lauded Programme,
die "kunst innerhalb der Reichweite" für Leute in Massachusetts 
holten und bestätigten die demokratischen Möglichkeiten eines 
Projektes, das über Kategorie und rassischen Zeilen in New-Orleans 
erreichte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des projets d'arts de nouvelle affaire ont été 
guidés par deux prétentions de roman : les artistes étaient 
des ouvriers et l'art était digne de travail culturel du soutien 
gouvernemental. Cet engagement a été démontré le plus 
excessivement dans le projet fédéral d'art (FAP), un programme de 
soulagement pour des artistes de dépression-ère. Quelques 
peintres et sculpteurs ont continué de travailler dans leurs studios 
avec l'aide des contrôles de soulagement et de la surveillance 
occasionnelle des administrateurs de WPA -- leur travail a été 
placé dans les bibliothèques, les écoles, et d'autres bâtiments 
publics. Les centaines également commanditées de FAP de muraux
et sculptures ont conçu pour les bâtiments municipaux et les espaces
publics. Les centres d'art de la Communauté de FAP ont 
travaillé pour créer de nouvelles assistances pour l'art en 
apportant l'éducation et les expositions d'art aux voisinages et 
communautés avec peu d'accès aux galeries et aux musées. Ces 
essais par des employés Thaddeus Clapp et Laurent A. Jones de FAP ont
glorifié les programmes qui ont apporté l'"art dans l'extension" 
pour des personnes dans le Massachusetts et ont affirmé les 
possibilités démocratiques d'un projet qui a atteint à travers la 
classe et les lignes raciales à la Nouvelle-Orléans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os projetos das artes do negócio novo foram 
guiados por duas suposições da novela: os artistas eram 
trabalhadores e a arte era digna labor cultural da sustentação de 
governo. Esse compromisso foi demonstrado o mais dramàtica no 
projeto federal da arte (FAP), um programa do relevo para artistas da 
depression-era. Alguns pintores e sculptors continuaram 
trabalhando em seus estúdios com o auxílio de verificações do 
relevo e da supervisão ocasional de administradores de WPA -- seu 
trabalho foi colocado nas bibliotecas, nas escolas, e em outros 
edifícios públicos. As centenas também patrocinadas de FAP 
dos murals e dos sculptures projetaram para edifícios municipais e 
espaços públicos. Os centros da arte da comunidade de FAP 
trabalharam para criar audiências novas para a arte trazendo a 
instrução e os exhibitions da arte às vizinhanças e comunidades 
com pouco acesso às galerias e aos museus. Estes essays por 
empregados Thaddeus Clapp e Lawrence A. Jones de FAP lauded os 
programas que trouxeram a "arte dentro do alcance" para povos em 
Massachusetts e afirmaram as possibilidades democráticas de um 
projeto que alcançasse através da classe e das linhas raciais em 
Nova Orleães.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I progetti di arti di nuovo affare sono stati 
guidati da due presupposti del romanzo: gli artisti erano operai
e l'arte era degno di lavoro culturale del supporto di governo. 
Quell'impegno è stato dimostrato il più drammaticamente nel 
progetto federale di arte (FAP), un programma di rilievo per gli 
artisti di depressione-era. Alcuni pittori e scultori hanno 
continuato a lavorare nei loro studi con l'assistenza dei controlli di
rilievo e del controllo occasionale degli amministratori di WPA -- il 
loro lavoro è stato disposto in librerie, in scuole ed in altre 
costruzioni pubbliche. Le centinaia anche patrocinate di FAP dei
murals e delle sculture hanno progettato per le costruzioni comunali e
gli spazi pubblici. I centri di arte della Comunità del FAP 
hanno funzionato per creare i nuovi pubblici per l'arte portando la 
formazione e le mostre di arte alle vicinanze e le Comunità con poco 
accesso alle gallerie ed ai musei. Questi saggi dagli impiegati 
Thaddeus Clapp e Lawrence A. Jones del FAP lauded i programmi che 
hanno portato "l'arte all'interno dell'estensione" per la gente in 
Massachusetts ed hanno affermato le possibilità democratiche di 
progetto che ha raggiunto attraverso codice categoria e le righe 
razziali a New Orleans.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα νέα προγράμματα τεχνών διαπραγμάτευσης 
καθοδηγήθηκαν από δύο νέες υποθέσεις: οι καλλιτέχνες ήταν
εργαζόμενοι και η τέχνη ήταν πολιτιστική εργασία αντάξια της 
κυβερνητικής υποστήριξης. Εκείνη η υποχρέωση καταδείχθηκε ο
πιό εντυπωσιακά στο ομοσπονδιακό έργο τέχνης (FAP), ένα 
πρόγραμμα ανακούφισης για τους καλλιτέχνες κατάθλιψη-εποχής. 
Μερικοί ζωγράφοι και γλύπτες συνέχισαν στα στούντιό τους 
με τη βοήθεια των ελέγχων ανακούφισης και την περιστασιακή 
επίβλεψη των διοικητών WPA -- η εργασία τους τοποθετήθηκε στις 
βιβλιοθήκες, τα σχολεία, και άλλα δημόσια κτήρια. FAP 
υποστήριξε επίσης τις εκατοντάδες των τοιχογραφιών και των 
γλυπτών που σχεδιάστηκαν για τα δημοτικά κτήρια και τους 
δημόσιους χώρους. Τα κοινοτικά κέντρα τέχνης FAP 
εργάστηκαν για να δημιουργήσουν τα νέα ακροατήρια για την τέχνη 
με να φέρουν την αισθητικές αγωγή και τις εκθέσεις στις γειτονιές
και τις κοινότητες με λίγη πρόσβαση στις στοές και τα μουσεία. 
Αυτά τα δοκίμια από FAP τους υπαλλήλους Thaddeus 
Clapp και Lawrence Α. Jones ηπαίνεσαν τα προγράμματα που 
έφεραν "την τέχνη προσιτή" για τους ανθρώπους στη Μασαχουσέτη και
βεβαίωσαν τις δημοκρατικές δυνατότητες ενός έργου που έφθασε σε 
ολόκληρη την κλάση και τις φυλετικές γραμμές στη Νέα Ορλεάνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los proyectos de los artes del nuevo reparto 
fueron dirigidos por dos asunciones de la novela: los artistas 
eran trabajadores y el arte era digno de trabajo cultural de la ayuda 
de gobierno. Esa consolidación fue demostrada lo más 
dramáticamente posible en el proyecto federal del arte (FAP), un 
programa de la relevación para los artistas de la depresio'n-era. 
Algunos pintores y escultores continuaron trabajando en sus 
estudios con la ayuda de los cheques de la relevación y de la 
supervisión ocasional de los administradores de WPA -- su trabajo fue
puesto en bibliotecas, escuelas, y otros edificios públicos. 
Los centenares también patrocinados de FAP de murals y de 
esculturas diseñaron para los edificios municipales y los espacios 
públicos. Los centros del arte de la comunidad de FAP 
trabajaron para crear las nuevas audiencias para el arte trayendo la 
educación y exposiciones del arte a las vecindades y a comunidades 
con poco acceso a las galerías y a los museos. Estos ensayos de
los empleados Thaddeus Clapp y Lorenzo A. Jones de FAP alabaron los 
programas que trajeron "arte dentro del alcance" para la gente en 
Massachusetts y afirmaron las posibilidades democráticas de un 
proyecto que alcanzó a través de clase y de líneas raciales en New 
Orleans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087408</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107405</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/art-within-reach-federal-art-project-community-art-centers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
