<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206018</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hands on the Land Teaching Materials</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hände auf den Land-Lehrmitteln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mains sur le matériel didactique de terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mãos nos materiais de ensino da terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mani sui materiali didattici della terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χέρια στα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά εδάφους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Manos en los materiales didácticos de la pista</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lessons for learning about the Everglades ecosystem, bat habitats, bull trout, rock classification, eagles, invasive species, forest carnivores, forest rebirth, North Cascades habitats and ancient peoples, plant morphological features, migrating birds, water quality in the wilderness, use of Geographic Information Systems (GIS) to map vegetation, and more. The site includes a teachers guide to the Great Sand Dunes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lektionen für das Lernen über das 
Everglades Oekosystem, Hieblebensräume, Stierforelle, 
Felsenklassifikation, Adler, Angriffssorte, Waldfleischfressende 
Tiere, Waldwiedergeburt, Nordkaskadelebensräume zur Verfügung und 
alte Völker, errichten morphologische Merkmale, Fortziehenvögel, 
Wasserqualität in der Wildnis, Gebrauch von geographischen 
Informationssystemen (GIS) Vegetation abzubilden und mehr. Die 
Site schließt eine Lehreranleitung zu den großen Sanddünen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons pour se renseigner sur 
l'écosystème d'Everglades, habitats de batte, truite de taureau, 
classification de roche, aigles, espèces invahissantes, 
carnivores de forêt, renaissance de forêt, nord monte en 
cascade des habitats et des peuples antiques, des dispositifs 
morphologiques d'usine, des oiseaux de passer, qualité de l'eau dans 
le désert, utilisation des systèmes d'information géographiques 
(GIs) de tracer la végétation, et plus. Le site inclut
un guide de professeurs des grandes dunes de sable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece lições aprendendo sobre o ecosystem de 
Everglades, habitats do bastão, truta do touro, classificação da 
rocha, águias, espécie invasive, carnivores da floresta, rebirth da 
floresta, habitats nortes das cascatas e os povos antigos, plantam 
características morphological, pássaros migrar, qualidade de água 
na região selvagem, uso de sistemas de informação geográficos 
(SOLDADOS) traçar a vegetação, e mais. O local inclui uma 
guia dos professores às dunas de areia grandes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni per imparare circa 
l'ecosistema di Everglades, gli habitat del blocco, la trota del toro,
la classificazione della roccia, le aquile, la specie invasive, i 
carnivori della foresta, il rebirth della foresta, habitat del nord 
delle cascate e la gente antica, pianta le caratteristiche 
morfologiche, gli uccelli di migrazione, la qualità dell'acqua nella 
selva, l'uso dei sistemi d'informazione geografici (GIS) tracciare la 
vegetazione e più. Il luogo include una guida degli insegnanti 
alle dune di sabbia grandi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα μαθήματα για την εκμάθηση για το 
Everglades οικοσύστημα, βιότοποι ροπάλων, πέστροφα ταύρων, 
ταξινόμηση βράχου, αετοί, της εισβολής είδη, δασικά 
carnivores, δασική αναγέννηση, βιότοποι βόρειων καταρρακτών 
και οι αρχαίοι λαοί, φυτεύουν τα μορφολογικά χαρακτηριστικά 
γνωρίσματα, τα αποδημητικά πουλιά, την ποιότητα νερού στην 
αγριότητα, τη χρήση των γεωγραφικών συστημάτων πληροφοριών 
(GIS) για να χαρτογραφήσουν τη βλάστηση, και περισσότερων. 
Η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει έναν οδηγό δασκάλων στους μεγάλους 
αμμόλοφους άμμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a las lecciones para aprender sobre el
ecosistema de Everglades, habitat del palo, trucha del toro, 
clasificación de la roca, águilas, especie invasora, carnívoros del
bosque, renacimiento del bosque, habitat del norte de las cascadas y 
la gente antigua, planta características morfológicas, pájaros de 
la migración, calidad del agua en el yermo, el uso de los sistemas de
información geográficos (SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN EL EJÉRCITO) de 
asociar la vegetación, y más. El sitio incluye una guía de 
los profesores a las grandes dunas de arena.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206018</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106820</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hands-on-the-land-teaching-materials</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
