<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107087</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107087</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087061</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The  Times  Reports on "the Day of Two Noons"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Zeit-Berichte über "den Tag von zwei 
Mittagen"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les états de périodes "le jour de deux midis"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os relatórios das épocas "no dia de dois 
meios-dias"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I rapporti di periodi "il giorno di due 
mezzogiorni"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι χρονικές εκθέσεις "την ημέρα δύο Noons"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los informes de las épocas sobre "el día de dos 
mediodías"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The 1883 adoption of four standard time zones did not come easily. Many Americans, particularly those who continued to mark the passage of time by the natural rhythms of the sun, resisted the efforts of railroad officials and scientists to impose standard time on the nation. William F. Allen, the first secretary of the railroad companies' General Time Convention (GTC), wrote and spoke tirelessly in his efforts to secure time standardization. To minimize opposition, the GTC's proposed new time zones deviated very little from existing norms: most changes were kept to half an hour or less. Sunday, November 18, 1883--known as the "day of two noons" because people were required to stop what they were doing and reset their clocks anywhere from two to thirty minutes--was remarkably orderly. This New York  Times  articledescribed the scene in the nation's largest city. Local and state laws soon ratified the new standard, but as late as 1915, citizen challenges to the time standard were still being considered by the courts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Annahme 1883 von vier Standardzeitzonen kam 
nicht leicht. Viele Amerikaner, besonders die, die fortfuhren, 
den Durchgang der Zeit durch die natürlichen Rhythmen der Sonne zu 
kennzeichnen, widerstanden den Bemühungen der Eisenbahnbeamter und 
Wissenschaftlern, Standardzeit der Nation aufzuerlegen. William 
F. Allen, die erste Sekretärin der Eisenbahn der Gesellschaften 
allgemeinen Zeit-Vereinbarung (GTC), schrieb und Speiche unermüdlich 
in seine Bemühungen, Zeitnormierung zu sichern. Um Opposition 
herabzusetzen, wichen die des GTCs vorgeschlagenen neuen Zeitzonen 
sehr wenig von vorhandenen Normen ab: die meisten Änderungen 
wurden zur halben Stunde oder weniger gehalten. Sonntag, 
November 18, 1883 -- bekannt als der "Tag von zwei Mittagen", weil 
Leute benoetigt wurden, zu stoppen, was sie taten und ihre Taktgeber 
überall von zwei bis dreißig Minuten zurücksetzten -- war 
bemerkenswert regelmäßig. Dieses New York setzt 
articledescribed die Szene in der größten Stadt der Nation Zeit 
fest. Einheimisch- und Zustandgesetze bestätigten bald den 
neuen Standard, aber so spät, wie 1915, Bürgerherausforderungen zur 
Zeitvorgabe noch durch die Gerichte betrachtet wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'adoption 1883 de quatre fuseaux horaires 
standard n'est pas venue facilement. Beaucoup d'Américains, en 
particulier ceux qui ont continué à marquer le passage du temps par 
les rythmes normaux du soleil, résisté les efforts des 
fonctionnaires de chemin de fer et scientifiques d'imposer le temps 
standard à la nation. William F. Allen, le premier secrétaire 
de la convention générale des sociétés de temps de chemin de fer 
(GTC), a écrit et rai inlassablement dans ses efforts de fixer 
l'étalonnage de temps. Pour réduire au minimum l'opposition, 
fuseaux horaires proposés du GTC les nouveaux ont dévié très peu 
des normes existantes : la plupart des changements ont été 
gardés à une demi-heure ou moins. Dimanche, 18 novembre 1883 
-- connu sous le nom de "jour de deux midis" parce que les gens ont 
été requis de s'arrêter ce qu'ils faisaient et ont remis à l'état
initial leurs horloges n'importe où de deux à trente minutes -- 
était remarquablement ordonné. Ce New York chronomètre 
articledescribed la scène dans la plus grande ville de la nation. 
Les lois de gens du pays et d'état bientôt ont ratifié la 
nouvelle norme, mais aussi tard qu'on considérait toujours 1915, 
défis de citoyen à la norme de temps par les cours.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O adoption 1883 de quatro zonas de tempo padrão 
não veio fàcilmente. Muitos americanos, particularmente 
aqueles que continuaram a marcar a passagem do tempo pelos ritmos 
naturais do sol, resistido os esforços de oficiais da estrada de 
ferro e cientistas impo o tempo padrão na nação. William F. 
Allen, primeira secretária da convenção geral companies' do tempo 
da estrada de ferro (GTC), escreveu e raio tirelessly em seus 
esforços fixar a estandardização do tempo. Para minimizar a 
oposição, as zonas de tempo novas propostas do GTC deviated muito 
pouco das normas existentes: a maioria de mudanças foram 
mantidas à metade um da hora ou mais menos. Domingo, novembro 
18, 1883 -- sabido como o "dia de dois meios-dias" porque os povos 
foram requeridos parar o que faziam e restauravam seus pulsos de 
disparo em qualquer lugar  dois a trinta minutos -- era notàvelmente 
em ordem. Esta New York cronometra articledescribed a cena na 
cidade a maior da nação. As leis do local e do estado 
ratificaram logo o padrão novo, mas tão tarde quanto 1915, desafios 
do cidadão ao padrão de tempo eram considerados ainda pelas cortes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'approvazione 1883 di quattro zone di tempo 
standard non è venuto facilmente. Molti Americani, specialmente
coloro che ha continuato a contrassegnare il passaggio di tempo dai 
ritmi naturali del sole, resistito a gli sforzi dei funzionari della 
ferrovia e scienziati imporre tempo standard alla nazione. 
William F. Allen, la prima segretaria della convenzione generale
delle società di tempo della ferrovia (GTC), ha scritto instancabile 
e spoke nei suoi sforzi assicurare la normalizzazione di tempo. 
Per minimizzare l'opposizione, zone di tempo proposte del GTC le
nuove hanno deviato pochissimo dalle norme attuali: la maggior 
parte dei cambiamenti si sono attenuti a mezz'ora o più di meno. 
Domenica, 18 novembre 1883 -- conosciuto come "il giorno di due 
mezzogiorni" perché la gente è stata tenuta a arrestarsi che cosa 
stavano facendo e ripristinato i loro orologi dovunque due - trenta 
minuti -- era notevolmente ordinata. Questa New York cronometra 
articledescribed la scena nella più grande città della nazione. 
Il local e dichiara le leggi presto ha ratificato il 
nuovo standard, ma in ritardo quanto 1915, sfide del cittadino allo 
standard di tempo ancora stava considerando dalle corti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η υιοθέτηση 1883 τεσσάρων πρότυπων χρονικών ζωνών 
δεν ήρθε εύκολα. Πολλοί Αμερικανοί, ιδιαίτερα εκείνοι που 
συνέχισαν να χαρακτηρίζουν τη μετάβαση του χρόνου από τους 
φυσικούς ρυθμούς του ήλιου, αντιστάθηκαν στις προσπάθειες των 
ανώτερων υπαλλήλων και των επιστημόνων σιδηροδρόμου για να 
επιβάλουν τον πρότυπο χρόνο στο έθνος. Θ*Ωηλληαμ F. 
Allen, ο πρώτος γραμματέας της γενικής χρονικής Συνθήκης των 
επιχειρήσεων σιδηροδρόμου (GTC), έγραψε και μίλησε ακούραστα 
στις προσπάθειές του να εξασφαλίσει τη χρονική τυποποίηση. 
Για να ελαχιστοποιήσει την αντίθεση, οι προτεινόμενες νέες 
χρονικές ζώνες του GTC παρέκκλιναν πολύ λίγα από τους 
υπάρχοντες κανόνες: οι περισσότερες αλλαγές τηρήθηκαν μισή
ώρα ή λιγότερο. Η Κυριακή, 18 Νοεμβρίου, 1883 -- 
γνωστά ως "ημέρα δύο noons" επειδή οι άνθρωποι έπρεπε για να 
σταματήσουν τι έκαναν και επαναρύθμισαν τα ρολόγια τους 
οπουδήποτε από δύο έως τριάντα λεπτά -- ήταν εντυπωσιακά 
τακτική. Αυτοί οι New York Times η σκηνή στη 
μεγαλύτερη πόλη του έθνους. Οι τοπικοί και κρατικοί νόμοι 
επικύρωσαν σύντομα τα νέα πρότυπα, αλλά τόσο αργά όπως το 
1915, προκλήσεις πολιτών στα χρονικά πρότυπα εξεταζόταν ακόμα
από τα δικαστήρια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La adopción 1883 de cuatro zonas de la hora 
estándar no vino fácilmente. Muchos americanos, determinado 
los que continuaron marcando el paso del tiempo por los ritmos 
naturales del sol, resistido los esfuerzos de los funcionarios del 
ferrocarril y científicos de imponer hora estándar ante la nación. 
Guillermo F. Allen, la primera secretaria de la convención 
general de sociedades del tiempo del ferrocarril (GTC), escribió y 
rayo incansable en sus esfuerzos de asegurar la estandardización del 
tiempo. Para reducir al mínimo la oposición, zonas de tiempo 
propuestas del GTC las nuevas se desviaron muy poco de normas 
existentes: la mayoría de los cambios fueron guardados a la 
mitad de la hora o menos. Domingo, 18 de noviembre de 1883 --
conocido como el "día de dos mediodías" porque requirieron a la 
gente parar lo que ella hacía y reajustó sus relojes dondequiera a 
partir dos a treinta minutos -- era notable ordenado. Esta Nueva
York mide el tiempo articledescribed la escena en la ciudad más 
grande de la nación. Los leyes del local y del estado pronto 
ratificaron el nuevo estándar, pero tan tarde como 1915, desafíos 
del ciudadano al estándar de tiempo todavía era considerado por las 
cortes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087061</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107087</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-times-reports-on-the-day-of-two-noons</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
