<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107079</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107079</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086460</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Many Hundreds are Sterving for Want of Employment": John Harrower Leaves London for Virginia, 1774</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"viele Hunderte sind Sterving mangels 
Beschäftigung": John Harrower verläßt London für Virginia, 
1774</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"centaines sont Sterving pour veulent de l'emploi"
: John Harrower quitte Londres pour la Virginie, 1774</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"muitas centenas são Sterving para querem do 
emprego": John Harrower sae de Londres para Virgínia, 1774</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"molte centinaia sono Sterving per desiderano di 
occupazione": John Harrower lascia Londra per la Virginia, 1774</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πολλές εκατοντάδες είναι Sterving ελλείψει της 
απασχόλησησ": Θ*Ιοχν Harrower Leaves Λονδίνο για τη 
Βιρτζίνια, 1774</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"muchos centenares son Sterving para desean del 
empleo": Juan Harrower sale de Londres para Virginia, 1774</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Migration across the Atlantic often involved a series of stages, drawing people to London before they embarked on their journey. John Harrower, a 40-year-old shopkeeper and tradesman, lived in the far north of the British Isles. Like many of the 40,000 residents of the Scottish Highlands who left after 1760, he faced poverty and little opportunity. Harrower initially planned to travel to the Netherlands but ended up in London. The great metropolis, the largest in the western world, swelled as thousands looked unsuccessfully for employment. After several weeks, Harrower signed an indenture to travel to Virginia as a schoolmaster. He sailed with 71 other male indentees, some from London, but many others from across England and Ireland. With his relatively privileged training, Harrower was fortunate and found a new life on a tidewater plantation. These excerpts from his journal tell of his time in London, journey across the Atlantic, and arrival in Virginia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Migration über dem Atlantik bezog häufig eine 
Reihe Stadien mit ein und zeichnete Leute nach London, bevor sie auf 
ihrer Reise sich einschifften. John Harrower, ein Ladenbesitzer 
40-year-old und Händler, gelebt im weiten Norden der britischen
Inseln. Wie viele der 40.000 Bewohner der schottischen 
Hochländer, die nach 1760 verließen, stellte er Armut und wenig 
Gelegenheit gegenüber. Harrower zuerst plante, in die 
Niederlande zu reisen aber beendete oben in London. Die große 
Hauptstadt, das größte in der westlichen Welt, geschwollen als 
Tausenden schaute erfolglos nach Beschäftigung. Nach einigen 
Wochen unterzeichnete Harrower eine errichtete Urkunde, um zu Virginia
als Schoolmaster zu reisen. Er segelte mit 71 anderen 
männlichen indentees, einigem von London, aber vielen anderen über 
von England und von Irland. Mit seinem verhältnismäßig 
privilegierten Training war Harrower glücklich und fand eine neue 
Lebensdauer auf einer tidewater Plantage. Diese Excerpts von 
seinem Journal erklären von seiner Zeit in London, von der Reise 
über dem Atlantik und von der Ankunft in Virginia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le transfert à travers l'Océan atlantique a 
souvent impliqué une série d'étapes, dessinant des personnes à 
Londres avant qu'elles se soient embarquées sur leur voyage. 
John Harrower, un commerçant 40-year-old et marchand, vécus 
dans le nord lointain des îles britanniques. Comme plusieurs 
des 40.000 résidants des montagnes écossaises qui sont parties 
après 1760, il a fait face à la pauvreté et à peu d'occasion. 
Harrower a au commencement projeté voyager aux Pays Bas mais
a terminé vers le haut à Londres. La grande métropole, le 
plus grand au monde occidental, gonflé comme milliers a regardé sans
succès pour l'emploi. Après plusieurs semaines, Harrower a 
signé un contrat synallagmatique bilatéral pour voyager à la 
Virginie en tant que maître. Il a navigué avec 71 autres 
indentees mâles, certains de Londres, mais beaucoup d'autres à 
travers d'Angleterre et d'Irlande. Avec sa formation 
relativement privilégiée, Harrower était chanceux et a trouvé une 
nouvelle vie sur une plantation d'eau de marée. Ces extraits de 
son journal racontent son temps à Londres, voyage à travers l'Océan
atlantique, et arrivée en Virginie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A migração através do Atlântico envolveu 
frequentemente uma série dos estágios, desenhando povos a Londres 
antes que embarked em sua viagem. John Harrower, um shopkeeper 
40-year-old e tradesman, vividos no norte distante dos isles 
britânicos. Como muitos dos 40.000 residentes dos highlands 
scottish que sairam após 1760, enfrentou a pobreza e a pouca 
oportunidade. Harrower inicialmente planeou viajar aos Países 
Baixos mas terminou acima em Londres. O metropolis grande, o 
maior no mundo ocidental, inchado como milhares olhou em vão para o 
emprego. Após diversas semanas, Harrower assinou um indenture 
para viajar a Virgínia como um schoolmaster. Sailed com outros 
71 indentees masculinos, algum de Londres, mas muito outro através de
Inglaterra e de Ireland. Com seu treinamento relativamente 
privilegiado, Harrower era afortunado e encontrava uma vida nova em 
uma plantação do tidewater. Estes excerpts de seu jornal dizem
de seu tempo em Londres, de viagem através do Atlântico, e de 
chegada em Virgínia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'espansione attraverso l'Atlantico ha coinvolto 
spesso una serie di fasi, dissipante la gente a Londra prima che 
intraprendessero il loro viaggio. John Harrower, un commerciante
40-year-old e commerciante, vivi nell'estremo nord delle isole 
britanniche. Come molti dei 40.000 residenti degli altopiani 
scozzesi che hanno andato dopo 1760, ha affrontato la povertà e poca 
occasione. Harrower inizialmente ha progettato viaggiare nei 
Paesi Bassi ma si è concluso in su a Londra. Il metropolis 
grande, il più grande nel mondo occidentale, gonfiato come migliaia 
ha osservato senza successo per occupazione. Dopo parecchie 
settimane, Harrower ha firmato un indenture per viaggiare alla 
Virginia come schoolmaster. Ha navigato con altro 71 indentees 
maschio, alcuno da Londra, ma molti altri attraverso dall'Inghilterra 
e dall'Irlanda. Con il suo addestramento relativamente 
privilegiato, Harrower era fortunato ed ha trovato una nuova vita su 
una piantagione del tidewater. Questi brani dal suo giornale 
dicono a del suo tempo a Londra, del viaggio attraverso l'Atlantico e 
dell'arrivo nella Virginia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μετανάστευση πέρα από τον Ατλαντικό περιέλαβε 
συχνά μια σειρά σταδίων, σύροντας τους ανθρώπους στο Λονδίνο 
προτού να αρχίσουν το ταξίδι τους. Θ*Ιοχν Harrower, ένας 
40-χρονών καταστηματάρχης και ένας καταστηματάρχης, 
έζησαν μακριά βόρεια των βρετανικών νησιών. Όπως πολλούς 
από τους 40.000 κατοίκους των σκωτσέζικων ορεινών περιοχών που
έφυγαν μετά από 1760, αντιμετώπισε την ένδεια και λίγη 
ευκαιρία. Το Harrower προγραμμάτισε αρχικά να ταξιδεψει 
στις Κάτω Χώρες αλλά τελείωσε επάνω στο Λονδίνο. Η μεγάλη
μητρόπολη, ο μεγαλύτερος στο δυτικό κόσμο, που πρήστηκε ως 
χιλιάδες κοίταξε ανεπιτυχώς για την απασχόληση. Μετά από 
αρκετές εβδομάδες, Harrower υπέγραψε ένα indenture για να 
ταξιδεψει στη Βιρτζίνια ως schoolmaster. Έπλευσε με 71 
άλλα αρσενικά indentees, μερικούς από το Λονδίνο, αλλά 
πολλούς άλλους από σε ολόκληρη την Αγγλία και την Ιρλανδία. 
Με τη σχετικά προνομιούχο κατάρτισή του, Harrower ήταν 
τυχερό και βρήκε μια νέα ζωή σε μια tidewater φυτεία. 
Αυτά τα αποσπάσματα από το περιοδικό του λένε του χρόνου 
του στο Λονδίνο, το ταξίδι πέρα από τον Ατλαντικό, και την άφιξη
στη Βιρτζίνια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La migración a través del Atlántico implicó a 
menudo una serie de etapas, trazando a gente a Londres antes de que 
ella emprendiera su viaje. Juan Harrower, comerciante 
40-year-old y comerciante, vividos en el norte lejano de las islas 
británicas. Como muchos de los 40.000 residentes de las 
montañas escocesas que se fueron después de 1760, él hizo frente a 
pobreza y a poca oportunidad. Harrower planeó viajar a los 
Países Bajos pero terminó inicialmente para arriba en Londres. 
La gran metrópoli, el más grande del mundo occidental, 
hinchado como millares miraba sin éxito para el empleo. 
Después de varias semanas, Harrower firmó un contrato para 
viajar a Virginia como profesor. Él navegó con 71 otros 
indentees masculinos, algunos de Londres, pero muchos otros a través 
de Inglaterra y de Irlanda. Con su entrenamiento relativamente 
privilegiado, Harrower era afortunado y encontró una nueva vida en 
una plantación del tidewater. Estos extractos de su diario 
dicen de su tiempo en Londres, de viaje a través del Atlántico, y de
llegada en Virginia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086460</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107079</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/many-hundreds-are-sterving-for-want-of-employment-john-harrower-leaves-london-for-virginia-1774</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
