<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107838</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107838</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086306</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Will Not Be Influenced in Appointments": Al Smith Accepts the Nomination for President</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich werde nicht in den Verabredungen" 
beeinflußt: Al Smith nimmt die Nennung für Präsidenten an</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je ne serai pas influencé dans les rendez-vous" 
: Al Smith reçoit la nomination pour le président</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu não serei influenciado nas nomeações": 
O al Smith aceita o nomination para o presidente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non sarò influenzato negli appuntamenti": 
Al Smith accetta la nomina per il presidente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"δεν θα επηρεαστώ στους διορισμούσ": Το Al 
Smith αποδέχεται το διορισμό για τον Πρόεδρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"me no influenciarán en citas": El al Smith
valida el nombramiento para el presidente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Religion figured prominently in the 1928 presidential election when Alfred E. Smith, the Democratic governor of New York, became the first Catholic to run as the candidate of a major political party. Smith, who ran against the Republican Secretary of Commerce Herbert Hoover, tried to downplay the subject of his religion. In his speech accepting the presidential nomination, Smith sought to reassure voters that he would not favor Catholics, "Wets" (supporters of Prohibition), or Easterners if elected president. While his words may have reassured some, his obvious New York accent reinforced the worries--and prejudices--of others.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Religion stellte vorstehend in der 
Präsidentenwahl 1928 dar, als Alfred E. Smith, der demokratische 
Gouverneur von New York, der erste Katholische wurde, zum als der 
Anwärter einer politischen hauptsächlichPartei zu laufen. 
Smith, der gegen den republikanischen Minister fuer 
Handel-Herbert Staubsauger lief, versuchte, das Thema seiner Religion 
unterzutreiben. In seiner Rede, welche die Präsidentennennung 
annimmt, suchte Smith, Wählern zu versicheren, daß er nicht 
Katholische bevorzugen würde, "naßmacht" (Verfechter des Verbots) 
oder Ostländer wenn gewählter Präsident. Während seine 
Wörter einigem versichert haben können, verstärkte sein 
offensichtlicher New York Akzent sich sorgt -- und benachteiligt -- 
von anderen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La religion a figuré en évidence dans 
l'élection 1928 présidentielle quand Alfred E. Smith, le gouverneur 
démocratique de New York, est devenu le premier catholique à 
exécuter en tant que candidat d'une partie politique importante. 
Smith, qui a exécuté contre le secrétaire républicain de 
l'aspirateur d'Herbert de commerce, a essayé de réduire la valeur du
sujet de sa religion. Dans son discours recevant la nomination 
présidentielle, Smith a recherché à rassurer des électeurs qu'il 
ne favoriserait pas des catholiques, "mouille" (des défenseurs de 
prohibition), ou des orientaux si président élu. Tandis que 
ses mots ont pu en avoir rassuré, son accent évident de New York a 
renforcé s'inquiète -- et compromet -- de d'autres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A religião figurou proeminente na eleição 1928 
presidencial quando Alfred E. Smith, regulador democrático de New 
York, se transformou o primeiro catholic a funcionar como o candidato 
de um partido político principal. Smith, que funcionou de 
encontro à secretária republicana do hoover de Herbert do comércio,
tentou downplay o assunto de sua religião. Em seu discurso que 
aceita o nomination presidencial, Smith procurou tranquilizar 
eleitores que não favoreceria catholics, "molha" (supporters da 
proibição), ou easterners se presidente eleito. Quando suas 
palavras puderem ter tranquilizado algum, seu acento óbvio de New 
York reforçou preocupa-se -- e prejudica -- de outro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La religione ha calcolato prominente nell'elezione
presidenziale 1928 quando Alfred E. Smith, il regolatore democratico 
di New York, è diventato il primo cattolico da funzionare come il 
candidato di un partito politico importante. Smith, che ha 
funzionato contro la segretaria Repubblicana del hoover del Herbert di 
commercio, ha provato a downplay l'argomento di sua religione. 
Nel suo discorso che accetta la nomina presidenziale, Smith ha 
cercato di riassicurare gli elettori che non favorirebbe i cattolici, 
"bagna" (sostenitori della proibizione), o easterners se presidente 
scelto. Mentre le sue parole possono riassicurare alcuno, il suo
accento evidente de New York ha rinforzato si preoccupa -- e 
pregiudica -- di altri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η θρησκεία βρέθηκε κυρίως στην προεδρική εκλογή του 
1928 όταν ο Alfred E. Smith, ο δημοκρατικός κυβερνήτης 
της Νέας Υόρκης, έγινε πρώτος ο καθολικός για να τρέξει ως 
υποψήφιο ενός σημαντικού πολιτικού κόμματος. Θ*Σμητχ, που 
αντιτέθηκε το δημοκρατικό γραμματέα του εμπορίου Herbert 
Hoover, δοκίμασε σε downplay το θέμα της θρησκείας του. 
Στην ομιλία του που αποδέχεται τον προεδρικό διορισμό, 
Smith επιδίωξε να καθησυχάσει τους ψηφοφόρους ότι δεν θα 
ευνοούσε τους Καθολικούς, "βρέχει" (υποστηρικτές της 
απαγόρευσης), ή ανατολικοί εάν εκλεγμένος Πρόεδρος. Ενώ 
οι λέξεις του μπορεί να είχαν καθησυχάσει μερικές, η προφανής 
έμφαση της Νέας Υόρκης του ενίσχυσε τις ανησυχίες -- και τις 
προκαταλήψεις -- άλλες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La religión calculó prominente en la elección 
presidencial 1928 cuando Alfred E. Smith, el gobernador democrático 
de Nueva York, hizo el primer católico a ejecutarse como el candidato
de un partido político importante. Smith, que se ejecutó 
contra la secretaria republicana de la aspiradora de Herberto del 
comercio, intentó downplay el tema de su religión. En su 
discurso que validaba el nombramiento presidencial, Smith intentó 
tranquilizar a votantes que él no favorecería a católicos, "moja" 
(los partidarios de la prohibición), o los easterners si presidente 
elegido. Mientras que sus palabras pudieron haber tranquilizado 
alguno, su acento obvio de Nueva York reforzó se preocupa -- y 
perjudica -- de otros.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086306</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107838</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-will-not-be-influenced-in-appointments-al-smith-accepts-the-nomination-for-president</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
