<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104309</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104309</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207245</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Theodore Roosevelt Inaugural Site: Birthplace of the Modern Presidency</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Theodore Roosevelt Eröffnungssite: 
Geburtsort des modernen Vorsitzes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Site Inaugural de Theodore Roosevelt : Lieu 
de naissance de la présidence moderne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Local Inaugural De Theodore Roosevelt: 
Birthplace do presidency moderno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luogo Inaugurale Di Theodore Roosevelt: 
Luogo di nascita della presidenza moderna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εναρκτήρια περιοχή Roosevelt Theodore: 
Τόπος γεννήσεως της σύγχρονης προεδρίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sitio Inaugural De Theodore Roosevelt: Lugar
de nacimiento de la presidencia moderna</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Examines the career of our 26th President -- the conditions under which he became a vice presidential candidate, the assassination of President McKinley, the home where TR was hastily inaugurated in 1901, and the influence he exerted on the nation and the presidency. His inauguration marked a turning point in the role of the presidency, launching a change in national policy and propelling the U.S. into world affairs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überprüft die Karriere unseres 26. Präsidenten 
-- die Bedingungen, unter denen er ein Vizepräsidentenanwärter, die 
Ermordung des Präsidenten McKinley, das Haus, in dem TR eilig 1901 
eröffnet wurde und der Einfluß wurde, die, er auf der Nation und dem
Vorsitz anwendete. Seine Einweihung kennzeichnete einen 
Drehpunkt in der Rolle des Vorsitzes, stieß eine Änderung in der 
nationalen Politik aus und treibt die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN in 
Weltangelegenheiten an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Examine la carrière de notre 26ème président --
les conditions dans lesquelles il est devenu un candidat présidentiel
vice, l'assassinat du Président McKinley, la maison où le TR a été
inauguré à la hâte en 1901, et l'influence qu'il a exercée sur la 
nation et la présidence. Son inauguration a marqué un tournant
dans le rôle de la présidence, lançant un changement de la 
politique nationale et propulsant les ETATS-UNIS dans des affaires du 
monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Examina a carreira de nosso 2õ presidente -- as 
circunstâncias sob que se transformou um candidato presidencial vice,
o assassination do presidente McKinley, a HOME onde o TR inaugurated 
hastily em 1901, e a influência que exerceu na nação e no 
presidency. Seu inauguration marcou um ponto de giro no papel do
presidency, lançando uma mudança na política nacional e propelindo 
os ESTADOS UNIDOS em casos do mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esamina la carriera del nostro ventiseiesimo 
presidente -- le circostanze in cui si è transformato in in un 
candidato presidenziale vice, nell'assassinio del presidente 
McKinley, nella sede in cui il TR è stato inaugurato frettolosamente 
in 1901 e nell'influenza che ha impiegato sulla nazione e sulla 
presidenza. La sua inaugurazione ha contrassegnato una svolta 
nel ruolo della presidenza, lanciante un cambiamento nella politica 
nazionale ed azionante gli STATI UNITI negli affari del mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξετάζει τη σταδιοδρομία του 26$ου Προέδρου μας -- οι 
όροι κάτω από τους οποίους έγινε προεδρικός υποψήφιος κακίας, 
η δολοφονία του Προέδρου McKinley, το σπίτι όπου το TR 
εγκαινιάστηκε βιαστικά το 1901, και η επιρροή άσκησε στο έθνος
και την προεδρία. Η εγκαινίασή του χαρακτήρισε μια κρίσιμη 
καμπή στο ρόλο της προεδρίας, που προωθεί μια αλλαγή στην εθνική
πολιτική και που ωθεί τις ΗΠΑ στις παγκόσμιες υποθέσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Examina la carrera de nuestro vigésimo sexto 
presidente -- las condiciones bajo las cuales él hizo un vice 
candidato presidencial, el asesinato de presidente McKinley, el hogar 
en donde el TR fue inaugurado precipitado en 1901, y la influencia que
él ejerció en la nación y la presidencia. Su inauguración 
marcó un momento crucial en el papel de la presidencia, lanzando un 
cambio en la política nacional y propulsando los ESTADOS UNIDOS en 
asuntos del mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207245</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104309</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/theodore-roosevelt-inaugural-site-birthplace-of-the-modern-presidency</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
