<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108264</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108264</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207249</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Thomas Jefferson's Plan for the University of Virginia: Lessons from the Lawn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Thomas Jeffersons Plan für die Universität von 
Virginia: Lektionen vom Rasen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plan de Thomas Jefferson pour l'université de la 
Virginie : Leçons de la pelouse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Planta de Thomas Jefferson para a universidade de 
Virgínia: Lições do gramado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programma del Thomas Jefferson per l'università 
di Virginia: Lezioni dal prato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχέδιο του Thomas Jefferson's για το πανεπιστήμιο 
της Βιρτζίνια: Μαθήματα από το χορτοτάπητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plan de Thomas Jefferson para la universidad de 
Virginia: Lecciones del césped</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Tells the story of the creation of the University of Virginia. After serving as President, Jefferson continued advocating for a statewide system of education in Virginia, hoping to extend education beyond the elite to the common man. Although the Virginia legislature refused to fund a plan for primary and secondary education, when it approved funding in 1818 to establish a state university, Jefferson immediately drew architectural plans for his ideal university.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erklärt die Geschichte der Kreation der 
Universität von Virginia. Nach Umhüllung als Präsidenten, 
fuhr Jefferson fort, für ein Nationalsystem der Ausbildung in 
Virginia zu befürworten und hoffte, Ausbildung über der Auslese 
hinaus auf den gemeinen Mann auszudehnen. Obgleich die Virginia 
Gesetzgebung ablehnte, einen Plan für Primär- und 
Sekundärausbildung zu finanzieren, als sie die anerkannte 
Finanzierung 1818, zum einer Landesuniversität, Jefferson 
herzustellen sofort architektonische Pläne für seine ideale 
Universität zeichnete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dit l'histoire de la création de l'université de
la Virginie. Après la portion comme président, Jefferson a 
continué de préconiser pour un système par état d'éducation en 
Virginie, espérant étendre l'éducation au delà de l'élite à 
l'homme commun. Bien que la législature de la Virginie ait 
refusé de placer un plan pour l'éducation primaire et secondaire, 
quand elle placement approuvé en 1818 pour fonder une université de 
l'Etat, Jefferson a immédiatement tracé des plans architecturaux 
pour son université idéale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Diz a história da criação da universidade de 
Virgínia. Após o serving como o presidente, Jefferson 
continuou advogando para um sistema statewide da instrução em 
Virgínia, esperando estender a instrução além do elite ao homem 
comum. Embora a legislatura de Virgínia recusasse financiar uma
planta para a instrução preliminar e secundária, quando financiar 
aprovado em 1818 para estabelecer uma universidade de estado, 
Jefferson desenhou imediatamente plantas architectural para sua 
universidade ideal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dice alla storia della creazione dell'università 
di Virginia. Dopo il serving come presidente, Jefferson ha 
continuato a sostenere per un sistema in tutto lo stato di formazione 
nella Virginia, sperante di estendere la formazione oltre l'elite 
all'uomo comune. Anche se la legislatura della Virginia ha 
rifiutato di costituire un fondo per un programma per formazione 
primaria e secondaria, quando costituire un fondo per approvato in 
1818 per stabilire un'università di dichiarare, Jefferson 
immediatamente ha dissipato i programmi architettonici per la sua 
università ideale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λέει την ιστορία της δημιουργίας του πανεπιστημίου της
Βιρτζίνια. Μετά από να χρησιμεύσει ως ο Πρόεδρος, 
Jefferson συνέχισε για ένα εθνικό σύστημα της εκπαίδευσης στη 
Βιρτζίνια, ελπίζοντας να επεκτείνει την εκπαίδευση πέρα από την 
ελίτ στο κοινό άτομο. Αν και το νομοθετικό σώμα της 
Βιρτζίνια αρνήθηκε να χρηματοδοτήσει ένα σχέδιο για την 
πρωτοβάθμια και δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση, όταν ενέκρινε τη 
χρηματοδότηση το 1818 για να καθιερώσει ένα κρατικό 
πανεπιστήμιο, Jefferson έσυρε αμέσως τα αρχιτεκτονικά σχέδια 
για το ιδανικό πανεπιστήμιό του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuenta la historia de la creación de la 
universidad de Virginia. Después de la porción como 
presidente, Jefferson continuó abogando para un sistema estatal de la
educación en Virginia, esperando ampliar la educación más allá de 
la élite al hombre común. Aunque la legislatura de Virginia 
rechazó financiar un plan para la educación primaria y secundaria, 
cuando financiamiento aprobado en 1818 para establecer una universidad
de estado, Jefferson trazó inmediatamente los planes arquitectónicos
para su universidad ideal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207249</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108264</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/thomas-jeffersons-plan-for-the-university-of-virginia-lessons-from-the-lawn</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
