<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105095</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105095</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086462</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mark Twain Satirizes "A Telephonic Conversation"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kennzeichnen Sie Twain Satirizes "Ein 
Telephonisches Gespräch"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Marque Twain Satirise "Une Conversation 
Téléphonique"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Marque Twain Satirizes "Uma Conversação 
Telephonic"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Contrassegni Twain Satirizes "Una Conversazione 
Telefonica"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Μαρκ Twain σατιρίζει "μια τηλεφωνική συνομιλία"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Marque Twain Satirizes "Una Conversación 
Telefónica"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Alexander Graham Bell first exhibited his telephone at the Centennial Exposition in Philadelphia in 1876, but many people were initially dubious about the utility of Bell's invention. Nevertheless, by the mid-1890s, about 300,000 phones were in use and by World War I, the number reached 10.5 million. Learning to use this new device, Americans wondered what to say to start a telephone conversation. Bell's choice for an initial greeting was "Ahoy." Others argued for more formal greetings like "What is wanted?" or "Are you there?" In 1877, Thomas Alva Edison, the famous inventor who developed the first practical telephone transmitter, solved the problem by introducing "Hello!" as the standard English telephone greeting. The word had been around for a little while--Twain had even used it in  Tom Sawyer --but why Edison chose to use it is not known. Whatever the derivation, "hello" had become standard by 1880 when Mark Twain used it in this comic sketch, "A Telephonic Conversation."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alexander Graham Bell stellte zuerst sein Telefon 
an der hundertjährigen Ausstellung in Philadelphia 1876 aus, aber 
viele Leute waren zuerst über das Hilfsprogramm von Erfindung Bell 
zweifelhaft. Dennoch durch das mid-1890s, waren ungefähr 
300.000 Telefone im Gebrauch und durch den Ersten Weltkrieg, erreichte
die Zahl 10.5 Million. Erlernend, diese neue Einheit, Amerikaner
zu benutzen wunderte sich was zu sagen, ein Telefongespräch zu 
beginnen. Wahl Bell für einen Ausgangsgruß war "ahoi." 
Andere argumentierten für formalere Grüße, wie ", was wird 
gewünscht?" oder "sind Sie dort?" 1877 Thomas Alva 
Edison, der berühmte Erfinder, der den ersten praktischen 
Telefonübermittler entwickelte, gelöst dem Problem durch das 
Einführen "hallo!" als der englische Telefonstandardgruß. 
Das Wort war herum für wenig gewesen, während -- Twain hatte 
es sogar in Tom Sawyer verwendet -- aber, warum Edison beschloß zu 
verwenden, bekannt es nicht. Was auch immer die Ableitung, 
"hallo" bis zum 1880 Standard geworden war, als Markierung Twain sie 
in dieser komischen Skizze verwendete, "ein telephonisches Gespräch."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Alexandre Graham Bell a montré la première fois 
son téléphone à l'exposition centennale à Philadelphie en 1876, 
mais beaucoup de personnes étaient au commencement douteuses au sujet
de l'utilitaire de l'invention de Bell. Néanmoins, par le 
mid-1890s, environ 300.000 téléphones étaient en service et par la 
Première Guerre Mondiale, le nombre a atteint 10.5 millions. 
Apprenant à utiliser ce nouveau dispositif, Américains s'est 
demandé quoi dire de commencer une conversation téléphonique. 
Le choix de Bell pour une première salutation était "oh." 
D'autres ont plaidé pour des salutations plus formelles comme 
"ce qui est voulu?" ou "êtes vous là?" En 1877, Thomas 
Alva Edison, l'inventeur célèbre qui a développé le premier 
émetteur pratique de téléphone, résolu le problème par la 
présentation "bonjour!" comme salutation anglaise standard de 
téléphone. Le mot avait été autour pour tandis que -- Twain 
l'avait même utilisé dans Tom Sawyer -- mais pourquoi 
Edison a choisi d'utiliser on ne le connaît pas. Celui qui la 
dérivation, "bonjour" soit devenue standard d'ici 1880 où la marque 
Twain l'a utilisée dans ce croquis comique, "une conversation 
téléphonique."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alexander Graham Bell exibiu primeiramente seu 
telefone na exposição centennial em Filadélfia em 1876, mas muitos 
povos eram inicialmente dubious sobre a utilidade da invenção de 
Bell. Não obstante, pelo mid-1890s, aproximadamente 300.000 
telefones estavam no uso e pelo world.war.i, o número alcançou 10.5 
milhões. Aprendendo usar este dispositivo novo, americanos quis
saber o que dizer começar uma conversação de telefone. A 
escolha de Bell para um cumprimento inicial era "ahoy." Outros 
discutiram para uns cumprimentos mais formais como "o que é querido?"
ou "está você lá?" Em 1877, Thomas Alva Edison, 
inventor famoso que desenvolveu o primeiro transmissor prático do 
telefone, resolvido o problema introduzindo "hello!" como o 
cumprimento inglês padrão do telefone. A palavra tinha estado 
ao redor para um pouco quando -- Twain o tinha usado mesmo em Tom 
Sawyer -- mas porque Edison escolheu se usar não se sabe. O que
quer que a derivação, "hello" se tinha tornado padrão por 1880 em 
que a marca Twain a usou neste esboço comic, "uma conversação 
telephonic."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alexander Graham Bell in primo luogo ha esibito il 
suo telefono all'esposizione centennale a Filadelfia in 1876, ma molta
gente era inizialmente dubbia circa il programma di utilità 
dell'invenzione della Bell. Tuttavia, dal mid-1890s, circa 
300.000 telefoni erano in uso e dal world.war.i, il numero ha 
raggiunto 10.5 milioni. Imparando utilizzare questo nuovo 
dispositivo, Americani si è domandato che cosa dire iniziare una 
conversazione telefonica. La scelta della Bell per un saluto 
iniziale era "ahoy." Altri hanno parlato a favore dei saluti 
più convenzionali come "che cosa è desiderato?" o "siete là?"
In 1877, Thomas Alva Edison, l'inventore famoso che ha 
sviluppato il primo trasmettitore pratico del telefono, risolto il 
problema introducendo "ciao!" come il saluto inglese standard 
del telefono. La parola era stata intorno per un piccolo mentre 
-- Twain persino lo aveva usato in Tom Sawyer -- ma perchè Edison ha 
scelto usare non è conosciuto. Qualunque la derivazione, "ciao"
era diventato standard entro 1880 in cui il contrassegno Twain la ha 
usata in questo abbozzo comic, "una conversazione telefonica."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Αλέξανδρος Graham Bell εξέθεσε αρχικά το 
τηλέφωνό του στην εκατονταετή έκθεση στη Φιλαδέλφεια το 1876, 
αλλά πολλοί άνθρωποι ήταν αρχικά αμφίβολοι για το βοήθημα της 
εφεύρεσης του κουδουνιού. Εντούτοις, από τα μέσα της 
1890s, περίπου 300.000 τηλέφωνα ήταν σε χρήση και από τον 
παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, ο αριθμός έφθασε σε 10,5 εκατομμύρια. 
Η εκμάθηση να χρησιμοποιείται αυτή η νέα συσκευή, 
Αμερικανοί αναρωτήθηκε τι να πει για να αρχίσει μια τηλεφωνική 
συνομιλία. Η επιλογή του κουδουνιού για έναν αρχικό 
χαιρετισμό ήταν "Ahoy." Αλλοι υποστήριξαν τους πιό 
επίσημους χαιρετισμούς όπως "τι είναι επιθυμητό;" ή 
"είναι εσείς εκεί;" Το 1877, ο Thomas Alva 
Edison, ο διάσημος εφευρέτης που ανέπτυξε την πρώτη πρακτική 
τηλεφωνική συσκευή αποστολής σημάτων, έλυσε το πρόβλημα με την 
εισαγωγή "γειάσοϋ" σαν πρότυπο αγγλικό τηλεφωνικό 
χαιρετισμό. Η λέξη ήταν γύρω για λίγο ενώ -- Twain την 
είχε χρησιμοποιήσει ακόμη και στον Tom Sawyer -- αλλά γιατί
ο Edison επέλεξε να χρησιμοποιήσει αυτό δεν είναι γνωστός. 
Οποιοσδήποτε η παραγωγή, "γειάσου" είχε γίνει πρότυπος 
από 1880 όταν το χρησιμοποίησε Mark Twain σε αυτό το 
κωμικό σκίτσο, "μια τηλεφωνική συνομιλία."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alexander Graham Bell primero exhibió su teléfono
en la exposición centenaria en Philadelphia en 1876, pero mucha gente
era inicialmente dudosa sobre el utilitario de la invención de Bell. 
Sin embargo, por el mid-1890s, cerca de 300.000 teléfonos 
estaban en uso y por Primera Guerra Mundial, el número alcanzó 10.5 
millones. Aprendiendo utilizar este nuevo dispositivo, 
americanos preguntaba qué decir comenzar una conversación de 
teléfono. La opción de Bell para un saludo inicial era "ahoy."
Otros discutieron para saludos más formales como "se desea 
qué?" o "está usted allí?" En 1877, Thomas Alva Edison,
el inventor famoso que desarrolló el primer transmisor práctico del 
teléfono, solucionado el problema introduciendo "hola!" como el
saludo inglés estándar del teléfono. La palabra había estado
alrededor para un poco mientras que -- Twain incluso lo había 
utilizado en Tom Sawyer -- pero porqué Edison eligió utilizar no se 
sabe. Lo que la derivación, "hola" había llegado a ser 
estándar antes de 1880 en que la marca Twain la utilizó en este 
bosquejo cómico, "una conversación telefónica."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086462</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105095</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/mark-twain-satirizes-a-telephonic-conversation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
