<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106258</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106258</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086319</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I'm Not Afraid of the A-Bomb": An Army Captain Tries to Dispel Fears about Radioactivity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich habe nicht vor der Ein-Bombe" Angst: 
Ein Armee-Kapitän Tries, Furcht über Radioaktivität zu 
zerstreuen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je n'ai pas peur de l'Un-Panne" : Un 
capitaine Tries d'armée de dissiper des craintes au sujet de la 
radioactivité</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu não estou receoso da Um-Bomba": Um 
capitão Tentar do exército dispel medos sobre o radioactivity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non sono impaurito della Un-Bomba": Un 
capitano Tries dell'esercito a dissipare i timori circa 
radioattività</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"δεν φοβάμαι την α-βόμβα": Ένας στρατός 
καπετάνιος Tries να διαλυθούν οι φόβοι για τη ραδιενέργεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no estoy asustado de la Uno-Bomba": Un 
capitán Tries del ejército disipar miedos sobre radiactividad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On July 1, 1946, less than a year after dropping atom bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki to end World War II, the U.S. embarked on its first postwar atomic weapons test at the Bikini Atoll in the Marshall Islands. David Bradley, a physician and member of the Radiological Safety Unit at Bikini, voiced concern over dangers from radioactivity in his 1948 best-seller,  No Place to Hide . In response to Bradley and other critics, the Atomic Energy Commission, the military, and other government agencies attempted to diffuse growing fears about radioactivity. The following  Collier's  article by a military officer--using the same eyewitness-account format as in Bradley's book--tried to persuade its readers that fears about "lingering radiation" were unfounded by documenting a test in the Nevada desert in which the military deliberately sent soldiers close to "ground zero" soon after an explosion. Some readers remained unconvinced; their published letters can be found following the article. In 1963, the U.S. and Soviet Union signed a treaty to halt atmospheric tests of nuclear weapons. By that time, some 300,000 U.S. military personnel and an unknown number of civilians in areas downwind from the test sites had been exposed to radiation. In subsequent years, studies revealed higher rates of leukemia, cancer, respiratory ailments, and other health problems among these groups. Underground atomic weapons tests continued at the Nevada Test Site until a moratorium was declared in 1992, after 928 nuclear tests.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An Juli 1, 1946, kleiner als ein Jahr, nachdem 
Atombomben auf Hiroschima und Nagasaki fallengelassen worden sind, um 
den Zweiten Weltkrieg zu beenden, die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, die auf 
seinem ersten Nachkriegsatomwaffetest am Bikini Atoll in den 
Marschall-Inseln eingeschifft werden. David Bradley, ein Arzt 
und Bauteil der radiologischen Sicherheit Maßeinheit am Bikini, 
geäußertes Interesse über Gefahren von der Radioaktivität in 
seinem 1948 Bestseller, kein Platz zum sich zu verstecken. In 
Erwiderung auf Bradley und andere Kritiker, die 
Atomenergie-Kommission, das Militär und andere Regierungsagenturen 
versucht, um wachsende Furcht über Radioaktivität zu zerstreuen. 
Der folgenden Artikel des Colliers durch einen militärischen 
Offizier -- mit gleichen Augenzeuge-berechnen Sie Format wie im Buch 
Bradleys -- versucht, um seine Leser zu überzeugen, daß Furcht über
"verweilende Strahlung" unbegründet war, indem sie einen Test in der 
Nevada Wüste dokumentierten, in der das Militär absichtlich Soldaten
nah an "Boden null" bald nach einer Explosion sendete. Einige 
Leser blieben unconvinced; ihre erschienenen Briefe können nach
dem Artikel gefunden werden. 1963 unterzeichneten die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und der Sowjet-Anschluß einen Vertrag, um 
atmosphärische Tests der Kernwaffen anzuhalten. Bis zum dieser 
Zeit waren etwas 300.000 VEREINIGTE STAATEN militärisches Personal 
und eine unbekannte Anzahl von Zivilisten in den Bereichen in 
Windrichtung von den Testsites Strahlung ausgesetzt worden. In 
den folgenden Jahren deckten Studien höhere Kinetik der Leukämie, 
des Krebses, der Atmungsunpäßlichkeiten und anderer Gesundheit 
Probleme unter diesen Gruppen auf. Unterirdische Atomwaffetests 
fuhren an der Nevada Test-Site, bis ein Moratorium 1992 erklärt war, 
nach 928 Kerntests fort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">1 juillet 1946, moins qu'une année après la 
baisse des bombes atomiques sur Hiroshima et Nagasaki pour terminer la
deuxième guerre mondiale, les ETATS-UNIS embarqués sur son premier 
essai d'après-guerre d'armes atomiques à l'Atoll de bikini en
Îles Marshall. David Bradley, un médecin et membre de 
l'unité radiologique de sûreté au bikini, souci exprimé au-dessus 
des dangers de la radioactivité en son 1948 best-seller, aucun 
endroit à cacher. En réponse à Bradley et d'autres 
critiques, la Commission d'énergie atomique, les militaires, et 
d'autres organismes gouvernementaux essayés pour répandre des 
craintes croissantes au sujet de la radioactivité. L'article 
suivant de Collier par un officier militaire -- en utilisant la 
même chose témoin-rendez compte format comme en livre de Bradley
-- jugé pour persuader ses lecteurs que les craintes au sujet "du 
rayonnement prolongé" étaient non fondées en documentant un essai 
dans le désert du Nevada dans lequel les militaires ont 
délibérément envoyé des soldats près de la "terre zéro" peu 
après une explosion. Quelques lecteurs sont restés unconvinced
; leurs lettres éditées peuvent être trouvées après 
l'article. En 1963, les ETATS-UNIS et Union Soviétique ont signé un
traité pour stopper les essais atmosphériques des armes nucléaires.
À ce moment-là, environ 300.000 personnels militaires des 
ETATS-UNIS et un nombre inconnu de civils dans les zones vent arrière
des sites d'essai avaient été exposés au rayonnement. En 
années ultérieures, les études ont indiqué des cadences plus 
élevées de leucémie, de cancer, de maux respiratoires, et d'autres 
problèmes de santé parmi ces groupes. Les essais souterrains 
d'armes atomiques ont continué au site d'essai du Nevada jusqu'à ce 
qu'un moratoire ait été déclaré en 1992, après 928 essais 
nucléaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em julho 1, 1946, menos do que um ano após ter 
deixado cair bombas de átomo em Hiroshima e em Nagasaki para terminar
a segunda guerra mundial, os ESTADOS UNIDOS embarked em seu primeiro 
teste postwar das armas atômicas no bikini Atoll nos consoles de 
marshall. David Bradley, um médico e membro da unidade 
radiological no bikini, interesse expresso de segurança sobre perigos
do radioactivity em seu 1948 bestseller, nenhum lugar a esconder. 
Em resposta a Bradley e outros críticos, o commission de 
energia atômica, as forças armadas, e outras agências de governo 
tentadas difundir medos crescentes sobre o radioactivity. O 
artigo do seguinte collier por um oficial militar -- usando o mesmo 
testemunha-explique formato como no livro de Bradley -- tentado 
persuadir seus leitores que os medos sobre "radiação lingering" eram
unfounded documentando um teste no deserto de Nevada em que as forças
armadas emitiram deliberadamente soldados perto da "terra zero" logo 
após uma explosão. Alguns leitores remanesceram unconvinced; 
suas letras publicadas podem ser encontradas depois do artigo. 
Em 1963, os ESTADOS UNIDOS e a Soviete-união assinaram um 
tratado para parar testes atmosféricos de armas nucleares. Por 
esse tempo, um 300.000 pessoais militares de ESTADOS UNIDOS e um 
número desconhecido dos civis nas áreas downwind dos locais de teste
tinham sido expostos à radiação. Em anos subseqüentes, os 
estudos revelaram umas taxas mais elevadas do leukemia, do cancer, de 
ailments respiratory, e de outros problemas de saúde entre estes 
grupos. Os testes subterrâneos das armas atômicas continuaram 
no local de teste de Nevada até que um moratorium estêve declarado 
em 1992, após 928 testes nucleares.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luglio 1, 1946, su di meno che un anno dopo avere 
caduto le bombe atomiche su Hiroshima e su Nagasaki per concludere la 
seconda guerra mondiale, gli STATI UNITI intrapresi la relativa prima 
prova dopoguerra delle armi atomiche al bikini Atoll nelle isole di 
marshall. David Bradley, un medico e membro dell'unità 
radiologica al bikini, preoccupazione espressa di sicurezza sopra i 
pericoli da radioattività in suo 1948 best-seller, nessun posto da 
nascondersi. In risposta a Bradley ed altri critici, la 
Commissione di energia atomica, i militari ed altri enti governativi 
tentati per diffondere i timori crescenti circa radioattività. 
L'articolo del seguente collier da un ufficiale militare -- 
usando lo stesso testimone-spieghi formato come in libro del Bradley 
-- provato per persaudere i relativi lettori che i timori circa 
"radiazione prolungata" erano non fondati documentando una prova nel 
deserto del Nevada in cui i militari hanno trasmesso deliberatamente i
soldati vicino "a terra zero" presto dopo un'esplosione. Alcuni 
lettori sono rimasto unconvinced; le loro lettere pubblicate 
possono essere trovate dopo l'articolo. In 1963, gli STATI UNITI
e l'Soviet-unione hanno firmato un trattato per fermare le prove 
atmosferiche delle armi nucleari. A quel punto, circa 300.000 
personali militari degli STATI UNITI e un numero sconosciuto di civili
nelle zone sottovento dai luoghi di prova erano stati esposti a 
radiazione. Durante gli anni successivi, gli studi hanno 
rivelato gli più alti tassi della leucemia, del cancro, dei ailments 
respiratori e di altri problemi di salute fra questi gruppi. Le 
prove sotterranee delle armi atomiche sono continuato al luogo di 
prova del Nevada fino a dichiarare una moratoria in 1992, dopo 928 
prove nucleari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Ιούλιο 1 ..1946, λιγότερο από στις έτ μετά 
από να ρίξουν τις βόμβες ατόμων στη Χιροσίμα και το Ναγκασάκι 
για να τελειώσουν τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ, οι ΗΠΑ άρχισαν την 
πρώτη μεταπολεμική δοκιμή ατομικών όπλων της στη bikini 
ατόλλη στα Marshall νησιά. Ο Δαβίδ Bradley, ένας 
παθολόγος και ένα μέλος της ραδιολογικής μονάδας ασφάλειας 
bikini, εξέφρασαν την ανησυχία σχετικά με τους κινδύνους από 
τη ραδιενέργεια στο best-$l*seller του 1948 του, καμία θέση 
που κρύβει. Σε απάντηση σε Bradley και άλλους κριτικούς, 
η Επιτροπή ατομικής ενέργειας, οι στρατιωτικές, και άλλες 
κυβερνητικές αντιπροσωπείες προσπάθησαν να διασκορπίσουν τους 
αυξανόμενους φόβους για τη ραδιενέργεια. Το άρθρο του 
ακόλουθου ανθρακωρύχου από έναν στρατιωτικό ανώτερο υπάλληλο --
που χρησιμοποιεί την ίδια μορφή αυτόπτης-απολογισμού όπως στο 
βιβλίο Bradley -- προσπάθησε να πείσει τους αναγνώστες του ότι
οι φόβοι για τη "παρατεταμένη ακτινοβολία" ήταν αβάσιμοι με την 
τεκμηρίωση μιας δοκιμής στην έρημο της Νεβάδας στην οποία οι 
στρατιωτικοί σκόπιμα σταλμένοι στρατιώτες κοντά "στο έδαφος 
μηδέν" σύντομα μετά από μια έκρηξη. Μερικοί αναγνώστες 
παρέμειναν μη πεπεισμένοι  οι δημοσιευμένες επιστολές τους 
μπορούν να βρεθούν μετά από το άρθρο. Το 1963, οι ΗΠΑ 
και η Σοβιετική Ένωση υπέγραψαν μια συνθήκη για να σταματήσουν 
τις ατμοσφαιρικές δοκιμές των πυρηνικών όπλων. Έως τότε, 
περίπου 300.000 ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ στρατιωτικό προσωπικό και ένας 
άγνωστος αριθμός πολιτών στις περιοχές downwind από τις 
περιοχές δοκιμής είχαν εκτεθεί στην ακτινοβολία. Στα 
επόμενα έτη, οι μελέτες αποκάλυψαν υψηλότερα ποσοστά 
λευχαιμίας, καρκίνου, αναπνευστικών ασθενειών, και άλλων 
προβλημάτων υγείας μεταξύ αυτών των ομάδων. Οι υπόγειες 
δοκιμές ατομικών όπλων συνεχίστηκαν επί του τόπου δοκιμής της 
Νεβάδας έως ότου δηλώθηκε μια ανάπαυλα το 1992, μετά από 
928 πυρηνικές δοκιμές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De julio el 1, 1946, menos que un año después de
caer bombas atómicas en Hiroshima y Nagasaki para terminar la Segunda
Guerra Mundial, los ESTADOS UNIDOS emprendidos su primera prueba de la
posguerra de las armas atómicas en el bikiní Atoll en las islas de 
ordenar. David Bradley, médico y miembro de la unidad 
radiológica en el bikiní, preocupación expresada de seguridad por 
peligros de la radiactividad en su 1948 bestseller, ningún lugar a 
ocultar. En respuesta a Bradley y otros críticos, la Comisión 
de energía atómica, los militares, y otras agencias de estatal 
procuradas para difundir miedos cada vez mayor sobre radiactividad. 
El artículo del collier siguiente de un oficial militar -- con 
el mismo testigo-considere formato como en el libro de Bradley -- 
intentado para persuadir a sus programas de lectura que los miedos 
sobre la "radiación persistente" eran infundados documentando una 
prueba en el desierto de Nevada en el cual los militares enviaron 
deliberadamente a soldados cerca de la "tierra cero" pronto después 
de una explosión. Algunos programas de lectura permanecían 
unconvinced; sus cartas publicadas se pueden encontrar después 
del artículo. En 1963, los ESTADOS UNIDOS y la Soviet-unio'n 
firmaron un tratado para parar las pruebas atmosféricas de armas 
nucleares. Para ese punto, habían expuesto a uno 300.000 
personal militar de ESTADOS UNIDOS y un número desconocido de civiles
en áreas viento abajo de los sitios de prueba a la radiación. 
En años subsecuentes, los estudios revelaron índices más 
altos de la leucemia, del cáncer, de las dolencias respiratorias, y 
de otros problemas de salud entre estos grupos. Las pruebas 
subterráneas de las armas atómicas continuaron en el sitio de prueba
de Nevada hasta que una moratoria fue declarada en 1992, después de 
928 pruebas nucleares.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086319</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106258</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/im-not-afraid-of-the-a-bomb-an-army-captain-tries-to-dispel-fears-about-radioactivity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
