<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104096</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104096</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209912</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Quadratic curve and graph display</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Quadratische Kurve und Diagrammbildschirmanzeige</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Affichage quadratique de courbe et de graphique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Indicador quadrático da curva e do gráfico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Visualizzazione quadratica del grafico e della 
curva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δευτέρου βαθμού παρουσίαση καμπυλών και γραφικών 
παραστάσεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Visualización cuadrática de la curva y del 
gráfico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet that allows the user to graphically explore the properties of a quadratic equation. Specifically, it is designed to foster an intuitive understanding of the effects of changing the three coefficients in the function. The applet shows a large graph of a quadratic (ax^2 + bx +c) and has three slider controls, one each for the coefficients a,b and c. As the sliders are moved, the graph is redrawn in real time illustrating the effects of these variations. The roots of the equation are shown both graphically and numerically, including the case where the roots are imaginary. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet, der dem Benutzer erlaubt,
die Eigenschaften einer quadratischen Gleichung graphisch zu 
erforschen. Spezifisch ist er konzipiert, um ein intuitives 
Verständnis der Effekte des Änderns der drei Koeffizienten in der 
Funktion zu fördern. Der applet zeigt ein großes Diagramm 
einer quadratischen Gleichung (ax^2 + bx +c) und hat drei 
Schweberkontrollen, eine je für die Koeffizienten a,b und c. Da
die Schweber verschoben werden, ist das Diagramm redrawn in der 
Istzeit, welche die Effekte dieser Varianten veranschaulicht. 
Die Wurzeln der Gleichung werden graphisch und numerisch, 
einschließlich den Fall gezeigt, in dem die Wurzeln eingebildet sind.
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif qui permet à l'utilisateur 
d'explorer graphiquement les propriétés d'une équation quadratique.
Spécifiquement, il est conçu pour stimuler un arrangement 
intuitif des effets de changer les trois coefficients dans la 
fonction. L'applet montre un grand graphique d'une équation 
quadratique (ax^2 + bx +c) et a trois commandes de glisseur, une  pour
les coefficients a,b et c. Car les glisseurs sont déplacés, le
graphique est redrawn en temps réel illustrant les effets de ces 
variations. Les racines de l'équation sont montrées 
graphiquement et numériquement, y compris le cas où les racines sont
imaginaires. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein 
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo que permita que o usuário 
explore gràfica as propriedades de uma equação quadrática. 
Especificamente, é projetado promover uma compreensão 
intuitive dos efeitos de mudar os três coeficientes na função. 
O applet mostra um gráfico grande de uma equação quadrática 
(ax^2 + bx +c) e tem três controles do slider, um cada para os 
coeficientes a,b e c. Porque os sliders são movidos, o gráfico
é redrawn no tempo real que ilustra os efeitos destas variações. 
As raizes da equação são mostradas  gràfica e numericamente,
including o caso onde as raizes são imaginárias. O applet pode
ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da 
sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode 
alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca 
com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um 
componente do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da 
referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo che permette che l'utente 
esplori graficamente le proprietà di un'equazione quadratica. 
Specificamente, è destinato per promuovere una comprensione 
intuitiva degli effetti di cambiare i tre coefficenti nella funzione. 
Il applet mostra un grande grafico di un'espressione quadratica 
(ax^2 + bx +c) ed ha tre comandi del cursore, uno ciascuno per i 
coefficenti a,b e c. Poichè i cursori sono spostati, il grafico
è redrawn in tempo reale che illustra gli effetti di queste 
variazioni. Le radici dell'equazione sono indicate graficamente 
che numericamente sia, compreso il caso dove le radici sono 
immaginarie. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di 
schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet που επιτρέπει στο χρήστη για 
να ερευνήσει γραφικά τις ιδιότητες μιας δευτέρου βαθμού 
εξίσωσης. Συγκεκριμένα, έχει ως σκοπό να ενθαρρύνει μια 
διαισθητική κατανόηση των αποτελεσμάτων της αλλαγής των τριών 
συντελεστών στη λειτουργία. Το applet εμφανίζει μεγάλη 
γραφική παράσταση μιας εξίσωσης δευτέρου βαθμού (ax^2 + bx 
+ γ) και έχει τους τρεις ελέγχους ολισθαινόντων ρυθμιστών, ένας 
κάθε για τους συντελεστές a,b και γ. Καθώς οι 
ολισθαίνοντες ρυθμιστές κινούνται, η γραφική παράσταση 
αποσύρεται στον πραγματικό χρόνο που επεξηγεί τα αποτελέσματα 
αυτών των παραλλαγών. Οι ρίζες της εξίσωσης εμφανίζονται 
και γραφικά και αριθμητικά, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της περίπτωσης 
όπου οι ρίζες είναι φανταστικές. Το Applet μπορεί να 
διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo que permite que el 
utilizador explore gráficamente las características de una ecuación
cuadrática. Específicamente, se diseña para fomentar una 
comprensión intuitiva de los efectos de cambiar los tres coeficientes
en la función. El applet muestra un gráfico grande de una 
ecuación cuadrática (ax^2 + el bx +c) y tiene tres controles del 
resbalador, uno por cada uno para los coeficientes a,b y c. Pues
se mueven los resbaladores, el gráfico es redrawn en el tiempo real 
que ilustra los efectos de estas variaciones. Las raíces de la 
ecuación se muestran gráficamente y numéricamente, incluyendo el 
caso donde están imaginarias las raíces. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209912</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104096</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/quadratic-curve-and-graph-display</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
