<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104189</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104189</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205580</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Kings and Queens of England</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Könige und die Königinnen von England</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les rois et les reines de l'Angleterre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os reis e as rainhas de Inglaterra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I re e le regine dell'Inghilterra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι βασιλιάδες και οι βασίλισσες της Αγγλίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los reyes y las reinas de Inglaterra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This module will enable you to learn the the historical sequence of the English Monarchs, their reigning dates, the royal house they belonged to (Plantangenet, Tudor, Hanover etc) and recognise a portrait of each one. The module is designed to be repeated, allowing you to build up knowledge of the subject with each cycle. The questions are generated randomly so will be different each time you run a test. There are information screens at the start of each test which outline the area of knowledge covered. The tests are divided into 3 groups to facilitate learning: Group 1 (Test 1) : Concentrates on understanding the different periods of history, when each period lasted and roughly which monarchs ruled during which one. Group 2 (Tests 2,3,4,5): These each specialise in one particular period of history and allow a more detailed build up of knowledge of the monarchs and dates for that period. Group 3 (Test 6): This is a general test that covers the whole period of English monarchy and combines the experience gained in the previous tests to see how well you can link monarchs and their dates. The module is suitable for anyone from 10 yrs upwards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Modul aktiviert Sie, die historische 
Reihenfolge der englischen Monarchen, ihre regierenden Daten, das 
königliche Haus zu erlernen, das sie (Plantangenet, Tudor, Hanover 
usw.) gehörten und ein Portrait von jedem erkennen. Das Modul 
ist konzipiert wiederholt zu werden und erlaubt Ihnen, Wissen des 
Themas mit jeder Schleife aufzubauen. Die Fragen werden 
festgelegt, nach dem zufall also werden jede Zeit unterschiedlich 
sein, die Sie einen Test laufen lassen. Es gibt Informationen 
Bildschirme beim Anfang jedes Tests, die den Wissensbereich umfaßt 
umreißen. Die Tests werden in 3 Gruppen geteilt, um zu erlernen
zu erleichtern: Gruppe 1 (Test 1): Konzentriert sich auf 
das Verstehen der unterschiedlichen Perioden der Geschichte, wenn jede
gedauerte Periode und ungefähr, die Monarchen anordneten während, 
welches einer. Gruppe 2 (Tests 2.3.4.5): Dieses jedes 
spezialisieren sich auf eine bestimmte Periode der Geschichte und 
erlauben einen ausführlicheren Aufbau des Wissens der Monarchen und 
der Daten während dieser Periode. Gruppe 3 (Test 6): 
Dieses ist ein allgemeiner Test, der die vollständige Periode 
der englischen Monarchie umfaßt und die Erfahrung kombiniert, 
die in den vorausgegangenen Tests gewonnen wird, um zu sehen, daß wie
gut Sie Monarchen und ihre Daten binden können. Das Modul ist 
für jedermann von 10 Jahren aufwärts verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module vous permettra d'apprendre le l'ordre 
historique des monarques anglais, leurs dates régnantes, la maison 
royale qu'ils ont appartenue à (Plantangenet, Tudor, Hannovre etc..) 
et identifient une verticale de chacun. Le module est conçu 
pour être répété, vous permettant d'accumuler la connaissance du 
sujet avec chaque cycle. Les questions sont produites 
aléatoirement ainsi seront différentes chaque fois que vous 
exécutez un essai. Il y a des écrans de l'information au 
début de chaque essai qui tracent les grandes lignes du domaine de la
connaissance couvert. Les essais sont divisés en 3 groupes pour
faciliter l'étude : Groupe 1 (Essai 1) : Se concentre sur
l'arrangement les différentes périodes de l'histoire, quand chaque 
période durée et rudement que les monarques ont régnée pendant le 
quel un. Groupe 2 (Essais 2.3.4.5) : Ce chacun se 
spécialise dans une période particulière de l'histoire et permet 
une accumulation plus détaillée de la connaissance des monarques et 
des dates pour cette période. Groupe 3 (Essai 6) : C'est 
un essai général qui couvre toute la période de monarchie anglaise 
et combine l'expérience acquise dans les essais précédents pour 
voir qu'à quel point vous pouvez joindre des monarques et leurs 
dates. Le module convient à n'importe qui de 10 ans 
d'ascendant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo permiti-lo-á de aprender o a 
seqüência histórica dos monarchs ingleses, suas datas reinando, a 
casa que real pertenceram a (Plantangenet, Tudor, Hanover etc.) e 
reconhecem um retrato de cada. O módulo é projetado ser 
repetido, permitindo que você construa acima do conhecimento do 
assunto com cada ciclo. As perguntas estão geradas aleatòria 
assim que serão diferentes cada vez que você funciona um teste. 
Há as telas da informação no início de cada teste que 
esboçam a área de conhecimento coberta. Os testes são 
divididos em 3 grupos para facilitar aprender: Grupo 1 (Teste 
1): Concentrar em compreender os períodos diferentes do 
history, quando cada período durado e aproximadamente que os monarchs
governaram durante qual um. Grupo 2 (Testes 2.3.4.5): Este
cada um especializa-se em um período particular do history e 
permite-se uma configuração mais detalhada acima do conhecimento dos
monarchs e das datas para esse período. Grupo 3 (Teste 6): 
Este é um teste geral que cubra o período inteiro do monarchy 
inglês e combine a experiência ganha nos testes precedentes para ver
como bom você pode ligar monarchs e suas datas. O módulo é 
apropriado para qualquer um de 10 anos ascendente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo vi permetterà di imparare la 
sequenza storica dei monarchi inglesi, le loro date di regno, la casa 
che reale hanno appartenuto a (Plantangenet, Tudor, Hannover ecc) e 
che riconoscono un ritratto di ogni. Il modulo è destinato 
per essere ripetuto, permettendo che sviluppiate la conoscenza 
dell'oggetto con ogni ciclo. Le domande sono generate a caso in 
modo da saranno differenti ogni volta fate funzionare una prova. 
Ci sono schermi delle informazioni all'inizio di ogni prova che 
descrivono la zona di conoscenza coperta. Le prove sono divise 
in 3 gruppi per facilitare imparare: Gruppo 1 (Prova 1): 
Si concentra sul capire i periodi differenti di storia, quando 
ogni periodo durato ed approssimativamente che i monarchi hanno 
regolato durante quale. Gruppo 2 (Prove 2.3.4.5): Questo 
ciascuno si specializza in un periodo particolare di storia e permette
un'accumulazione più dettagliata di conoscenza dei monarchi e delle 
date per quel periodo. Gruppo 3 (Prova 6): Ciò è una 
prova generale che riguarda il periodo intero di monarchy inglese e 
che unisce l'esperienza guadagnata nelle prove precedenti per vedere 
che come potete collegare i monarchi e le loro date. Il modulo 
è adatto a chiunque ascendente da 10 anni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα θα επιτρέψει σε σας για να μάθει την 
ιστορική ακολουθία των αγγλικών μοναρχών, οι βασιλεύοντας 
ημερομηνίες τους, το βασιλικό σπίτι που άνηκαν (Plantangenet, 
Tudor, Αννόβερο κ.λπ...) και αναγνωρίζουν ένα πορτρέτο καθένα.
Η ενότητα έχει ως σκοπό να επαναληφθεί, επιτρέποντας σε σας
για να ενισχύσει τη γνώση του θέματος με κάθε κύκλο. Οι 
ερωτήσεις παράγονται τυχαία έτσι θα είναι διαφορετικές κάθε 
φορά που τρέχετε μια δοκιμή. Υπάρχουν οθόνες πληροφοριών 
στην έναρξη κάθε δοκιμής που περιγράφουν τον τομέα της γνώσης 
που καλύπτεται. Οι δοκιμές διαιρούνται σε 3 ομάδες για να 
διευκολύνουν την εκμάθηση: Ομάδα 1 (δοκιμή 1): 
επικεντρώνεται στην κατανόηση των διαφορετικών περιόδων ιστορίας,
όταν διάρκεσε κάθε περίοδος και που κατά προσέγγιση οι μονάρχες
κυβέρνησαν κατά τη διάρκεια ποιου ενός. Ομάδα 2 (δοκιμές 
2,3,4,5): αυτή η κάθε μια ειδικεύεται σε μια ιδιαίτερη περίοδο
ιστορίας και επιτρέπει μια πιό λεπτομερή συγκέντρωση της γνώσης 
των μοναρχών και των ημερομηνιών για εκείνη την περίοδο. 
Ομάδα 3 (δοκιμή 6): αυτό είναι μια γενική δοκιμή που 
καλύπτει ολόκληρη την περίοδο αγγλικής μοναρχίας και συνδυάζει 
την εμπειρία που αποκτιέται στις προηγούμενες δοκιμές που 
βλέπουνε πόσο καλά μπορείτε να συνδέσετε τους μονάρχες και
τις ημερομηνίες τους. Η ενότητα είναι κατάλληλη για καθεμία
από 10 yrs προς τα πάνω.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo le permitirá aprender el secuencia 
histórica de los monarcas ingleses, sus fechas reinantes, la casa 
real que pertenecieron a (Plantangenet, Tudor, Hannover etc) y que 
reconocen un retrato de cada. El módulo se diseña para ser 
relanzado, permitiendo que usted acumule el conocimiento del tema con 
cada ciclo. Las preguntas se generan aleatoriamente así que 
serán diferentes cada vez que usted ejecuta una prueba. Hay las
pantallas de la información en el comienzo de cada prueba que 
contornean el área del conocimiento cubierta. Las pruebas se 
dividen en 3 grupos para facilitar el aprender: Grupo 1 (Prueba 
1): Se concentra en entender los diversos períodos de la 
historia, cuando cada período durado y áspero que los monarcas 
gobernaron durante cuál uno. Grupo 2 (Pruebas 2.3.4.5): 
Este cada uno se especializa en un período determinado de la 
historia y permite una acumulación más detallada del conocimiento de
los monarcas y de las fechas para ese período. Grupo 3 (Prueba 
6): Ésta es una prueba general que cubre el período entero de 
la monarquía inglesa y combina la experiencia ganada en las pruebas 
anteriores para considerar cómo esta' bien usted puede conectar 
monarcas y sus fechas. El módulo es conveniente para cualquier 
persona a partir de 10 años de ascendente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PHIL RUSTAGE
FN:PHIL RUSTAGE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205580</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104189</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-kings-and-queens-of-england</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
