<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107342</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107342</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207211</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Knife River: Early Village Life on the Plains</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Messer-Fluß: Frühe Dorf-Lebensdauer auf 
den Ebenen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fleuve de Couteau : La vie tôt de village 
sur les plaines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rio Da Faca: Vida adiantada da vila nas 
planícies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fiume Della Lama: Vita in anticipo del 
villaggio sulle pianure</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποταμός μαχαιριών: Πρόωρη του χωριού ζωή στις 
πεδιάδες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Río Del Cuchillo: Vida temprana de la aldea
en los llanos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes village life in the Hidatsa and Mandan tribes during the peak of their culture in the early 19th century (North Dakota). It helps students compare information about these seasonally nomadic Plains villagers with the more popularized film and textbook history of nomadic horse-culture Indians such as the Lakota and Cheyenne.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt das Dorfleben in den Hidatsa und Mandan
Stämmen während der Spitze ihrer Kultur im frühen 19. Jahrhundert 
(North Dakota). Es hilft Kursteilnehmern, Informationen über 
diese saisonal nomadischen Ebenen Dorfbewohner mit der popularisierten
Film- und Lehrbuchgeschichte der nomadischen Pferd-Kultur Inder wie 
des Lakota und des Cheyennes zu vergleichen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit la vie de village dans les tribus de 
Hidatsa et de Mandan pendant la crête de leur culture au 19ème 
siècle tôt (Dakota du nord). Il aide des étudiants à 
comparer des informations sur ces villageois de façon saisonnière 
nomades de plaines à l'histoire plus popularisée de film et de 
manuel des Indiens nomades de cheval-culture tels que le Lakota et 
Cheyenne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve a vida da vila nos tribes de Hidatsa e de
Mandan durante o pico de sua cultura no 1ø século adiantado (dakota 
norte). Ajuda a estudantes comparar a informação sobre estes 
aldeões seasonally nomadic das planícies com o history popularized 
da película e do textbook de indians nomadic da cavalo-cultura tais 
como o Lakota e o Cheyenne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive la vita del villaggio nelle tribù di 
Mandan e di Hidatsa durante il picco della loro coltura nel 
diciannovesimo secolo in anticipo (il Dakota del Nord). Aiuta 
gli allievi a paragonare le informazioni su questi villagers secondo 
la stagione nomadi delle pianure alla storia diffusa del manuale e 
della pellicola degli indiani nomadi della cavallo-coltura quali il 
Lakota e Cheyenne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει την του χωριού ζωή στις φυλές Hidatsa 
και Mandan κατά τη διάρκεια της αιχμής του πολιτισμού τους στις
αρχές του 19$ου αιώνα (βόρεια Ντακότα). Βοηθά τους 
σπουδαστές να συγκρίνουν τις πληροφορίες για αυτούς τους εποχιακά
νομαδικούς χωρικούς πεδιάδων με την ιστορία ταινιών και 
εγχειριδίων του νομαδικού άλογο-πολιτισμού Ινδοί όπως το 
Lakota και το Cheyenne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe vida de la aldea en las tribus de Hidatsa
y de Mandan durante el pico de su cultura en el diecinueveavo siglo 
temprano (Dakota del Norte). Ayuda a estudiantes a comparar la 
información sobre estos aldeanos estacional nómadas de los llanos 
con la historia popularizada de la película y del libro de textos de 
los indios nómadas de la caballo-cultura tales como el Lakota y la 
Cheyenne.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207211</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107342</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/knife-river-early-village-life-on-the-plains</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
