<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107429</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107429</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206794</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">How Your Brain Understands What Your Ear Hears</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wie Ihr Gehirn Versteht, Was Ihr Ohr Hört</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comment Votre Cerveau Comprend Ce que Votre 
Oreille Entend</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como Seu Cérebro Compreende O que Sua Orelha Se 
ouve</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come Il Vostro Cervello Capisce Che cosa Il Vostro
Orecchio Si sente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πώς ο εγκέφαλός σας καταλαβαίνει τι το αυτί σας 
ακούει</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cómo Su Cerebro Entiende Lo que Oye Su Oído</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students learn how audio and visual cues can help communication, how loudness is measured, how changes in the hearing pathway may affect hearing, and how to prevent hearing loss. Animations (under student activities) show an ear hearing the Gettysburg Address in 5 languages, a graphic display of pitch and volume, and how sounds are converted into electrical impulses and sent to the brain.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer erlernen, wie Audio- und 
Sichtstichwörter Kommunikation helfen können, wie Lautstärke 
gemessen wird, wie Änderungen in der Hörfähigkeit Bahn 
Hörfähigkeit beeinflussen können und wie man Verlust der 
Hörfähigkeit verhindert. Animationen (unter 
Kursteilnehmeraktivitäten) zeigen ein Ohr, welches die Gettysburg 
Adresse in 5 Sprachen, eine graphische Bildschirmanzeige des 
Taktabstandes und Datenträger hört und wie Töne in elektrische 
Antriebe umgewandelt werden und zum Gehirn geschickt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les étudiants d'aides apprennent comment les 
caractères indicateurs sonores et visuels peuvent aider la 
transmission, comment le volume est mesuré, comment les changements 
de la voie d'audition peuvent affecter l'audition, et comment 
empêcher la perte d'audition. Les animations (sous des 
activités d'étudiant) montrent une oreille entendant l'adresse de 
Gettysburg dans 5 langages, un affichage graphique de lancement et le 
volume, et comment des bruits sont convertis en impulsions 
électriques et envoyés au cerveau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os estudantes das ajudas aprendem como as 
sugestões audio e visuais podem ajudar a uma comunicação, como o 
loudness é medido, como as mudanças no pathway do hearing podem 
afetar o hearing, e como impedir a perda de hearing. Os 
animations (sob atividades do estudante) mostram uma orelha que ouve o
endereço de Gettysburg em 5 línguas, um indicador gráfico do passo 
e o volume, e como os sons são convertidos em impulsos elétricos e 
emitidos ao cérebro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli allievi di aiuti imparano come le indicazioni 
audio e visive possono aiutare la comunicazione, come la sonorità è 
misurata, come i cambiamenti nella via di udienza possono interessare 
l'udienza e come impedire la perdita della capacità uditiva. Le
animazioni (sotto le attività dell'allievo) mostrano un orecchio che 
sente l'indirizzo di Gettysburg in 5 linguaggi, un dispositivo grafico
del passo ed il volume e come i suoni sono convertiti in impulsi 
elettrici e sono trasmessi al cervello.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να μάθουν πώς τα ηχητικά και 
οπτικά συνθήματα μπορούν να βοηθήσουν την επικοινωνία, πώς η 
ηχηρότητα μετριέται, πώς οι αλλαγές στη διάβαση ακρόασης 
μπορούν να έχουν επιπτώσεις στην ακρόαση, και πώς να αποτρέψει 
την απώλεια ακοής. Οι ζωτικότητες (κάτω από τις 
δραστηριότητες σπουδαστών) εμφανίζουν ένα αυτί ακούοντας τη 
διεύθυνση Gettysburg σε 5 γλώσσες, μια γραφική παρουσίαση της 
πίσσας και την ένταση του ήχου, και πώς οι ήχοι μετατρέπονται 
στις ηλεκτρικές ωθήσεις και στέλνονται στον εγκέφαλο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los estudiantes de las ayudas aprenden cómo las 
señales audio y visuales pueden ayudar a la comunicación, cómo se 
mide la intensidad, cómo los cambios en el camino de la audiencia 
pueden afectar la audiencia, y cómo prevenir pérdida de oído. 
Las animaciones (bajo actividades del estudiante) muestran un 
oído que oye el direccionamiento de Gettysburg en 5 lenguajes, una 
representación gráfica de la echada y el volumen, y cómo los 
sonidos se convierten en impulsos eléctricos y se envían al cerebro.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206794</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107429</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/how-your-brain-understands-what-your-ear-hears</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
