<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108615</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108615</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086837</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"So Cheapened the White Man's Labor": White Artisans Contest the Labor of Black Workers, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"verbilligte so die weißen Arbeit des Mannes": 
Weiße Handwerker wetteifern die Arbeit der schwarzen Arbeiter, 
1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"a ainsi déprécié le travail de l'homme blanc" 
: Les artisans blancs contestent le travail des ouvriers noirs, 
1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"depreciou assim o trabalho do homem branco": 
Os artisans brancos contestam o trabalho de trabalhadores 
pretos, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"così ha ridotto il Lavoro dell'uomo 
bianco": Gli artigianale bianchi contestano il Lavoro degli
operai neri, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έτσι Cheapened η λευκιά ανθρώπινη εργασία": 
Ασπρο Artisans αμφισβητεί την εργασία των μαύρων 
εργαζομένων, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"degradó tan el trabajo del hombre blanco": 
Los artesanos blancos disputan el trabajo de trabajadores 
negros, 1838</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While the numbers of free blacks remained small in the South through the mid-nineteenth century, their presence aroused great anxiety among whites. Legislatures passed laws limiting African-American political and social rights. Non-slaveholding whites often viewed free black labor as competition, especially in urban areas where tensions between the two groups sometimes ran high. In 1838, J. J. Flournoy, a white Georgian artisan, wrote this letter to the Athens  Southern Banner  complaining about the competition posed by black workers. While he noted in passing that the white majority of the poor should band together to elect representatives to ensure laws that would privilege white labor over black, he more forcefully appealed to a common "whiteness" among contractors and carpenters, proprietors and workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während die Zahlen freien Schwarzen im Süden 
durch das mittler-19.jahrhundert klein blieben, weckte ihre 
Anwesenheit große Angst unter Weiß. Gesetzgebungen 
verabschiedeten die Gesetze, die Afrikanisch-Amerikanische politische 
und Sozialrechte begrenzen. Non-slaveholding Weiß sah häufig 
freie Schwarzarbeit als Konkurrenz, besonders in den städtischen 
Bereichen an, wohin Spannkräfte zwischen den zwei Gruppen manchmal 
stark liefen. 1838 schrieb J. J. Flournoy, ein weißer 
georgischer Handwerker, diesen Brief zur Athen südlichen Fahne 
beschwerend über die Konkurrenz, die von den schwarzen Arbeitern 
aufgeworfen wurde. Während er beim Überschreiten beachtete, 
daß die weiße Majorität der Armen zusammen mit einem Band versehen 
sollte, um Repräsentanten zu wählen, um Gesetze sicherzustellen, die
Weißarbeit Überschußschwarzes privilegieren würden, gefiel er 
stärker einer geläufigen "Weiße" unter Fremdfirmen und Tischler, 
Eigentümer und Arbeiter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que les nombres de noirs libres demeuraient
petits dans les Sud par le mi-dix-neuvième siècle, leur 
présence a réveillé la grande inquiétude parmi des blancs. 
Les législatures ont passé des lois limitant des droites 
politiques et sociales afro-américaines. Les blancs de 
Non-slaveholding ont souvent visualisé le travail libre de noir comme
concurrence, particulièrement dans des zones urbaines où les 
tensions entre les deux groupes parfois ont fonctionné haut. En
1838, J. J. Flournoy, un artisan géorgien blanc, a écrit cette 
lettre au drapeau méridional d'Athènes se plaignant au sujet de la 
concurrence posée par les ouvriers noirs. Tandis qu'il notait 
dans le dépassement que la majorité blanche des pauvres devrait se 
réunir ensemble pour choisir des représentants pour assurer les lois
qui favoriseraient le noir d'excédent de travail de blanc, il plus 
avec force a fait appel à une "blancheur" commune parmi des 
entrepreneurs et des charpentiers, des propriétaires et des ouvriers.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando os números de pretos livres remanesceram 
pequenos no sul com o mid-décimo nono século, sua presença 
despertou a ansiedade grande entre brancos. As legislaturas 
passaram as leis que limitam direitas políticas e sociais 
Africano-Americanas. Os brancos de Non-slaveholding viram 
frequentemente o trabalho livre do preto como a competição, especial
nas áreas urbanas aonde as tensões entre os dois grupos funcionaram 
às vezes altamente. Em 1838, J. J. Flournoy, um artisan 
georgian branco, escreveu esta letra à bandeira do sul de Atenas 
queixando-se sobre a competição posed por trabalhadores pretos. 
Quando anotou na passagem que a maioria branca dos pobres deve 
se unir junto para eleger representantes para assegurar as leis que 
privilegiariam o preto do excesso do trabalho do branco, apelou mais 
forcefully a um "whiteness comum" entre contratantes e carpinteiros, 
proprietors e trabalhadores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre i numeri di neri liberi sono rimasto 
piccoli nel sud con il metà di-diciannovesimo secolo, la loro 
presenza ha destato l'ansia grande fra i bianchi. Le legislature
hanno approvato le leggi che limitano i diritti politici e sociali 
Africano-Americani. I bianchi di Non-slaveholding hanno 
osservato spesso il lavoro nero libero come concorrenza, 
particolarmente nelle aree urbane dove i tensionamenti fra i due 
gruppi a volte hanno funzionato su. In 1838, J. J. Flournoy, un 
artigianale georgiano bianco, ha scritto questa lettera alla bandiera 
del sud de Atene protestante circa la concorrenza proposta dagli 
operai neri. Mentre ha notato nel passare che la maggioranza 
bianca del povero dovrebbe legare insieme per scegliere i 
rappresentanti per accertare le leggi che privilegierebbero il nero 
bianco dell'eccedenza di lavoro, più validamente ha fatto 
appello "ad una bianchezza" comune fra gli appaltatori e carpentieri, 
proprietari ed operai.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ οι αριθμοί ελεύθερων Μαύρων παρέμειναν μικροί 
στο νότο μέσω του μέσος-δέκατου έννατου αιώνα, η παρουσία τους 
ξύπνησε τη μεγάλη ανησυχία μεταξύ των λευκών. Τα 
νομοθετικά σώματα πέρασαν τους νόμους που περιορίζουν τα 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά πολιτικά και κοινωνικά δικαιώματα. 
Τα μη-σλαβεχολδηνγ λευκά εμφάνισαν συχνά την ελεύθερη μαύρη
εργασία ως ανταγωνισμό, ειδικά στις αστικές περιοχές όπου οι 
εντάσεις μεταξύ των δύο ομάδων έτρεξαν μερικές φορές υψηλό. 
Το 1838, Θ*ι. Θ*ι. Flournoy, άσπρος της Γεωργίας ένας 
χειροτεχνικός, έγραψε αυτήν την επιστολή στο νότιο έμβλημα της 
Αθήνας παραπονούμενος για τον ανταγωνισμό που τέθηκε από τους 
μαύρους εργαζομένους. Ενώ σημείωσε στη διάβαση ότι η 
άσπρη πλειοψηφία των φτωχών πρέπει να ενώσει μαζί για να 
εκλέξει τους αντιπροσώπους για να εξασφαλίσει νόμους που θα 
παρείχαν προνόμια στη λευκιά εργασία πέρα από το Μαύρο, 
απευθύνθηκε πιό δυνατά σε μια κοινή "λευκότητα" μεταξύ των 
αναδόχων και των ξυλουργών, των ιδιοκτητών και των εργαζομένων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que los números de negros libres 
seguían siendo pequeños en el sur con el mediados de-diecinueveavo 
siglo, su presencia despertó gran ansiedad entre blancos. Las 
legislaturas aprobaron los leyes que limitaban las derechas políticas
y sociales Africano-Americanas. Los blancos de Non-slaveholding 
vieron a menudo el trabajo libre del negro como competición, 
especialmente en las áreas urbanas adonde las tensiones entre los dos
grupos se ejecutaron a veces arriba. En 1838, J. J. Flournoy, 
artesano georgiano blanco, escribió esta letra a la bandera 
meridional de Atenas quejándose por la competición planteada por los
trabajadores negros. Mientras que él observó en pasar que la 
mayoría blanca de los pobres debe congregar junta para elegir a 
representantes para asegurar los leyes que privilegiarían negro del 
excedente del trabajo del blanco, él más poderosamente abrogó a una
"blancura común" entre contratistas y los carpinteros, los 
propietarios y los trabajadores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086837</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108615</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/so-cheapened-the-white-mans-labor-white-artisans-contest-the-labor-of-black-workers-1838</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
