<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104106</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104106</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087335</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Severe and Proud Dame She Was": Mary Rowlandson Lives Among the Indians, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"strengen und stolzen Dame She Was": Mary 
Rowlandson lebt unter den Indern, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"dame She Was grave et fière" : Mary 
Rowlandson vit parmi les Indiens, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"dame Ela Ser severo e orgulhoso": Mary 
Rowlandson vive entre os indians, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"dame She un Was severo e fiero": Mary 
Rowlandson vive fra gli indiani, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια αυστηρή και υπερήφανη κυρία She Was": 
Θ*Μαρυ Rowlandson Lives Among οι Ινδοί, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"dama She Was severo y orgulloso": Maria 
Rowlandson vive entre los indios, 1675</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Metacom, or King Philip as he was called by the English, led a confederation of Indian groups in 1675 in a military effort to roll back the encroaching English settlements of southern New England. For several months the Indians led raids and secured victories against the English, who found it difficult to combat the Indian style of warfare. Mary Rowlandson, a minister's wife, was captured along with several of her children in one of those raids on the frontier outpost of Lancaster, Massachusetts. For eleven weeks she traveled with the Wampanoags and Nipmucs in central Massachusetts. Her account provided great insight into the relationship of English and Indian cultures at this critical point. While Rowlandson relied heavily upon her faith to see her through her troubles, she also came to understand some of the workings of Indian society, as in her account of Weetamoo. Mary was ransomed in 1676, the same year that the English, with their greater numbers and the support of their Indian allies, achieved Philip's defeat and the scattering of the region's remaining Indian settlements.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Metacom oder König Philip, wie er durch Englisch 
benannt wurde, geführt einem Bündnis der indischen Gruppen 1675 in 
einer militärischen Bemühung, die englischen Regelungen Eingreifens 
von Südneu-England zurück zu rollen. Für einige Monate 
führten die Inder Überfälle und sicherten Siege gegen Englisch, das
es schwierig, die indische Art der Kriegsführung zu bekämpfen fand. 
Mary Rowlandson, Frau eines Ministers, wurde zusammen mit 
mehreren ihrer Kinder in einem jener Überfälle auf dem 
Grenzvorposten von Lancaster, Massachusetts erfaßt. Für elf 
Wochen reiste sie mit dem Wampanoags und dem Nipmucs in zentralem 
Massachusetts. Ihr Konto stellte großen Einblick in das 
Verhältnis der englischen und indischen Kulturen an diesem kritischen
Punkt zur Verfügung. Während Rowlandson schwer auf ihren 
Glauben baute, um sie durch sie zu sehen Mühen, kam sie auch, einige 
der Funktionen der indischen Gesellschaft, wie in ihrem Konto von 
Weetamoo zu verstehen. Mary war ransomed 1676, das gleiche Jahr,
dem Englisch, mit ihren grösseren Zahlen und dem Support ihrer 
Inderverbündeten, Niederlage Philips und das Zerstreuen der 
restlichen indischen Regelungen der Region erzielte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Metacom, ou roi Philip comme il s'est appelé 
par l'anglais, mené une confédération des groupes indiens en 1675 
dans un effort militaire de rouler en arrière les règlements anglais
d'empiétement de la Nouvelle Angleterre méridionale. Pendant 
plusieurs mois les Indiens ont mené des incursions et ont fixé des 
victoires contre l'anglais, qui l'a trouvé difficile de combattre le 
modèle indien de la guerre. Mary Rowlandson, l'épouse d'un 
ministre, a été capturée avec plusieurs de ses enfants dans une de 
ces incursions sur l'avant-poste de frontière de Lancaster, le 
Massachusetts. Pendant onze semaines elle a voyagé avec le 
Wampanoags et le Nipmucs dans le Massachusetts central. Son 
compte a fourni la grande perspicacité dans le rapport des cultures 
anglaises et indiennes à ce point critique. Tandis que 
Rowlandson comptait fortement sur sa foi pour la voir par elle des 
ennuis, elle est également venue pour comprendre certains des 
fonctionnements de la société indienne, comme dans son compte de 
Weetamoo. Mary était ransomed en 1676, la même année que 
l'anglais, avec leurs plus grands nombres et le support de leurs 
alliés d'Indien, a réalisé la défaite de Philip et la 
dispersion des règlements indiens restants de la région.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Metacom, ou rei Philip como foi chamado pelo 
inglês, conduzido um confederation de grupos indian em 1675 em um 
esforço militar rolar para trás os estabelecimentos ingleses 
encroaching de Nova Inglaterra do sul. Por diversos meses os 
indians conduziram a invasões e fixaram vitórias de encontro ao 
inglês, que encontrou difícil de combater o estilo indian da guerra.
Mary Rowlandson, esposa de um ministro, foi capturada junto com 
diversas de suas crianças em uma daquelas invasões no outpost da 
fronteira de Lancaster, Massachusetts. Por onze semanas viajou 
com o Wampanoags e o Nipmucs em Massachusetts central. Seu 
cliente forneceu a introspecção grande no relacionamento de culturas
inglesas e indian neste ponto crítico. Quando Rowlandson 
confiou pesadamente em sua fé para a ver através dela problemas, 
veio também compreender alguns dos funcionamentos da sociedade 
indian, como em seu cliente de Weetamoo. Mary era ransomed em 
1676, o mesmo ano que o inglês, com seus números mais grandes e a 
sustentação de seus aliados do indian, conseguiu a derrota de Philip
e dispersar dos estabelecimentos indian restantes da região.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Metacom, o re Philip come è stato chiamato 
dall'inglese, condotto una confederazione dei gruppi indiani in 1675 
in uno sforzo militare rotolare indietro gli stabilimenti inglesi di 
invasione della Nuova Inghilterra del sud. Per parecchi mesi gli
indiani hanno condotto le incursioni ed hanno assicurato le vittorie 
contro l'inglese, che lo ha trovato difficile combattere lo stile 
indiano di guerra. Mary Rowlandson, una moglie del ministro, 
è stata bloccata con vari dei suoi bambini in una di quelle 
incursioni sull'avamposto di frontiera di Lancaster, Massachusetts. 
Per undici settimane ha viaggiato con il Wampanoags ed il 
Nipmucs in Massachusetts centrale. Il suo cliente ha fornito la 
comprensione grande nel rapporto delle colture inglesi ed indiane a 
questo punto critico. Mentre Rowlandson ha contato pesante sulla
sua fede per vederlo attraverso lei difficoltà, egualmente è venuto 
capire alcuni dei funzionamenti della società indiana, come nel suo 
cliente di Weetamoo. Mary era ransomed in 1676, lo stesso anno 
che l'inglese, con i loro numeri più grandi ed il supporto di loro 
alleati dell'indiano, ha realizzato la sconfitta del Philip e la 
dispersione degli stabilimenti indiani restanti della regione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Metacom, ή ο βασιλιάς Philip όπως κλήθηκε 
από τους Αγγλους, οδήγησε μια συνομοσπονδία των ινδικών ομάδων 
το 1675 σε μια στρατιωτική προσπάθεια να κυληθούν πίσω οι 
καταπατούσες αγγλικές τακτοποιήσεις της νότιας Νέας Αγγλίας. 
Για αρκετούς μήνες οι Ινδοί οδήγησαν τις επιδρομές και 
εξασφάλισαν τις νίκες ενάντια στους Αγγλους, οι οποίοι το βρήκαν
δύσκολο να καταπολεμήσουν το ινδικό ύφος της εχθροπραξίας. 
Θ*Μαρυ Rowlandson, η σύζυγος ενός υπουργού, συλλήφθηκε 
μαζί με αρκετά από τα παιδιά της σε μια από εκείνες τις 
επιδρομές στο συνοριακό φυλάκιο του Λάνκαστερ, Μασαχουσέτη. 
Για ένδεκα εβδομάδες ταξίδεψε με το Wampanoags και το 
Nipmucs στην κεντρική Μασαχουσέτη. Ο απολογισμός της 
παρείχε τη μεγάλη διορατικότητα στη σχέση των αγγλικών και 
ινδικών πολιτισμών σε αυτό το κρίσιμο σημείο. Ενώ 
Rowlandson στηρίχθηκε σε μεγάλο ποσοστό επάνω στην πίστη της 
για να την δει μέσω των προβλημάτων της, ήρθε επίσης 
να καταλάβει μερικών από τα έργα της ινδικής κοινωνίας, όπως 
στον απολογισμό Weetamoo της. Θ*Μαρυ εξαγοράστηκε το 
1676, το ίδιο έτος ότι οι Αγγλοι, με τους μεγαλύτερους 
αριθμούς τους και την υποστήριξη των ινδικών συμμάχων τους, 
επέτυχαν την ήττα του Philip και τη διασπορά της περιοχής που 
παραμένει ινδικές τακτοποιήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Metacom, o rey Philip como el inglés le llamó, 
conducido una confederación de grupos indios en 1675 en un esfuerzo 
militar de rodar detrás los establecimientos ingleses de la 
usurpación de Nueva Inglaterra meridional. Por varios meses los
indios condujeron incursiones y aseguraron victorias contra el 
inglés, que encontró difícil de combatir el estilo indio de la 
guerra. Capturaron a Maria Rowlandson, esposa de un ministro, 
junto con varios de sus niños en una de esas incursiones en el puesto
avanzado de la frontera de Lancaster, Massachusetts. Por once 
semanas ella viajó con el Wampanoags y el Nipmucs en Massachusetts 
central. Su cuenta proporcionó a la gran penetración en el 
lazo de culturas inglesas e indias en esta punta crítica. 
Mientras que Rowlandson confió pesadamente en su fe para verla 
a través de ella los apuros, ella también vino entender algunos de 
los funcionamientos de la sociedad india, como en su cuenta de 
Weetamoo. Maria era ransomed en 1676, el mismo año que el 
inglés, con sus mayores números y la ayuda de sus aliados del indio,
alcanzó la derrota de Philip y la dispersión de los establecimientos
indios restantes de la región.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087335</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104106</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-severe-and-proud-dame-she-was-mary-rowlandson-lives-among-the-indians-1675</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
