<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107794</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107794</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209797</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Area of an annulus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bereich eines Rings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zone d'un anneau</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Área de um annulus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Zona di un anello</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοχή ενός δακτυλίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Área de una pieza anular</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet show how to compute the area of an annulus. Text on the page explains that the area is the overall area minus the area of the circular 'hole' in the center. For those who prefer it in a formula that is given. The user can resize the two circles defining the annulus and visually estimate the area from a unit grid drawn inside it. A companion page is Definition of an Annulus at http://www.mathopenref.com/annulus.html Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet zeigen, 
wie man den Bereich eines Rings berechnet. Text auf der Seite 
beschreibt, daß der Bereich der gesamte Bereich minus des Bereiches 
der kreisförmigen ' Bohrung ' in der Mitte ist. Für die, die 
ihn in einer Formel bevorzugen, die gegeben wird. Der Benutzer 
kann die zwei Kreise die Größe neu bestimmen den Ring definierend 
und den Bereich von einem Maßeinheit Rasterfeld sichtlich schätzen, 
das innerhalb es gezeichnet wird. Ein Begleiter, den Seite 
Definition eines Rings am http://www.mathopenref.com/annulus.html 
applet ist, kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif montrent 
comment calculer la zone d'un anneau. Le texte à la page 
explique que la zone est la zone globale sans la zone du 'trou 
'circulaire au centre. Pour ceux qui le préfèrent dans une 
formule qui est donnée. L'utilisateur peut remettre à la côte
les deux cercles définissant l'anneau et visuellement estimer la zone
d'une grille d'unité dessinée à l'intérieur d'elle. Un 
compagnon que la page est définition d'un anneau à l'applet de 
http://www.mathopenref.com/annulus.html peut être agrandi à la 
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo mostram como 
computar a área de um annulus. O texto na página explica que a
área é a área total menos a área ' do furo circular ' no centro. 
Para aqueles que o preferem em uma fórmula que seja dada. 
O usuário pode resize os dois círculos que define o annulus e 
visualmente estimar a área de uma grade da unidade desenhada dentro 
dela. Um companheiro que a página é definição de um annulus 
no applet de http://www.mathopenref.com/annulus.html pode ser ampliado
ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo mostrano come 
computare la zona di un anello. Il testo alla pagina spiega che 
la zona è la zona generale meno la zona 'del foro 'circolare nel 
centro. Per coloro che lo preferisce in una formula che è data.
L'utente può ridimensionare i due cerchi che definisce l'anello
e valutare visivamente la zona da una griglia dell'unità dissipata 
all'interno di esso. Un compagno che la pagina è definizione di
un anello al applet di http://www.mathopenref.com/annulus.html può 
essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un 
proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo 
può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella 
libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è 
un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet επιδεικνύουν 
πώς να υπολογίσουν την περιοχή ενός δακτυλίου. Το κείμενο 
στη σελίδα εξηγεί ότι η περιοχή είναι η γενική περιοχή μείον 
τον τομέα της κυκλικής "τρύπασ" στο κέντρο. Για εκείνους 
που το προτιμούν σε έναν τύπο που δίνεται. Ο χρήστης 
μπορεί να επαναταξινομήσει τους δύο κύκλους καθορίζοντας το 
δακτύλιο και να υπολογίσει οπτικά την περιοχή από ένα πλέγμα 
μονάδων που σύρεται μέσα σε το. Μια σελίδα συντρόφων είναι
καθορισμός ενός δακτυλίου σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com/annulus.html Applet μπορεί να 
διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo muestran cómo
computar el área de una pieza anular. El texto en la 
paginación explica que el área es el área total menos el área del 
' agujero circular ' en el centro. Para los que lo prefieren en 
un fórmula se dé que. El utilizador puede volver a clasificar 
según el tamaño los dos círculos que define la pieza anular y 
estimar visualmente el área de una rejilla de la unidad trazada 
dentro de ella. Un compañero que la paginación es definición 
de una pieza anular en el applet de 
http://www.mathopenref.com/annulus.html puede ser agrandado a la talla
de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de 
clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede 
tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209797</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107794</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/area-of-an-annulus</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
