<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103954</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103954</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206022</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chemicals, the Environment, and You</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chemikalien, die Umgebung und Sie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Produits chimiques, l'environnement, et vous</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Produtos químicos, o ambiente, e você</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prodotti chimici, l'ambiente e voi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χημικές ουσίες, το περιβάλλον, και εσείς</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Productos químicos, el ambiente, y usted</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lessons for learning about the relationship between chemicals in the environment and human health. Topics include the science of toxicology, dose-response relationships, individual susceptibility, risk assessment, and environmental hazards. Students are introduced to the ever-changing nature of our understanding of how chemicals influence the health of living organisms.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lektionen für das Lernen über das 
Verhältnis zwischen Chemikalien in der Umgebung und menschlicher 
Gesundheit zur Verfügung. Themen schließen die Wissenschaft 
von Toxikologie, von Dosis-Antwort Verhältnissen, von einzelner 
Anfälligkeit, von Risikobeurteilung und von Klimagefahren ein. 
Kursteilnehmer werden zur überhaupt-ändernden Natur unseres 
Verständnisses eingeführt von, wie Chemikalien die Gesundheit der 
lebenden organismen beeinflussen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons pour se renseigner sur le 
rapport entre les produits chimiques dans l'environnement et la santé
humaine. Les sujets incluent la science de la toxicologie, des 
rapports de dose-réponse, de la susceptibilité individuelle, de la 
évaluation des risques, et des dangers pour l'environnement. 
Des étudiants sont présentés à la nature jamais-changeante 
de notre arrangement de la façon dont les produits chimiques 
influencent la santé de la matière organique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece lições aprendendo sobre o relacionamento 
entre produtos químicos no ambiente e a saúde humana. Os 
tópicos incluem a ciência do toxicology, dos relacionamentos da 
dose-resposta, do susceptibility individual, da avaliação de risco, 
e de perigos ambientais. Os estudantes são introduzidos à 
natureza sempre-em mudança de nossa compreensão de como os produtos 
químicos influenciam a saúde de organismos vivos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni per imparare circa il rapporto 
fra i prodotti chimici nell'ambiente e la salute umana. I 
soggetti includono la scienza di tossicologia, dei rapporti di 
dose-risposta, della predisposizione specifica, della valutazione di 
rischio e dei rischi ambientali. Gli allievi sono introdotti 
alla natura mai-cambiante della nostra comprensione di come i prodotti
chimici influenzano la salute degli organismi viventi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα μαθήματα για την εκμάθηση για τη σχέση 
μεταξύ των χημικών ουσιών στο περιβάλλον και της ανθρώπινης 
υγείας. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν την επιστήμη της 
τοξικολογίας, των σχέσεων δόσης-αντίδρασης, της ιδιαίτερης 
ευαισθησίας, της αξιολόγησης του κινδύνου, και των περιβαλλοντικών
κινδύνων. Οι σπουδαστές εισάγονται στη συνεχώς 
μεταβαλλόμενη φύση της κατανόησης για το πώς μας οι χημικές 
ουσίες επηρεάζουν την υγεία των οργανισμών διαβίωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a las lecciones para aprender sobre el 
lazo entre los productos químicos en el ambiente y la salud humana. 
Los asuntos incluyen la ciencia de la toxicología, de los lazos
de la dosis-respuesta, de la susceptibilidad individual, del gravamen 
de riesgo, y de peligros para el medio ambiente. Introducen a 
los estudiantes a la naturaleza siempre-que cambia de nuestra 
comprensión de cómo los productos químicos influencian la salud de 
organismos vivos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206022</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103954</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chemicals-the-environment-and-you</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
