<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/713582822</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>713582822</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973924</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chemistry Games: Plastics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chemie-Spiele: Plastik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Chimie : Plastiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Do Chemistry: Plásticos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Chimica: Plastica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια χημείας: Πλαστικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Química: Plásticos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! For thousands of years people have been using silk, wool, cotton, wood and leather. In the last century or so, we have added plastics to this list. Key to developing the plastics we now use were the discoveries made by the Nobel Prize awarded scientists Ziegler and Natta in the 1950s. There are two major groups of plastics - some melt when heated and others don't. Find out why!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Für Tausenden Jahre haben Leute Seide, Wollen, Baumwolle, Holz 
und Leder benutzt. Im letzten Jahrhundert oder so, haben wir 
Plastik dieser Liste hinzugefügt. Taste zum Entwickeln des 
Plastiks, den wir jetzt benutzen, waren die Entdeckungen, die durch 
den Nobelpreis gebildet wurden, der Wissenschaftler Ziegler und Natta 
in den fünfziger Jahren zugesprochen wurde. Es gibt zwei 
Hauptgruppen Plastik - irgendeine Schmelze, wenn sie und andere nicht 
erhitzt werden. Finden Sie warum heraus!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Pour des 
milliers d'années les gens avaient utilisé la soie, les laines, le 
coton, le bois et le cuir. En dernier siècle ou ainsi, nous 
avons ajouté des plastiques à cette liste. La clé à 
développer les plastiques que nous utilisons maintenant étaient les 
découvertes faites par le prix Nobel attribué des scientifiques 
Ziegler et Natta dans les années 50. Il y a deux groupes 
principaux de plastiques - une certaine fonte une fois de chauffage et
d'autres pas . Découvrez pourquoi !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Para 
milhares dos anos os povos têm usado a seda, as lãs, o algodão, a 
madeira e o couro. No último século ou assim, nós adicionamos
plásticos a esta lista. A chave a desenvolver os plásticos que
nós nos usamos agora era as descobertas feitas pelo prêmio de nobel 
concedido cientistas Ziegler e Natta nos 1950s. Há dois grupos 
principais dos plásticos - algum derretimento quando aquecido e outro
não . Encontre para fora porque!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Per le migliaia di anni la 
gente sta usando la seta, le lane, il cotone, il legno ed il cuoio. 
Nel secolo scorso o così, abbiamo aggiunto la plastica a questa
lista. Il tasto a sviluppare la plastica che ora usiamo era le 
scoperte fatte dal premio Nobel ricevuto gli scienziati Ziegler e 
Natta negli anni 50. Ci sono due gruppi importanti della 
plastica - una certa fusione una volta riscaldati ed altri non. 
Scopra perchè!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Για 
χιλιάδες έτη οι άνθρωποι έχουν χρησιμοποιήσει το μετάξι, το 
μαλλί, το βαμβάκι, το ξύλο και το δέρμα. Στον τελευταίο 
αιώνα ή έτσι, έχουμε προσθέσει τα πλαστικά σε αυτόν τον 
κατάλογο. Το κλειδί για την ανάπτυξη των πλαστικών που 
χρησιμοποιούμε τώρα ήταν οι ανακαλύψεις που έγιναν από το 
βραβείο Νόμπελ που απονεμήθηκε τους επιστήμονες Ziegler και 
Natta στη δεκαετία του '50. Υπάρχουν δύο σημαντικές 
ομάδες πλαστικών - κάποιο λειωμένο μέταλλο όταν θερμαμένες και 
άλλες όχι. Ανακαλύψτε γιατΐ</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Para los
millares de años la gente ha estado utilizando la seda, las lanas, 
algodón, la madera y el cuero. En el siglo pasado o así pues, 
hemos agregado los plásticos a esta lista. El clave a 
desarrollar los plásticos que ahora utilizamos era los 
descubrimientos hechos por el premio Nobel concedido los científicos 
Ziegler y Natta en los años 50. Hay dos grupos importantes de 
los plásticos - un cierto derretimiento cuando están calentada y no 
lo hacen otros. ¡Descubra porqué!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973924</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>713582822</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chemistry-games-plastics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
