<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103239</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103239</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206466</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Spanish Treasure Fleets of 1715 and 1733: Disasters Strike at Sea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spanische Schatz-Flotten 1715 und 1733: 
Unfall-Schlag am Meer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Flottes espagnoles de trésor de 1715 et de 1733 :
Grève de désastres en mer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Frotas espanholas do tesouro de 1715 e de 1733: 
Batida dos disastres no mar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lle flotte spagnole del tesoro di 1715 e di 1733: 
Colpo di disastri in mare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ισπανικοί στόλοι θησαυρών 1715 και 1733: Οι
καταστροφές χτυπούν εν πλω</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Flotas españolas del tesoro de 1715 y 1733: 
Huelga de los desastres en el mar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">discusses Spain's search for gold and silver in the New World (1500s-1700s) and its treasure fleet system, which was intended to protect its treasure-laden ships from being seized by England, France, and the Netherlands. In 1715 and 1733, hurricanes devastated Spain's treasure fleets off the coast of Florida. Today, two of the sunken ships' remains are protected as Florida Underwater Archaeological Preserves.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">behandelt Suche Spaniens nach Gold und Silber in 
der neuen Welt (1500s-1700s) und in seinem Schatzflottesystem, das 
seine Schatz-beladenen Schiffe vor durch England, Frankreich und die 
Niederlande ergriffen werden schützen sollte. 1715 und 1733 
verwüsteten Hurrikane Schatzflotten Spaniens weg von der Küste von 
Florida. Heute werden zwei des Wanne Remains der Schiffe als 
Florida Underwater archäologische Konserven geschützt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">discute la recherche de l'Espagne de l'or et de 
l'argent dans le nouveau monde (1500s-1700s) et son système de flotte
de trésor, qui a été destiné pour protéger ses bateaux 
trésor-chargés contre être saisi par l'Angleterre, la France, et 
les Pays Bas. En 1715 et 1733, les ouragans ont dévasté 
les flottes du trésor de l'Espagne outre de la côte de la Floride. 
Aujourd'hui, deux des restes des bateaux évier sont protégés 
comme conserves sous l'eau archéologiques de la Floride.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">discute a busca de Spain para o ouro e a prata no 
mundo novo (1500s-1700s) e em seu sistema da frota do tesouro, que foi
pretendido proteger seus navios tesouro-treasure-laden de ser 
apreendido por Inglaterra, por France, e pelos Países Baixos. 
Em 1715 e em 1733, os furacões devastated frotas do tesouro de 
Spain fora da costa de Florida. Hoje, dois do remains dos navios
dissipador são protegidos como preserves debaixo d'água 
archaeological de Florida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">discute la ricerca della Spagna di oro e di 
argento nel nuovo mondo (1500s-1700s) e nel relativo sistema della 
flotta del tesoro, che è stato inteso per proteggere le relative navi
tesoro-cariche dal grippaggio dall'Inghilterra, dalla Francia e dai 
Paesi Bassi. In 1715 ed in 1733, gli uragani hanno devastato le 
flotte del tesoro della Spagna fuori del litorale di Florida. 
Oggi, due del remains delle navi dispersore sono protetti come 
conserve underwater archaeological della Florida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">συζητά την αναζήτηση της Ισπανίας χρυσός και 
ασημένιος στο νέο κόσμο (1500s-1700s) και το σύστημα στόλου 
θησαυρών του, το οποίο προορίστηκε να προστατεύσει τα 
θησαυρός-φορτωμένα σκάφη του από την κατάσχεση από την Αγγλία, 
τη Γαλλία, και τις Κάτω Χώρες. Το 1715 και το 1733, οι 
τυφώνες κατάστρεψαν τους στόλους θησαυρών της Ισπανίας από την 
ακτή της Φλώριδας. Σήμερα, δύο από τα βυθισμένα 
υπολείμματα των σκαφών προστατεύονται ως υποβρύχιες αρχαιολογικές
κονσέρβες της Φλώριδας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">discute la búsqueda de España para el oro y la 
plata en el mundo nuevo (1500s-1700s) y su sistema de la flota del 
tesoro, que fue pensado para proteger sus naves de treasure-cargado 
contra ser agarrado por Inglaterra, Francia, y los Países Bajos. 
En 1715 y 1733, los huracanes devastaron las flotas del tesoro 
de España de la costa de la Florida. Hoy, dos del restos de las
naves fregadero se protegen como cotos bajo el agua arqueológicos de 
la Florida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206466</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103239</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/spanish-treasure-fleets-of-1715-and-1733-disasters-strike-at-sea</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
