<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106210</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106210</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086482</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"More Like A Pig Than a Bear": Mariano Guadalupe Vallejo Is Taken Prisoner During the Bear Flag Revolt, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"mehr wie ein Schwein als ein Bär": Mariano 
Guadalupe Vallejo wird Gefangenen während des Bär Markierungsfahne 
Aufruhrs, 1846 genommen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"plus comme un porc qu'un ours" : Mariano 
Guadalupe Vallejo est pris le prisonnier pendant la révolte 
d'indicateur d'ours, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"mais como um porco do que um urso": Mariano 
Guadalupe Vallejo é feito exame do prisioneiro durante a revolta da 
bandeira do urso, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"più come un maiale che un orso": Mariano 
Guadalupe Vallejo è preso il prigioniero durante la sommossa della 
bandierina dell'orso, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Περισσότεροι συμπαθούν έναν χοίρο από μια αρκούδα":
Ο Mariano guadalupe Vallejo είναι ληφθείς 
φυλακισμένος κατά τη διάρκεια της επανάστασης σημαιών αρκούδων, 
1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"más como un cerdo que un oso": Mariano 
Guadalupe Vallejo se toma a preso durante la rebelión del indicador 
del oso, 1846</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the war with Mexico, United States troops seized power. Captain John C. Fremont, western explorer and engineer, led an uprising of American settlers and Californios (Spanish ranching families in Alta California) who supported American annexation. Mariano Guadalupe Vallejo was born into a prominent family and pursued a career in the military and politics. He, like many other Californios, believed that the American presence promoted economic prosperity and political stability. During the Bear Flag Revolt of 1846, Fremont captured Sonoma and raised the flag of an independent California. Vallejo, however, was taken prisoner by Fremont's forces and held for two months. Despite his treatment, Vallejo maintained his American sympathies and went on to serve in the first state legislative body. When he and many others attempted to validate their Mexican land grants, he found his way blocked and eventually lost a ruling in the U.S. Supreme Court. Stripped of much of his influence and fortune, he wrote his five-volume "true history" of Californias, while living on a mere portion of his once vast holdings. Vallejo donated this history to H. H. Bancroft, the famous Californian historian.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Krieges mit Mexiko, ergriffen 
Vereinigte Staaten Truppen Energie. Kapitän John C. Fremont, 
westlicher Forscher und Ingenieur, führte einen Aufstieg der 
amerikanischen Siedleren und des Californios (spanische ranching 
Familien in Alta Kalifornien) die amerikanische Annexion 
unterstützten. Mariano Guadalupe Vallejo wurde in eine 
vorstehende Familie getragen und eine Karriere im Militär und in der 
Politik ausübte. Er, wie viele anderes Californios, glaubte, 
daß die amerikanische Anwesenheit ökonomischen Wohlstand und 
politische Stabilität förderte. Während des Bär 
Markierungsfahne Aufruhrs von 1846, Fremont erfaßtes Sonoma und 
angehoben der Markierungsfahne von einem unabhängigen Kalifornien. 
Vallejo jedoch wurde Gefangenen durch Kräfte Fremonts genommen 
und für zwei Monate angehalten. Trotz seiner Behandlung behielt
Vallejo seine amerikanischen Sympathien bei und fuhr fort, im 
gesetzgebenden Körper des ersten Zustandes zu dienen. Als er 
und viele andere versuchten, ihre mexikanischen Landbewilligungen zu 
validieren, fand er seine Methode geblockt und verlor schließlich ein
Anordnen im VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchsten Gericht. Entfernt von 
viel seines Einflusses und Vermögens, schrieb er seinen 
Fünfdatenträger "zutreffende Geschichte" von Californias, beim Leben
auf einen bloßen Teil von seinem einmal beträchtliche Holdings. 
Vallejo spendete diese Geschichte zu H. H. Bancroft, der 
berühmte kalifornische Historiker.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la guerre avec le Mexique, les troupes des
Etats-Unis ont saisi la puissance. Capitaine John C. Fremont, 
explorateur occidental et ingénieur, a mené un soulèvement des 
colons américains et du Californios (familles ranching espagnoles 
dans Alta la Californie) qui ont supporté l'annexation américaine. 
Mariano Guadalupe Vallejo a été soutenu dans une famille en 
avant et a poursuivi une carrière dans les militaires et la 
politique. Il, comme des beaucoup de l'autre Californios, a cru 
que la présence américaine a favorisé la prospérité économique 
et la stabilité politique. Pendant la révolte d'indicateur 
d'ours de 1846, Sonoma capturé par Fremont et augmenté l'indicateur 
d'une Californie indépendante. Vallejo, cependant, a été pris
le prisonnier par les forces de Fremont's et tenu pendant deux mois. 
En dépit de son traitement, Vallejo a mis à jour ses 
sympathies américaines et a continué pour servir dans le corps 
législatif du premier état. Quand lui et beaucoup d'autres ont
essayé de valider leurs concessions mexicaines de terre, il a trouvé
son chemin bloqué et a par la suite détruit régner dans la cour 
suprême des ETATS-UNIS. Éliminé de beaucoup de son influence 
et fortune, il a écrit son cinq-volume "histoire vraie" de 
Californias, tout en vivant sur une seule partie à lui les 
possessions une fois vastes. Vallejo a donné cette histoire à 
H. H. Bancroft, l'historien californien célèbre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a guerra com o México, as tropas unidas 
dos estados apreenderam a potência. O capitão John C. Fremont,
explorador ocidental e coordenador, conduziu a um uprising dos 
settlers americanos e do Californios (famílias ranching espanholas em
Alta Califórnia) que suportaram o annexation americano. Mariano
Guadalupe Vallejo foi carregado em uma família proeminente e 
perseguiu uma carreira nas forças armadas e na política. , 
como muitos o outro Californios, acreditou que a presença americana 
promoveu a prosperidade econômica e a estabilidade política. 
Durante a revolta da bandeira do urso de 1846, Sonoma capturado 
Fremont e levantado a bandeira de uma Califórnia independente. 
Vallejo, entretanto, foi feito exame do prisioneiro por forças 
de Fremont e prendido por dois meses. Apesar de seu tratamento, 
Vallejo manteve seus sympathies americanos e foi sobre servir no corpo
legislativo do primeiro estado. Quando e muito outro tentaram 
validar suas concessões mexicanas da terra, encontrou sua maneira 
obstruída e perdeu eventualmente governar na corte suprema de ESTADOS
UNIDOS. Descascado de muita de suas influência e fortuna, 
escreveu seu cinco-volume "history verdadeiro" de Californias, ao 
viver em uma mera parcela de his terras arrendadas uma vez vastas. 
Vallejo doou este history a H. H. Bancroft, historian 
californian famoso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la guerra con il Messico, unito 
Dichiara l'potenza grippata truppe. Il capitano John C. 
Fremont, esploratore occidentale ed assistente tecnico, ha condotto 
una rivolta dei settlers americani e di Californios (famiglie 
ranching spagnole in Alta California) che hanno sostenuto il 
annexation americano. Mariano Guadalupe Vallejo è stato 
sopportato in una famiglia prominente ed ha perseguito una carriera 
nei militari e nella politica. , come i molti l'altro 
Californios, ha creduto che la presenza americana promuovesse la 
prosperità economica e la stabilità politica. Durante la 
sommossa della bandierina dell'orso di 1846, Fremont ha bloccato 
Sonoma ed ha alzato la bandierina di una California indipendente. 
Vallejo, tuttavia, è stato preso il prigioniero dalle forze del
Fremont ed è stato tenuto per due mesi. Malgrado il suo 
trattamento, Vallejo ha effettuato le sue compassione americane ed ha 
continuato a servire nel prime dichiara l'ente legislativo. 
Quando lui e molti altri hanno tentato di convalidare le loro 
concessioni messicane della terra, ha trovato il suo modo ostruito e 
finalmente ha perso un regolamento nella Corte suprema degli STATI 
UNITI. Messo a nudo di molta della sue influenza e fortuna, ha 
scritto il suo cinque-volume "storia allineare" di Californias, mentre
viveva su una parte pura di suo azioni una volta ampie. 
Vallejo ha donato questa storia a H. H. Bancroft, lo storico 
californiano famoso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια πόλεμος με το Μεξικό, τα Ηνωμένα 
στρατεύματα πήραν δια της βίας τη δύναμη. Ο καπετάνιος 
John C. Fremont, ο δυτικοί εξερευνητής και ο μηχανικός, 
οδήγησαν μια έγερση των αμερικανικών αποίκων και Californios 
(ισπανικές διευθύνοντας ένα αγρόκτημα οικογένειες σε Alta 
Καλιφόρνια) που υποστήριξαν την αμερικανική προσάρτηση. Ο 
Mariano guadalupe Vallejo γεννήθηκε σε μια προεξέχουσα 
οικογένεια και ακολούθησε μια σταδιοδρομία στο στρατιωτικό και την
πολιτική. , Όπως πολλούς άλλο Californios, εθεώρησε ότι
η αμερικανική παρουσία προώθησε την οικονομική ευημερία και την 
πολιτική σταθερότητα. Κατά τη διάρκεια της επανάστασης 
σημαιών αρκούδων 1846, Fremont συνέλαβε Sonoma και αύξησε
τη σημαία μιας ανεξάρτητης Καλιφόρνιας. Το Vallejo, 
εντούτοις, ήταν ληφθείς φυλακισμένος από τις δυνάμεις Fremont
και ισχυμένος για δύο μήνες. Παρά την επεξεργασία του, 
Vallejo διατήρησε τις αμερικανικές συμπόνοιές του και πήγε για
να εξυπηρετήσει στο πρώτο κρατικό νομοθετικό σώμα. Όταν 
αυτός και πολλοί άλλοι προσπάθησαν να επικυρώσουν τις 
μεξικάνικες επιχορηγήσεις εδάφους τους, βρήκε τον τρόπο του 
εμποδισμένο και τελικά χαμένο μια απόφαση στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ανώτατο
δικαστήριο. Γδυμένος ενός μεγάλου μέρους της επιρροής και 
της τύχης του, έγραψε την πέντε-ένταση του ήχου του "αληθινή 
ιστορία" Californias, ζωντανός σε μια μόνη μερίδα των μιά 
φορά απέραντων μετοχών του. Το Vallejo έδωσε αυτήν την 
ιστορία σε Χ. Χ. Bancroft, ο διάσημος καλιφορνέζικος ιστορικός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la guerra con México, las tropas de 
Estados Unidos agarraron potencia. Capitán Juan C. Fremont, 
explorador occidental e ingeniero, condujo una sublevación de los 
colonos americanos y de Californios (familias ranching españolas en 
Alta California) que utilizaron la anexión americana. Mariano 
Guadalupe Vallejo fue llevado en una familia prominente y persiguió 
una carrera en los militares y la política. Él, como muchos el
otro Californios, creyó que la presencia americana promovió 
prosperidad económica y estabilidad política. Durante la 
rebelión del indicador del oso de 1846, Sonoma capturado Fremont y 
levantado el indicador de una California independiente. Vallejo, 
sin embargo, fue tomado a preso por las fuerzas de Fremont y sostenido
por dos meses. A pesar de su tratamiento, Vallejo mantuvo sus 
condolencias americanas y continuó servir en el cuerpo legislativo 
del primer estado. Cuando él y muchos otros procuraron validar 
sus concesiones mexicanas de la pista, él encontró su manera 
bloqueada y perdió eventual una decisión en el Tribunal Supremo de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS. Eliminado de mucha de su influencia y fortuna, 
él escribió su cinco-volumen "historia verdadera" de Californias, 
mientras que vivía en una porción mera el suyo las tenencias una vez
extensas. Vallejo donó esta historia a H. H. Bancroft, el 
historiador californiano famoso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086482</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106210</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/more-like-a-pig-than-a-bear-mariano-guadalupe-vallejo-is-taken-prisoner-during-the-bear-flag-revolt-1846</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
