<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104411</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104411</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206065</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ocean Explorer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ozean-Forscher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorateur d'Océan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explorador Do Oceano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esploratore Dell'Oceano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ωκεάνιος εξερευνητής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explorador Del Océano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides 165 lesson plans developed to bring entire classrooms on board for exploration and discovery. Topics include deep-sea hydrothermal vents and their spectacular animal communities, benthic creatures of the Northern Gulf of Mexico (one of Earth's most geologically complex regions), seafloor methane, unexplored deep reef habitats off the Carolinas, the Titanic, and the mystery of the Steamship Portland (lost in a 1898 storm off New England).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt 165 Lektionpläne zur Verfügung, die 
entwickelt werden, um gesamte Klassenzimmer für Erforschung und 
Entdeckung an Bord zu holen. Themen schließen hydrothermale 
Tiefseeentlüftungsöffnungen und ihre großartigen 
Tiergemeinschaften, benthischen Geschöpfe des Nordgolfs von Mexiko 
(eine von komplizierten Regionen der Masse am geologischsten), 
seafloor Methan, nicht erforschten tiefen Reeflebensräume weg vom 
Carolinas, das Titanic und das Geheimnis des Steamship Portland ein 
(verloren in einem Sturm 1898 weg von Neu-England).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit 165 plans de leçon développés pour 
apporter les salles de classe entières à bord pour l'exploration et 
la découverte. Les sujets incluent les évents hydrothermiques 
hauturiers et les leurs communautés animales spectaculaires, 
créatures benthiques du Golfe nordique du Mexique (une des régions 
le plus géologiquement complexes de la terre), méthane de seafloor, 
habitats profonds encore inconnus de récif outre du Carolinas, 
Titanic, et le mystère du navire à vapeur Portland (détruit 
dans des 1898 donnez l'assaut à outre de la Nouvelle Angleterre).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece 165 plantas da lição desenvolvidas para 
trazer salas de aula inteiras na placa para a exploração e a 
descoberta. Os tópicos incluem respiradouros hydrothermal 
deep-sea e seus comunidades animais espectaculares, criaturas benthic 
do golfo de México do norte (uma de regiões o mais geologically 
complexas da terra), methane do seafloor, habitats profundos 
unexplored do recife fora do Carolinas, o Titanic, e o mistério do 
steamship Portland (perdido em uma tempestade 1898 fora de Nova 
Inglaterra).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce 165 programmi di lezione sviluppati per 
portare le intere aule a bordo per esplorazione e la scoperta. 
I soggetti includono gli sfiati idrotermali di alto mare e le 
loro Comunità animali spettacolari, creature bentoniche del golfo del
Messico nordico (una delle regioni il più geologicamente complesse 
della terra), metano di seafloor, habitat profondi inesplorati del 
reef fuori del Carolinas, il Titanic ed il mistero della nave a vapore
Portland (persa in una tempesta 1898 fuori della Nuova Inghilterra).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει 165 σχέδια μαθήματος που αναπτύσσονται για 
να φέρουν τις ολόκληρες τάξεις εν πλω για την εξερεύνηση και την 
ανακάλυψη. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τις βαθύβιες 
υδροθερμικές διεξόδους και τις θεαματικές ζωικές κοινότητές 
τους, βενθικά πλάσματα του βόρειου κόλπου του Μεξικού (μια από 
τις γήινες τις περισσότερες γεωλογικά σύνθετες περιοχές), του 
μεθανίου θαλάσσιου πυθμένα, των ανεξερεύνητων βαθιών βιότοπων 
σκοπέλων από το Carolinas, του τιτανικού, και του μυστηρίου του
ατμοπλοίου Πόρτλαντ (που χάνεται σε μια θύελλα 1898 από τη 
Νέα Αγγλία).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a 165 planes de la lección 
desarrollados para traer salas de clase enteras a bordo para la 
exploración y el descubrimiento. Los asuntos incluyen 
respiraderos hidrotérmicos de alta mar y sus comunidades animales 
espectaculares, criaturas bénticas del golfo de México norteño (una
de las regiones lo más geológico posible complejas de la tierra), 
metano del seafloor, habitat profundos inexplorados del filón del 
Carolinas, el Titanic, y el misterio del buque de vapor Portland 
(perdida en una tormenta 1898 de Nueva Inglaterra).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206065</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104411</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ocean-explorer</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
