<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107806</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107806</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101514</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">TeraShake: A Southern California Earthquake Simulation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">TeraShake: Eine Südliche Kalifornien 
Erdbeben-Simulation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">TeraShake : Une Simulation Méridionale de 
Tremblement de terre de la Californie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">TeraShake: Uma Simulação Do sul Do 
Terremoto De Califórnia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">TeraShake: Una Simulazione Del sud Di 
Terremoto Della California</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">TeraShake: Μια νότια προσομοίωση σεισμού 
Καλιφόρνιας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">TeraShake: Una Simulación Meridional Del 
Terremoto De California</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The TeraShake simulations modeled the earth shaking that would rattle Southern California if a 230 kilometer section of the San Andreas fault ruptured producing a magnitude 7.7 earthquake. Two rupture scenarios were simulated, one rupturing from north to south, beginning near Wrightwood, California, and a second one rupturing from south to north, starting near Bombay Beach, California. To model this region, the simulations used a 3,000 by 1,500 by 400 mesh, dividing the volume into 1.8 billion cubes with a spatial resolution of 200 meters on a side, and with a maximum frequency of .5 hertz -- the biggest and most detailed simulation of this region to date. In such a large simulation, a key challenge was to handle the enormous range of length scales, which extends from 200 meters -- especially important near the ground surface and rupturing fault -- to hundreds of kilometers across the entire domain. For more information see: http://visservices.sdsc.edu/projects/scec/terashake/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die TeraShake Simulationen formten das Masse 
Rütteln, das Südkalifornien rattern würde, wenn ein 
230-Kilometer-Kapitel der San Andreas Störung das Produzieren eines 
Größe 7.7 Erdbebens brach. Zwei Abbruchdrehbücher wurden, 
eins simuliert, das vom Norden bis zum Süden bricht und fingen nahe 
Wrightwood, Kalifornien an, und zweitem brechend vom Süden zu Nord 
und begannen nahe Bombay Strand, Kalifornien. Um diese Region zu
formen, verwendeten die Simulationen 3.000 durch 1.500 durch das 
Ineinandergreifen 400 und bis jetzt teilten den Datenträger in 1.8 
Milliarde Würfel mit einer räumlichen Zerlegung von 200 Metern auf 
einer Seite und mit einer maximalen Frequenz von 5 Hz -- die größte 
und ausführlichste Simulation dieser Region. In solch einer 
großer Simulation sollte eine Schlüsselherausforderung die enorme 
Strecke der Länge Skalen handhaben, die von 200 Metern -- besonders 
wichtiges nahes die Grundoberfläche und die brechen Störung -- auf 
Hunderte Kilometer über dem gesamten Gebiet sich ausdehnt. Zu 
mehr Information sehen Sie: 
http://visservices.sdsc.edu/projects/scec/terashake/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les simulations de TeraShake ont modelé la 
secousse de la terre qui cliquetterait la Californie méridionale si 
une section de 230 kilomètres du défaut de San Andreas rompait 
produire un tremblement de terre de la grandeur 7.7. Deux 
scénarios de rupture ont été simulés, on se rompant du nord aux 
sud, commençant près de Wrightwood, de Californie, et d'un 
second se rompant des sud à du nord, commençant près de la
plage de Bombay, la Californie. Pour modeler cette région, les 
simulations ont employé des 3.000 par 1.500 par la maille 400, 
divisant le volume en 1.8 milliard de cubes avec une résolution 
spatiale de 200 mètres d'un côté, et avec une fréquence maximum 
des hertz de 5 -- la plus grande et la plus détaillée simulation de 
cette région jusqu'ici. Dans une si grande simulation, un défi
principal devait manipuler l'énorme intervalle des échelles de 
longueur, qui s'étend de 200 mètres -- particulièrement proche 
important la surface et le défaut au sol de rupture -- aux centaines 
de kilomètres à travers le domaine entier. Pour plus 
d'information voyez : 
http://visservices.sdsc.edu/projects/scec/terashake/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As simulações de TeraShake modelaram a 
agitação da terra que chocalharia Califórnia do sul se uma seção 
de 230 quilômetros da falha do San Andreas rompesse produzir um 
terremoto do valor 7.7. Dois scenarios da ruptura foram 
simulados, um que rompe do norte a sul, começando perto de 
Wrightwood, de Califórnia, e de uma segunda que rompe do sul a norte,
começando perto da praia de Bombaim, Califórnia. Para modelar 
esta região, as simulações usaram uns 3.000 por 1.500 pelo 
engranzamento 400, dividindo o volume em 1.8 bilhão cubos com uma 
definição spatial de 200 medidores em um lado, e com uma 
freqüência máxima de hertz do 5 -- a simulação a mais grande e a 
mais detalhada desta região à data. Em uma simulação tão 
grande, um desafio chave devia segurar a escala enorme de escalas do 
comprimento, que estende de 200 medidores -- especial próximo 
importante a superfície e a falha à terra romper -- às centenas dos
quilômetros através do domínio inteiro. Para mais 
informação veja: 
http://visservices.sdsc.edu/projects/scec/terashake/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le simulazioni di TeraShake hanno modellato 
l'agitazione della terra che sconcerterebbe la California del sud se 
una sezione da 230 chilometri del difetto di San Andreas rompesse 
produrre un terremoto di grandezza 7.7. Due piani d'azione della
rottura sono stati simulati, uno che si rompe da nord a sud, 
cominciando vicino a Wrightwood, alla California e seconda che si 
rompe dal sud a del nord, cominciando vicino alla spiaggia de Bombay, 
la California. Per modellare questa regione, le simulazioni 
hanno usato i 3.000 da 1.500 dalla maglia 400, dividente il volume in 
1.8 miliardo cubi con una risoluzione spaziale di 200 tester da un 
lato e con una frequenza massima dei hertz del 5 -- la simulazione 
più grande e più dettagliata di questa regione fin qui. In 
così grande simulazione, una sfida chiave doveva maneggiare la gamma 
enorme di scale di lunghezza, che si estende da 200 tester -- 
particolarmente vicino importante la superficie ed il difetto al suolo
di rottura -- fino le centinaia dei chilometri attraverso l'intero 
settore. Per le più informazioni veda: 
http://visservices.sdsc.edu/projects/scec/terashake/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι προσομοιώσεις TeraShake διαμόρφωσαν τη γη 
τινάζοντας που θα κροτάλιζε νότια Καλιφόρνια εάν ένα τμήμα 
230 χιλιομέτρου της βλάβης SAN Ανδρέας έσπασε την παραγωγή 
ενός μεγέθους 7,7 σεισμός. Δύο σενάρια ρήξης 
μιμήθηκαν, ένα σπάζοντας από το Βορρά στο νότο, που αρχίζει 
κοντά σε Wrightwood, Καλιφόρνια, και έναν δεύτερο που σπάζει 
από το νότο στο Βορρά, που αρχίζει κοντά στην παραλία της 
Βομβάη, Καλιφόρνια. Για να διαμορφώσουν αυτήν την περιοχή, 
οι προσομοιώσεις χρησιμοποίησαν 3.000 από 1.500 από 400 
παγιδεύουν, διαιρώντας την ένταση του ήχου σε 1,8 
δισεκατομμύριο κύβους με ένα χωρικό ψήφισμα 200 μέτρων 
σχετικά με μια πλευρά, και με μια μέγιστη συχνότητα των χερτς 5 --
η μεγαλύτερη και πιό λεπτομερής προσομοίωση αυτής της περιοχής 
μέχρι σήμερα. Σε μια τέτοια μεγάλη προσομοίωση, μια βασική
πρόκληση ήταν να αντιμετωπιστεί η τεράστια σειρά των κλιμάκων 
μήκους, η οποία επεκτείνεται από 200 μέτρα -- ιδιαίτερα 
σημαντικός κοντινός η επίγεια επιφάνεια και ρήξη της βλάβης -- 
στις εκατοντάδες των χιλιομέτρων πέρα από την ολόκληρη δικτυακή 
γειτονιά. Για περισσότερες πληροφορίες δείτε: 
http://visservices.sdsc.edu/projects/scec/terashake/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las simulaciones de TeraShake modelaron sacudarir 
de la tierra que confundiría California meridional si una sección de
230 kilómetros del incidente del San Andreas rompió producir un 
terremoto de la magnitud 7.7. Dos decorados de la ruptura fueron
simulados, uno que rompía del norte a del sur, comenzando cerca de 
Wrightwood, de California, y segunda que rompía del sur a del norte, 
comenzando cerca de la playa de Bombay, California. Para modelar
esta región, las simulaciones utilizaron 3.000 por 1.500 por el 
acoplamiento 400, dividiendo el volumen en 1.8 mil millones cubos con 
una resolución espacial de 200 contadores en una cara, y con una 
frecuencia máxima de los hertzios del 5 -- la simulación más grande
y más detallada de esta región hasta la fecha. En una 
simulación tan grande, un desafío dominante era manejar el rango 
enorme de las escalas de la longitud, que extiende a partir de 200 
contadores -- especialmente cercano importante la superficie y el 
incidente de tierra el romper -- a los centenares de kilómetros a 
través del dominio entero. Para más información vea: 
http://visservices.sdsc.edu/projects/scec/terashake/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SDSC
FN:SDSC
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101514</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107806</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/terashake-a-southern-california-earthquake-simulation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
