<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107049</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107049</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205597</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mountain dialect: Reading between the spoken lines</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gebirgsdialekt: Ablesen zwischen den 
gesprochenen Zeilen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dialecte de montagne : Lecture entre les 
lignes parlées</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dialect da montanha: Leitura entre as linhas
faladas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dialetto della montagna: Leggendo fra le 
righe parlate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διάλεκτος βουνών: Ανάγνωση μεταξύ των 
προφορικών γραμμών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dialecto de la montaña: Lectura entre las 
líneas habladas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson plan uses Chapter 13 of Our Southern Highlanders as a jumping-off point to help students achieve social studies and English language arts objectives while developing an appreciation of the uniqueness of regional speech patterns, the complexities of ethnographic encounter, and the need to interrogate primary sources carefully to identify potential biases and misinformation in them. Historical content includes American slavery, the turn-of-the-century, and the Great Depression.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Lektionplan verwendet Kapitel 13 unserer 
südlichen Highlanders wie ein springender-weg Punkt, um 
Kursteilnehmern zu helfen, Sozialstudien und englische 
Sprachenkunstlernziele beim Entwickeln einer Anerkennung der 
Einzigartigkeit von regionalen Redemustern, von Kompliziertheiten des 
ethnographischen Treffens und von Notwendigkeit zu erzielen, 
Primärquellen sorgfältig abzufragen, um mögliche Vorspannungen und 
Fehlinformation in ihnen zu kennzeichnen. Historischer Inhalt 
schließt amerikanische Sklaverei, die Jahrhundertwende und den großen 
Tiefstand ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce plan de leçon emploie le chapitre 13 de nos 
montagnards méridionaux comme un point branchant-hors fonction pour 
aider des étudiants à atteindre des études et des objectifs sociaux
d'arts d'anglais tout en développant une appréciation de l'unicité 
des configurations régionales de la parole, des complexités de la 
rencontre ethnographique, et de la nécessité d'interroger des 
sources primaires soigneusement pour identifier des polarisations et 
l'information fausse potentielles dans elles. Le contenu 
historique inclut l'esclavage américain, le tourner-de-le-siècle, et
la grande dépression.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta planta da lição usa o capítulo 13 de 
nossos highlanders do sul como um ponto saltando-fora ajudar a 
estudantes conseguir estudos e objetivos sociais das artes da língua 
inglesa ao desenvolver uma apreciação do uniqueness de testes 
padrões regionais do discurso, das complexidades do encontro 
ethnographic, e da necessidade interrogate com cuidado fontes 
preliminares para identificar polarizações e o misinformation 
potenciais neles. O índice histórico inclui o slavery 
americano, o gir-$$$-$$$-SÉCULO, e o depression grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma di lezione usa il capitolo 13 dei
nostri highlanders del sud come un punto di salto-fuori per aiutare 
gli allievi a realizzare gli studi e gli obiettivi sociali di arti di 
lingua inglese mentre sviluppa un apprezzamento dell'unicità dei 
modelli regionali di discorso, delle complessità dell'incontro 
ethnographic e della necessità consultare con attenzione le sorgenti 
primarie per identificare loro le polarizzazioni e l'informazione 
sbagliata potenziali. Il soddisfare storico include lo slavery 
americano, il gir-de-$$$-SECOLO e la depressione grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος χρησιμοποιεί το κεφάλαιο 
13 νότια highlanders μας δεδομένου ότι πηδώ-μακριά δείξτε 
για να βοηθήσετε τους σπουδαστές να επιτύχουν τους κοινωνικούς 
στόχους μελετών και τεχνών αγγλικής γλώσσας αναπτυσσόμενος μια 
εκτίμηση της μοναδικότητας των περιφερειακών λεκτικών προτύπων, 
οι περιπλοκές της εθνογραφικής σύγκρουσης, και της ανάγκης να 
ρωτηθούν οι αρχικές πηγές για να προσδιορίσει προσεκτικά τις 
πιθανές πολώσεις και την παραπληροφόρηση σε τα. Το ιστορικό 
περιεχόμενο περιλαμβάνει την αμερικανική σκλαβιά, το 
στροφή-$$$-Ο-ΑΙΏΝΑ, και τη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de la lección utiliza el capítulo 13 
de nuestros montañeses meridionales como una punta que salta -apagado
para ayudar a estudiantes a alcanzar estudios y objetivos sociales de 
los artes del lenguaje inglés mientras que desarrolla un aprecio de 
la unicidad de los modelos regionales del discurso, de las 
complejidades del encuentro etnográfico, y de la necesidad de 
interrogar a fuentes primarias cuidadosamente para identificar 
diagonales y la información falsa potenciales en ellos. El 
contenido histórico incluye esclavitud americana, el dar 
vuelta-de-$$$-SIGLO, y la gran depresión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KATHRYN WALBERT
FN:KATHRYN WALBERT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205597</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107049</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mountain-dialect-reading-between-the-spoken-lines</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
