<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106806</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106806</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209809</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chord </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Akkord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Corde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Corda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Corda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χορδή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Acorde</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate a chord of a circle. The applet shows a circle and two draggable points on its periphery, with the chord drawn between them. A command button turns on the perpendicular bisector of the chord. As you drag the chord about, you can see that the perpendicular bisector always passes through the center of the circle. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die einen Akkord eines Kreises zeigen. Der applet 
zeigt einen Kreis und zwei draggable Punkte auf seiner Peripherie, 
wenn der Akkord zwischen sie gezeichnet ist. Eine Befehl Taste 
schaltet das Senkrechtbisector des Akkords ein. Da Sie den 
Akkord ungefähr schleppen, können Sie sehen, daß das 
Senkrechtbisector immer durch die Mitte des Kreises überschreitet. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent une corde d'un cercle. L'applet montre un cercle
et deux points draggable sur sa périphérie, avec la corde dessinée 
entre eux. Un bouton de commande allume le bisector 
perpendiculaire de la corde. Car vous traînez la corde environ,
vous pouvez voir que le bisector perpendiculaire traverse toujours le 
centre du cercle. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de 
plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. 
Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut 
lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison 
ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem uma corda de um círculo. O applet mostra um círculo
e dois pontos draggable em sua periferia, com a corda desenhada entre 
eles. Uma tecla de comando gira sobre o bisector perpendicular 
da corda. Porque você arrasta a corda aproximadamente, você 
pode ver que o bisector perpendicular passa sempre através do centro 
do círculo. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano una corda di un cerchio. Il applet mostra un cerchio 
e due punti draggable sulla relativa periferia, con la corda dissipata
fra loro. Un pulsante di comando accende il bisector 
perpendicolare della corda. Poichè trascinate la corda circa, 
potete vedere che il bisector perpendicolare attraversa sempre il 
centro del cerchio. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato 
di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν μια χορδή ενός κύκλου. Το applet εμφανίζει
έναν κύκλο και δύο draggable σημεία στην περιφέρειά του, με 
τη χορδή που σύρεται μεταξύ τους. Ένα κουμπί εντολής 
ανοίγει την κάθετο διαχωριστική της χορδής. Δεδομένου ότι 
σέρνετε τη χορδή περίπου, μπορείτε να δείτε ότι 
κάθετος ο διαχωριστικός περνά πάντα μέσω του κέντρου του 
κύκλου. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran un acorde de un círculo. El applet muestra un 
círculo y dos puntas draggable en su periferia, con el acorde trazado
entre ellas. Un botón de comando gira el bisector perpendicular
del acorde. Pues usted arrastra el acorde alrededor, usted puede
ver que el bisector perpendicular pasa siempre a través del centro 
del círculo. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209809</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106806</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chord</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
