<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105449</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105449</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086802</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Save Sacco and Vanzetti": The Defense Committee's Plea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"außer Sacco und Vanzetti": Der Vorwand Des
Schutzverbands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"économiser Sacco et Vanzetti" : La 
Réclamation du Comité De Défense</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"excepto Sacco e Vanzetti": O Plea De 
Comitê De Defesa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"risparmi Sacco e Vanzetti": La Richiesta 
Del Comitato Di Difesa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εκτός από Sacco και Vanzetti": Η αίτηση 
της αμυντικής Επιτροπής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"excepto Sacco y Vanzetti": La Súplica Del 
Comité De Defensa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The emotional and highly publicized case of Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti became a touchstone and rallying cry for American radicals in the early 20th century. The two Italian immigrants were accused in 1920 of murdering a paymaster in a holdup. Although the evidence against them was flimsy, they were readily convicted, in large part because they were immigrants and anarchists. Despite international protests, they were executed on August 23, 1927. Novelist John Dos Passos became deeply involved in the case after he visited Sacco and Vanzetti in Massachusetts prisons. In the fall of 1920 he joined the Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Committee.  Facing the Chair  was the committee's official report. In it Dos Passos dissected the complicated legal case, countering the prosecution account and excoriating the miscarriage of justice. In addition to its rhetorical argument,  Facing the Chair  appealed to readers' humanity with poignant descriptions of the two men's long imprisonment. Dos Passos's bitterly ironic subtitle--"The Americanization of Two Foreign-born Workingmen"--pointed to the nativist sentiment that colored the prosecution.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der emotionale und in hohem Grade publizierte 
Kasten von Nicola Sacco und von Bartolomeo Vanzetti wurde ein 
Prüfstein und Sammelnschrei für amerikanische Radikale im 
frühen 20. Jahrhundert. Die zwei italienischen Immigranten 
wurden 1920 der Ermordung einer Zahlstelle in einem Holdup 
beschuldigt. Obgleich der Beweis gegen sie schwach war, wurden 
sie betriebsbereit, im großen Teil überführt, weil sie Immigranten 
und Anarchisten waren. Trotz der internationalen Proteste wurden
sie an August 23, 1927 durchgeführt. Novelist-John DOS Passos 
wurde im Fall tief beteiligt, nachdem er Sacco und Vanzetti in den 
Massachusetts Gefängnissen besuchte. Im Fall von 1920 verband 
er den Sacco-Vanzetti Schutzverband. Den Stuhl 
gegenüberzustellen war der amtliche Report des Ausschusses. In 
ihm zergliederte DOS Passos die schwierige Rechtssache, widersprach 
dem Verfolgungkonto und mißbilligt den Fehlschlag von Gerechtigkeit. 
Zusätzlich zu seinem rhetorischen Argument den Stuhl 
gegenüberstellend gefiel Menschlichkeit der Leser mit poignant 
Beschreibungen der zwei langen Gefangenschaft der Männer. DOS 
Passoss bitterlich ironischer Untertitel -- "the Amerikanisierung 
von zwei Foreign-born Workingmen" -- gezeigt auf das nativist Gefühl,
das die Verfolgung färbte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La caisse émotive et fortement annoncée de 
Nicola Sacco et de Bartolomeo Vanzetti est devenue une pierre de touche et 
cri de rassemblement pour les radicaux américains en début du 20ème
siècle. Les deux immigrés italiens ont été accusés dans 
1920 d'assassiner un caissier dans un holdup. Bien que 
l'évidence contre eux ait été fragile, ils ont été aisément 
condamnés, dans la grande partie parce qu'ils étaient des immigrés 
et des anarchistes. En dépit des protestations internationales,
on les a exécuté 23 août 1927. DOS Passos de John de 
romancier est devenu profondément impliqué dans le cas après qu'il 
ait visité Sacco et Vanzetti dans des prisons du Massachusetts. 
En automne de 1920 il a joint le comité de défense de 
Sacco-Vanzetti. Faire face à la chaise était l'état officiel 
du comité. Dans lui le DOS Passos a disséqué le cas légal 
compliqué, parant le compte de poursuite et excoriant la perte de la 
justice. En plus de son argument rhétorique, faisant face à la
chaise a fait appel à l'humanité des lecteurs avec des descriptions 
intenses des deux du long emprisonnement hommes. Sous-titre 
amèrement ironique de DOS Passos -- "l'Américanisation de deux 
ouvriers nés à l'étranger" -- dirigé au sentiment nativiste qui a 
coloré la poursuite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A caixa emocional e altamente publicized de Nicola
Sacco e de Bartolomeo Vanzetti transformou-se um touchstone e grito 
rallying para radicais americanos no 20o século adiantado. Os 
dois immigrants italianos foram acusados em 1920 de assassinar um 
paymaster em um holdup. Embora a evidência de encontro a eles 
fosse frágil, convicted prontamente, na parte grande porque eram 
immigrants e anarquistas. Apesar dos protestos internacionais, 
foram executados agosto em 23, 1927. O Dos Passos de John do 
novelist tornou-se profundamente involvido no caso depois que visitou 
Sacco e Vanzetti em prisões de Massachusetts. Na queda de 1920 
juntou o comitê de defesa de Sacco-Vanzetti. Enfrentar a 
cadeira era o relatório oficial do comitê. Nele o Dos Passos 
dissected o caso legal complicado, opondo o cliente do prosecution e 
excoriating o miscarriage da justiça. Além a seu argumento 
rhetorical, enfrentando a cadeira apelou ao humanity dos leitores com 
descrições poignant do aprisionamento longo dos dois homens. 
Subtítulo amargamente ironic do Dos Passos -- "o 
americanization de dois workingmen foreign-born" -- apontado ao 
sentiment nativist que coloriu o prosecution.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La cassa impressionabile ed altamente divulg di 
Nicola Sacco e di Bartolomeo Vanzetti si è transformata in in un 
touchstone e radunandosi gridi per i radicali americani 
nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo. I due immigranti italiani sono 
stati accusati in 1920 di assassinio del paymaster in un arresto. 
Anche se la prova contro di loro era fragile, sono stati 
condannati prontamente, nella grande parte perché erano immigranti ed
anarchici. Malgrado le proteste internazionali, sono stati 
eseguiti il 23 agosto 1927. Il DOS Passos del John del 
romanziere è stato profondamente implicato nel caso dopo che 
visitasse Sacco e Vanzetti nelle prigioni del Massachusetts. 
Nell'autunno di 1920 ha fatto parte del comitato di difesa di 
Sacco-Vanzetti. Di fronte alla sedia era la relazione ufficiale 
del comitato. In esso il DOS Passos ha dissecato il caso legale 
complicato, ricambiante il cliente di processo ed excoriating il 
miscarriage di giustizia. Oltre che il relativo argomento 
retorico, affrontante la sedia ha fatto appello ad umanità dei 
lettori con le descrizioni poignant dell'imprigionamento lungo dei due
uomini. Sottotitolo amaramente ironico del DOS Passos -- "il 
americanization di due workingmen foreign-born" -- indicato al 
sentimento nativist che ha colorato il processo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η συναισθηματική και ιδιαίτερα κοινοποιημένη περίπτωση
Nicola Sacco και του Bartolomeo Vanzetti έγινε μια 
κραυγή λύδιων λίθων και συνάθροισης για τους αμερικανικούς 
ριζοσπάστες στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα. Οι δύο ιταλικοί 
μετανάστες κατηγορήθηκαν το 1920 για τη δολοφονία ενός ταμία 
σε μια παύση. Αν και τα στοιχεία ενάντια σε τους ήταν ψιλά,
καταδικάστηκαν εύκολα, στο μεγάλο μέρος επειδή ήταν μετανάστες 
και αναρχικοί. Παρά τις διεθνείς διαμαρτυρίες, εκτελέσθηκαν
στις 23 Αυγούστου, 1927, ο μυθιστοριογράφος John Dos 
Passos αναμίχθηκε βαθειά στην περίπτωση αφότου επισκέφτηκε 
Sacco και Vanzetti στις φυλακές της Μασαχουσέτης. Το 
φθινόπωρο του 1920 προσχώρησε στην αμυντική σαθθο- Vanzetti 
Επιτροπή. Η αντιμετώπιση της έδρας ήταν η επίσημη έκθεση 
της επιτροπής. Σε το το DOS Passos τεμάχισε την 
περίπλοκη νομική περίπτωση, που αντιμετωπίζει τον απολογισμό 
συνέχισης και poy η αποβολή της δικαιοσύνης. Εκτός από 
το ρητορικό όρισμά της, που αντιμετωπίζει η έδρα απευθύνθηκε 
στην ανθρωπότητα των αναγνωστών με τις οδυνηρές περιγραφές της 
μακροχρόνιας φυλάκισης των δύο ατόμων. Ειρωνικός υπότιτλος
DOS Passos πικρά -- "η αμερικανοποίηση δύο ξένος-γεννημένο 
Workingmen" -- που δείχνεται το συναίσθημα nativist που 
χρωμάτισε τη συνέχιση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La caja emocional y altamente publicada de Nicola 
Sacco y de Bartolomeo Vanzetti se convirtió en una piedra de toque y grito
de la reunión para los radicales americanos en el vigésimo siglo 
temprano. Acusaron a los dos inmigrantes italianos en 1920 de 
asesinar un paymaster en una interrupción. Aunque la evidencia 
contra ellos era débil, los condenaron fácilmente, en parte grande 
porque eran inmigrantes y anarquistas. A pesar de protestas 
internacionales, los ejecutaron 23 de agosto de 1927. El DOS 
Passos de Juan del novelista llegó a estar profundamente implicado en
el caso después de que él visitara Sacco y Vanzetti en las prisiones
de Massachusetts. En la caída de 1920 él ensambló a comité 
de defensa de Sacco-Vanzetti. Hacer frente a la silla era el 
informe oficial del comité. En él el DOS Passos disecó el 
caso legal complicado, contradiciendo la cuenta del procesamiento y 
excoriating el aborto de la justicia. Además de su argumento 
retórico, haciendo frente a la silla abrogó a la humanidad de los 
programas de lectura con descripciones conmovedoras del 
encarcelamiento largo de los dos hombres. Subtítulo amargamente
irónico del DOS Passos -- "el americanization de dos workingmen 
foreign-born" -- señalado al sentimiento nativista que coloreó el 
procesamiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086802</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105449</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/save-sacco-and-vanzetti-the-defense-committees-plea</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
