<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106515</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106515</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200653</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Biofilms: Online Manual</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Biofilms: Onlinehandbuch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Biofilms : Manuel En ligne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biofilms: Manual Em linha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Biofilms: Manuale In linea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Biofilms: Θ*ον-ληνε εγχειρίδιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biofilms: Manual En línea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This on-line collection of exercises can be conducted to illustrate the formation and properties of microbial biofilms. Activities include: A Biofilm Primer, An Interesting Paradox, Build a Biofilm Reactor, Bring 'em Back Alive, Buccal Epithelial Cells &amp; Bacterial Cells: Negative Staining, Buried Slide Technique, Dental Biofilms, Flow Through Gram Stain, Microbial Fishing, Pellicle Formation in a Hay Infusion, Rhizosphere Visualization, Microbial Leaching of Copper Ore, Build a Winogradsky Column, Growth of Dental Plaque in vitro, Biofilms from Soil Crumbs, Vinegar Production and Acetic Acid Titration, Isolation of Azospirillum, Observation of the Formation of Biofilms in a Flowing Environment, Measuring Biofilm Depth.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Onlineansammlung Übungen kann geleitet 
werden, um die Anordnung und die Eigenschaften von Mikrobenbiofilms zu
veranschaulichen. Aktivitäten schließen ein: Eine 
Biofilm Zündkapsel, ein interessantes Paradox, bauen einen Biofilm 
Reaktor auf, holen ' EM rückseitige lebendige, bukkale Epithelzellen 
u. bakterielle Zellen: Das negative Beflecken, begrabene 
Plättchen-Technik, zahnmedizinisches Biofilms, fließen Gramm-Fleck, 
Mikrobenfischen, Pellicle Anordnung in einer Heu-Infusion, 
Rhizosphäre-Sichtbarmachung, Mikrobenauslaugen des Kupfererzes durch,
bauen eine Winogradsky Spalte, Wachstum des Zahnbelags in vitro, 
Biofilms von den Boden-Krumen, Essig-Produktion und 
Essigsäure-Titrierung, Lokalisierung von Azospirillum, Beobachtung 
der Anordnung von Biofilms in einer flüssigen Umgebung auf und messen
Biofilm Tiefe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette collection en ligne d'exercices peut être 
conduite pour illustrer la formation et les propriétés des biofilms 
microbiens. Les activités incluent : Une amorce de 
Biofilm, un paradoxe intéressant, construisent un réacteur de 
Biofilm, apportent à 'fin de support les cellules épithéliales 
vivantes et buccales arrières et les cellules bactériennes : 
La souillure négative, technique enterrée de glissière, 
Biofilms dentaire, traversent la tache de gramme, la pêche 
microbienne, formation de Pellicle dans une infusion de foin, la 
visualisation de rhizosphère, lixiviation microbienne du minerai de 
cuivre, établissent une colonne de Winogradsky, la croissance de la 
plaque dentaire in vitro, le Biofilms des miettes de sol, la 
production au vinaigre et la titration d'acide acétique, l'isolement 
d'Azospirillum, observation de la formation de Biofilms dans un 
environnement débordant, mesurant la profondeur de Biofilm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta coleção em linha dos exercícios pode ser 
conduzida para ilustrar a formação e as propriedades de biofilms 
microbial. As atividades incluem: Um primer de Biofilm, um
paradox interessante, constrói um reator de Biofilm, traz ' a em 
pilhas epithelial vivas, orais traseiras &amp; pilhas bacterianas: 
Manchar negativo, técnica enterrada da corrediça, Biofilms 
dental, corre através da mancha do grama, pesca microbial, formação
em um infusion do feno, visualization de Pellicle do rhizosphere, 
leaching microbial do minério de cobre, constrói uma coluna de 
Winogradsky, o crescimento da chapa dental em vitro, o Biofilms das 
migalhas do solo, a produção do vinagre e o titration do ácido 
acetic, isolação de Azospirillum, observação da formação de 
Biofilms em um ambiente fluindo, medindo a profundidade de Biofilm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa accumulazione in linea delle esercitazioni 
può essere condotta per illustrare la formazione e le proprietà dei 
biofilms microbici. Le attività includono: Un iniettore 
di Biofilm, un paradosso interessante, costruisce un reattore di 
Biofilm, porta 'a em le cellule epiteliali vive e orali posteriori &amp; 
le cellule batteriche: La macchiatura negativa, la tecnica 
sepolta dello scorrevole, Biofilms dentale, attraversa la macchia di 
grammo, la pesca microbica, la formazione in un'infusione del fieno, 
la visualizzazione del rizosfero, lisciviazione microbica di Pellicle 
del minerale di rame, sviluppa una colonna di Winogradsky, lo sviluppo
di piastra dentale in vitro, Biofilms dalle briciole del terreno, la 
produzione dell'all'aceto e la titolazione dell'acido acetico, 
l'isolamento di Azospirillum, osservazione della formazione di 
Biofilms in un ambiente fluente, misurante la profondità di Biofilm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σε απευθείας σύνδεση συλλογή των ασκήσεων 
μπορεί να διευθυνθεί για να επεξηγήσει το σχηματισμό και τις 
ιδιότητες των μικροβιακών biofilms. Οι δραστηριότητες 
περιλαμβάνουν: Ένας Biofilm εγχυτήρας, ένα ενδιαφέρον 
παράδοξο, χτίζει έναν αντιδραστήρα Biofilm, φέρνει "em τα 
πίσω ζωντανά, στοματικά epithelial κύτταρα &amp; τα βακτηριακά 
κύτταρα: Το αρνητικό λέκιασμα, θαμμένη τεχνική 
φωτογραφικών διαφανειών, οδοντικό Biofilms, ροή μέσω του λεκέ
γραμμαρίου, μικροβιακή αλιεία, Pellicle σχηματισμός σε μια 
έγχυση σανού, απεικόνιση ριζοσφαιρών, μικροβιακή διύλιση του 
μεταλλεύματος χαλκού, χτίζει μια στήλη Winogradsky, την αύξηση
της οδοντικής πινακίδας in vitro, Biofilms από 
εδαφολογικά crumbs, την παραγωγή ξιδιού και την τιτλοδότηση 
οξικού οξέος, απομόνωση Azospirillum, παρατήρηση του 
σχηματισμού Biofilms σε ένα ρέοντας περιβάλλον, που μετρά το 
βάθος Biofilm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta colección en línea de ejercicios se puede 
conducir para ilustrar la formación y las características de 
biofilms microbianos. Las actividades incluyen: Una 
cartilla de Biofilm, una paradoja interesante, construye un reactor de
Biofilm, trae a ' em las células epiteliales vivas, bucales 
posteriores y las células bacterianas: El mancharse negativo, 
técnica enterrada de la diapositiva, Biofilms dental, atraviesa la 
mancha del gramo, pesca microbiana, formación en una infusión del 
heno, visualización del rhizosphere, lixiviación microbiana de 
Pellicle del mineral de cobre, construye una columna de Winogradsky, 
crecimiento de la placa dental in vitro, Biofilms de las migas del 
suelo, la producción y la titulación del ácido acético, 
aislamiento de Azospirillum, observación del vinagre de la formación
de Biofilms en un ambiente que fluye, midiendo la profundidad de 
Biofilm.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOHN LENNOX
FN:JOHN LENNOX
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PENN STATE ALTOONA
FN:PENN STATE ALTOONA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200653</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106515</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/biofilms-online-manual</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
