<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105692</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105692</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086288</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Just Loved that School": Henrietta Chief Recalls an Indian Boarding School in the Early 20th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich liebte gerade diese Schule": Henrietta 
Leiter ruft ein indisches Internat im frühen 20. Jahrhundert wieder 
auf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai juste aimé cette école" : Le chef de
Henrietta rappelle un internat indien en début du 20ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu amei apenas essa escola": O chefe de 
Henrietta recorda uma escola boarding indian no 20o século adiantado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"amavo appena quella scuola": Il capo di 
Henrietta ricorda un collegio indiano nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"αγάπησα ακριβώς εκείνο το σχολείο": Το 
Henrietta υπενθυμίζει Προϊστάμενος ένα ινδικό σχολείο τροφής 
στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"acabo de amar esa escuela": El jefe de 
Henrietta recuerda un colegio de internos indio en el vigésimo siglo 
temprano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this 1970 interview with University of South Dakota historian Herbert Hoover, Henrietta Chief, A Winnebago, talks of her religious conversion at the Tomah School in the first decade of the 20th century. The Tomah school was one of the federal government's off-reservation boarding schools, the linchpin of federal policy after 1887 to Americanize and assimilate Indian youth by removing them from their home environment and culture. Henrietta Chief's conversion made her a fervent apostle of Christianity for the rest of her life.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Interview 1970 mit Universität des 
South Dakota Historiker Herbert Staubsaugers, Henrietta Leiter, ein 
Winnebago, Gespräche ihrer frommen Konvertierung an der Tomah Schule 
in der ersten Dekade des 20. Jahrhunderts. Die Tomah Schule war 
eins der Wegreservierung der Bundesregierung Internate, der 
Vorstrecker von Bundespolitik nach 1887, zum der indischen Jugend zu 
amerikanisieren und anzupassen, indem sie sie von ihrer familiären 
Umgebung und von Kultur löschte. Konvertierung des Henrietta 
Leiters bildete sie einen glühenden Apostel vom Christentum für den 
Rest ihrer Lebensdauer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette entrevue 1970 avec l'université de 
l'aspirateur du sud d'Herbert d'historien du Dakota, chef de 
Henrietta, un Winnebago, entretiens de sa conversion religieuse à 
l'école de Tomah dans la première décennie du 20ème siècle. 
L'école de Tomah était l'un des internats de la hors 
fonction-réservation de gouvernement fédéral, la clavette d'essieu 
de la politique fédérale après 1887 pour américaniser et assimiler
la jeunesse indienne en les retirant de leur environnement familial et
culture. La conversion du chef de Henrietta lui a fait un 
apôtre ardant du christianisme pour le reste de sa vie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta entrevista 1970 com a universidade do hoover
sul de Herbert do historian de Dakota, chefe de Henrietta, um 
Winnebago, conversas de sua conversão religiosa na escola de Tomah na
primeira década do 20o século. A escola de Tomah era uma das 
escolas boarding do fora-off-reservation de governo federal, o 
linchpin da política federal após 1887 para americanize e assimilate
a juventude indian removendo as de seus ambiente home e cultura. 
A conversão do chefe de Henrietta fêz-lhe um apostle fervent 
do christianity para o descanso de sua vida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa intervista 1970 con l'università di 
hoover del Herbert dello storico del Dakota del Sud, capo di 
Henrietta, un Winnebago, colloqui della sua conversione religiosa 
alla scuola di Tomah nella prima decade del ventesimo secolo. La
scuola di Tomah era uno dei collegi di fuori-prenotazione del governo 
federale, la chiave di volta della politica federale dopo 1887 per 
americanize ed assimilare la gioventù indiana rimuovendoli dal loro 
ambiente familiare e coltura. La conversione del capo di 
Henrietta gli ha reso un apostle fervent di christianity per il resto 
della sua vita.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη του 1970 με το πανεπιστήμιο 
του ιστορικού Herbert Hoover, Henrietta της νότιας 
Ντακότας Προϊστάμενος, ένα Winnebago, συζητήσεις της θρησκευτικής
μετατροπής της στο σχολείο Tomah στην πρώτη δεκαετία του 20ού 
αιώνα. Το σχολείο Tomah ήταν ένα από τα σχολεία τροφής
από-επιφύλαξης της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης, η περόνη τροχού της
ομοσπονδιακής πολιτικής μετά από 1887 σε Americanize και 
αφομοιώνει την ινδική νεολαία με την αφαίρεση τους από το 
οικογενειακό περιβάλλον και τον πολιτισμό τους. Η μετατροπή 
Henrietta Προϊστάμενος την έκανε έναν ένθερμο απόστολο του 
χριστιανισμού για το υπόλοιπο της ζωής της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta entrevista 1970 con la universidad de la 
aspiradora de Herberto del historiador de Dakota del Sur, jefe de 
Henrietta, un Winnebago, negociaciones de su conversión religiosa en 
la escuela de Tomah en la primera década del vigésimo siglo. 
La escuela de Tomah era uno de los colegios de internos de la 
apagado-reservacio'n del gobierno federal, la pezonera de la política
federal después de 1887 para americanize y para asimilar la juventud 
india quitándolos de su ambiente familiar y cultura. La 
conversión del jefe de Henrietta le hizo a apostle ferviente del 
cristianismo para el resto de su vida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086288</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105692</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-just-loved-that-school-henrietta-chief-recalls-an-indian-boarding-school-in-the-early-20th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
