<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107286</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107286</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087190</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Don't Know What Will Happen to Our People": A Mill Worker Describes Effects of Layoffs on a Virginia Mill Town</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir wissen nicht, was unseren Leuten" geschieht: 
Ein Tausendstel-Arbeiter beschreibt Effekte von vorübergehenden
Entlassungen auf einer Virginia Tausendstel-Stadt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous ne savons pas ce qui arrivera à nos 
personnes" : Un ouvrier de moulin décrit des effets des 
licenciements sur une ville de moulin de la Virginie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós não sabemos o que acontecerá a nossos 
povos": Um trabalhador do moinho descreve efeitos das dispensas 
em uma cidade do moinho de Virgínia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non conosciamo che cosa accadrà alla nostra 
gente": Un operaio del laminatoio descrive gli effetti dei 
licenziamenti su una città del laminatoio della Virginia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν ξέρουμε τι θα συμβεί στους ανθρώπους μασ": 
Ένας εργαζόμενος μύλων περιγράφει τα αποτελέσματα των 
προσωρινών απολύσεων σε μια πόλη μύλων της Βιρτζίνια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no sabemos qué sucederá a nuestra gente": 
Un trabajador del molino describe efectos de despidos en una 
ciudad del molino de Virginia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Congress passed the Fair Labor Standards Act (FLSA) on June 25, 1938, the last major piece of New Deal legislation. The act outlawed child labor and guaranteed a minimum wage of 40 cents an hour and a maximum work week of 40 hours, benefiting more than 22 million workers. Although the law helped establish a precedent for the Federal regulation of work conditions, conservative forces in Congress effectively exempted many workers, such as waiters, cooks, janitors, farm workers, and domestics, from its coverage. In October 1949, President Harry S. Truman signed into law the Fair Labor Standards Amendments of 1949, raising the minimum wage to 75 cents hour and extending coverage, but still leaving many workers unprotected. In the following statement to the 1949 Senate subcommittee on FLSA amendments, Shirley Hall, described as a "typical cotton-textile worker," discussed material and psychological concerns over layoffs from her town's main source of employment: a large cotton mill. She also argued that an increased minimum wage would increase consumer spending and boost the economy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kongreß führte die angemessene Richtlinie- für 
angemessene Arbeitsbedingungentat (FLSA) an Juni 25, 1938, das letzte 
Hauptstück von Gesetzgebung des neuen Abkommens. Die Tat 
geächtete Kinderarbeit und garantiert ein minimaler Lohn von 40 Cents
ein die Stunde und eine maximale Arbeit Woche von 40 Stunden, mehr als
22 Million Arbeiter fördernd. Obgleich das geholfene Gesetz, 
einen Präzedenzfall für die Bundesverordnung der Arbeit herzustellen
bedingt, befreiten konservative Kräfte im Kongreß effektiv viele 
Arbeiter, wie Kellner, Köche, Hausmeister, Landarbeiter und 
Hausangestellte, von seiner Dichte. Im Oktober 1949, 
unterzeichnete Präsident Harry S. Truman in Gesetz die angemessenen 
Richtlinie- für angemessene Arbeitsbedingungenänderungen von 1949, 
anhob den minimalen Lohn zu einer 75-Cent-Stunde und ausdehnt Dichte, 
aber noch ließ viele Arbeiter ungeschützt. In der folgenden 
Anweisung zur Senatunterausschuß 1949 auf FLSA Änderungen, 
behandelte Shirley Hall, beschrieben als "typischer 
Baumwolle-Gewebearbeiter," materielle und psychologische Interessen 
Übervorübergehende Entlassungen von der Hauptquelle ihre Stadt der 
Beschäftigung: eine große Baumwollspinnerei. Sie 
argumentierte auch, daß ein erhöhter minimaler Lohn 
Verbraucherausgabe erhöhen und die Wirtschaft aufladen würde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le congrès a passé l'acte juste de normes de 
travail (FLSA) 25 juin 1938, le dernier morceau principal de 
législation de nouvelle affaire. Le travail des enfants 
proscrit par acte et garanti un salaire minimum de 40 cents par heure 
et une semaine maximum de travail de 40 heures, bénéficiant plus de 
22 millions d'ouvriers. Bien que la loi aidée à établir un 
précédent pour le règlement fédéral du travail conditionne, les 
forces conservatrices dans le congrès ont pertinemment exempté 
beaucoup d'ouvriers, tels que des serveurs, cuisiniers, portiers, 
ouvriers de ferme, et domestiques, de son assurance. En octobre 
1949, le Président Harry S. Truman a signé dans la loi les 
amendements justes de normes de travail de 1949, augmentant le salaire
minimum à l'heure de 75 cents et étendant l'assurance, mais laissant
toujours beaucoup d'ouvriers non protégés. Dans le rapport 
suivant au sous-comité 1949 de sénat sur des amendements de FLSA, 
Shirley Hall, décrit en tant que "ouvrier typique de coton-textile," 
a discuté des licenciements finis de soucis matériels et 
psychologiques de la source principale de sa ville d'emploi : 
une grande filature de coton. Elle a également argué du 
fait qu'un salaire minimum accru augmenterait la dépense du 
consommateur et amplifierait l'économie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O congress passou o ato justo dos padrões labor 
(FLSA) junho em 25, 1938, a última parte principal de legislação do
negócio novo. O trabalho de criança outlawed ato e garantido 
um salário mínimo de 40 centavos um a hora e uma semana máxima do 
trabalho de 40 horas, beneficiando mais de 22 milhão trabalhadores. 
Embora a lei ajudada estabelecer um precedent para o regulamento
federal do trabalho condicionasse, as forças conservadoras no 
congress exempted eficazmente muitos trabalhadores, tais como 
empregados de mesa, cozinheiros, janitors, trabalhadores de fazenda, e
domestics, de sua cobertura. Em outubro 1949, o presidente Harry
S. Truman assinou na lei as emendas justas dos padrões labor de 1949,
levantando o salário mínimo para uma hora de 75 centavos e 
estendendo a cobertura, mas deixando ainda muitos trabalhadores 
desprotegidos. Na seguinte indicação à subcomissão 1949 do 
senate em emendas de FLSA, Shirley Salão, descrito como "um 
trabalhador típico de algodão-cotton-textile," discutiu dispensas 
excedentes dos interesses materiais e psicológicos da fonte principal
da sua cidade do emprego: um moinho de algodão grande. 
Discutiu também que um salário mínimo aumentado aumentaria a 
despesa do consumidor e impulsionaria a economia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il congresso ha passato la Legge Di lavoro giusta
di standard (FLSA) il 25 giugno 1938, l'ultima parte principale di 
legislazione di nuovo affare. Il lavoro del bambino 
proscritto atto e garantito uno stipendio minimo di 40 centesimi un 
l'ora e una settimana massima del lavoro di 40 ore, avvantaggianti 
più di 22 milione operai. Anche se la legge contribuita a 
stabilire un precedente per la regolazione federale di lavoro 
condiziona, le forze conservatrici nel congresso hanno esentato 
efficacemente molti operai, quali i camerieri, cuochi, janitors, 
manodopera agricola e domestics, dal relativo riempimento. Nel 
mese di ottobre del 1949, il presidente Harry S. Truman ha firmato in 
legge le correzioni Di lavoro giuste di standard di 1949, sollevanti
lo stipendio minimo ad un'ora dei 75 centesimi ed amplianti il 
riempimento, ma ancora lascianti molti operai non protetti. 
Nella seguente istruzione al sottocomitato 1949 del senato sulle
correzioni di FLSA, Shirley Corridoio, descritto come "operaio tipico 
della cotone-tessile," ha discusso i licenziamenti eccessivi di 
preoccupazioni materiali e psicologiche dalla sorgente principale 
della sua città di occupazione: un grande cotonificio. 
Egualmente ha sostenuto che uno stipendio minimo aumentato 
aumenterebbe la spesa del consumatore ed amplificherebbe 
l'economia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το συνέδριο πέρασε το δίκαιο νόμο προτύπων εργασίας 
(FLSA) στις 25 Ιουνίου ..1938, το τελευταίο σημαντικό 
κομμάτι της νέας νομοθεσίας διαπραγμάτευσης. Η πράξη 
πρόγραψε την παιδική εργασία και εγγυήθηκε έναν βασικό μισθό 
40 σεντ μια ώρα και μια μέγιστη εβδομάδα εργασίας 40 ωρών, 
που ωφελούν περισσότερους από 22 εκατομμύριο εργαζομένους. 
Αν και ο νόμος που ενισχύθηκε να καθιερώσει ένα προηγούμενο
για τον ομοσπονδιακό κανονισμό των όρων εργασίας, συντηρητικές 
δυνάμεις στο συνέδριο απάλλαξε αποτελεσματικά πολλούς 
εργαζομένους, όπως οι σερβιτόροι, οι μάγειρες, janitors, οι 
αγρότες, και το domestics, από την κάλυψή του. Τον 
Οκτώβριο του 1949, ο Πρόεδρος Harry S. Truman υπέγραψε 
στο νόμο τις δίκαιες τροποποιήσεις προτύπων εργασίας του 1949,
που αυξάνουν το βασικό μισθό στην ώρα 75 σεντ και που 
επεκτείνουν την κάλυψη, αλλά ακόμα που αφήνουν πολλούς 
εργαζομένους μη προστατευμέούς. Στην ακόλουθη δήλωση στην 
υποεπιτροπή Συγκλήτου του 1949 στις τροποποιήσεις FLSA, η 
αίθουσα Shirley, που περιγράφηκε ως "χαρακτηριστικός 
βαμβάκι-υφαντικός εργαζόμενος," συζήτησε τις υλικές και 
ψυχολογικές ανησυχίες σχετικά με τις προσωρινές απολύσεις από τη
βασική πηγή απασχόλησης της πόλης της: ένας μεγάλος μύλος
βαμβακιού. Επίσης υποστήριξε ότι ένας αυξανόμενος βασικός
μισθός θα αύξανε τα καταναλωτικά έξοδα και θα ωθούσε την 
οικονομία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El congreso pasó el acto justo de los estándares
de trabajo (FLSA) 25 de junio de 1938, el pedazo principal pasado 
de legislación del nuevo reparto. El trabajo de niño proscrito
acto y garantizado un salario mínimo de 40 centavos por hora y una 
semana máxima del trabajo de 40 horas, beneficiando a más de 22 
millones de trabajadores. Aunque la ley ayudada a establecer un 
precedente para la regulación federal del trabajo condiciona, las 
fuerzas conservadoras en congreso eximieron con eficacia a muchos 
trabajadores, tales como camareros, cocineros, porteros, trabajadores 
de granja, y domestics, de su cobertura. En octubre de 1949, 
presidente Harry S. Truman firmó en ley las enmiendas justas de los 
estándares de trabajo de 1949, levantando el salario mínimo a hora 
de 75 centavos y ampliando cobertura, pero todavía dejando muchos 
trabajadores desprotegidos. En la declaración siguiente al 
subcomité 1949 del senado en enmiendas de FLSA, Shirley Pasillo, 
descrito como "trabajador típico del algodo'n-textil," discutió 
despidos excesivos de las preocupaciones materiales y psicologicas de 
la fuente principal de su ciudad del empleo: una fábrica de 
algodón grande. Ella también discutió que un salario mínimo 
creciente aumentara el gasto del consumidor y alzara la economía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087190</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107286</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-dont-know-what-will-happen-to-our-people-a-mill-worker-describes-effects-of-layoffs-on-a-virginia-mill-town</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
