<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107647</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107647</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209915</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ray </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Strahl</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rayon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Raio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Raggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ραυ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rayo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the definition of a ray. The applet presents one point and a line that goes from that point off to infinity. As the point is dragged the line moves but it is never possible to reveal the other line end. See also the entries for line segment and line. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Definition eines Strahls zeigen. Der applet 
stellt einen Punkt und eine Zeile dar, die von diesem Punkt zur 
Unbegrenztheit ausgeht. Da dem Punkt die Zeile Bewegungen aber 
geschleppt wird, es ist nie möglich, die andere Zeile Ende 
aufzudecken. Sehen Sie auch die Einträge für Strich und 
zeichnen Sie. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch 
mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent la définition d'un rayon. L'applet présente un
point et une ligne qui va de ce point hors fonction à l'infini. 
Car le point est traîné la ligne mouvements mais il n'est 
jamais possible d'indiquer l'autre ligne extrémité. Voyez 
également les entrées pour la ligne segment et rayez. L'applet
peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un 
projecteur de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la 
salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem a definição de um raio. O applet apresenta um ponto
e uma linha que se apague desse ponto à infinidade. Porque o 
ponto é arrastado a linha movimentos mas é nunca possível revelar a
outra linha extremidade. Veja também as entradas para a linha 
segmento e alinhe-as. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de 
tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois 
de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo 
o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma 
sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano la definizione di un raggio. Il applet presenta un 
punto e una riga che si spegne da quel punto all'infinità. 
Poichè il punto è trascinato la riga movimenti ma non è mai 
possibile rivelare l'altra riga estremità. Veda inoltre le 
entrate per la riga segmento ed allineisi. Il applet può essere
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τον καθορισμό μιας ακτίνας. Το applet 
παρουσιάζει ένα σημείο και μια γραμμή που πηγαίνει από εκείνο 
το σημείο μακριά στο άπειρο. Δεδομένου ότι το σημείο 
σέρνεται η γραμμή κινείται αλλά δεν είναι ποτέ δυνατό να 
αποκαλυφθεί το άλλο τέλος γραμμών. Δείτε επίσης 
τις καταχωρήσεις γιατί η γραμμή τέμνει και γραμμή. Το 
Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη 
χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην 
τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από 
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran la definición de un rayo. El applet presenta una 
punta y una línea que se apague de esa punta al infinito. Pues 
la punta se arrastra la línea movimientos pero nunca es posible 
revelar la otra línea extremo. Vea también las entradas para 
la línea segmento y alinee. El applet se puede agrandar a la 
talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala 
de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede
tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209915</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107647</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ray</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
