<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105637</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105637</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212852</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Trace Gases</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spur Gase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gaz de Trace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gáses Do Traço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gas Della Traccia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αέρια ιχνών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gases Del Rastro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Stella model allows students to learn about chemical mass balance in the atmosphere and apply this concept to atmospheric chlorofluorocarbon (important for ozone depletion) and carbon dioxide (important for global warming) concentration changes. Students will learn about chemical mass balance of the global atmosphere, understand the relationship between atmospheric life-time, source emission strength, and equilibrium concentration and be able to apply this to CFC concentration changes before and after international policies calling for the phase out of CFC production. The exercise is most useful in an introductory geoscience class with content related to global warming, ozone depletion, or global scale atmospheric pollution. This site also offers teaching notes and tips, teaching materials and assessment ideas. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Stella Modell erlaubt Kursteilnehmern, 
über chemische Ausgleichsmasse in der Atmosphäre zu erlernen und 
dieses Konzept Konzentration an der atmosphärischen des 
Chlorofluorocarbon (wichtig für Ozon-Entleerung) und des 
Kohlendioxyds anzuwenden (wichtig für das globale Wärmen) ändert. 
Die Kursteilnehmer erlernen über chemische Ausgleichsmasse der 
globalen Atmosphäre, verstehen das Verhältnis zwischen 
atmosphärischer Lebenszeit, Quellemissionstärke, und 
Gleichgewichtkonzentration und können, dieses CFC Konzentration 
Änderungen an der vorher und nachher internationalen Politik 
anzuwenden verlangend abwickeln der CFC Produktion. Die Übung 
ist in einer einleitenden geoscience Kategorie mit dem Inhalt am 
nützlichsten, der auf dem globalen Wärmen, Ozon-Entleerung oder 
atmosphärischer Verunreinigung der globalen Skala in Verbindung 
gestanden wird. Diese Site bietet auch unterrichtende 
Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel und Einschätzung Ideen an. 
Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce modèle de Stella permet à des étudiants de 
se renseigner sur le bilan de matière chimique dans l'atmosphère et 
s'appliquer ce concept à la concentration atmosphérique 
chlorofluorocarbone (important pour l'épuisement de l'ozone) et en 
anhydride carbonique (important pour le chauffage global) change. 
Les étudiants se renseigneront sur le bilan de matière 
chimique de l'atmosphère globale, comprennent le rapport entre la 
vie, la force d'émission de source, et la concentration 
atmosphériques d'équilibre et puissent s'appliquer ceci aux 
politiques avant et après internationales de changements de 
concentration de CFC nécessitant l'élimination progressive de la 
production de CFC. L'exercice est le plus utile dans une classe 
préliminaire de geoscience avec le contenu lié au chauffage global, 
à l'épuisement de l'ozone, ou à la pollution atmosphérique 
d'échelle globale. Ce site offre également les notes et les 
extrémités d'enseignement, le matériel didactique et les idées 
d'évaluation. Cette activité fait partie de la collection de 
point de départ : http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este modelo de Stella permite que os estudantes 
aprendam sobre o contrapeso maciço químico na atmosfera e aplicar 
este conceito à concentração atmosférica do chlorofluorocarbon 
(importante para o depletion do ozônio) e do dióxido de carbono 
(importante para se aquecer global) muda. Os estudantes 
aprenderão sobre o contrapeso maciço químico da atmosfera global, 
compreendem o relacionamento entre a vida, a força da emissão da 
fonte, e a concentração atmosféricas do equilíbrio e possam  
aplicar isto às políticas before.and.after internacionais das 
mudanças da concentração de CFC chamando-se para a fase fora da 
produção de CFC. O exercício é o mais útil em uma classe 
introdutória do geoscience com o índice relacionado a aquecer-se 
global, a depletion do ozônio, ou à poluição atmosférica da 
escala global. Este local oferece também notas e pontas 
ensinando, materiais de ensino e idéias da avaliação. Esta 
atividade é parte da coleção do ponto começar: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modello di Stella permette che gli allievi 
imparino circa equilibrio totale chimico nell'atmosfera ed applicare 
questo concetto a concentrazione atmosferica nell'anidride carbonica 
e) svuotamento dell'ozono per importante (nel chlorofluorocarbon 
(importante per il riscaldamento globale) cambia. Gli allievi 
impareranno circa equilibrio totale chimico dell'atmosfera globale, 
capiscono il rapporto fra il corso della vita, la resistenza 
dell'emissione di sorgente e la concentrazione atmosferici di 
equilibrio e possono applicare questo alle politiche prima e dopo 
internazionali dei cambiamenti di concentrazione di CFC richiedenti 
l'eliminazione progressiva di produzione di CFC. L'esercitazione
è più utile in un codice categoria introduttivo di geoscience con il
soddisfare relativo al riscaldamento globale, allo svuotamento 
dell'ozono, o all'inquinamento atmosferico della scala globale. 
Questo luogo egualmente offre le note e punte d'istruzione, 
materiali didattici ed idee di valutazione. Questa attività fa 
parte dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μοντέλο της Στέλλα επιτρέπει στους σπουδαστές
για να μάθει για τη χημική μαζική ισορροπία στην ατμόσφαιρα και 
να εφαρμόσει αυτήν την έννοια στον ατμοσφαιρικό χλωροφλωροάνθρακα
(σημαντικό για τη μείωση όζοντος) και τις αλλαγές συγκέντρωσης 
διοξειδίου του άνθρακα (σημαντικού για την παγκόσμια αύξηση της 
θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου). Οι 
σπουδαστές θα μάθουν για τη χημική μαζική ισορροπία της 
σφαιρικής ατμόσφαιρας, να καταλάβουν τη σχέση μεταξύ της 
ατμοσφαιρικής διάρκειας ζωής, δύναμη εκπομπής πηγής, και η 
συγκέντρωση ισορροπίας και να είναι σε θέση να εφαρμόσει αυτό 
στη συγκέντρωση CFC αλλάζει πριν και μετά από τις διεθνείς 
πολιτικές που απαιτούν τη φάση από την παραγωγή CFC. Η 
άσκηση είναι η πιό χρήσιμοη σε μια εισαγωγική κλάση 
geoscience με το περιεχόμενο σχετικό με την παγκόσμια αύξηση 
της θερμοκρασίας λόγω του φαινομένου του θερμοκηπίου, τη μείωση 
όζοντος, ή τη σφαιρική ατμοσφαιρική ρύπανση κλίμακας. 
Αυτή η περιοχή προσφέρει επίσης τις σημειώσεις και τις 
άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά και τις ιδέες 
αξιολόγησης. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής
αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este modelo de Stella permite que los estudiantes 
aprendan sobre equilibrio total químico en la atmósfera y aplicar 
este concepto a la concentración atmosférica del chlorofluorocarbon 
(importante para el agotamiento del ozono) y del bióxido de carbono 
(importante para calentarse global) cambia. Los estudiantes 
aprenderán sobre el equilibrio total químico de la atmósfera 
global, entienden el lazo entre el curso de la vida, la fuerza de la 
emisión de la fuente, y la concentración atmosféricos del 
equilibrio y puedan aplicar esto a las políticas antes y después 
internacionales de los cambios de la concentración de CFC llamando 
para la eliminación progresiva de la producción de CFC. El 
ejercicio es el más útil de una clase introductoria del geoscience 
con el contenido relacionado con calentarse global, el agotamiento del
ozono, o la contaminación atmosférica de la escala global. 
Este sitio también ofrece notas y las extremidades de 
enseñanza, los materiales didácticos y las ideas del gravamen. 
Esta actividad es parte de la colección del punto de partida: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MACKAY
FN:ROBERT MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212852</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105637</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/trace-gases</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
