<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105074</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105074</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087387</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"An Awful Battle at Homestead, Pa."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"eine schreckliche Schlacht am Gehöft, PA."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une bataille terrible à la ferme, PA."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma batalha terrível no homestead, Pa."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una battaglia terribile alla fattoria, PA."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια φοβερή μάχη στο αγροτικό σπίτι, PA."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una batalla tremenda en la granja, PA."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1892, owner Andrew Carnegie and his plant manager Henry Clay Frick decided to break the steelworkers union at the Carnegie Steel Company plant in Homestead, Pennsylvania. Frick locked out the steelworkers and hired 300 armed guards from the Pinkerton National Detective Agency to protect non-union strikebreakers. When the Pinkertons arrived on barges, armed steelworkers defeated them in a bloody pitched battle. Later, however, the state militia supported Carnegie, and the strikealong with the unionwas broken. The  National Police Gazette  portrayed the July 6, 1892, fight between striking workers and Pinkerton strike-breakers on the Monongahela River. A national weekly directed to male readers, many of whom were workers, the  Police Gazette  occasionally covered labor conflict, expressing sympathy toward strikers while also exploiting the more sensational aspects of the events.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1892 entschieden Inhaber Andrew Carnegie und sein 
Betriebsleiter Henry-Lehm Frick, den Steelworkersanschluß am Carnegie
Steel Company Betrieb im Gehöft, Pennsylvania zu brechen. Frick
sperrte aus den Steelworkers und stellte 300 bewaffneten Schutz vom 
Pinkerton nationalen Detektivbüro an, um nicht organisierte 
Streikbrecher zu schützen. Als das Pinkertons auf Lastkähnen 
ankam, besiegten bewaffnete Steelworkers sie in einer blutigen 
geworfenen Schlacht. Später jedoch unterstützte die 
Zustandmiliz Carnegie, und das strikealong mit den unionwas gebrochen.
Die nationale Polizei-Zeitung schilderte den Juli 6, 1892, Kampf
zwischen auffallenden Arbeitern und Pinkerton Streikbrechern auf dem 
Monongahela Fluß. Eine nationale Wochenzeitung verwies auf 
männliche Leser, viele von wem waren Arbeiter, die umfaßte 
Arbeitßüberschneidung der Polizei-Zeitung gelegentlich und drückte 
Sympathie in Richtung zu den Schlaggeräten bei die mehr sensational 
Aspekte der Fälle auch ausnutzen aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1892, le propriétaire Andrew Carnegie et son argile 
Frick d'Henry de directeur d'installation ont décidé de casser 
l'union de travailleurs dans l'industrie sidérurgique à l'usine de 
Carnegie Steel Company dans la ferme, Pennsylvanie. Frick a 
verrouillé hors des travailleurs dans l'industrie sidérurgique et a 
loué 300 gardes armées de l'agence de détectives nationale de 
Pinkerton pour protéger les briseurs de grève non syndiqué. 
Quand le Pinkertons est arrivé sur des chalands, les 
travailleurs dans l'industrie sidérurgique armés les ont défaits 
dans une bataille lancée sanglante. Plus tard, cependant, la 
milice d'état a supporté Carnegie, et le strikealong avec les 
unionwas cassé. La gazette nationale de police a dépeint 
6 juillet 1892, le combat entre les ouvriers et les briseurs de 
grève saisissants de Pinkerton sur le fleuve de Monongahela. Un
hebdomadaire national a dirigé vers les lecteurs mâles, beaucoup de 
qui étaient des ouvriers, le conflit de travail de temps en temps 
couvert de gazette de police, exprimant la sympathie vers des butées 
tout en également exploitant les aspects plus sensationnels des 
événements.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1892, o proprietário Andrew Carnegie e sua argila 
Frick do Henry do gerente de planta decidiram-se quebrar a união dos 
steelworkers na planta de Carnegie Aço Companhia no homestead, 
Pensilvânia. Frick travou para fora dos steelworkers e empregou
300 protetores armados da agência detective nacional de Pinkerton 
para proteger strikebreakers non-union. Quando o Pinkertons 
chegou em barcas, os steelworkers armados derrotaram-nas em uma 
batalha lançada sangrenta. Mais tarde, entretanto, a milícia 
do estado suportou Carnegie, e o strikealong com os unionwas quebrado.
O gazette nacional das polícias portrayed julho o 6, 1892, a 
luta entre trabalhadores e strike-breakers impressionantes de 
Pinkerton no rio de Monongahela. Um semanário nacional dirigiu 
aos leitores masculinos, muitos de quem eram trabalhadores, o conflito
labor ocasionalmente coberto do gazette das polícias, expressando o 
sympathy para grevistas ao também explorar mais aspectos do 
sensational dos eventos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1892, il proprietario Andrew Carnegie e la sua argilla 
Frick di henry del direttore di stabilimento hanno deciso rompere 
l'unione degli addetti alla lavorazione dell'acciaio nella pianta di 
Carnegie Steel Company in fattoria, Pensilvania. Frick ha 
bloccato verso l'esterno gli addetti alla lavorazione dell'acciaio ed 
ha assunto 300 protezioni munite dall'agenzia detective nazionale di 
Pinkerton per proteggere i crumiri non sindacali. Quando il 
Pinkertons è arrivato sulle chiatte, gli addetti alla lavorazione 
dell'acciaio muniti le hanno sconfitte in una battaglia lanciata 
sanguinante. Più successivamente, tuttavia, la milizia di 
dichiarare ha sostenuto Carnegie e lo strikealong con i unionwas 
rotto. Il gazette nazionale della polizia ha ritratto 6 luglio 
1892, la lotta fra gli operai ed i crumiri notevoli di Pinkerton sul 
fiume di Monongahela. Un settimanale nazionale ha diretto verso 
i lettori maschii, molti di chi erano operai, il conflitto di lavoro 
occasionalmente coperto del gazette della polizia, esprimente la 
compassione verso i percussori mentre però sfruttando le più 
funzioni di sensational degli eventi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1892, ο ιδιοκτήτης Andrew Carnegie και ο 
διευθυντής εγκαταστάσεών του Henry Clay Frick αποφάσισαν 
να σπάσουν την ένωση σιδηρουργών στις εγκαταστάσεις επιχείρησης 
χάλυβα Carnegie στο αγροτικό σπίτι, Πενσυλβανία. Το 
Frick κλείδωσε έξω τους σιδηρουργούς και μίσθωσε 300 
οπλισμένες φρουρές από την εθνική αντιπροσωπεία ιδιωτικών 
αστυνομικών Pinkerton για να προστατεύσει μη συνδικαλιστικά 
strikebreakers. Όταν το Pinkertons έφθασε στις 
φορτηγίδες, οι οπλισμένοι σιδηρουργοί τις νίκησαν σε μια αιματηρή
ριγμένη μάχη. Αργότερα, εντούτοις, η κρατική πολιτοφυλακή 
υποστήριξε Carnegie, και το strikealong με τα unionwas που 
έσπασαν. Η εφημερίδα εθνικής αστυνομίας απεικόνισε τις 6 
Ιουλίου ..1892, την πάλη μεταξύ των απεργών εργαζομένων και 
strike-breakers Pinkerton στον ποταμό Monongahela. Οι 
εθνικοί εβδομαδιαία κατευθυνόμενοι έως αρσενικοί αναγνώστες, 
πολλοί από τους οποίους ήταν εργαζόμενοι, η εφημερίδα 
αστυνομίας κάλυψαν περιστασιακά τη σύγκρουση εργασίας, 
εκφράζοντας τη συμπόνοια προς τους απεργούς επίσης εκμεταλλεμένος
τις πιό συγκλονιστικές πτυχές των γεγονότων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1892, el propietario Andrew Carnegie y su arcilla Frick
del Henrio del director de planta decidían romper la unión de los 
trabajadores siderúrgicos en la planta de Carnegie Steel Company en 
la granja, Pennsylvania. Frick bloqueó fuera de los 
trabajadores siderúrgicos y empleó a 300 protectores armados de la 
agencia detective nacional de Pinkerton para proteger a rompehuelgas 
no sindicales. Cuando el Pinkertons llegó en las lanchas a 
remolque, los trabajadores siderúrgicos armados las derrotaron en una
batalla echada sangrienta. Más adelante, sin embargo, la 
milicia del estado utilizó Carnegie, y el strikealong con los 
unionwas roto. La gaceta nacional del policía retrató de julio
el 6 de 1892, la lucha entre los trabajadores y los rompehuelgas 
llamativos de Pinkerton en el río de Monongahela. Un semanario 
nacional dirigió a los programas de lectura masculinos, muchos de 
quién eran trabajadores, el conflicto de trabajo de vez en cuando 
cubierto de la gaceta del policía, expresando condolencia hacia 
huelguistas mientras que también explotaba los más aspectos del 
sensational de los acontecimientos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087387</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105074</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-awful-battle-at-homestead-pa</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
