<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103410</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103410</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973933</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Genetic Code</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Genetischer Code</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Code Génétique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Código Genetic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Codice Genetico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Γενετικός κώδικας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Código Genético</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! We need several thousands of different proteins in our body. It is the genetic material, the DNA, in our cells that provides the information needed to produce all these proteins. The genetic information is stored in molecules represented by three-letter words called codons. These words need to be translated to the "protein language" of 20 words, each representing an amino acid. Translate the code and challenge a friend to a five in a row game online!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Wir benötigen einige Tausenden der unterschiedlichen Proteine 
in unserem Körper. Es ist das genetische Material, die DNA, in 
unseren Zellen, die die Informationen liefert, die benötigt werden, 
um alle diese Proteine zu produzieren. Die genetischen 
Informationen werden in den Molekülen gespeichert, die durch die 
Dreizeichen Wörter dargestellt werden, die codons genannt werden. 
Diese Wörter müssen zur "Proteinsprache" von 20 Wörtern, 
jedes übersetzt werden, das eine Aminosäure darstellt. 
Übersetzen Sie den Code und fordern Sie einen Freund bis fünf 
in einem Reihe Spiel online heraus!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Nous 
avons besoin de plusieurs milliers de différentes protéines dans 
notre corps. C'est le matériel génétique, l'ADN, en nos 
cellules qui fournit les informations requises pour produire toutes 
ces protéines. L'information génétique est stockée en 
molécules représentées par des mots de trois-lettre appelés les 
codons. Ces mots doivent être traduits au "langage de 
protéine" de 20 mots, chacun qui représente un acide aminé. 
Traduisez le code et défiez un ami à des cinq dans un jeu de 
ligne en ligne !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Nós 
necessitamos diversos milhares de proteínas diferentes em nosso 
corpo. É o material genetic, o DNA, em nossas pilhas que 
fornece a informação necessitada produzir todas estas proteínas. 
A informação genetic é armazenada nas moléculas 
representadas pelas palavras da três-letra chamadas codons. 
Estas palavras necessitam ser traduzidas da "à língua 
proteína" de 20 palavras, cada uma que representa um amino-ácido. 
Traduza o código e desafie um amigo a uns cinco em um jogo da 
fileira em linha!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Abbiamo bisogno di parecchie 
migliaia delle proteine differenti nel nostro corpo. È il 
materiale genetico, il DNA, in nostre cellule che fornisce le 
informazioni state necessarie per produrre tutte queste proteine. 
Le informazioni genetiche sono memorizzate in molecole 
rappresentate dalle parole della tre-lettera chiamate codons. 
Queste parole devono essere tradotte "al linguaggio della 
proteina" di 20 parole, ciascuno che rappresenta un amminoacido. 
Traduca il codice e sfidi un amico ai cinque in un gioco di fila
in linea!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! 
Χρειαζόμαστε διάφορες χιλιάδες διαφορετικές πρωτεϊ'νες στο 
σώμα μας. Είναι το γενετικό υλικό, το DNA, στα κύτταρά 
μας που παρέχει τις πληροφορίες που απαιτούνται για να παραγάγουν 
όλες αυτές τις πρωτεϊ'νες. Οι γενετικές πληροφορίες 
καταχωρούνται στα μόρια που αντιπροσωπεύονται από τις λέξεις 
τρεις-επιστολών αποκαλούμενες codons. Αυτές οι λέξεις 
πρέπει να μεταφραστούν στη "πρωτεϊνική γλώσσα" 20 λέξεων, κάθε 
μια που αντιπροσωπεύει ένα αμινοξύ. Μεταφράστε τον κώδικα 
και προκαλέστε έναν φίλο πέντε σε ένα παιχνίδι σειρών 
on-line!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! 
Necesitamos varios millares de diversas proteínas en nuestro 
cuerpo. Es el material genético, la DNA, en nuestras células 
que proporciona a la información necesitada para producir todas estas
proteínas. La información genética se salva en las moléculas
representadas por las palabras de la tres-carta llamadas los codons. 
Estas palabras necesitan ser traducidas al "lenguaje de la 
proteína" de 20 palabras, cada uno que representa un aminoácido. 
¡Traduzca el código y desafíe a amigo a cinco en un juego de 
la fila en línea!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973933</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103410</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-genetic-code</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
