<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103695</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103695</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087407</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Are We Nothing But Living Machines?" A New York Sewing Woman Protests Wages and Working Conditions, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sind Wir Nichts Aber Lebende Maschinen?" 
Eine New York nähende Frau protestiert Löhne und 
Arbeitsbedingungen, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Sommes Nous Rien Mais Les Machines de Vie?" 
Une femme de couture de New York proteste des salaires et des 
conditions de travail, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Somos Nós Nada Mas Máquinas Vivendo?" Uma
mulher sewing de New York protesta salários e condições de 
funcionamento, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Siamo Niente Ma Macchine Viventi?" Una 
donna di cucito de New York protesta gli stipendi e le condizioni di 
lavoro, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">_ "είμαι εμείς τίποτα αλλά ζω μηχανή;" Αμοιβές
διαμαρτυριών ράβοντας γυναικών της Νέας Υόρκης και συνθήκες 
εργασίας, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Somos Nada Pero Las Máquinas Que viven?" 
Una mujer de costura de Nueva York protesta salarios y las 
condiciones de trabajo, 1863</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Since at least the 1830s, New York working women endured low pay, long hours, and difficult working conditions. Concerned observers noted that some were even forced to turn to prostitution to supplement their meager incomes. During the Civil War, poor men flocked to the army (wealthier men could purchase substitutes for $300). The women left behind were now responsible for supporting families on their own. While wartime production created additional opportunities for women to work, it also led to even greater exploitation as factory owners pushed their workers to turn out more goods. Under these conditions, some women, such as this one, suggested that collective action might provide a solution.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Seit mindestens dem 1830s hielten New York 
Funktion Frauen niedrige Bezahlung, lange Stunden und schwierige 
Arbeitsbedingungen aus. Beteiligte Beobachter beachteten, daß 
einige sogar erzwungen wurden, an Prostitution zu wenden, um ihre 
mageren Einkommen zu ergänzen. Während des Bürgerkrieges 
scharten sich arme Männer zur Armee (wohlhabendere Männer konnten 
Ersatz für $300 kaufen). Die Frauen, die nach gelassen wurden, 
waren jetzt für das Unterstützen der Familien auf ihren Selbst 
verantwortlich. Während Kriegproduktion zusätzliche 
Gelegenheiten erstellte, damit Frauen arbeiten, führte sie auch zu 
sogar grössere Ausnutzung, während Fabrikinhaber ihre Arbeiter zur 
Umdrehung aus mehr Waren drückten. Unter diesen Bedingungen 
schlugen einige Frauen, wie diese vor, daß Kollektivtätigkeit eine 
Lösung zur Verfügung stellen konnte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Depuis au moins le 1830s, les travailleuses 
actives de New York ont supporté le bas salaire, les longues heures, 
et les conditions de travail difficiles. Les observateurs 
intéressés ont noté que certains ont été même forcés de se 
tourner vers la prostitution pour compléter leurs revenus maigres. 
Pendant la guerre civile, les pauvres hommes se sont assemblés 
à l'armée (des hommes plus riches pourraient acheter des produits de
remplacement pour $300). Les femmes laissées étaient 
maintenant responsables de supporter des familles sur leurs propres. 
Tandis que la production de temps de guerre créait des 
occasions supplémentaires pour que les femmes travaillent, elle a 
également mené encore à une plus grande exploitation pendant que 
les propriétaires d'usine poussaient leurs ouvriers pour s'avérer 
plus de marchandises. Dans ces conditions, quelques femmes, 
telles que celle-ci, ont proposé que l'action collective pourrait 
fournir une solution.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Desde ao menos o 1830s, as mulheres de 
funcionamento de New York resistiram o pagamento baixo, horas longas, 
e condições de funcionamento difíceis. Os observadores 
interessados anotaram que alguns estiveram forçados mesmo a girar 
para a prostituição para suplementar suas rendas meager. 
Durante a guerra civil, os homens deficientes reuniram-se ao 
exército (uns homens mais ricos poderiam comprar substitutos para 
$300). As mulheres deixadas atrás eram agora responsáveis para
suportar famílias no seus próprios. Quando a produção do 
wartime criou oportunidades adicionais para que as mulheres trabalhem,
conduziu também mesmo a uma exploração mais grande enquanto os 
proprietários da fábrica empurraram seus trabalhadores para a volta 
para fora de mais bens. Sob estas circunstâncias, algumas 
mulheres, tais como esta, sugeriram que a ação coletiva pôde 
fornecer uma solução.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Almeno dal 1830s, le donne lavorarici de New York 
hanno resistito alla paga bassa, alle ore lunghe ed alle condizioni di
lavoro difficili. Gli osservatori interessati hanno notato che 
alcuni persino sono stati costretti a girarsi verso prostituzione per 
completare i loro redditi meager. Durante la guerra civile, i 
poveri uomini si sono affollati all'esercito (gli uomini più 
ricchi potrebbero comprare i sostituti per $300). Le donne 
lasciate ora erano responsabili del sostegno delle famiglie da sè. 
Mentre la produzione di wartime ha creato le occasioni 
supplementari affinchè le donne funzioni, egualmente ha condotto 
ancora a sfruttamento più grande mentre i proprietari della fabbrica 
hanno spinto i loro operai per risultare più merci. In queste 
circostanze, alcune donne, come questa, hanno suggerito che l'azione 
collettiva potrebbe fornire una soluzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι τουλάχιστον το 1830s, εργαζόμενες 
γυναίκες της Νέας Υόρκης υπόμεινε χαμηλό πληρώστε, πολλές 
ώρες, και δύσκολες συνθήκες εργασίας. Οι ενδιαφερόμενοι 
παρατηρητές σημείωσαν ότι μερικοί αναγκάστηκαν ακόμη και να 
γυρίσουν στην πορνεία για να συμπληρώσουν τα πενιχρά εισοδήματά 
τους. Κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου πολέμου, τα φτωχά 
άτομα συγκεντρώθηκαν στο στρατό (τα πλουσιότερα άτομα μπόρεσαν 
να αγοράσουν τα υποκατάστατα $300). Οι γυναίκες που 
αφέθηκαν πίσω ήταν τώρα αρμόδιες για την υποστήριξη των 
οικογενειών από μόνες τους. Ενώ η εν καιρώ πολέμου 
παραγωγή δημιούργησε τις πρόσθετες ευκαιρίες για τις γυναίκες να 
εργαστούν, οδήγησε επίσης ακόμα στη μεγαλύτερη εκμετάλλευση 
καθώς οι ιδιοκτήτες εργοστασίων ώθησαν τους εργαζομένους τους για
να βγάλουν περισσότερα αγαθά. Υπό αυτούς τους όρους, 
μερικές γυναίκες, όπως αυτή, πρότειναν ότι η συλλογική 
ενέργεια να παρέχει μια λύση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Desde por lo menos el 1830s, las mujeres de 
funcionamiento de Nueva York aguantaron paga baja, largases horas, y 
condiciones de trabajo difíciles. Los observadores en cuestión
observaron que algunos incluso fueron forzados dar vuelta a la 
prostitución para suplir sus rentas pobres. Durante la guerra 
civil, los hombres pobres se reunieron al ejército (hombres más 
ricos podrían comprar los substitutos para $300). Las mujeres 
dejadas detrás eran responsables ahora de utilizar a familias en sus 
el propios. Mientras que la producción del tiempo de guerra 
creó las oportunidades adicionales para que las mujeres trabajen, 
también condujo incluso a la mayor explotación mientras que los 
propietarios de la fábrica empujaron a sus trabajadores para resultar
más mercancías. Bajo estas condiciones, algunas mujeres, tales
como ésta, sugirieron que la acción colectiva pudiera proporcionar a
una solución.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087407</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103695</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/are-we-nothing-but-living-machines-a-new-york-sewing-woman-protests-wages-and-working-conditions-1863</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
