<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106939</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106939</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087569</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Colorado Teaching Learning and Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kolorado unterrichtendes Lernen und Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude et technologie d'enseignement du Colorado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem e tecnologia ensinando de Colorado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparare e tecnologia d'istruzione del Colorado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκμάθηση και τεχνολογία διδασκαλίας του Κολοράντο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El aprender y tecnología de enseñanza de 
Colorado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to the Colorado Teaching, Learning and Technology (CTLT) web site. CTLT was established over four years ago to move innovations in technology and data-driven decision-making into the practice of educators (Pre-K-20) across Colorado. CTLT is now a project of the School of Education at the University of Colorado at Denver. We continue to serve educators at all levels through a variety of grant-funded and fee-for service initiatives. This website provides a window to the varied offerings of CTLT as well as links to additional information about the projects that CTLT either leads or in which CTLT participates.</string>
          </description>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zur Kolorado Unterricht, Lernen- und 
Technologie(CTLT) Web site. Über CTLT wurde vier Jahren 
hergestellt vor, um Innovationen in der Technologie und in der 
data-driven Beschlußfassung in die Praxis der Erzieher (Pre-K-20) 
über Kolorado zu verschieben. CTLT ist jetzt ein Projekt der 
Schule der Ausbildung an der Universität von Kolorado in Denver. 
Wir fahren fort, Erzieher auf allen Stufen durch eine Vielzahl 
von bewilligen-finanziert und Gebühr-für Service-Initiativen zu 
dienen. Diese Web site stellt ein Fenster zu den mannigfaltigen 
Zubringern von CTLT sowie Links zu den zusätzlichen Informationen 
über die Projekte zur Verfügung, an denen CTLT entweder Leitungen 
oder, an welchem CTLT teilnimmt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue au site Web d'enseignement, d'étude et 
de technologie du Colorado (CTLT). CTLT a été établi sur il y
a quatre ans pour entrer des innovations en technologie et prise de 
décision data-driven dans la pratique des éducateurs (Pre-K-20) à 
travers le Colorado. CTLT est maintenant un projet de l'école 
de l'éducation à l'université du Colorado à Denver. Nous 
continuons à servir des éducateurs à tous les niveaux par une 
variété d'accorder-placé et honoraire-pour des initiatives de 
service. Ce site Web fournit une fenêtre aux offres diverses de
CTLT aussi bien que des liens aux informations supplémentaires sur 
les projets à qui des fils de sortie de CTLT ou à quel CTLT 
participe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda ao Web site do ensino, da aprendizagem e
da tecnologia de Colorado (CTLT). CTLT foi estabelecido sobre 
quatro anos há para mover inovações na tecnologia e na tomada de 
decisão data-driven na prática dos educadores (Pre-K-20) através de
Colorado. CTLT é agora um projeto da escola da instrução na 
universidade de Colorado em Denver. Nós continuamos a servir a 
educadores em todos os níveis com uma variedade do conced-financiado 
e taxa-para iniciativas do serviço. Este Web site fornece uma 
janela aos offerings variados de CTLT as.well.as as ligações à 
informação adicional sobre os projetos em que ligações de CTLT ou 
em que CTLT participa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto al Web site di insegnamento, imparare e 
di tecnologia del Colorado (CTLT). CTLT è stato stabilito in 
quattro anni fa per entrare le innovazioni nella tecnologia e nella 
risoluzione data-driven nella pratica degli educatori (Pre-K-20) 
attraverso Colorado. CTLT ora è un progetto della scuola di 
formazione all'università di Colorado a Denver. Continuiamo a 
servire gli educatori a tutti i livelli con una varietà del 
assegn-costituito un fondo per di e tassa-per le iniziative di 
servizio. Questo Web site fornisce una finestra alle offerte 
varie di CTLT così come i collegamenti alle informazioni 
supplementari sui progetti a che cavi di CTLT o a quali CTLT 
partecipa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στη διδασκαλία του Κολοράντο, εκμάθηση και 
ιστοχώρος τεχνολογίας (CTLT). CTLT καθιερώθηκε πάνω 
από τέσσερα έτη πριν για να κινήσει τις καινοτομίες στην 
τεχνολογία και την στοιχείο-οδηγημένη λήψη αποφάσεων στην 
πρακτική των εκπαιδευτικών (προ-Κ-20) πέρα από το Κολοράντο. 
CTLT είναι τώρα ένα πρόγραμμα του σχολείου της 
εκπαίδευσης στο πανεπιστήμιο του Κολοράντο στο Ντένβερ. 
Συνεχίζουμε να εξυπηρετούμε τους εκπαιδευτικούς σε όλα τα 
επίπεδα μέσω ποικίλης επιχορήγηση-χρηματοδοτούμενης από τον και 
αμοιβή-για τις πρωτοβουλίες υπηρεσιών. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος 
παρέχει ένα παράθυρο στις ποικίλες προσφορές CTLT καθώς 
επίσης και των συνδέσεων με τις πρόσθετες πληροφορίες για τα 
προγράμματα ότι είτε μόλυβδοι CTLT είτε στους οποίους CTLT
συμμετέχει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recepción al Web site de la enseñanza, el 
aprender y de la tecnología de Colorado (CTLT). CTLT fue 
establecido sobre hace cuatro años para mover innovaciones en 
tecnología y la toma de decisión data-driven en la práctica de los 
educadores (Pre-K-20) a través de Colorado. CTLT ahora es un 
proyecto de la escuela de la educación en la universidad de Colorado 
en Denver. Continuamos sirviendo a educadores en todos los 
niveles con una variedad de conceder-financiado y honorario-para las 
iniciativas del servicio. Este Web site proporciona a una 
ventana a las ofrendas variadas de CTLT así como conexiones a la 
información adicional sobre los proyectos que los terminales de 
componente de CTLT u o en qué CTLT participa.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087569</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106939</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/ctlt</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
