<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103439</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103439</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087280</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Christ-like Character: A Catholic Priest Champions Henry George</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">A Christ-wie Zeichen: Ein 
Katholisch-Priester-Meister-Henry George</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">A Christ-comme Le Caractère : Henry 
George de Champions de Prêtre de Catholique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Christ-como O Caráter: Um Henry George 
Dos Campeões Do Priest Do Catholic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A Christ-come Il Carattere: Un Henry George 
Dei Campioni Del Priest Del Cattolico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας Χριστός-ομοειδής χαρακτήρας: Ένας 
καθολικός ιερέας υπερασπίζεται Henry George</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A Cristo-como Carácter: Un Henrio George De
los Campeones Del Sacerdote Del Católico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the late 19th century, Irish-Catholic immigrants and their children were a bulwark of the New York Democratic Party and especially the machine politicians of Tammany Hall. In the mayoral election of 1886, Tammany fought hard to retain the support of these Irish-Catholic voters in the race between Democrat Abram Hewitt and United Labor Party candidate Henry George. While Catholic Church leaders opposed George and actively worked to prevent his election, Father Edward McGlynn enthusiastically backed his candidacy and praised him in this 1886 interview. Several years earlier McGlynn had read George's  Progress and Poverty  and had become a committed supporter of his single-tax economic theories. McGlynn's persistent labor activism led to his excommunication in 1887. Although pressure from liberal Catholics brought about his reinstatement in 1892, his superior soon transferred him to upstate New York--thereby removing his voice from the local labor scene.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert waren 
Irisch-Katholische Immigranten und ihre Kinder ein Bollwerk der 
New York demokratischen Partei und besonders die Maschine 
Politiker von Tammany Hall. In der bürgermeisterlichen Wahl von
1886, in Tammany stark gekämpft, um den Support dieser 
Irisch-Katholischen Wähler im Rennen zwischen Demokraten Abram Hewitt
und vereinigtem ArbeitsParteianwärterhenry George beizubehalten. 
Während katholische Kirche Führer entgegengesetztes George und
aktiv gearbeitet, um seine Wahl zu verhindern, hervorbringen, 
unterstützte Edward McGlynn enthusiastisch seine Kandidatur und pries
ihn in diesem Interview 1886. Hatte einige Jahre früheres 
McGlynn Fortschritt und Armut Georges gelesen und war ein festgelegter
Verfechter seiner Einzelnsteuer ökonomischen Theorien geworden. 
McGlynns hartnäckiger Arbeitsaktivismus führte zu sein 
excommunication 1887. Obgleich Druck von den liberalen 
Katholischen seine Wiedereinsetzung 1892 hervorbrachte, übertrug sein
Vorgesetzter ihn bald auf upstate New York -- seine Stimme von der 
lokalen Arbeitsszene dadurch löschen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vers la fin du 19ème siècle, les immigrés 
Irlandais-Catholiques et leurs enfants étaient un rempart du parti 
démocratique de New York et particulièrement les politiciens de 
machine de Tammany hall. Dans l'élection du maire de 1886, 
Tammany combattu dur pour maintenir le support de ces électeurs 
Irlandais-Catholiques dans la course entre le démocrate Abram Hewitt 
et a uni Henry George de candidat de parti travailliste. 
Tandis que l'église catholique George opposé par amorces 
et activement travaillé pour empêcher son élection, engendrent 
Edouard McGlynn a avec enthousiasme soutenu sa candidature et l'a
félicité dans cette entrevue 1886. McGlynn plusieurs années 
plus tôt avait lu le progrès et la pauvreté de George et 
était devenu un défenseur commis de ses théories économiques de 
simple-impôt. L'activisme de travail persistant de McGlynn a 
mené à son excommunication en 1887. Bien que la pression des 
catholiques libéraux ait provoqué son rétablissement en 1892, son 
supérieur l'a bientôt transféré à New York hors de la ville -- retirer
de ce fait sa voix de la scène de travail locale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 1ø século atrasado, os immigrants 
Irish-irish-Catholic e suas crianças eram um bulwark do partido 
democrático de New York e especial os políticos da máquina de 
Tammany salão. Na eleição mayoral de 1886, Tammany lutado 
duramente para reter a sustentação destes eleitores 
Irish-irish-Catholic na raça entre a democrata Abram Hewitt e uniu o 
Henry George do candidato do partido labor. Quando a igreja 
catholic George oposto líderes e trabalhado ativamente para impedir 
sua eleição, genar Edward McGlynn suportou entusiàstica seu 
candidacy e elogiou-o nesta entrevista 1886. Um McGlynn diversos
anos mais adiantado tinha lido o progresso e a pobreza de George e 
tinha-se transformado um supporter cometido de suas teorias 
econômicas do único-imposto. O activism labor persistente de 
McGlynn conduziu a seu excommunication em 1887. Embora a 
pressão dos catholics liberais causasse seu reinstatement em 1892, 
seu superior transferiu-o logo ao upstate New York -- desse modo 
remover sua voz da cena labor local.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verso la fine del diciannovesimo secolo, gli 
immigranti Irlandese-Cattolici ed i loro bambini erano un bulwark del 
partito democratico de New York e particolarmente i politici della 
macchina di Tammany corridoio. Nell'elezione mayoral di 1886, 
Tammany ha combattuto duro per mantenere il supporto di questi 
elettori Irlandese-Cattolici nella corsa fra la carbossimetilazione 
Abram Hewitt ed ha unito il henry Di lavoro George del candidato del 
partito. Mentre i capi della chiesa cattolica hanno 
opposto George ed attivamente hanno lavorato per impedire la sua 
elezione, generare Edward McGlynn ha sostenuto entusiastico la sua 
candidatura e lo ha elogiato in questa intervista 1886. McGlynn 
più iniziale parecchi anni aveva letto il progresso e la povertà del
George e si era transformato in in un sostenitore commesso delle sue 
teorie economiche di singolo-tassa. Il activism di lavoro 
persistente del McGlynn ha condotto al suo excommunication in 1887. 
Anche se la pressione dai cattolici liberali ha determinato la 
sua reintegrazione in 1892, il suo superiore presto lo ha trasferito a
upstate New York -- quindi rimuovere la sua voce dalla scena 
di lavoro locale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, οι ιρλανδικός-καθολικοί
μετανάστες και τα παιδιά τους ήταν ένα πρόχωμα του Δημοκρατικού 
Κόμματος της Νέας Υόρκης και ειδικά των πολιτικών μηχανών της 
αίθουσας Tammany. Στη mayoral εκλογή 1886, Tammany
πάλεψε σκληρά για να διατηρήσει την υποστήριξη αυτών των 
ιρλανδικός-καθολικών ψηφοφόρων στον αγώνα ταχύτητας μεταξύ του 
δημοκράτη Abram Hewitt και ένωσε τον υποψήφιο Henry 
George εργατικού κόμματος. Ενώ οι καθολικοί ηγέτες 
εκκλησιών αντέταξαν George και εργάστηκαν ενεργά για να 
αποτρέψουν την εκλογή του, ο πατέρας Edward McGlynn 
υποστήριξε ενθουσιωδώς την υποψηφιότητά του και τον εγκωμίασε σε 
αυτήν την συνέντευξη 1886. Αρκετά έτη προηγούμενο 
McGlynn είχαν διαβάσει την πρόοδο και την ένδεια George και 
είχαν γίνει δεσμευμένος υποστηρικτής του ενιαίος-φόρου του 
οικονομικές θεωρίες. McGlynn's ο επίμονος ακτιβισμός 
εργασίας οδήγησε excommunication του το 1887. Αν και η 
πίεση από τους φιλελεύθερους Καθολικούς επέφερε την 
επανεγκατάστασή του το 1892, ο ανώτερός του τον μετέφερε 
σύντομα στην εκτός κράτους Νέα Υόρκη -- με αυτόν τον τρόπο 
αφαιρώντας τη φωνή του από την τοπική σκηνή εργασίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la a fines del siglo XIX, los inmigrantes 
Irlande's-Cato'licos y sus niños eran un baluarte del partido 
democrático de Nueva York y especialmente los políticos de la 
máquina de Tammany pasillo. En la elección mayoral de 1886, 
Tammany de combate difícilmente para conservar la ayuda de estos 
votantes Irlande's-Cato'licos en la raza entre el demócrata Abram 
Hewitt y unió el Henrio George del candidato del partido laborista. 
Mientras que la iglesia católica George opuesto los arranques 
de cinta y trabajado activamente para prevenir su elección, engendra 
Edward McGlynn movió hacia atrás entusiástico su candidatura y lo 
elogió en esta entrevista 1886. McGlynn varios años anterior 
había leído el progreso y la pobreza de George y se había 
convertido en un partidario confiado de sus teorías económicas del 
solo-impuesto. El activismo de trabajo persistente de McGlynn 
condujo a su excommunication en 1887. Aunque la presión de 
católicos liberales causó su restablecimiento en 1892, su superior 
pronto lo transfirió al upstate Nueva York -- de tal modo quitar su 
voz de la escena de trabajo local.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087280</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103439</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-christ-like-character-a-catholic-priest-champions-henry-george</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
