<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108521</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108521</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205538</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Flags of the European Union</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Markierungsfahnen des europäischen Anschlußes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Indicateurs de l'union européenne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bandeiras da união européia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bandierine di Unione Europea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σημαίες της Ευρωπαϊκής Ένωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Indicadores de la unión europea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Learn the flags, countries and capital cities of the European Union. Play a variety of learning games, including anagrams, memory games, mystery word games and multiple choice quizzes. The module contains the following levels: Easy flag matching game with European Union flags. Multiple choice quiz: match flags to countries Multiple choice quiz: match capital cities with their countries. Mystery word games: guess capitals and countries. Memory game: match flags and countries. Memory game: match flags and capitals. Anagram games with countries and capitals of the European Union. Cloze test </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erlernen Sie die Markierungsfahnen, die Länder 
und die Hauptstädte des europäischen Anschlußes. Spielen Sie 
eine Vielzahl der erlernenspiele, einschließlich Anagramme, 
Speicherspiele, Geheimniswortspiele und mehrfache auserlesene Quizen. 
Das Modul enthält die folgenden Stufen: Einfache 
Markierungsfahne zusammenpassendes Spiel mit europäischen 
Anschlußmarkierungsfahnen. Mehrfacher auserlesener Quiz: 
Übereinstimmung Markierungsfahnen zum mehrfachen auserlesenen 
Quiz der Länder: Übereinstimmung Hauptstädte mit ihren 
Ländern. Geheimniswortspiele: Vermutungkapitalien und 
-länder. Speicherspiel: Übereinstimmung 
Markierungsfahnen und Länder. Speicherspiel: 
Übereinstimmung Markierungsfahnen und Kapitalien. 
Anagrammspiele mit Ländern und Kapitalien des europäischen 
Anschlußes. Cloze Test</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Apprenez les indicateurs, les pays et les villes 
capitales de l'union européenne. Jouez une variété de jeux 
d'étude, y compris des anagrammes, des jeux de mémoire, des jeux de 
mots de mystère et des jeux bien choisis multiples. Le module 
contient les niveaux suivants : Jeu assorti d'indicateur facile 
avec les indicateurs européens des syndicats. Jeu bien choisi 
multiple : indicateurs d'allumette au jeu bien choisi multiple 
de pays : villes capitales d'allumette avec leurs pays. 
Jeux de mots de mystère : capitaux et pays de conjecture.
Jeu de mémoire : indicateurs et pays d'allumette. 
Jeu de mémoire : indicateurs et capitaux d'allumette. 
Jeux d'anagramme avec des pays et des capitaux de l'union 
européenne. Essai Cloze</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprenda as bandeiras, os países e as cidades 
importantas da união européia. Jogue uma variedade de jogos de
aprendizagem, including anagrams, jogos da memória, jogos de palavra 
do mistério e quizzes bem escolhidos múltiplos. O módulo 
contem os seguintes níveis: Jogo combinando da bandeira fácil 
com as bandeiras européias da união. Quiz bem escolhido 
múltiplo: bandeiras do fósforo ao quiz bem escolhido múltiplo
dos países: cidades importantas do fósforo com seus países. 
Jogos de palavra do mistério: capitais e países da 
suposição. Jogo da memória: bandeiras e países do 
fósforo. Jogo da memória: bandeiras e capitais do 
fósforo. Jogos do anagram com países e capitais da união 
européia. Teste cloze</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Impari le bandierine, i paesi e le città capitali
di Unione Europea. Gioc una varietà di giochi imparanti, compreso i
anagrams, i giochi di memoria, i giochi di parola di mistero ed i quiz
choice multipli. Il modulo contiene i seguenti livelli: 
Gioco di corrispondenza della bandierina facile con le 
bandierine di Unione Europea. Quiz choice multiplo: bandierine
della corrispondenza al quiz choice multiplo dei paesi: città 
capitali della corrispondenza con i loro paesi. Giochi di parola
di mistero: capitali e paesi di congettura. Gioco di 
memoria: bandierine e paesi della corrispondenza. Gioco di
memoria: bandierine e capitali della corrispondenza. 
Giochi del anagram con i paesi ed i capitali di Unione Europea. 
Prova Cloze</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μάθετε τις σημαίες, τις χώρες και τις κύριες πόλεις 
της Ευρωπαϊκής Ένωσης. Παίξτε ποικίλα παιχνίδια 
εκμάθησης, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των αναγραμμάτων, των παιχνιδιών 
μνήμης, των παιχνιδιών λέξης μυστηρίου και των πολλαπλάσιων 
διαγωνισμοων γνώσεων επιλογής. Η ενότητα περιέχει τα 
ακόλουθα επίπεδα: Εύκολο ταιριάζοντας με παιχνίδι σημαιών 
με τις σημαίες της Ευρωπαϊκής Ένωσης. Πολλαπλάσιος 
διαγωνισμός γνώσεων επιλογής: σημαίες αντιστοιχιών στον 
πολλαπλάσιο διαγωνισμό γνώσεων επιλογής χωρών: κύριες 
πόλεις αντιστοιχιών με τις χώρες τους. Παιχνίδια λέξης 
μυστηρίου: κεφάλαια και χώρες εικασίας. Παιχνίδι 
μνήμης: σημαίες και χώρες αντιστοιχιών. Παιχνίδι 
μνήμης: σημαίες και κεφάλαια αντιστοιχιών. Παιχνίδια 
αναγραμμάτων με τις χώρες και τα κεφάλαια της Ευρωπαϊκής Ένωσης.
Cloze δοκιμή</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aprenda los indicadores, los países y las 
ciudades capitales de la unión europea. Juegue una variedad de 
juegos que aprenden, incluyendo anagrams, juegos de la memoria, juegos
de palabra del misterio y concursos bien escogidos múltiples. 
El módulo contiene los niveles siguientes: Juego que 
corresponde con del indicador fácil con los indicadores europeos de 
la unión. Concurso bien escogido múltiple: indicadores 
del emparejamiento al concurso bien escogido múltiple de los países:
ciudades capitales del emparejamiento con sus países. 
Juegos de palabra del misterio: capitales y países de la 
conjetura. Juego de la memoria: indicadores y países del 
emparejamiento. Juego de la memoria: indicadores y 
capitales del emparejamiento. Juegos del anagram con los países
y los capitales de la unión europea. Prueba cloze</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:QEDOC EDUCATIONAL TEAM
FN:QEDOC EDUCATIONAL TEAM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205538</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108521</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/flags-of-the-european-union</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
