<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108071</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108071</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086141</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Eye on the East: Labor Calls for Ban on Chinese Immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auge auf dem Osten: Arbeit Aufrufe für 
Verbot auf chinesischer Immigration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Oeil sur l'est : Appels de travail pour 
l'interdiction de l'immigration chinoise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Olho no leste: Atendimentos do trabalho para
a proibição no immigration chinês</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Occhio sull'est: Richieste di lavoro 
per il divieto di immigrazione cinese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μάτι στην ανατολή: Κλήσεις εργασίας για την 
απαγόρευση στην κινεζική μετανάστευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ojo en el este: Llamadas del trabajo para la
interdicción en la inmigración china</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The San Francisco Building Trades Council (BTC), which Patrick McCarthy helped organize in 1898, actively participated in the anti-Asian agitation that characterized California politics, particularly labor politics, in the late-19th century. The BTC, like the national American Federation of Labor (AFL), argued that the very presence of Chinese (and, after 1900, Japanese and Korean immigrants as well) dragged down the living standards of white workers. This memorial from a 1901 Chinese exclusion convention in San Francisco devoted to strategies for preventing Chinese immigration, called on Congress to use its legislative powers to limit the arrival of Asian aliens to America. It was reprinted in a 1902 AFL pamphlet.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der San Francisco Baugewerbe-Rat (BTC), der 
Patrick McCarthy geholfen, 1898 zu organisieren, aktiv teilgenommen an
der Anti-Asiatischen Bewegung, die Kalifornien Politik kennzeichnete, 
besonders Arbeitspolitik, im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert.
Das BTC, wie die nationale amerikanische Vereinigung der Arbeit 
(AFL), argumentierte, daß die Anwesenheit des Chinesen (und, nach 
1900, japanischer und koreanischer Immigranten außerdem) hinunter die
lebenden Standards der weißen Arbeiter schleppte. Dieses 
Denkmal von einer Ausschlußversammlung mit 1901 Chinesen in San 
Francisco widmete sich Strategien für das Verhindern der chinesischen
Immigration, ersuchter Kongreß, um seine gesetzgebenden Energien zu 
verwenden, die Ankunft der asiatischen Ausländer nach Amerika zu 
begrenzen. Es wurde in einer 1902 AFL Flugschrift neugedruckt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Conseil de industries du bâtiment de San 
Francisco (BTC), qui Patrick McCarthy aidé à organiser en 1898, 
activement participé à l'agitation anti-Asiatique qui a 
caractérisé la politique de la Californie, en particulier la 
politique de travail, en fin du 19me siècle. Le BTC, comme la 
fédération américaine nationale du travail (AFL), a argué du fait 
que la présence même du Chinois (et, après de 1900, japonais et 
coréens immigrés aussi bien) a traîné en bas des normes vivantes 
des ouvriers blancs. Ce mémorial d'une convention d'exclusion 
de 1901 Chinois dans San Francisco a consacré aux stratégies pour 
empêcher l'immigration chinoise, le congrès invité pour utiliser 
ses puissances législatives de limiter l'arrivée des étrangers 
asiatiques en Amérique. Il a été réimprimé dans une 
brochure de 1902 AFL.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O conselho dos comércios de edifício do San 
Francisco (BTC), que Patrick McCarthy ajudado organizar em 1898, 
participado ativamente no agitation anti-anti-Asian que caracterizou a
política de Califórnia, particularmente política labor, no século 
late-19th. O BTC, como o federation americano nacional do 
trabalho (AFL), discutiu que a presença very do chinês (e, após de 
1900, immigrants japoneses e korean também) arrastou abaixo os 
padrões vivos dos trabalhadores brancos. Este memorial de uma 
convenção da exclusão de 1901 chineses em San Francisco devotou às
estratégias para impedir o immigration chinês, congress convidado 
para usar suas potências legislativas limitar a chegada de 
estrangeiros asian a América. Reprinted em um panfleto de 1902 
AFL.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Consiglio di commerci edificio de San Francisco 
(BTC), che Patrick McCarthy contribuito ad organizzare in 1898, 
attivamente partecipato all'agitazione anti-Asiatica che ha 
caratterizzato la politica della California, specialmente politica 
di lavoro, nel fine del 19esimo secolo. Il BTC, come la 
federazione americana nazionale del Lavoro (AFL), ha sostenuto 
che la presenza stessa del cinese (e, dopo di 1900, immigranti 
giapponesi e coreani pure) si è trascinata giù gli standard viventi 
degli operai bianchi. Questo memoriale da una convenzione 1901 
di esclusione di cinese a San Francisco ha dedicato alle 
strategie per impedire l'immigrazione cinese, congresso invitato 
per usare le relative potenzi legislative limitare l'arrivo degli 
stranieri asiatici in America. È stato ristampato in un 
opuscolo di 1902 AFL.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εμπορικό Συμβούλιο κτηρίου του Σαν Φρανσίσκο 
(BTC), που ο Πάτρικ McCarthy βοήθησε να οργανώσει το 1898,
συμμετείχε ενεργά στην αντι-ασιατική αναταραχή που χαρακτήρισε 
την πολιτική Καλιφόρνιας, ιδιαίτερα πολιτική εργασίας, στο 
late-19th αιώνα. Το BTC, όπως την εθνική αμερικανική 
ομοσπονδία της εργασίας (AFL), υποστήριξε ότι η ίδια η 
παρουσία των κινέζικων (και, μετά από το 1900, ιαπωνικών και 
κορεατικών μεταναστών επίσης) που σέρθηκαν κάτω από το βιοτικό 
επίπεδο των λευκών εργαζομένων. Αυτό το μνημείο από μια 
σύμβαση αποκλεισμού του 1901 κινεζική στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο που 
αφιερώθηκε στις στρατηγικές για την κινεζική μετανάστευση, κάλεσε
το συνέδριο για να χρησιμοποιήσει τις νομοθετικές δυνάμεις του να 
περιορίσει την άφιξη των ασιατικών αλλοδαπών στην Αμερική. 
Ανατυπώθηκε σε ένα τεύχος AFL του 1902.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El consejo de los comercios de edificio de San 
Francisco (BTC), que Patrick McCarthy ayudado a ordenar en 1898, 
participado activamente en la agitación contra-Asia'tica que 
caracterizó la política de California, determinado política de 
trabajo, en el siglo de fines del siglo diecinueve. El BTC, como
la federación americana nacional del trabajo (AFL), discutió que la 
misma presencia del chino (y, después de 1900, japoneses y coreanos 
inmigrantes también) arrastrara abajo de los estándares vivos de los
trabajadores blancos. Este monumento de una convención de la 
exclusión de 1901 chinos en San Francisco dedicó a las estrategias 
para prevenir la inmigración china, congreso invitado para utilizar 
sus potencias legislativas de limitar la llegada de extranjeros 
asiáticos a América. Fue reimpreso en un folleto de 1902 AFL.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086141</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108071</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/eye-on-the-east-labor-calls-for-ban-on-chinese-immigration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
