<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106218</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106218</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201841</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Indigenous Myths &amp; Legends </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eingeborene Mythen U. Legenden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mythes et Légendes Indigènes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mitos &amp; Legendas Indígenos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Miti &amp; Leggende Indigeni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γηγενείς μύθοι &amp; μύθοι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mitos Y Leyendas Indígenas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, your students will explore the creation myths and legends of different Indigenous Peoples. They will get the chance to compare and contrast their similarities and differences with other myths and legends from around the world. Applying their newfound information and imagination, they will write and illustrate a myth as a modern day short story for younger children, selecting one of the groups of Indigenous People. The story must be typed and submitted using a word processing program. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität erforschen Ihre 
Kursteilnehmer die Kreation Mythen und die Legenden der 
unterschiedlichen eingeborenen Völker. Sie erhalten die 
Wahrscheinlichkeit, ihre Ähnlichkeiten und Unterschiede zu anderen 
Mythen und zu Legenden um von der Welt zu vergleichen und zu 
kontrastieren. Ihre neuentdeckten Informationen und Phantasie 
anwendend, schreiben sie und veranschaulichen einen Mythus als moderne
Tageskurzschlußgeschichte für jüngere Kinder und wählen eine der 
Gruppen der eingeborenen Völker aus. Die Geschichte muß mit 
einem Textverarbeitung Programm geschrieben werden und eingegeben 
werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, vos étudiants exploreront 
les mythes de création et les légendes du différent peuple 
autochtone. Ils obtiendront la chance de comparer et contraster 
leurs similitudes et différences à d'autres mythes et légendes de 
partout dans le monde. Appliquant la leur information et 
imagination récemment découvertes, ils écriront et illustreront un 
mythe comme histoire moderne de short de jour pour les enfants plus en
bas âge, choisissant un des groupes de peuple autochtone. 
L'histoire doit être tapée et soumise en utilisant un 
programme de traitement de texte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, seus estudantes explorarão os 
mitos da criação e as legendas de povos indígenos diferentes. 
Começarão a possibilidade comparar e contrastar suas 
similaridades e diferenças com outros mitos e legendas em torno do 
mundo. Aplicando suas informação e imaginação newfound, 
escreverão e ilustrarão um mito como uma história moderna do short 
do dia para umas crianças mais novas, selecionando um dos grupos de 
povos indígenos. A história deve ser datilografada e submetido
usando um programa processar de palavra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, i vostri allievi esploreranno
i miti della creazione e le leggende della gente indigena differente. 
Otterranno la probabilità paragonare e contrapporre le loro 
somiglianze e differenze ad altri miti e leggende intorno al mondo. 
Applicando le loro informazioni ed immaginazione newfound, 
scriveranno ed illustreranno un mito come storia moderna di short di 
giorno per i bambini più in giovane età, selezionante uno dei gruppi
della gente indigena. La storia deve essere digitata e 
presentata usando un programma di elaborazione di testi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές σας θα 
ερευνήσουν τους μύθους δημιουργιών και τους μύθους των 
διαφορετικών γηγενών λαών. Θα πάρουν την πιθανότητα να 
συγκριθούν και να αντιπαραβληθούν οι ομοιότητες και οι διαφορές με
άλλους μύθους και οι μύθοι τους από σε όλο τον κόσμο. 
Εφαρμόζοντας τις προσφάτως ανευρεθείσες πληροφορίες και τη 
φαντασία τους, θα γράψουν και θα επεξηγήσουν έναν μύθο ως 
σύγχρονη σύντομη ιστορία ημέρας για τα πιό μικρά παιδιά, που 
επιλέγουν μιας από τις ομάδες γηγενών ανθρώπων. Η ιστορία 
πρέπει να δακτυλογραφηθεί και να υποβληθεί χρησιμοποιώντας ένα 
πρόγραμμα επεξεργασίας κειμένου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, sus estudiantes explorarán los
mitos de la creación y las leyendas de diversa gente indígena. 
Conseguirán la ocasión de comparar y de poner en contraste sus
semejanzas y diferencias con otros mitos y leyendas alrededor del 
mundo. Aplicando su información e imaginación newfound, 
escribirán e ilustrarán un mito como historia moderna del 
cortocircuito del día para niños más jóvenes, seleccionando a uno 
de los grupos de gente indígena. La historia se debe pulsar y 
someter usando un programa del tratamiento de textos de textos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201841</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Free to use or adapt for educational purposes only</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106218</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/indigenous-myths-legends</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
