<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103360</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103360</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Daisyworld Stella Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Daisyworld Stella Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité De Daisyworld Stella</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade De Daisyworld Stella</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Di Daisyworld Stella</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Daisyworld Στέλλα Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad De Daisyworld Stella</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Daisyworld model is a very simple planet that has only two species of life on its surface - white and black daisies, and bare ground. Daisyworld is a good example of homeostasis and was first proposed by James Lovelock as a plausible example of his Gaia hypothesis. The Daisyworld activity helps students build a Stella model of Daisyworld from scratch. After constructing the model they perform guided experiments to explore the behavior of Daisyworld to changes in model parameters and assumptions. Students will learn the basics of Stella and Model construction in the Stella environment, the concept of homeostasis, how to surface albedo changes that can influence local and global temperature and ho to use a plausible plant growth factor as a function of local temperature. The activity takes 3 to 4 hours to complete and is appropriate for introductory geoscience course with an Earth Systems approach. This Starting Point page includes teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas and additional resources on the Daisyworld activity.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Daisyworld Modell ist ein sehr einfacher Planet, 
der nur zwei Sorten Leben auf seinen Oberfläche - weißen und 
schwarzen Gänseblümchen und bloßen Boden hat. Daisyworld ist 
ein gutes Beispiel von Homeostasis und wurde zuerst von James Lovelock
als plausibles Beispiel seiner Gaia Hypothese vorgeschlagen. Die
Daisyworld Aktivität Hilfen Kursteilnehmer bauen ein Stella Modell 
von Daisyworld vom Kratzer auf. Nachdem sie das Modell 
konstruiert haben, führen sie geführte Experimente durch, um das 
Verhalten von Daisyworld zu den Änderungen in den vorbildlichen 
Parametern und in den Annahmen zu erforschen. Kursteilnehmer 
erlernen die Grundlagen von Stella und vorbildlicher Aufbau in der 
Stella Umgebung, das Konzept von Homeostasis, wie man 
Albedoänderungen auftaucht, die lokale und globale Temperatur und das
ho beeinflussen können, zum eines plausiblen Betriebswachstumfaktors 
als Funktion der lokalen Temperatur zu verwenden. Die Aktivität
dauert 3 bis 4 Stunden, zum durchzuführen und ist für einleitenden 
geoscience Kurs mit einer Masse Systeme Annäherung angebracht. 
Diese Ausgangspunktseite schließt unterrichtende Anmerkungen 
und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen und zusätzliche 
Betriebsmittel auf der Daisyworld Aktivität ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le modèle de Daisyworld est une planète très 
simple qui a seulement deux espèces de la vie sur ses marguerites
blanches et noires de surface -, et terre nue. Daisyworld est un
bon exemple d'homéostasie et a été proposé la première fois par 
James Lovelock comme exemple plausible de sa hypothèse de Gaia. 
Les étudiants d'aides d'activité de Daisyworld établissent un
modèle de Stella de Daisyworld à partir de zéro. Après la 
construction du modèle ils exécutent des expériences guidées pour 
explorer le comportement de Daisyworld aux changements des paramètres
et des prétentions modèles. Les étudiants apprendront les 
fondations de Stella et construction modèle dans l'environnement de 
Stella, le concept de l'homéostasie, comment apprêter les 
changements d'albedo qui peuvent influencer la température locale et 
globale et le ho pour utiliser un facteur plausible de croissance de 
plantes en fonction de la température locale. L'activité prend
3 à 4 heures à terminer et est appropriée pour le cours 
préliminaire de geoscience avec une approche systématisée de la 
terre. Cette page de point de départ inclut les notes et les 
extrémités d'enseignement, le matériel didactique, les idées 
d'évaluation et les ressources supplémentaires sur l'activité de 
Daisyworld.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O modelo de Daisyworld é um planeta muito simples
que tenha somente duas espécies da vida em seus daisies brancos e 
pretos da superfície -, e a terra desencapada. Daisyworld é um
exemplo bom da homeostase e foi proposto primeiramente por James 
Lovelock como um exemplo plausible de sua hipótese de Gaia. Os 
estudantes das ajudas da atividade de Daisyworld constroem um modelo 
de Stella de Daisyworld do risco. Após ter construído o modelo
executam experiências guiadas para explorar o comportamento de 
Daisyworld às mudanças nos parâmetros e nas suposições modelo. 
Os estudantes aprenderão os princípios de Stella e a 
construção modelo no ambiente de Stella, o conceito da homeostase, 
como aplainar as mudanças do albedo que podem influenciar a 
temperatura local e global e o ho para usar um fator plausible do 
crescimento de planta em função da temperatura local. A 
atividade faz exame de 3 a 4 horas a terminar e é apropriada para o 
curso introdutório do geoscience com uma aproximação de sistemas da
terra. Esta página do ponto começar inclui notas e pontas 
ensinando, materiais de ensino, idéias da avaliação e recursos 
adicionais na atividade de Daisyworld.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il modello di Daisyworld è un pianeta molto 
semplice che ha soltanto due specie di vita sulle relative margherite 
bianche e nere della superficie - e terra nuda. Daisyworld è un
buon esempio di homeostasis ed in primo luogo è stato proposto da 
James Lovelock come esempio plausibile della sua ipotesi di Gaia. 
Gli allievi di aiuti di attività di Daisyworld sviluppano un 
modello di Stella di Daisyworld da zero. Dopo la costruzione del
modello effettuano gli esperimenti guidati per esplorare il 
comportamento di Daisyworld ai cambiamenti nei parametri e nei 
presupposti di modello. Gli allievi impareranno i principi 
fondamentali di Stella e costruzione di modello nell'ambiente di 
Stella, il concetto di homeostasis, come emergere cambiamenti di 
albedo che possono influenzare la temperatura locale e globale ed il 
ho per usare un fattore plausibile di sviluppo di pianta in funzione 
della temperatura locale. L'attività occorre 3 - 4 ore da 
completare ed è adatta per il corso introduttivo di geoscience con un
approccio sistematico della terra. Questa pagina del punto di 
partenza include le note e punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici, 
idee di valutazione e risorse supplementari sull'attività di 
Daisyworld.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μοντέλο Daisyworld είναι ένας πολύ απλός 
πλανήτης που έχει μόνο δύο είδη ζωής στην επιφάνειά του - 
άσπρες και μαύρες μαργαρίτες, και το γυμνό έδαφος. Το 
Daisyworld είναι ένα καλό παράδειγμα homeostasis και 
προτάθηκε αρχικά από james Lovelock ως εύλογο παράδειγμα 
της υπόθεσης της Gaia του. Η δραστηριότητα Daisyworld 
βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να χτίσουν ένα μοντέλο της Στέλλα 
Daisyworld από την αρχή. Μετά από να κατασκευάσουν το 
μοντέλο εκτελούν τα καθοδηγημένα πειράματα για να ερευνήσουν τη 
συμπεριφορά Daisyworld στις αλλαγές στις πρότυπες παραμέτρους 
και τις υποθέσεις. Οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν τα βασικά της 
Στέλλα και της πρότυπης κατασκευής στο περιβάλλον της Στέλλα, η 
έννοια homeostasis, πώς να εμφανιστούν albedo τις αλλαγές 
που μπορούν να επηρεάσουν την τοπική και σφαιρική θερμοκρασία και
ho για να χρησιμοποιήσει έναν εύλογο παράγοντα αύξησης 
εγκαταστάσεων ως λειτουργία της τοπικής θερμοκρασίας. Η 
δραστηριότητα διαρκεί 3 έως 4 ώρες που ολοκληρώνουν και είναι 
κατάλληλη για την εισαγωγική σειρά μαθημάτων geoscience με μια 
προσέγγιση γήινων συστημάτων. Αυτή η σελίδα αφετηρίας 
περιλαμβάνει τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα 
εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης και τα πρόσθετα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς στη δραστηριότητα Daisyworld.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El modelo de Daisyworld es un planeta muy simple 
que tiene solamente dos especies de la vida en sus margaritas blancas 
y negras de la superficie -, y tierra descubierta. Daisyworld es
un buen ejemplo del homeostasis y primero fue propuesto por James 
Lovelock como ejemplo plausible de su hipótesis de Gaia. Los 
estudiantes de las ayudas de la actividad de Daisyworld construyen un 
modelo de Stella de Daisyworld del rasguño. Después de 
construir el modelo realizan experimentos dirigidos para explorar el 
comportamiento de Daisyworld a los cambios en los parámetros y las 
asunciones modelo. Los estudiantes aprenderán los fundamentos 
de Stella y la construcción modelo en el ambiente de Stella, el 
concepto del homeostasis, cómo emerger los cambios del albedo que 
pueden influenciar temperatura local y global y el ho para utilizar un
factor plausible del crecimiento vegetal en función de temperatura 
local. La actividad toma 3 a 4 horas a terminar y es apropiada 
para el curso introductorio del geoscience con un acercamiento de 
sistemas de la tierra. Esta paginación del punto de partida 
incluye notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales 
didácticos, las ideas del gravamen y los recursos adicionales en la 
actividad de Daisyworld.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103360</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/daisyworld-stella-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
