<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086833</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Six Families Budget Their Money, 1884</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sechs Familien Etat Ihr Geld, 1884</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Budget de Six Familles Leur Argent, 1884</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Orçamento De Seis Famílias Seu Dinheiro, 1884</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Preventivo Delle Sei Famiglie I Loro Soldi, 
1884</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προϋπολογισμός έξι οικογενειών τα χρήματά τους, 
1884</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Presupuesto De Seis Familias Su Dinero, 1884</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">These six family budgets collected by the Illinois Bureau of Labor Statistics in 1884 show the range of family incomes and spending patterns within the working class. Although skill level was probably the most important determinant of wages, relatively few male breadwinners were able to earn a "family wage"--enough to support their wives and children decently. Most families pooled their members' wages in what historians call the "family economy." The wages of children and teenagers often meant the difference between a modicum of comfort and mere survival, and women who were not working for wages sometimes brought in money by operating home-based businesses such as washing clothes or keeping boarders. Women also contributed to the family's economic survival by managing the household budget, sharing resources with other female householders, and scavenging for discarded food, clothes, and fuel. Unlike current times, prices were not constantly rising in the late-19th century, and the period's declining prices (particularly food prices) allowed a modest, gradual improvement in working-class living standards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese sechs Familie Etats sammelten durch das 
Illinois Büro von Arbeitsstatistiken in Erscheinen 1884 die Strecke 
der Familie Einkommen und der Ausgabe Muster innerhalb der Funktion 
Kategorie. Obgleich Fähigkeit Stufe vermutlich der wichtigste 
bestimmende Faktor der Löhne war, konnten verhältnismäßig wenige 
männliche Brotverdiener, einen "Familie Lohn" zu erwerben -- genug, 
um ihre Frauen und Kinder decently zu unterstützen. Die meisten
Familien vereinigten Löhne ihrer Bauteile in, was Historiker nennen 
die "Familie Wirtschaft." Die Löhne der Kinder und der 
Jugendlichen bedeuteten häufig den Unterschied zwischen einem Minimum
des Komforts und bloßem Überleben, und Frauen, die nicht für Löhne
arbeiteten, holten manchmal in Geld durch funktionierende 
Haus-gegründete Geschäfte wie waschende Kleidung oder 
Haltenkostgänger. Frauen trugen auch zum ökonomischen 
Überleben der Familie bei, indem sie den Haushalt Etat handhatten und
Betriebsmittel mit anderen weiblichen Householders und Ausstossen von 
Unreinheiten für verworfene Nahrung, Kleidung und Kraftstoff teilten.
Anders als aktuelle Uhrzeiten stiegen Preise nicht ständig in 
das des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert, und die abfallenden 
Preise der Periode (besonders Lebensmittelpreise) erlaubten eine 
bescheidene, stufenweise Verbesserung in lebenden Standards der 
Arbeiterklasse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces budgets de six familles ont rassemblé par le 
bureau de l'Illinois des statistiques de travail dans l'exposition 
1884 l'intervalle des revenus de famille et des configurations de 
dépense dans la classe ouvrière. Bien que le niveau de 
compétence ait été probablement la cause déterminante la plus 
importante des salaires, relativement peu de soutiens de famille 
mâles pouvaient gagner un "salaire de famille" assez -- pour 
supporter leurs épouses et enfants decently. La plupart des 
familles ont mis les salaires en commun de leurs membres dans ce que 
les historiens appellent l'"économie de famille." Les salaires 
des enfants et des adolescents ont souvent signifié la différence 
entre une parcelle de confort et la seule survie, et les femmes qui ne
travaillaient pas pour des salaires ont parfois apporté l'argent par 
des entreprises maison-basées opérantes telles que les vêtements de
lavage ou des internes de garder. Les femmes ont également 
contribué à la survie économique de la famille en contrôlant le 
budget de ménage, partageant des ressources avec d'autres chefs de 
ménage féminins, et le balayage pour la nourriture, les vêtements, 
et le carburant jetés. À la différence des périodes 
actuelles, les prix n'étaient pas en hausse constamment en fin du 
19me siècle, et les prix en baisse de la période (en particulier 
prix de denrées alimentaires) ont permis une amélioration modeste et
progressive des normes vivantes de classe ouvrier.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estes orçamentos de seis famílias coletaram pelo
departamento de Illinois de statistics labor na mostra 1884 a escala 
de rendas da família e de testes padrões da despesa dentro da classe
de funcionamento. Embora o nível de habilidade fosse 
provavelmente a determinante a mais importante dos salários, 
relativamente poucos breadwinners masculinos podiam  ganhar da "um 
salário família" -- bastante para suportar decently suas esposas e 
crianças. A maioria de famílias pooled salários dos seus 
membros em o que os historians se chamam da "a economia família." 
Os salários das crianças e dos teenagers significaram 
frequentemente a diferença entre um modicum do conforto e a mera 
sobrevivência, e as mulheres que não estavam trabalhando para 
salários trouxeram às vezes no dinheiro por negócios HOME-BASEADOS 
operando-se tais como a roupa de lavagem ou boarders manter-se. 
As mulheres contribuíram também à sobrevivência econômica 
da família controlando o orçamento da casa, compartilhando de 
recursos com outros householders fêmeas, e de scavenging para o 
alimento, a roupa, e o combustível rejeitados. Ao contrário 
das épocas atuais, os preços não se estavam levantando 
constantemente no século late-19th, e os preços declinando do 
período (particularmente preços de alimento) permitiram uma melhoria
modesta, gradual em padrões vivos do working-class.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questi preventivi delle sei famiglie hanno 
raccolto dall'ufficio dell'Illinois delle statistiche Di lavoro 
nell'esposizione 1884 la gamma di redditi della famiglia e modelli 
spendere all'interno del codice categoria di funzionamento. 
Anche se il livello di abilità era probabilmente il 
determinante più importante degli stipendi, relativamente pochi 
breadwinners maschii potevano guadagnare "uno stipendio della 
famiglia" -- abbastanza per sostenere le loro mogli e bambini 
decently. La maggior parte delle famiglie hanno riunito gli 
stipendi dei loro membri in che cosa gli storici chiamano "l'economia 
della famiglia." Gli stipendi dei bambini e degli adolescenti 
hanno significato spesso la differenza fra un modicum di comodità e 
la sopravvivenza pura e le donne che non stavano lavorando per gli 
stipendi a volte hanno portato in soldi dai commerci sede-basati di 
funzionamento quali i vestiti di lavaggio o boarders mantenere. 
Le donne egualmente hanno contribuito alla sopravvivenza 
economica della famiglia gestendo il preventivo della famiglia, 
ripartente le risorse con altri capofamiglia femminili ed il lavaggio 
per l'alimento, i vestiti ed il combustibile scartati. Diverso 
dei periodi correnti, i prezzi non stavano aumentando costantemente 
nel fine del 19esimo secolo ed i prezzi declinanti del periodo 
(specialmente prezzi di alimento) hanno permesso un miglioramento 
modesto e graduale negli standard viventi della classe operaia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτοί οι έξι οικογενειακοί προϋπολογισμοί που 
συλλέγονται από το γραφείο του Ιλλινόις των στατιστικών εργασίας
το 1884 εμφανίζουν τη σειρά των οικογενειακών εισοδημάτων και 
των προτύπων εξόδων μέσα στην εργατική τάξη. Αν και το 
επίπεδο ικανότητας ήταν πιθανώς ο σημαντικότερος καθοριστικός 
παράγοντας των αμοιβών, σχετικά λίγοι αρσενικοί τροφοδότες της 
οικογενείας ήταν σε θέση να κερδίσουν μια "οικογενειακή αμοιβή" 
-- αρκετοί να υποστηρίξουν τις συζύγους και τα παιδιά τους 
decently. Οι περισσότερες οικογένειες συγκέντρωσαν τις 
αμοιβές των μελών τους σε ποιους ιστορικούς καλέστε τη 
"οικογενειακή οικονομία." Οι αμοιβές των παιδιών και των 
εφήβων σήμαναν συχνά τη διαφορά μεταξύ ενός modicum της 
άνεσης και της μόνης επιβίωσης, και τις γυναίκες που δεν 
εργάζονταν για τις αμοιβές που παρουσιάστηκαν μερικές φορές στα 
χρήματα από τις λειτουργούσες σπίτι-βασισμένες επιχειρήσεις 
όπως τα ενδύματα πλύσης ή δεν κρατούσαν τους οικότροφους. 
Οι γυναίκες συνέβαλαν επίσης στην οικογενειακή οικονομική 
επιβίωση με τη διαχείριση του οικιακού προϋπολογισμού, τη 
διανομή των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς με άλλους θηλυκούς 
ιδιοκτήτες, και τη σάρωση για τα απορριμμένα τρόφιμα, τα 
ενδύματα, και τα καύσιμα. Αντίθετα από τους παρόντες 
χρόνους, οι τιμές δεν αυξάνονταν συνεχώς στο late-19th αιώνα, 
και οι μειωμένος τιμές της περιόδου (ιδιαίτερα τιμές τροφίμων) 
επέτρεψαν μια μέτρια, βαθμιαία βελτίωση στο βιοτικό επίπεδο 
εργατικών τάξεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estos presupuestos de seis familias recogieron por
la oficina de Illinois de la estadística de trabajo en la 
demostración 1884 el rango de las rentas de la familia y de los 
modelos del gasto dentro de la clase obrera. Aunque el nivel de 
habilidad era probablemente el determinante más importante de 
salarios, relativamente pocos breadwinners masculinos podían ganar un
"salario de la familia" -- bastante para apoyar a sus esposas y niños
decently. La mayoría de las familias reunieron los salarios de 
sus miembros en lo que llaman los historiadores la "economía de la 
familia." Los salarios de niños y de adolescentes significaron 
a menudo la diferencia entre un modicum de la comodidad y la 
supervivencia mera, y las mujeres que no trabajaban para los salarios 
trajeron a veces en dinero por negocios hogar-basados de 
funcionamiento tales como ropas que se lavaban o los huéspedes el 
guardar. Las mujeres también contribuyeron a la supervivencia 
económica de la familia manejando el presupuesto de la casa, 
compartiendo recursos con otros cabezas de familia femeninos, y el 
barrido para el alimento, las ropas, y el combustible desechados. 
Desemejante de épocas actuales, los precios no se levantaban 
constantemente en el siglo de fines del siglo diecinueve, y los 
precios que declinaban del período (determinado precios de alimento) 
permitieron una mejora modesta, gradual en estándares vivos de la 
clase obrera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086833</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106671</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/six-families-budget-their-money-1884</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
