<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106162</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106162</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202572</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Connecting Folktales and Culture in North Carolina and Beyond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anschließendes Folktales und Kultur in 
Nord-Carolina und jenseits</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Folktales se reliant et culture en Caroline 
du nord et là-bas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Folktales conectando e cultura em North.carolina e
além</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Folktales di collegamento e coltura in 
North.carolina e di là</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύνδεση Folktales και πολιτισμός στη βόρεια 
Καρολίνα και πέρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Folktales que conecta y cultura en Carolina del 
Norte y más allá</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students will explore connections to North Carolina culture as they engage in reading and analyzing three folktales of North Carolina Literary Festival author, William Hooks. After comparing these stories to other versions of the traditional tales, students will become authors and storytellers themselves as they rewrite a tale from a new cultural point of view. Opportunities are also included to extend this study to world cultures and folktales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer erforschen Anschlüsse zur 
Nord-Carolina Kultur, wie sie sich engagieren, wenn sie drei folktales
Nord-Carolina literarischen Festivalautor lesen und analysieren, 
William Haken. Nachdem sie diese Geschichten mit anderen 
Versionen der traditionellen Geschichten verglichen haben, werden 
Kursteilnehmer Autoren und storytellers selbst, wie sie eine 
Geschichte von einem neuen kulturellen Gesichtspunkt neu schreiben. 
Gelegenheiten sind auch, diese Studie auf Weltkulturen und 
folktales auszudehnen eingeschlossen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants exploreront des connexions à la 
culture du nord de la Caroline comme ils s'engagent en lisant et 
en analysant trois folktales d'auteur littéraire du nord de 
festival de la Caroline, crochets de William. Après avoir 
comparé ces histoires à d'autres versions des contes traditionnels, 
les étudiants deviendront les auteurs et les storytellers eux-mêmes 
comme ils récrivent un conte d'un nouveau point de vue culturel. 
Des occasions sont également incluses d'étendre cette étude 
aux cultures et aux folktales du monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes explorarão conexões à cultura de 
North.carolina como acoplam em ler e em analisar três folktales do 
autor literário do festival de North.carolina, ganchos de William. 
Após ter comparado estas histórias a outras versões dos tales
tradicionais, os estudantes transformar-se-ão os autores e os 
storytellers eles mesmos como reescrevem um tale de um ponto cultural 
novo da vista. As oportunidades são incluídas também de 
estender este estudo às culturas e aos folktales do mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi esploreranno i collegamenti alla 
coltura del North.carolina come si agganciano nella lettura e 
nell'analizzare dei tre folktales dell'autore letterario di 
Festival del North.carolina, ganci del William. Dopo avere 
confrontato queste storia ad altre versioni dei racconti tradizionali,
gli allievi si transformeranno in in autori ed in storytellers essi 
stessi come riscrivono un racconto da un nuovo punto di vista 
culturale. Le occasioni egualmente sono incluse estendere questo
studio fino le colture ed i folktales del mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα ερευνήσουν τις συνδέσεις στον 
πολιτισμό της βόρειας Καρολίνας όπως συμμετέχουν στην ανάγνωση 
και την ανάλυση τριών folktales του λογοτεχνικού συντάκτη 
φεστιβάλ της βόρειας Καρολίνας, William Hooks. Μετά 
από να συγκρίνουν αυτές τις ιστορίες με άλλες εκδόσεις των 
παραδοσιακών ιστοριών, οι σπουδαστές θα γίνουν συντάκτες και 
storytellers οι ίδιοι δεδομένου ότι ξαναγράφουν μια ιστορία 
από νέα πολιτιστική άποψη. Οι ευκαιρίες συμπεριλαμβάνονται
επίσης για να επεκτείνουν αυτήν την μελέτη στους παγκόσμιους 
πολιτισμούς και folktales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes explorarán las conexiones a la 
cultura de Carolina del Norte como enganchan a leer y a analizar tres 
folktales de autor literario del festival de Carolina del Norte, 
ganchos de Guillermo. Después de comparar estas historias a 
otras versiones de los cuentos tradicionales, los estudiantes harán 
los autores y los storytellers ellos mismos como reescriben un cuento 
desde un nuevo punto de vista cultural. Las oportunidades 
también se incluyen de ampliar este estudio a las culturas y a los 
folktales del mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JEANNE MUNOZ
FN:JEANNE MUNOZ
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202572</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106162</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/connecting-folktales-and-culture-in-north-carolina-and-beyond</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
