<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108418</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108418</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205475</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Made</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikaner Bildete</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Américain A fait</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Americano Fêz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'Americano Ha fatto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανός έκανε</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Americano Hizo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"American Made" is a film about a Sikh American family whose car breaks down en route to the Grand Canyon, and their only hope for escape is the remote desert highway and the occasional passing car. When car after car fails to stop, family members are forced to confront their notions of faith, conformity, tradition, and sacrifice-and question what it means to be "American" today. This lesson plan includes discussion activities about the definition of family, cultural research activities, and writing assignments related to students' personal histories.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der gebildete Amerikaner" ist ein Film über eine
Sikh amerikanische Familie deren Auto unten auf dem Weg zum Grand 
Canyon bricht, und ihre nur Hoffnung für Entweichen ist die 
Remotewüste Datenbahn und das gelegentliche überschreitene Auto. 
Wenn werden Auto, nachdem Auto stoppen nicht kann, Familie 
Bauteile erzwungen, ihre Begriffe des Glaubens, der Übereinstimmung, 
der Tradition und Opfer-und der Frage zu konfrontieren, was es 
bedeutet, zu sein "Amerikaner" heute. Dieser Lektionplan 
schließt Diskussion Aktivitäten über die Definition der Familie, 
kulturelle Forschung Aktivitäten und die Schreiben Anweisungen, die 
auf persönlichen Geschichten der Kursteilnehmer in Verbindung 
gestanden werden ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'"Américain fait" est un film au sujet d'une 
famille américaine sikhe dont la voiture est en panne en route 
à la gorge grande, et leur seulement espoir pour l'évasion est 
l'omnibus à distance de désert et la voiture de dépassement 
occasionnelle. Quand la voiture après que la voiture ne 
s'arrête pas, membres de famille sont forcées de confronter leurs 
notions de la foi, de la conformité, de la tradition, et sacrifice-et
de la question ce que signifie elle pour être "Américain" 
aujourd'hui. Ce plan de leçon inclut des activités de 
discussion au sujet de la définition de la famille, des activités 
culturelles de recherches, et des affectations d'écriture liées aux 
histoires personnelles des étudiants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o "americano feito" é uma película sobre uma 
família americana de Sikh cujo o carro quebre para baixo a caminho à
garganta grande, e sua somente esperança para o escape é a estrada 
remota do deserto e o carro de passagem ocasional. Quando o 
carro depois que o carro não para, membros da família é forçado a 
confrontar suas noções da fé, do conformity, da tradição, e 
sacrifício-e da pergunta o que significa ser "americano" hoje. 
Esta planta da lição inclui atividades da discussão sobre a 
definição da família, atividades cultural da pesquisa, e 
atribuições da escrita relacionadas aos histories pessoais dos 
estudantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'americano fatto" è una pellicola circa una 
famiglia americana di Sikh di cui l'automobile analizza in viaggio al 
grande canyon e la loro soltanto speranza per la fuga è la strada 
principale a distanza del deserto e l'automobile passante occasionale.
Quando l'automobile dopo che l'automobile non riesca a 
arrestarsi, membri della famiglia è costretto a confrontare le loro 
nozioni di fede, di conformità, di tradizione e sacrificio-e della 
domanda che cosa significa oggi essere "americano". Questo 
programma di lezione include le attività di discussione circa la 
definizione della famiglia, le attività culturali di ricerca e le 
assegnazioni di scrittura relative ai dati storici personali degli 
allievi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αμερικανός που γίνεται" είναι μια ταινία για μια σιχ 
αμερικανική οικογένεια το της οποίας αυτοκίνητο παθαίνει βλάβη 
καθ'οδόν στο μεγάλο φαράγγι, και η μόνη ελπίδα τους για τη 
διαφυγή είναι η απομακρυσμένη εθνική οδός ερήμων και το 
περιστασιακό περνώντας αυτοκίνητο. Όταν το αυτοκίνητο 
αφότου αποτυγχάνει να σταματήσει το αυτοκίνητο, οικογενειακά 
μέλη αναγκάζεται να αντιμετωπίσει τις έννοιές τους πίστης, 
συμμόρφωσης, παράδοσης, και θυσία-και ερώτησης τι σημαίνει για να
είναι "αμερικανικά" σήμερα. Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος 
περιλαμβάνει τις δραστηριότητες συζήτησης για τον καθορισμό της 
οικογένειας, τις πολιτιστικές ερευνητικές δραστηριότητες, και τις 
αναθέσεις γραψίματος σχετικές με τις προσωπικές ιστορίες των 
σπουδαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el "americano hecho" es una película sobre una 
familia americana de Sikh que coche analice en el camino a la barranca
magnífica, y su solamente esperanza del escape es la carretera 
alejada del desierto y el coche que pasa ocasional. Cuando el 
coche después de que el coche no pueda parar, miembros de la familia 
se fuerza enfrentar sus nociones de la fe, de la conformidad, de la 
tradición, y sacrificio-y de la pregunta qué significa ser 
"americano" hoy. Este plan de la lección incluye actividades de
la discusión sobre la definición de la familia, actividades 
culturales de la investigación, y las asignaciones de la escritura 
relacionadas con las historias personales de los estudiantes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205475</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108418</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-made</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
