<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104603</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104603</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206542</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Artifact Road Show</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kunstprodukt-Straße Erscheinen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Exposition de Route d'Objet façonné</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mostra Da Estrada Do Artifact</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esposizione Della Strada Del Manufatto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο δρόμος χειροποίητου αντικειμένου εμφανίζει</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Demostración Del Camino Del Artefacto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">outlines a staff development workshop and offers lessons designed to help students put historical events in context and see them as a part of a larger story. Use of primary resources is the focus -- where to find them, what they are, how to examine them, and how to construct the context to tell the whole story.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">umreißt eine Personalentwicklung Werkstatt und 
bietet die Lektionen an, die konzipiert sind, um Kursteilnehmern zu 
helfen, historische Fälle in Kontext einzusetzen und sie als Teil 
einer größeren Geschichte zu sehen. Gebrauch von 
Primärbetriebsmitteln ist der Fokus -- wo man findet sie, was sie 
sind, wie man sie überprüft und wie man den Kontext konstruiert, um 
die vollständige Geschichte zu erklären.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">trace les grandes lignes d'un atelier de 
perfectionnement du personnel et offre des leçons conçues pour aider
des étudiants à mettre des événements historiques dans le contexte
et à les voir comme partie d'une plus grande histoire. 
L'utilisation des ressources primaires est le foyer -- où 
trouver elles, ce qui sont elles, comment les examiner, et comment 
construire le contexte pour dire l'histoire entière.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">esboça uma oficina do desenvolvimento de equipe 
de funcionários e oferece as lições projetadas ajudar a estudantes 
pôr eventos históricos no contexto e vê-los como uma parte de uma 
história maior. O uso de recursos preliminares é o foco -- 
onde encontrar os, o que são, como examiná-los, e como construir o 
contexto para dizer a história inteira.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive un workshop di sviluppo di personale ed 
offre le lezioni destinate per aiutare gli allievi a mettere gli 
eventi storici nel contesto ed a vederli come parte di più grande 
storia. L'uso delle risorse primarie è il fuoco -- dove trovare
loro, che cosa sono, come esaminarle e come costruire il contesto per 
dire alla storia intera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει ένα εργαστήριο ανάπτυξης προσωπικού και 
προσφέρει τα μαθήματα με σκοπό να βοηθήσουν τους σπουδαστές να 
βάλουν τις ιστορικές εκδηλώσεις στο πλαίσιο και να τις 
δουν ως μέρος μιας μεγαλύτερης ιστορίας. Η χρήση
των αρχικών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς είναι η εστίαση -- πού να 
αυτοί βρεθούν, τι είναι, πώς να τα εξετάσουν, και πώς να 
κατασκευάσουν το πλαίσιο για να πουν ολόκληρη την ιστορία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contornea un taller del desarrollo de personal y 
ofrece las lecciones diseñadas para ayudar a estudiantes a poner 
acontecimientos históricos en contexto y a verlos como parte de una 
historia más grande. El uso de recursos primarios es el foco --
donde encontrar los, cuáles son, cómo examinarlos, y cómo construir
el contexto para contar la historia entera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206542</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104603</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/artifact-road-show</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
