<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103368</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103368</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087139</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Traveling.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reisen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Déplacement.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Viajar.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Viaggiare.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ταξίδι.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El viajar.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After the Civil War, southern African Americans exercised their new freedom in many ways; one of them was traveling where and when they chose. Thousands of newly freedpeople took to the roads at war's end, most of them trying to reunite with family members sold away or displaced during the war. In some cases, freedmen and women walked hundreds of miles in search of parents, children, siblings, or spouses. This engraving was published in Edward King's  The Great South , one of many postwar surveys of southern life that fed northerners' curiosity about the region that they had defeated in war.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach dem Bürgerkrieg übten südliche afrikanische 
Amerikaner ihre neue Freiheit in vielen Methoden aus; einer von 
ihnen reiste wohin und als sie wählten. Tausenden eben 
freedpeople nahmen zu den Straßen am Ende des Krieges, verkauften die
meisten ihnen versuchend, sich mit Familie Bauteilen zu 
wiedervereinigen weg oder verlegt während des Krieges. In 
einigen Fällen gingen Freedmen und Frauen Hunderte Meilen auf der 
Suche nach Eltern, Kindern, Geschwister oder Gatten. Dieser 
Stich wurde in The Great South, eine des Edward Königs vieler 
Nachkriegsübersichten der südlichen Lebensdauer veröffentlicht, die
Neugier der northerners' über die Region einzogen, die sie im Krieg 
besiegt hatten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après la guerre civile, les Américains africains 
méridionaux ont exercé leur nouvelle liberté de beaucoup de voies ;
l'un d'entre eux voyageait où et quand ils ont choisi. 
Les milliers nouvellement de freedpeople ont pris aux routes à 
l'extrémité de la guerre, la plupart d'entre elles essayant de 
réunir aux membres de famille s'est vendue loin ou déplacé pendant 
la guerre. Dans certains cas, les freedmen et les femmes ont 
marché des centaines de milles à la recherche des parents, des 
enfants, des enfants de mêmes parents, ou des conjoints. Cette 
gravure a été éditée dans The Great sud, une d'Edouard 
du Roi de beaucoup d'études d'après-guerre de la vie méridionale 
qui curiosité ont alimenté habitants du Nord 'au sujet de la région 
qu'ils avaient défaite dans la guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após a guerra civil, os americanos africanos do sul 
exercitaram sua liberdade nova em muitas maneiras; um deles 
viajava aonde e quando escolheram. Os milhares recentemente do 
freedpeople fizeram exame às estradas na extremidade da guerra, a 
maioria delas que tentam reun com os membros da família venderam 
afastado ou deslocado durante a guerra. Em alguns casos, os 
freedmen e as mulheres andaram centenas das milhas na busca dos pais, 
das crianças, dos siblings, ou dos esposos. Este engraving foi 
publicado em Grande Sul de Edward do rei, um de muitos exames postwar 
da vida do sul que alimentaram a curiosidade dos northerners' sobre a 
região que tinham derrotado na guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo la guerra civile, gli Americani africani del sud 
hanno esercitato la loro nuova libertà in molti modi; un di 
loro stava viaggiando dove e quando hanno scelto. Le migliaia 
recentemente di freedpeople hanno preso alle strade all'estremità 
della guerra, la maggior parte di loro che provano a reunite con i 
membri della famiglia hanno venduto via o spostato durante la guerra. 
In alcuni casi, i freedmen e le donne hanno camminato centinaia 
delle miglia alla ricerca dei genitori, dei bambini, dei fratelli 
germani, o degli sposi. Questa incisione è stata pubblicata in 
The Great South, una di Edward del re di molte indagini dopoguerra di 
vita del sud che hanno alimentato la curiosità dei northerners circa 
la regione che avevano sconfitto nella guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο, νότιοι αφρικανικοί 
Αμερικανοί άσκησαν τη νέα ελευθερία τους από πολλές απόψεις  
ένας από τους ταξίδευε όπου και πότε επέλεξαν. 
Χιλιάδες freedpeople πρόσφατα πήραν στους δρόμους στο 
πολεμικό τέλος, τα περισσότερα από τους που προσπαθούν να 
επανασυνδέσουν με τα οικογενειακά μέλη που πωλήθηκαν μακριά ή 
που μετατοπίστηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου. Σε μερικές
περιπτώσεις, οι απελεύθεροι και οι γυναίκες περπάτησαν τις 
εκατοντάδες των μιλίων σε αναζήτηση των γονέων, των παιδιών, των 
αμφιθαλών, ή των συζύγων. Αυτή η χάραξη δημοσιεύθηκε νότο
του Edward King's στο μεγάλο, μια από πολλές μεταπολεμικές 
έρευνες για τη νότια ζωή που τααΐε την περιέργεια των βορείων 
για την περιοχή που είχαν νικήσει στον πόλεμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de la guerra civil, los americanos africanos 
meridionales ejercitaron su nueva libertad de muchas maneras; 
una de ellos viajaba adonde y cuando eligieron. Los 
millares de freedpeople llevaron nuevamente los caminos en el extremo 
de la guerra, la mayoría de ellos que intentaban juntarse con los 
miembros de la familia vendieron lejos o desplazado durante la guerra.
En algunos casos, los freedmen y las mujeres recorrieron los 
centenares de millas en la búsqueda de padres, de niños, de 
hermanos, o de esposos. Este grabado fue publicado en The Great 
South, una de Edward de rey de muchas encuestas de la posguerra de la 
vida meridional que alimentaron la curiosidad de los northerners sobre
la región que habían derrotado en guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087139</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103368</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/traveling</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
