<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106066</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106066</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085252</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Life on the Home Front</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leben auf der Hauptfrontseite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vie sur l'avant à la maison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vida na parte dianteira home</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vita sulla parte anteriore domestica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωή στο μέτωπο "Οικιαών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vida en el frente casero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As the picture of the 1942 Santa Ana High School graduating class shows, uniformed graduates were headed into the service right after graduation day  some may have been volunteers and others drafted. Those who weren't eligible for service could volunteer to help the war effort at home. As the images in this topic show, people at home contributed to the war effort in a variety of ways. Many people readied for possible enemy attack. In one photograph men carry glass globes that will dim street lamps and allow for a "blackout" so that enemy planes won't be able to see the location of a city or town. Another photograph shows volunteer air spotters looking at a map, and another shows a women at a table recruiting volunteers to help spot suspicious aircraft. Raising money was another way to help. Some civilians supported the war effort by buying war bonds directly. Others raised money for war bonds through fundraisers like the Shangri La Queen beauty contest, pictured here. Many products were rationed during the war, and the government emphasized the importance of self-sufficiency. Nearly 20 million Americans  including the fourth-grade children in Colorado and a Japanese-American family relocated to Madison, Wisconsin, shown here answered the government's request to plant "victory gardens" to raise their own food. These gardens, large and small, produced up to 40% of all food that was consumed. One photo even shows children raising rabbits for food in their back yard. Not everyone supported the war effort. As you can see in the photograph of a peace protest at UC Berkeley, some citizens wanted no part in the war and held peace strikes and rallies. After the bombing of Pearl Harbor, life at home changed for Japanese Americans. Those on the West Coast faced internment in addition to prejudice and discrimination. During a brief period before internment became mandatory, Japanese Americans were allowed to choose voluntary evacuation to the Midwest. A photograph shows the Nomura family standing in front of their new home in Madison, Wisconsin.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während die Abbildung der Sankt Ana High School 
graduierenden Kategorie Erscheinen 1942, uniformed, wurden Absolvent 
in das Service-Recht, nachdem Staffelungtag einige Freiwilliger 
gewesen sein können und in gezeichnete worden andere vorangegangen. 
Die, die nicht für Service geeignet waren, konnten sich 
freiwillig erbieten, der Kriegbemühung zu Hause zu helfen. Da 
die Bilder in diesem Thema darstellen, trugen Leute zu Hause zur 
Kriegbemühung in einer Vielzahl von Methoden bei. Viele Leute 
vorbereitet für möglichen feindlichen Angriff. In einer 
Fotographie tragen Männer Glaskugeln, die Straße Lampen verdunkeln 
und eine "Verdunkelung" zulassen, damit feindliche Flächen nicht 
können, den Standort einer Stadt oder der Stadt zu sehen. Eine 
anderen freiwilligen Luftaufklärer der Fotographie Erscheinen, die 
eine Karte betrachten, und eine anderen Erscheinen Frauen an eine 
Tabelle einziehenden Freiwilligern, um zu helfen, mißtrauisches 
Flugzeug zu beschmutzen. Geld anzuheben war eine andere Methode 
zu helfen. Einige Zivilisten unterstützten die Kriegbemühung, 
indem sie direkt Kriegbindungen kauften. Andere hoben das Geld 
für Kriegbindungen durch Geldbeschaffer wie den Shangri 
La-Königinschönheit Wettbewerb an, hier dargestellt. Viele 
Produkte wurden während des Krieges rationiert, und die Regierung hob
den Wert von Selbstüberhebung hervor. Fast 20 Million 
Amerikaner einschließlich die Viertgrad Kinder in Kolorado und eine 
Japanisch-Amerikanische Familie verlagerten nach Madison, Wisconsin, 
gezeigt hier geantwortet dem Antrag der Regierung, "Sieggärten" zu 
errichten, um ihre eigene Nahrung anzuheben. Diese Gärten, 
groß und klein, produziert bis 40% aller Nahrung, die verbraucht 
wurde. Ein Foto zeigt sogar die Kinder, die Kaninchen für 
Nahrung in ihrem rückseitigen Yard anheben. Nicht jeder 
unterstützte die Kriegbemühung. Wie Sie in die Fotographie 
eines Friedensprotestes bei UC Berkeley sehen können, wünschten 
einige Bürger kein Teil im Krieg und hielten Friedensschläge und 
Sammlungen an. Nach der Bombardierung von Pearl Harbor, änderte
das Leben zu Hause für japanische Amerikaner. Die auf der 
Westküste stellten Internierung zusätzlich zum Vorurteil und zur 
Unterscheidung gegenüber. Während einer kurzen Periode, bevor 
Internierung den vorgeschriebenen stand, japanischen Amerikanern 
wurden gewährt, um freiwillige Evakuierung zum Mittelwesten zu 
wählen. Eine Fotographie zeigt die Nomura Familie, die vor 
ihrem neuen Haus in Madison, Wisconsin steht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Car l'image de la classe 1942 recevante un diplôme
de lycée de Santa Ana montre, des diplômés en uniforme ont
été dirigés dans la droite de service après que jour de remise des
diplômes certains aient pu avoir été des volontaires et d'autres 
dessinées. Ceux qui n'étaient pas habilités au service 
pourraient offrir pour aider l'effort de guerre à la maison. 
Car les images dans ce sujet montrent, les gens ont à la maison
contribué à l'effort de guerre par une multitude de moyens. 
Beaucoup de personnes préparées pour l'attaque ennemie 
possible. En une photographie les hommes portent les globes de 
verre qui obscurciront des réverbères et tiendront compte d'un 
"arrêt total" de sorte que les avions ennemis ne puissent pas voir 
l'emplacement d'une ville ou d'une ville. Des autres 
observateurs volontaires d'air d'expositions de photographie regardant
une carte, et des expositions différentes femmes aux volontaires 
recruteurs d'une table pour aider à repèrer l'avion soupçonneux. 
Le soulèvement de l'argent était une autre voie d'aider. 
Quelques civils ont supporté l'effort de guerre en achetant des
obligations de guerre directement. D'autres ont soulevé 
l'argent pour des obligations de guerre par des collecteurs de fonds comme le 
concours de beauté de reine de La de Shangri, décrit ici. 
Beaucoup de produits ont été rationnés pendant la guerre, et 
le gouvernement a souligné l'importance de art de l'auto-portrait-sufficiency. 
Presque 20 millions d'Américains comprenant les enfants de 
quatrième-catégorie dans le Colorado et une famille 
Japonais-Américaine ont replacé à Madison, le Wisconsin, montré 
ici répondu la demande du gouvernement de planter des "jardins de 
victoire" pour soulever leur propre nourriture. Ces jardins, 
grand et petit, produits jusqu'à 40% de toute la nourriture qui a 
été consommée. Une photo montre même des enfants soulevant 
des lapins pour la nourriture en leur cour arrière. Pas chacun 
a supporté l'effort de guerre. Comme vous pouvez voir dans la 
photographie d'une protestation de paix chez Berkeley UC, quelques 
citoyens n'ont voulu aucune partie dans la guerre et ont tenu des 
grèves et des rassemblements de paix. Après le bombardement du
port de perle, la vie a à la maison changé pour les Américains 
japonais. Ceux sur la côte occidentale ont fait face à 
l'internement en plus du préjudice et de la discrimination. 
Pendant une brève période avant que l'internement soit allé 
bien aux Américains obligatoires et japonais ont été laissés 
choisir l'évacuation volontaire au Midwest. Une photographie 
montre la famille de Nomura se tenant devant leur nouvelle maison à 
Madison, le Wisconsin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto o retrato das mostras 1942 se graduando da
classe da High School de Santa Ana, uniformed os graduados foram 
dirigidos na direita do serviço depois que dia de graduação alguns 
podem ter sido voluntários e em outra esboçada. Aqueles que 
não eram elegíveis para o serviço poderiam oferecer-se para ajudar 
ao esforço da guerra na HOME. Porque as imagens neste tópico 
mostram, os povos na HOME contribuíram ao esforço da guerra em uma 
variedade das maneiras. Muitos povos aprontados para o ataque 
inimigo possível. Em uma fotografia os homens carregam os 
globos de vidro que escurecerão lâmpadas de rua e as permitirão um 
"escurecimento" de modo que os planos inimigos não possam  ver a 
posição de uma cidade ou de uma cidade. Uns outros 
observadores voluntários do ar das mostras da fotografia que olham um
mapa, e umas outras mostras mulheres em voluntários recrutando de uma
tabela para ajudar manchar o avião suspicious. Levantar o 
dinheiro era uma outra maneira ajudar. Alguns civis suportaram o
esforço da guerra comprando ligações de guerra diretamente. 
Outros levantaram o dinheiro para ligações de guerra com os 
fundraisers como a competição da beleza da rainha do la de Shangri, 
retratado aqui. Muitos produtos foram racionados durante a 
guerra, e o governo emfatizou a importância do self-sufficiency. 
Quase 20 milhão americanos including as crianças da 
quarto-classe em Colorado e uma família Japonês-Americana relocated 
a Madison, Wisconsin, mostrado respondido aqui o pedido do governo 
plantar da "jardins vitória" para levantar seu próprio alimento. 
Estes jardins, grande e pequeno, produzidos até 40% de todo o 
alimento que foi consumido. Uma foto mostra mesmo as crianças 
que levantam coelhos para o alimento em sua jarda traseira. Não
todos suportou o esforço da guerra. Como você pode ver na 
fotografia de um protesto da paz em Berkeley UC, alguns cidadãos não
quiseram nenhuma parte na guerra e prenderam batidas e rallies da paz.
Após o bombardeio do porto de pérola, a vida na HOME mudou 
para americanos japoneses. Aqueles na costa ocidental 
enfrentaram o internamento além para prejudicar e a discriminação. 
Durante um período breve antes que o internamento assentou bem 
em americanos imperativos, japoneses foram reservados para escolher a 
evacuação voluntária ao Midwest. Uma fotografia mostra a 
família de Nomura que está na frente de sua HOME nova em Madison, 
Wisconsin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre l'immagine delle esposizioni di laurea 1942 
del codice categoria della High School della Santa Ana, uniformed i 
laureati capo nella destra di servizio dopo che giorno di graduazione 
alcuni potessero essere volontari ed in altre disegnate. Coloro 
che non era eleggibile per servizio potrebbero offrirsi 
volontariamente per aiutare lo sforzo di guerra nel paese. 
Poichè le immagini in questo soggetto mostrano, la gente nel 
paese ha contribuito allo sforzo di guerra in una varietà di modi. 
Molta gente ha aspettato per l'attacco nemico possibile. 
In una fotografia gli uomini trasportano i globi di vetro che 
oscureranno le lampade di via e terranno conto "una mancanza di 
corrente elettrica" in modo che gli aerei nemici non possano vedere la
posizione di una città o di una città. Gli altri spotters 
volontari dell'aria di esposizioni della fotografia che guardano un 
programma e lle altre esposizioni donne ai volontari di reclutamento 
della tabella per contribuire a macchiare velivolo sospettoso. 
L'innalzamento dei soldi era un altro modo aiutare. Alcuni
civili hanno sostenuto lo sforzo di guerra comprando i legami di 
guerra direttamente. Altri hanno alzato i soldi per i legami di 
guerra con i fundraisers come il concorso di bellezza della regina 
della La di Shangri, descritti qui. Molti prodotti sono stati 
razionati durante la guerra ed il governo ha dato risalto 
all'importanza di autosufficienza. Quasi 20 milione Americani 
compreso i bambini di quarto-grade in Colorado e una famiglia 
Giapponese-Americana hanno riassegnato a Madison, Wisconsin, indicato 
qui risposto a la richiesta del governo di piantare "i giardini di 
vittoria" per alzare il loro proprio alimento. Questi giardini, 
grande e piccolo, prodotti fino a 40% di tutto l'alimento che è stato
consumato. Una foto persino mostra i bambini che alzano i 
conigli per alimento nella loro iarda posteriore. Non tutto ha 
sostenuto lo sforzo di guerra. Come potete vedere nella 
fotografia di una protesta di pace a Berkeley UC, alcuni cittadini non
hanno desiderato parte nella guerra ed hanno tenuto i colpi ed i 
raduni di pace. Dopo il bombardamento del porto di perla, la 
vita nel paese è cambiato per gli Americani giapponesi. Quelli 
sul litorale ad ovest hanno affrontato l'internamento oltre che il 
pregiudizio e la distinzione. Durante il breve periodo prima che
l'internamento stesse bene agli Americani obbligatori e giapponesi si 
sono conceduti scegliere l'evacuamento volontario al Midwest. 
Una fotografia mostra la famiglia di Nomura che si leva in piedi
davanti la loro nuova sede a Madison, Wisconsin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όπως η εικόνα της ana Santa του 1942 κλάσης 
βαθμολόγησης γυμνασίου εμφανίζει, οι πτυχιούχοι διευθύνθηκε στο 
δικαίωμα υπηρεσιών αφότου ημέρα βαθμολόγησης μπορεί να ήταν 
μερικοί εθελοντές και άλλοι που συντάσσονται. Εκείνοι που 
δεν ήταν επιλέξιμοι για την υπηρεσία θα μπορούσαν να προσφερθούν 
εθελοντικά να βοηθήσουν την πολεμική προσπάθεια στο σπίτι. 
Όπως οι εικόνες σε αυτό το θέμα εμφανίζουν, οι άνθρωποι 
συνέβαλαν στο σπίτι στην πολεμική προσπάθεια με ποικίλους 
τρόπους. Πολλοί άνθρωποι ανέμειναν για την πιθανή 
εχθρική επίθεση. Σε μια φωτογραφία τα άτομα φέρνουν τις 
σφαίρες γυαλιού που θα εξασθενίσουν τους λαμπτήρες οδών και θα 
επιτρέψουν μια "συσκότιση" έτσι ότι τα εχθρικά αεροπλάνα θα 
είναι ικανά να δουν τη θέση μιας πόλης ή μιας 
κωμόπολης. Μια άλλη φωτογραφία εμφανίζει εθελοντικά 
spotters αέρα εξετάζοντας έναν χάρτη, και άλλος εμφανίζει τις
γυναίκες σε έναν πίνακα που στρατολογούν τους εθελοντές για να 
βοηθήσει να επισημάνει τα ύποπτα αεροσκάφη. Η συγκέντρωση 
των χρημάτων ήταν ένας άλλος τρόπος να βοηθήσει. Μερικοί 
πολίτες υποστήριξαν την πολεμική προσπάθεια με να αγοράσουν τους 
πολεμικούς δεσμούς άμεσα. Αλλοι συγκέντρωσαν τα χρήματα 
για τους πολεμικούς δεσμούς μέσω των fundraisers όπως το 
διαγωνισμό ομορφιάς βασίλισσας Λα Shangri, που απεικονίστηκε 
εδώ. Πολλά προϊόντα διανεμήθηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια του 
πολέμου, και η κυβέρνηση υπογράμμισε τη σημασία της αυτάρκειας. 
Σχεδόν 20 εκατομμύριο Αμερικανοί συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
παιδιών τέταρτος-βαθμού στο Κολοράντο και μιας 
ιαπωνικός-αμερικανικής οικογένειας που επανεντοπίζεται στο 
Μάντισον, Wisconsin, που εμφανίζεται εδώ απαντημένος στο 
κυβερνητικό αίτημα να φυτεψουν "τη νίκη καλλιεργούν" για να 
αυξήσουν τα τρόφιμά τους. Αυτοί οι κήποι, μεγάλος και 
μικρός, παρήγαγαν μέχρι 40% όλων των τροφίμων που 
καταναλώθηκαν. Μια φωτογραφία εμφανίζει ακόμη και παιδιά 
που ανατρέφουν τα κουνέλια για τα τρόφιμα στην πίσω αυλή τους. 
Όχι ο καθένας υποστήριξε την πολεμική προσπάθεια. 
Δεδομένου ότι μπορείτε να δείτε στη φωτογραφία 
μιας διαμαρτυρίας ειρήνης σε UC Μπέρκλεϋ, μερικοί πολίτες δεν
θέλησαν κανένα μέρος στον πόλεμο και κράτησαν τις απεργίες και 
τις συναθροίσεις ειρήνης. Μετά από το βομβαρδισμό του 
λιμανιού μαργαριταριών, η ζωή άλλαξε στο σπίτι για ιαπωνικούς 
Αμερικανούς. Εκείνοι στη δυτική ακτή αντιμετώπισαν τον 
περιορισμό εκτός από την προκατάληψη και τη διάκριση. Κατά
τη διάρκεια μιας συνοπτικής περιόδου προτού ο περιορισμός να 
γίνει υποχρεωτικός, ιαπωνικοί Αμερικανοί είχαν την άδεια για να 
επιλέξουν την εθελοντική εκκένωση midwest. Μια φωτογραφία
εμφανίζει οικογένεια Nomura που στέκεται μπροστά από το νέο 
σπίτι τους στο Μάντισον, Wisconsin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pues el cuadro de la clase que gradúa 1942 de la 
High School secundaria de Santa Ana muestra, dirigieron a los 
graduados uniformados en la derecha del servicio después de que
día de graduación algunos pudieron haber sido voluntarios y otras 
bosquejadas. Los que no eran elegibles para el servicio podrían
ofrecerse voluntariamente a ayudar al esfuerzo de la guerra en el 
país. Pues las imágenes en este asunto muestran, la gente en 
el país contribuyó al esfuerzo de la guerra en una variedad de 
maneras. Mucha gente alistada para el ataque enemigo posible. 
En una fotografía los hombres llevan los globos de cristal que 
amortiguarán las lámparas de calle y permitirán un "apagón" de 
modo que los planos enemigos no puedan considerar la localización de 
una ciudad o de una ciudad. Otros observadores de tiro 
voluntarios del aire de las demostraciones de la fotografía que miran
una correspondencia, y otras demostraciones mujeres en los voluntarios
de reclutamiento de un vector para ayudar a manchar el avión 
sospechoso. Levantar el dinero era otra manera de ayudar. 
Algunos civiles utilizaron el esfuerzo de la guerra comprando 
enlaces de guerra directamente. Otros levantaron el dinero para 
los enlaces de guerra con fundraisers como la competencia de la 
belleza de la reina del la de Shangri, representado aquí. 
Muchos productos fueron racionados durante la guerra, y el 
gobierno acentuó la importancia de la autosuficiencia. Casi 20 
millones de americanos incluyendo los niños del cuarto-grado en 
Colorado y una familia Japone's-Americana volvieron a poner a Madison,
Wisconsin, mostrado aquí contestado la petición del gobierno de 
plantar "jardines de la victoria" para levantar su propio alimento. 
Estos jardines, grande y pequeño, producidos el hasta 40% de 
todo el alimento que fue consumido. Una foto incluso muestra a 
niños que crían los conejos para el alimento en su yarda posterior. 
No cada uno utilizó el esfuerzo de la guerra. Como usted 
puede ver en la fotografía de una protesta de la paz en Berkeley UC, 
algunos ciudadanos no desearon ninguna parte en la guerra y celebraron
huelgas y reuniones de la paz. Después del bombardeo del puerto
de perla, la vida en el país cambió para los americanos japoneses. 
Ésos en la costa del oeste hicieron frente a la internación 
además de prejudicar y de la discriminación. Durante un 
período abreviado antes de que sintió bien la internación a 
americanos obligatorios, japoneses fueron permitidos para elegir la 
evacuación voluntaria al Cercano oeste. Una fotografía muestra
a familia de Nomura que está parada delante de su nuevo hogar en 
Madison, Wisconsin.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085252</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106066</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/life-on-the-home-front</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
