<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105623</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105623</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087034</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The red flag in New York--Riotous communist workingmen driven from Tompkins Square by the mounted police, Tuesday, January 13th, 1874."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die rote Markierungsfahne New York -- Riotous in 
den kommunistischen Workingmen angetrieben vom Tompkins Quadrat von 
der eingehangenen Polizei, Dienstag, Januar 13., 1874."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'indicateur rouge à New York -- ouvriers 
communistes de séditieux conduits par la place de Tompkins par la 
police montée, mardi, le 13 janvier, 1874."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a bandeira vermelha nos workingmen comunistas de 
New York -- de Riotous dirigidos do quadrado pelas polícias montadas,
terça-feira de Tompkins, janeiro 1ó, 1874."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la bandierina rossa in workingmen comunisti di 
Riotous -- de New York guidati dal quadrato dalla polizia montata, 
martedì, 13 gennaio 1874 di Tompkins."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η κόκκινη σημαία στη Νέα Υόρκη -- ο στασιαστικός 
κομμουνιστής οδηγημένος από Tompkins το τετράγωνο από την 
έφιππη αστυνομία, Τρίτη, 13$η Ιανουαρίου, 1874."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el indicador rojo en los workingmen comunistas de
Nueva York -- de Riotous conducidos del cuadrado por el policía 
montado, martes, 13 de enero de 1874 de Tompkins."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As the depression of the 1870s deepened, demonstrations by unemployed workers took place all over the country. Workers and their allies demanding relief and job programs often were met with official violenceand were treated with hostility by the nation's press. On January 13, 1874 a workers' demonstration in Tompkins Square in New York City was broken up when mounted police moved in, beating demonstrators with clubs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wie der Tiefstand des vertieften 1870s, Demonstrationen 
durch arbeitslose Arbeiter ganz über dem Land stattfand. Die 
Arbeiter und ihre Verbündeten, die Entlastung und Jobprogramme 
häufig verlangen, wurden amtliches violenceand wurden behandelt mit 
Feindseligkeit durch die Presse der Nation getroffen. An Januar 
13, 1874 war eine Demonstration der Arbeiter im Tompkins Quadrat in 
New York City oben unterbrochen, als eingehangene Polizei innen bewog 
und schlug Demonstrationsmodelle mit Vereinen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comme la dépression du 1870s approfondi, démonstrations 
par les ouvriers sans emploi a eu lieu partout le pays. Des 
ouvriers et leurs alliés exigeant des programmes de soulagement et de
travail souvent ont été rencontrés le violenceand officiel ont 
été traités avec l'hostilité par la presse de la nation. 
13 janvier 1874 une démonstration des ouvriers dans la place 
de Tompkins à New York City était cassée en hausse quand la police 
montée s'est déplacée dedans, battant des programmes de 
démonstration avec des clubs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como o depression do 1870s aprofundado, demonstrações 
por trabalhadores unemployed ocorreu toda sobre o país. Os 
trabalhadores e seus aliados que exigem programas do relevo e do 
trabalho foram encontrados com frequentemente com violenceand oficial 
foram tratados com a hostilidade pela imprensa da nação. 
Janeiro em 13, 1874 uma demonstração dos trabalhadores no 
quadrado de Tompkins em New York City era quebrada acima quando as 
polícias montadas se moveram dentro, batendo demonstradores com 
clubes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come la depressione del 1870s approfondito, dimostrazioni 
dagli operai disoccupati ha avvenuto dappertutto il paese. Gli 
operai ed i loro alleati che richiedono i programmi di lavoro e di 
rilievo sono stati incontrati spesso violenceand ufficiale sono stati 
trattati con ostilità dalla pressa della nazione. Il 13 gennaio
1874 una dimostrazione degli operai nel quadrato di Tompkins a New 
York City era rotta in su quando la polizia montata si è mossa 
dentro, battendo i dimostranti con i randelli.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σαν κατάθλιψη 1870s που εμβαθύθηκαν, οι επιδείξεις 
από τους άνεργους εργαζομένους πραγματοποιήθηκαν σε όλη τη χώρα.
Οι εργαζόμενοι και οι σύμμαχοί τους που απαιτούν τα 
προγράμματα ανακούφισης και εργασίας συχνά συναντήθηκαν με τον 
ανώτερο υπάλληλο violenceand αντιμετωπίστηκαν με την εχθρότητα 
από τον Τύπο του έθνους. Στις 13 Ιανουαρίου ..1874 μια
επίδειξη των εργαζομένων στο τετράγωνο Tompkins στην πόλη της 
Νέας Υόρκης χωρίστηκε όταν κινήθηκε μέσα η έφιππη αστυνομία, 
κτυπώντας τους επιδεικνύοντες με τις λέσχες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Como la depresión del 1870s profundizado, demostraciones 
de los trabajadores parados ocurrió todo sobre el país. 
Satisficieron a los trabajadores y a sus aliados que exigían 
programas de la relevación y del trabajo a menudo con el violenceand 
oficial fueron tratados con hostilidad por la prensa de la nación. 
13 de enero de 1874 una demostración de los trabajadores en 
el cuadrado de Tompkins en New York City estaba quebrada para arriba 
cuando el policía montado se movió adentro, batiendo manifestantes 
con los clubs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087034</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105623</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-red-flag-in-new-york-riotous-communist-workingmen-driven-from-tompkins-square-by-the-mounted-police-tuesday-january-13th-1874</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
