<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103495</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103495</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087414</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Auto Tours for Women's Suffrage: An Oral Memoir</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Automobil bereist für Stimmrecht der Frauen: 
Eine Mundabhandlung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'automobile voyage pour le suffrage des femmes : 
Un Mémoire Oral</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O automóvel excursiona para o suffrage das 
mulheres: Um Memoir Oral</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'automobile fa un giro di per suffrage delle 
donne: Una Memoria Orale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτόματοι γύροι για την ψήφο των γυναικών: 
Προφορικά απομνημονεύματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El automóvil viaja para el sufragio de las 
mujeres: Una Memoria Oral</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The struggle for women's suffrage, which culminated with the ratification of the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution on August 26, 1920, involved many different kinds of women and many different tactics. Laura Ellsworth Seiler, interviewed by historian Sherna Gluck in 1973, came from a prosperous New York state family and started a suffrage club while a student at Cornell. In this excerpt from Gluck's interview, Seiler recalled campaigning for suffrage after college on an automobile tour, with her mother in tow as chaperon. In contrast to some historical accounts that emphasized the narrowing of the campaign in the 20th century, Seiler remembered arguing for the vote along with other reforms, and emphasizing the importance of suffrage as a way to improve social conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kampf für Stimmrecht der Frauen, das mit der 
Bestätigung der 19.änderung zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit an
August 26 kulminierte, 1920, bezog viele unterschiedliche Arten Frauen
und viele unterschiedliche Taktiken mit ein. Laura Ellsworth 
Seiler, interviewt vom Historiker Sherna Gluck 1973, kam von einer 
wohlhabenden Staat New-Yorkfamilie und begann eine Stimmrechtverein 
während ein Kursteilnehmer in Cornell. In diesem Excerpt vom 
Interview Glucks, rief Seiler wieder auf, für Stimmrecht nachdem 
Hochschule auf einer Automobiltour, mit ihrer Mutter im Schleppseil 
als Aufsichtsperson zu werben. Im Gegensatz zu einigen 
historischen Konten, die das Verengen der Kampagne im 20. Jahrhundert 
hervorhoben, erinnerte sich Seiler, für die Stimme zusammen mit 
anderen Verbesserungen zu argumentieren, und den Wert des Stimmrechts 
als Methode hervorzuheben, Sozialbedingungen zu verbessern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La lutte pour le suffrage des femmes, qui a 
culminé avec la ratification du dix-neuvième amendement à la 
constitution des ETATS-UNIS 26 août 1920, a impliqué beaucoup de 
différents genres de femmes et beaucoup de différente tactique. 
Laura Ellsworth Seiler, interviewé par l'historien Sherna Gluck
en 1973, est venu d'une famille prospère de l'état de New-York et a 
commencé un club de suffrage tandis qu'un étudiant à Cornell. 
Dans cet extrait de l'entrevue de Gluck, Seiler s'est rappelé 
faire campagne pour le suffrage après qu'université en excursion 
d'automobile, avec sa mère dans le remorquage comme surveillant. 
Contrairement à quelques comptes historiques qui ont souligné 
le rétrécissement de la campagne au 20ème siècle, Seiler s'est 
rappelé de plaider pour la voix avec d'autres réformes, et de 
souligner l'importance du suffrage comme voie d'améliorer des 
conditions sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O esforço para o suffrage das mulheres, que 
culminou com o ratification da décima nona emenda ao constitution de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS agosto em 26, 1920, envolveu muitos tipos diferentes 
das mulheres e muitas táticas diferentes. Laura Ellsworth 
Seiler, entrevistado pelo historian Sherna Gluck em 1973, veio de uma 
família próspera do estado de New York e começou um clube do 
suffrage quando um estudante em Cornell. Neste excerpt da 
entrevista de Gluck, Seiler recordou fazer campanha para o suffrage 
depois que faculdade em uma excursão do automóvel, com sua matriz no
reboque como o chaperon. No contraste a alguns clientes 
históricos que emfatizaram se estreitar da campanha no 20o século, 
Seiler recordou discutir para o voto junto com outras reformas, e 
emfatizar a importância do suffrage como uma maneira melhorar 
circunstâncias sociais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lotta per suffrage delle donne, che ha 
culminato con la ratifica della diciannovesima correzione alla 
costituzione degli STATI UNITI il 26 agosto 1920, ha coinvolto molti 
generi differenti di donne e molte tattiche differenti. Laura 
Ellsworth Seiler, intervistato dallo storico Sherna Gluck in 1973, è 
venuto da New York prosperosa dichiara la famiglia ed ha 
iniziato un randello di suffrage mentre un allievo a Cornell. In
questo brano dall'intervista del Gluck, Seiler ha ricordato fare una 
campagna per il suffrage dopo che università durante un giro 
dell'automobile, con la sua madre nel rimorchio come chaperon. 
Contrariamente ad alcuni clienti storici che hanno dato risalto 
allo stringimento della campagna nel ventesimo secolo, Seiler si è 
ricordato di parlare a favore del voto con altre riforme e dare 
risalto all'importanza di suffrage come modo migliorare le circostanze
sociali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η προσπάθεια για την ψήφο των γυναικών, που κατέληξε 
με την επικύρωση της δέκατης έννατης τροποποίησης στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
σύνταγμα στις 26 Αυγούστου ..1920, περιέλαβε πολλά 
διαφορετικά είδη γυναικών και πολλές διαφορετική τακτική. 
Η Laura Ellsworth Seiler, που πέρασε από συνέντευξη 
από τον ιστορικό Sherna Gluck το 1973, προήλθε από μια 
ακμάζουσα κρατική οικογένεια της Νέας Υόρκης και άρχισε μια 
λέσχη ψήφου ενώ ένας σπουδαστής στο Cornell. Σε αυτό το
απόσπασμα από τη συνέντευξη Gluck, Seiler υπενθύμισε να 
κάνει εκστρατεία για την ψήφο μετά από το κολλέγιο σε έναν 
αυτοκινητικό γύρο, με τη μητέρα της στη ρυμούλκηση ως σκούφο. 
Σε αντίθεση με μερικούς ιστορικούς απολογισμούς που 
υπογράμμισαν το στένεμα της εκστρατείας στο 20ό αιώνα, Seiler 
θυμήθηκε την ψηφοφορία μαζί με άλλες μεταρρυθμίσεις, και τη 
σημασία της ψήφου ως τρόπο να βελτιωθούν οι κοινωνικοί όροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La lucha para el sufragio de las mujeres, que 
culminó con la ratificación de la diecinueveavo enmienda a la 
constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS 26 de agosto de 1920, implicó 
muchas diversas clases de mujeres y muchas diversas táctica. 
Laura Ellsworth Seiler, entrevistado con por el historiador 
Sherna Gluck en 1973, vino de una familia próspera del estado de 
Nueva York y comenzó a club del sufragio mientras que un estudiante 
en Cornell. En este extracto de la entrevista de Gluck, Seiler 
recordó el hacer campaña para el sufragio después de que 
universidad en un viaje del automóvil, con su madre en remolque como 
chaperon. En contraste con algunas cuentas históricas que 
acentuaron enangostar de la campaña en el vigésimo siglo, Seiler 
recordó discutir para el voto junto con otras reformas, y acentuar la
importancia del sufragio como manera de mejorar condiciones sociales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087414</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103495</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/auto-tours-for-womens-suffrage-an-oral-memoir</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
