<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106528</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106528</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086127</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Escape.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Entweichen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Évasion.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escape.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fuga.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαφυγή.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escape.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By mid-century, slavery had become the central, defining institution of southern cultural and economic life. As slavery became more entrenched in southern society, so too did the everyday resistance of African-Americans. Slaves resisted the regimen of work by feigning ignorance, breaking tools, or injuring animals. By forming communities and maintaining familial ties as best they could, slaves asserted their humanity in the face of the dehumanizing effects of bondage. Running away also remained an important form of resistance. This icon, or symbol, appeared on notices about fugitive slaves in the classified section of the Mobile, Alabama,  Commercial Register  in the 1830s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bis zum Mid-century war Sklaverei das zentrale geworden 
und Anstalt des südlichen kulturellen und Wirtschaftslebens 
definiert. Während Sklaverei in der südlichen Gesellschaft 
befestigter wurde, tat so auch den täglichen Widerstand der 
Afrikanisch-Amerikaner. Sklaven widerstanden der Regierung der 
Arbeit, indem sie Unwissenheit vortäuschten brachen, Hilfsmittel, 
oder Tiere verletzten. Indem sie Gemeinschaften bildeten und 
familial Gleichheit beibehielten, da gut sie konnten, erklärten 
Sklaven ihre Menschlichkeit angesichts der entmenschlichenden Effekte 
der Knechtschaft. Weg laufen blieb auch ein wichtiges Formular 
des Widerstandes. Diese Ikone oder das Symbol, geerschienen auf 
Begriffen über Flüchtling schuftet im eingestuften Kapitel des 
Mobiles, Alabama, kommerzielles Register im 1830s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Par la moitié du siècle, l'esclavage était devenu le 
central, définissant l'établissement de la vie culturelle et 
économique méridionale. Pendant que l'esclavage devenait plus 
indélogeable dans la société méridionale, a tellement aussi fait 
la résistance journalière des Afro-Américains. Les esclaves ont 
résisté au régime du travail en simulant l'ignorance, en cassant 
des outils, ou en blessant des animaux. En formant les 
communautés et en mettant à jour les cravates familiales car mieux
ils pourraient, les esclaves ont affirmé leur humanité face aux 
effets de déshumanisation du servage. L'exécution loin est 
également demeurée une forme importante de résistance. Ce 
graphisme, ou symbole, apparu sur des notifications au sujet de 
fugitif asservit dans la section classifiée du mobile, Alabama, 
registre de commerce dans le 1830s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pelo mid-century, o slavery tinha-se transformado o 
central, definindo a instituição da vida cultural e econômica do 
sul. Enquanto o slavery se tornou mais entrenched na sociedade 
do sul, fêz assim demasiado a resistência diária dos 
Africano-Americanos. Os escravos resistiram o regimen do 
trabalho fingindo o ignorance, quebrando ferramentas, ou ferindo 
animais. Dando forma a comunidades e mantendo laços familial 
porque melhor poderiam, os escravos afirmaram seu humanity na cara dos
efeitos dehumanizing do bondage. Funcionar afastado remanesceu 
também um formulário importante da resistência. Este ícone, 
ou o símbolo, aparecido em observações sobre o fugitive slaves na 
seção classificada do móbil, Alabama, registo comercial no 1830s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Entro la metà del secolo, lo slavery si era transformato 
in nel centrale, definendo l'istituzione di vita culturale ed 
economica del sud. Mentre lo slavery è diventato più 
entrenched nella società del sud, così anche ha fatto la resistenza 
giornaliere degli Africano-Americani. Gli schiavi hanno 
resistito al regime di lavoro fingendo l'ignoranza, rompendo gli 
strumenti, o danneggiando gli animali. Formando le Comunità ed 
effettuando i legami familial poichè potrebbero il più bene, gli 
schiavi hanno asserito la loro umanità di fronte agli effetti di 
disumanizzazione di bondage. Funzionare via egualmente è 
rimasto una forma importante di resistenza. Questa icona, o il 
simbolo, comparso sugli avvisi circa il fuggitivo assoggetta nella 
sezione classificata del mobile, Alabama, registro commerciale nel 
1830s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέχρι mid-century, η σκλαβιά είχε γίνει η 
κεντρική, καθορίζοντας το όργανο της νότιας πολιτιστικής 
και οικονομικής ζωής. Δεδομένου ότι η σκλαβιά έγινε 
περισσότερο περιχαρακωμένη στη νότια κοινωνία, τόσο επίσης 
έκανε την καθημερινή αντίσταση αφρικανικός-Αμερικανών. Οι 
σκλάβοι αντιστάθηκαν στη θεραπευτική αγωγή της εργασίας με 
feigning την άγνοια, τα σπάζοντας εργαλεία, ή την πληγή των 
ζώων. Με τη διαμόρφωση των κοινοτήτων και τη διατήρηση των 
οικογενειακών δεσμών ως καλύτερο που θα μπορούσαν, οι σκλάβοι 
βεβαίωσαν την ανθρωπότητά τους παρά τα αποκτηνώνοντας 
αποτελέσματα της δουλείας. Να τρέξει μακριά επίσης 
παρέμεινε μια σημαντική μορφή της αντίστασης. Αυτό το 
εικονίδιο, ή το σύμβολο, εμφανίστηκε στις ειδοποιήσεις για τους 
σκλάβους προσφύγων στο ταξινομημένο τμήμα του κινητού, Αλαμπάμα,
εμπορικός κατάλογος στο 1830s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por mediados de siglo, la esclavitud se había convertido 
en la central, definiendo a la institución de la vida cultural y 
económica meridional. Mientras que la esclavitud llegó a ser 
más atrincherada en sociedad meridional, hizo tan también la 
resistencia diaria de Africano-Americanos. Los esclavos 
resistieron el régimen del trabajo fingiendo ignorancia, rompiendo 
las herramientas, o dañando animales. Formando a comunidades y 
manteniendo lazos familial como podrían lo más mejor posible, los 
esclavos afirmaron su humanidad en la cara de los efectos de 
deshumanización del bondage. El ejecutarse lejos también 
seguía siendo una forma importante de resistencia. Este icono, 
o el símbolo, aparecido en avisos sobre fugitivo esclaviza en la 
sección clasificada del móvil, Alabama, registro comercial en el 
1830s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086127</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106528</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/escape</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
