<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107540</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205793</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NEA Jazz in the Schools</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NEA Jazz in den Schulen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jazz de NEA dans les écoles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jazz de NEA nas escolas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jazz di NEA nelle scuole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τζαζ NEA στα σχολεία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jazz de NEA en las escuelas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">traces the history of jazz from its birth in New Orleans to the swing era, bebop, and new frontiers. Five lessons include essays, videos, photos, and nearly 100 music clips of Scott Joplin, Jelly Roll Morton, Louie Armstrong, Fletcher Henderson, Duke Ellington, Count Basie, Charlie Parker, Bud Powell, Miles Davis, Charlie Mingus, Sonny Rollins, John Coltrane, and others. Lessons include social and political context and are designed for history classes as well as music.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">vollzieht die Geschichte von Jazz von seiner 
Geburt in New-Orleans zur Schwingenära, zum bebop und zu den neuen 
Grenzen nach. Fünf Lektionen enthalten Versuche, videos, Fotos 
und fast 100 Musikclips von Scott Joplin, Gelee-Rolle Morton, Louie 
Armstrong, Fletcher Henderson, Herzog Ellington, Zählimpuls Basie, 
Charlie Parker, Knospe Powell, Meilen Davis, Charlie Mingus, Sonny 
Rollins, John Coltrane und andere. Lektionen schließen Sozial- 
und politischen Kontext ein und sind für Geschichte Kategorien sowie 
Musik bestimmt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">trace l'histoire du jazz de sa naissance à la 
Nouvelle-Orléans à l'ère d'oscillation, au bebop, et aux nouvelles 
frontières. Cinq leçons incluent des essais, des videos, des 
photos, et presque 100 clips de musique de Scott Joplin, 
roulement Morton, Louie Armstrong, Fletcher Henderson, duc Ellington, 
compte Basie, Charlie Parker, bourgeon Powell, milles de gelée 
de Davis, Charlie Mingus, Sonny Rollins, John Coltrane, et d'autres. 
Les leçons incluent le contexte social et politique et sont 
conçues pour des classes d'histoire aussi bien que la musique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">segue o history do jazz de seu nascimento em Nova 
Orleães à era do balanço, ao bebop, e às fronteiras novas. 
Cinco lições incluem essays, videos, fotos, e quase 100 
grampos da música de Scott Joplin, rolo Morton da geléia, Louie 
Armstrong, Fletcher Henderson, duque Ellington, contagem Basie, 
Charlie Parker, bud Powell, milhas de Davis, Charlie Mingus, Sonny 
Rollins, John Coltrane, e outro. As lições incluem o contexto 
social e político e são projetadas para classes do history 
as.well.as a música.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">segue la storia di jazz dalla relativa nascita a 
New Orleans all'era dell'oscillazione, al bebop ed alle nuove 
frontiere. Cinque lezioni includono i saggi, i videos, le foto e
quasi 100 clip di musica di Scott Joplin, il rullo Morton, Louie 
Armstrong, Fletcher Henderson, il duca Ellington, il conteggio Basie, 
Charlie Parker, il germoglio Powell, miglia della gelatina di Davis, 
Charlie Mingus, Sonny Rollins, John Coltrane ed altri. Le 
lezioni includono il contesto sociale e politico e sono progettate per
i codici categoria di storia così come musica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επισημαίνει την ιστορία της τζαζ από τη γέννησή του 
στη Νέα Ορλεάνη στην εποχή ταλάντευσης, bebop, και τα νέα 
σύνορα. Πέντε μαθήματα περιλαμβάνουν τα δοκίμια, τα 
βίντεο, φωτογραφίες, και σχεδόν 100 συνδετήρες μουσικής 
Scott Joplin, ρόλος Morton, Louie Armstrong, 
Fletcher Henderson, δούκας Ellington, αρίθμηση Basie, 
Τσάρλυ Parker, οφθαλμός Powell, μίλια ζελατίνας του 
Νταίηβις, Τσάρλυ Mingus, Sonny Rollins, John 
Coltrane, και άλλα. Τα μαθήματα περιλαμβάνουν το 
κοινωνικό και πολιτικό πλαίσιο και σχεδιάζονται για τις κλάσεις 
ιστορίας καθώς επίσης και τη μουσική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">rastrea la historia del jazz de su nacimiento en 
New Orleans a la era del oscilación, al bebop, y a las nuevas 
fronteras. Cinco lecciones incluyen ensayos, videos, las fotos, 
y casi 100 clips de la música de Scott Joplin, rodillo Morton, Louie 
Armstrong, Fletcher Henderson, duque Ellington, cuenta Basie, Charlie 
Parker, brote Powell, millas de la jalea de Davis, Charlie Mingus, 
Sonny Rollins, Juan Coltrane, y otros. Las lecciones incluyen 
contexto social y político y se diseñan para las clases de la 
historia así como música.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205793</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107540</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nea-jazz-in-the-schools</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
