<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104206</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104206</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206985</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Homestead Act of 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Gehöft-Tat von 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'acte de ferme de 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato do homestead de 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge della fattoria di 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο νόμος αγροτικών σπιτιών 1862</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto de la granja de 1862</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts efforts to improve homesteading laws and make land ownership possible for more settlers. The distribution of government lands had been an issue since the Revolutionary War. Preemption -- settling the land first and paying for it later -- became national policy; however, supporting legislation was stymied until the secession of Southern states. See one of the first applications for land under this law. Teaching activities are included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nachzählungbemühungen, homesteading Gesetze zu 
verbessern und Landbesitz zu ermöglichen für mehr Siedleren. 
Die Verteilung der Regierung landet war gewesen eine Ausgabe, da
revolutionäre War. Preemption -- das Land zuerst vereinbarend und 
für es später zahlend -- nationale Politik wurde; jedoch war 
unterstützende Gesetzgebung stymied bis die Sezession der 
südlichen Zustände. Sehen Sie eine der ersten Anwendungen für
Land unter dieses Gesetz. Unterrichtende Aktivitäten sind 
enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">efforts de recomptes d'améliorer des lois 
homesteading et de rendre la propriété terrienne possible à plus de
colons. La distribution du gouvernement débarque avait été 
une issue puisque War. Preemption révolutionnaire -- arrangeant la 
terre d'abord et payant elle plus tard -- est devenu politique 
nationale ; cependant, la législation supportante était 
stymied jusqu'à la secession des états méridionaux. Voyez 
une des premières applications pour la terre en vertu de cette loi. 
Les activités d'enseignement sont incluses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">esforços dos recounts melhorar leis homesteading 
e fazer a posse de terra possível para mais settlers. A 
distribuição do governo aterra tinha sido uma edição desde que a 
Guerra revolucionária Preemption -- estabelecindo a terra 
primeiramente e pagando por ela mais tarde -- se transformou política
nacional; entretanto, a legislação suportando era stymied até
o secession de estados do sul. Veja uma das primeiras 
aplicações para a terra sob esta lei. As atividades ensinando 
são incluídas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sforzi di conteggi migliorare le leggi 
homesteading e permettere proprietà terriera per più settlers. 
La distribuzione del governo atterra era stata un'edizione 
poiché la War. la Preemption rivoluzionaria -- depositando la terra 
in primo luogo e pagando esso più successivamente -- si è 
transformata in nella politica nazionale; tuttavia, la 
legislazione di sostegno era stymied fino a che il secession di del 
sud non dichiarasse. Veda una delle prime applicazioni per
terra secondo questa legge. Le attività d'istruzione sono 
incluse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί τις προσπάθειες να βελτιωθούν οι 
homesteading νόμοι και να κατασταθεί η ιδιοκτησία εδάφους 
πιθανή για περισσότερους αποίκους. Η διανομή των 
κυβερνητικών εδαφών ήταν ένα ζήτημα από τον επαναστατικό 
πόλεμο. Το δικαίωμα προτίμησης -- που εγκαθιστά το έδαφος 
πρώτα και που πληρώνει για το αργότερα -- έγινε εθνική πολιτική 
εντούτοις, η ενισχυτική νομοθεσία ήταν μέχρι την αποχώρηση
των νότιων κρατών. Δείτε μιας από τις πρώτες 
εφαρμογές για το έδαφος βάσει αυτού του νόμου. Οι 
δραστηριότητες διδασκαλίας συμπεριλαμβάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">esfuerzos de los recuentos de mejorar leyes 
homesteading y de hacer propiedad de terreno posible para más 
colonos. La distribución del gobierno aterriza había sido una 
edición puesto que la War. revolucionaria Preemption -- colocando la 
pista primero y pagando ella más adelante -- hizo política nacional;
sin embargo, la legislación que utilizaba era stymied hasta la 
secesión de estados meridionales. Vea una de las primeras 
aplicaciones para la pista bajo esta ley. Las actividades de 
enseñanza son incluidas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206985</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104206</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-homestead-act-of-1862</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
