<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105671</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203790</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Marine Microbial Ecology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Marinemikrobenökologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Écologie Microbienne Marine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ecology Microbial Marinho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ecologia Microbica Marina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θαλάσσια μικροβιακή οικολογία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ecología Microbiana Marina</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This image-rich website from the Australian Antarctic Division's Biology program describes its research in marine microbial ecology. It includes an introduction of microbial ecology and microbial processes, followed by information about the research project. Field sampling, microscopy, flow cytometry, pigment analysis, flourometry, HPLC, culturing, feeding experiments, and the research staff are each discussed using vivid imagery. Links are provided to related websites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Bild-reiche Web site vom australischen 
antarktischen Biologieprogramm der Abteilung beschreibt seine 
Forschung in der Marinemikrobenökologie. Sie schließt eine 
Einleitung von Mikrobenökologie und von Mikrobenprozessen ein, 
gefolgt von den Informationen über das Forschung Projekt. 
Fangen Sie Musterstück, Mikroskopie auf, fließen Sie
cytometry, die Pigmentanalyse, flourometry, HPLC und züchten, 
Fütterungsexperimente, und das Forschungspersonal ist jede 
behandelten verwendenden klaren Bilder. Links werden zu in 
Verbindung stehenden Web site zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web image-riche du programme de la 
biologie de la Division antarctique australienne décrit sa recherche 
en écologie microbienne marine. Il inclut une introduction de 
l'écologie microbienne et des processus microbiens, suivie des 
informations sur le projet de recherche. Le prélèvement de 
zone, microscopie, coulent cytometry, analyse de colorant, 
flourometry, CHROMATOGRAPHIE LIQUIDE SOUS HAUTE PRESSION, cultivant, 
des essais d'alimentation, et le personnel de recherche sont chaque 
langage figuré vif d'utilisation discuté. Des liens sont 
fournis aux sites Web relatifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site imagem-rico do programa da biologia 
da divisão antarctic australian descreve sua pesquisa no ecology 
microbial marinho. Inclui uma introdução do ecology microbial 
e de processos microbial, seguida pela informação sobre o projeto de
pesquisa. A amostragem do campo, microscopy, flui cytometry, 
análise do pigment, flourometry, HPLC, cultivando, experiências de 
alimentação, e a equipe de funcionários de pesquisa é cada imagery
vívido usando-se discutido. As ligações são fornecidas aos 
Web site relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site immagine-ricco dal programma di 
biologia della divisione antartica australiana descrive la relativa 
ricerca in ecologia microbica marina. Include un'introduzione 
dell'ecologia microbica e dei processi microbici, seguita dalle 
informazioni sul progetto di ricerca. Il campione del campo, 
microscopia, fluisce cytometry, analisi del pigmento, flourometry, 
HPLC, coltivando, prove di alimentazione ed il personale di ricerca è
ogni linguaggio figurato chiaro usando discusso. I collegamenti 
sono forniti ai Web site relativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εικόνα-πλούσιος ιστοχώρος από το πρόγραμμα 
της βιολογίας του αυστραλιανού ανταρκτικού τμήματος περιγράφει 
την έρευνά του στη θαλάσσια μικροβιακή οικολογία. 
Περιλαμβάνει μια εισαγωγή της μικροβιακής οικολογίας και των
μικροβιακών διαδικασιών, που ακολουθείται από τις πληροφορίες για
το ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα. Η δειγματοληψία πεδίων, 
μικροσκόπηση, ρέει cytometry, ανάλυση χρωστικών ουσιών, 
flourometry, HPLC, καλλιέργεια, πειράματα σίτισης, και το 
ερευνητικό προσωπικό κάθε ένα συζητείται χρησιμοποιώντας τα 
ζωηρά καλολογικά στοιχεία. Οι συνδέσεις παρέχονται στους 
σχετικούς ιστοχώρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site imagen-rico del programa de la 
biología de la división antártica australiana describe su 
investigación en ecología microbiana marina. Incluye una 
introducción de la ecología microbiana y de los procesos 
microbianos, seguida por la información sobre el proyecto de 
investigación. El muestreo del campo, microscopia, fluye 
cytometry, análisis del pigmento, flourometry, HPLC, cultivando, las 
pruebas de alimentación, y el personal de investigación es cada 
imágenes vivas que usan discutidas. Las conexiones se 
proporcionan a los Web site relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AUSTRALIAN ANTARCTIC DIVISION
FN:AUSTRALIAN ANTARCTIC DIVISION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203790</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105671</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/marine-microbial-ecology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
