<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103738</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103738</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206743</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Biology: U.S. Geological Survey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Biologie: VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geologische 
Übersicht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Biologie : Enquête Géologique des 
ETATS-UNIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biologia: Exame Geological de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Biologia: Indagine Geologica degli STATI 
UNITI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η βιολογία: ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ Γεωλογική έρευνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biología: Encuesta sobre Geológica ESTADOS
UNIDOS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides research results, photos, projects, and other resources for studies in biology, biodiversity, and ecology. Learn about butterflies and moths of North America, bat research, invasive species, environmental contaminants' effects on plants and animals, redwood research, surf scoters, sea otters, reptiles and amphibians of southern California, the desert tortoise, habitat conservation, and genetic diversity across different species groups.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Forschungsresultate, Fotos, Projekte und 
andere Betriebsmittel für Studien in der Biologie, im Biodiversity 
und in der Ökologie zur Verfügung. Erlernen Sie über 
Basisrecheneinheiten und Motten von Nordamerika, Hiebforschung, 
Angriffssorte, Effekte der Klimaverschmutzer auf Betriebe und Tiere, 
Rotholzforschung, Brandung Scoters, Seeotter, Reptilien und Amphibien 
von Südkalifornien, Wüstenschildkröte, Lebensraumerhaltung und 
genetische Verschiedenartigkeit über unterschiedlichen Sortegruppen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des résultats de la recherche, des 
photos, des projets, et d'autres ressources pour des études en 
biologie, biodiversité, et écologie. Renseignez-vous sur des 
papillons et des mites de l'Amérique du nord, la recherche de 
batte, les espèces invahissantes, les effets des contaminants 
environnementaux sur des plantes et des animaux, la recherche de 
séquoia, les macreuses de vague déferlante, les loutres de mer, 
les reptiles et les amphibies de la Californie méridionale, la tortue
de désert, l'économie d'habitat, et diversité génétique à 
travers différents groupes d'espèces.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece resultados de pesquisa, fotos, projetos, e
outros recursos para estudos na biologia, no biodiversity, e no 
ecology. Aprenda sobre borboletas e traças de America do Norte,
pesquisa do bastão, espécie invasive, efeitos dos contaminadores 
ambientais em plantas e animais, pesquisa do redwood, scoters do surf,
lontras do mar, répteis e anfíbios de Califórnia do sul, a 
tartaruga de deserto, o conservation do habitat, e diversidade genetic
através dos grupos diferentes da espécie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce i risultati della ricerca, le foto, i 
progetti ed altre risorse per gli studi in biologia, biodiversity ed 
ecologia. Impari circa le farfalle e lepidotteri dell'America 
del Nord, ricerca del blocco, specie invasive, effetti degli agenti 
inquinanti ambientali sulle piante ed animali, ricerca del redwood, 
scoters del surf, lontre del mare, rettili ed anfibi della California 
del sud, il tortoise di deserto, la conservazione dell'habitat e la 
diversità genetica attraverso i gruppi differenti di specie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα ερευνητικά αποτελέσματα, τις φωτογραφίες, 
τα προγράμματα, και άλλα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς για τις μελέτες 
στη βιολογία, τη βιοποικιλότητα, και την οικολογία. Μάθετε 
για τις πεταλούδες και οι σκώροι της Βόρειας Αμερικής, της 
έρευνας ροπάλων, των της εισβολής ειδών, των αποτελεσμάτων των 
περιβαλλοντικών μολυσματικών παραγόντων στα φυτά και τα ζώα, 
redwood της έρευνας, των μαυροπαπιών κυματωγών, των ενυδρίδων 
θάλασσας, των ερπετών και των αμφιβίων νότιας Καλιφόρνιας, η 
έρημος, συντήρηση βιότοπων, και γενετική ποικιλομορφία στις 
διαφορετικές ομάδες ειδών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a resultados de investigación, a las 
fotos, a los proyectos, y a otros recursos para los estudios en 
biología, biodiversidad, y ecología. Aprenda sobre mariposas y 
las polillas de Norteamérica, investigación del palo, especie 
invasora, los efectos de los contaminantes ambientales sobre las 
plantas y los animales, investigación de la secoya, los scoters de la
resaca, las nutrias del mar, los reptiles y los anfibios de California
meridional, la tortuga de desierto, la conservación del habitat, y 
diversidad genética a través de diversos grupos de la especie.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206743</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103738</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/biology-u-s-geological-survey</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
