<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105148</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105148</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087301</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Georgia Sharecropper's Story of Forced Labor ca. 1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eines Georgia Sharecroppers Geschichte der 
vorverlegten Arbeit Ca. 1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une histoire des Métayers de la Géorgie du 
travail obligatoire ca. 1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">História de Geórgia um Sharecropper do trabalho 
forçado ca. 1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia della Georgia uno Sharecropper del 
Lavoro forzato ca. 1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιστορία ενός της Γεωργίας επίμορτου καλλιεργητή της
καταναγκαστικής εργασίας περίπου το 1900</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia de Georgia un Sharecropper del trabajo 
forzado ca. 1900</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">At the turn of the century the group of black women most subject to sexual exploitation and abuse were those who lived under the system of quasi-slavery known as "peonage."Under contract labor laws, which existed in almost every southern state, a laborer who signed a contract and then quit his or her job could be arrested. The horrors of this system of forced labor (as well as the equally horrific system of convict labor) are detailed in this stark, turn-of-the-century personal account of life under the "peonage" system in the South, published in the  Independent  magazine in 1904. Although this account by an African-American man did not focus especially on the sexual exploitation suffered by his wife and others, his report described how his wife was forced to become a mistress to the plantation's owner.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An der Jahrhundertwende waren die Gruppe der 
schwarzen Frauen am meisten abhängig von sexueller Ausnutzung und der
Mißbrauch die, die unter dem System der Quasisklaverei bekannt 
lebten, als "peonage."Under Vertrag Arbeitsrechte, die in fast jedem 
südlichen Zustand existierten, ein Hilfsarbeiter, der einen Vertrag 
und dann unterzeichnete, seinen oder Job konnten festgehalten werden 
beendete. Die Grausigkeiten dieses Systems der vorverlegten 
Arbeit (so gut, wie das gleichmäßig entsetzliche System von Arbeit 
überführen), werden in diesem steifen, das persönliche Konto der 
Jahrhundertwende vom Leben unter dem "peonage" System im Süden genau 
geschildert, veröffentlicht in der unabhängigen Zeitschrift 1904. 
Obgleich dieses Konto durch einen Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen 
Mann nicht besonders auf die sexuelle Ausnutzung konzentrierte, die 
von seiner Frau und von anderen erlitten wurde, beschrieb sein Report,
wie seine Frau erzwungen wurde, eine Geliebte zum Inhaber der Plantage
zu werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À la fin du siècle le groupe de femmes noires 
plus sujet à l'exploitation sexuelle et l'abus étaient ceux qui a 
vécu sous le système du quasi-esclavage connu sous le nom de "les 
lois de main-d'oeuvre contractuelle de peonage."Under, qui ont existé
dans presque chaque état méridional, un travailleur qui a signé un 
contrat et puis a quitté son travail pourraient être arrêtées. 
Les horreurs de ce système de travail obligatoire (comme le 
système également terrifiant de condamnez le travail) sont 
détaillées dans ce rigide, compte personnel de tourner-de-le-siècle
de la vie sous le système de "peonage" dans les Sud, édité 
dans le magasin indépendant en 1904. Bien que ce compte par un 
homme afro-américain ne se soit pas concentré particulièrement sur 
l'exploitation sexuelle soufferte par son épouse et d'autres, son 
état a décrit comment son épouse a été forcée de devenir une 
maîtresse au propriétaire de la plantation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na volta do século o grupo de mulheres pretas a 
maioria de assunto à exploração sexual e abuso estava aqueles que 
viveram sob o sistema do quasi-quasi-slavery sabido como de "as leis 
labor de contrato peonage."Under, que existiram em quase cada estado 
do sul, um laborer que assinasse um contrato e então parasse seu ou 
seu trabalho poderiam ser prendidas. Os horrors deste sistema de
trabalho forçado (assim como o sistema ingualmente horrific de 
convict o trabalho) são detalhados neste stark, um cliente pessoal de
gir-$$$-$$$-SÉCULO da vida sob o sistema do "peonage" no sul, 
publicado no compartimento independente em 1904. Embora este 
cliente por um homem Africano-Americano não focalizasse especial na 
exploração sexual sofrida por sua esposa e por outra, seu relatório
descreveu como sua esposa foi forçada a se transformar um mistress ao
proprietário da plantação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alla fine del secolo il gruppo delle donne nere 
più conforme a sfruttamento sessuale e l'abuso erano coloro che ha 
vissuto sotto il sistema di quasi-quasi-slavery conosciuto come "le 
leggi di lavoro del contratto di peonage."Under, che hanno esistito 
in quasi ogni del sud dichiarano, un laborer che ha firmato un 
contratto ed allora ha rinunciato il suo lavoro potrebbe essere 
arrestato. Gli orrori di questo sistema del lavoro forzato 
(come pure il sistema ugualmente horrific di condanni il lavoro) 
sono dettagliati in questo rigido, cliente personale di 
gir-de-$$$-SECOLO di vita sotto il sistema "di peonage" nel sud, 
pubblicato nello scomparto indipendente in 1904. Anche se questo
cliente dall'uomo Africano-Americano non ha messo a fuoco 
particolarmente sullo sfruttamento sessuale sofferto dalla sua moglie 
e da altre, il suo rapporto ha descritto come la sua moglie è stata 
costretta a diventare un mistress al proprietario della piantagione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο γύρισμα του αιώνα η ομάδα μαύρων γυναικών το 
περισσότερο θέμα στη σεξουαλική εκμετάλλευση και κατάχρηση ήταν 
εκείνοι που έζησαν στο πλαίσιο του συστήματος της 
σχεδόν-σκλαβιάς γνωστού ως "εργατικά δίκαια συμβάσεων 
peonage."Under, που υπήρξαν σχεδόν σε κάθε νότιο κράτος, ένα 
laborer που υπέγραψε μια σύμβαση και εγκατέλειψε έπειτα την 
εργασία του/της θα μπορούσε να συλληφθεί. Οι φρίκες αυτού 
του συστήματος της καταναγκαστικής εργασίας (καθώς επίσης και το 
εξίσου φρικιαστικό σύστημα καταδικάζει την εργασία) είναι 
λεπτομερείς σε αυτόν τον άκαμπτο, προσωπικό απολογισμό 
στροφή-$$$-Ο-ΑΙΏΝΑ της ζωής στο πλαίσιο του συστήματος 
"peonage" στο νότο, που δημοσιεύεται στο ανεξάρτητο περιοδικό 
το 1904. Αν και αυτός ο απολογισμός από ένα 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικό άτομο δεν εστίασε ειδικά στη σεξουαλική 
εκμετάλλευση που υποφέρεται από τη σύζυγό του και άλλες, η 
έκθεσή του περιέγραψε πώς η σύζυγός του αναγκάστηκε να γίνει 
κυρία στον ιδιοκτήτη της φυτείας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Al final del siglo el grupo de mujeres negras más
conforme a la explotación sexual y el abuso eran los que vivieron 
bajo sistema de la cuasi-esclavitud conocido como "los leyes de 
trabajo de contrato de peonage."Under, que existieron en casi cada 
estado meridional, un laborer que firmó un contrato y entonces salió
su o su trabajo podrían ser arrestados. Los horrores de este 
sistema del trabajo forzado (tan bien como el sistema igualmente 
horrific de condene el trabajo) se detallan en este rígido, cuenta 
personal del dar vuelta-de-$$$-SIGLO de vida bajo sistema del 
"peonage" en el sur, publicada en el compartimiento Independiente en 
1904. Aunque esta cuenta de un hombre Africano-Americano no se 
centró especialmente en la explotación sexual sufrida por su esposa 
y otras, su informe describió cómo forzaron a su esposa hacer una 
amante al propietario de la plantación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087301</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105148</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-georgia-sharecroppers-story-of-forced-labor-ca-1900</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
