<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105170</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105170</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087101</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"They Teamed Up With The Police And The Klan:" Jack O'Dell On Red Baiting in the National Maritime Union</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie Teamed Oben Mit Der Polizei Und Dem Klan:" 
Jack O'Dell auf dem roten Anlocken im nationalen Seeanschluß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Elles Teamed Vers le haut Avec La Police et Le 
Klan :" Jack o'Dell sur l'amorce rouge dans l'union maritime 
nationale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Elas Teamed Acima Com As Polícias E O Klan:" 
Jack O'Dell em baiting vermelho na união marítima nacional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Teamed In su Con La Polizia Ed Il Klan:" 
Jack O'Dell sull'adescamento rosso nell'unione marittima 
nazionale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Συνεργάστηκαν με την αστυνομία και το Klan:" 
Γρύλος O'Dell κόκκινο να δελεάσει στην εθνική θαλάσσια 
ένωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ellas Teamed Para arriba Con El Policía Y El 
Klan:" Gato O'Dell en el hostigamiento rojo en la unión 
marítimo nacional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When the CIO initiated Operation Dixie in 1946 to challenge racial discrimination and organize workers in the largely unorganized South, Jack O'Dell signed up as a volunteer organizer. He was met with a steep resistance to racial integration and a groundswell of Cold War anti-communism that crippled and then killed the CIO's will to radically alter the working conditions of the South. Nationwide, the CIO expelled unions it claimed were influenced by communists _ amounting to nearly a million workers. Jack O'Dell was one victim of the anti-communist purge. He lost his membership in the National Maritime Union in 1950, one day after the start of the Korean War.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als die CIO initialisierte Operation Dixie 1946, 
zum der rassischen Unterscheidung herauszufordern und der Arbeiter in 
zu organisieren groß Süden unorganized, Jack O'Dell unterzeichnet 
herauf als freiwilligen Organisator. Er wurde einen steilen 
Widerstand zur rassischen Integration und ein Anschwellen des kalten 
Krieges anti-Kommunismus getroffen, das und dann den CIO's Willen 
verkrüppelte beendete, um die Arbeitsbedingungen des Südens radikal 
zu ändern. Im ganzen Land trieb das CIO Anschlüße weg, die es
wurde beeinflußt von den Kommunisten behauptete _, die fast Million 
Arbeiter betragen. Jack O'Dell war ein Opfer des 
Anti-kommunistischen Löschens. Er verlor seine Mitgliedschaft 
im nationalen Seeanschluß 1950, einen Tag nach dem Anfang des 
koreanischen Krieges.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand l'exécution lancée par CIO Dixie en 1946 
pour défier la discrimination raciale et pour organiser des ouvriers 
dans les Sud en grande partie mal organisés, Jack o'Dell s'est
engagée en tant qu'organisateur volontaire. Il a 
été rencontré une résistance raide à l'intégration raciale et 
une vague de fond du l'anti-communisme de guerre froide qui a 
estropié et a puis détruit la volonté de CIO's pour modifier 
radicalement les conditions de travail des Sud. Dans 
tout le pays, le CIO a expulsé des syndicats qu'il a réclamés ont 
été influencés par des communistes _ s'élevant presque à million 
d'ouvriers. Jack o'Dell était une victime de la purge 
anti-communiste. Il a détruit son adhésion dans l'union 
maritime nationale en 1950, un jour après le début de la guerre 
coréenne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando a operação iniciada CIO Dixie em 1946 
para desafiar a discriminação racial e para organizar trabalhadores 
no unorganized pela maior parte o sul, Jack O'Dell assinado acima como
de um organizer voluntário. Foi encontrado com com uma 
resistência íngreme à integração racial e um groundswell do 
anti-anti-communism da guerra fria que aleijasse e matasse então a 
vontade de CIO's para alterar radical as condições de funcionamento 
do sul. Por todo o país, o CIO expeliu uniões que reivindicou 
foi influenciado pelos comunistas _ que atingem quase milhão 
trabalhadores. Jack O'Dell era uma vítima da remoção 
anti-comunista. Perdeu sua sociedade na união marítima 
nacional em 1950, um dia após o começo da guerra korean.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando il funzionamento iniziato CIO Dixie in 1946
per sfidare la distinzione razziale e per organizzare gli operai in in
gran parte unorganized il sud, Jack O'Dell firmato come su 
organizzatore volontario. È stato incontrato una resistenza 
ripida ad integrazione razziale e un groundswell di anti-comunismo di 
guerra fredda che ha paralizzato ed allora ha ucciso la volontà di 
CIO's per alterare radicalmente le condizioni di lavoro del sud. 
In tutta la nazione, il CIO ha espulso i sindacati che ha 
sostenuto è stato influenzato dai comunisti _ che ammontano quasi ad 
milione operai. Jack O'Dell era una vittima dell'eliminazione 
dei fogli inceppati anti-comunista. Ha perso il suo insieme dei 
membri nell'unione marittima nazionale in 1950, un giorno dopo 
l'inizio della guerra coreana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν το CIO άρχισε τη λειτουργία Dixie το 1946
για να προκαλέσει τη φυλετική διάκριση και να οργανώσει τους 
εργαζομένους στον κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος ανοργάνωτο νότο, ο 
Jack O'Dell υπέγραψε επάνω ως εθελοντικός διοργανωτής. 
Συναντήθηκε με μια απότομη αντίσταση στη φυλετική 
ολοκλήρωση και ένα groundswell του αντι-κομμουνισμού ψυχρού 
πολέμου που ακρωτηρίασαν και σκότωσαν έπειτα τη θέληση του CIO
για να αλλάξουν ριζικά τις συνθήκες εργασίας του νότου. Σε 
εθνικό επίπεδο, οι CIO ενώσεις αυτό απαίτησαν ότι 
επηρεάστηκε από τους κομμουνιστές _ ανερχόμενος σε σχεδόν 
εκατομμύριο εργαζομένους. Ο Jack O'Dell ήταν ένα θύμα
της αντικομμουνιστούς εκκαθάρισης. Έχασε την ιδιότητα 
μέλους του στην εθνική θαλάσσια ένωση το 1950, μια ημέρα μετά
από την έναρξη του κορεατικού πολέμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando la operación iniciada CIO Dixie en 1946 
para desafiar la discriminación racial y para ordenar a trabajadores 
en unorganized en gran parte el sur, Gato O'Dell firmado encima como 
de organizador voluntario. Lo satisficieron con una resistencia 
escarpada a la integración racial y un groundswell del 
contra-comunismo de la guerra fría que lisió y después mató a la 
voluntad de CIO's para alterar radicalmente las condiciones de trabajo
del sur. Por toda la nación, el CIO expelió uniones que 
demandó fue influenciado por los comunistas _ que ascendían casi a 
millón de trabajadores. Gato O'Dell era una víctima de la 
purgación contra-comunista. Él perdió su calidad de miembro 
en la unión marítimo nacional en 1950, un día después del comienzo
de la guerra coreana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087101</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105170</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/they-teamed-up-with-the-police-and-the-klan-jack-odell-on-red-baiting-in-the-national-maritime-union</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
