<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108198</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108198</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205853</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Honky Tonks, Hymns, and the Blues</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Honky Tonks, Hymnen und das Blau</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Honky Tonks, hymnes, et les bleus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Honky Tonks, hymns, e os azuis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Honky Tonks, hymns e gli azzurri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Honky Tonks, ύμνοι, και τα μπλε</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Honky Tonks, himnos, y los azul</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the history of country guitar, country fiddling, country blues, Jimmie Rodgers (the father of country music), Thomas Dorsey (famous for raunchy records and sacred hymns), the Carter Family, Bob Wills and western swing, the Maddox Brothers and sister Rose, accordion-inspired conjunto (combination) music along Mexico's northern border, honky tonk women, and more. Descriptions, photos, and sound clips of music and interviews are included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft die Geschichte der Landguitarre, das 
fiedelnde Land, Landblau, Jimmie Rodgers (der Vater der Countrymusik),
Thomas Dorsey (berühmt für raunchy Sätze und heilige 
Hymnen), die Carter Familie, Bob willt und westliches 
Schwingen, die Maddox Brüder und Schwester Rose, 
Akkordeon-angespornte conjunto (Kombination) Musik entlang Mexikos 
Nordrand, Honky tonk Frauen und mehr. Beschreibungen, Fotos und 
Tonclips von Musik und Interviews sind enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine l'histoire de la guitare de pays, pays 
jouant du violon, bleus de pays, Jimmie Rodgers (le père de la 
musique de pays), Thomas Dorsey (célèbre pour les enregistrements 
lascifs et les hymnes sacrées), la famille de Charretier, Bob 
veut et oscillation occidentale, les frères et soeur Rose, musique 
accordéon-inspirée de Maddox de conjunto (combinaison) le long du 
cadre nordique du Mexique, femmes de tonk de honky, et plus. Les
descriptions, les photos, et les clips de bruit de la musique et les 
entrevues sont inclus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina o history da guitarra do país, país que 
fiddling, azuis do país, Jimmie Rodgers (pai da música de país), 
Thomas Dorsey (famoso para registros raunchy e hymns sacred), a 
família de Carter, Bob quer e balanço ocidental, os irmãos de 
Maddox e irmã Rosa, música acordeão-inspirada do conjunto 
(combinação) ao longo da beira do norte de México, mulheres do tonk
do honky, e mais. As descrições, as fotos, e os grampos do som
da música e as entrevistas são incluídos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina la storia del guitar del paese, il paese 
che fiddling, gli azzurri del paese, Jimmie Rodgers (il padre di 
musica di paese), Thomas Dorsey (famoso per i record raunchy e hymns 
sacred), la famiglia di Carter, Bob vuole ed oscillazione occidentale,
i fratelli di Maddox e sorella Rosa, musica fisarmonica-ispirata di 
conjunto (combinazione) lungo il bordo nordico del Messico, donne del 
tonk del honky e più. Le descrizioni, le foto e le clip del 
suono di musica e le interviste sono incluse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την ιστορία της κιθάρας χωρών, να παίξει 
βιολί χωρών, μπλε χωρών, Jimmie Rodgers (ο πατέρας της 
μουσικής χωρών), Thomas Dorsey (διάσημο για τα λάγνα αρχεία
και τους ιερούς ύμνους), η οικογένεια Carter, διαθήκες 
βαριδιών και η δυτική ταλάντευση, οι αδελφοί Maddox και η 
αδελφή αυξήθηκαν, ακκορντέον-εμπνευσμένη μουσική conjunto 
(συνδυασμός) κατά μήκος των βόρειων συνόρων του Μεξικού, 
honky γυναίκες tonk, και περισσότερο. Οι περιγραφές, οι
φωτογραφίες, και οι υγιείς συνδετήρες της μουσικής και οι 
συνεντεύξεις συμπεριλαμβάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina la historia de la guitarra del país, 
país que toca el violín, azul del país, Jimmie Rodgers (el padre de
la música de país), Thomas Dorsey (famoso por expedientes raunchy y 
los himnos sagrados), la familia de Carretero, Bob quiere y 
oscilación occidental, los hermanos y hermana Rose, música 
acordio'n-inspirada de Maddox del conjunto (combinación) a lo largo 
de la frontera norteña de México, mujeres del tonk del honky, y 
más. Las descripciones, las fotos, y los clips del sonido de la
música y las entrevistas son incluidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205853</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108198</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/honky-tonks-hymns-and-the-blues</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
