<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103181</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103181</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086188</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Genesee Had Railroads": Kenneth Platt Recalls the Importance of the Railroad to Late Nineteenth-Century Western Towns</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Genesee Hatte Eisenbahnen": Kenneth Platt 
erinnert an den Wert der Eisenbahn spätes 19.-Jahrhundert zu den 
westlichen Städten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Genesee A eu des Chemins de fer" : 
Kenneth Platt rappelle l'importance du chemin de fer aux 
villes occidentales de défunt Dix-neuvième-Siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Genesee Teve Estradas de ferro": Kenneth 
Platt recorda a importância da estrada de ferro às cidades 
ocidentais de Décimo-Século atrasado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Genesee Ha avuto Ferrovie": Kenneth Platt 
ricorda l'importanza della ferrovia alle città occidentali del 
Diciannovesimo-Secolo tardo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Genesee είχε τους σιδηροδρόμουσ": Κέννεθ 
Platt Recalls η σημασία του σιδηροδρόμου στις πρόσφατες 
δυτικές πόλεις δέκατος-αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Genesee Tenía Ferrocarriles": Kenneth 
Platt recuerda la importancia del ferrocarril a las ciudades 
occidentales del último Diecinueveavo-Siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The penetration of the railroads into the West in the late nineteenth century had a profound impact on local economies. For a period of ten years in the 1880s the Latah County, Idaho town of Genesee experienced this phenomenon. One town boomed while its neighbors languished in economic isolation, largely as a result of the rail station in Genesee. In this oral history interview, Kenneth Platt described the railroad's impact on Latah County.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Durchgriff der Eisenbahnen in den Westen im 
späten 19.jahrhundert hatte eine profunde Auswirkung auf lokale 
Wirtschaftssysteme. Während einer Periode von 10 Jahren im 
1880s erfuhr die Latah Grafschaft, Idaho Stadt von Genesee dieses 
Phänomen. Eine Stadt dröhnte, während seine Nachbarn in der 
ökonomischen Lokalisierung schmachteten, groß resultierend aus der 
Schiene Station in Genesee. In diesem Mundgeschichte Interview 
beschrieb Kenneth Platt die Auswirkung der Eisenbahn auf Latah 
Grafschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La pénétration des chemins de fer dans 
l'occidental vers la fin du dix-neuvième siècle a eu un impact 
profond sur des économies locales. Pendant une période de dix 
ans dans le 1880s le comté de Latah, ville de l'Idaho de Genesee a 
éprouvé ce phénomène. Une ville a grondé tandis que ses 
voisins languissaient dans l'isolement économique, en grande partie 
en raison de la station de rail dans Genesee. Dans cette 
entrevue orale d'histoire, Kenneth Platt a décrit l'impact du 
chemin de fer sur le comté de Latah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A penetração das estradas de ferro no oeste no 
décimo nono século atrasado teve um impacto profundo em economias 
locais. Por um período de dez anos no 1880s o condado de Latah,
cidade de Idaho de Genesee experimentou este fenômeno. Uma 
cidade cresceu quando seus vizinhos languished na isolação 
econômica, pela maior parte em conseqüência da estação do trilho 
em Genesee. Nesta entrevista oral do history, Kenneth Platt 
descreveu o impacto da estrada de ferro no condado de Latah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La penetrazione delle ferrovie nell'ad ovest verso
la fine del diciannovesimo secolo ha avuta un effetto profondo sulle 
economie locali. Per un periodo di dieci anni nel 1880s la 
contea di Latah, città dell'Idaho di Genesee ha avvertito questo 
fenomeno. Una città ha cresciuto mentre i relativi vicinoi 
languished nell'isolamento economico, in gran parte come conseguenza 
della stazione della guida in Genesee. In questa intervista 
orale di storia, Kenneth Platt ha descritto l'effetto della ferrovia 
sulla contea di Latah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διείσδυση των σιδηροδρόμων στη δύση προς το τέλος 
του δέκατου έννατου αιώνα άσκησε βαθιά επίδραση στις τοπικές 
οικονομίες. Για μια περίοδο δέκα ετών στο 1880s ο 
Latah νομός, πόλη του Idaho Genesee δοκίμασε αυτό το 
φαινόμενο. Μια πόλη βόυιξε ενώ οι γείτονές του ατόνησαν 
μεμονωμένα οικονομική, κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος ως αποτέλεσμα του 
σταθμού ραγών σε Genesee. Σε αυτήν την προφορική 
συνέντευξη ιστορίας, Κέννεθ Platt περιέγραψε τον αντίκτυπο του
σιδηροδρόμου στο νομό Latah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La penetración de los ferrocarriles en el oeste 
en el a fines del siglo diecinueve tenía un impacto profundo en 
economías locales. Por un período de diez años en el 1880s el
condado de Latah, ciudad de Idaho de Genesee experimentó este 
fenómeno. Una ciudad creció mientras que sus vecinos 
languished en el aislamiento económico, en gran parte como resultado 
de la estación del carril en Genesee. En esta entrevista oral 
de la historia, Kenneth Platt describió el impacto del ferrocarril en
el condado de Latah.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086188</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103181</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/genesee-had-railroads-kenneth-platt-recalls-the-importance-of-the-railroad-to-late-nineteenth-century-western-towns</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
