<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106971</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106971</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206026</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Polluted Runoff</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beschmutzter Abfluß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Écoulement Pollué</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Runoff Polluted</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scolo Inquinante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μολυσμένη απορροή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Salida Contaminada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lessons and activities for studying how runoff affects streams, how to analyze what's upstream and downstream from your community (watersheds), and how families can reduce nonpoint source pollution, which results from rainfall or snowmelt moving over and through the ground.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lektionen zur Verfügung und Aktivitäten 
für das Studieren, wie Abfluß Ströme beeinflußt, wie man was 
aufwärts und von Ihrer Gemeinschaft (Wasserscheiden) abwärts 
gerichtetes ist analysiert und wie Familien nonpoint 
Quellverunreinigung verringern können, die aus Niederschlag oder dem 
snowmelt bewegt über und durch den Boden resultiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons et des activités pour 
étudier comment l'écoulement affecte des jets, comment analyser ce 
qui est ascendant et descendant de votre communauté (lignes de 
partage), et comment les familles peuvent réduire la pollution de 
source de nonpoint, au-dessus dont résulte des précipitations ou du 
snowmelt se déplacer et par la terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece lições e atividades para estudar como o 
runoff afeta córregos, como analisar o que é rio acima e downstream 
de sua comunidade (watersheds), e como as famílias podem reduzir a 
poluição da fonte do nonpoint, que resulta do rainfall ou do 
snowmelt se mover sobre e através da terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni ed attività per studiare come
lo scolo interessa i flussi, come analizzare che cosa è verso l'alto 
e downstream dalla vostra Comunità (spartiacque) e come le famiglie 
possono ridurre l'inquinamento di sorgente del nonpoint, cui deriva da
pioggia o da snowmelt muoversi sopra ed attraverso la terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα μαθήματα και τις δραστηριότητες για τη 
μελέτη πώς η απορροή έχει επιπτώσεις στα ρεύματα, πώς να 
αναλύσει ποιοι προς τα πάνω και προς τα κάτω από την κοινότητά 
σας (υδροκρίτες), και πώς οι οικογένειες μπορούν να μειώσουν 
nonpoint τη ρύπανση πηγής, η οποία προκύπτει από τις 
βροχοπτώσεις ή snowmelt την κίνηση πέρα από και μέσω το 
έδαφος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a lecciones y las actividades para 
estudiar cómo la salida afecta secuencias, cómo analizar cuál es 
por aguas arriba y en sentido descendiente de su comunidad (líneas 
divisoria de las aguas), y cómo las familias pueden reducir la 
contaminación de la fuente del nonpoint, sobre la cual resulta de la 
precipitación o del snowmelt la mudanza y a través de la tierra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206026</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106971</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/polluted-runoff</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
