<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103464</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103464</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086268</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Am Almost a Prisoner": Women Plead for Contraception</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich bin fast ein Gefangener": Frauen 
plädieren für Empfängnisverhütung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je suis presque un prisonnier" : Les femmes
parlent en faveur de la contraception</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu sou quase um prisioneiro": As mulheres 
plead para o contraception</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sono quasi un prigioniero": Le donne 
supplicano per la contraccezione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"είμαι σχεδόν φυλακισμένοσ": Οι γυναίκες 
παρακαλούν για την αντισύλληψη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"casi soy un preso": Las mujeres abogan por 
para la contracepción</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Improved birth control was one crucial element in women's exercise of sexual freedom. Though people had practiced methods of fertility control for hundreds of years, the 20th century saw the advent of more reliable technologies that allowed a sharper separation between sex and reproduction. Before World War I, birth control advocates confronted a large and often hostile audience of opponents. By the 1920s, though, changing sexual ideologies made such ideas more widely acceptable. The major figure in the American birth control movement, Margaret Sanger, began her crusade as a militant radical whose birth control agitation grew out of her nursing experience in working-class communities. Sanger received 250,000 letters from women asking for advice about birth control. In 1928 Sanger published a selection of the letters in her book  Motherhood in Bondage . The letters remain a powerful testament to the vulnerability of women without access to reliable contraception.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verbesserte Geburtenkontrolle war ein 
entscheidendes Element in der Übung der Frauen der sexuellen 
Freiheit. Obwohl Leute Methoden der Ergiebigkeitsteuerung für 
Hunderte Jahre geübt hatten, sah das 20. Jahrhundert das Aufkommen 
der zuverlässigeren Technologien, die eine schärfere Trennung 
zwischen Geschlecht und Wiedergabe erlaubten. Vor dem Ersten 
Weltkrieg konfrontierten Geburtenkontrollefürsprecher ein großes und
häufig feindliches Publikum der Konkurrenten. Bis zum den 
zwanziger Jahren obwohl, ändernde sexuelle Ideologien solche Ideen 
weit annehmbar bildeten. Die Hauptabbildung in der 
amerikanischen Geburtenkontrollebewegung, Margaret Sanger, fing ihren 
Kreuzzug als militantes Radikal an dessen Geburtenkontrollebewegung 
aus ihrer Krankenpflegeerfahrung in den Arbeiterklassegemeinschaften 
heraus wuchs. Sanger erhielt 250.000 Briefe von den Frauen, die 
um Rat nach Geburtenkontrolle bitten. Sanger 1928 
veröffentlicht einer Auswahl der Zeichen in ihrer Buch Mutterschaft 
in der Knechtschaft. Die Zeichen bleiben ein leistungsfähiges 
Testament zur Verwundbarkeit der Frauen ohne Zugriff zur 
zuverlässigen Empfängnisverhütung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le contrôle des naissances amélioré était un 
élément crucial chez l'exercice des femmes de la liberté sexuelle. 
Bien que les gens aient pratiqué des méthodes de commande de 
fertilité pour des centaines d'années, le 20ème siècle a vu 
l'arrivée des technologies plus fiables qui ont permis une 
séparation plus marquée entre le sexe et la reproduction. 
Avant la Première Guerre Mondiale, les avocats de contrôle des
naissances ont confronté une grande et souvent hostile assistance des
adversaires. Par les années 20, bien que, les idéologies 
sexuelles changeantes aient rendu de telles idées plus largement 
acceptables. La figure principale dans le mouvement américain 
de contrôle des naissances, Margaret Sanger, a commencé sa 
croisade comme radical militant dont l'agitation de contrôle des 
naissances s'est développée hors de sa expérience de soins des 
communautés de classe ouvrière. Sanger a reçu 250.000 lettres
des femmes demandant le conseil sur le contrôle des naissances. 
En Sanger 1928 édité une sélection des lettres dans sa 
maternité de livre dans le servage. Les lettres demeurent un 
testament puissant à la vulnérabilité des femmes sans accès à la 
contraception fiable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O controle de nascimento melhorado era um elemento
crucial no exercício das mulheres da liberdade sexual. Embora 
os povos tinham praticado métodos do controle da fertilidade para 
centenas dos anos, o 20o século viu o advent de umas tecnologias mais
de confiança que permitissem uma separação mais afiada entre o sexo
e a reprodução. Antes do world.war.i, os advogados do controle
de nascimento confrontaram uma audiência grande e frequentemente 
hostil dos oponentes. Pelos 1920s, embora, os ideologies sexual 
em mudança fizeram tais idéias mais extensamente aceitáveis. 
A figura principal no movimento americano do controle de 
nascimento, Margaret Sanger, começou seu crusade como um radical 
militant cujo o agitation do controle de nascimento crescesse fora de 
sua experiência dos cuidados em comunidades do working-class. 
Sanger recebeu 250.000 letras das mulheres que pedem conselho 
sobre o controle de nascimento. Em Sanger 1928 publicado uma 
seleção das letras em seu motherhood do livro no bondage. As 
letras remanescem um testament poderoso ao vulnerability das mulheres 
sem acesso ao contraception de confiança.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il controllo di nascita migliorato era un elemento
cruciale nell'esercitazione delle donne della libertà sessuale. 
Benchè la gente si eserciti nei metodi di controllo di 
fertilità per le centinaia degli anni, il ventesimo secolo ha visto 
l'avvenimento delle tecnologie più certe che hanno permesso una 
separazione più marcata fra il sesso e la riproduzione. Prima 
del world.war.i, i fautori di controllo di nascita hanno confrontato 
un grande e pubblico spesso ostile degli avversari. Entro gli 
anni 20, benchè, le ideologie sessuali cambianti rendano tali idee 
più ampiamente accettabili. La figura principale nel movimento 
americano di controllo di nascita, Margaret Sanger, ha cominciato il 
suo crusade come radicale del militante di cui l'agitazione di 
controllo di nascita si è sviluppata dalla sua esperienza di 
professione d'infermiera di Comunità della classe operaia. 
Sanger ha ricevuto 250.000 lettere dalle donne che chiedono il 
consiglio riguardo al controllo di nascita. In Sanger 1928 
pubblicato una selezione delle lettere nella sua maternità del libro 
nel bondage. Le lettere rimangono un testamento potente alla 
vulnerabilità delle donne senza accesso alla contraccezione certa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο βελτιωμένος έλεγχος γέννησης ήταν ένα κρίσιμο 
στοιχείο στην άσκηση των γυναικών της σεξουαλικής ελευθερίας. 
Αν και οι άνθρωποι είχαν εφαρμόσει τις μεθόδους ελέγχου 
γονιμότητας για τις εκατοντάδες των ετών, ο 20ός αιώνας 
εβλέίδε την εμφάνιση των πιό αξιόπιστων τεχνολογιών που 
επέτρεψαν έναν αιχμηρότερο χωρισμό μεταξύ του φύλου και της 
αναπαραγωγής. Πριν από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, οι συνήγοροι
ελέγχου γέννησης αντιμετώπισαν ένα μεγάλο και συχνά εχθρικό 
ακροατήριο αντιπάλων. Μέχρι τη δεκαετία του '20, εν 
τούτοις, που αλλάζει οι σεξουαλικές ιδεολογίες κατέστησαν 
τέτοιες ιδέες ευρύτερα αποδεκτές. Ο σημαντικότερος αριθμός
στην αμερικανική μετακίνηση ελέγχου γέννησης, Margaret 
Sanger, άρχισε τη σταυροφορία της ως στρατευμένο ριζοσπάστη η ο
οποίος αναταραχή ελέγχου γέννησης αυξήθηκε από την εμπειρία 
περιποίησής της στις κοινότητες εργατικών τάξεων. Το 
Sanger έλαβε 250.000 επιστολές από τις γυναίκες που ζητούν 
τις συμβουλές για τον έλεγχο γέννησης. Το 1928 Sanger 
δημοσίευσε μια επιλογή των επιστολών στη μητρότητα βιβλίων της 
στη δουλεία. Οι επιστολές παραμένουν μια ισχυρή διαθήκη 
στην ευπάθεια των γυναικών χωρίς πρόσβαση στην αξιόπιστη 
αντισύλληψη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El control de la natalidad mejorado era un 
elemento crucial en el ejercicio de las mujeres de la libertad sexual.
Aunque la gente había practicado métodos de control de la 
fertilidad para los centenares de años, el vigésimo siglo consideró
el advenimiento de tecnologías más confiables que permitieron una 
separación más sostenida entre el sexo y la reproducción. 
Antes de Primera Guerra Mundial, los abogados del control de la 
natalidad enfrentaron a audiencia grande y a menudo hostil de 
opositores. Por los años 20, aunque, las ideologías sexuales 
que cambiaban hicieron tales ideas más extensamente aceptables. 
La figura principal en el movimiento americano del control de la
natalidad, Margaret Sanger, comenzó su cruzada como radical 
militante que agitación del control de la natalidad creció fuera de
su experiencia del oficio de enfermera en comunidades de la clase 
obrera. Sanger recibió 250.000 letras de las mujeres que 
pedían consejo acerca de control de la natalidad. En Sanger 
1928 publicado una selección de las cartas en su maternidad del libro
en bondage. Las cartas siguen siendo un testamento de gran 
alcance a la vulnerabilidad de mujeres sin el acceso a la 
contracepción confiable.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086268</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103464</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-am-almost-a-prisoner-women-plead-for-contraception</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
