<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108293</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108293</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201585</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Evidence of Ancient Martian Life in Meteorite ALH84001?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beweis der alten Martian Lebensdauer im Meteorit 
ALH84001?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Évidence de la vie antique de Martian en 
météorite ALH84001 ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Evidência da vida antiga de Martian no meteorite 
ALH84001?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prova di vita antica del Martian in meteorite 
ALH84001?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στοιχεία της αρχαίας Αριανής ζωής στο μετεωρίτη 
ALH84001;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Evidencia de la vida antigua de Martian en el 
meteorito ALH84001?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This NASA website provides a summary of a study led by NASA's David McKay that may provide evidence for past life on Mars. McKay and his team found carbonate globule features on the ALH84001 meteorite that appear to be nanofossils. In addition, secondary mineral phases and hydrocarbons provide further evidence for past life. The website features color photographs as well as links to related web pages.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese die NASA Web site liefert eine Zusammenfassung einer
Studie, die von David McKay NASAs geführt wird, der Beweis für 
letzte Lebensdauer auf Mars zur Verfügung stellen kann. McKay 
und sein Team fanden Karbonatkügelchenmerkmale auf dem Meteorit 
ALH84001, die scheinen, nanofossils zu sein. Zusätzlich stellen
Sekundärmineralphasen und Kohlenwasserstoffe weiteren Beweis für 
letzte Lebensdauer zur Verfügung. Die Web site kennzeichnet 
Farbe Fotographien sowie Links zu in Verbindung stehenden Webseiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web de la NASA fournit un sommaire d'une étude 
menée par David McKay de NASA's qui peut fournir l'évidence pour la 
vie passée sur Mars. McKay et son équipe ont trouvé des 
dispositifs de globule de carbonate sur la météorite ALH84001 qui 
semblent être des nanofossils. En outre, les phases minérales 
secondaires et les hydrocarbures fournissent davantage d'évidence 
pour la vie passée. Le site Web comporte des photographies de 
couleur aussi bien que des liens aux pages Web relatives.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site da NASA fornece um sumário de um estudo 
conduzido por David McKay de NASA que pode fornecer a evidência para 
a vida passada em Marte. McKay e sua equipe encontraram 
características do globule do carbonato no meteorite ALH84001 que 
parecem ser nanofossils. Além, as fases minerais secundárias e
os hidrocarbonetos fornecem uma evidência mais adicional para a vida 
passada. O Web site caracteriza fotografias da cor as.well.as as
ligações aos Web pages relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site della NASA fornisce un sommario di uno 
studio condotto da David McKay della NASA che può fornire la prova 
per vita passata su Marte. McKay e la sua squadra hanno trovato 
le caratteristiche del globulo del carbonato sul meteorite ALH84001 
che sembrano essere nanofossils. In più, le fasi minerali 
secondarie e gli idrocarburi forniscono ulteriore prova per vita 
passata. Il Web site caratterizza le fotografie di colore così 
come i collegamenti ai Web pagi relativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος της NASA παρέχει μια περίληψη 
μιας μελέτης που οδηγείται από το Δαβίδ McKay της NASA που 
μπορεί να παρέχει τα στοιχεία για την προηγούμενη ζωή στον Αρη. 
McKay και η ομάδα του βρήκε globule ανθρακικού άλατος
τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα στο μετεωρίτη ALH84001 που 
εμφανίζονται να είναι nanofossils. Επιπλέον, οι 
δευτεροβάθμιες ορυκτές φάσεις και οι υδρογονάνθρακες παρέχουν τα 
περαιτέρω στοιχεία για την προηγούμενη ζωή. Τα 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα ιστοχώρου χρωματίζουν τις φωτογραφίες 
καθώς επίσης και τις συνδέσεις με σχετικές ιστοσελίδας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site de la NASA proporciona a un resumen de un 
estudio conducido por David McKay de NASÁs que pueda proporcionar a 
la evidencia para la última vida en Marte. McKay y su equipo 
encontraron características del glóbulo del carbonato en el 
meteorito ALH84001 que aparecen ser nanofossils. Además, las 
fases mineral secundarias y los hidrocarburos proporcionan a evidencia
adicional para la última vida. El Web site ofrece las 
fotografías del color así como conexiones a los Web pages 
relacionados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DR. DAVID R. WILLIAMS
FN:DR. DAVID R. WILLIAMS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NASA
FN:NASA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201585</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108293</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/evidence-of-ancient-martian-life-in-meteorite-alh84001</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
