<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105287</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105287</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086780</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reformer Jane Addams Critiques  The Birth of a Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reformer Jane Addams Kritiken die Geburt 
einer Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Critiques de Jane Addams de réformateur la 
naissance d'une nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Críticas de Reformer Jane Addams o nascimento de 
uma nação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Valutazioni di Reformer Jane Addams la nascita di 
una nazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταρρυθμιστής Jane Addams Critiques The 
Birth ενός έθνους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Críticas de Jane Addams del reformador el 
nacimiento de una nación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Birth of a Nation , which opened in March 1915, was simultaneously a landmark in the history of American cinema and a landmark in American racism. The film depicted the South, following the assassination of President Lincoln, as ruled by rapacious African Americans, who by the film's end were heroically overthrown from power by the Ku Klux Klan. The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) attempted to mount boycott of the film, but it failed to stir significant white opposition. Ten days after  Birth  opened in New York City, noted reformer and NAACP board member Jane Addams (founder of Hull House, the Chicago settlement house) was interviewed by the  New York Post  about the film. Though Addams abhorred the film's portrayal of African Americans, she nonetheless conceded--perhaps intimidated by director D.W. Griffith's unrelenting efforts to cloak the film in the mantle of historical "accuracy"--that "some of the elements of the plot are based on actual events." This statement suggested how deeply the pro-Southern interpretation of Reconstruction had permeated popular understanding of that history, and Griffith was able to cite contemporary academic historians to support this view.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Geburt einer Nation, die im März 1915 sich 
öffnete, war gleichzeitig ein Grenzstein in der Geschichte des 
amerikanischen Kinos und ein Grenzstein im amerikanischen Rassismus. 
Der Film stellte das Süd bildlich dar und folgte der Ermordung 
des Präsidenten Lincoln, wie von den rapacious afrikanischen 
Amerikanern angeordnet, die durch das Ende des Filmes heroisch von der
Energie durch das Ku Klux Klan besiegt wurden. Die nationale 
Verbindung für die Zuführung der Farbiger (NAACP) versuchte, Boykott
des Filmes, aber ihn einzuhängen nicht konnte bedeutende weiße 
Opposition rühren. 10 sich Tage nachdem Geburt in New York 
City, beachteter Reformer öffnete und NAACP Brettbauteil Jane 
Addams (Gründer des Rumpf-Hauses, des Chicago Regelung Hauses) durch 
den New York Pfosten über den Film interviewt wurde. Obwohl 
Addams die Schilderung des Filmes der afrikanischen Amerikaner 
verabscheute, gestand sie nichtsdestoweniger zu -- möglicherweise 
eingeschüchtert durch Direktor D.W. Griffith unnachgiebige 
Bemühungen, den Film im Umhang der historischen "Genauigkeit" zu 
verbergen -- den "einige der Elemente des Plots basieren auf 
tatsächlichen Fällen." Diese Anweisung schlug vor, wie tief 
die Pro-Südliche Deutung der Rekonstruktion populäres Verständnis 
dieser Geschichte durchdrungen hatte, und Griffith konnte, 
zeitgenössische akademische Historiker zu zitieren, um diese Ansicht 
zu unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La naissance d'une nation, qui s'est ouverte en 
mars 1915, était simultanément une borne limite dans l'histoire du 
cinéma américain et une borne limite dans le racisme américain. 
Le film a dépeint le du sud, suivant l'assassinat du 
Président Lincoln, comme régné par les Américains africains 
rapaces, qui par l'extrémité du film ont été héroïquement 
renversés de la puissance par le Ku Klux Klan. L'association 
nationale pour l'avancement des personnes de couleur (NAACP) a essayé
de monter le boycott du film, mais lui n'a pas remué l'opposition 
blanche significative. Pendant Dix jours après que la naissance
s'est ouverte à New York City, réformateur remarquable et membre du 
conseil de NAACP Jane Addams (fondateur de Chambre de coque, de la 
maison de règlement de Chicago) a été interviewé par le poteau de 
New York au sujet du film. Bien qu'addams abhorred la 
représentation du film des Américains africains, elle a néanmoins 
concédé -- peut-être intimidé par des efforts persistants de 
directeur D.W. Griffith de masquer le film dans le manteau de 
l'"exactitude" historique -- que "certains des éléments du traçage 
sont basé sur des événements réels." Ce rapport a suggéré 
comment profondément la traduction pro-Méridionale de la 
reconstruction avait imprégné l'arrangement populaire de cette 
histoire, et Griffith pouvait citer les historiens contemporains 
d'universitaire pour supporter cette vue.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O nascimento de uma nação, que abrisse em março
1915, era simultaneamente um marco no history do cinema americano e um
marco no racism americano. A película descreveu o sul, seguindo
o assassination do presidente Lincoln, como governado pelos americanos
africanos rapacious, que pela extremidade da película overthrown 
heroically da potência pelo Ku Klux Klan. A associação 
nacional para o avanço dos povos coloridos (NAACP) tentou montá-la o
boycott da película, mas não agitou a oposição branca 
significativa. Dez dias depois que o nascimento abriu em New 
York City, reformer notável e membro de placa Jane de NAACP Addams 
(founder da casa do hull, da casa do estabelecimento de Chicago) foi 
entrevistado pelo borne de New York sobre a película. Embora 
Addams abhorred o portrayal da película de americanos africanos, 
nonetheless conceded -- talvez intimidated por esforços unrelenting 
do diretor D.W. Griffith cloak a película no mantle da "exatidão 
histórica" -- que "alguns dos elementos do lote são baseados em 
eventos reais." Esta indicação sugeriu como profundamente a 
interpretação pro-Do sul do reconstruction permeated a compreensão 
popular desse history, e Griffith podia  cite historians academic 
contemporary para suportar esta vista.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La nascita di una nazione, che si è aperta nel 
mese di marzo del 1915, era simultaneamente un limite nella storia del
cinematografo americano e un limite nel razzismo americano. La 
pellicola ha descritto il del sud, seguendo l'assassinio del 
presidente Lincoln, come regolato dagli Americani africani rapacious, 
che dall'estremità della pellicola eroico overthrown da potenza dal 
Ku Klux Klan. L'associazione nazionale per l'avanzamento della 
gente colorata (NAACP) ha tentato di montarla il boicottaggio della 
pellicola, ma non è riuscito a mescolare l'opposizione bianca 
significativa. Dieci giorni dopo che la nascita si apra a New 
York City, reformer celebre e membro Jane Addams (fondatore del 
bordo di NAACP della Camera del guscio, della casa di 
stabilimento del Chicago) è stato intervistato dall'alberino de New 
York circa la pellicola. Benchè Addams abhorred la 
rappresentazione della pellicola degli Americani africani, ciò 
nonostante ha concesso -- forse intimidito dagli sforzi inesorabili 
del direttore D.W. Griffith cloak la pellicola nel manto "di 
esattezza" storica -- che "alcuni degli elementi del diagramma sono 
basati sugli eventi reali." Questa istruzione ha suggerito 
quanto profondamente l'interpretazione pro-Del sud di ricostruzione 
aveva pervaso la comprensione popolare di quella storia e Griffith 
poteva citare gli storici accademici contemporanei per sostenere 
questa vista.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η γέννηση ενός έθνους, που άνοιξε τον Μάρτιο του 
1915, ήταν ταυτόχρονα ένα ορόσημο στην ιστορία του 
αμερικανικού κινηματογράφου και ένα ορόσημο στον αμερικανικό 
ρατσισμό. Η ταινία απεικόνισε το νότο, μετά από τη 
δολοφονία του Προέδρου Lincoln, όπως κυβερνιέται από 
αρπακτικούς αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς, οι οποίοι από το τέλος της
ταινίας νικήθηκαν ηρωικά από τη δύναμη από το Ku Klux 
Klan. Η εθνική ένωση για την πρόοδο των έγχρωμων 
ανθρώπων (NAACP) προσπάθησε να επικολλήσει το μποϊκοτάρισμα 
της ταινίας, αλλά απέτυχε να ανακατώσει τη σημαντική άσπρη 
αντίθεση. Δέκα ημέρες μετά από τη γέννηση που άνοιξαν στη
Νέα Υόρκη η πόλη, σημείωσε το μεταρρυθμιστή και το μέλος Jane
Addams συμβουλίων NAACP (ιδρυτής του σπιτιού του Hull, το 
σπίτι τακτοποίησης του Σικάγου) πέρασε από συνέντευξη με το 
ταχυδρομείο της Νέας Υόρκης για την ταινία. Αν και Addams
η απεικόνιση της ταινίας αφρικανικών Αμερικανών, εν τούτοις 
παραχώρησε -- ίσως εκφοβισμένος από τις άκαμπτες προσπάθειες 
σκηνοθέτη D.W. griffith στον επενδύτη την ταινία στο μανδύα 
της ιστορικής "ακρίβειασ" -- ότι "μερικά από τα στοιχεία της 
πλοκής είναι βασισμένα στα πραγματικά γεγονότα." Αυτή η 
δήλωση πρότεινε πόσο βαθειά η υπέρ-νότια ερμηνεία της 
αναδημιουργίας είχε διαπεράσει τη δημοφιλή κατανόηση εκείνης της
ιστορίας, και griffith ήταν σε θέση να αναφέρει τους 
σύγχρονους ακαδημαϊκούς ιστορικούς για να υποστηρίξει αυτήν την 
όψη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El nacimiento de una nación, que se abrió en 
marcha de 1915, era simultáneamente una señal en la historia del 
cine americano y una señal en racismo americano. La película 
representó el del sur, siguiendo el asesinato de presidente Lincoln, 
según lo gobernado por los americanos africanos rapaces, que por el 
extremo de la película heroico fueron derrocados de potencia por el 
Ku Klux Klan. La asociación nacional para el adelanto de la 
gente coloreada (NAACP) procuró montar el boicoteo de la película, 
pero la no pudo revolver la oposición blanca significativa. 
Diez días después de que el nacimiento se abrió en New York 
City, reformador conocido y miembro del Consejo de NAACP Jane Addams 
(fundador de la casa del casco, de la casa del establecimiento de 
Chicago) fue entrevistado con por el poste de Nueva York sobre la 
película. Aunque Addams abhorred la representación de la 
película de americanos africanos, ella no obstante concedió -- 
quizás intimidado por esfuerzos implacables de director D.W. Griffith
de disimular la película en la capa de la "exactitud histórica" -- 
que "algunos de los elementos del diagrama se basan en acontecimientos
reales." Esta declaración sugirió cómo la interpretación 
favorable-Meridional de la reconstrucción había impregnado 
profundamente la comprensión popular de esa historia, y Griffith 
podía citar a historiadores académicos contemporáneos para utilizar
esta visión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086780</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105287</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/reformer-jane-addams-critiques-the-birth-of-a-nation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
