<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108173</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108173</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086403</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Leave Them Alone; That Is the Remedy": A Manufacturer's Solution to the Depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Lassen Sie Sie Allein; Das ist das 
Hilfsmittel ": Lösung eines Herstellers zum Tiefstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Laissez-Les Seules ; C'est le remède ": 
La solution d'un constructeur à la dépression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Deixe-os Sozinha; Aquele é o remédio ": 
Solução de um fabricante ao depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Lascile Sole; Quello è il rimedio ": 
Soluzione del fornitore alla depressione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τους αφήστε μόνο  Αυτή είναι η θεραπεία ": 
Η λύση ενός κατασκευαστή στην κατάθλιψη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Déjelas Solas; Ése es el remedio ": 
Solución de un fabricante a la depresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With depression looming as a continual threat to the U.S. economy in the late 19th century, Americans debated how the government should respond to hard times--a question still unanswered today. Manufacturers--then as now--usually took the position that government should not interfere with the workings of the "free market." When J. H. Walker, a shoe manufacturer from Worcester, Massachusetts, testified in 1878 before a congressional committee investigating "the causes of the general depression in labor and business," he argued simply that the government should do nothing at all for the vast army of unemployed. "Leave them alone; that is the remedy," he declared.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenn der Tiefstand als kontinuierliche Drohung 
auftaucht, zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Wirtschaft im des späten 19. 
jahrhunderts Jahrhundert, debattierten Amerikaner, wie die Regierung 
auf harte Zeiten noch reagieren sollte -- eine Frage, die heute 
unbeantwortet ist. Hersteller -- dann als jetzt -- nahmen 
normalerweise die Position, daß Regierung nicht die Funktionen des 
"freien Marktes behinderen sollte." Wenn J. H. Walker, ein 
Schuhhersteller von Worcester, Massachusetts, bezeugt 1878, bevor ein 
Kongreßausschuß, der "die Ursachen des allgemeinen Tiefstands in der
Arbeit und im Geschäft," er nachforscht, einfach argumentierte, daß 
die Regierung nichts an allen für die beträchtliche Armee der 
Arbeitsloser tun sollte. "lassen Sie sie allein; das ist 
das Hilfsmittel, "er erklärte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec la dépression apparaissant indistinctement 
comme menace continuelle à l'économie des ETATS-UNIS vers la fin du 
19ème siècle, les Américains ont discuté comment le gouvernement 
devrait répondre aux périodes difficiles -- une question encore sans
réponse aujourd'hui. Les constructeurs -- puis en tant que 
maintenant -- ont habituellement pris la position que le gouvernement 
ne devrait pas gêner les fonctionnements "du marché libre." 
Quand J. H. Walker, un constructeur de chaussure de Worcester, 
le Massachusetts, témoigné en 1878 avant qu'un comité 
congressionnel étudiant "les causes de la dépression générale dans
le travail et les affaires," il ait argué du fait simplement que le 
gouvernement devrait ne faire rien du tout pour la vaste armée des 
chômeurs. "laissez-les seuls ; c'est le remède, "il a 
déclaré.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com o depression que aparece como uma ameaça 
contínua à economia de ESTADOS UNIDOS no 1ø século atrasado, os 
americanos debateram como o governo deve responder às épocas duras 
-- uma pergunta ainda não respondida hoje. Os fabricantes -- 
então como agora -- fizeram exame geralmente da posição que o 
governo não deve interferir com os funcionamentos "do mercado livre."
Quando J. H. Walker, um fabricante da sapata de Worcester, 
Massachusetts, testified em 1878 antes que um comitê congressional 
que investiga "as causas do depression geral no trabalho e no 
negócio," ele discutir simplesmente que o governo deve não fazer 
nada em tudo para o exército vasto dos desempregados. "deixe-os
sozinhos; aquele é o remédio, "declarou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con la depressione che appare in lontananza come 
minaccia continua all'economia degli STATI UNITI verso la fine del 
diciannovesimo secolo, gli Americani hanno dibattuto come il governo 
dovrebbe rispondere ancora ai periodi duri -- una domanda senza 
risposta oggi. I fornitori -- allora come ora -- hanno preso 
solitamente la posizione che il governo non dovrebbe interferire con i
funzionamenti "del mercato libero." Quando J. H. Walker, un 
fornitore del pattino da Worcester, Massachusetts, testimoniato in 
1878 prima che un comitato congressuale che studia "le cause della 
depressione generale nel lavoro e nel commercio," lui sostenga 
semplicemente che il governo dovrebbe non fare niente affatto per 
l'esercito ampio dei disoccupati. "lascilo sole; quello è
il rimedio, "ha dichiarato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την κατάθλιψη που εμφανίζεται ως συνεχής απειλή 
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ οικονομία προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, 
Αμερικανοί συζήτησαν πώς η κυβέρνηση πρέπει να αποκριθεί στους 
σκληρούς χρόνους -- μια ερώτηση ακόμα αναπάντητη σήμερα. 
Οι κατασκευαστές -- έπειτα όπως τώρα -- συνήθως 
υποστήριξαν τη θέση ότι η κυβέρνηση δεν πρέπει να παρεμποδίσει 
τα έργα της "ελεύθερης αγοράς." Όταν Θ*ι. Χ. Walker, 
ένας κατασκευαστής παπουτσιών από το Worcester, Μασαχουσέτη, 
πιστοποίησε το 1878 ενώπιον μιας του Κογκρέσου επιτροπής 
ερευνών "τις αιτίες της γενικής κατάθλιψης στην εργασία και την 
επιχείρηση," υποστήριξε απλά ότι η κυβέρνηση δεν πρέπει να 
κάνει τίποτα καθόλου όλες για τον απέραντο στρατό των ανέργων. 
"Τους αφήστε μόνο  αυτή είναι η θεραπεία, "δήλωσε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la depresión asomando como amenaza continua a
la economía de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la a fines del siglo XIX, los 
americanos discutieron cómo el gobierno debe todavía responder a las
épocas duras -- una pregunta por contestar hoy. Los fabricantes
-- entonces como ahora -- tomaron generalmente la posición que el 
gobierno no debe interferir con los funcionamientos del "mercado 
libre." Cuando J. H. Walker, fabricante del zapato de Worcester,
Massachusetts, atestiguado en 1878 antes de que un comité del 
congreso que investigaba "las causas de la depresión general en 
trabajo y negocio," él discutiera simplemente que el gobierno hiciera
nada en todos para el ejército extenso de parados. "déjelos 
sola; ése es el remedio, "él declaró.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086403</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108173</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/leave-them-alone-that-is-the-remedy-a-manufacturers-solution-to-the-depression</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
