<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105958</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105958</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086481</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"More Important Than Gold": FDR's First Fireside Chat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wichtiger Als Gold": Kamin-Schwätzchen FDR 
Ersten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Plus important Que l'Or" : Causerie du Coin 
du feu de FDR Premier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Mais importante Do que O Ouro": Bate-papo Do
Fireside Do FDR Primeiro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Più importante Dell'Oro": Chiacchierata Del
Focolare Del FDR Primo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σημαντικότερος από χρυσόσ": Συνομιλία εστιών 
FDR πρώτη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Más importante Que El Oro": Charla Del 
Hogar Del FDR Primer</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When President Franklin D. Roosevelt took office in 1933, one in four Americans was out of work nationally, but in some cities and some industries unemployment was well over 50 percent. Equally troubling were the bank panics. Between 1929 and 1931, 4,000 banks closed for good; by 1933 the number rose to more than 9,000, with $2.5 billion in lost deposits. Banks never have as much in their vaults as people have deposited, and if all depositors claim their money at once, the bank is ruined. Millions of Americans lost their money because they arrived at the bank too late to withdraw their savings. The panics raised troubling questions about credit, value, and the nature of capitalism itself. And they made clear the unpredictable relationship between public perception and general financial health--the extent to which the economy seemed to work as long as everyone believed that it would. To stop the run on banks, many states simply closed their banks the day before Roosevelt's inauguration. Roosevelt himself declared a four-day "bank holiday" almost immediately upon taking office and made a national radio address on Sunday, March 12, 1933, to explain the banking problem. This excerpt from Roosevelt's first "fireside chat" demonstrated the new president's remarkable capacity to project his personal warmth and charm into the nation's living rooms.   Audio is an excerpt of the full address.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als Präsident Franklin D. Roosevelt Amt 1933 
übernahm, war eins auf vier Amerikaner aus Arbeit heraus national, 
aber in einigen Städte und in etwas Industrien war Arbeitslosigkeit 
gut über 50 Prozent. Gleichmäßig bemühten die Bank in Panik 
versetzt. Zwischen 1929 und 1931 schlossen 4.000 Bänke für 
gutes; um 1933 erhöhte sich die Zahl bis mehr als 9.000, mit 
$2.5 Milliarde in verlorenen Ablagerungen. Bänke haben nie so 
viel in ihren Wölbungen, wie Leute niedergelegt haben, und wenn alle 
Galvaniseure ihr Geld sofort behaupten, wird die Bank ruiniert. 
Millionen Amerikaner verloren ihr Geld, weil sie in der Bank zu 
spät ankamen, um ihre Sparungen zu entnehmen. Versetzt 
angehoben in Panik, Fragen über Gutschrift, Wert und die Natur von 
Kapitalismus selbst bemühend. Und sie bildeten klar das 
unvorhersehbare Verhältnis zwischen allgemeiner Vorstellung und 
allgemeiner finanzieller Gesundheit -- den Umfang, in dem die 
Wirtschaft schien, so lang zu arbeiten, wie jeder glaubte, daß es 
wurde. Um den Durchlauf auf Bänken zu stoppen, schlossen viele 
Zustände einfach ihre Bänke der Tag vor Einweihung Roosevelts. 
Roosevelt selbst erklärte einen viertätigen "Bankfeiertag" 
fast sofort nach dem Übernehmen des Amts und ließ eine nationale 
Rundfunkansprache am Sonntag, März 12, 1933, das Bankverkehr Problem 
erklären. Dieses Excerpt Roosevelts ersten "vom 
Kaminschwätzchen" zeigte die neuen bemerkenswerte Kapazität des 
Präsidenten, seine persönliche Wärme und Charme in die lebenden 
Räume der Nation zu projizieren. Audio ist ein Excerpt der 
vollen Adresse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand le Président Franklin D. Roosevelt a pris 
le bureau en 1933, un dans quatre Américains était sans emploi 
nationalement, mais dans quelques villes et quelques industries le 
chômage était bien plus de 50 pour cent. Préoccupaient 
également la banque panique. Entre 1929 et 1931, 4.000 banques 
se sont fermées pour de bon ; par 1933 le nombre a monté plus 
de à 9.000, avec $2.5 milliards dans les dépôts perdus. Les 
banques n'ont jamais autant dans leurs chambres fortes que les gens 
ont déposé, et si tous les déposants demandent leur argent 
immédiatement, la banque est ruinée. Les millions 
d'Américains ont détruit leur argent parce qu'ils sont arrivés à 
la banque trop tard pour retirer leur épargne. Panique 
augmenté préoccupant des questions au sujet de degré de solvabilité, de 
valeur, et de la nature du capitalisme elle-même. Et ils ont 
fait clairement le rapport imprévisible entre la perception publique 
et la santé financière générale -- le point auquel l'économie a 
semblé fonctionner aussi longtemps que chacun a cru qu'il . 
Pour arrêter le passage sur des banques, beaucoup d'états 
simplement ont fermé leurs banques le jour avant l'inauguration de 
Roosevelt. Roosevelt lui-même a déclaré des "vacances de 
banque" de quatre jours presque immédiatement en prenant le bureau et
a fait un discours par radio national dimanche, 12 mars 1933, pour 
expliquer le problème d'opérations bancaires. Cet extrait de 
la "causerie du coin du feu" de Roosevelt premier a démontré du 
nouveau la capacité remarquable président de projeter sa chaleur et 
charme personnels dans les salles vivantes de la nation. 
L'acoustique est un extrait de la pleine adresse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando o presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt fêz 
exame do escritório em 1933, um em quatro americanos estava fora do 
trabalho nacionalmente, mas em algumas cidades e em algumas 
indústrias o desemprego estava bem sobre 50 por cento. Estava 
incomodando ingualmente o banco apavora-se. Entre 1929 e 1931, 
4.000 bancos fecharam-se para o bom; por 1933 o número 
levantou-se mais a de 9.000, com os $2.5 bilhões em depósitos 
perdidos. Os bancos nunca têm tanto quanto em seus vaults como 
os povos depositaram, e se todos os depositantes reivindicarem seu 
dinheiro em uma vez, o banco é arruinado. Os milhões dos 
americanos perderam seu dinheiro porque chegaram no banco demasiado 
tarde para retirar suas economias. Apavora-se levantado 
incomodando perguntas sobre o crédito, o valor, e a natureza do 
capitalismo própria. E fizeram claramente o relacionamento 
impredizível entre a percepção pública e a saúde financeira geral
-- a extensão a que a economia pareceu trabalhar tão por muito tempo
como todos acreditou que . Para parar o funcionamento em bancos,
muitos estados fecharam simplesmente seus bancos o dia antes do 
inauguration de Roosevelt. Roosevelt ele mesmo declarou de "um 
feriado banco four-day" quase imediatamente em cima de fazer exame do 
escritório e fêz um endereço de rádio nacional em domingo, março 
12, 1933, para explicar o problema da operação bancária. Este
excerpt do "do bate-papo fireside" de Roosevelt primeiro demonstrou a 
capacidade notável do presidente novo projetar seus calor e encanto 
pessoais nos quartos vivos da nação. O áudio é um excerpt do
endereço cheio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando il presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt ha 
preso l'ufficio in 1933, uno in quattro Americani era senza lavoro 
nazionalmente, ma in alcune città ed in alcune industrie 
disoccupazione era bene oltre 50 per cento. Stava disturbandosi 
ugualmente la banca si lascia prendere dal panico. Fra 
1929 e 1931, 4.000 banche chiuse per la merce; di 1933 
il numero è aumentato più di a 9.000, con $2.5 miliardo nei depositi
persi. La banca non ha mai tanto nelle loro volte come la 
gente ha depositato e se tutti i depositanti reclamano i loro soldi 
immediatamente, la banca è rovinata. Milioni di Americani
hanno perso i loro soldi perché sono arrivato troppo in ritardo alla 
banca per ritirare il loro risparmio. Si lascia prendere 
dal panico alzato disturbandosi le domande circa accreditamento, 
valore e la natura del capitalismo in se. Ed hanno fatto 
chiaramente il rapporto imprevedibile fra la percezione pubblica e la 
salute finanziaria generale -- il limite a cui l'economia ha sembrato 
funzionare finchè tutta ha creduto che. Per arrestare il 
funzionamento sulla banca, molti dichiarano semplicemente 
chiuso la loro banca il giorno prima dell'inaugurazione del 
Roosevelt. Roosevelt egli stesso ha dichiarato "una festa della 
banca" di quattro giorni quasi immediatamente sulla presa 
dell'ufficio ed ha fatto un indirizzo radiofonico nazionale la 
domenica, 12 marzo 1933, per spiegare il problema di operazioni 
bancarie. Questo brano "da chiacchierata del focolare" del 
Roosevelt primo ha dimostrato la capacità notevole del nuovo 
presidente di proiettare il suoi calore e fascino personali nelle 
stanze viventi della nazione. L'audio è un brano dell'indirizzo
completo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν ο Πρόεδρος Franklin D. Roosevelt πήρε το 
γραφείο το 1933, το ένα σε τέσσερις Αμερικανούς ήταν άνεργο 
εθνικά, αλλά σε μερικές πόλεις και μερικές βιομηχανίες η 
ανεργία ήταν καλά πάνω από 50 τοις εκατό. Εξίσου 
ενοχλώντας ήταν το panics τραπεζών. Μεταξύ 1929 και 
1931, 4.000 τράπεζες έκλεισαν για καλό  μέχρι το 
1933 ο αριθμός ανήλθε σε περισσότερο από 9.000, με $2,5 
δισεκατομμύρια στις χαμένες καταθέσεις. Οι τράπεζες δεν 
έχουν ποτέ τόσο στους υπόγειους θαλάμους τους όσο και οι 
άνθρωποι έχουν καταθέσει, και εάν όλοι οι καταθέτες απαιτούν τα
χρήματά τους αμέσως, η τράπεζα είναι. Τα εκατομμύρια 
Αμερικανών έχασαν τα χρήματά τους επειδή έφθασαν στην τράπεζα 
πάρα πολύ αργά για να αποσύρουν την αποταμίευσή τους. Το 
panics δημιούργησε τα ενοχλώντας ερωτήματα για την πίστωση, την
αξία, και τη φύση της κεφαλαιοκρατίας η ίδια. Και 
κατέστησαν σαφή την απρόβλεπτη σχέση μεταξύ της δημόσιας 
αντίληψης και της γενικής οικονομικής υγείας -- ο βαθμός στον 
οποίο η οικονομία φάνηκε να λειτουργεί εφ' όσον εθεώρησε ο 
καθένας ότι. Για να σταματήσουν το τρέξιμο στις τράπεζες, 
πολλά κράτη έκλεισαν απλά τις τράπεζές τους η ημέρα πριν από 
την εγκαινίαση Roosevelt. Το Roosevelt ο ίδιος δήλωσε 
τεσσάρων ημερών "διακοπές τραπεζών" σχεδόν αμέσως επάνω στη 
λήψη του γραφείου και έκανε μια εθνική ραδιο διεύθυνση την 
Κυριακή, 12 Μαρτίου ..1933, για να εξηγήσει το τραπεζικό 
πρόβλημα. Αυτό το απόσπασμα από "συνομιλία εστιών" 
Roosevelt την πρώτη κατέδειξε την αξιοπρόσεκτη ικανότητα του 
νέου Προέδρου να προβάλει την προσωπικές ζεστασιά και τη γοητεία
του στα καθιστικά του έθνους. Ο ήχος είναι ένα απόσπασμα 
της πλήρους διεύθυνσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt tomó la 
oficina en 1933, una en cuatro americanos estaba sin trabajo 
nacionalmente, pero en algunas ciudades y algunas industrias el 
desempleo estaba bien sobre 50 por ciento. Preocupaba igualmente
la batería se atierra. Entre 1929 y 1931, 4.000 baterías se 
cerraron para el bueno; por 1933 el número se levantó más a 
de 9.000, con $2.5 mil millones en depósitos perdidos. Las 
baterías nunca tienen tanto en sus cámaras acorazadas como la gente 
ha depositado, y si todos los depositantes demandan su dinero 
inmediatamente, la batería está arruinada. Millones de 
americanos perdieron su dinero porque llegaron la batería demasiado 
tarde para retirar sus ahorros. Se atierra levantado preocupando
preguntas sobre crédito, valor, y la naturaleza del capitalismo sí 
mismo. E hicieron claramente el lazo imprevisible entre la 
opinión pública y la salud financiera general -- el fragmento a el 
cual la economía se parecía trabajar mientras cada una creyó que . 
Para parar el funcionamiento en las baterías, muchos estados 
cerraron simplemente sus baterías el día antes de la inauguración 
de Roosevelt. Roosevelt mismo declaró un "día de fiesta de 
batería de cuatro días" casi inmediatamente sobre tomar la oficina e
hizo un direccionamiento de radio nacional el domingo, de marcha la 12
de 1933, para explicar el problema de las actividades bancarias. 
Este extracto de la "charla del hogar" de Roosevelt primer 
demostró la capacidad notable del nuevo presidente de proyectar su 
calor y encanto personales en los cuartos vivos de la nación. 
El audio es un extracto del direccionamiento completo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086481</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105958</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/more-important-than-gold-fdrs-first-fireside-chat</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
