<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086252</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">How A Battle Is Sketched</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wie Eine Schlacht Skizziert Wird</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comment Une Bataille Est esquissée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como Uma Batalha É esboçada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come Una Battaglia È abbozzata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πώς μια μάχη σκιαγραφείται</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cómo Se bosqueja Una Batalla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this article, written 24 years after the war for the children's magazine  St. Nicholas , former  Harper's Weekly  sketch-artist Theodore R. Davis recollects the hazardous and inventive ways that pictorial journalists reported the Civil War. While photography was still in its infancy--unable yet to capture action or to be cheaply reproduced in periodicals or books--artists' battlefront sketches were the public's primary source of visual news of the war's people, places and events. Davis, who was 21 at the start of the war, was typical of this new type of reporter, recording direct observations or collected stories in rough sketches and notes that were dispatched to newspaper offices in New York where they were made into wood engravings and printed as illustrations in publications such as  Harper's Weekly ,  Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper , and the  New York Illustrated News  (the South had no comparable pictorial news resource).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Artikel 24 Jahre nach dem Krieg für Str.
Nicholas geschrieben Zeitschrift der Kinder, ehemaligen Harpers 
bedenkt wöchentlicher Skizze-Künstler Theodore R. Davis die 
gefährlichen und erfinderischen Methoden, daß bildhafte Journalisten
über den Bürgerkrieg berichteten. Während Fotographie noch in
seiner Kindheit war -- nicht imstande dennoch Tätigkeit erfassen oder
in den Zeitschriften oder in den Büchern billig reproduziert werden 
-- Skizzen battlefront der Künstler waren die Primärquelle der 
Öffentlichkeit der Sichtnachrichten der Leute des Krieges, Plätze 
und Fälle. Davis, das 21 beim Anfang des Krieges war, war von 
diesem neuen Typen der unmittelbarer Beobachtungen des Reporters, des 
Speicherns oder der gesammelten Geschichten in den rauhen Skizzen und 
der Anmerkungen, die zu den Zeitung Büros in New York geschickt 
wurden, in denen sie in hölzerne Stiche gebildet wurden und druckten,
während Abbildungen in den Publikationen wie Harpers wöchentlichen, 
aufrichtigen Leslies erläuterter Zeitung und dem New York Nachrichten
veranschaulichten (der Süden hatte kein vergleichbares bildhaftes 
Nachrichten Hilfsmittel) typisch.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En cet article, écrit 24 ans après la guerre pour
la rue Nicholas du magazine des enfants, le croquis-artiste 
hebdomadaire Theodore R. Davis d'ancien Harper rappelle les voies 
dangereuses et inventives que les journalistes imagés ont enregistré
la guerre civile. Tandis que la photographie était toujours 
dans sa petite enfance -- incapable pourtant pour capturer l'action ou
être à bon marché reproduit en périodiques ou livres -- les 
croquis du battlefront des artistes étaient la source primaire du 
public de nouvelles visuelles des personnes de la guerre, des endroits
et des événements. Davis, qui était 21 au début de la 
guerre, était typique de ce nouveau type des observations directes de
journaliste, d'enregistrement ou des histoires rassemblées dans des 
croquis approximatifs et de notes qui ont été acheminées aux 
bureaux de journal à New York où ils ont été transformés en les 
gravures du bois et ont imprimé pendant que les illustrations en 
publications telles que le journal illustré de Leslie hebdomadaire et
franc de Harper, et New York illustraient des nouvelles (les 
Sud n'a eu aucune ressource imagée comparable de nouvelles).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste artigo, escrito 24 anos após a guerra para 
St. Nicholas do compartimento das crianças, o esboço-artista semanal
Theodore R. Davis de Harper anterior recorda as maneiras perigosas e 
inventive que os journalists pictorial relataram a guerra civil. 
Quando a fotografia estava ainda em seu infancy -- incapaz 
contudo para capturar a ação ou para ser reproduzido barata nos 
periodicals ou nos livros -- os esboços do battlefront dos artistas 
eram a fonte preliminar do público da notícia visual dos povos da 
guerra, lugares e eventos. Davis, que era 21 no início da 
guerra, era típico deste tipo novo de observações diretas do 
repórter, da gravação ou de histórias coletadas em esboços 
ásperos e de notas que foram despachadas aos escritórios do jornal 
em New York onde foram feitos nos engravings de madeira e imprimiram 
enquanto as ilustrações nas publicações tais como o jornal 
ilustrado de Leslie semanal, frank de Harper, e a New York ilustraram 
a notícia (o sul não teve nenhum recurso pictorial comparável da 
notícia).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo articolo, scritto 24 anni dopo la guerra 
per la st Nicholas dello scomparto dei bambini, l'abbozzo-artista 
settimanale Theodore R. Davis del Harper precedente ricorda i modi 
pericolosi ed inventivi che i giornalisti pittorici hanno segnalato la
guerra civile. Mentre la fotographia era ancora nella relativa 
infanzia -- incapace tuttavia bloccare azione o essere riprodotto 
economicamente in periodici o libri -- gli abbozzi del battlefront 
degli artisti erano la sorgente primaria del pubblico delle notizie 
visive della gente della guerra, posti ed eventi. Davis, che era
21 all'inizio della guerra, era tipico di questo nuovo tipo di 
osservazioni dirette di registrazione, del reporter o di storia 
raccolte negli abbozzi approssimativi e di note che sono state spedite
agli uffici del giornale a New York in cui sono stati trasformati le 
incisioni del legno ed hanno stampato mentre le illustrazioni in 
pubblicazioni quali il giornale illustrato del Leslie settimanale e 
franco del Harper e New York hanno illustrato le notizie (il sud non 
ha disposto di mezzo pittorico paragonabile di notizie).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το άρθρο, που γράφεται 24 έτη μετά από 
τον πόλεμο για το περιοδικό ST Nicholas των παιδιών, ο 
εβδομαδιαίος σκίτσο-καλλιτέχνης Theodore Ρ. Νταίηβις 
προηγούμενου Harper ανακαλεί τους επικίνδυνους και εφευρετικούς
τρόπους ότι οι εικονογραφικοί δημοσιογράφοι εξέθεσαν τον εμφύλιο
πόλεμο. Ενώ η φωτογραφία ήταν ακόμα στα σπάργανα -- 
ανίκανη ακόμα να συλλάβει την ενέργεια ή να αναπαραχθεί φτηνά 
στα περιοδικά ή κρατά -- των καλλιτεχνών battlefront τα σκίτσα
ήταν η αρχική πηγή του κοινού οπτικών ειδήσεων των πολεμικών 
ανθρώπων, των θέσεων και των γεγονότων. Ο Νταίηβις, που 
ήταν 21 στην έναρξη του πολέμου, ήταν χαρακτηριστικός αυτού 
του νέου τύπου δημοσιογράφου, άμεσες παρατηρήσεις καταγραφής ή 
συνέλεξε τις ιστορίες στα τραχιές σκίτσα και τις σημειώσεις που 
αποστάλησαν στα γραφεία εφημερίδων στη Νέα Υόρκη όπου έγιναν 
στις ξύλινες χαράξεις και τύπωσαν ως απεικονίσεις στις 
δημοσιεύσεις όπως η εβδομαδιαία έκδοση Harper, η 
διευκρινισμένη εφημερίδα του Frank Leslie's, και οι 
διευκρινισμένες η Νέα Υόρκη ειδήσεις (ο νότος δεν είχε κανένα 
συγκρίσιμο εικονογραφικό στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς ειδήσεων).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este artículo, escrito 24 años después de la 
guerra para St. Nicholas del compartimiento de los niños, el 
bosquejo-artista semanal Theodore R. Davis de Harper anterior recuerda
las maneras peligrosas e inventivas que los periodistas ilustrados 
señalaron la guerra civil. Mientras que la fotografía todavía
estaba en su infancia -- incapaz con todo capturar la acción o ser 
reproducido barato en periódicos o libros -- los bosquejos del 
battlefront de los artistas eran la fuente primaria del público de 
las noticias visuales de la gente de la guerra, lugares y 
acontecimientos. Davis, que era 21 en el comienzo de la guerra, 
era típico de este nuevo tipo de observaciones directas del 
reportero, de la registración o de historias recogidas en bosquejos 
ásperos y de notas que fueron enviadas a las oficinas del periódico 
en Nueva York en donde fueron hechos en los grabados de madera e 
imprimieron mientras que las ilustraciones en publicaciones tales como
periódico ilustrado de Leslie semanal, franco de Harper, y la Nueva 
York ilustraron noticias (el sur no tenía ningún recurso ilustrado 
comparable de las noticias).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086252</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105335</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/how-a-battle-is-sketched</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
