<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108338</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108338</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Why Topography?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Warum Topographie?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pourquoi Topographie ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Por que Topography?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Perchè Topografia?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γιατί τοπογραφία;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Por qué Topografía?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Part of the supporting resources for the School of Earth Sciences dynamic earth module, the -Why Topography?- site discusses two models introduced in the 19th century that are still used to explain topographic variations. These models are the Pratt and Airy models of isostasy. In the Pratt model, high topography (relative to surroundings) is due to lower density whereas in the Airy model, high topography is due to thick crust.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Teil der unterstützenden Betriebsmittel für die Schule 
des dynamischen Moduls Masse der Geowissenschaften, - warum 
Topographie? - Site behandelt zwei Modelle, die im 19. 
Jahrhundert eingeführt werden, die noch benutzt werden, um 
topographische Varianten zu erklären. Diese Modelle sind das 
Pratt und die Airy Modelle der Isostasie. Im Pratt Modell liegt 
hohe Topographie (im Verhältnis zu Umlagerungen) an der niedrigeren 
Dichte, während in der Airy vorbildlichen, hohen Topographie an der 
starken Kruste liegt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une partie des ressources supportantes pour l'école du 
module dynamique de la terre de sciences de la terre, - pourquoi 
topographie ? - le site discute deux modèles présentés au 
19ème siècle qui sont encore employés pour expliquer des variations
topographiques. Ces modèles sont le Pratt et les modèles bien 
aérés de l'isostasie. Dans le modèle de Pratt, la topographie
élevée (relativement aux environnements) est due à un plus faible 
densité tandis qu'en topographie modèle et élevée bien aérée est
dû à la croûte épaisse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Parte dos recursos suportando para a escola do módulo 
dinâmico da terra das ciências de terra, - porque topography? - 
o local discute dois modelos introduzidos no 1ø século que 
são usados ainda explicar variações topographic. Estes 
modelos são o Pratt e os modelos airy do isostasy. No modelo de
Pratt, o topography elevado (relativo aos arredors) é  devido a uma 
densidade mais baixa visto que no topography modelo, elevado airy é  
devido à crosta grossa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parte delle risorse di sostegno per la scuola del modulo 
dinamico della terra di scienze della terra, - perchè topografia? - 
il luogo discute due modelli introdotti nel diciannovesimo 
secolo che ancora sono usati per spiegare le variazioni topografiche. 
Questi modelli sono il Pratt ed i modelli airy di isostasy. 
Nel modello di Pratt, l'alta topografia (riguardante i dintorni)
è dovuto densità più bassa mentre in topografia di modello e alta 
airy è dovuto la crosta spessa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέρος των ενισχυτικών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς για το 
σχολείο της δυναμικής γήινης ενότητας γήινων επιστημών, - γιατί
τοπογραφία; - η περιοχή συζητά δύο μοντέλα που εισάγονται 
στο 19$ο αιώνα που χρησιμοποιούνται ακόμα για να εξηγήσουν τις 
τοπογραφικές παραλλαγές. Αυτά τα μοντέλα είναι το Pratt 
και τα αερώδη μοντέλα isostasy. Στο μοντέλο Pratt, η 
υψηλή τοπογραφία (σχετικά με τα περίχωρα) οφείλεται στη 
χαμηλότερη πυκνότητα ενώ αερώδη στον πρότυπο, η υψηλή 
τοπογραφία οφείλεται στην παχιά κρούστα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Parte de los recursos que utilizan para la escuela del 
módulo dinámico de la tierra de las geologías, - porqué 
topografía? - el sitio discute dos modelos introducidos en el 
diecinueveavo siglo que todavía se utilicen para explicar variaciones
topográficas. Estos modelos son el Pratt y los modelos airy del
isostasy. En el modelo de Pratt, la alta topografía 
(concerniente a alrededores) es debido a una densidad más baja 
mientras que en la topografía modelo, alta airy es debido a la 
corteza gruesa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROB BUTLER
FN:ROB BUTLER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CLARE GORDON
FN:CLARE GORDON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108338</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/why-topography</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
