<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106056</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106056</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206788</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">New Deal Network, Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt Institute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neues Abkommen-Netz, Franklin und Eleanor 
Roosevelt Institut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Réseau de nouvelle affaire, Franklin et institut 
d'Eleanor Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rede do negócio novo, Franklin e instituto de 
Eleanor Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rete di nuovo affare, Franklin ed istituto di 
Eleanor Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νέα δίκτυο διαπραγμάτευσης, Franklin και ίδρυμα 
Eleanor Roosevelt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Red del nuevo reparto, Franklin e instituto de 
Eleanor Roosevelt</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides research and teaching resources devoted to the public works and arts projects of the New Deal, including information on how the Great Depression affected children, and workers programs for women that made dolls to be sold for children in nurseries, schools, and hospitals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Forschung und Unterrichtendie 
betriebsmittel zur Verfügung, die den Arbeiten und den kunstprojekten
des neuen Abkommens, einschließlich Informationen gewidmet werden 
auf, wie der große Tiefstand Kinder beeinflußte, und 
Arbeiterprogramme für Frauen, die die für bildeten Kinder in den 
Baumschulen, in den Schulen und in den Krankenhäusern verkauft zu 
werden Puppen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des ressources de recherches et 
d'enseignement consacrées aux travaux publics et aux projets d'arts 
de la nouvelle affaire, y compris l'information sur la façon dont la 
grande dépression a affecté des enfants, et des programmes 
d'ouvriers pour les femmes qui ont fait des poupées à vendre pour 
des enfants dans les pépinières, les écoles, et les hôpitaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece os recursos da pesquisa e ensinar 
devotados aos trabalhos públicos e aos projetos das artes do negócio
novo, including a informação em como o depression grande afetou 
crianças, e os programas dos trabalhadores para as mulheres que 
fizeram as bonecas a ser vendidas para crianças nos berçários, nas 
escolas, e nos hospitais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le risorse di istruzione e di ricerca 
dedicate ai lavori pubblici ed ai progetti di arti di nuovo affare, 
compreso le informazioni su come la depressione grande ha interessato 
i bambini ed i programmi degli operai per le donne che hanno fatto le 
bambole da vendere per i bambini in scuole materne, in scuole ed in 
ospedali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς έρευνας και 
διδασκαλίας που αφιερώνονται στα δημόσια έργα και τα έργα τεχνών
της νέας διαπραγμάτευσης, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των πληροφοριών για 
τον τρόπο με τον οποίο η μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση είχε 
επιπτώσεις στα παιδιά, και των προγραμμάτων εργαζομένων για τις 
γυναίκες που έκαναν τις κούκλες που πωλούνται για τα παιδιά στους
βρεφικούς σταθμούς, τα σχολεία, και τα νοσοκομεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a los recursos de la investigación y 
de la enseñanza dedicados a los trabajos públicos y a los proyectos 
de los artes del nuevo reparto, incluyendo la información en cómo la
gran depresión afectó a niños, y programas de los trabajadores para
las mujeres que hicieron las muñecas que se venderán para los niños
en cuartos de niños, escuelas, y hospitales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206788</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106056</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/new-deal-network-franklin-and-eleanor-roosevelt-institute</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
