<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108550</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108550</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hard Times</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Harte Zeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Périodes Difficiles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Épocas Duras</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Periodi Duri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκληροί χρόνοι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Épocas Duras</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The US stock market crash of 1929 set off the most severe economic depression in the Western world. The so-called Great Depression lasted more than a decade, until approximately 1941. In the United States, the general atmosphere was one of desolation, as expressed in the Dorothea Lange photograph "Thirteen Million Unemployed Fill the City in the Early Thirties," which shows men leaning against a wall in San Francisco. Many photographs in this topic were taken by Lange, one of the primary chroniclers of the Great Depression. Lange had been taking portraits of wealthy individuals in her studio, but she felt compelled to go out on the streets and take photographs of everyday people. In 1933, she marked the start of her documentary career what she called her "first street image": "White Angel Bread Line," a photograph of a man waiting for food at a soup kitchen run by a San Francisco widow. The images in this group reflect the lives of average citizens struggling to get by. Photographs show unemployed men waiting in long lines. One Lange photo shows a man sleeping in a parking lot. Rural areas were also hard hit. As several of these images show, some people lived in "Hoovervilles" ? temporary towns of makeshift housing that got their name from President Herbert Hoover, who was blamed for the problems that led to the Depression. The image captions written at the time (such as "Not much room in this one room shack, but it?s shelter from a trying winter" and "These Hooverville children are ashamed of their home ? can you blame them?") express the conditions that people endured and reveal the way people felt.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der US Börsesystemabsturz von Set 1929 weg 
von der strengsten Wirtschaftskrise in der westlichen Welt. Der 
sogenannte große Tiefstand dauerte mehr als eine Dekade, bis 
ungefähr 1941. In den Vereinigten Staaten war die allgemeine 
Atmosphäre eine von Verwüstung, wie in der Dorothea Lange 
Fotographie "dreizehn Million Arbeitslos-Fülle ausgedrückt die Stadt
in den frühen dreißiger Jahren,", die die Männer zeigt, die an 
einer Wand in San Francisco sich lehnen. Viele Fotographien in 
diesem Thema wurden von Lange, einer der Primärchronisten des großen
Tiefstands genommen. Lange hatte Portraits der wohlhabenden 
Einzelpersonen in ihrem Studio genommen, aber sie glaubte gezwungen, 
um auf die Straßen zu erlöschen und Fotographien der täglichen 
Leute zu nehmen. 1933 kennzeichnete sie den Anfang ihrer 
dokumentarischen Karriere, was sie ihr "erstes Straße Bild" nannte: 
"weiße Engel Brot-Zeile," eine Fotographie einer 
Mannwartenahrung an einer Suppeküche laufen durch eine San Francisco 
Witwe. Die Bilder in dieser Gruppe reflektieren die Leben der 
durchschnittlichen Bürger, die kämpfen, um Fotographien Erscheinen 
die arbeitslosen Männer vorbei zu erhalten, die in lange Zeilen 
warten. Ein Lange Foto zeigt einen Mann, der in einem Parkenlot 
schläft. Ländliche Gebiete waren auch fest getroffen. 
Als mehrere dieser Bilder stellen Sie, einige Leute wohnte in 
"Hoovervilles" dar? temporäre Städte des behelfsmäßigen 
Gehäuses, die ihren Namen vom Präsidenten Herbert Hoover erhielten, 
der für die Probleme das getadelt wurde, führten zu den Tiefstand. 
Die Bilduntertitelen zu der Zeit geschrieben (wie "nicht viel 
Raum in diesem ein Raum shack, aber it?s Schutz von einem versuchenden
Winter" und "diese Hooverville Kinder seien Sie über ihr Haus 
beschämt? können Sie sie tadeln?") drücken Sie die 
Bedingungen, die Leute aushielten aus und decken Sie den Methode 
Leutefilz auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La panne totale de marché boursier des USA du 
positionnement 1929 outre de la dépression économique la plus grave 
dans le monde occidental. La prétendue grande dépression a 
duré plus qu'une décennie, jusqu'approximativement à 1941. 
Aux Etats-Unis, l'atmosphère générale était une de 
désolation, comme exprimé en photographie de Dorothea Lange "treize 
millions de remplissage de chômeurs la ville dans les années '30 
tôt," qui montre des hommes se penchant contre un mur dans San 
Francisco. Beaucoup de photographies dans ce sujet ont été 
prises par Lange, un des chroniqueurs primaires de la grande 
dépression. Lange avait pris des verticales des individus 
riches dans son studio, mais elle s'est sentie compulsive pour sortir 
sur les rues et pour prendre des photographies des personnes 
journalières. En 1933, elle a marqué le début de sa carrière
documentaire ce qu'elle a appelé sa "première image de rue" : 
"la ligne blanche de pain d'ange," une photographie d'un aliment
d'attente d'homme à une cuisine de potage fonctionnent par une veuve 
de San Francisco. Les images dans ce groupe reflètent les 
vies des citoyens moyens luttant pour passer à exposition de 
photographies les hommes sans emploi attendant dans de longues lignes.
Une photo de Lange montre un homme dormant dans un sort de 
stationnement. Les zones rurales étaient également gravement 
atteintes. En tant que plusieurs de ces images montrez, certains
a habité dans "Hoovervilles" ? les villes provisoires du 
logement expédient qui ont obtenu leur nom du Président Herbert 
Hoover, qui a été blâmé des problèmes cela ont mené à la 
dépression. Les légendes d'image écrites alors (comme "pas 
beaucoup de pièce dans cette cabane d'une pièce, mais comme 
abri d'it?s d'un hiver d'essai" et "ces enfants de Hooverville ayez 
honte de leur maison ? pouvez vous les blâmer ?") 
exprimez les conditions que les gens ont supportées et indiquez
le feutre de personnes de voie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ruído elétrico de mercado conservado em 
estoque dos E. U. do jogo 1929 fora do depression econômico o mais 
severo no mundo ocidental. O depression grande so-called durou 
mais do que uma década, até aproximadamente 1941. Nos estados 
unidos, a atmosfera geral era um do desolation, como expressado na 
fotografia de Dorothea Lange "treze milhão suficiências dos 
desempregados a cidade nos thirties adiantados," que mostra os homens 
que se inclinam de encontro a uma parede em San Francisco. 
Muitas fotografias neste tópico foram feitas exame por Lange, 
um dos chroniclers preliminares do depression grande. Lange tem 
feito exame de retratos de indivíduos ricos em seu estúdio, mas 
sentiu compelida para sair nas ruas e para fazer exame de fotografias 
de povos diários. Em 1933, marcou o começo de sua carreira 
documentary o que chamou sua "primeira imagem da rua": "a linha 
branca do pão do angel," uma fotografia de um alimento de espera do 
homem em uma cozinha da sopa funciona por uma viúva do San Francisco.
As imagens neste grupo refletem as vidas dos cidadãos médios 
que esforçam-se para começar perto a mostra das fotografias os 
homens unemployed que esperam em linhas longas. Uma foto de 
Lange mostra um homem que dorme em um lote do estacionamento. As
áreas rurais eram também batida dura. Como diversas destas 
imagens mostre, alguns povos viveu em "Hoovervilles"? as cidades
provisórias da carcaça temporária que começaram seu nome do 
presidente Herbert Hoover, que foi responsabilizado pelos problemas 
isso conduziram ao depression. Os subtítulos da imagem escritos
naquele tempo (como "não muito quarto neste shack de um quarto, mas 
abrigo dos it?s de um inverno tentando" e "estas crianças de 
Hooverville seja ashamed de sua HOME? pode você 
responsabilizá-los?") expresse as circunstâncias que os povos 
resistiram e revele o feltro dos povos da maneira.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'arresto di mercato azionario degli Stati Uniti 
dell'insieme 1929 fuori della depressione economica più severa nel 
mondo occidentale. La cosiddetta depressione grande ha durato 
più di una decade, fino a circa 1941. In unito 
Dichiara, l'atmosfera generale era uno di desolation, come 
espresso nella fotografia di Dorothea Lange "tredici milione materiali
di riempimento dei disoccupati la città nei thirties in anticipo," 
che mostra gli uomini che si appoggiano contro una parete a San 
Francisco. Molte fotografie in questo soggetto sono state prese 
da Lange, uno dei chroniclers primari della depressione grande. 
Lange stava prendendo i ritratti degli individui ricchi nel 
suo studio, ma ha ritenuto coercitiva per uscire sulle vie e per 
prendere le fotografie della gente giornaliere. In 1933, ha 
contrassegnato l'inizio della sua carriera documentaria che cosa ha 
chiamato la sua "prima immagine della via": "la riga bianca del 
pane di angelo," una fotografia di un alimento attendente dell'uomo ad
una cucina della minestra funziona da una vedova de San Francisco. 
Le immagini in questo gruppo riflettono le vite dei cittadini 
medii che lottano per ottenere vicino ad esposizione delle fotografie 
gli uomini disoccupati che attendono nelle righe lunghe. Una 
foto di Lange mostra un uomo che dorme in un lotto di parcheggio. 
Le zone rurali erano egualmente duramente colpite. Come 
alcune di queste immagini mostri, qualche gente ha vissuto "in 
Hoovervilles"? le città provvisorie di alloggiamento 
improvvisato che hanno ottenuto il loro nome dal presidente Herbert 
Hoover, che è stato incolpato di i problemi quello hanno condotto 
alla depressione. I titoli di immagine scritti allora (quali 
"non molta stanza in questo shack dell'una stanza, ma il riparo dei 
it?s da un inverno provante" e "questi bambini di Hooverville sia 
ashamed della loro sede? potete incolparli di?") esprima 
le circostanze a che la gente ha resistito e riveli il feltro della 
gente di modo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η συντριβή αμερικανικού χρηματιστηρίου του συνόλου του
1929 από την πιό βαριά οικονομική ύφεση στο δυτικό κόσμο. 
Η αποκαλούμενη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση διάρκεσε μια 
περισσότερο από δεκαετία, έως περίπου το 1941. Στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, η γενική ατμόσφαιρα ήταν μιας ατμόσφαιρας 
από θλίψης, όπως εκφράζεται στη φωτογραφία Dorothea Lange 
"που δέκα τρία εκατομμύριο άνεργοι γεμίζουν την πόλη στις αρχές
των δεκαετιών του '30," που εμφανίζει άτομα που κλίνουν ενάντια 
τοίχος στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο. Πολλές φωτογραφίες σε αυτό το 
θέμα λήφθηκαν από Lange, ένας από τους αρχικούς 
χρονικογράφους της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης. Το Lange 
έπαιρνε τα πορτρέτα των πλούσιων ατόμων στο στούντιό της, αλλά 
αισθάνθηκε αναγκασμένη για να βγεί στις οδούς και να ληφθούν οι 
φωτογραφίες των καθημερινών ανθρώπων. Το 1933, 
χαρακτήρισε την έναρξη της αποδεικτικής σταδιοδρομίας της τι 
κάλεσε "πρώτη εικόνα οδών τησ": "Ασπρη γραμμή ψωμιού 
αγγέλου," μια φωτογραφία ενός ατόμου που περιμένει τα τρόφιμα σε
μια κουζίνα σούπας που οργανώνεται από μια χήρα του Σαν 
Φρανσίσκο. Οι εικόνες σε αυτήν την ομάδα απεικονίζουν ότι 
οι ζωές των μέσων πολιτών που αγωνίζονται να πάρουν από τις 
φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν άνεργα άτομα που περιμένουν στις 
μακροχρόνιες γραμμές. Μια φωτογραφία Lange εμφανίζει 
ύπνο ατόμων σε ένα μέρος χώρων στάθμευσης. Οι αγροτικές 
περιοχές επίσης σκληρά χτυπήθηκαν. Όπως αρκετές από 
αυτές τις εικόνες εμφανίστε, μερικοί άνθρωποι έζησαν "σε 
Hoovervilles"; προσωρινές πόλεις της προσωρινής κατοικίας
που πήρε το όνομά τους από τον Πρόεδρο Herbert Hoover, ο 
οποίος κατηγορήθηκε για τα προβλήματα που οδήγησαν στην 
κατάθλιψη. Οι τίτλοι εικόνας που γράφονται στο χρόνο (όπως
"πολύ δωμάτιο σε αυτό η καλύβα δωματίων, αλλά το καταφύγιο 
it?s από έναν χειμώνα προσπάθειασ" και "αυτά τα παιδιά 
Hooverville δεν είναι ντροπιασμένη του σπιτιού τους; 
μπορείτε να τους κατηγορήσετε;") εκφράστε τους όρους 
που οι άνθρωποι που υπομένονται και αποκαλύπτουν τους ανθρώπους 
τρόπων αισθητούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La caída de la bolsa de los E.E.U.U. del 
conjunto 1929 de la depresión económica más severa del mundo 
occidental. La gran depresión supuesta duró más que una 
década, hasta aproximadamente 1941. En los Estados Unidos, la 
atmósfera general era una de desolation, según lo expresado en la 
fotografía de Dorothea Lange "trece millones de terraplenes de los 
parados la ciudad en los años 30 tempranos," que muestra a hombres 
que se inclinan contra una pared en San Francisco. Muchas 
fotografías en este asunto fueron tomadas por Lange, uno de los 
cronistas primarios de la gran depresión. Lange había estado
tomando los retratos de individuos ricos en su estudio, pero ella se 
sentía obligada para salir en las calles y para tomar las 
fotografías de la gente diaria. En 1933, ella marcó el 
comienzo de su carrera documental qué ella llamó su "primera imagen 
de la calle": "la línea blanca del pan del ángel," una 
fotografía de un alimento que espera del hombre para en una cocina de
la sopa se ejecuta por una viuda de San Francisco. Las imágenes
en este grupo reflejan las vidas de los ciudadanos medios que luchan 
para pasar a demostración de las fotografías los hombres parados que
esperan en líneas largas. Una foto de Lange muestra a hombre 
que duerme en una porción del estacionamiento. Las áreas 
rurales eran también golpe duro. ¿Como varias de estas 
imágenes muestre, alguna gente vivió en "Hoovervilles"? las 
ciudades temporales de la cubierta de expediente que consiguieron su 
nombre de presidente Herberto Hoover, que fue culpado por los 
problemas eso condujeron a la depresión. ¿Los encabezamientos 
de la imagen escritos en ese entonces (por ejemplo "no mucho sitio en 
este shack de un sitio, sino abrigo de los it?s a partir de un 
invierno que intenta" y "estos niños de Hooverville esté avergonzado
de su hogar? puede usted culparlos?") exprese las 
condiciones que la gente aguantó y revele el fieltro de la gente de 
la manera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108550</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hard-times</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
