<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103828</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103828</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202555</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Respecting Differences</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Respektieren Von von Unterschieden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Respect des Différences</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Respeitando Diferenças</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rispetto Delle Differenze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σεβασμός των διαφορών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Respetar Diferencias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Guidance/Drama unit offers students the opportunity to identify prejudices and understand how certain character traits such as tolerance, respect, and kindness affect their choice of behavior. Since this lesson addresses sensitive issues, teachers should avoid situations that could be hurtful to individuals or groups. This unit can be adapted to almost any age group or ability level.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Guidance/Drama Maßeinheit bietet 
Kursteilnehmern die Gelegenheit an, Vorurteile zu kennzeichnen und zu 
verstehen, wie bestimmte Zeichenmerkmale wie Toleranz, Respekt und 
Freundlichkeit ihre Wahl des Verhaltens beeinflussen. Da diese 
Lektion heikle Punkte adressiert, sollten Lehrer Situationen 
vermeiden, die zu den Einzelpersonen oder zu den Gruppen hurtful sein 
konnten. Diese Maßeinheit kann fast jeder möglicher 
Altersklasse- oder Fähigkeitsstufe angepaßt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette unité de Guidance/Drama donne à des 
étudiants l'occasion d'identifier des préjudices et de comprendre 
comment certains traits de caractère tels comme tolérance, respect, 
et bonté affectent leur choix du comportement. Puisque cette 
leçon adresse les questions sensibles, les professeurs devraient 
éviter les situations qui pourraient être nuisibles aux individus ou
aux groupes. Cette unité peut être adaptée à presque 
n'importe quel niveau de catégorie d'âge ou de capacités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta unidade de Guidance/Drama oferece a 
estudantes a oportunidade de identificar preconceitos e compreender 
como determinados traços do caráter tais como a tolerância, o 
respeito, e a bondade afetam sua escolha do comportamento. Desde
que esta lição se dirige a edições sensíveis, os professores 
devem evitar as situações que poderiam ser hurtful aos indivíduos 
ou aos grupos. Esta unidade pode ser adaptada a quase todo o 
nível do grupo ou da abilidade de idade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa unità di Guidance/Drama offre ad allievi 
l'opportunità di identificare i pregiudizi e capire come determinate 
caratteristiche del carattere quali tolleranza, rispetto e bontà 
interessano la loro scelta di comportamento. Poiché questa 
lezione richiama le edizioni sensibili, gli insegnanti dovrebbero 
evitare le situazioni che potrebbero essere hurtful agli individui o 
ai gruppi. Questa unità può essere adattata a quasi tutto il 
livello del gruppo d'età o di abilità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η μονάδα καθοδήγησης/δράματος προσφέρει στους 
σπουδαστές την ευκαιρία να προσδιορίσει τις προκαταλήψεις και να 
καταλάβει πώς ορισμένα γνωρίσματα χαρακτήρα όπως η ανοχή, ο 
σεβασμός, και η ευγένεια έχουν επιπτώσεις στην επιλογή 
συμπεριφοράς τους. Δεδομένου ότι αυτό το μάθημα 
αντιμετωπίζει τα ευαίσθητα ζητήματα, οι δάσκαλοι πρέπει να 
αποφύγουν τις καταστάσεις που θα μπορούσαν να είναι hurtful στα
άτομα ή τις ομάδες. Αυτή η μονάδα μπορεί να προσαρμοστεί 
επίπεδο σχεδόν σε οποιοδήποτε ηλικίας ομάδας ή δυνατότητας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta unidad de Guidance/Drama ofrece a estudiantes
la oportunidad de identificar prejudicar y de entender cómo ciertos 
rasgos del carácter tales como tolerancia, respecto, y amabilidad 
afectan su opción del comportamiento. Puesto que esta lección 
trata ediciones sensibles, los profesores deben evitar las situaciones
que podrían ser que hace daño a los individuos o a los grupos. 
Esta unidad se puede adaptar a casi cualquier nivel de la 
categoría o de la capacidad de edad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DARYL WALKER
FN:DARYL WALKER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JUDY PEELE
FN:JUDY PEELE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202555</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103828</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/respecting-differences</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
