<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103532</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103532</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973935</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Blood Typing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Blutgruppenermittlung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Taper de Sang</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Datilografar Do Sangue</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Digitare Di Anima</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Δακτυλογράφηση αίματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: El Pulsar De la 
Sangre</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! In this game you have to blood type each patient and give them a blood transfusion. Are you able to do that? If not, maybe you should read the introduction to blood typing before you start, otherwise you will put the patients' lives in danger!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
In diesem Spiel müssen Sie Bluttyp jeder Patient und ihnen eine
Bluttransfusion zu geben. Können Sie, das zu tun? Wenn 
nicht, möglicherweise sollten Sie die Einleitung zu lesen 
Blutgruppenermittlung, bevor Sie beginnen, andernfalls setzen Sie die 
Lebensdauern der Patienten in Gefahr ein!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Dans ce 
jeu vous devez type de sang chaque patient et leur donner une 
transfusion sanguine. Pouvez-vous faire cela ? Si pas, 
peut-être vous devriez lire l'introduction au sang tapant avant que 
vous commenciez, autrement vous mettrez les vies des patients en 
danger !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Neste 
jogo você tem que tipo do sangue cada paciente e para dar-lhes um 
transfusion de sangue. Pode você  fazer isso? If.not, 
talvez você deve ler a introdução ao sangue que datilografa antes 
que você comece, se não você porá as vidas dos pacientes no 
perigo!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! In questo gioco dovete tipo di
anima ogni paziente e dare loro una trasfusione di sangue. 
Potete fare quello? Se non, forse dovreste leggere 
l'introduzione ad anima che digitate prima che cominci, altrimenti 
metterete le vite dei pazienti nel pericolo!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Σε 
αυτό το παιχνίδι πρέπει τύπος αίματος κάθε ασθενής και να τους 
δώσετε μια μετάγγιση αίματος. Είστε ικανοί να κάνετε 
αυτού; Αν όχι, ίσως πρέπει να διαβάσετε την εισαγωγή στο 
αίμα δακτυλογραφώντας προτού να αρχίσετε, διαφορετικά θα βάλετε 
τις ζωές των ασθενών στον κίνδυνο!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! En este 
juego usted tiene que tipo de la sangre cada paciente y darles una 
transfusión de sangre. ¿Puede usted  hacer eso? ¡Si no, 
usted debe leer quizá la introducción a la sangre que pulsa antes de
que usted comience, si no usted pondrá las vidas de los pacientes en 
peligro!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973935</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103532</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-blood-typing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
