<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105593</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105593</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211600</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Plate Tectonics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Plattentektonik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tectonique de Plat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tectonics De Placa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tettonica Di Piastra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τεκτονική πιάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tectónica De Placa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity from the Discover Our Earth project, students explore the theory of plate tectonics and related phenomena using the interactive mapping and data analysis environment of The Quick Earth Study Tool, QUEST. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität von entdecken erforschen 
unser Masse Projekt, Kursteilnehmer die Theorie der Plattentektonik 
und der in Verbindung stehenden Phänomene mit dem interaktiven 
Diagramm und Datenanalyseumgebung des schnellen Masse Studie 
Hilfsmittels, SUCHE. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können 
Benutzer auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext
für Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité du découvrir notre projet de
la terre, étudiants explorent la théorie de tectonique de plat et de
phénomènes relatifs en utilisant l'environnement interactif 
d'analyse de tracer et de données de l'outil rapide d'étude de la 
terre, RECHERCHE. À cette page de point de départ, les 
utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations sur les buts d'étude 
de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités d'utilisation, 
d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, les idées 
d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade descobrir nosso projeto da terra, 
estudantes explora a teoria do tectonics de placa e de fenômenos 
relacionados usando o ambiente interativo da ferramenta rápida do 
estudo da terra, QUEST da análise traçar e de dados. Nesta 
página do ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação
sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as 
pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias 
da avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività dalla scoperta il nostro 
progetto della terra, allievi esplora la teoria della tettonica di 
piastra e dei fenomeni relativi usando l'ambiente interattivo dello 
strumento rapido di studio della terra, RICERCA di analisi di dati e 
di tracciato. A questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti 
possono accedere alle informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti 
dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di istruzione, di uso note 
e, i materiali didattici, le idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i 
soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα από Discover το γήινο 
πρόγραμμά μας, σπουδαστές ερευνά τη θεωρία της τεκτονικής 
πιάτων και των σχετικών φαινομένων χρησιμοποιώντας το διαλογικό 
περιβάλλον ανάλυσης χαρτογράφησης και στοιχείων του γρήγορου 
εργαλείου γήινης μελέτης, ΑΝΑΖΗΤΗΣΗ. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα 
αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες
για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις
σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις 
ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad del descubrir nuestro proyecto 
de la tierra, estudiantes explora la teoría de la tectónica de placa
y de los fenómenos relacionados usando el ambiente interactivo de la 
herramienta rápida del estudio de la tierra, BÚSQUEDA del análisis 
el asociar y de datos. En esta paginación del punto de partida,
los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre las metas
que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades del uso, de
la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las ideas del 
gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DISCOVER OUR EARTH TEAM AT CORNELL UNIVERSITY
FN:DISCOVER OUR EARTH TEAM AT CORNELL UNIVERSITY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211600</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105593</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/plate-tectonics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
