<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105216</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105216</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The New Negro": "When He's Hit, He Hits Back!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Der Neue Schwarze": "Wenn Er Geschlagen 
Wird, Schlägt Er Zurück!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Nouveau Nègre" : "Quand Il Est frappé,
Il Frappe En arrière!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Negro Novo": "Quando É batido, Bate Para
trás!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Nuovo Negro": "Quando È colpito, 
Colpisce Indietro!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο νέος νέγροσ": "Όταν χτύπησε, χτυπά πίσω!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Nuevo Negro": "Cuando Lo Golpean, Él 
Golpea Detrás!"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the years immediately following World War I, tens of thousands of southern blacks and returning black soldiers flocked to the nation's Northern cities looking for good jobs and a measure of respect and security. Many white Americans, fearful of competition for scarce jobs and housing, responded by attacking black citizens in a spate of urban race riots. In urban African-American enclaves, the 1920s were marked by a flowering of cultural expressions and a proliferation of black self-help organizations that accompanied the era of the "New Negro." Many black leaders, including religious figures, embraced racial pride and militancy. This 1921 article by Rollin Lynde Hartt, a white Congregational minister and journalist, captured well what was "new" in the New Negro: an aggressive willingness to defend black communities against white racist attacks and a desire to celebrate the accomplishments of African-American communities in the North.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den Jahren direkt nach dem Ersten Weltkrieg, scharten 
sich 10 Tausenden der südlichen Schwarzer und zurückkommende 
schwarze Soldaten zu den Nordstädte der Nation, die guten Jobs und 
einem Maß nach Respekt und Sicherheit suchen. Viele weiße 
Amerikaner, ängstliches der Konkurrenz für knappe Jobs und Gehäuse,
reagiert, indem sie schwarze Bürger in einer Überflutung des 
städtischen Rennens angreifen, randaliert. In den städtischen 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Enklaven wurden die zwanziger Jahre durch 
ein Blühen der kulturellen Ausdrücke und eine starke Verbreitung der
schwarzen Self-helporganisationen gekennzeichnet, die begleiteten die 
Ära des "neuen Schwarzen." Viele schwarze Führer, 
einschließlich fromme Abbildungen, umfaßten rassischen Stolz und 
Militancy. Dieser Artikel 1921 durch Rollin Lynde Hartt, ein 
weißer Gemeindeminister und Journalist, gut erfaßt, was im neuen 
Schwarzen "neu" war: eine konkurrenzfähige Bereitwilligkeit, 
schwarze Gemeinschaften gegen weiße Rassistangriffe und einen Wunsch 
zu verteidigen, die Vollendungen der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen 
Gemeinschaften im Norden zu feiern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En années juste après la Première Guerre Mondiale, les 
dizaines de milliers de noirs méridionaux et les soldats noirs de 
renvoi se sont assemblés aux villes nordiques de la nation 
recherchant les bons travaux et une mesure de respect et de 
sécurité. Beaucoup d'Américains blancs, craintifs de la 
concurrence pour les travaux rares et le logement, répondue en 
attaquant les citoyens noirs dans un flux de course urbaine s'ameute. 
Dans les enclaves afro-américaines urbaines, les années 20 ont 
été marquées par une fleuraison des expressions culturelles et une 
prolifération des organismes noirs de art de l'auto-portrait-help qui ont 
accompagné l'ère du "nouveau nègre." Beaucoup d'amorces 
noires, y compris les figures religieuses, ont embrassé la fierté et
le militantisme raciaux. Cet article 1921 par Rollin Lynde 
Hartt, un ministre en assemblée blanc et journaliste, capturés bien 
ce qu'il y avait de neuf "" dans le nouveau nègre : une bonne 
volonté agressive de défendre les communautés noires contre les 
attaques blanches de raciste et un désir de célébrer les 
accomplissements des communautés afro-américaines dans le nord.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos anos imediatamente depois do world.war.i, os dez dos 
milhares de pretos do sul e os soldados pretos de retorno reuniram-se 
às cidades do norte da nação que procuram trabalhos bons e uma 
medida do respeito e da segurança. Muitos americanos brancos, 
temíveis da competição para trabalhos escassos e carcaça, 
respondida atacando cidadãos pretos em um spate da raça urbana 
amotinam-se. Em enclaves Africano-Americanos urbanos, os 1920s 
foram marcados flowering de expressões cultural e por um 
proliferation das organizações pretas do self-help que acompanharam 
a era "do negro novo." Muitos líderes pretos, including figuras
religiosas, embraced o orgulho e o militancy raciais. Este 
artigo 1921 por Rollin Lynde Hartt, um ministro congregational branco 
e journalist, capturados bem o que era "novo" no negro novo: um 
voluntariedade aggressive defender comunidades pretas de encontro aos 
ataques brancos do racist e um desejo comemorar as realizações de 
comunidades Africano-Americanas no norte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante gli anni subito dopo del world.war.i, i dieci 
delle migliaia dei neri del sud ed i soldati neri di ritorno si sono 
affollati alle città nordiche della nazione che cercano i buoni 
lavori e una misura di rispetto e di sicurezza. Molti Americani 
bianchi, spaventosi di concorrenza per i lavori limitati e 
l'alloggiamento, risposta attacando i cittadini neri in un flusso 
della corsa urbana si solleva. In zone franche 
Africano-Americane urbane, gli anni 20 sono stati contrassegnati 
tramite una fioritura delle espressioni culturali e una proliferazione
delle organizzazioni nere di self-help che hanno accompagnato l'era 
"di nuovo negro." Molti capi neri, compreso le figure 
religiose, hanno abbracciato l'orgoglio e la militanza razziali. 
Questo articolo 1921 da Rollin Lynde Hartt, un ministro 
congregational bianco e giornalista, bloccati bene che cosa era 
"nuovo" nel nuovo negro: una compiacenza aggressiva difendere le
Comunità nere contro gli attacchi bianchi del razzista e un desiderio
celebrare le realizzazioni delle Comunità Africano-Americane nel 
nord.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στα έτη αμέσως μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, οι 
δεκάδες χιλιάδων νότιοι Μαύροι και επιστρέφοντας μαύροι 
στρατιώτες συγκεντρώθηκαν στις βόρειες πόλεις του έθνους που 
αναζητούν τις καλές θέσεις εργασίας και ένα μέτρο του σεβασμού 
και της ασφάλειας. Πολλοί λευκοί Αμερικανοί, έντρομοι του 
ανταγωνισμού για τις λιγοστές εργασίες και την κατοικία, που 
αποκρίνεται με να επιτεθεί στους μαύρους πολίτες στο α χείμαρρος 
των αστικών φυλετικών ταραχών. Στα αστικά 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά περίκλειστα εδάφη, η δεκαετία του '20 
χαρακτηρίστηκε από ένα άνθισμα των πολιτιστικών εκφράσεων και 
έναν πολλαπλασιασμό των μαύρων οργανώσεων αυτοβοήθειας που 
συνόδευσαν την εποχή του "νέου νέγρου." Πολλοί μαύροι 
ηγέτες, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των θρησκευτικών αριθμών, αγκαλίασαν 
τη φυλετικές υπερηφάνεια και τη μαχητικότητα. Αυτό το άρθρο
του 1921 από Rollin Lynde Hartt, έναν λευκούς 
εκκλησιαστικούς υπουργό και έναν δημοσιογράφο, συνέλαβε καλά τι 
ήταν "νέο" στο νέο νέγρο: μια επιθετική προθυμία να 
υπερασπιστούν οι μαύρες κοινότητες ενάντια στις άσπρες 
ρατσιστικές επιθέσεις και μια επιθυμία να γιορταστούν οι 
ολοκληρώσεις των αφρικανικός-αμερικανικών κοινοτήτων στο Βορρά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años inmediatamente después de la Primera Guerra 
Mundial, los diez de millares de negros meridionales y los soldados 
negros que volvían se reunieron a las ciudades norteñas de la 
nación que buscaban buenos trabajos y una medida de respecto y de 
seguridad. Muchos americanos blancos, temerosos de la 
competición para los trabajos escasos y la cubierta, respondida 
atacando a ciudadanos negros en una crecida de la raza urbana se 
desenfrenan. En enclaves Africano-Americanos urbanos, los años 
20 fueron marcados por un florecimiento de expresiones culturales y 
una proliferación de las organizaciones negras del esfuerzo personal 
que acompañaron la era del "nuevo negro." Muchos arranques de 
cinta negros, incluyendo figuras religiosas, abrazaron orgullo y 
militancia raciales. Este artículo 1921 de Rollin Lynde Hartt, 
ministro congregational blanco y periodista, capturados bien cuál era
"nuevo" en el nuevo negro: una buena voluntad agresiva de 
defender comunidades negras contra los ataques blancos del racista y 
un deseo de celebrar las realizaciones de comunidades 
Africano-Americanas en el norte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087007</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105216</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-new-negro-when-hes-hit-he-hits-back</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
