<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105162</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105162</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206447</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Thomas Jefferson Papers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Thomas Jefferson Papiere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Papiers de Thomas Jefferson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Papéis De Thomas Jefferson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le Carte Dal Thomas Jefferson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Thomas Jefferson Papers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Papeles De Thomas Jefferson</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">contains more than 20,000 digitized images of various letters, memoranda, notes, and drafts of documents, books, papers, letters, and manuscripts of the third President, as well as correspondence, commonplace books, and financial account books. The online collection is being produced in installments. The first release deals with Mr. Jefferson's general correspondence, dating from 1621 through 1789, and documents relating to Virginia history, from 1606-1737.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält mehr als 20.000 digitalisierte Bilder der
verschiedenen Zeichen, der Protokolle, der Anmerkungen und der 
Entwürfe der Dokumente, der Bücher, der Papiere, der Zeichen und der
Manuskripte des dritten Präsidenten, sowie Korrespondenz, der 
alltäglichen Bücher und der Finanzbuchhaltungskontobücher. 
Die Onlineansammlung wird in den Ratenzahlungen produziert. 
Die erste Freigabe beschäftigt allgemeine Korrespondenz Herrn 
Jeffersons und datiert von 1621 bis 1789 und Dokumente in bezug auf 
Virginia Geschichte, von 1606-1737.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">contient plus de 20.000 images numérisées de 
divers lettres, mémorandums, notes, et ébauches des documents, des 
livres, des papiers, des lettres, et des manuscrits du troisième 
président, aussi bien que la correspondance, des livres banals, et 
des livres de compte. La collection en ligne est produite dans 
les acomptes. La première version traite la correspondance 
générale de M. Jefferson's, datant de 1621 à 1789, et des documents
concernant l'histoire de la Virginie, de 1606-1737.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">contem mais de 20.000 imagens digitadas de vários
letras, memorandos, notas, e esboços dos originais, dos livros, dos 
papéis, das letras, e dos manuscritos do terceiro presidente, 
as.well.as a correspondência, de livros commonplace, e de livros de 
cliente financeiro. A coleção em linha está sendo produzida 
nas prestações. A primeira liberação trata da 
correspondência geral do Sr. Jefferson, datando de 1621 a 1789, e 
documenta relacionar-se ao history de Virgínia, de 1606-1737.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">contiene più di 20.000 immagini date valori 
numerici a di vari lettere, memorandum, note e brutte copie dei 
documenti, dei libri, delle carte, delle lettere e dei manoscritti del
terzo presidente, così come corrispondenza, dei libri ordinari e dei 
libri di conto finanziario. L'accumulazione in linea sta 
producenda i a rate. La prima versione si occupa della 
corrispondenza generale del sig. Jefferson, datando da 1621 a 1789 ed 
i documenti per quanto riguarda la storia della Virginia, da 
1606-1737.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιέχει περισσότερες από 20.000 μεταλλαγμένες 
εικόνες των διάφορων επιστολών, των υπομνημάτων, των σημειώσεων, 
και των σχεδίων των εγγράφων, των βιβλίων, των εγγράφων, των 
επιστολών, και των χειρογράφων του τρίτου Προέδρου, καθώς επίσης
και της αλληλογραφίας, των κοινών βιβλίων, και των βιβλίων 
οικονομικού απολογισμού. Η σε απευθείας σύνδεση συλλογή 
παράγεται στις δόσεις. Η πρώτη έκδοση εξετάζει τη γενική 
αλληλογραφία του κ. Jefferson's, που χρονολογούν από 1621 
μέχρι 1789, και τα έγγραφα σχετικά με την ιστορία της 
Βιρτζίνια, από 1606-1737.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contiene más de 20.000 imágenes digitalizadas de
varios cartas, memorándums, notas, y bosquejos de documentos, de 
libros, de papeles, de cartas, y de manuscritos del tercer presidente,
así como correspondencia, de libros corrientes, y de libros de la 
cuenta financiera. La colección en línea se está produciendo 
en instalaciones. El primer desbloquear se ocupa de 
correspondencia general de Sr. Jefferson, fechando a partir el 1621 a 
1789, y los documentos referente a la historia de Virginia, a partir 
de 1606-1737.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206447</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105162</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-thomas-jefferson-papers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
