<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104597</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104597</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973972</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mapojib Experience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mapojib Erfahrung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expérience de Mapojib</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Experiência De Mapojib</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esperienza Di Mapojib</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εμπειρία Mapojib</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Experiencia De Mapojib</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Mapojib experience follows two young characters, Daroo and Sung Min, through their experience in Mapojib. Mapojib is a famous Korean BBQ restaurant. Through their trip they'll experience the customs and language specific to eating out in Korea. What delicious foods will our friends find at Mapojib! Mapojib experience is part of a larger series of experiences that span the most common activities found in Korea. These games have been created to share the experiences with foreigners interested in learning more about Korean culture.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>ko</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mapojib Erfahrung folgt zwei jungen Zeichen, Daroo 
und gesungener Minute, durch ihre Erfahrung in Mapojib. Mapojib 
ist eine berühmte Koreaner BBQ Gaststätte. Durch ihre Reise 
erfahren sie die Gewohnheiten und das Sprachenbesonderen zum Essen 
heraus in Korea. Welche köstliche Nahrungsmittel willen, finden
unsere Freunde bei Mapojib! Mapojib Erfahrung ist ein Teil einer
größeren Reihe Erfahrungen, die die geläufigsten Aktivitäten 
überspannen, die in Korea gefunden werden. Diese Spiele sind 
erstellt worden, um die Erfahrungen mit den Ausländern zu teilen, die
an dem Lernen mehr über koreanische Kultur interessiert werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'expérience de Mapojib suit deux jeunes 
caractères, Daroo et minute chantée, par leur expérience de 
Mapojib. Mapojib est un restaurant célèbre de BBQ de Coréen. 
Par leur voyage ils éprouveront les coutumes et le détail de 
langage à manger dehors en Corée. Quelles nourritures 
délicieuses veulent nos amis trouvent chez Mapojib ! 
L'expérience de Mapojib fait partie d'une plus grande série 
d'expériences qui enjambent les activités les plus communes 
trouvées en Corée. Ces jeux ont été créés pour partager 
les expériences avec des Étrangers intéressés à apprendre plus au
sujet de la culture coréenne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A experiência de Mapojib segue dois caráteres 
novos, Daroo e minuto cantado, com sua experiência em Mapojib. 
Mapojib é um restaurante famoso do BBQ do coreano. Com 
seu desengate experimentarão os costumes e o específico da língua a
comer para fora em Coreia. Que alimentos deliciosos querem 
nossos amigos encontram em Mapojib! A experiência de Mapojib é
parte de uma série maior das experiências que medem as atividades as
mais comuns encontradas em Coreia. Estes jogos foram criados 
para compartilhar das experiências com os estrangeiros interessados 
em aprender mais sobre a cultura korean.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'esperienza di Mapojib segue due caratteri 
giovani, Daroo e minuto cantato, con la loro esperienza di Mapojib. 
Mapojib è un ristorante famoso del BBQ del Coreano. Con 
il loro viaggio avvertiranno le abitudini ed il linguaggio specifici 
al consumo fuori in Corea. Che alimenti squisiti vogliono i 
nostri amici trovano a Mapojib! L'esperienza di Mapojib fa parte
di più ampia serie di esperienze che misurano le attività più 
comuni trovate in Corea. Questi giochi sono stati creati per 
ripartire le esperienze con gli stranieri interessati ad imparare più
circa coltura coreana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εμπειρία Mapojib ακολουθεί δύο νέους χαρακτήρες,
Daroo και τραγουδημένο λ., μέσω της εμπειρίας τους σε 
Mapojib. Το Mapojib είναι ένα διάσημο κορεατικό bbq
εστιατόριο. Μέσω του ταξιδιού τους θα δοκιμάσουν το 
τελωνείο και τη γλώσσα συγκεκριμένα για έξω στην Κορέα. 
Ποια εύγευστα τρόφιμα οι φίλοι μας θα βρούν σε Mapojib! 
Η εμπειρία Mapojib είναι μέρος μιας μεγαλύτερης σειράς 
εμπειρίας που εκτείνεται τις πιό κοινές δραστηριότητες που 
βρίσκονται στην Κορέα. Αυτά τα παιχνίδια έχουν 
δημιουργηθεί για να μοιραστούν την εμπειρία με τους αλλοδαπούς 
ενδιαφερόμενους στην εκμάθηση περισσότερων για τον κορεατικό 
πολιτισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La experiencia de Mapojib sigue dos caracteres 
jóvenes, Daroo y minuto cantado, con su experiencia en Mapojib. 
Mapojib es un restaurante famoso del Bbq del coreano. Con 
su viaje experimentarán los costumbres y el específico del lenguaje 
a comer hacia fuera en Corea. ¡Qué alimentos deliciosos quieren
nuestros amigos encuentran en Mapojib! La experiencia de Mapojib
es parte de una serie más grande de experiencias que atraviesen las 
actividades más comunes encontradas en Corea. Estos juegos se 
han creado para compartir las experiencias con los extranjeros 
interesados en aprender más sobre cultura coreana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BRENDAN COYLE
FN:BRENDAN COYLE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973972</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104597</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mapojib-experience</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
