<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107812</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107812</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206774</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Church in the Southern Black Community, 1780-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kirche in der südlichen schwarzen 
Gemeinschaft, 1780-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'église dans la Communauté noire méridionale, 
1780-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A igreja na comunidade preta do sul, 1780-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La chiesa nella Comunità nera del sud, 1780-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εκκλησία στη νότια μαύρη Κοινότητα, 1780-1925</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La iglesia en la comunidad negra meridional, 
1780-1925</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">traces how Southern African-Americans experienced Protestant Christianity and transformed it into the central institution of community life. Coverage begins with white churches' conversion efforts and depicts the contradictions between the egalitarian potential of evangelical Christianity and the realities of slavery. It focuses on how the black community adapted evangelical Christianity, making it a metaphor for freedom, community, and personal survival.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">verfolgt, wie südliche Afrikanisch-Amerikaner 
protestierendes Christentum erfuhren und es in die zentrale Anstalt 
des Gemeinschaftslebens umwandelten. Dichte fängt mit 
Bemühungen Konvertierung der weißen Kirchen an und stellt die 
Widersprüche zwischen dem gleichmacherischen Potential des 
evangelischen Christentums und den Wirklichkeiten der Sklaverei 
bildlich dar. Sie konzentriert auf, wie die schwarze 
Gemeinschaft das evangelische Christentum anpaßte und es eine 
Metapher für Freiheit, Gemeinschaft und persönliches Überleben 
bildete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">trace comment les Afro-Américains méridionaux ont 
éprouvé le christianisme protestant et l'ont transformé en 
établissement central de la vie de la communauté. L'assurance 
commence par les efforts de la conversion des églises blanches et 
dépeint les contradictions entre le potentiel égalitaire du 
christianisme évangélique et les réalités de l'esclavage. 
Elle se concentre sur la façon dont la communauté noire a 
adapté le christianisme évangélique, faisant lui une métaphore 
pour la liberté, à la communauté, et à survie personnelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">segue como os Africano-Americanos do sul 
experimentaram o christianity protestant e o transformaram na 
instituição central da vida da comunidade. A cobertura começa
com os esforços da conversão das igrejas brancas e descreve os 
contradictions entre o potencial egalitarian do christianity 
evangelical e as realidades do slavery. Focaliza em como a 
comunidade preta adaptou o christianity evangelical, fazendo a lhe um 
metaphor para a liberdade, a comunidade, e a sobrevivência pessoal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">segue come gli Africano-Americani del sud hanno 
avvertito il christianity protestante e lo hanno trasformato 
nell'istituzione centrale di vita della Comunità. Il 
riempimento comincia con gli sforzi di conversione delle chiese 
bianche e descrive le contraddizioni fra il potenziale egalitario di 
christianity evangelical e le realtà di slavery. Mette a fuoco 
su come la Comunità nera ha adattato il christianity evangelical, 
rendente esso una metafora per la libertà, a Comunità ed a 
sopravvivenza personale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επισημαίνει πώς νότιοι αφρικανικός-Αμερικανοί 
δοκίμασαν τον προτεσταντικό χριστιανισμό και τον μετασχημάτισαν 
στο κεντρικό όργανο της κοινοτικής ζωής. Η κάλυψη 
αρχίζει με τις προσπάθειες μετατροπής των άσπρων εκκλησιών και 
απεικονίζει τις αντιφάσεις μεταξύ της egalitarian δυνατότητας 
του εβαγγελικού χριστιανισμού και των πραγματικοτήτων της 
σκλαβιάς. Εστιάζει στον τρόπο με τον οποίο η μαύρη 
κοινότητα προσάρμοσε τον εβαγγελικό χριστιανισμό, που κάνει το 
μια μεταφορά για την ελευθερία, την κοινότητα, και την προσωπική 
επιβίωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">rastrea cómo los Africano-Americanos meridionales
experimentaron el cristianismo protestante y lo transformaron en la 
institución central de la vida de la comunidad. La cobertura 
comienza con los esfuerzos de la conversión de las iglesias blancas y
representa las contradicciones entre el potencial igualitario del 
cristianismo evangélico y las realidades de la esclavitud. Se 
centra en cómo la comunidad negra adaptó el cristianismo 
evangélico, haciendo le una metáfora para la libertad, comunidad, y 
supervivencia personal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206774</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107812</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-church-in-the-southern-black-community-1780-1925</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
