<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106131</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201311</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dive and Discover's Deeper Discovery: Hydrothermal Vents</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tauchen Sie und entdeckten tiefere Entdeckung: 
Hydrothermale Entlüftungsöffnungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plongez et avez découvert une découverte plus 
profonde : Évents Hydrothermiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mergulhe e descobriram uma descoberta mais 
profunda: Respiradouros Hydrothermal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tuffisi e scoperto la scoperta più profonda: 
Sfiati Idrotermali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βουτήξτε και ανακάλυψε τη βαθύτερη ανακάλυψη: 
Υδροθερμικές διέξοδοι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Zambúllase y descubrieron un descubrimiento más 
profundo: Respiraderos Hidrotérmicos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Dive and Discover is an interactive distance learning web site designed to immerse you in the excitement of discovery and exploration of the deep seafloor. On this particular website, Dive and Discover takes you on a deeper discovery of hydrothermal vents. This site features an introduction to hydrothermal vent systems, including vent basics, vents around the world, chemistry, boiling points, interactive diagrams, videos, a quiz, and links to selected Dive and Discover hydrothermal vent-related seafloor expeditions. This web page also provides links to other Deeper Discovery topics, Dive and Discover seafloor expeditions, a teacher's page, and further Dive and Discover information.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Und entdecken ist tauchen eine interaktive Abstand
Lernenweb site, die konzipiert ist, um Sie in der Aufregung der 
Entdeckung und der Erforschung des tiefen seafloor unterzutauchen. 
Auf dieser bestimmten Web site entdeckt Tauchen und Nehmen Sie 
auf einer tieferen Entdeckung der hydrothermalen 
Entlüftungsöffnungen. Dieses Situationsmerkmale eine 
Einleitung in eine hydrothermalen Entlüftungssysteme, einschließlich
Entlüftungsöffnung Grundlagen, Entlüftungsöffnungen um die Welt, 
Chemie, Siedepunkte, interaktive Diagramme, videos, ein Quiz und Links
zu ausgewähltem Tauchen und entdecken hydrothermale 
Entlüftungsöffnung-in Verbindung stehende seafloor Expeditionen. 
Diese Webseite auch stellt Links zu anderen tieferen 
Entdeckungthemen, Tauchen zur Verfügung und entdeckt seafloor 
Expeditionen, Seite eines Lehrers und weiter taucht und entdeckt 
Informationen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plongent et découvrent est un site Web interactif
d'étude de distance conçu pour vous immerger dans l'excitation de la
découverte et de l'exploration du seafloor profond. Sur ce site
Web particulier, le piqué et découvrent des prises vous sur une 
découverte plus profonde des évents hydrothermiques. Les 
dispositifs de ce site une introduction aux circuits de mise à l'air 
libre hydrothermiques, y compris des fondations d'évent, des évents 
autour du monde, chimie, des points d'ébullition, des diagrammes 
interactifs, des videos, un jeu, et des liens au piqué choisi et 
découvrent des expéditions évent-connexes hydrothermiques de 
seafloor. Cette page Web également fournit des liens à 
d'autres sujets plus profonds de découverte, piqué et découvre des 
expéditions de seafloor, la page d'un professeur, et plus loin plonge
et découvre l'information.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mergulha e descobre é um Web site interativo da 
aprendizagem de distância projetado immerse o no excitamento da 
descoberta e da exploração do seafloor profundo. Neste Web 
site particular, o mergulho e descobre tomadas você em uma descoberta
mais profunda de respiradouros hydrothermal. As características
deste local uma introdução aos sistemas de respiradouro 
hydrothermal, including princípios do respiradouro, respiradouros em 
torno do mundo, chemistry, pontos fervendo, diagramas interativos, 
videos, um quiz, e as ligações ao mergulho selecionado e descobrem 
expedições respiradouro-relacionadas hydrothermal do seafloor. 
Este Web page também fornece as ligações a outros tópicos 
mais profundos da descoberta, mergulho e descobre expedições do 
seafloor, página de um professor, e mais mais mergulha e descobre a 
informação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Si tuffa e scopre è un Web site interattivo 
imparare di distanza destinato per immergerli nell'eccitamento della 
scoperta e dell'esplorazione del seafloor profondo. Su questo 
Web site particolare, il tuffo e scopre gli introiti voi su una 
scoperta più profonda degli sfiati idrotermali. Caratteristiche
di questo luogo un'introduzione ai sistemi di sfiato idrotermali, 
compreso i principi fondamentali dello sfiato, sfiati intorno al 
mondo, chimica, punti di ebollizione, schemi interattivi, videos, un 
quiz e collegamenti al tuffo selezionato e scoprono le spedizioni 
sfiato-relative idrotermali di seafloor. Questo Web page 
egualmente fornisce i collegamenti ad altri soggetti più profondi di 
scoperta, tuffo e scopre le spedizioni di seafloor, pagina 
dell'insegnante e più ulteriormente si tuffa e scopre le 
informazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βουτήξτε και ανακαλύψτε είναι ένας διαλογικός 
ιστοχώρος από απόσταση εκμάθησης με σκοπό να σας βυθίσει στον 
ενθουσιασμό της ανακάλυψης και την εξερεύνηση του βαθιού 
θαλάσσιου πυθμένα. Σε αυτόν τον ιδιαίτερο ιστοχώρο, 
βουτήξτε και ανακαλύψτε σας παίρνει σε μια βαθύτερη ανακάλυψη των
υδροθερμικών διεξόδων. Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει μια 
εισαγωγή στα συστήματα υδροθερμικών διεξόδων, συμπεριλαμβανομένων
των βασικών διεξόδων, αερίζει σε όλο τον κόσμο, χημεία, σημεία 
βρασμού, διαλογικά διαγράμματα, βίντεο, ένας διαγωνισμός 
γνώσεων, και οι συνδέσεις με επιλεγμένος βουτούν και ανακαλύπτουν
τις υδροθερμικές διέξοδος-σχετικές με το αποστολές θαλάσσιου 
πυθμένα. Αυτή η ιστοσελίδας παρέχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις 
με άλλα βαθύτερα θέματα ανακαλύψεων, βουτά και ανακαλύπτει τις 
αποστολές θαλάσσιου πυθμένα, η σελίδα ενός δασκάλου, και βουτά 
περαιτέρω και ανακαλύπτει τις πληροφορίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Se zambulle y descubre es un Web site interactivo 
el aprender de distancia diseñado para sumergirle en el entusiasmo 
del descubrimiento y de la exploración del seafloor profundo. 
En este Web site determinado, la zambullida y descubre tomas 
usted en un descubrimiento más profundo de respiraderos 
hidrotérmicos. Las características de este sitio una 
introducción a los sistemas de respiradero hidrotérmicos, incluyendo
fundamentos del respiradero, los respiraderos alrededor del mundo, 
química, las puntas que hierven, los diagramas interactivos, los 
videos, un concurso, y las conexiones a la zambullida seleccionada y 
descubren a expediciones respiradero-relacionadas hidrotérmicas del 
seafloor. Este Web page también proporciona a las conexiones a 
otros asuntos más profundos del descubrimiento, zambullida y descubre
las expediciones del seafloor, paginación de un profesor, y más 
lejos se zambulle y descubre la información.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WOODS HOLE OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTION
FN:WOODS HOLE OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201311</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106131</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/dive-and-discovers-deeper-discovery-hydrothermal-vents</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
