<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087465</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Can 52,600,000 TV Set Owners Be Wrong?:  Look  Magazine Assesses American Television in 1960</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dose 52.600.000 Fernsehapparat Set-Inhaber Sind? 
Falsch: Blick-Zeitschrift setzt amerikanisches Fernsehen 1960 
fest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Propriétaires de Positionnement de TV du 
Bidon 52.600.000 Aient Tort ? : Le magasin de regard évalue la 
télévision américaine en 1960</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Proprietários Do Jogo de Tevê Da Lata 
52.600.000 Sejam Errados?: O compartimento do olhar avalia a 
televisão americana em 1960</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I Proprietari Dell'Insieme di TV Della Latta 
52.600.000 Sono Errati?: Lo scomparto di sguardo valuta la 
televisione americana in 1960</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μπορέστε 52.600.000 ιδιοκτήτες συνόλου TV να 
είστε λανθασμένος;: Φανείτε περιοδικό αξιολογεί την 
αμερικανική τηλεόραση το 1960</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Propietarios Del Aparato de TV De la Lata 
52.600.000 Sean Incorrectos?: El compartimiento de la mirada 
evalúa la televisión americana en 1960</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although experimental telecasts began in the 1920s and commercial broadcasting made a tentative start in 1939, the television industry first blossomed after World War II. In 1949, one million sets were in use, mostly in urban areas. By the end of the 1950s, Americans had purchased more than 50 million sets. As with earlier forms of mass culture--especially radio and movies--the advent of television on a national scale brought forth a debate in popular forums on its quality, societal effects, and potential. While writer Paddy Cheyevsky in 1953 characterized television as "the marvelous medium of the ordinary," Federal Communications Commission Director Newton Minow, eight years later, charged that broadcasters had created "a vast wasteland" inhabited predominately with "game shows, violence, audience participation shows, formula comedies about totally unbelievable families, blood and thunder, mayhem, violence, sadism, murder, western bad men, western good men, private eyes, gangsters, more violence, and cartoons." The following article shows how a popular magazine assessed television's past, present, and possible future in 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich experimentelle Telecasts in den zwanziger
Jahren anfingen und kommerzielle Sendung einen vorläufigen Anfang 
1939 bildete, blühte die Fernsehenindustrie zuerst nach dem Zweiten 
Weltkrieg. 1949 waren eine Million Sets im Gebrauch, meistens in
den städtischen Bereichen. Ende der fünfziger Jahre hatten 
Amerikaner mehr als 50 Million Sets gekauft. Wie mit früheren 
Formularen der Massenkultur -- besonders Radio und Filme -- das 
Aufkommen des Fernsehens auf einer nationalen Skala holte weiter eine 
Debatte in den populären Foren auf seiner Qualität, 
gesellschaftlichen Effekten und Potential. Während Verfasser 
Paddy Cheyevsky in 1953 Fernsehen als "der erstaunliche Medium des 
Üblichen kennzeichnete," beauftragen Bundeskommunikationen Direktor 
Newton Minow, acht Jahre später, aufgeladen, daß Rundfunkstationen 
"ein beträchtliches Ödland hergestellt hatten", das überwiegend 
bewohnt wurde mit "Spielerscheinen, Gewalttätigkeit, Publikum 
Teilnahmeerscheinen, Formelkomödien über total unglaubliche 
Familien, Blut und Donner, Verstümmelung, Gewalttätigkeit, 
Sadismus, Mord, westliche falsche Männer, westliche gute 
Männer, private Augen, Gangster, mehr Gewalttätigkeit und 
Karikaturen." Festsetzte hinter, der folgende Artikel zeigt, wie
eine populäre Zeitschrift des Fernsehens, Geschenk und mögliche 
Zukunft 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que les télédiffusions expérimentales 
aient commencé dans les années 20 et la radiodiffusion commerciale a
fait un début expérimental en 1939, l'industrie de télévision 
s'est développée la première fois après la deuxième guerre 
mondiale. En 1949, un million de positionnements étaient en 
service, la plupart du temps dans des zones urbaines. Vers la 
fin des années 50, les Américains avaient acheté plus de 50 
millions de positionnements. Comme avec des formes plus tôt de 
culture de masse -- particulièrement radio et films -- l'arrivée de 
la télévision sur une échelle nationale a apporté une discussion 
dans les forum populaires sur sa qualité, effets sociaux, et 
potentiel. Tandis que le paddy Cheyevsky d'auteur dans 1953 
caractérisait la télévision comme "support merveilleux de 
l'ordinaire," les transmissions fédérales commissionnent directeur 
Newton Minow, huit ans après, chargé que les radiodiffuseurs avaient
créé "une vaste terre en friche" habitée d'une matière 
prédominante avec des "expositions de jeu, violence, des expositions 
de participation d'assistances, des comédies de formule au sujet des 
familles totalement incroyables, sang et tonnerre, mutilation, 
violence, sadisme, meurtre, de mauvais hommes occidentaux, de bons 
hommes occidentaux, des détectives privés, des bandits, plus de 
violence, et des dessins animés." L'article suivant montre 
après la façon dont un magasin populaire a évalué la télévision,
présent, et futur possible en 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora os telecasts experimentais começassem nos 
1920s e a transmissão comercial fizesse um começo tentative em 1939,
a indústria da televisão floresceu primeiramente após a segunda 
guerra mundial. Em 1949, um milhão jogos estavam no uso, na 
maior parte em áreas urbanas. Para o fim dos 1950s, os 
americanos tinham comprado mais de 50 milhão jogos. Como com 
formulários mais adiantados da cultura maciça -- especial rádio e 
filmes -- o advent da televisão em uma escala nacional trouxe adiante
um debate em forums populares em seus qualidade, efeitos societal, e 
potencial. Quando o paddy Cheyevsky do escritor em 1953 
caracterizou a televisão como "o media maravilhoso do ordinário," as
comunicações federais comissão o diretor Newton Minow, oito anos 
mais tarde, carregado que os radiodifusores tinham criado "um 
wasteland vasto" habitado predominately com do "as mostras jogo, a 
violência, as mostras da participação das audiências, os comedies 
da fórmula sobre famílias totalmente inacreditáveis, o sangue e o 
trovão, o mayhem, a violência, o sadism, o assassinato, homens maus 
ocidentais, homens bons ocidentais, os olhos confidenciais, os 
gangsters, a mais violência, e os cartoons." O seguinte artigo 
mostra como um compartimento popular avaliou a televisão após, 
presente, e futuro possível em 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se i telecasts sperimentali hanno cominciato
negli anni 20 ed il broadcasting commerciale ha fatto un inizio 
sperimentale in 1939, l'industria della televisione in primo luogo è 
sbocciato dopo la seconda guerra mondiale. In 1949, un milione 
di insiemi erano in uso, principalmente nelle aree urbane. Per 
la fine degli anni 50, gli Americani avevano comprato più di 50 
milione insiemi. Come con le forme più in anticipo di coltura 
totale -- particolarmente radio e film -- l'avvenimento del the
della televisione su una scala nazionale ha causato un dibattito in 
tribune popolari sulla relativi qualità, effetti sociali e 
potenziale. Mentre la risaia Cheyevsky del produttore in 1953 ha
caratterizzato la televisione come "il media meraviglioso 
dell'ordinario," le comunicazioni federali Commissione il direttore 
Newton Minow, otto anni più successivamente, caricato che i 
distributori a spaglio avevano creato "un terreno incolto ampio" 
abitato predominately con "le esposizioni del gioco, violenza, 
esposizioni di partecipazione dei pubblici, commedie di formula 
circa le famiglie completamente unbelievable, anima e tuono, mayhem, 
violenza, sadism, omicidio, uomini difettosi occidentali, buoni uomini
occidentali, occhi riservati, gangsters, più violenza e fumetti." 
Il seguente articolo mostra come uno scomparto popolare ha 
valutato la televisione oltre, presente e futuro possibile in 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και οι πειραματικές τηλεοπτικές εκπομπές άρχισαν 
στη δεκαετία του '20 και η εμπορική ραδιοφωνική αναμετάδοση έκανε
μια δοκιμαστική έναρξη το 1939, η τηλεοπτική βιομηχανία άνθισε
αρχικά μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Το 1949, ένα 
εκατομμύριο σύνολα ήταν σε χρήση, συνήθως στις αστικές 
περιοχές. Μέχρι το τέλος της δεκαετίας του '50, Αμερικανοί 
είχαν αγοράσει περισσότερα από 50 εκατομμύριο σύνολα. 
Όπως με τις προηγούμενες μορφές του μαζικού πολιτισμού -- 
ειδικά ραδιόφωνο και κινηματογράφοι -- η εμφάνιση της τηλεόρασης 
σε μια εθνική κλίμακα έφερε εμπρός μια συζήτηση στα δημοφιλή 
φόρουμ στην ποιότητα, τα κοινωνικά αποτελέσματα, και τη 
δυνατότητά της. Ενώ ο ορυζώνας Cheyevsky συγγραφέων το 
1953 χαρακτήρισε την τηλεόραση ως "θαυμάσιο μέσο του 
συνηθισμένου," η ομοσπονδιακή Επιτροπή ανακοινώσεων σκηνοθέτης 
Newton Minow, οκτώ έτη αργότερα, χρέωσε ότι οι εκφωνητές 
είχαν δημιουργήσει "μια απέραντη χέρσα περιοχή" που κατοικήθηκε 
κυρίως με "το παιχνίδι εμφανίζουν, η βία, συμμετοχή ακροατηρίων 
εμφανίζει, κωμωδίες τύπου για τις συνολικά απίστευτες 
οικογένειες, αίμα και βροντή, mayhem, βία, σαδισμός, 
δολοφονία, δυτικά κακά άτομα, δυτικά καλά άτομα, ιδιωτικά 
μάτια, γκάγκστερ, περισσότερη βία, και κινούμενα σχέδια." 
Το ακόλουθο άρθρο επιδεικνύει πώς ένα δημοφιλές περιοδικό
αξιολόγησε το τηλεοπτικό προηγούμενο, παρόν, και πιθανό μέλλον 
το 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque las transmisiones por televisión 
experimentales comenzaron en los años 20 y la difusión comercial 
hizo un comienzo tentativo en 1939, la industria de la televisión 
primero floreció después de la Segunda Guerra Mundial. En 
1949, un millón conjuntos estaban en uso, sobre todo en áreas 
urbanas. Para el final de los años 50, los americanos habían 
comprado más de 50 millones de conjuntos. Como con formas 
anteriores de cultura total -- especialmente radio y las películas --
el advenimiento de la televisión en una escala nacional trajo 
adelante un discusión en foros populares en su calidad, efectos 
societal, y potencial. Mientras que el paddy Cheyevsky del 
programa de escritura en 1953 caracterizó la televisión como "el 
media maravilloso del ordinario," las comunicaciones federales 
Comisión a director Newton Minow, ocho años más tarde, cargado que 
los locutores habían creado "una tierra extensa" habitada 
predominately con "demostraciones del juego, violencia, las 
demostraciones de la participación de las audiencias, las comedias 
del fórmula sobre las familias totalmente increíbles, sangre y 
trueno, mutilación, violencia, sadismo, asesinato, los malos hombres 
occidentales, los buenos hombres occidentales, los ojos privados, los 
gángsteres, más violencia, y las historietas." El artículo 
siguiente muestra más allá de cómo un compartimiento popular 
evaluó la televisión, presente, y futuro posible en 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087465</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104953</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/can-52-600-000-tv-set-owners-be-wrong-look-magazine-assesses-american-television-in-1960</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
