<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103723</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103723</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202670</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Stories From the Holocaust</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichten vom Holocaust</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoires de Holocauste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Histórias do Holocaust</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia dal Holocaust</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορίες από το ολοκαύτωμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historias del Holocaust</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson is designed to supplement a study of World War II. Students will read first hand accounts of individuals who escaped Nazi persecution and eventually settled in Asheville, North Carolina. This lesson may be used as an 8th grade Social Sciences or English project (It could also be used as an integrated project), 10th grade English, or 11th grade US Social Sciences. This lesson use the NCEcho portal to access the material.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion ist konzipiert, um eine Studie des 
Zweiten Weltkrieges zu ergänzen. Kursteilnehmer lesen erste 
Handkonten der Einzelpersonen, die Nazi Verfolgung entgingen und 
schließlich in Asheville, Nord-Carolina vereinbaren. Diese 
Lektion kann als ein 8. Grad Sozialwissenschaften verwendet werden 
oder englisches Projekt (sie könnte als integriertes Projekt auch 
verwendet werden), 10. Grad Englisch oder 11. Grad US 
Sozialwissenschaften. Dieser Lektiongebrauch das NCEcho Portal, 
auf das Material zuzugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon est conçue pour compléter une 
étude de la deuxième guerre mondiale. Les étudiants liront 
des comptes de première main des individus qui ont échappé à la 
persécution Nazie et par la suite arrangents à Asheville, 
Caroline du nord. Cette leçon peut être utilisée en tant
que d'une 8ème sciences sociales catégorie ou projet anglais (elle 
pourrait également être utilisée comme projet intégré), 10ème 
anglais de catégorie, ou sciences sociales des USA de la 11ème 
catégorie. Cette utilisation de leçon le portail de NCEcho 
d'accéder au matériel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição é projetada suplementar um estudo da
segunda guerra mundial. Os estudantes lerão primeiros clientes 
da mão dos indivíduos que escaparam do persecution nazi e 
estabelecems eventualmente em Asheville, North.carolina. Esta 
lição pode ser usada como ciências sociais de uma å classe ou 
projeto inglês (poderia também ser usada como um projeto integrado),
10o inglês da classe, ou ciências sociais dos E. U. da 11a classe. 
Este uso da lição o portal de NCEcho alcançar o material.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione è destinata per completare uno 
studio sulla seconda guerra mondiale. Gli allievi leggeranno i 
primi clienti della mano degli individui che hanno fuoriuscito il 
persecution Nazista e finalmente depositati a Asheville, 
North.carolina. Questa lezione può essere usata come scienze 
sociali dell'ottavo grado o il progetto inglese (potrebbe anche essere
usata come progetto integrato), decimo inglese del grado, o le scienze
sociali degli Stati Uniti dell'undicesimo grado. Questo uso di 
lezione il portal di NCEcho accedere al materiale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα έχει ως σκοπό να συμπληρώσει μια 
μελέτη του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
διαβάσουν τους πρώτους απολογισμούς χεριών των ατόμων που 
δραπέτευσαν τη ναζιστική δίωξη και εγκατέστησαν τελικά στο 
Ασβιλλ, βόρεια Καρολίνα. Αυτό το μάθημα μπορεί να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί ως κοινωνικές επιστήμες ενός 8ες βαθμού ή 
αγγλικό πρόγραμμα (μπόρεσε επίσης να χρησιμοποιηθεί ως 
ενσωματωμένο πρόγραμμα), 10η τάξη αγγλικά, ή κοινωνικές 
επιστήμες των 11ων ΗΠΑ βαθμού. Αυτό το μάθημα χρησιμοποιεί 
την πύλη NCEcho για να έχει πρόσβαση στο υλικό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección se diseña para suplir un estudio de
la Segunda Guerra Mundial. Los estudiantes leerán cuentas de 
primera mano de los individuos que escaparon la persecución nazi y 
colocados eventual en Asheville, Carolina del Norte. Esta 
lección se puede utilizar como ciencias sociales de un 8vo grado o 
proyecto inglés (podría también ser utilizada como proyecto 
integrado), 10mo inglés del grado, o las ciencias sociales de los 
E.E.U.U. del 11mo grado. Este uso de la lección el portal de 
NCEcho de tener acceso al material.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BILLIE CLEMENS
FN:BILLIE CLEMENS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202670</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103723</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/stories-from-the-holocaust</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
