<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105947</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105947</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204430</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Discovering elements online</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Elemente entdecken Online</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Découvrant des éléments en ligne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Descobrindo os elementos em linha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scoprendo gli elementi in linea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανακαλύπτοντας τα στοιχεία σε απευθείας σύνδεση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Descubriendo los elementos en línea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students will work independently and in small groups to research assigned elements on the internet with sites given in advance. They will then contribute to a class database with their individual information. The database will then be made available for students to again work independently and in pairs to answer questions created from a class discussion to discover relationships about the elements.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer arbeiten unabhängig und in den 
kleinen Gruppen, zum der zugewiesenen Elemente auf dem Internet mit 
den Sites zu erforschen, die im voraus gegeben werden. Sie 
tragen dann zu einer Kategorie Datenbank mit ihren einzelnen 
Informationen bei. Die Datenbank wird dann für Kursteilnehmer 
zur Verfügung gestellt, um wieder unabhängig zu arbeiten und in den 
Paaren, zum der Fragen zu beantworten, die von einer Kategorie 
Diskussion erstellt werden, um Verhältnisse über die Elemente zu 
entdecken.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants travailleront indépendamment et 
dans de petits groupes pour rechercher les éléments assignés sur 
l'Internet avec des sites donnés à l'avance. Ils contribueront
alors à une base de données de classe avec leur information 
individuelle. La base de données sera alors faite fonctionner 
disponible pour des étudiants encore indépendamment et dans les 
paires pour répondre à des questions créées d'une discussion de 
classe pour découvrir des rapports au sujet des éléments.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes trabalharão independentemente e nos
grupos pequenos para pesquisar elementos atribuídos no Internet com 
os locais dados adiantado. Contribuirão então a uma base de 
dados da classe com sua informação individual. A base de dados
será feita então disponível para estudantes para trabalhar outra 
vez independentemente e em pares para responder às perguntas criadas 
de uma discussão da classe para descobrir relacionamentos sobre os 
elementos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi lavoreranno indipendentemente e nei 
piccoli gruppi per ricercare gli elementi assegnati sul Internet con i
luoghi dati in anticipo. Allora contribuiranno ad una base di 
dati del codice categoria con le loro informazioni specifiche. 
La base di dati allora sarà fatta funzionare disponibile per 
gli allievi ancora indipendentemente e negli accoppiamenti per 
rispondere alle domande create da una discussione del codice categoria
per scoprire i rapporti circa gli elementi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα εργαστούν ανεξάρτητα και στις μικρές 
ομάδες ανατεθειμένα στα έρευνα στοιχεία για το διαδίκτυο με τις 
περιοχές που δίνονται εκ των προτέρων. Θα συμβάλουν έπειτα 
σε μια βάση δεδομένων κλάσης με τις μεμονωμένες πληροφορίες τους.
Η βάση δεδομένων θα παρασχεθεί έπειτα για τους σπουδαστές 
για να λειτουργήσει πάλι ανεξάρτητα και ανά τα ζευγάρια για να 
απαντήσει στις ερωτήσεις που δημιουργούνται από μια συζήτηση 
κλάσης για να ανακαλύψουν τις σχέσεις για τα στοιχεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes trabajarán independientemente y 
en los grupos pequeños para investigar elementos asignados en el 
Internet con los sitios dados por adelantado. Entonces 
contribuirán a una base de datos de la clase con su información 
individual. La base de datos entonces será hecha disponible 
para los estudiantes para trabajar otra vez independientemente y en 
los pares para contestar a las preguntas creadas de una discusión de 
la clase para descubrir lazos sobre los elementos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TRISH LOUDERMILT
FN:TRISH LOUDERMILT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204430</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105947</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/discovering-elements-online</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
