<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108002</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108002</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>813092637</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AP US Government &amp; Politics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AP US Regierung U. Politik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gouvernement et Politique de AP USA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Governo &amp; Política do Ap E. U.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Governo &amp; Politica di Ap Stati Uniti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κυβέρνηση &amp; πολιτική AP ΗΠΑ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gobierno Y Política del Ap LOS E.E.U.U.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The UCCP Advanced Placement (AP) US Government and Politics course is a one semester survey of American Government and Politics covering the Constitution, political beliefs, political parties, interest groups, institutions of government, public policy and civil rights. Emphasis is placed on critical and evaluative thinking skills, essay writing, and interpretation of original documents. This curriculum covers all of the material outlined by the College Board as necessary to prepare you to pass the US Government and Politics exam.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der UCCP vorgerückte Plazierung (AP) US Regierung
und Politikkurs ist eine Übersicht mit einen Semestern der 
amerikanischen Regierung und der Politik, welche die Beschaffenheit, 
den politischen Glauben, die politischen Parteien, die Interesse
Gruppen, die Anstalten der Regierung, die allgemeine Politik und die 
Zivilrechte umfaßt. Nachdruck wird auf die kritische und 
abschätzende denkende Fähigkeiten, Versuchschreiben und Deutung der 
Originalurkunden gelegt. Dieser Lehrplan umfaßt die ganze 
Material, das durch das Hochschulgremium wie benötigt, Sie 
vorzubereiten, die US Regierung und Politikprüfung zu führen 
umrissen wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le cours de gouvernement et de politique des USA 
du placement avancé par UCCP (AP) est une enquête d'un semestre de 
gouvernement américain et de politique couvrant la constitution, la 
croyance politique, les parties politiques, les groupes d'intérêt, 
les établissements du gouvernement, l'ordre public et les droits 
civiques. L'accent est mis sur des qualifications, l'écriture 
d'essai, et la traduction de pensée critiques et évaluatives des 
documents initiaux. Ce programme d'études couvre tout le 
matériel tracé les grandes lignes par le conseil d'université selon
les besoins pour vous préparer passer l'examen de gouvernement et de 
politique des USA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O curso avançado UCCP do governo e da política 
dos E. U. da colocação (AP) é um exame de um semester do governo 
americano e da política que cobrem o constitution, a opinião 
política, os partidos políticos, os grupos de interesse, as 
instituições do governo, a política pública e as direitas civis. 
A ênfase é colocada em habilidades, na escrita do essay, e na 
interpretação pensando críticas e evaluativas de originais 
originais. Este curriculum cobre todo o material esboçado pela 
placa de faculdade como necessário prepará-lo para passar o exam do 
governo e da política dos E. U..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il UCCP ha avanzato il governo degli Stati Uniti 
di disposizione (AP) ed il corso di politica è un'indagine di un 
semestre del governo americano e della politica che riguardano la 
costituzione, la credenza politica, i partiti politici, i gruppi di 
interesse comune, le istituzioni del governo, la politica pubblica ed 
i diritti civili. È messo in evidenza le abilità, la scrittura
di saggio e l'interpretazione pensanti critiche e valutative dei 
documenti originali. Questo programma di studi tratta tutto il 
materiale descritto dal Bordo dell'università come necessario 
prepararli per passare il exam di governo e di politica degli Stati 
Uniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το UCCP προώθησε την κυβέρνηση τοποθέτησης (AP) 
ΗΠΑ και η σειρά μαθημάτων πολιτικής είναι μια έρευνα ενός 
εξαμήνου για την αμερικανικές κυβέρνηση και την πολιτική που 
καλύπτουν το σύνταγμα, πολιτικές πεποιθήσεις, πολιτικά κόμματα, 
ομάδες ενδιαφέροντος, όργανα της κυβέρνησης, της δημόσιας
πολιτικής και των αστικών δικαιωμάτων. Έμφαση δίνεται στις 
κρίσιμες και αξιολογικές δεξιότητες σκέψης, το δοκίμιο 
γράφοντας, και την ερμηνεία των αρχικών εγγράφων. Αυτό το 
πρόγραμμα σπουδών καλύπτει όλο το υλικό που περιγράφεται από 
τον πίνακα κολλεγίου για να σας προετοιμάσει ανάλογα με τις 
ανάγκες για να περάσει το διαγωνισμό αμερικανικών κυβέρνησης και 
πολιτικής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El curso avanzado UCCP del gobierno y de la 
política de los E.E.U.U. de la colocación (AP) es una encuesta sobre
un semestre del gobierno americano y de la política que cubren la 
constitución, la creencia política, los partidos políticos, los 
grupos de interés, las instituciones del gobierno, el orden público 
y las derechas civiles. El énfasis se pone en habilidades, la 
escritura del ensayo, y la interpretación de pensamiento críticas y 
evaluativas de documentos originales. Este plan de estudios 
cubre todo el material contorneado por la tarjeta de universidad como 
necesaria para prepararle para aprobar el examen del gobierno y de la 
política de los E.E.U.U..</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNKNOWN
FN:UNKNOWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>813092637</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108002</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ap-us-government-politics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
