<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106527</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106527</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206278</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Division of Educational Programs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abteilung der pädagogischen Programme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Division des programmes éducatifs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Divisão de programas educacionais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Divisione dei programmi educativi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τμήμα των εκπαιδευτικών προγραμμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">División de programas educativos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the place to apply for research participation programs at Argonne as well as 18 other Department of Energy facilities. The site has information on the Laboratory's many other educational programs, including the National Neutron and X-Ray School, Nuclear Science and Technology Graduate Programs, National and International programs, and pre- and post-college programs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist der Platz, zum Forschung Teilnahmeprogramme bei
Argonne sowie 18 anderer Abteilung der Energieteildienste zu 
beantragen. Die Site hat Informationen über viele andere 
pädagogische Programme des Labors, einschließlich die nationale 
Neutron-und Röntgenstrahl-Schule, die Kernwissenschaft und 
Technologie-graduierten Programm-, nationale und 
internationaleprogramme und vor und Pfosten-Hochschuleprogramme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est l'endroit pour appliquer pour des programmes de
participation de recherches chez Argonne aussi bien que 18 l'autre 
ministère de l'énergie des équipements. Le site a 
l'information sur beaucoup d'autres programmes éducatifs du 
laboratoire, y compris l'école nationale de neutron et de rayon X, 
des programmes de programmes de la Science et de technologie, 
nationaux et internationaux gradués nucléaires, et des programmes 
pré et de poteau-université.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o lugar para aplicar para programas da 
participação da pesquisa em Argonne as.well.as 18 o outro 
departamento de facilidades da energia. O local tem a 
informação em muitos outros programas educacionais do laboratório, 
including a escola nacional do nêutron e do raio X, programas 
graduados nucleares dos programas da ciência e da tecnologia, os 
nacionais e os internacionais, e programas pre- e da borne-faculdade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il posto per fare domanda per i programmi di 
partecipazione di ricerca a Argonne così come 18 l'altro Dipartimento
per l'energia le attrezzature. Il luogo ha informazioni su molti
altri programmi educativi del laboratorio, compreso la scuola 
nazionale dei raggi X e del neutrone, i programmi nazionali ed 
internazionali laureati nucleari di programmi di tecnologia e di 
scienza, e programmi dell'alberino-università e pre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι η θέση για να ισχύσει για τα προγράμματα 
ερευνητικής συμμετοχής σε Argonne καθώς επίσης και 18 άλλες
εγκαταστάσεις τμήματος ενέργειας. Η περιοχή έχει τις 
πληροφορίες για τα εργαστηριακά πολλά άλλα εκπαιδευτικά 
προγράμματα, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του εθνικού νετρονίου και του των
ακτίνων X σχολείου, των πυρηνικών διαβαθμισμένων προγραμμάτων 
επιστήμης και τεχνολογίας, των εθνικών και διεθνών προγραμμάτων, 
και προ - και μετα-κολλεγίων προγράμματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el lugar para solicitar programas de la 
participación de la investigación en Argonne así como 18 el otro 
Ministerio de recursos de la Energía. El sitio tiene 
información sobre muchos otros programas educativos del laboratorio, 
incluyendo la escuela nacional del neutrón y de la radiografía, 
programas graduados nucleares de los programas de la ciencia y de la 
tecnología, nacionales e internacionales, y los programas pre y de la
poste-universidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206278</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106527</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/division-of-educational-programs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
