<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108039</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108039</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086472</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Metacom Relates Indian Complaints about the English Settlers, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Metacom steht indische Beanstandungen über die 
englischen Siedleren, 1675 in Verbindung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Metacom associe les plaintes indiennes au sujet des
colons anglais, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Metacom relaciona as queixas indian sobre os 
settlers ingleses, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Metacom collega i reclami indiani circa i settlers 
inglesi, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Metacom αφορά τις ινδικές καταγγελίες για τους 
αγγλικούς αποίκους, 1675</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Metacom relaciona las quejas indias sobre los 
colonos ingleses, 1675</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Metacom or King Philip, leader of the Wampanoags near Plymouth colony, led many other Indians into a widespread revolt against the colonists of southern New England in 1675. The conflict had been brewing for some time over a set of longstanding grievances between Europeans and Indians. In that tense atmosphere, John Easton, Attorney General of the Rhode Island colony, met Philip in June of 1675 in an effort to negotiate a settlement. Easton recorded Philip's complaints, including the steady loss of Wampanoag land to the Europeans; the English colonists' growing herds of cattle and their destruction of Indian crops; and the unequal justice Indians received in the English courts. This meeting between Easton and Metacom proved futile, however, and the war (which became the bloodiest in U.S. history relative to the size of the population) began late that month.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Metacom oder König Philip, Führer des Wampanoags
nahe Plymouth Kolonie, führten viele andere Inder in einen 
weitverbreiteten Aufruhr gegen die Kolonisten von Südneu-England 
1675. Die $überschneidung hatte für irgendeinen 
Zeitüberschuß ein Set althergebrachte Beschwerden zwischen 
Europäern und Indern gebraut. In dieser angespannten 
Atmosphäre traf John Easton, Generalstaatsanwalt der Rhode-Insel 
Kolonie, Philip im Juni von 1675 in einer Bemühung, über eine 
Regelung zu verhandeln. Easton speicherte Beanstandungen 
Philips, einschließlich den unveränderlichen Verlust des Wampanoag 
Landes zu den Europäern; die englischen wachsenden Herden der 
Kolonisten des Viehs und ihre Zerstörung der indischen Getreide; 
und die ungleichen Gerechtigkeit Inder empfangen in den 
englischen Gerichten. Diese Sitzung zwischen Easton und Metacom 
prüfte, daß vergeblich, jedoch und der Krieg (welches in der 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte im Verhältnis zu der Größe der 
Bevölkerung das blutigste wurde), spät diesen Monat anfing.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Metacom ou roi Philip, amorce du Wampanoags 
près de la colonie de Plymouth, a mené beaucoup d'autres Indiens 
dans une révolte répandue contre les colons de la Nouvelle 
Angleterre méridionale en 1675. Le conflit avait brassé 
pendant un certain temps excédent un ensemble de réclamations de 
longue date entre Européens et Indiens. En cette atmosphère 
tendue, John Easton, général de mandataire de la colonie 
d'île de Rhode, a rencontré Philip en juin de 1675 dans un effort 
de négocier un règlement. Easton a enregistré les plaintes de
Philip, y compris la perte régulière de terre de Wampanoag aux 
Européens ; les troupeaux grandissants des colons anglais de 
bétail et leur destruction des collectes indiennes ; et les 
Indiens inégaux de justice reçus dans les cours anglaises. 
Cette réunion entre Easton et Metacom s'est avérée que 
futile, cependant, et la guerre (ce qui est devenue la plus sanglante 
dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS relativement à la taille de la 
population) a commencé tard ce mois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Metacom ou o rei Philip, líder do Wampanoags 
perto da colônia de Plymouth, conduziram a muitos outros indians em 
uma revolta difundida de encontro aos colonos de Nova Inglaterra do 
sul em 1675. O conflito brewing para algum excesso do tempo um 
jogo de queixas longstanding entre Europeus e indians. Nessa 
atmosfera tensa, John Easton, general de advogado da colônia do 
console de Rhode, encontrou-se com Philip em junho de 1675 em um 
esforço negociar um estabelecimento. Easton gravou queixas de 
Philip, including a perda constante da terra de Wampanoag aos 
Europeus; os rebanhos crescentes dos colonos ingleses do gado e 
sua destruição de colheitas indian; e os indians desiguais da 
justiça recebidos nas cortes inglesas. Esta reunião entre 
Easton e Metacom provou que futile, entretanto, e a guerra (qual se 
transformou a mais sangrenta no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS relativo ao 
tamanho da população) começou tarde esse mês.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Metacom o il re Philip, capo del Wampanoags
vicino alla colonia della Plymouth, ha condotto molti altri indiani in
una sommossa diffusa contro i colonizzatori della Nuova Inghilterra 
del sud in 1675. Il conflitto stava fermentando per un certo 
tempo eccedenza un insieme delle rimostranze di vecchia data fra 
Europei e gli indiani. In quell'atmosfera teso, John Easton, 
General di avvocato della colonia dell'Rhode-isola, ha venuto a 
contatto di Philip in giugno di 1675 in uno sforzo negoziare uno 
stabilimento. Easton ha registrato i reclami del Philip, 
compreso la perdita costante della terra di Wampanoag agli Europei; 
le greggi crescenti dei colonizzatori inglesi dei bestiami e la 
loro distruzione dei raccolti indiani; e gli indiani disuguali 
della giustizia ricevuti nelle corti inglesi. Questa riunione 
fra Easton e Metacom è risultato che inutile, tuttavia e la guerra 
(quale si è transformata in nel più sanguinante nella storia degli 
STATI UNITI riguardante il formato della popolazione) ha cominciato in
ritardo quel mese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Metacom ή ο βασιλιάς Philip, ηγέτης του 
Wampanoags κοντά στην αποικία του Πλύμουθ, οδήγησε πολλούς 
άλλους Ινδούς σε μια διαδεδομένη επανάσταση ενάντια στους 
αποίκους της νότιας Νέας Αγγλίας το 1675. Η σύγκρουση 
παρασκεύαζε για κάποιο χρόνο πέρα από ένα σύνολο από μακρού 
υφιστάμενων διαμαρτυριών μεταξύ των Ευρωπαίων και Ινδών. Σε
εκείνη την ανήσυχη ατμόσφαιρα, John Easton, γενικός 
εισαγγελέας της αποικίας της Ρόδου, συνάντησε τον Philip τον 
Ιούνιο 1675 σε μια προσπάθεια να συζητηθεί μια τακτοποίηση. 
Το Easton κατέγραψε τις καταγγελίες του Philip, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της σταθερής απώλειας εδάφους Wampanoag 
στους Ευρωπαίους  τα αυξανόμενα κοπάδια των αγγλικών 
αποίκων των βοοειδών και η καταστροφή ινδικών συγκομιδών τους  
και η άνιση δικαιοσύνη Ινδοί έλαβε στα αγγλικά δικαστήρια.
Αυτή η συνεδρίαση μεταξύ Easton και Metacom 
αποδεδειγμένου ανώφελων, εντούτοις, και ο πόλεμος (που έγιναν οι 
πιό αιματηροί στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία σχετικά με το μέγεθος του 
πληθυσμού) άρχισαν αργά εκείνο τον μήνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Metacom o rey Philip, arranque de cinta del 
Wampanoags cerca de la colonia de Plymouth, condujo a muchos otros 
indios en una rebelión extensa contra los colonos de Nueva Inglaterra
meridional en 1675. El conflicto había estado elaborando 
cerveza para un cierto excedente del tiempo un conjunto de agravios de
muchos años entre europeos y los indios. En esa atmósfera 
tensa, Juan Easton, general de abogado de la colonia de la Rhode-isla,
resolvió Philip en junio de 1675 en un esfuerzo de negociar un 
establecimiento. Easton registró las quejas de Philip, 
incluyendo la pérdida constante de pista de Wampanoag a los europeos;
las manadas crecientes de los colonos ingleses de ganados y su 
destrucción de cosechas indias; y los indios desiguales de la 
justicia recibidos en las cortes inglesas. Esta reunión entre 
Easton y Metacom probó que vano, sin embargo, y la guerra (cuál se 
convirtió en la más sangrienta de la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
concerniente a la talla de la población) comenzó tarde ese mes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086472</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108039</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/metacom-relates-indian-complaints-about-the-english-settlers-1675</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
