<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108535</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108535</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205685</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hawthorne in Salem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hawthorne in Salem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hawthorne à Salem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hawthorne em Salem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hawthorne a Salem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Hawthorne στο Σάλεμ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hawthorne en Salem</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores Nathaniel Hawthorne's connection to Salem, Massachusetts, with a primary focus on the Custom House sketch, the first chapter of The Scarlet Letter. The site also presents materials from museums in Salem, as well as lectures and excerpts from books and articles by leading Hawthorne scholars.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht Nathaniel Hawthornes Anschluß nach 
Salem, Massachusetts, mit einem Primärfokus auf der Zollamtskizze, 
das erste Kapitel des Scarlet-Zeichens. Die Site stellt auch 
Materialien von den Museen in Salem, sowie Vorträge und Excerpts von 
den Büchern und von den Artikeln dar, indem sie Hawthorne Gelehrte 
führt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore la correspondance de Nathaniel Hawthorne 
vers Salem, le Massachusetts, avec un foyer primaire sur le croquis de
bureau de douane, le premier chapitre de la lettre d'écarlate. 
Le site présente également des matériaux des musées à 
Salem, aussi bien que des conférences et des extraits des livres et 
des articles en menant des disciples de Hawthorne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora a conexão de Nathaniel Hawthorne a Salem,
Massachusetts, com um foco preliminar no esboço da casa feita sob 
encomenda, o primeiro capítulo da letra do scarlet. O local 
apresenta também materiais dos museus em Salem, as.well.as lectures e
excerpts dos livros e dos artigos conduzindo a scholars de Hawthorne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora il collegamento di Nathaniel Hawthorne a 
Salem, Massachusetts, con un fuoco primario sull'abbozzo della Camera 
su ordinazione, il primo capitolo della lettera di scarlet. Il 
luogo egualmente presenta i materiali dai musei a Salem, così come le
conferenze ed i brani dai libri e dagli articoli conducendo gli 
eruditi di Hawthorne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά τη σύνδεση Nathaniel Hawthorne στο Σάλεμ, 
Μασαχουσέτη, με μια αρχική εστίαση στο σκίτσο σπιτιών συνήθειας,
το πρώτο κεφάλαιο της ερυθράς επιστολής. Η περιοχή 
παρουσιάζει επίσης τα υλικά από τα μουσεία στο Σάλεμ, καθώς 
επίσης και τις διαλέξεις και τα αποσπάσματα από τα βιβλία και τα 
άρθρα με την οδήγηση των μελετητών Hawthorne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora la conexión de Nathaniel Hawthorne a 
Salem, Massachusetts, con un foco primario en el bosquejo de la casa 
de encargo, el primer capítulo de la carta del escarlata. El 
sitio también presenta los materiales de museos en Salem, así como 
conferencias y extractos de los libros y de los artículos conduciendo
a eruditos de Hawthorne.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205685</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108535</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hawthorne-in-salem</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
