<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105746</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105746</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Hispano Ranchos of Northern New Mexico: Continuity and Change</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Hispano Ranchs von Nordnew-Mexico: 
Durchgang und Änderung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les ranchos de Hispano du Nouveau-Mexique nordique 
: Continuité et changement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os ranchos de Hispano de Novo México do norte: 
Continuidade e mudança</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I ranchi di Hispano del Nuovo Messico del Nord: 
Continuità e cambiamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ranchos Hispano του βόρειου New Mexico: 
Συνοχή και αλλαγή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los ranchos de Hispano de New México norteño: 
Continuidad y cambio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features the small subsistence farms, or ranchos, created by Hispanos, early Spanish settlers of New Mexico, during the 1800s in the mountain valleys of the Pecos and Mora rivers. Houses were built from the same adobe used to construct Indian pueblos and Spanish missions, with decorative details added based on architectural fashions brought to New Mexico after it became a U.S. territory in 1851. Irrigation ditches were dug and regulated by rules dating back centuries.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet die kleinen Erwerbsmittelbauernhöfe 
oder die Ranchs, hergestellt von Hispanos, frühe spanische Siedleren 
von New-Mexico, während des 1800s in den Gebirgssenken der Pecos und 
Mora Flüsse. Häuser wurden vom gleichen luftgetrockneten 
Ziegelstein aufgebaut, der benutzt wurde, um indische Pueblos zu 
konstruieren und spanische Missionen, wenn die dekorativen Details 
hinzugefügt auf architektonischer Art und Weise basiert sind, holten 
nach New-Mexico, nachdem es eine VEREINIGTE STAATEN Gegend 1851 wurde.
Bewässerungabzugsgräben wurden bis zum Richtlinien 
zurückgehenden Jahrhunderten gegraben und geregelt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte les petites fermes de subsistance, ou des
ranchos, créés par Hispanos, de premiers colons espagnols du nouveau
Mexique, pendant le 1800s dans les vallées de montagne des fleuves de
Pecos et de Mora. Des Chambres ont été construites du même 
adobe employé pour construire les pueblos indiens et les missions 
espagnoles, avec les détails décoratifs ajoutés basés sur des 
modes architecturales ont apporté au Nouveau-Mexique après que ce 
soit devenu un territoire des ETATS-UNIS en 1851. Des fossés 
d'irrigation ont été creusés et réglés par des siècles 
remontants à de règles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza as fazendas pequenas do subsistence, 
ou os ranchos, criados por Hispanos, settlers espanhóis adiantados de
Novo México, durante o 1800s nos vales da montanha dos rios de Pecos 
e de Mora. As casas foram construídas do mesmo adôbe usado 
construir povoados indíginos indian e as missões espanholas, com os 
detalhes decorativos adicionados baseados em formas architectural 
trouxeram a Novo México depois que se transformou um território de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS em 1851. As valas da irrigação foram escavadas 
e reguladas pelas réguas que datam séculos traseiros.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza i piccoli poderi di sussistenza, o 
ranchi, creati da Hispanos, settlers spagnoli in anticipo del Nuovo 
Messico, durante il 1800s nelle valli della montagna dei fiumi di Mora
e di Pecos. Le Camere sono state costruite dallo stesso adobe 
usato per costruire i pueblos indiani e le missioni spagnole, con i 
particolari decorativi aggiunti basati sulle mode architettoniche 
hanno portato nel Nuovo Messico dopo che si transformasse in in un 
territorio degli STATI UNITI in 1851. Le fosse di irrigazione 
sono state scavate e regolato state dalle regole che datano i secoli 
posteriori.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τα μικρά αγροκτήματα επιβίωσης, ή 
ranchos, που δημιουργούνται από Hispanos, τους πρώτους 
ισπανικούς αποίκους του New Mexico, κατά τη διάρκεια του 
1800s στις κοιλάδες βουνών των ΧΚΑΕ και των ποταμών Mora. 
Τα σπίτια χτίστηκαν από την ίδια πλίθα που χρησιμοποιήθηκε
για να κατασκευάσει τα ινδικά pueblos και οι ισπανικές 
αποστολές, με τις διακοσμητικές λεπτομέρειες που προστέθηκαν 
βασισμένες στις αρχιτεκτονικές μόδες που παρουσιάστηκαν στο New
Mexico αφότου έγινε μια ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ περιοχή σε 1851, τάφρους
άρδευσης σκάφτηκαν και ρυθμίστηκαν από τους κανόνες 
χρονολογώντας τους πίσω αιώνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece las granjas pequeñas de la subsistencia, o
los ranchos, creados por Hispanos, los colonos españoles tempranos de
New México, durante el 1800s en los valles de la montaña de los 
ríos de Pecos y de Mora. Las casas fueron construidas del mismo
adobe usado para construir pueblos indios y las misiones españolas, 
con los detalles decorativos agregados basados en maneras 
arquitectónicas trajeron a New México después de que se convirtió 
en un territorio de ESTADOS UNIDOS en 1851. Las zanjas de la 
irrigación fueron cavadas y reguladas por las reglas que fechaban 
siglos posteriores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105746</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-hispano-ranchos-of-northern-new-mexico-continuity-and-change</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
