<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107889</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107889</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086260</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Huey Long Is a Superman": Gerald L. K. Smith Defends the Kingfish</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"langes Huey ist ein Superman": Gerald L. K.
Smith Defends der Kingfish</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Huey long est Superman" : Gerald L. K. 
Smith Defends la Sériole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Huey longo é um superman": Gerald L. K. 
Smith Defender o kingfish</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Huey lungo è un superman": Gerald L. K. 
Smith Defends il kingfish</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Huey μακρύ είναι υπεράνθρωποσ": Ο Gerald 
L. Κ. Smith υπερασπίζει το σκουμπρί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Huey largo es un Superhombre": Gerald L. K. 
Smith Defends el kingfish</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Huey Long, elected Governor of Louisiana in 1928 and U.S. Senator in 1930, ruled Louisiana as a virtual dictator, but he also initiated massive public works programs, improved public education and public health, and even established some restrictions on corporate power in the state. While Long was an early supporter of President Roosevelt, by the fall of 1933 the Long-Roosevelt alliance had ruptured, in part over Long's growing interest in running for president. In 1934 Long organized his own, alternative political organization, the Share-Our-Wealth Society, through which he advocated a populist program for redistributing wealth through sharply graduated income and inheritance taxes. Hodding Carter, the liberal editor of the  Daily Courier  in his hometown of Hammond, Louisiana, however, repeatedly warned against Long's corruption and demagoguery. When the  New Republic  published an attack on Long by Carter, it also ran this strong defense by one of Long's closest associates, Gerald L. K. Smith.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Huey sehnen sich, gewählt Gouverneur von 
Louisiana 1928 und VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senator 1930, angeordnetes 
Louisiana als virtueller Diktator, aber er initialisiert auch massive 
Arbeitenprogramme, verbessertes Unterrichtswesen und öffentliches 
Gesundheitswesen, und sogar hergestellt einigen Beschränkungen auf 
korporativer Energie im Zustand. Wenn war ein früher Verfechter
des Präsidenten Roosevelt, bis zum dem Fall von 1933, die das 
Lange-Roosevelt Bündnis gebrochen hatte, im Teilüberschuß lang, 
der, lang Interesse wächst, an, für Präsidenten zu laufen. In
1934 lang organisiert seine Selbst, alternative politische 
Organisation, die Anteil-Unser-Fülle Gesellschaft, durch die er ein 
Volksprogramm für das Neuverteilen von von Fülle durch scharf 
graduiertes Einkommen und Erbschaftssteuern befürwortete. 
Hodding Carter, der liberale Herausgeber des täglichen Eilboten
in seiner Heimatstadt von Hammond, Louisiana jedoch wiederholt gewarnt
gegen lange Korruption und Demagogie. Als die neue Republik 
einen Angriff auf langem durch Carter veröffentlichte, ließ es auch 
diese starke Verteidigung durch einen von langen nähsten Teilnehmern,
Gerald L. K. Smith laufen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Huey désirent ardemment, élu gouverneur de la 
Louisiane en 1928 et sénateur des ETATS-UNIS en 1930, Louisiane 
régnée en tant que dictateur virtuel, mais il lance également des 
programmes massifs de travaux publics, l'éducation publique 
améliorée et la santé publique, et même établi quelques 
restrictions à la puissance de corporation dans l'état. Tandis
que long était un défenseur tôt du Président Roosevelt, par la 
chute de 1933 que la Longue-Roosevelt alliance s'était rompue, dans 
l'excédent de partie accroissant longtemps l'intérêt pour 
l'exécution pour le président. Dans 1934 longtemps organisés 
ses propres, organisation politique alternative, la société de 
Part-Notre-Richesse, par laquelle il a préconisé un programme 
populiste pour redistribuer la richesse par le revenu et les impôts 
sur les successions brusquement reçus un diplôme. Hodding 
Charretier, l'éditeur libéral du courier quotidien à sa ville 
natale de Hammond, Louisiane, cependant, à plusieurs reprises mise en
garde contre la longues corruption et démagogie. Quand la 
nouvelle République a édité une attaque sur long par Charretier, il
a également exécuté cette défense forte par un de longs associés 
les plus étroits, Gerald L. K. Smith.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Huey long, eleito regulador de Louisiana em 1928 e
senator em 1930, Louisiana governado de ESTADOS UNIDOS como um ditador
virtual, mas inicía também programas de trabalhos públicos 
maciços, a instrução pública melhorada e a saúde pública, e 
estabelecido mesmo algumas limitações na potência incorporada no 
estado. Quando longo era um supporter adiantado do presidente 
Roosevelt, pela queda de 1933 que o alliance Longo-Roosevelt tinha 
rompido, no excesso da parte que cresce por muito tempo o interesse em
funcionar para o presidente. Em 1934 organizados por muito tempo
seus próprios, organização política alternativa, sociedade da 
Parte-Nosso-Riqueza, através de que advogou um programa populist para
redistributing a riqueza com os impostos agudamente graduados da renda
e de inheritance. Hodding Carter, o editor liberal do correio 
diário em seu hometown de Hammond, Louisiana, entretanto, advertido 
repetidamente de encontro ao corruption e ao demagoguery longos. 
Quando a república nova publicou um ataque em longo por Carter,
funcionou também esta defesa forte por um de associados os mais 
próximos longos, Gerald L. K. Smith.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Huey desidera, scelto regolatore della Luisiana in
1928 e senatore in 1930, Luisiana regolata degli STATI UNITI come 
dictator virtuale, ma egualmente inizia i programmi voluminosi di 
lavori pubblici, la formazione pubblica migliorata e la sanità 
pubblica e perfino stabilito alcune limitazioni su potenza corporativa
nel dichiarare. Mentre lungo era un sostenitore in anticipo del
presidente Roosevelt, entro la caduta di 1933 che l'alleanza 
Lunga-Roosevelt si era rotta, nell'eccedenza della parte lungamente 
che sviluppa l'interesse nel funzionare per il presidente. In 
1934 lungamente organizzati il suoi propri, organizzazione politica 
alternativa, la società di Parte-Nostro-Ricchezza, attraverso cui ha 
sostenuto un programma populistico per la ridistribuzione della 
ricchezza con reddito e le tasse di successione acutamente laureati. 
Hodding Carter, l'editore liberale del corriere quotidiano a suo
hometown di Hammond, Luisiana, tuttavia, ha messo in guardia 
ripetutamente contro la corruzione ed il demagoguery lunghi. 
Quando la nuova Repubblica ha pubblicato un attacco a lungo da 
Carter, egualmente ha fatto funzionare questa difesa forte da uno dei 
soci i più vicini lunghi, Gerald L. K. Smith.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Huey μακρύ, εκλεγμένος τον κυβερνήτη της 
Λουιζιάνας το 1928 και τον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ γερουσιαστή το 1930, 
κυβέρνησε τη Λουιζιάνα ως εικονικό δικτάτορα, αλλά άρχισε 
επίσης τα ογκώδη προγράμματα δημόσιων έργων, τη βελτιωμένες 
δημόσιες εκπαίδευση και δημόσια την υγεία, και ακόμη και 
καθιερωμένος μερικούς περιορισμούς στην εταιρική δύναμη στο 
κράτος. Ενώ πολύ ήταν πρώτος υποστηρικτής του Προέδρου 
Roosevelt, από το φθινόπωρο του 1933 η συμμαχία μακρύς- 
Roosevelt είχε σπάσει, εν μέρει πέρα από το μακροχρόνιο 
αυξανόμενο ενδιαφέρον για το τρέξιμο για τον Πρόεδρο. Το 
1934 πολύ οργανωμένος δικοί δικοί του, εναλλακτική πολιτική 
οργάνωση, η κοινωνία μερίδιο-μας-πλούτου, μέσω της οποίας 
υποστήριξε ένα λαϊκιστικό πρόγραμμα για τον πλούτο μέσω των 
αισθητά βαθμολογημένων φόρων εισοδήματος και κληρονομιάς. Hodding Carter, ο φιλελεύθερος επεξεργαστής του καθημερινού 
αγγελιαφόρου στο hometown Hammond του, Λουιζιάνα, εντούτοις, 
που προειδοποιείται επανειλημμένα ενάντια στη μακροχρόνιες 
δωροδοκία και τη δημαγωγία. Όταν η νέα Δημοκρατία 
δημοσίευσε μια επίθεση επάνω μακροχρόνια από Carter, έτρεξε 
επίσης αυτήν την ισχυρή υπεράσπιση από έναν από τους πολύ πιό
στενούς συνεταίρους, Gerald L. Κ. Smith.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Huey desea, elegido gobernador de Luisiana en 1928
y senador en 1930, Luisiana gobernada de ESTADOS UNIDOS como dictador 
virtual, pero él también inició programas de trabajos públicos 
masivos, la educación pública mejorada y la salud pública, e 
incluso establecido algunas restricciones en potencia corporativa en 
el estado. Mientras que es largo era un partidario temprano de 
presidente Roosevelt, por la caída de 1933 que la alianza 
Larga-Roosevelt había roto, en el excedente de la parte que crecía 
de largo interés en ejecutarse para el presidente. En 1934 de 
largo ordenados sus el propios, organización política alternativa, 
la sociedad de la Parte-Nuestro-Abundancia, a través de quien él 
abogó un programa populista para redistribuir abundancia con 
impuestos sostenidamente graduados de la renta y de herencia. 
Hodding Carretero, el editor liberal del mensajero diario en su 
ciudad natal de Hammond, Luisiana, sin embargo, advertida en varias 
ocasiones contra la corrupción y el demagoguery largos. Cuando 
la nueva república publicó un ataque contra largo de Carretero, 
también ejecutó esta defensa fuerte por uno de asociados más 
cercanos largos, Gerald L. K. Smith.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086260</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107889</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/huey-long-is-a-superman-gerald-l-k-smith-defends-the-kingfish</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
