<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106280</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106280</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087229</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">When Racism Was Respectable: Franz Boas on "The Instability of Human Types"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als Rassismus Beachtlich War: Franz Boas auf
"der Instabilität der menschlichen Typen"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand Le Racisme Était Respectable : Boas 
de Franz sur "l'instabilité des types humains"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando O Racism Era Respeitável: Boas de 
Franz "na instabilidade de tipos humanos"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando Il Razzismo Era Respectable: Boa di 
Franz "sull'instabilità dei tipi umani"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν ο ρατσισμός ήταν αξιοσέβαστος: Θ*Φρανζ 
Boas "στην αστάθεια των ανθρώπινων τύπων"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando El Racismo Era Respetable: Boas de 
Franz en "la inestabilidad de tipos humanos"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Racism remained potent in the 1920s, but ideas about race were changing, particularly among intellectuals. Almost without exception, social scientists and scholars in the 1890s assumed that race was one of the central ways of understanding human beings. But a profound change in American thinking occurred in the first two decades of the 20th century. A new philosophy, that today might be termed "cultural relativism," began to influence American intellectuals and their students. The emergence of this philosophy in the U.S. owes a great deal to Franz Boas, a German-Jewish anthropologist who taught at Columbia University from 1896 through the 1930s. In this essay, "The Instability of Human Types," delivered at an academic conference on race in 1911, Boas boldly argued against assumptions of innate racial inferiority; insisting that culture, not nature, explained differences among the people of the world. Boas's students included the anthropologist Margaret Mead and the writer Zora Neale Hurston.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rassismus blieb in den zwanziger Jahren stark, 
aber Ideen über Rennen änderten, besonders unter Intellektuellen. 
Fast ohne Ausnahme, nahmen Sozialwissenschaftler und Gelehrte im
1890s an, daß Rennen eine der zentralen Methoden des Verstehens der 
Menschen war. Aber eine profunde Änderung im amerikanischen 
Denken trat in den ersten zwei Dekaden des 20. Jahrhunderts ein. 
Eine neue Philosophie, die konnte heute benannt werden 
"kulturelles relativism," fing an, amerikanische Intellektuelle und 
ihre Kursteilnehmer zu beeinflussen. Das Hervortreten dieser 
Philosophie in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN verdankt sehr viel Franz Boas, 
ein Deutsch-Jüdischer Anthropologe, der an der Kolumbien Universität
von 1896 durch die dreißiger Jahre unterrichtete. In diesem 
Versuch "die Instabilität der menschlichen Typen," lieferte bei einer
akademischen Konferenz auf Rennen 1911, die Boas, die mutig gegen 
Annahmen der angeborenen rassischen Unterlegenheit argumentiert 
wurden; diese Kultur beharrend, erklärte nicht, Natur, 
Unterschiede unter den Leuten der Welt. Kursteilnehmer der Boas 
enthielten den Anthropologen Margaret Mead und den Verfasser Zora 
Neale Hurston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le racisme est demeuré efficace dans les années 
20, mais les idées au sujet de la course changeaient, en particulier 
parmi des intellectuels. Presque sans exception, les sociologues
et les disciples dans le 1890s ont supposé que la course était l'une
des voies centrales des êtres humains d'arrangement. Mais un 
changement profond de la pensée américaine s'est produit dans les 
deux premières décennies du 20ème siècle. Une nouvelle 
philosophie, celle aujourd'hui pourrait se nommer "relativisme 
culturel," a commencé à influencer les intellectuels américains et 
leurs étudiants. L'apparition de cette philosophie aux 
ETATS-UNIS doit beaucoup aux boas de Franz, un anthropologue 
Allemand-Juif qui a enseigné à l'université de Colombie de 1896 par
les années 30. Dans cet essai, "l'instabilité des types 
humains," a livré à une conférence d'universitaire sur la course en 
1911, boas gras discutés contre des acceptations d'infériorité 
raciale innée ; exigeant cette culture, pas la nature, a 
expliqué des différences parmi les personnes du monde. Les 
étudiants des boas ont inclus l'anthropologue Margaret Mead
et l'auteur Zora Neale Hurston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O racism remanesceu potent nos 1920s, mas as 
idéias sobre a raça estavam mudando, particularmente entre 
intelectuais. Quase sem exceção, os cientistas sociais e os 
scholars no 1890s supuseram que a raça era uma das maneiras centrais 
de compreender seres humanos. Mas uma mudança profunda em 
pensar americano ocorreu nas primeiras duas décadas do 20o século. 
Uma filosofia nova, aquela hoje pôde ser denominada "relativism
cultural," começou a influenciar intelectuais americanos e seus 
estudantes. O emergence desta filosofia nos ESTADOS UNIDOS deve 
bastante às boas de Franz, um antropólogo Alemão-german-Jewish que 
ensine na universidade de Colômbia de 1896 com os 1930s. Neste 
essay, "a instabilidade de tipos humanos," entregou em uma 
conferência academic sobre a raça em 1911, boas discutidas 
corajosamente de encontro às suposições do inferiority racial 
innate; insistindo essa cultura, não a natureza, explicou 
diferenças entre os povos do mundo. Os estudantes das boas 
incluíram o antropólogo Margaret Mead e o escritor Zora Neale 
Hurston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il razzismo è rimasto potente negli anni 20, ma 
le idee circa la corsa stavano cambiando, specialmente fra gli 
intellettuali. Quasi senza eccezione, i sociologi e gli eruditi 
nel 1890s hanno supposto che la corsa era uno dei modi centrali di 
capire gli esseri umani. Ma un cambiamento profondo nel pensare 
americano si è presentato nelle prime due decadi del ventesimo 
secolo. Una nuova filosofia, quella oggi potrebbe essere 
chiamata "relativism culturale," ha cominciato ad influenzare gli 
intellettuali americani ed i loro allievi. L'emersione di questa
filosofia negli STATI UNITI deve molto ai boa di Franz, un antropologo
Tedesco-Ebreo che ha insegnato all'università della Colombia da 1896 
con i 1930s. In questo saggio, "l'instabilità dei tipi umani," 
ha trasportato ad un congresso accademico sulla corsa in 1911, boa 
discussi GRASSETTO contro i presupposti del inferiority razziale 
innato; insistendo quella coltura, non la natura, ha spiegato le
differenze fra la gente del mondo. Gli allievi dei boa hanno 
incluso l'antropologo Margaret Mead ed il produttore Zora Neale 
Hurston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ρατσισμός παρέμεινε ισχυρός στη δεκαετία του '20, 
αλλά οι ιδέες για τη φυλή άλλαζαν, ιδιαίτερα μεταξύ των 
διανοούμενων. Σχεδόν χωρίς εξαίρεση, οι κοινωνικοί 
επιστήμονες και οι μελετητές στο 1890s υπέθεσαν ότι η φυλή 
ήταν ένας από τους κεντρικούς τρόπους τα ανθρώπινα οντα. 
Αλλά μια βαθιά αλλαγή στην αμερικανική σκέψη εμφανισμένος 
στις πρώτες δύο δεκαετίες του 20ού αιώνα. Μια νέα 
φιλοσοφία, που σήμερα να κληθεί το "πολιτιστικό σχετικισμό," 
άρχισε να επηρεάζει τους αμερικανικούς διανοούμενους και τους 
σπουδαστές τους. Η εμφάνιση αυτής της φιλοσοφίας στις ΗΠΑ 
οφείλει πολλής στο Franz Boas, ένας γερμανικός-εβραϊκός 
ανθρωπολόγος που δίδαξε στο πανεπιστήμιο της Κολούμπια από 
1896 μέσω της δεκαετίας του '30. Σε αυτό το δοκίμιο, "η 
αστάθεια των ανθρώπινων τύπων," παραδοθείς σε μια ακαδημαϊκή 
διάσκεψη σχετικά με τη φυλή το 1911, boas θαρραλέα 
μιλημένος ενάντια στις υποθέσεις της έμφυτης φυλετικής 
κατωτερότητας  επιμένοντας ότι ο πολιτισμός, όχι φύση, 
εξήγησε τις διαφορές μεταξύ των ανθρώπων του κόσμου. Boas οι σπουδαστές περιέλαβαν τον ανθρωπολόγο Margaret 
Mead και το συγγραφέα Zora Neale Hurston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El racismo seguía siendo potente en los años 20,
pero las ideas sobre la raza cambiaban, determinado entre 
intelectuales. Casi sin la anomalía, los científicos sociales 
y los eruditos en el 1890s asumieron que la raza era una de las 
maneras centrales de entender seres humanos. Pero un cambio 
profundo en el pensamiento americano ocurrió en las primeras dos 
décadas del vigésimo siglo. Una nueva filosofía, de que hoy 
se pudo llamar "relativism cultural," comenzó a influenciar a 
intelectuales americanos y a sus estudiantes. La aparición de 
esta filosofía en los ESTADOS UNIDOS debe mucho a las boas de Franz, 
antropólogo Alema'n-Judi'o que enseñó en la universidad de Colombia
a partir del 1896 con los años 30. En este ensayo, "la 
inestabilidad de tipos humanos," entregó en una conferencia 
académica sobre la raza en 1911, boas discutidas audazmente contra 
asunciones de la inferioridad racial natural; insistiendo esa 
cultura, no la naturaleza, explicó diferencias entre la gente del 
mundo. Los estudiantes de las boas incluyeron al antropólogo 
Margaret Mead y a programa de escritura Zora Neale Hurston.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087229</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106280</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/when-racism-was-respectable-franz-boas-on-the-instability-of-human-types</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
