<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104513</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104513</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087499</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Communists are second to none in our devotion to our people and to our country": Prosecution and Defense Statements, 1949 Trial of American Communist Party Leaders</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Kommunisten sind an zweiter Stelle zu keinen in 
unserer Hingabe zu unseren Leuten und zu unserem Land": 
Verfolgung und Verteidigung Statements, Versuch 1949 von 
amerikanischen kommunistischen Partei-Führern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les "communistes sont en second lieu à aucun dans
notre dévotion à nos personnes et à notre pays" : Poursuite 
et défense Statements, épreuve 1949 d'amorces américaines de parti 
communiste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os "comunistas são em segundo a nenhuns em nossa 
devoção a nossos povos e a nosso país": Prosecution e defesa 
Indicação, experimentação 1949 de líderes americanos do partido 
comunista</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i comunisti sono in secondo luogo a nessun nella 
nostra devozione alla nostra gente ed al nostro paese": Processo
e difesa Statements, prova 1949 dei Capi americani del partito 
comunista</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι κομμουνιστές είναι δεύτεροι σε κανένας στην 
αφοσίωσή μας στους ανθρώπους μας και στη χώρα μασ": 
Δηλώσεις συνέχισης και υπεράσπισης, δίκη του 1949 των 
αμερικανικών κομμουνιστικών αρχηγών κόμματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los "comunistas están en segundo lugar a ningunos
en nuestra dedicación a nuestra gente y a nuestro país": 
Procesamiento y defensa Statements, ensayo 1949 de arranques de 
cinta americanos del partido comunista</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1919, during the post-World War I "Red Scare," the Supreme Court ruled that the First Amendment protection of free speech was not applicable in circumstances in which there was a "clear and present danger" that "substantive evils that Congress has a right to prevent" would occur as a result of that speech. In 1940, Congress passed the Smith Act, making illegal the advocacy of overthrowing state or national governments. Although the Act was not used against members of the Communist Party during World War II, 11 Communist Party leaders were convicted under the Act in 1949 following the build up of Cold War tensions. In the following opening statements of that trial, the U.S. prosecuting attorney, John F. X. McGohey and the general secretary of the Communist Party, Eugene Dennis, offered widely divergent descriptions of the Party's goals. The Supreme Court upheld the guilty verdicts in 1951, ruling that government action against the defendants was required under the "clear and present danger" test. The ruling further argued that the Party, which was "in the very least ideologically attuned" with Communist countries, had formed "a highly organized conspiracy," that created the present danger. In subsequent years, Congress passed additional anti-Communist laws, and courts obtained 93 convictions of Party members. After the liberal-leaning Warren Court's 1956 ruling that mere advocacy of revolution was insufficient grounds to convict, the U.S. government ended their prosecution of Communists for Party membership alone.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1919 während des Pfosten-Weltkrieges I "roter 
Schrecken," ordnete das Höchste Gericht an, daß der erste Änderung 
Schutz der freien Rede nicht unter Umständen anwendbar war, unter 
denen es eine "freie und anwesende Gefahr" gab, die "substantivische 
Übel, daß Kongreß hat ein Recht zu verhindern" resultierend aus 
dieser Rede auftreten würden. 1940 führte Kongreß die Smith 
Tat und bildete ungültig die Befürwortung vom Besiegen des Zustandes
oder der Nationalregierungen. Obgleich die Tat nicht gegen 
Bauteile der kommunistischen Partei während des Zweiten 
Weltkrieges verwendet wurde, wurden 11 kommunistische 
Parteiführer unter der Tat in 1949 dem Aufbau der Spannkräfte 
des kalten Krieges folgend überführt. In den folgenden 
Dateieröffnungsanweisungen über diesen Versuch, boten der VEREINIGTE
STAATEN verfolgende Rechtsanwalt, John F. X. McGohey und die 
allgemeine Sekretärin der kommunistischen Partei, Eugene 
Dennis, weit unterschiedliche Beschreibungen der Parteiziele an. 
Das Höchste Gericht unterstützte die schuldigen 
Urteilssprüche 1951 und anordnete, daß Regierung Tätigkeit gegen 
die Beklagten unter dem Test "der freien und anwesenden Gefahr" 
benoetigt wurde. Das Anordnen argumentierte weiter, daß die 
Partei, die "in sehr wenig ideologisch abgestimmt" mit 
kommunistischen Ländern war, "eine in hohem Grade organisierte 
Verschwörung gebildet hatte,", das die anwesende Gefahr erstellte. 
In den folgenden Jahren erreichten der geführte Kongreß 
zusätzliche Anti-Kommunistische Gesetze und die Gerichte 93 
Überzeugungen der Parteibauteile. Nach dem 
liberal-lehnenden Warren Gericht 1956, das anordnet, daß bloße 
Befürwortung der Umdrehung war der unzulängliche zu überführen 
Boden, beendete die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung ihre Verfolgung der 
Kommunisten für Parteimitgliedschaft alleine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1919, pendant la guerre I "alarme rouge de 
poteau-Monde," la cour suprême a régné que la protection du premier
amendement du discours libre n'était pas applicable dans les 
circonstances dans lesquelles il y avait "un danger clair et actuel" 
que "les maux substantifs que le congrès a une droite d'empêcher" se
produiraient en raison de ce discours. En 1940, le congrès a 
passé la Loi de Smith, faisant illégal la recommandation de 
renverser l'état ou les gouvernements nationaux. Bien que 
l'acte n'ait pas été utilisé contre des membres du parti communiste
pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, 11 amorces de parti communiste 
ont été condamnées sous la Loi dans 1949 suivant l'accumulation des
tensions de guerre froide. Dans les rapports d'ouverture 
suivants de cette épreuve, le mandataire de poursuite des ETATS-UNIS,
John F. X. McGohey et le secrétaire général du parti communiste, 
Eugene Dennis, ont offert largement des descriptions divergentes des 
buts de la partie. La cour suprême a confirmé les verdicts 
coupables en 1951, régnant que l'action de gouvernement contre les 
défendeurs a été exigée à l'essai "de danger clair et actuel". 
Régner en outre a argué du fait que la partie, qui était 
"dans  moins idéologiquement adapté" avec les pays communistes, 
avait formé "une conspiration fortement organisée," qui a créé le 
danger actuel. En années ultérieures, le congrès passé des 
lois anti-Communistes supplémentaires, et les cours ont obtenu 93 
convictions des membres de partie. Après la cour depenchement 
1956 de Warren régnant que la seule recommandation de la révolution 
était les raisons insuffisantes à condamner, le gouvernement des 
ETATS-UNIS a terminé leur poursuite des communistes pour seule 
l'adhésion de partie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1919, durante a guerra I "scare vermelho do 
borne-Mundo," a corte suprema governou que a proteção da primeira 
emenda do discurso livre não era aplicável nas circunstâncias em 
que havia "um perigo desobstruído e atual" que "os evils substantivos
que o congress tem uma direita impedir" ocorressem em conseqüência 
desse discurso. Em 1940, o congress passou o ato de Smith, 
fazendo ilegal o advocacy de overthrowing o estado ou governos 
nacionais. Embora o ato não fosse usado de encontro aos membros
do partido comunista durante a segunda guerra mundial, 11 líderes do 
partido comunista convicted sob o ato em 1949 que seguem a 
configuração acima de tensões da guerra fria. Nas seguintes 
indicações de abertura dessa experimentação, o advogado 
prosecuting de ESTADOS UNIDOS, John F. X. McGohey e a secretária 
geral do partido comunista, Eugene Dennis, ofereceram extensamente 
descrições divergent dos objetivos do partido. A corte suprema
upheld os verdicts culpados em 1951, governando que a ação do 
governo de encontro aos réus estêve requerida sob "o teste do perigo
desobstruído e atual". Governar discutiu mais mais que o 
partido, que estava "no attuned muito o mais menos ideologically" com 
países comunistas, tinha dado forma "a um conspiracy altamente 
organizado," que criou o perigo atual. Em anos subseqüentes, o 
congress passado leis anti-Comunistas adicionais, e as cortes 
obtiveram 93 convicções de membros do partido. Após a corte 
liberal-inclinando-se 1956 de Warren que governa que o mero advocacy 
da volta era terras insuficientes a convict, o governo de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS terminou seu prosecution dos comunistas para a sociedade do 
partido sozinho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1919, durante la guerra I "spavento rosso del 
alberino-Mondo," la Corte suprema ha regolato che la protezione di 
prima correzione di discorso libero non era applicabile nelle 
circostanze in cui ci era "un pericolo libero ed attuale" che "le 
malvagità sostanziali che il congresso ha una destra evitare" 
accadrebbero come conseguenza di quel discorso. In 1940, il 
congresso ha passato la Legge dello Smith, rendente illegale 
l'avvocatura di overthrowing dichiara o governi nazionali. 
Anche se la Legge non è stata usata contro i membri del partito
comunista durante la seconda guerra mondiale, 11 capo del 
partito comunista è stato condannato a norma della legge in 1949 che 
seguono l'accumulazione dei tensionamenti di guerra fredda. 
Nelle seguenti istruzione di apertura di quella prova, 
l'avvocato di proseguimento degli STATI UNITI, John F. X. McGohey e la
segretaria generale del partito comunista, Eugene Dennis, hanno 
offerto ampiamente le descrizioni divergenti degli obiettivi del 
partito. La Corte suprema ha sostenuto i verdetti colpevoli in 
1951, regolando che l'azione di governo contro i difensori è stata 
richiesta sotto "la prova di pericolo libero ed attuale". Il 
regolamento più ulteriormente ha sostenuto che il partito, che era 
"in adattato il più minimo ideologicamente" con i paesi comunisti, 
aveva formato "una cospirazione altamente organizzata," che ha creato 
il pericolo attuale. Durante gli anni successivi, il congresso 
ha approvato le leggi anti-Comuniste supplementari e le corti hanno 
ottenuto 93 convinzioni dei membri del partito. Dopo la corte 
liberale-pendente 1956 di Warren che regola che l'avvocatura pura del 
giro era motivi insufficienti da condannare, il governo degli STATI 
UNITI ha concluso il loro processo dei comunisti per l'insieme dei 
membri del partito da solo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1919, κατά τη διάρκεια του μετα-παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου Ι ο "κόκκινος τρόμος," το ανώτατο δικαστήριο κυβέρνησε 
ότι η πρώτη προστασία τροποποιήσεων της ελεύθερης ομιλίας δεν 
ίσχυσε στις περιστάσεις στις οποίες υπήρξε ένας "σαφής και 
παρών κίνδυνοσ" ότι τα "ουσιαστικά κακά ότι το συνέδριο έχει 
το δικαίωμα να αποτρέψει" θα εμφανίζονταν ως αποτέλεσμα εκείνης 
της ομιλίας. Το 1940, το συνέδριο πέρασε το νόμο 
Smith, που καθιστά παράνομη την υπεράσπιση της νίκης του 
κράτους ή των εθνικών κυβερνήσεων. Αν και ο νόμος δεν 
χρησιμοποιήθηκε ενάντια στα μέλη του Κομμουνιστικού Κόμματος 
κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, 11 κομμουνιστικοί 
αρχηγοί κόμματος καταδικάστηκαν στο πλαίσιο του νόμου το 1949 
μετά από τη συγκέντρωση των εντάσεων ψυχρού πολέμου. Στις 
ακόλουθες εναρκτήριες δηλώσεις εκείνης της δοκιμής, ο 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ διωκτικός πληρεξούσιος, John F. Χ. McGohey και
ο γενικός γραμματέας του Κομμουνιστικού Κόμματος, Eugene 
Dennis, πρόσφεραν τις ευρέως διάφορες περιγραφές των στόχων 
του συμβαλλόμενου μέρους. Το ανώτατο δικαστήριο υποστήριξε 
τις ένοχες αποφάσεις το 1951, κυβερνών ότι η κυβερνητική 
ενέργεια ενάντια στους κατηγορουμένους απαιτήθηκε κάτω από τη 
δοκιμή "σαφούς και παρόντος κινδύνου". Η απόφαση περαιτέρω
υποστήριξε ότι το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος, που ήταν "πολύ ο πιό 
ελάχιστα ιδεολογικά προσαρμοσμένη" με τις κομμουνιστικές χώρες, 
είχε διαμορφώσει "μια ιδιαίτερα οργανωμένη συνωμοσία," που 
δημιούργησε τον παρόντα κίνδυνο. Στα επόμενα έτη, το 
συνέδριο πέρασε τους πρόσθετους αντικομμουνιστείς νόμους, και τα 
δικαστήρια έλαβαν 93 πεποιθήσεις των μελών συμβαλλόμενου 
μέρους. Μετά από φιλελεύθερος-κλίνοντας το 1956 του 
δικαστηρίου κυκεώνων που κυβερνά ότι η μόνη υπεράσπιση της 
επανάστασης συνέτρεξε ανεπαρκείς λόγοι για να καταδικάσει, η 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ κυβέρνηση τελείωσε τη συνέχιση κομμουνιστών τους για 
την ιδιότητα μέλους συμβαλλόμενου μέρους μόνο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1919, durante la guerra I "susto rojo del 
poste-Mundo," el Tribunal Supremo gobernó que la protección de la 
primera enmienda del discurso libre no era aplicable en las 
circunstancias en las cuales había "un peligro claro y actual" que 
los "males substantivos que el congreso tiene una derecha de prevenir"
ocurrirían como resultado de ese discurso. En 1940, el congreso
pasó el acto de Smith, haciendo ilegal la defensa de derrocar el 
estado o gobiernos nacionales. Aunque el acto no fue utilizado 
contra miembros del partido comunista durante la Segunda Guerra 
Mundial, condenaron a 11 arranques de cinta del partido comunista bajo
acto en 1949 que seguían la acumulación de las tensiones de la 
guerra fría. En las declaraciones de apertura siguientes de ese
ensayo, el abogado de procesamiento de ESTADOS UNIDOS, Juan F. X. 
McGohey y la secretaria general del partido comunista, Eugene Dennis, 
ofrecieron extensamente las descripciones divergentes de las metas del
partido. El Tribunal Supremo mantuvo los veredictos culpables en
1951, gobernando que la acción del gobierno contra los demandados fue
requerida bajo prueba "del peligro claro y actual". La decisión
discutió más lejos que el partido, que estaba "en adaptado muy lo 
más menos posible ideológico" con los países comunistas, había 
formado "una conspiración altamente ordenada," que creó el actual 
peligro. En años subsecuentes, el congreso pasado los leyes 
contra-Comunistas adicionales, y las cortes obtuvieron 93 convicciones
de los miembros del partido. Después de la corte 1956 de Warren
liberal-que se inclinaba que gobernaba que la defensa mera de la 
revolución era argumentos escasos a condenar, el gobierno de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS terminó su procesamiento de los comunistas para la calidad de 
miembro del partido solamente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087499</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104513</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/communists-are-second-to-none-in-our-devotion-to-our-people-and-to-our-country-prosecution-and-defense-statements-1949-trial-of-american-communist-party-leaders</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
