<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105200</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105200</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086981</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Lowell Mill Girls Go on Strike, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Lowell Tausendstel-Mädchen streiken, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les filles de moulin de Lowell font la grève, 
1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As meninas do moinho de Lowell vão na batida, 
1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le ragazze del laminatoio de Lowell vanno sul 
colpo, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα κορίτσια μύλων του Lowell πηγαίνουν στην 
απεργία, 1836</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las muchachas del molino de Lowell van en la 
huelga, 1836</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A group of Boston capitalists built a major textile manufacturing center in Lowell, Massachusetts, in the second quarter of the 19th century. The first factories recruited women from rural New England as their labor force. These young women, far from home, lived in rows of boardinghouses adjacent to the growing number of mills. The industrial production of textiles was highly profitable,and the number of factories in Lowell and other mill towns increased. More mills led to overproduction, which led to a drop in prices and profits. Mill owners reduced wages and speeded up the pace of work. The young female operatives organized to protest these wage cuts in 1834 and 1836. Harriet Hanson Robinson was one of those factory operatives; she began work in Lowell at the age of ten, later becoming an author and advocate of women's suffrage. In 1898 she published  Loom and Spindle , a memoir of her Lowell experiences, where she recounted the strike of 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Gruppe Boston Kapitalisten baute ein 
Haupttextilindustriegebiet in Lowell, Massachusetts, im zweiten 
Viertel des 19. Jahrhunderts auf. Die ersten Fabriken zogen 
Frauen von landwirtschaftlichem Neu-England als ihre Arbeitskräfte 
ein. Diese jungen Frauen, weit von Haus, lebten in den Reihen 
von boardinghouses neben der wachsenden Zahl Tausendsteln. Die 
industrielle Industrieproduktion der Gewebe war in hohem Grade 
rentabel, und die Zahl Fabriken in Lowell und in anderen 
Tausendstelstädten erhöhte sich. Mehr Tausendstel führten zu 
Überproduktion, die zu einen Tropfen der Preise und der Profite 
führte. Verringerte Löhne des Tausendstels Inhaber und 
beschleunigt herauf den Schritt der Arbeit. Die jungen 
weiblichen Arbeiter, die organisiert werden, um diese zu protestieren 
Lohn, schneidet 1834 und 1836 ein. Harriet Hanson Robinson war 
einer jener Fabrikarbeiter; sie fing Arbeit in Lowell am Alter 
von 10 an und später wurde ein Autor und ein Fürsprecher des 
Stimmrechts der Frauen. 1898 veröffentlichte sie Webstuhl und 
Spindel, eine Abhandlung ihrer Lowell Erfahrungen, in denen sie den 
Schlag von 1836 nachzählte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un groupe de capitalistes de Boston a établi un 
centre de fabrication important de textile à Lowell, le 
Massachusetts, dans le deuxième trimestre du 19ème siècle. 
Les premières usines ont recruté des femmes de Nouvelle 
Angleterre rurale en tant que leur main-d'oeuvre. Ces jeunes 
femmes, loin de maison, ont vécu dans les lignes des boardinghouses 
à côté du nombre de plus en plus important des moulins. La 
production industrielle des textiles était fortement profitable, et 
le nombre d'usines à Lowell et d'autres villes de moulin a augmenté.
Plus de moulins ont mené à la surproduction, qui a mené à 
une baisse dans les prix et les bénéfices. Salaires réduits 
par propriétaires de moulin et expédié vers le haut du pas du 
travail. Les jeunes employés féminins organisés pour 
protester des ces réduction de salaire en 1834 et 1836. Harriet
Hanson Robinson était l'un de ces employés d'usine ; elle a 
commencé le travail à Lowell à l'âge de dix, plus tard devenant un
auteur et une avocate du suffrage des femmes. En 1898 elle a 
édité le manche et l'axe, un mémoire de ses expériences de Lowell,
où elle a raconté la grève de 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um grupo de capitalistas de Boston construiu um 
centro de manufacturing principal de textile em Lowell, Massachusetts,
no segundo quarto do 1ø século. As primeiras fábricas 
recrutaram mulheres de Nova Inglaterra rural como sua força labor. 
Estas mulheres novas, longe da HOME, viveram nas fileiras dos 
boardinghouses junto ao número de crescimento dos moinhos. A 
produção industrial dos textiles era altamente profitable, e o 
número das fábricas em Lowell e em outras cidades do moinho 
aumentou. Mais moinhos conduziram ao overproduction, que 
conduziu a uma gota nos preços e nos lucros. Salários 
reduzidos proprietários do moinho e apressado acima do ritmo do 
trabalho. Os operatives fêmeas novos organizados para protestar
estes salário cortam dentro 1834 e 1836. Harriet Hanson 
Robinson era um daqueles operatives da fábrica; começou o 
trabalho em Lowell na idade de dez, mais tarde transformando-se um 
autor e um advogado do suffrage das mulheres. Em 1898 publicou o
tear e o eixo, um memoir de suas experiências de Lowell, onde 
recounted a batida de 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un gruppo dei capitalisti de Boston ha sviluppato 
un centro di manufacturing importante della tessile a Lowell, 
Massachusetts, nel secondo trimestre del diciannovesimo secolo. 
Le prime fabbriche hanno reclutato le donne dalla Nuova 
Inghilterra rurale come loro forza di lavoro. Queste donne 
giovani, lontano dalla sede, hanno vissuto nelle file dei 
boardinghouses adiacente al numero crescere di laminatoi. La 
produzione industriale delle tessile era altamente vantaggiosa ed il 
numero di fabbriche a Lowell ed altre città del laminatoio è 
aumentato. Più laminatoi hanno condotto alla sovrapproduzione, 
che ha condotto ad un calo nei prezzi e nei profitti. Stipendi 
ridotti proprietari del laminatoio ed accelerato sul passo di lavoro. 
Gli operatori femminili giovani organizzati per protestare i 
questi stipendio taglia dentro 1834 e 1836. Harriet Hanson 
Robinson era uno di quegli operatori della fabbrica; ha 
cominciato il lavoro a Lowell all'età di dieci, più successivamente 
diventando un autore e un fautore di suffrage delle donne. In 
1898 ha pubblicato il telaio e l'alberino, una memoria delle sue 
esperienze de Lowell, dove ha raccontato il colpo di 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια ομάδα κεφαλαιοκρατών της Βοστώνης έχτισε ένα 
σημαντικό υφαντικό κατασκευαστικό κέντρο στο Lowell, 
Μασαχουσέτη, στο δεύτερο τέταρτο του 19$ου αιώνα. Τα πρώτα 
εργοστάσια στρατολόγησαν τις γυναίκες από την αγροτική Νέα 
Αγγλία ως εργατικό δυναμικό τους. Αυτές οι νέες γυναίκες, 
μακριά από το σπίτι, έζησαν στις σειρές των boardinghouses 
δίπλα στον αυξανόμενο αριθμό μύλων. Η βιομηχανική παραγωγή
των κλωστοϋφαντουργικών προϊόντων ήταν ιδιαίτερα κερδοφόρα, και
ο αριθμός εργοστασίων στο Lowell και άλλων πόλεων μύλων 
αυξήθηκε. Περισσότεροι μύλοι οδήγησαν στην υπερπαραγωγή, η 
οποία οδήγησε σε μια μείωση των τιμών και των κερδών. Οι 
ιδιοκτήτες μύλων μείωσαν τις αμοιβές και επιτάχυναν επάνω το 
ρυθμό της εργασίας. Οι νέοι θηλυκοί χειριστές που 
οργανώθηκαν για να διαμαρτυρηθούν αυτές τις αποκοπές αμοιβών το 
1834 και 1836, Harriet Hanson Robinson ήταν ένας από
εκείνους τους χειριστές εργοστασίων  άρχισε την εργασία στο
Lowell στην ηλικία δέκα, γίνοντας αργότερα συντάκτης και 
συνήγορος της ψήφου των γυναικών. Το 1898 δημοσίευσε τον 
αργαλειό και τον άξονα, απομνημονεύματα της εμπειρίας του 
Lowell της, όπου εξιστόρησε την απεργία 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un grupo de los capitalistas de Boston construyó 
un centro de fabricación importante del textil en Lowell, 
Massachusetts, en el segundo trimestre del diecinueveavo siglo. 
Las primeras fábricas reclutaron a mujeres de Nueva Inglaterra 
rural como su mano de obra. Estas mujeres jóvenes, lejos del 
hogar, vivieron en filas de boardinghouses adyacente al número 
creciente de molinos. La producción industrial de textiles era 
altamente provechosa, y el número de fábricas en Lowell y otras 
ciudades del molino aumentó. Más molinos condujeron a la 
superproducción, que condujo a una gota en precios y beneficios. 
Salarios reducidos propietarios del molino y apresurado encima 
del paso del trabajo. Los operarios femeninos jóvenes ordenados
para protestar estos salario cortan adentro 1834 y 1836. Harriet
Hanson Robinson era uno de esos operarios de la fábrica; ella 
comenzó el trabajo en Lowell en la edad de diez, más adelante 
haciendo autor y abogado del sufragio de las mujeres. En 1898 
ella publicó el telar y el eje de rotación, una memoria de sus 
experiencias de Lowell, donde ella contó de nuevo la huelga de 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086981</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105200</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-lowell-mill-girls-go-on-strike-1836</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
