<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107807</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107807</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086307</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Witnessed the Steel Strike": Joe Rudiak Remembers the 1919 Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich zeugte den Stahlschlag": Joe Rudiak 
erinnert sich den an Schlag 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'étais témoin de la grève en acier" : 
Joe Rudiak se rappelle la grève 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu testemunhei a batida de aço": Joe 
Rudiak recorda a batida 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho testimoniato il colpo d'acciaio": Joe 
Rudiak si ricorda del colpo 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"βεβαίωσα την απεργία χάλυβα": Θ*Ιοε Rudiak 
Remembers η απεργία του 1919</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"atestigüé la huelga de acero": Joe Rudiak
recuerda la huelga 1919</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Though the Great Steel Strike of 1919 failed in its immediate aims, it left a legacy in the steel regions of the United States that lasted for decades. In 1974 when historian Peter Gotlieb asked former steelworker Joe Rudiak, the son of Polish immigrants, about his participation in unionization struggles in the 1930s, he started by recalling his memories of the 1919 steel strike as a young boy. Here, Rudiak told how his father was blacklisted for acknowledging his support of the union. From such experiences, he explained, unionism got "embedded in you."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obwohl der große Stahlschlag von 1919 in seinen 
sofortigen Zielen ausfiel, es nach links eine Legacy in den 
Stahlregionen der Vereinigten Staaten, die für Dekaden dauerten. 
1974, als Historiker Peter Gotlieb ehemaligen Steelworker Joe 
Rudiak fragte, kämpft der Sohn der polnischen Immigranten, über 
seine Teilnahme am Unionization in den dreißiger Jahren, er begann, 
indem er seine Speicher des Stahlschlages 1919 als junger Junge 
erinnert an. Hier erklärte Rudiak, wie sein Vater für das 
Bestätigen seines Supports des Anschlußes auf die schwarze Liste 
gesetzt wurde. Von solchen Erfahrungen erklärte er, das 
unionism, das erhalten wurde "eingebettet in Ihnen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que la grande grève en acier de 1919 ait 
échoué dans ses objectifs immédiats, il à gauche un legs dans les 
régions en acier des Etats-Unis qui ont duré pendant des décennies.
En 1974 quand l'historien Peter Gotlieb a demandé à 
l'ancien travailleur dans l'industrie sidérurgique Joe Rudiak, le 
fils des immigrés polonais, au sujet de sa participation à la 
syndicalisation lutte dans les années 30, il a commencé par rappeler
ses mémoires de la grève 1919 en acier en tant que jeune garçon. 
Ici, Rudiak a indiqué que son père a été mis sur la liste 
noire pour reconnaître son support de l'union. De telles 
expériences, il a expliqué, syndicalisme obtenu "encastré dans 
vous."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora a batida de aço grande de 1919 falhou em 
seus alvos imediatos, ele à esquerda um legacy nas regiões de aço 
dos estados unidos que duraram por décadas. Em 1974 quando o 
historian Peter Gotlieb perguntou a steelworker anterior Joe Rudiak, o
filho de immigrants poloneses, sobre sua participação no 
unionization esforça-se nos 1930s, ele começou recordando suas 
memórias da batida 1919 de aço como um menino novo. Aqui, 
Rudiak disse como seu pai foi posto reconhecendo sua sustentação da 
união. De tais experiências, explicou, unionism começado 
"encaixado em você."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benchè il colpo d'acciaio grande di 1919 venga a 
mancare nei relativi obiettivi immediati, a sinistra che un'eredità 
nelle regioni d'acciaio del unito Dichiara quella ha durato le 
decadi. In 1974 quando lo storico Peter Gotlieb ha chiesto 
all'ex addetto alla lavorazione dell'acciaio Joe Rudiak, il figlio 
degli immigranti polacchi, circa la sua partecipazione al unionization
lotta nei 1930s, lui ha cominciato ricordando le sue memorie del colpo
d'acciaio 1919 come ragazzo giovane. Qui, Rudiak ha detto a come
il suo padre è stato messo in per il riconoscimento del suo supporto 
dell'unione. Da tali esperienze, ha spiegato, unionism ottenuto 
"incastonato in voi."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και η μεγάλη απεργία χάλυβα του 1919 απέτυχε 
στους άμεσους στόχους της, άφησε μια κληρονομιά περιοχή χάλυβα 
των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών που διάρκεσαν για δεκαετίες. Το 
1974 όταν ρώτησε ο ιστορικός Peter Gotlieb τον 
προηγούμενο σιδηρουργό Joe Rudiak, ο γιος των πολωνικών 
μεταναστών, για τη συμμετοχή του στις προσπάθειες 
συνδικαλικοποίησης στη δεκαετία του '30, άρχισε με την υπενθύμιση 
των μνημών του της απεργίας χάλυβα του 1919 ως νέο αγόρι. 
Εδώ, Rudiak είπε πώς ο πατέρας του βάλθηκε στη μαύρη 
λίστα για την αναγνώριση της υποστήριξής του της ένωσης. 
Από τέτοια εμπειρία, εξήγησε, συνδικαλισμός που αποκτάται 
"ενσωματωμένος σε σας."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque la gran huelga de acero de 1919 falló en 
sus punterías inmediatas, él a la izquierda una herencia en las 
regiones de acero de los Estados Unidos que duraron por décadas. 
En 1974 cuando el historiador Peter Gotlieb preguntó a 
trabajador siderúrgico anterior Joe Rudiak, el hijo de inmigrantes 
polacos, sobre su participación en la sindicalización lucha en los 
años 30, él comenzó recordando sus memorias de la huelga de acero 
1919 como muchacho joven. Aquí, Rudiak dijo cómo pusieron a su
padre para reconocer su ayuda de la unión. De tales 
experiencias, él explicó, unionism conseguido "embutido en usted."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086307</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107807</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-witnessed-the-steel-strike-joe-rudiak-remembers-the-1919-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
