<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107470</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107470</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087591</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Access Excellence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Greifen Sie Auf Hervorragende Leistung Zu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Accédez À l'Excellence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alcance O Excellence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Accedi Al Merito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τελειότητα πρόσβασης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tenga acceso A la Excelencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Access Excellence, launched in 1993, is a national educational program that provides health, biology and life science teachers access to their colleagues, scientists, and critical sources of new scientific information via the World Wide Web. The program was originally developed and launched by Genentech Inc., and in 1999 joined the National Health Museum, a non-profit organization founded by former U.S. Surgeon General C. Everett Koop as a national center for health education. Access Excellence will form the core of the educational component of the National Health Museum Website that is currently under development. .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Greifen Sie auf die hervorragende Leistung, 
ausgestoßen 1993 zu, ist ein nationales pädagogisches Programm, das 
Gesundheit, auf Biologie liefert und Lebenwissenschaft Lehrer zu ihren
Kollegen, zu Wissenschaftlern und zu kritischen Quellen der neuen 
Fachinformation über das World Wide Web zugreifen. Das Programm
wurde ursprünglich durch Genentech Inc. und in 1999 verband das 
nationale Gesundheit Museum, eine gemeinnützige Organisation 
entwickelt und ausgestoßen, die von allgemeinem ehemaliger VEREINIGTE
STAATEN Chirurg C. Everett Koop als nationale Mitte für Gesundheit 
Ausbildung gegründet wurde. Zugriff hervorragende Leistung 
bildet den Kern des pädagogischen Bestandteils der nationalen 
Gesundheit Museum Web site, die aktuell unter Entwicklung ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Accédez à l'excellence, lancée en 1993, êtes 
un programme éducatif national qui fournit la santé, biologie et des
professeurs de la science de vie accèdent à leurs collègues, 
scientifiques, et sources critiques de nouvelle information 
scientifique par l'intermédiaire du Web mondial. Le 
programme a été initialement développé et lancé par Genentech 
Inc., et à 1999 s'est associé le musée national de santé, une 
organisation à but non lucratif fondée par C. Everett Koop Général
ancien ETATS-UNIS chirurgien comme centre national pour l'éducation 
sanitaire. L'excellence d'accès formera le noyau du composant 
éducatif du site Web national de musée de santé qui est actuel en 
cours de développement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alcance o excellence, lançado em 1993, seja um 
programa educacional nacional que forneça a saúde, biologia e 
professores da ciência de vida alcance a seus colegas, cientistas, e 
fontes críticas da informação científica nova através do World 
Wide Web. O programa originalmente foi desenvolvido e lançado 
por Genentech Inc., e em 1999 juntou o museu nacional da saúde, uma 
organização non-profit fundada ESTADOS UNIDOS cirurgião anterior 
por C. geral Everett Koop como um centro nacional para a instrução 
de saúde. O excellence do acesso dará forma ao núcleo do 
componente educacional do Web site nacional do museu da saúde que 
está atualmente sob o desenvolvimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Accedi al merito, lanciato in 1993, è un 
programma educativo nazionale che fornisce la salute, biologia ed 
insegnanti di scienze biologiche accede a ai loro colleghe, scienziati
e sorgenti critiche di nuova informazione scientifica via il World 
Wide Web. Il programma originalmente è stato sviluppato e 
lanciato stato da Genentech Inc. ed a 1999 si è associato il museo 
nazionale di salute, un'organizzazione senza scopo di lucro fondata 
l'ex STATI UNITI chirurgo da C. Everett Koop generale come centro 
nazionale per educazione sanitaria. Il merito di accesso 
formerà il nucleo del componente educativo del Web site nazionale del
museo di salute che è attualmente in fase di sviluppo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η τελειότητα πρόσβασης, που προωθείται το 1993, 
είναι ένα εθνικό εκπαιδευτικό πρόγραμμα που παρέχει την 
πρόσβαση δασκάλων υγείας, της βιολογίας και βιολογικής επιστήμης
στους συναδέλφους, τους επιστήμονες, και τις κρίσιμες πηγές νέων 
επιστημονικών πληροφοριών τους μέσω του World Wide Web. 
Το πρόγραμμα αναπτύχθηκε αρχικά και εγκαινιάστηκε από 
Genentech Inc., και το 1999 ένωσε το εθνικό μουσείο 
υγείας, μια μη κερδοσκοπική οργάνωση που ιδρύθηκε από τις πρώην 
ΗΠΑ Surgeon General Γ. Everett Koop ως εθνικό κέντρο για
την υγειονομική αγωγή. Η τελειότητα πρόσβασης θα 
διαμορφώσει τον πυρήνα του εκπαιδευτικού συστατικού του εθνικού 
ιστοχώρου μουσείων υγείας που είναι αυτήν την περίοδο υπό 
ανάπτυξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tenga acceso a la excelencia, lanzada en 1993, es 
un programa educativo nacional que proporciona a la salud, biología y
los profesores de la ciencia de vida tiene acceso a sus colegas, 
científicos, y fuentes críticas de la nueva información científica
vía el Web mundial. El programa fue desarrollado y 
lanzado originalmente por Genentech Inc., y en 1999 ensambló el museo
nacional de la salud, una organización no lucrativa fundada por 
ESTADOS UNIDOS cirujano anterior C. general Everett Koop como centro 
nacional para la educación de salud. La excelencia del acceso 
formará la base del componente educativo del Web site nacional del 
museo de la salud que está actualmente en desarrollo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087591</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107470</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/access-excellence</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
