<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103151</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103151</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101280</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Canary in a Coal Mine (MWV16)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kanarienvogel in einer Kohlengrube (MWV16)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Canari dans une mine de houille (MWV16)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Canário em uma mina de carvão (MWV16)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Canarino in una miniera di carbone (MWV16)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καναρίνι σε ένα ορυχείο άνθρακα (MWV16)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Canario en una mina de carbón (MWV16)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Coral reefs are dying a death of a thousand cuts and their disappearance threatens not only the incredibly diverse ecosystem that depends on them, but also human health and welfare. In this episode of MicrobeWorld Video marine scientists Ove Hoegh-Guldberg, Ph.D., chair of marine studies at the University of Queensland in Brisbane, Australia, and Kiho Kim, Ph.D., director of the environmental studies program at American University, explain the important relationship between microbes and corals, and how this delicate symbiosis that sustains life on and around reefs is facing numerous threats from human interactions to global climate change. In addition, Tundi Agardy, Ph.D., founder and executive director of Sound Seas, discusses the need for public policy and community-based conservation efforts that may help stave off the degradation of these vital ocean ecosystems. According to a 2004 report issued by the World Wildlife Fund, 24% of the world's reefs are under imminent risk of collapse through human pressures; and a further 26% are under a longer term threat of collapse. If nothing is done to protect these resources, many scientists estimate that reefs around the West Indies in the Caribbean will be gone by 2020, while the Great Barrier Reef may only last for another three decades. Please visit the following sites for more information about coral reefs:www.climateshifts.org, www.reefrelief.org, www.coralreef.noaa.gov</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Korallenriffe sterben einen Tod von tausend 
Schnitten und ihr Verschwinden bedroht nicht nur das unglaublich 
verschiedene Oekosystem, das von ihnen abhängt, aber auch menschliche
Gesundheit und Wohlfahrt. In dieser Episode MicrobeWorld der 
video Marinewissenschaftler Ove Hoegh-Guldberg, Ph.D., Stuhl der 
Marine studiert an der Universität von Queensland in Brisbane, in 
Australien und in Kiho Kim, Ph.D., Direktor des Klimastudien Programms
an der amerikanischen Universität, erklärt das wichtige Verhältnis 
zwischen Mikroben und Korallen und wie diese empfindliche Symbiose, 
der das Leben auf und um Reefs unterstützt, zahlreiche Drohungen von 
den menschlichen Interaktionen zur globalen Klimaänderung 
gegenüberstellt. Zusätzlich Tundi Agardy, Ph.D., Gründer- und
Leitprogrammbehandelt direktor von stichhaltigen Meeren, die 
Notwendigkeit an der allgemeinen Politik und an 
Gemeinschaft-gegründeten Erhaltung Bemühungen, die Daube weg von der
Verminderung dieser lebenswichtigen Ozeanoekosysteme helfen können. 
Entsprechend einem Report 2004, der durch die 
Weltwildnis-Kapital herausgegeben wird, sind 24% der Reefs der Welt 
unter unmittelbar drohender Gefahr des Einsturzes durch menschlichen 
Druck; und ein weiteres 26% sind unter einer längerfristigen 
Drohung des Einsturzes. Wenn nichts, diese Betriebsmittel zu 
schützen erfolgt ist, schätzen viele Wissenschaftler, daß Reefs um 
die Westinseln in den Karibischen Meeren bis zum 2020 gegangen werden,
während das große Wallriff nur kann, dauern Sie für andere drei 
Dekaden. Besichtigen Sie bitte die folgenden Sites zu mehr 
Information über Koralle reefs:www.climateshifts.org, 
www.reefrelief.org, www.coralreef.noaa.gov</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les récifs de corail meurent une mort d'mille 
coupes et leur disparition menace non seulement l'écosystème 
incroyablement divers qui dépend d'elles, mais également la santé 
humaine et le bien-être. Dans cet épisode des scientifiques 
marins visuels Ove Hoegh-Guldberg, Ph.D., chaise de MicrobeWorld de 
soldat de marine étudie à l'université du Queensland à Brisbane, 
en Australie, et Kiho Kim, Ph.D., directeur du programme 
environnemental d'études à l'université américaine, explique le 
rapport important entre les microbes et les coraux, et comment cette 
symbiose sensible sur laquelle soutient la vie et autour des récifs 
fait face à de nombreuses menaces des interactions humaines au 
changement global de climat. En outre, le directeur de Tundi 
Agardy, de Ph.D., de fondateur et de directeur des mers saines, 
discute le besoin d'ordre public et d'efforts communauté-basés 
d'économie qui peuvent aider la barre outre de la dégradation de ces
écosystèmes essentiels d'océan. Selon un état 2004 émis par
les fonds de faune du monde, 24% des récifs du monde sont sous le 
risque imminent d'effondrement par des pressions humaines ; et 
un 26% plus encore est sous une menace à plus long terme de 
l'effondrement. Si rien à est fait protéger ces ressources, 
beaucoup de scientifiques estiment que des récifs autour des Indes 
occidentales dans les Caraïbes seront allés d'ici 2020, alors que le
grand récif de barrière peut seulement durez pendant encore trois 
décennies. Veuillez visiter les sites suivants pour plus 
d'informations sur le corail reefs:www.climateshifts.org, 
www.reefrelief.org, www.coralreef.noaa.gov</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os recifes corais estão morrendo uma morte de mil
cortes e seu disappearance ameaça não somente o ecosystem incredibly
diverso que depende deles, mas também a saúde humana e o bem-estar. 
Neste episode dos cientistas marinhos video Ove Hoegh-Guldberg 
de MicrobeWorld, Ph.D., cadeira do fuzileiro naval estuda na 
universidade de Queensland em Brisbane, em Austrália, e em Kiho Kim, 
Ph.D., diretor do programa ambiental dos estudos na universidade 
americana, explicam o relacionamento importante entre micróbios e 
corais, e como este symbiosis delicado em que sustenta a vida e em 
torno dos recifes está enfrentando ameaças numerosas das 
interações humanas à mudança global do clima. Além, o 
diretor de Tundi Agardy, de Ph.D., de founder e de executivo de mares 
sadios, discute a necessidade para a política pública e os esforços
comunidade-baseados do conservation que podem ajudar ao stave fora da 
degradação destes ecosystems vitais do oceano. De acordo com 
um relatório 2004 emitido pelo fundo dos animais selvagens do mundo, 
24% dos recifes do mundo estão sob o risco imminent do colapso com as
pressões humanas; e um 26% mais adicional estão sob uma 
ameaça mais longa do termo do colapso. Se nada for feito 
proteger estes recursos, muitos cientistas estimam que os recifes em 
torno das Índias ocidentais nas Caraíbas estarão idos por 2020, 
quando o recife de barreira grande puder somente dure por outras três
décadas. Visite por favor os seguintes locais para mais 
informação sobre o coral reefs:www.climateshifts.org, 
www.reefrelief.org, www.coralreef.noaa.gov</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I reefs di corallo stanno morendo una morte di 
mille tagli e la loro scomparsa minaccia non soltanto l'ecosistema 
incredibilmente vario che dipende da loro, ma anche la salute umana ed
il benessere. In questo episodio di video scienziati marini Ove 
Hoegh-Guldberg, Ph.D., sedia di MicrobeWorld del fante di marina 
studia all'università de Queensland Brisbane, in Australia e Kiho 
Kim, Ph.D., direttore del programma ambientale di studi 
all'università americana, spiegano il rapporto importante fra i 
microbi ed i corals e come questa simbiosi fragile su che sostiene la 
vita ed intorno ai reefs sta affrontando le minacce numerose dalle 
interazioni umane al cambiamento globale di clima. In più, il 
direttore di Tundi Agardy, di Ph.D., del fondatore e dell'esecutivo 
dei mari sani, discute l'esigenza della politica pubblica e degli 
sforzi Comunità-basati di conservazione che possono aiutare la doga 
fuori della degradazione di questi ecosistemi vitali dell'oceano. 
Secondo un rapporto 2004 pubblicato dal fondo monetario della 
fauna selvatica del mondo, 24% dei reefs del mondo sono sotto il 
rischio imminente di crollo con le pressioni umane; e un 26% 
più ancora è sotto una minaccia a termine più lungo del crollo. 
Se niente è fatto proteggere queste risorse, molti scienziati 
valutano che i reefs intorno alle Indie ad ovest nei Caraibi saranno 
andati entro 2020, mentre il reef di barriera grande può soltanto 
duri altre tre decadi. Visiti prego i seguenti luoghi per le 
più informazioni su coral reefs:www.climateshifts.org, 
www.reefrelief.org, www.coralreef.noaa.gov</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι κοραλλιογενείς ύφαλοι είναι πεθαίνοντας ένας 
θάνατος χιλίων αποκοπών και η εξαφάνισή τους απειλεί όχι μόνο 
το απίστευτα διαφορετικό οικοσύστημα που εξαρτάται από τους, 
αλλά και την ανθρώπινη υγεία και την ευημερία. Σε αυτό το 
επεισόδιο MicrobeWorld των τηλεοπτικών θαλασσίων επιστημόνων 
Ove χοεγχ- Guldberg, ph. Δ., καρέκλα των θαλασσίων μελετών
στο πανεπιστήμιο του Queensland στο Μπρίσμπαν, την Αυστραλία, 
και Kiho Kim, ph. Δ., σκηνοθέτης του περιβαλλοντικού 
προγράμματος μελετών στο αμερικανικό πανεπιστήμιο, εξηγήστε τη 
σημαντική σχέση μεταξύ των μικροβίων και των κοραλλιών, και πώς 
αυτή η λεπτή συμβίωση που στηρίζει τη ζωή σε και γύρω από τους 
σκοπέλους αντιμετωπίζει τις πολυάριθμες απειλές από τις 
ανθρώπινες αλληλεπιδράσεις στη σφαιρική αλλαγή κλίματος. 
Επιπλέον, Tundi Agardy, ph. Δ., ιδρυτής και 
εκτελεστικός σκηνοθέτης των υγιών θαλασσών, συζητά την ανάγκη 
για τη δημόσια πολιτική και τις σε κοινοτικό επίπεδο προσπάθειες 
συντήρησης που μπορούν να βοηθήσουν να εξορκίσουν την υποβάθμιση 
αυτών των ζωτικής σημασίας ωκεάνιων οικοσυστημάτων. 
Σύμφωνα με μια έκθεση του 2004 που παρουσιάζεται από το 
Ταμείο παγκόσμιας άγριας φύσης, 24% των παγκόσμιων σκοπέλων 
είναι κάτω από τον επικείμενο κίνδυνο κατάρρευσης μέσω των 
ανθρώπινων πιέσεων  και ένα περαιτέρω 26% είναι κάτω 
από μια πιο μακροπρόθεσμη απειλή της κατάρρευσης. Εάν 
τίποτα δεν γίνεται για να προστατεύσει αυτά τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς, πολλοί επιστήμονες υπολογίζουν ότι τους σκοπέλους 
γύρω από τις δυτικές Ινδίες στις Καραϊβικές Θάλασσες θα πάνε 
μέχρι το 2020, ενώ ο μεγάλος σκόπελος εμποδίων μπορεί μόνο 
να διαρκέσει για άλλες τρεις δεκαετίες. Παρακαλώ 
επισκεφτείτε τις ακόλουθες περιοχές για περισσότερες πληροφορίες 
για το κοράλλι reefs:www.climateshifts.org, www.reefrelief.org,
www.coralreef.noaa.gov</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los filones coralinos están muriendo una muerte 
de mil cortes y su desaparición amenaza no solamente el ecosistema 
increíblemente diverso que depende de ellos, pero también la salud 
humana y el bienestar. En este episodio de los científicos 
marinas video Ove Hoegh-Guldberg, Ph.D., silla de MicrobeWorld del 
infante de marina estudia en la universidad de Queensland en Brisbane,
Australia, y Kiho Kim, Ph.D., director del programa ambiental de los 
estudios en la universidad americana, explica el lazo importante entre
los microbios y los corales, y cómo esta simbiosis delicada en la 
cual sostiene vida y alrededor de los filones está haciendo frente a 
amenazas numerosas de interacciones humanas al cambio global del 
clima. Además, el director de Tundi Agardy, de Ph.D., del 
fundador y del ejecutivo de los mares de los sonidos, discute la 
necesidad del orden público y de los esfuerzos comunidad-basados de 
la conservación que pueden ayudar al bastón de la degradación de 
estos ecosistemas vitales del océano. Según un informe 2004 
publicado por el fondo de la fauna del mundo, los 24% de los filones 
del mundo están bajo riesgo inminente del derrumbamiento con 
presiones humanas; y 26% más están bajo amenaza más larga del
término del derrumbamiento. Si no se hace nada proteger estos 
recursos, muchos científicos estiman que los filones alrededor de 
Indias del oeste en el Caribe serán idos antes de 2020, mientras que 
puede el gran filón de barrera solamente dure por otras tres 
décadas. Visite por favor los sitios siguientes para más 
información sobre el coral reefs:www.climateshifts.org, 
www.reefrelief.org, www.coralreef.noaa.gov</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MICROBEWORLD
FN:MICROBEWORLD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101280</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103151</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/canary-in-a-coal-mine-mwv16</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
