<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107072</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107072</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087226</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"What You Really Want Is an Autopsy": Frances Perkins and the U. S. Government Conference in Joplin, Missouri, 1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"was Sie wirklich wünschen, eine Autopsie" ist: 
Frances Perkins und die USREGIERUNG Konferenz in Joplin, 
Missouri, 1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"ce qui vous voulez vraiment est une autopsie" : 
Frances Perkins et la conférence de gouvernement des 
États-Unis en Joplin, Missouri, 1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o que você quer realmente é uma autópsia": 
Frances Perkins e a conferência do governo dos E. U. em Joplin,
Missouri, 1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"che cosa realmente desiderate è un'analisi": 
Frances Perkins ed il congresso di governo degli Stati Uniti in 
Joplin, Missouri, 1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τι θέλετε πραγματικά είναι μια αυτοψία": 
Θ*Φρανθες Perkins και η κυβερνητική διάσκεψη του Θ*u. Θ*ς. 
σε Joplin, Μισσούρι, 1940</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"qué usted realmente desea es una autopsia": 
Frances Perkins y la conferencia del gobierno de los E.E.U.U. en
Joplin, Missouri, 1940</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In April 1940 Secretary of Labor Frances Perkins convened a conference in Missouri concerning the silicosis crisis that had emerged in the late 1930s. The differing perspectives on the disease and workers' health are apparent in these excerpts from the Tristate Silicosis Conference. Evan Just, representing industry, claimed that silicosis is a social, not an industrial, problem. Ex-miner Tony McTeer disputed Just's analysis, arguing that he, himself, contracted silicosis even though he had worked only in mines that employed the improved "wet drilling" method. The legendary public health advocate Dr. Alice Hamilton, representing the Public Health Service, spoke on the medical aspects of industrial hygiene and showed that, despite industry's claims, little had improved over the past twenty-five years.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im April 1940 Minister fuer Arbeit Frances kam 
Perkins eine Konferenz in Missouri hinsichtlich ist der Silikosekrise 
zusammen, die in den späten dreißiger Jahren aufgetaucht war. 
Die unterscheidenen Perspektiven auf der Krankheit und 
Gesundheit der Arbeiter sind in diesen Excerpts von der 
Tristatesilikose-Konferenz offensichtlich. Evan gerade, 
Industrie darstellend, behauptete, daß Silikose ein Sozial ist, nicht
ein industrielles, Problem. Ehemaliger Bergarbeiter Tony McTeer 
diskutierte die gerechte Analyse und argumentierte, daß er, selbst, 
Vertrag Silikose abschloß, obwohl er nur in den Gruben gearbeitet 
hatte, die die verbesserte "nasse bohren" Methode einsetzten. 
Der legendäre Dr. Alice Hamilton Fürsprecher des öffentlichen
Gesundheitswesens, den öffentliches Gesundheitswesen-Service 
darstellend, sprach über die medizinischen Aspekte der industriellen 
Hygiene und zeigte dem, trotz der Ansprüche der Industrie, wenig 
hatte verbessert über den letzten fünfundzwanzig Jahren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le secrétaire d'avril 1940 du travail 
Frances Perkins a assemblé une conférence au Missouri au sujet de la
crise de silicose qui avait émergé vers la fin des années 30. 
Les perspectives différentes sur la maladie et la santé des 
ouvriers sont évidentes dans ces extraits de la conférence de trois 
états de silicose. Evan juste, représentant l'industrie, a 
réclamé que la silicose est une sociale, pas un industriel, 
problème. Le ancien mineur McTeer Élégant a contesté 
l'analyse juste, arguant du fait qu'il, a contracté lui-même la 
silicose quoiqu'il ait travaillé seulement dans les mines qui ont 
utilisé "la méthode de forage" humide améliorée. Le Dr. 
légendaire Alice Hamilton d'avocat de santé publique, représentant 
le service de santé publique, a parlé des aspects médicaux de 
l'hygiène industrielle et a montré à cela, en dépit des 
réclamations de l'industrie, à peu s'était amélioré au cours des 
vingt-cinq dernières années.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na secretária de abril 1940 de trabalho Frances 
Perkins reuniu uma conferência em Missouri a respeito da crise do 
silicosis que tinha emergido nos 1930s atrasados. Os 
perspectives diferindo na doença e na saúde dos trabalhadores são 
aparentes nestes excerpts da conferência tristate do silicosis. 
Evan apenas, representando a indústria, reivindicou que o 
silicosis é um social, não um industrial, problema. O ex-miner
McTeer tony disputou a análise justa, discutindo que, ele mesmo, 
contraiu o silicosis mesmo que trabalhasse somente nas minas que 
empregaram o método "perfurando" molhado melhorado. O Dr. 
legendário Alice Hamilton do advogado da saúde pública, 
representando o serviço de saúde pública, falou nos aspectos 
médicos da higiene industrial e mostrou a isso, apesar das 
reivindicações da indústria, a pouco tinha melhorado sobre os 
twenty-five anos passados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella segretaria di aprile del 1940 di Frances 
Di lavoro Perkins ha convocato un congresso nel Missouri riguardo 
alla crisi di silicosi che era emerso verso la fine dei 1930s. 
Le prospettive differenti sulla malattia e sulla salute degli 
operai sono apparenti in questi brani dal congresso di tre stati di 
silicosi. Evan appena, rappresentando l'industria, ha sostenuto 
che la silicosi è un sociale, non un industriale, problema. 
L'ex-minatore McTeer tony ha disputato l'analisi giusta, 
sostenente che, egli stesso, ha contratto la silicosi anche se aveva 
lavorato soltanto in miniere che hanno impiegato il metodo 
"perforante" bagnato migliorato. Il Dott. leggendario Alice 
Hamilton del fautore di sanità pubblica, rappresentante il servizio 
sanitario pubblico, ha parlato sulle funzioni mediche di salubrità ed
ha mostrato quello, malgrado i reclami dell'industria, piccolo aveva 
migliorato in questi ultimi venticinque anni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Απρίλιο του 1940 ο γραμματέας της εργασίας 
Frances Perkins συγκάλεσε μια διάσκεψη στο Μισσούρι σχετικά 
με την κρίση πυριτίασης που είχε προκύψει προς το τέλος της 
δεκαετίας του '30. Οι διαφορετικές προοπτικές στην ασθένεια 
και υγεία εργαζομένων τη "είναι προφανείς σε αυτά τα αποσπάσματα
από τη διάσκεψη πυριτίασης Tristate. Ο Evan Just, 
που αντιπροσωπεύει τη βιομηχανία, υποστήριξε ότι η πυριτίαση 
είναι μια κοινωνική, όχι ένας βιομηχανικός, πρόβλημα. Ex-miner Tony McTeer αμφισβήτησε τη δίκαιη ανάλυση, 
υποστηρίζοντας ότι, ο ίδιος, συμβλήθηκε την πυριτίαση ακόμα κι 
αν είχε εργαστεί μόνο στα ορυχεία που υιοθέτησαν τη βελτιωμένη 
μέθοδο "υγρών διατρήσεων". Ο θρυλικός συνήγορος δημόσιας 
υγείας ο Δρ Alice Χάμιλτον, που αντιπροσωπεύει την υπηρεσία 
δημόσιας υγείας, μίλησε στις ιατρικές πτυχές της βιομηχανικής 
υγιεινής και έδειξε ότι, παρά τις αξιώσεις της βιομηχανίας, 
λίγα είχαν βελτιωθεί κατά τη διάρκεια των προηγούμενων εικοσι 
πέντε ετών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la secretaria de abril de 1940 del trabajo 
Frances Perkins convocó una conferencia en Missouri referente a la 
crisis de la silicosis que había emergido en los últimos años 30. 
Las perspectivas que diferencian en la enfermedad y la salud de 
los trabajadores son evidentes en estos extractos de la conferencia de
triple estado de la silicosis. Evan apenas, representando 
industria, demandó que la silicosis es una social, no un industrial, 
problema. El minero McTeer tony disputó el análisis justo, 
discutiendo que él, sí mismo, contrajo silicosis aunque él había 
trabajado solamente en las minas que emplearon el método "que 
perforaba" mojado mejorado. El Dr. legendario Alicia Hamilton 
del abogado de la salud pública, representando el servicio médico 
público, habló en los aspectos médicos de la higiene industrial y 
mostró eso, a pesar de las demandas de la industria, a poco había 
mejorado sobre los últimos veinticinco años.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087226</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107072</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/what-you-really-want-is-an-autopsy-frances-perkins-and-the-u-s-government-conference-in-joplin-missouri-1940</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
