<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105484</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105484</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086799</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sarah Osborn Recollects Her Experiences in the Revolutionary War, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sarah Osborn bedenkt sie Erfahrungen im 
revolutionären Krieg, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sarah Osborn la rappelle des expériences de la 
guerre révolutionnaire, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sarah Osborn recorda-a experiências na guerra 
revolucionária, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sarah Osborn la ricorda esperienze di guerra 
rivoluzionaria, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Sarah Osborn ανακαλεί την εμπειρία της στον 
επαναστατικό πόλεμο, 1837</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sarah Osborn la recuerda las experiencias en la 
guerra revolucionaria, 1837</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Women participated actively in a variety of ways during the War for Independence; some even traveled with the Patriot army. Sarah Osborn was a servant in a blacksmith's household in Albany, New York, when she met and married Aaron Osborn, a blacksmith and Revolutionary war veteran, in 1780. When he re-enlisted as a commissary sergeant without informing her, Sarah agreed to accompany him. They went first to West Point, and Sarah later traveled with the Continental army for the campaign in the southern colonies, working as a washerwoman and cook. Her vivid description included a meeting with General Washington and memories of the surrender of British forces at Yorktown. This account comes from a deposition she filed in 1837, at the age of eighty-one, as part of a claim under the first pension act for Revolutionary war veterans and their widows.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frauen nahmen aktiv an einer Vielzahl von Methoden
während des Krieges für Unabhängigkeit teil; einige reisten 
sogar mit der Patriotarmee. Sarah Osborn war ein Bedienstetes im
Haushalt eines Schmiedes in Albanien, New York, als sie Aaron Osborn, 
ein Schmied und revolutionären Kriegveteran traf und verband, 1780. 
Als er als BeauftragtSergeant re-enlisted, ohne sie zu 
informieren,WAR Sarah damit einverstanden, ihn zu begleiten. Sie
gingen zuerst zum Westpunkt, und Sarah reiste später mit der 
kontinentalen Armee für die Kampagne in den südlichen Kolonien und 
arbeitete als Washerwoman und Koch. Ihre klare Beschreibung 
schloß eine Sitzung mit General Washington und Speicher der 
Auslieferung der britischen Kräfte bei Yorktown ein. Dieses 
Konto kommt von einer Absetzung, die sie 1837 archivierte, am Alter 
von eighty-one, als Teil eines Anspruches unter die erste Pensiontat 
für revolutionäre Kriegveterane und ihre Witwen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les femmes ont participé activement à une 
variété de voies pendant la guerre pour l'indépendance ; 
certains ont même voyagé avec l'armée de patriote. 
Sarah Osborn était un domestique dans le ménage d'un forgeron 
à Albany, New York, quand elle a rencontré et a marié Aaron Osborn,
un forgeron et ancien combattant révolutionnaire, en 1780. 
Quand il re-enlisted en tant que sergent de commissaire sans
l'informer, Sarah a accepté de l'accompagner. Ils sont allés 
d'abord au point occidental, et Sarah plus tard a voyagé avec 
l'armée continentale pour la campagne dans les colonies 
méridionales, travaillant en tant qu'une blanchisseuse et cuisinier. 
Sa description vive a inclus une réunion avec le Général 
Washington et mémoires de la reddition des forces britanniques chez 
Yorktown. Ce compte relève d'un dépôt qu'elle a classé en 
1837, à l'âge de l'eighty-one, en tant qu'élément d'une 
réclamation du premier acte de pension pour les anciens combattants 
révolutionnaires et leurs veuves.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As mulheres participaram ativamente em uma 
variedade das maneiras durante a guerra para a independência; 
alguns viajaram mesmo com o exército do patriot. Sarah 
Osborn era um empregado na casa de um ferreiro em Albany, New York, 
quando se encontrou com e se casou Aaron Osborn, um ferreiro e veteran
de guerra revolucionário, em 1780. Quando re-enlisted como um 
sergeant do commissary sem a informar, Sarah concordou acompanhá-lo. 
Foram primeiramente ao ponto ocidental, e Sarah viajou mais 
tarde com o exército continental para a campanha nas colônias do 
sul, trabalhando como um washerwoman e um cozinheiro. Sua 
descrição vívida incluiu uma reunião com general Washington e 
memórias da rendição de forças britânicas em Yorktown. Este
cliente vem de um deposition que arquivou em 1837, na idade do 
eighty-one, como a parte de uma reivindicação sob o primeiro ato da 
pensão para veterans de guerra revolucionários e suas viúvas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le donne hanno partecipato attivamente ad una 
varietà di modi durante la guerra per indipendenza; alcuni 
persino hanno viaggiato con l'esercito del patriot. Sarah Osborn
era un servo nella famiglia del fabbro a Albany, New York, quando ha 
venuto a contatto e sposato di Aaron Osborn, un fabbro e veterano di 
guerra rivoluzionario, in 1780. Quando re-enlisted come sergeant
del commissario senza informarla, Sarah ha accosentito per 
accompagnarlo. Sono andato in primo luogo a punto ad ovest e 
Sarah più successivamente ha viaggiato con l'esercito continentale 
per la campagna nelle colonie del sud, funzionando come un washerwoman
e cuoco. La sua descrizione chiara ha incluso una riunione con 
il General Washington e memorie della resa delle forze britanniche a 
Yorktown. Questo cliente viene da un deposito che ha archiviato 
in 1837, all'età del eighty-one, come componente di un reclamo a 
norma della prima legge di pensione per i veterani di guerra 
rivoluzionari e le loro vedove.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι γυναίκες συμμετείχαν ενεργά με ποικίλους τρόπους 
κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου για την ανεξαρτησία  μερικοί 
ταξίδεψαν ακόμη και με το στρατό πατριωτών. Το Sarah 
Osborn ήταν υπάλληλος στην οικογένεια ενός σιδηρουργού στο 
Αλμπανυ, Νέα Υόρκη, όταν συνάντησε και πάντρεψε τον Aaron 
Osborn, έναν σιδηρουργό και έναν επαναστατικό πολεμικό 
παλαίμαχο, το 1780. Όταν επαν-που στρατολογήθηκε ως 
commissary λοχίας χωρίς πληροφόρηση την, Sarah συμφώνησε να 
τον συνοδεύσει. Πήγαν πρώτα στο δυτικό σημείο, και Sarah
ταξίδεψε αργότερα με τον ηπειρωτικό στρατό για την εκστρατεία 
στις νότιες αποικίες, που λειτουργούν ως πλύστρα και μάγειρας. 
Η ζωηρή περιγραφή της περιέλαβε μια συνεδρίαση με το 
στρατηγό Washington και μνήμες της παράδοσης των βρετανικών 
δυνάμεων σε Yorktown. Αυτός ο απολογισμός προέρχεται από
μια απόθεση που αρχειοθέτησε το 1837, στην ηλικία ογδόντα 
ενός, ως τμήμα μιας αξίωσης κάτω από την πρώτη συνταξιοδοτική 
πράξη για τους επαναστατικούς πολεμικούς παλαιμάχους και τις 
χήρες τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las mujeres participaron activamente en una 
variedad de maneras durante la guerra para la independencia; 
algunos incluso viajaron con el ejército del patriota. 
Sarah Osborn era criado en la casa de un herrero en Albany, 
Nueva York, cuando ella resolvió y casó Aaron Osborn, herrero y 
veterano de guerra revolucionario, en 1780. Cuando él alistó 
de nuevo como sargento del comisario sin informarle, Sarah acordó 
acompañarlo. Fueron primero a la punta del oeste, y Sarah 
viajó más adelante con el ejército continental para la campaña en 
las colonias meridionales, trabajando como un washerwoman y cocinero. 
Su descripción viva incluyó una reunión con el general 
Washington y memorias de la entrega de fuerzas británicas en 
Yorktown. Esta cuenta viene de una deposición que ella 
clasifió en 1837, en la edad del eighty-one, como parte de una 
demanda bajo primer acto de la pensión para los veteranos de guerra 
revolucionarios y sus viudas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086799</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105484</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sarah-osborn-recollects-her-experiences-in-the-revolutionary-war-1837</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
