<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104971</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104971</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205863</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Influences of Art on Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Einflüsse der kunst auf Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les influences de l'art sur Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As influências da arte em Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le influenze di arte su Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι επιρροές της τέχνης σε Yellowstone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las influencias del arte en Yellowstone</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features paintings, photos, and drawings, many of which contributed to the creation of the nation's first national park. The waterfalls, geysers, rock formations, and vistas in these works helped spread an appreciation of the wonders of Yellowstone. When President Grant signed into law the bill establishing Yellowstone as our first national park in 1872, he set in motion the tradition of preserving other tracts of great beauty for future generations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet Anstriche, Fotos und Zeichnungen, von 
denen viele zur Kreation des ersten Nationalparks der Nation 
beitrugen. Die Wasserfälle, die Geysire, die Felsenanordnungen 
und die vistas in diesen Arbeiten geholfen, eine Anerkennung der 
Wunder von Yellowstone zu verbreiten. Als Präsident Grant in 
Gesetz die Rechnung Yellowstone als unser erster Nationalpark 1872 
herstellend unterzeichnete, stellte er in Bewegung die Tradition des 
Konservierens anderer Flächen der großen Schönheit für zukünftige
Erzeugungen ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte des peintures, des photos, et des 
schémas, dont beaucoup ont contribué à la création du premier parc
national de la nation. Les chutes d'eau, les geysers, les 
formations de roche, et les vistas dans ces travaux aidés pour 
écarter une appréciation des merveilles de Yellowstone. Quand 
le Président Grant a signé dans la loi la facture établissant 
Yellowstone en tant que notre premier parc national en 1872, il a mis 
en marche la tradition de préserver d'autres régions de grande 
beauté pour de futures générations.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza pinturas, fotos, e desenhos, muitos de
que contribuíram à criação do primeiro parque nacional da nação.
As cachoeiras, os geysers, as formações de rocha, e os vistas 
nestes trabalhos ajudados espalhar uma apreciação das maravilhas de 
Yellowstone. Quando o presidente Grant assinou na lei a conta 
que estabelece Yellowstone como nosso primeiro parque nacional em 
1872, ajustou no movimento a tradição de preservar outros intervalos
da beleza grande para as gerações futuras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza le pitture, le foto e le 
illustrazioni, molti di cui hanno contribuito alla creazione del primo
parco nazionale della nazione. Le cascate, i geyser, le 
formazioni rocciose ed i vistas in questi impianti contribuiti per 
spargere un apprezzamento dei wonders di Yellowstone. Quando il 
presidente Grant ha firmato in legge la fattura che stabilisce 
Yellowstone come nostro primo parco nazionale in 1872, ha regolato nel
movimento la tradizione di conservazione degli altri tratti della 
bellezza grande per le generazioni future.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τα έργα ζωγραφικής, τις φωτογραφίες, και 
τα σχέδια, πολλά από τα οποία συνέβαλαν στη δημιουργία του 
πρώτου εθνικού πάρκου του έθνους. Οι καταρράκτες, 
geysers, οι σχηματισμοί βράχου, και vistas σε αυτές τις 
εργασίες που ενισχύονται να διαδώσουν μια εκτίμηση αναρωτιούνται 
Yellowstone. Όταν ο Πρόεδρος Grant υπέγραψε στο νόμο 
το λογαριασμό που καθιερώνει Yellowstone ως πρώτο εθνικό πάρκο
μας το 1872, έθεσε σε κίνηση την παράδοση της συντήρησης άλλων
κομματιών της μεγάλης ομορφιάς για τις μελλοντικές γενεές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece pinturas, las fotos, y los gráficos, 
muchos de los cuales contribuyeron a la creación del primer parque 
nacional de la nación. Las cascadas, los géiseres, las 
formaciones de roca, y los vistas en estos trabajos ayudados para 
separar un aprecio de las maravillas de Yellowstone. Cuando 
presidente Grant firmó en ley la cuenta que establecía Yellowstone 
como nuestro primer parque nacional en 1872, él fijó en el 
movimiento la tradición de preservar otras zonas de la gran belleza 
para las generaciones futuras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205863</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104971</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-influences-of-art-on-yellowstone</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
