<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107895</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107895</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087466</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Can I Scrub Your White Marble Steps?"A Black Migrant Recalls Life in Philadelphia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"kann ich Ihre weiße Marmorsteps?"A schwarze 
Wander- Rückruf-Lebensdauer in Philadelphia scheuern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"peux je frotter votre vie migratrice noire de 
marbre blanche de rappels de Steps?"A à Philadelphie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"posso eu esfregar sua vida emigrante preta de 
mármore branca das recordações de Steps?"A em Filadélfia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"posso fregare la vostra vita migratore nera di 
marmo bianca di richiami di Steps?"A a Filadelfia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μπορώ να τρίψω την άσπρη μαρμάρινη μαύρη 
αποδημητική ζωή ανακλήσεων Steps?"A σας στη Φιλαδέλφεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"puedo fregar su vida migratoria negra de mármol 
blanca de memorias de Steps?"A en Philadelphia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1910s hundreds of thousands of African Americans headed North in the Great Migration. Arthur Dingle was one of them. Dingle was born in the small town of Manning, North Carolina, in 1891. After holding hotel jobs in several cities, he took a job with the Pennsylvania Railroad in Philadelphia. Promised his job back if he enlisted in World War I, the company made good on its promise when Dingle remained in Philadelphia after the war. This interview with Arthur Dingle was conducted by Charles Hardy in 1983 for the Goin' North Project.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den 1910s gehen die Hunderte von Tausenden der 
afrikanischen Amerikaner nördlich in der großen Migration voran. 
Arthur Dingle war eins von ihnen. Dingle wurde in der 
kleinen Stadt des Bemannens, Nord-Carolina, 1891 getragen. 
Nachdem er Hoteljobs in einigen Städte angehalten hatte, nahm 
er einen Job mit der Pennsylvania Eisenbahn in Philadelphia. 
Versprach seine Jobrückseite, wenn er im Ersten Weltkrieg 
eintrug, die Firma gebildet gut auf seiner Versprechung, als Dingle in
Philadelphia nach dem Krieg blieb. Dieses Interview mit Arthur 
Dingle wurde von Charles Hardy 1983 für das Goin ' Nordprojekt 
geleitet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les années 10 les centaines de milliers 
d'Américains africains dirigent le nord dans le grand 
transfert. Arthur Dingle était l'une d'entre elles. 
Dingle a été soutenu dans la petite ville de l'homme, 
Caroline du nord, en 1891. Après avoir tenu les travaux 
d'hôtel dans plusieurs villes, il a pris un travail avec le chemin de
fer de la Pennsylvanie à Philadelphie. A promis son dos du 
travail s'il enrôlait dans la Première Guerre Mondiale, la compagnie
réparée sur sa promesse quand Dingle est resté à Philadelphie 
après la guerre. Cette entrevue avec Arthur Dingle a été 
conduite par Charles Hardy en 1983 projet du nord pour Goin '.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1910s as centenas dos milhares de americanos 
africanos dirigem para o norte na migração grande. Arthur 
Dingle era um delas. Dingle foi carregado na cidade pequena de 
equipar, North.carolina, em 1891. Após ter prendido trabalhos 
do hotel em diversas cidades, fêz exame de um trabalho com a estrada 
de ferro de Pensilvânia em Filadélfia. Prometeu sua parte 
traseira se se alistasse no world.war.i, a companhia do trabalho feita
boa em sua promessa quando Dingle remanesceu em Filadélfia após a 
guerra. Esta entrevista com Arthur Dingle foi conduzida por 
Charles Hardy em 1983 para o projeto norte do Goin '.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli anni 10 le centinaia dei migliaia degli 
Americani africani dirigono a nord nell'espansione grande. 
Arthur Dingle era una di loro. Dingle è stato sopportato 
nella piccola città dell'uomo, North.carolina, in 1891. Dopo i 
lavori dell'hotel della tenuta in parecchie città, ha preso un 
lavoro con la ferrovia della Pensilvania a Filadelfia. Ha 
promesso la sua parte posteriore se arruolasse nel world.war.i, 
l'azienda di lavoro compensata sulla relativa promessa quando Dingle 
è rimasto a Filadelfia dopo la guerra. Questa intervista con 
Arthur Dingle è stata condotta da Charles Hardy in 1983 per progetto 
del nord Goin '.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σε 1910s εκατοντάδες χιλιάδες αφρικανικών 
Αμερικανών διεύθυναν το Βορρά στη μεγάλη μετανάστευση. 
Αρθούρος Dingle ήταν ένας από τους. Dingle 
γεννήθηκε στη μικρή πόλη της επάνδρωσης, βόρεια Καρολίνα, το 
1891. Μετά από να κρατήσει τις εργασίες ξενοδοχείων σε 
διάφορες πόλεις, ανάλαβε δουλειά με το σιδηρόδρομο της 
Πενσυλβανίας στη Φιλαδέλφεια. Υποσχέθηκε την πλάτη εργασίας
του εάν στρατολόγησε στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, η επιχείρηση που 
έγινε το αγαθό στην υπόσχεσή του όταν παρέμεινε dingle στη 
Φιλαδέλφεια μετά από τον πόλεμο. Αυτή η συνέντευξη με 
αρθούρο Dingle πραγματοποιήθηκε από Charles Hardy το 
1983 για "βόρειο το Goin πρόγραμμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años 10 los centenares de millares de 
americanos africanos dirigieron al norte en la gran migración. 
Arturo Dingle era uno de ellos. Dingle fue llevado en la 
ciudad pequeña de servir, Carolina del Norte, en 1891. Después
de llevar a cabo trabajos del hotel en varias ciudades, él tomó un 
trabajo con el ferrocarril de Pennsylvania en Philadelphia. 
Prometió su parte posteriora si él alistó en Primera Guerra 
Mundial, la compañía del trabajo hecha buena en su promesa cuando 
Dingle permanecía en Philadelphia después de la guerra. Esta 
entrevista con Arturo Dingle fue conducida por Charles Hardy en 1983 
para el proyecto del norte del Goin '.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087466</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107895</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/can-i-scrub-your-white-marble-steps-a-black-migrant-recalls-life-in-philadelphia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
