<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/74125</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>74125</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>SDT</catalog>
            <entry>848fb71b-c020-4f3f-bcdd-821dbd67e534#1#4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="hu">Nagy Sándor</string>
            <string language="en">Alexander the Great</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alexander das große</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Alexandre le grand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alexander o grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alexander il grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αλέξανδρος ο μεγάλος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alexander el grande</string>
          </title>
          <language>hu</language>
          <description>
            <string language="hu">Nagy Sándor (A görög festészet az utókorra csak másolatban – főleg mozaikokban – megörökített alkotásokat hagyott. Ilyen volt Pompeji városban a lávatenger alatt megtalált Nagy Sándorról készült festmény mozaikmásolata. Ez az alkotás csak másolat ugyan, művészi értéke azonban vitathatatlan.)</string>
            <string language="en">Alexander the Great (The greek painting handed down only copies recorded mainly in mosaics. Such mosaic copy was the painting on Alexander the Great founded in the city of Pompeji under the lavasea. This work is only a copy, but its artistic value is unarguable</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="hu">nagy sándor pompej</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alexander das große (der griechische Anstrich 
übergab hinunter die nur Exemplare, die hauptsächlich in den 
Mosaiken gespeichert wurden. Solches Mosaikexemplar war der 
Anstrich auf Alexander das große gegründet in der Stadt von Pompeji 
unter dem lavasea. Diese Arbeit ist nur ein Exemplar, aber sein 
künstlerischer Wert ist unarguable</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Alexandre le grand (la peinture grecque remise en
bas seulement des copies enregistrées principalement dans les 
mosaïques. Une telle copie de mosaïque était la peinture sur 
Alexandre le grand fondé dans la ville de Pompeji sous le lavasea. 
Ce travail est seulement une copie, mais son valeur artistique 
est indiscutable</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alexander o grande (a pintura grega entregou 
abaixo somente as cópias gravadas principalmente nos mosaics. 
Tal cópia do mosaic era a pintura em Alexander o grande fundado
na cidade de Pompeji sob o lavasea. Este trabalho é somente uma
cópia, mas seu valor artístico é unarguable</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alexander il grande (la pittura greca trasmessa 
soltanto le copie registrate pricipalmente in mosaici. Tale 
copia del mosaico era la pittura su Alexander il grande fondato nella 
città di Pompeji sotto il lavasea. Questo lavoro è soltanto 
una copia, ma il relativo valore artistico è unarguable</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αλέξανδρος ο μεγάλος (η ελληνική ζωγραφική που 
δίνεται κάτω από μόνο τα αντίγραφα που καταγράφονται κυρίως στα
μωσαϊκά. Τέτοιο αντίγραφο μωσαϊκών ήταν η ζωγραφική στον
Αλέξανδρο ο μεγάλος που ιδρύθηκε στην πόλη Pompeji κάτω από 
το lavasea. Αυτή η εργασία είναι μόνο ένα αντίγραφο, 
αλλά η καλλιτεχνική αξία της είναι μη συζητήσιμη</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alexander el grande (la pintura griega dio abajo 
solamente de las copias registradas principalmente en mosaicos. 
Tal copia del mosaico era la pintura en Alexander el grande 
fundado en la ciudad de Pompeji bajo el lavasea. Este trabajo es
solamente una copia, pero su valor artístico es unarguable</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>image</value>
          </learningResourceType>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="hu">A tartalom kizárólag kizárólag az oktatás illetve tudományos kutatás céljára használható szigorúan non-profit jelleggel.</string>
            <string language="en">The content may be used for the sole purpose of illustration for teaching or scientific research and only for a strictly non-commercial purpose.</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard 
version:3.0
n:;
fn:
org:Kossuth Kiadó Rt.
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>856</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
        org:Sulinet
        version:3.0
        end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>74125</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://sdt.sulinet.hu/Player/default.aspx?g=848fb71b-c020-4f3f-bcdd-821dbd67e534&amp;v=1&amp;b=4</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
