<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/87016</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>87016</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:ait.opetaja.ee:7a475efda10f7100f3e37c0c6cb4753d5bd55fd5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>1</catalog>
            <entry>7a475efda10f7100f3e37c0c6cb4753d5bd55fd5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="et">Sõnavara</string>
            <string language="en">Vocabulary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wortschatz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vocabulaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vocabulário</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vocabolario</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λεξιλόγιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vocabulario</string>
          </title>
          <language>et</language>
          <description>
            <string language="et">Veebilehel on kogumik harjutusi, e-teste, ristsõnu ning slaidiprogramme, mis on mõeldud kasutamiseks I ja II kooliastmes emakeele tundide lõimimiseks arvutiõpetusega. Neid materjale saab õpetaja kasutada nii tunni alguses häälestamiseks ja huvi äratamiseks kui ka tunni lõpus kokkuvõtete tegemiseks ning tähelepanu hoidmiseks, kui laps hakkab väsima. Valminud materjale on võimalik kasutada töös kogu klassiga või siis individuaalseks kasutamiseks õppetöö diferentseerimisel. Kogumik on kasutajasõbralik ning kujundus lastepärane. Töölehtede tegevusjuhised on üheselt mõistetavad, erinevate ülesannete käivitamine on lihtne. Ülesannetes on kerge orienteeruda, seetõttu on selle iseseisev kasutamine jõukohane ka õpiraskustega õpilastele.</string>
            <string language="en">Webpage includes a collection of e-tests, crosswords and slideshows meant for integration of mother tongue and computer study in the 1st and 2nd stage of study. These tests can be used both as warm-up exercises at the beginning of the lessons and as attention keeping exercises when a child starts to lose attention. The material can be used for the whole class or for individual teaching. The collection is user-friendly and design is meant for children. Worksheet rubrics are easily understood; opening of different tasks is easy. It is easy to navigate on the webpage, so even students with special need manage to do it.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="et">Algõpetus</string>
            <string language="et">Eesti keel</string>
            <string language="et">sõnavara</string>
            <string language="en">Basic School</string>
            <string language="en">Estonian language</string>
            <string language="en">Vocabulary</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Webseite schließt eine Ansammlung Etests, 
Kreuzworträtsel und Slideshows ein, die für Integration der 
Muttersprache- und Computeruntersuchung im 1. und 2. Stadium der 
Studie bedeutet werden. Diese Tests können als Vorwärmung 
Übungen am Anfang der Lektionen benutzt werden und als 
Aufmerksamkeit, die Übungen hält, wenn ein Kind beginnt, 
Aufmerksamkeit zu verlieren. Das Material kann für die 
vollständige Kategorie oder für einzelnen Unterricht benutzt werden.
Die Ansammlung ist benutzerfreundlich und Design wird für 
Kinder bedeutet. Bogenrubriken werden leicht verstanden; 
Öffnung der unterschiedlichen Aufgaben ist einfach. Zu 
steuern ist einfach, auf der Webseite, also handhaben gleichmäßige 
Kursteilnehmer mit spezieller Notwendigkeit, sie zu tun.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La page Web inclut une collection d'e-essais, de
mots croisé et de présentations signifiés pour l'intégration de 
l'enquête sur ordinateur de langue maternelle et dans la 1ère et 
2ème étape de l'étude. Ces essais peuvent être utilisés 
comme exercices de préchauffage au début des leçons et comme 
attention gardant des exercices quand un enfant commence à détruire 
l'attention. Le matériel peut être utilisé pour la classe 
entière ou pour l'enseignement individuel. La collection est 
conviviale et la conception est signifiée pour des enfants. Des
rubriques de tableau sont facilement comprises ; l'ouverture de 
différent charge est facile. Il est facile de diriger 
sur la page Web, ainsi les étudiants égaux avec le besoin spécial
parviennent à le faire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web page inclui uma coleção dos e-testes, dos 
crosswords e dos slideshows significados para a integração do estudo
de lingüeta e de computador de matriz no 1o e ò estágio do estudo. 
Estes testes podem ser usados  como exercícios do warm-up no 
começo das lições e como a atenção que mantem exercícios quando 
uma criança começa perder a atenção. O material pode ser 
usado para a classe inteira ou para o ensino individual. A 
coleção é user-friendly e o projeto é significado para crianças. 
Os rubrics da folha são compreendidos fàcilmente; a 
abertura de tarefas diferentes é fácil. É fácil navigate no 
Web page, assim que os estudantes uniformes com necessidade especial 
controlam fazê-la.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web page include una collezione di e-prove, di
parole incrociate e di slideshows significati per integrazione della 
ricerca su ordinatore della lingua materna e nella prima e seconda 
fase dello studio. Queste prove possono essere usate sia come 
esercitazioni di preriscaldamento all'inizio delle lezioni che come 
attenzione che mantiene le esercitazioni quando un bambino comincia 
perdere l'attenzione. Il materiale può essere usato per il 
codice categoria intero o per insegnamento specifico. 
L'accumulazione è facile da usare ed il disegno è significato 
per i bambini. Le rubriche del foglio di lavoro sono capite 
facilmente; l'apertura delle mansioni differenti è facile. 
È facile da traversare sul Web page, in modo da gli allievi 
uniformi con bisogno speciale riescono a farli.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Webpage περιλαμβάνει μια συλλογή των ε-δοκιμών, 
σταυρόλεξα και slideshows σημαμένος για την ολοκλήρωση της 
μητρικής γλώσσας και της μελέτης υπολογιστών στο 1$ο και 2$ο 
στάδιο της μελέτης. Αυτές οι δοκιμές μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν και ως ασκήσεις προθέρμανσης στην αρχή των 
μαθημάτων και ως προσοχή που κρατά τις ασκήσεις όταν αρχίζει να 
χάνει ένα παιδί την προσοχή. Το υλικό μπορεί να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί για ολόκληρη την κλάση ή για τη μεμονωμένη 
διδασκαλία. Η συλλογή είναι φιλική προς το χρήστη και το 
σχέδιο σημαίνουν για τα παιδιά. Οι ρουμπρίκες φύλλων 
εργασίας γίνονται κατανοητές εύκολα  το άνοιγμα των 
διαφορετικών στοιχειωδών εργασιών είναι εύκολο. Είναι 
εύκολο να πλοηγήσει στο webpage, τόσο ακόμη και οι σπουδαστές 
με ειδική ανάγκη κατορθώνουν να το κάνουν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web page incluye una colección de e-pruebas, 
de crucigramas y de slideshows significados para la integración del 
estudio materno del lengua y por computadora en la 1ra y 2da etapa del
estudio. Estas pruebas se pueden utilizar como ejercicios del 
calentamiento en el principio de las lecciones y como atención que 
guarda ejercicios cuando un niño comienza a perder la atención. 
El material se puede utilizar para la clase entera o para la 
enseñanza individual. La colección es convivial y el diseño 
se significa para los niños. Las rúbricas de la hoja de 
trabajo se entienden fácilmente; la apertura de diversas tareas
es fácil. Es fácil navegar en el Web page, así que los 
estudiantes uniformes con necesidad especial manejan hacerla.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grundlegende Schule</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Estnische Sprache</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wortschatz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">École de base</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Langage estonien</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vocabulaire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escola Básica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Língua estonian</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vocabulário</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scuola Di base</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lingua estone</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vocabolario</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βασικό σχολείο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εσθονική γλώσσα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λεξιλόγιο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escuela Básica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lenguaje estonio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vocabulario</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;;;;
FN:Tuuli Koitjärv
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:ait.opetaja.ee:7a475efda10f7100f3e37c0c6cb4753d5bd55fd5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>et</language>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>1</catalog>
            <entry>7a475efda10f7100f3e37c0c6cb4753d5bd55fd5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Tallinn University
N:Tallinn University
ORG:Tallinn University
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-04-03T20:56:19.58Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-LRE">6-11</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>web page</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>440</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1024</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>87016</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ait.opetaja.ee/WaramuWeb/metadata?catalog=1&amp;id=7a475efda10f7100f3e37c0c6cb4753d5bd55fd5</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
