<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/29764</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>29764</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_7531</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7531</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7531</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">18.062J Mathematics for Computer Science, Fall 2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik 18.062J für Informatik, Fall 2005 
(MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">mathématiques 18.062J pour l'informatique, automne
2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">matemática 18.062J para a informática de, queda 
2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">matematica 18.062J per informatica, caduta 2005 
(MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">18.062J μαθηματικά για την πληροφορική, πτώση του 
2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">matemáticas 18.062J para la informática, caída 
2005 (MIT)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "Mathematical tools and methods for computer science and engineering. Emphasis on development of rigorous thinking, analytical skills, and mathematical sophistication while learning elementary discrete mathematics. Topics: mathematical proofs; induction and well-ordering; divisibility and congruences; asymptotic notation and growth of functions; sets, relations, functions, and graphs; counting theory; recurrences and generating functions; and discrete probability.  Description from course home page:  This is an introductory course in Discrete Mathematics oriented toward Computer Science and Engineering. The course divides roughly into thirds:  Fundamental Concepts of Mathematics: Definitions, Proofs, Sets, Functions, Relations  Discrete Structures: Modular Arithmetic, Graphs, State Machines, Counting  Discrete Probability Theory  A version of this course from a previous term was also taught as part of the Singapore-MIT Alliance (SMA) programme as course number SMA 5512 (Mathematics for Computer Science). "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">counting principles</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">sets</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">integer congruences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">structural induction</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">permutations and combinations</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">asymptotic notation and growth of functions</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">mathematical definitions</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">generating functions</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">computer science</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">recursive definition</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">formal logic notation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">proofs and applicable methods</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">well-ordering</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">recurrences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Computer Science</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">discrete probability</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">relations</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">induction</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">proof methods</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">state machines and invariants</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">elementary graph theory</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">discrete mathematics</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web site 
(http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute of 
Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "mathematische Hilfsmittel und Methoden für 
Informatik und Technik. Hauptgewicht auf Entwicklung des 
rigorosen Denkens, der analytischen Fähigkeiten und der 
mathematischen Weltklugheit beim Lernen der grundlegenden getrennten 
Mathematik. Themen: mathematische Beweise; Induktion
und gut-Einrichtung; Teilbarkeit und Übereinstimmungen; 
asymptotische Darstellung und Wachstum von Funktionen; 
Sets, Relationen, Funktionen und Diagramme; Zählen von 
von Theorie; Wiederauftreten und festlegen Funktionen; und
getrennte Wahrscheinlichkeit. Beschreibung vom Kurshome Page: 
Dieses ist ein Einleitungskurs in der getrennten Mathematik, die
in Richtung zur Informatik und der Technik orientiert wird. Der 
Kurs teilt sich ungefähr in an dritter Stelle: Grundlegende 
Konzepte von Mathematik: Definitionen, Beweise, Sets, 
Funktionen, Relationen Getrennte Strukturen: Modulare 
Arithmetik, Diagramme, die Zustand-Maschinen, getrennte Version der 
Wahrscheinlichkeitstheorie A dieses Kurses von einer vorhergehenden 
Bezeichnung zählend wurde auch als Teil des Programms des Bündnisses
Singapur-MIT (SMA) als Kurszahl SMA 5512 unterrichtet (Mathematik für
Informatik). "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare
(http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "outils 
mathématiques et méthodes pour l'informatique et l'ingénierie. 
Emphase sur le développement de la pensée rigoureuse, des 
qualifications analytiques, et de la sophistication mathématique tout
en apprenant des mathématiques discrètes élémentaires. 
Sujets : preuves mathématiques ; induction et 
bien-ordre ; divisibilité et congruences ; notation 
asymptotique et croissance des fonctions ; positionnements, 
relations, fonctions, et graphiques ; compte de la théorie ; 
répétitions et fonctions de se produire ; et 
probabilité discrète. Description de Home Page de cours : 
C'est un cours d'initiation des mathématiques discrètes 
orientées vers l'informatique et l'ingénierie. Le cours se 
divise rudement en troisièmement : Concepts fondamentaux des 
mathématiques : Définitions, Preuves, Positionnements, 
Fonctions, Structures Discrètes de Relations : On a également 
enseigné l'arithmétique modulaire, graphiques, machines d'état, 
comptant la version discrète de la théorie des probabilités A de ce
cours d'une limite précédente en tant qu'élément du programme de 
l'alliance Singapour-MIT (SMA) comme nombre SMA 5512 de cours (des 
mathématiques pour l'informatique). "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT OpenCourseWare
(http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de Tecnología de 
Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre para que 
qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do uso. 
A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "ferramentas matemáticas e métodos para a 
informática e a engenharia de. Ênfase no desenvolvimento de 
pensar rigorous, de habilidades analíticas, e do sophistication 
matemático ao aprender a matemática discreta elementar. 
Tópicos: provas matemáticas; indução e 
bem-requisitar; divisibility e congruences; notação 
asymptotic e crescimento das funções; jogos, relações, 
funções, e gráficos; contando a teoria; retornos e 
funções gerar; e probabilidade discreta. Descrição do 
Home Page do curso: Este é um curso introdutório na 
matemática discreta orientada para a informática e a engenharia de. 
O curso divide-se aproximadamente em em terceiro lugar: 
Conceitos fundamentais da matemática: Definições, 
Provas, Jogos, Funções, Estruturas Discretas Das Relações: A
aritmética modular, gráficos, máquinas do estado, contando a 
versão discreta da teoria de probabilidade A deste curso de um termo 
precedente foi ensinada também enquanto parte do programa do alliance
Singapore-Singapore-MIT (SMA) como o número SMA 5512 do curso 
(matemática para a informática de). "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "strumenti matematici e metodi per 
informatica ed ingegneria. Enfasi su sviluppo pensare rigoroso, 
di abilità analitiche e di elaborazione matematica mentre imparando 
matematica discreta elementare. Soggetti: prove 
matematiche; induzione e bene-ordinare; divisibilità e 
congruenze; notazione asintotica e sviluppo delle funzioni; 
insiemi, rapporti, funzioni e grafici; conteggio della 
teoria; ricorrenze e funzioni di generazione; e 
probabilità discreta. Descrizione dal Home Page di corso: 
Ciò è un corso introduttivo nella matematica discreta 
orientata verso l'informatica e l'ingegneria. Il corso si divide
approssimativamente nei terzo: Concetti fondamentali di 
matematica: Definizioni, Prove, Insiemi, Funzioni, Strutture 
Discrete Di Rapporti: L'aritmetica modulare, grafici, 
Dichiara le macchine, contanti la versione discreta di teoria 
delle probabilità A di questo corso da un termine precedente 
egualmente è stata insegnata come componente il 
Singapore-Singapore-MIT del programma di alleanza (SMA) come numero 
SMA 5512 di corso (matematica per informatica). "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Μαθηματικά εργαλεία και μέθοδοι για την πληροφορική και την
εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική. Έμφαση στην ανάπτυξη της αυστηρής 
σκέψης, των αναλυτικών δεξιοτήτων, και της μαθηματικής 
εκλέπτυνσης μαθαίνοντας τα στοιχειώδη ιδιαίτερα μαθηματικά. 
Θέματα: μαθηματικές αποδείξεις  επαγωγή και 
καλά-διαταγή  divisibility και συμφωνίες  
ασυμπτωτικές σημείωση και αύξηση των λειτουργιών  
σύνολα, σχέσεις, λειτουργίες, και γραφικές παραστάσεις  
μετρώντας θεωρία  επαναλήψεις και παραγωγικές 
λειτουργίες  και ιδιαίτερη πιθανότητα. Περιγραφή από 
την αρχική σελίδα σειράς μαθημάτων: Αυτό είναι μια 
εισαγωγική σειρά μαθημάτων στα ιδιαίτερα μαθηματικά που 
προσανατολίζονται προς την πληροφορική και την εφαρμοσμένη 
μηχανική. Η σειρά μαθημάτων διαιρεί κατά προσέγγιση σε 
τρίτα: Θεμελιώδεις έννοιες των μαθηματικών: Ορισμοί, 
αποδείξεις, σύνολα, λειτουργίες, ιδιαίτερες δομές σχέσεων: 
Η μορφωματική αριθμητική, γραφικές παραστάσεις, κρατικές 
μηχανές, μετρώντας ιδιαίτερη έκδοση θεωρίας πιθανότητας Α αυτής
της σειράς μαθημάτων από έναν προηγούμενο όρο διδάχθηκε επίσης
ως τμήμα του προγράμματος συμμαχίας Σινγκαπούρη- Mit (SMA) 
ως αριθμός SMA 5512 σειράς μαθημάτων (μαθηματικά για την 
πληροφορική). "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
"herramientas matemáticas y métodos para la informática y la 
ingeniería. Énfasis en el desarrollo del pensamiento riguroso,
de habilidades analíticas, y de la sofisticación matemática 
mientras que aprende matemáticas discretas elementales. 
Asuntos: pruebas matemáticas; inducción y 
bien-peticio'n; divisibilidad y congruencias; notación 
asintótica y crecimiento de funciones; conjuntos, relaciones, 
funciones, y gráficos; cuenta de teoría; repeticiones y 
funciones de la generación; y probabilidad discreta. 
Descripción del Home Page del curso: Esto es un curso 
preliminar en las matemáticas discretas orientadas hacia la 
informática y la ingeniería. El curso se divide áspero en 
tercero: Conceptos fundamentales de las matemáticas: 
Definiciones, Pruebas, Conjuntos, Funciones, Estructuras 
Discretas De las Relaciones: La aritmética modular, gráficos, 
máquinas del estado, contando la versión discreta de la teoría de 
las probabilidades A de este curso de un término anterior también 
fue enseñada como parte del programa de la alianza 
Singapur-Singapore-MIT (SMA) como número SMA 5512 del curso (las 
matemáticas para la informática). "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zählen von von Grundregeln</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sets</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ganzzahl Übereinstimmungen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">strukturelle Induktion</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Permutationen und Kombinationen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">asymptotische Darstellung und Wachstum von Funktionen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">mathematische Definitionen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Festlegen von von Funktionen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Informatik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">rekursive Definition</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">formale Logikdarstellung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beweise und anwendbare Methoden</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elektrotechnik und Informatik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">gut-Einrichtung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wiederauftreten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Informatik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">getrennte Wahrscheinlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Relationen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Induktion</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Beweismethoden</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zustand Maschinen und invariants</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">grundlegende Graphentheorie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">getrennte Mathematik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">compte des principes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">positionnements</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">congruences de nombre entier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">induction structurale</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">permutations et combinaisons</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">notation asymptotique et croissance des fonctions</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">définitions mathématiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">produire des fonctions</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">informatique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">définition récursive</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">notation formelle de logique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">preuves et méthodes applicables</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Électrotechnique et informatique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">bien-ordre</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">répétitions</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et informatique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">probabilité discrète</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">relations</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">induction</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">méthodes de preuve</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">machines et invariants d'état</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">théorie de graphique élémentaire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">mathématiques discrètes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">contando princípios</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">jogos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">congruences do inteiro</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">indução estrutural</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">permutações e combinações</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">notação asymptotic e crescimento das funções</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">definições matemáticas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">gerando funções</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">informática de</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">definição recursive</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">notação formal da lógica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">provas e métodos aplicáveis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Engenharia elétrica e informática de</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">bem-requisitar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">retornos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e informática de</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">probabilidade discreta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">relações</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">indução</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">métodos da prova</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">máquinas e invariants do estado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">teoria de gráfico elementar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">matemática discreta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">conteggio dei principii</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">insiemi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">congruenze di numero intero</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">induzione strutturale</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">permutazioni e combinazioni</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">notazione asintotica e sviluppo delle funzioni</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">definizioni matematiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">generazione delle funzioni</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">informatica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">definizione ricorsiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">notazione convenzionale di logica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">prove e metodi applicabili</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ingegneria elettrica ed informatica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">bene-ordinamento</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ricorrenze</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica ed informatica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">probabilità discreta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">rapporti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">induzione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">metodi della prova</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dichiari le macchine ed i invariants</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">teoria di grafico elementare</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">matematica discreta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μετρώντας αρχές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σύνολα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">συμφωνίες ακέραιων αριθμών</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δομική επαγωγή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μεταλλαγές και συνδυασμοί</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ασυμπτωτικές σημείωση και αύξηση των λειτουργιών</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μαθηματικοί ορισμοί</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παραγωγικές λειτουργίες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πληροφορική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επαναλαμβανόμενος καθορισμός</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επίσημη σημείωση λογικής</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποδείξεις και εφαρμόσιμες μέθοδοι</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηλεκτρική εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική και πληροφορική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">καλά-διαταγή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επαναλήψεις</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και πληροφορική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ιδιαίτερη πιθανότητα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχέσεις</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επαγωγή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μέθοδοι απόδειξης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">κρατικές μηχανές και σταθερές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">στοιχειώδης θεωρία γραφικών παραστάσεων</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ιδιαίτερα μαθηματικά</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta de principios</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">conjuntos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">congruencias del número entero</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">inducción estructural</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">permutaciones y combinaciones</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">notación asintótica y crecimiento de funciones</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">definiciones matemáticas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">generación de funciones</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">informática</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">definición recurrente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">notación formal de la lógica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">pruebas y métodos aplicables</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ingeniería eléctrica e informática</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">bien-peticio'n</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">repeticiones</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas e informática</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">probabilidad discreta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">relaciones</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">inducción</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">métodos de la prueba</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">máquinas e invariants del estado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">teoría de gráfico elemental</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">matemáticas discretas</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>790</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">mathematics</string>
                <string language="sv">matematik</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7531-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7531-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:53:15.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T05:58:42.68Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_7531</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Electrical-Engineering-and-Computer-Science/6-042JFall-2005/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
