<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107361</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107361</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209918</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Golden Rectangle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Goldene Viereck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Rectangle D'or</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Retângulo Dourado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Rettangolo Dorato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το χρυσό ορθογώνιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Rectángulo De oro</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that illustrate the properties the 'Golden Rectangle' whose sides are in the 'golden Ratio' of 1 : 1.618 : 1. The applet shows a golden rectangle whose vertices a re draggable. When dragged the rectangle changes to remain in the that shape. The web page discusses some properties of a golden rectangle and where it appears in art. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Eigenschaften das ' goldene Viereck ' 
veranschaulichen, dessen Seiten im ' goldenen Verhältnis ' von 1 
sind: 1.618: 1. Der applet zeigt ein goldenes 
Viereck dessen Gipfel ein Re draggable. Wenn es geschleppt wird,
ändert das Viereck, um in der dieser Form zu bleiben. Die 
Webseite behandelt einige Eigenschaften eines goldenen Viereckes und 
wo sie in der kunst erscheint. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang
für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui illustrent les propriétés 'le rectangle d'or 'dont les côtés 
sont dans 'le taux d'or 'de 1 : 1.618 : 1. L'applet 
montre un rectangle d'or dont les sommets un Re draggable. Une 
fois traîné le rectangle change pour demeurer dans la cette forme. 
La page Web discute quelques propriétés d'un rectangle d'or 
et où elle apparaît dans l'art. L'applet peut être agrandi à
la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
ilustrem as propriedades ' o retângulo dourado ' cujos os lados 
estão ' na relação dourada ' de 1: 1.618: 1. O 
applet mostra um retângulo dourado cujos vertices um re draggable. 
Quando arrastado o retângulo muda para remanescer nessa forma. 
O Web page discute algumas propriedades de um retângulo dourado
e onde aparece na arte. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de
tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois 
de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo 
o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma 
sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
illustrano le proprietà 'il rettangolo dorato 'di cui i lati sono 
'nel rapporto dorato 'di 1: 1.618: 1. Il applet 
mostra un rettangolo dorato di cui vertici un Re draggable. Una 
volta trascinato il rettangolo cambia per rimanere nella quella 
figura. Il Web page discute alcune proprietà di un rettangolo 
dorato e dove compare nell'arte. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
επεξηγούν τις ιδιότητες το "χρυσό ορθογώνιο" οι του οποίου 
πλευρές είναι σε "χρυσή αναλογία" 1: 1.618: 1. Το 
applet εμφανίζει χρυσό ορθογώνιο του οποίου vertices ένα Πε
draggable. Όταν σέρνεται το ορθογώνιο αλλάζει για να 
παραμείνει ότι μορφή. Ιστοσελίδας συζητά μερικές 
ιδιότητες ενός χρυσού ορθογωνίου και όπου εμφανίζεται στο αρθ. 
Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη 
χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην 
τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από 
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
ilustran las características el ' rectángulo de oro ' que caras 
están en la ' relación de transformación de oro ' de 1: 
1.618: 1. El applet muestra un rectángulo de oro 
que cimas un re draggable. Cuando está arrastrado el 
rectángulo cambia para permanecer en la esa dimensión de una 
variable. El Web page discute algunas características de un 
rectángulo de oro y donde aparece en arte. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209918</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107361</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-golden-rectangle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
