<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106734</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106734</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087450</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bryan's "Cross of Gold" Speech: Mesmerizing the Masses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rede von Gold Bryans "Kreuz": Hypnotisieren 
der Massen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La parole d'or de Bryan "croix" : Hypnotiser
les masses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Discurso do ouro de Bryan "cruz": 
Mesmerizing as massas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Discorso dell'oro del Bryan "traversa": 
Mesmerizing le masse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σταυρός του Bryan "της χρυσήσ" ομιλίας: Να 
γοητεύσει τις μάζες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Discurso del oro de Bryan "cruz": 
Mesmerizing las masas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The most famous speech in American political history was delivered by William Jennings Bryan on July 9, 1896, at the Democratic National Convention in Chicago. The issue was whether to endorse the free coinage of silver at a ratio of silver to gold of 16 to 1. (This inflationary measure would have increased the amount of money in circulation and aided cash-poor and debt-burdened farmers.) After speeches on the subject by several U.S. Senators, Bryan rose to speak. The thirty-six-year-old former Congressman from Nebraska aspired to be the Democratic nominee for president, and he had been skillfully, but quietly, building support for himself among the delegates. His dramatic speaking style and rhetoric roused the crowd to a frenzy. The response, wrote one reporter, "came like one great burst of artillery." Men and women screamed and waved their hats and canes. "Some," wrote another reporter, "like demented things, divested themselves of their coats and flung them high in the air." The next day the convention nominated Bryan for President on the fifth ballot. The full text of William Jenning Bryan's famous "Cross of Gold" speech appears below. The audio portion is an excerpt. [Note on the recording: In 1896 recording technology was in its infancy, and recording a political convention would have been impossible. But in the early 20th century, the fame of Bryan's "Cross of Gold" speech led him to repeat it numerous times on the Chautauqua lecture circuit where he was an enormously popular speaker. In 1921 (25 years after the original speech), he recorded portions of the speech for Gennett Records in Richmond, Indiana. Although the recording does not capture the power and drama of the original address, it does allow us to hear Bryan delivering this famous speech.]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die berühmteste Rede in der amerikanischen 
politischen Geschichte wurde von William Jennings Bryan an Juli 9, 
1896, an demokratischen Nationalkonventin Chicago geliefert. Die
Ausgabe war, ob man die freie Prägung des Silbers an einem 
Verhältnis des Silbers zum Gold von 16 bis 1 indossiert. 
(dieses inflationistische Maß würde die Menge des Geldumlaufs 
erhöht haben und den Bargeld-schlechten und Schuld-belasteten 
Landwirten. geholfen) Nach Reden auf dem Thema durch einige 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senatoren, stieg Bryan, um zu sprechen. Das 
dreißig-sechs-Jahr-alte ehemalige Kongreßabgeordnete von Nebraska 
strebte, der demokratische Kandidat für Präsidenten zu sein, und er 
war geschickt, aber ruhig gewesen und Support für unter den 
Delegierten aufgebaut. Seine drastische sprechende Art und 
Rhetorik roused die Masse zu einer Raserei. Die Antwort, schrieb
einen Reporter, "kam wie ein großer Impuls von Artillerie." 
Männer und Frauen schrieen und bewogen ihre Hüte und Stöcke 
wellenartig. "einige," schrieben einen anderen Reporter, "wie 
demented die Sachen, beraubt ihrer Mäntel und ihnen Höhe in der Luft
geschleudert." Die am nächsten Tag Versammlung ernannte Bryan 
für Präsidenten auf dem fünften Stimmzettel. Das Ganztext des
William Jenning Bryans der berühmten "Kreuz Gold" Rede erscheint 
unten. Der Audioteil ist ein Excerpt. [ Anmerkung über 
die Aufnahme: war 1896 speichernde Technologie in seiner 
Kindheit, und eine politische Versammlung zu speichern würde 
unmöglich gewesen sein. Aber im frühen 20. Jahrhundert, 
führte der Ruhm der Rede von Gold Bryans "Kreuz" ihn, es zahlreiche 
Zeiten auf dem Chautauqua Vortragstromkreis zu wiederholen, in dem er 
ein enorm populärer Sprecher war. 1921 (25 Jahre nach der 
ursprünglichen Rede), speicherte er Teile der Rede für Gennett 
Sätze in Richmond, Indiana. Obgleich die Aufnahme nicht die 
Energie und das Drama der ursprünglichen Adresse erfaßt, erlaubt sie
uns, Bryan zu hören, diese berühmte Rede zu liefern. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le discours le plus célèbre dans l'histoire 
politique américaine a été fourni par William Jennings Bryan 
9 juillet 1896, à la convention nationale démocratique Chicago. 
L'issue était si approuver l'invention libre de l'argent à un 
rapport d'argent à l'or de 16 à 1. (cette mesure 
inflationniste aurait augmenté le montant d'argent dans la 
circulation et avait aidé les fermiers argent-pauvres et 
dette-chargés.) Après des discours sur le sujet par plusieurs 
sénateurs des ETATS-UNIS, Bryan s'est levé pour parler. Le 
trente-six-année-vieil ancien membre du Congrès du Nébraska a 
aspiré pour être le dénommé démocratique pour le président, et 
il avait été habilement, mais tranquillement, établissant le 
soutien de se parmi les délégués. Son modèle et rhétorique 
parlants excessifs ont suscité la foule à une frénésie. 
La réponse, a écrit un journaliste, "est venue comme un grand 
éclat d'artillerie." Les hommes et les femmes ont crié et ont 
ondulé leurs chapeaux et cannes. "certains," ont écrit un 
autre journaliste, "comme des choses démentes, privées de leurs 
manteaux et jetées leur la haute dans le ciel." Le jour suivant
la convention a nommé Bryan pour le président sur le cinquième 
vote. L'à texte intégral du discours célèbre d'or de William
Jenning Bryan "croix" apparaît ci-dessous. La partie sonore est
un extrait. [ note sur l'enregistrement : En 1896 
technologies d'enregistrement était dans sa petite enfance, et 
l'enregistrement d'une convention politique aurait été impossible. 
Mais en début du 20ème siècle, la renommée de la parole d'or
de Bryan "croix" l'a mené à le répéter de nombreuses périodes sur
le circuit de conférence de Chautauqua où il était un orateur 
énormément populaire. En 1921 (25 ans après le discours 
initial), il a enregistré des parties du discours pour des 
enregistrements de Gennett à Richmond, Indiana. Bien que 
l'enregistrement ne capture pas la puissance et le drame de l'adresse 
initiale, il nous permet d'entendre Bryan fournir ce discours 
célèbre. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O discurso o mais famoso no history político 
americano foi entregado por William Jennings Bryan julho em 9, 1896, 
na convenção nacional democrática em Chicago. A edição era 
se endossar o coinage livre da prata em uma relação da prata a um 
ouro de 16 a 1. (esta medida inflationary aumentaria a 
quantidade de dinheiro na circulação e ajudaria a fazendeiros 
dinheiro-deficientes e débito-debt-burdened.) Após discursos 
no assunto por diversos senators de ESTADOS UNIDOS, Bryan levantou-se 
para falar. O congressista anterior trinta-seis-ano-velho de 
Nebraska aspired ser o nominee democrático para o presidente, e tinha
sido skillfully, mas quietamente, construindo a sustentação para 
himself entre os delegados. Seus estilo e rhetoric faladores 
dramáticos roused a multidão a um frenzy. A resposta, escreveu
um repórter, "veio como um estouro grande da artilharia." Os 
homens e as mulheres gritaram e acenaram seus chapéus e bastões. 
"alguns," escreveram um outro repórter, "como demented as 
coisas, divested de seus revestimentos e arremessadas lhes a 
elevação no ar." No dia seguinte a convenção nomeou Bryan 
para o presidente na quinta cédula. O texto cheio do discurso 
famoso do ouro de William Jenning Bryan "cruz" publica-se abaixo. 
A parcela audio é um excerpt. [ nota na gravação: 
Em 1896 tecnologias de gravação estavam em seu infancy, e 
gravar uma convenção política seria impossível. Mas no 20o 
século adiantado, a fama do discurso do ouro de Bryan "cruz" 
conduziu-lhe repeti-la épocas numerosas no circuito do lecture de 
Chautauqua onde era um altofalante enormemente popular. Em 1921 
(25 anos após o discurso original), gravou parcelas do discurso para 
registros de Gennett em Richmond, Indiana. Embora a gravação 
não capture a potência e o drama do endereço original, permite que 
nós ouçam Bryan entregar este discurso famoso. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il discorso più famoso nella storia politica 
americana è stato trasportato da William Jennings Bryan il 9 luglio 
1896, alla convenzione nazionale democratica in Chicago. 
L'edizione era se firmare l'invenzione libera di argento ad un 
rapporto di argento ad un oro di 16 - 1. (questa misura 
inflazionistica avrebbe aumentato l'importo di soldi nella 
circolazione ed aiutato cash-povero e debito-caricato i 
coltivatori.) Dopo i discorsi sull'oggetto da parecchi senatori 
degli STATI UNITI, Bryan è aumentato per parlare. Il 
trenta-sei-anno-vecchio ex membro del Congresso dal Nebraska ha 
aspirato essere il nominee democratico per il presidente ed era stato 
abilmente, ma tranquillamente, sviluppandogli il sostegno fra i 
delegati. Il suoi stile e retorica parlanti drammatici roused la
folla ad un frenzy. La risposta, ha scritto un reporter, "è
venuto come un burst grande di artiglieria." Gli uomini e le 
donne hanno gridato e fluttuato i loro cappelli e canne. 
"alcuni," hanno scritto un altro reporter, "come demented le
cose, private dei loro cappotti e scagliate loro il high nell'aria." 
Il giorno seguente la convenzione ha nominato Bryan per il 
presidente sulla quinta scheda elettorale. L'a testo integrale 
di discorso famoso dell'oro del William Jenning Bryan "traversa" 
compare sotto. La parte audio è un brano. [ nota sulla 
registrazione: In 1896 tecnologie di registrazione era nella 
relativa infanzia e registrare una convenzione politica sarebbe stata 
impossibile. Ma nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, la fama di 
discorso dell'oro del Bryan "traversa" lo ha condotto ripeterlo 
periodi numerosi sul circuito di conferenza di Chautauqua in cui era 
un altoparlante enormemente popolare. In 1921 (25 anni dopo il 
discorso originale), ha registrato le parti del discorso per i record 
di Gennett a Richmond, Indiana. Anche se la registrazione non 
blocca l'potenza ed il dramma dell'indirizzo originale, permette che 
noi sentiamo Bryan trasportare questo discorso famoso. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διασημότερη ομιλία στην αμερικανική πολιτική 
ιστορία παραδόθηκε από William Jennings Bryan στις 9 
Ιουλίου ..1896, στη δημοκρατική εθνική Συνθήκη στο Σικάγο. 
Το ζήτημα ήταν εάν για να επικυρώσει την ελεύθερη 
δημιουργία του ασημιού σε μια αναλογία του ασημιού στο χρυσό 
16 έως 1. (Αυτό το πληθωριστικό μέτρο θα είχε αυξήσει 
το χρηματικό ποσό στην κυκλοφορία και τους βοηθημένους 
μετρητό-φτωχούς και τους χρέος-φορτωμένους αγρότες.) Μετά 
από τις ομιλίες στο θέμα διάφορων ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ γερουσιαστών, ο 
Bryan αυξήθηκε για να μιλήσει. Το 
τριάντα-έξι-χρονών προηγούμενο μέλος του Κογκρέσσου 
από τη Νεμπράσκα επεδίωξε να είναι ο δημοκρατικός υποψήφιος για 
τον Πρόεδρο, και ήταν skillfully, αλλά ήσυχα, χτίζοντας την 
υποστήριξη για τον μεταξύ των εκπροσώπων. Το δραματικές 
ύφος και η ρητορική ομιλίας του παρακίνησαν το πλήθος σε έναν 
παροξυσμό. Η απάντηση, έγραψε έναν δημοσιογράφο, "ήρθε 
όπως μια μεγάλη έκρηξη του πυροβολικού." Οι άνδρες και οι 
γυναίκες κραύγασαν και κυμάτισαν τα καπέλα και τους καλάμους 
τους. "Μερικοί," έγραψαν έναν άλλο δημοσιογράφο, "όπως τα 
παραώμονα πράγματα, στερήθηκαν των παλτών τους και τους πέταξαν 
υψηλούς στον αέρα." Η επόμενη ημέρα η σύμβαση όρισε το 
Bryan για τον Πρόεδρο στην πέμπτη ψήφο. Το πλήρες 
κείμενο του διάσημου "σταυρού William Jenning Bryan's της 
χρυσήσ" ομιλίας εμφανίζεται κατωτέρω. Η ηχητική μερίδα 
είναι ένα απόσπασμα. [ Σημείωση για την καταγραφή: 
Το 1896 η τεχνολογία καταγραφής ήταν στα σπάργανα, και η 
καταγραφή μιας πολιτικής σύμβασης θα ήταν αδύνατη. Αλλά 
στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, η φήμη σταυρού του Bryan του "της 
χρυσήσ" ομιλίας τον οδήγησε για να το επαναλάβει πολυάριθμοι 
χρόνοι στο κύκλωμα διάλεξης Chautauqua όπου ήταν πάρα πολύ 
δημοφιλής ομιλητής. Σε 1921.25 έτη μετά από την αρχική 
ομιλία), κατέγραψε τις μερίδες της ομιλίας για τα αρχεία 
Gennett στο Ρίτσμοντ, Ινδιάνα. Αν και η καταγραφή δεν 
συλλαμβάνει τη δύναμη και το δράμα της αρχικής διεύθυνσης, 
επιτρέπει σε μας για να ακούσει το Bryan αυτήν την διάσημη 
ομιλία. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El discurso más famoso de la historia política 
americana fue entregado por Guillermo Jennings Bryan 9 de julio de 
1896, en la convención nacional democrática en Chicago. La 
edición era si endosar la invención libre de la plata en una 
relación de transformación de la plata al oro de 16 a 1. (esta
medida inflacionista habría aumentado la cantidad de dinero en la 
circulación y había ayudado a granjeros efectivo-pobres y 
deuda-cargados.) Después de discursos en el tema de varios 
senadores de ESTADOS UNIDOS, Bryan se levantó para hablar. El 
treinta-seis-año-viejo miembro del Congreso anterior de Nebraska 
aspiró ser el candidato democrático para el presidente, y él había
estado hábilmente, pero reservado, construyendo la ayuda para se 
entre los delegados. Su estilo y retórico de discurso 
dramáticos roused a muchedumbre a un frenesí. La respuesta, 
escribió a un reportero, "vino como una gran explosión de la 
artillería." Los hombres y las mujeres gritaron y agitaron sus 
sombreros y bastones. "algunos," escribieron a otro reportero, 
"como demented las cosas, privadas de sus capas y arrojadas les colmo 
en el aire." La convención nominó el día siguiente Bryan para
el presidente en la quinto balota. El texto completo del 
discurso famoso del oro de Guillermo Jenning Bryan "cruz" aparece 
abajo. La porción audio es un extracto. [ nota sobre la 
grabación: En 1896 tecnologías de registración estaba en su 
infancia, y la registración de una convención política habría sido
imposible. Pero en el vigésimo siglo temprano, la fama 
del discurso del oro de Bryan "cruz" lo condujo a relanzarla las 
épocas numerosas en el circuito de la conferencia de Chautauqua donde
él estaba un locutor enormemente popular. En 1921 (25 años 
después del discurso original), él registró las porciones del 
discurso para los expedientes de Gennett en Richmond, Indiana. 
Aunque la grabación no captura la potencia y el drama del 
direccionamiento original, permite que oigamos Bryan el entregar de 
este discurso famoso. ]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087450</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106734</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bryans-cross-of-gold-speech-mesmerizing-the-masses</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
