<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106291</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106291</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207134</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Life Apart: Hasidism in America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Lebensdauer Auseinander: Hasidism in 
Amerika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Vie À part : Hasidism en Amérique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma Vida Distante: Hasidism em América</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una Vita A parte: Hasidism in America</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια ζωή χώρια: Hasidism στην Αμερική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Vida Aparte: Hasidism en América</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a documentary on this movement within Orthodox Judaism. The Hasidic ideal is to live a hallowed life in which even the most mundane action is sanctified. Hasidim live in tightly-knit communities centered around a rebbe, the community's political and religious leader. Most of the 200,000 American Hasidim live in NYC. This website provides the film script, reviews, a discussion forum, and 15 essays on Hasidism.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Dokumentarfilm auf dieser Bewegung 
innerhalb des orthodoxen Judentums. Das ideale Hasidic soll 
leben eine geheiligte Lebensdauer, in der sogar die weltlichste 
Tätigkeit sanctified. Hasidim, das fest-stricken Phasen ist 
innen, die Gemeinschaften, die um ein rebbe, politischen und frommen 
einen Führer der Gemeinschaft gezentriert werden. Die meisten 
des 200.000 Amerikaners Hasidim Phasen in NYC. Diese Web site 
stellt den Filmindex, die Zusammenfassungen, ein Diskussion Forum und 
15 Versuche auf Hasidism zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un documentaire sur ce mouvement dans le 
judaïsme orthodoxe. Le Hasidic idéal doit vivre une vie 
sanctifiée l'où même l'action la plus mondaine est sanctifiée. 
Hasidim de phase serré-tricotent dedans les communautés 
concentrées sur un rebbe, une amorce politique et religieuse de la 
communauté. La majeure partie 200.000 de l'Américain Hasidim 
de phase dans NYC. Ce site Web fournit la séquence type de 
film, des revues, un forum de discussion, et 15 essais sur Hasidism.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um documentary neste movimento dentro do 
judaism orthodox. O Hasidic ideal deve viver uma vida hallowed 
em que mesmo a ação a mais mundane sanctified. Hasidim vivo 
apertado-tightly-knit dentro as comunidades centradas em torno de um 
rebbe, de um líder político e religioso da comunidade. A 
maioria 200.000 do americano Hasidim vivo em NYC. Este Web site 
fornece o certificado da película, revisões, um forum da discussão,
e 15 essays em Hasidism.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un documentary su questo movimento all'interno 
di judaism ortodosso. Il Hasidic ideale deve vivere una vita 
hallowed in où persino l'azione più mundane sanctified. 
Hasidim in tensione dentro stretto-lavora a maglia le Comunità 
concentrate intorno ad un rebbe, ad un capo politico e 
religioso della Comunità. La maggior parte 200.000 
dell'americano Hasidim in tensione in NYC. Questo Web site 
fornisce lo scritto della pellicola, le revisioni, una tribuna di 
discussione e 15 saggi su Hasidism.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα ντοκιμαντέρ σε αυτήν την μετακίνηση μέσα 
σε ορθόδοξο Judaism. Το hasidic ιδανικό είναι να ζήσει
μια καθαγιασμένη ζωή στην οποία ακόμη και η πιό εγκόσμια 
ενέργεια είναι. Το Hasidim ζωντανό μέσα στενά-πλέκει 
τις κοινότητες που κεντροθετούνται γύρω από ένα rebbe, τον 
πολιτικό και θρησκευτικό ηγέτη της κοινότητας. Τα 
περισσότερα από τα 200.000 αμερικανικό Hasidim ζωντανό σε 
NYC. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος παρέχει το αρχείο εντολών 
ταινιών, τις αναθεωρήσεις, φόρουμ συζήτησης, και 15 δοκίμια σε
Hasidism.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un documentary en este movimiento dentro del 
judaísmo ortodoxo. El Hasidic ideal debe vivir una vida 
santificada en la cual incluso se santifique la acción más mundana. 
Hasidim vivo adentro apretado-hace punto a comunidades centradas
alrededor de un rebbe, de un arranque de cinta político y religioso 
de la comunidad. La mayoría 200.000 del americano Hasidim vivo 
en NYC. Este Web site proporciona a la escritura de la 
película, a revisiones, a un foro de la discusión, y a 15 ensayos en
Hasidism.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207134</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106291</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-life-apart-hasidism-in-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
