<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105600</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105600</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086343</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Is This America?": An English Family Travels Up the Mississippi to Their New Home in Illinois, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ist Dieses Amerika?": Eine englische 
Familie reist herauf das Mississippi zu ihrem neuen Haus in Illinois, 
1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Est La Cette Amérique?" : Une famille 
anglaise voyage vers le haut du Mississippi à leur nouvelle maison en
Illinois, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"É Esta América?": Uma família inglesa 
viaja acima do Mississippi a sua HOME nova em Illinois, 1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"È La Questa America?": Una famiglia 
inglese viaggia sul Mississippi alla loro nuova sede nell'Illinois, 
1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είναι αυτή η Αμερική;": Μια αγγλική οικογένεια
ταξιδεύει επάνω στο Μισισιπή στη νέα "Οικία" τους στο Ιλλινόις, 
1831</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Es Esta América?": Una familia inglesa 
viaja encima del Mississippi a su nuevo hogar en Illinois, 1831</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Thirty-eight year old Rebecca Burlend and her family left England in 1831 for a new life in Pike County, Illinois. Driven to emigrate by poverty, they hoped to own their own land in the United States and chose Pike County based on the letters of "Mr. B.," a settler who had gone before them. After more than two months at sea, the family landed in New Orleans, where Burlend observed the horrors of the slave trade firsthand. From there they traveled by steamboat up the Mississippi River to Illinois. Many immigrants--then and now--experience the kind of fear and confusion that the Burlends felt on arriving at what looked to them like a deserted wilderness. After the "many difficulties" of the book's title, the family settled successfully in Illinois. Rebecca Burlend wrote this book with the assistance of her son, the author and teacher Edward Burlend, during a return visit to England in 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Thirty-eight Einjahres- Rebecca Burlend und ihre 
Familie verließen England 1831 für eine neue Lebensdauer in der 
Spiess-Grafschaft, Illinois. Angetrieben, um durch Armut 
auszuwandern, hofften sie zu eigenem ihrem eigenem Land in den 
Vereinigten Staaten und wählten die Spiess-Grafschaft, die auf den 
Zeichen "des Herrn B.," ein Siedler basierte, der vor ihnen gegangen 
war. Nach mehr als zwei Monaten am Meer, landete die Familie in 
New-Orleans, in dem Burlend die Grausigkeiten des Sklave Handels aus 
erster Hand beobachtete. Von dort reisten ihnen durch steamboat 
herauf den Mississippi Fluß zu Illinois. Viele Immigranten -- 
dann und jetzt -- erfahren die Art von Furcht und von Durcheinander 
die der Burlends Filz auf dem Ankommen in, was zu ihnen wie einer 
verlassenen Wildnis schaute. Nach den "vielen Schwierigkeiten" 
des Namens des Buches, rechnete die Familie erfolgreich in Illinois 
ab. Rebecca Burlend schrieb dieses Buch mit der Unterstützung 
ihres Sohns, des Autors und des Lehrers Edward Burlend, während eines
Rückholbesuchs nach England 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'année vieux Rebecca Burlend de Thirty-eight et 
sa famille ont quitté l'Angleterre en 1831 pendant une nouvelle vie 
dans le comté de brochet, l'Illinois. Piloté pour émigrer par
la pauvreté, ils ont espéré à propre leur propre terre aux 
Etats-Unis et ont choisi le comté de brochet basé sur les lettres de
"M. B.," un colon qui était allé avant elles. Après plus de 
deux mois en mer, la famille a débarqué à la Nouvelle-Orléans, où
Burlend a observé les horreurs du commerce slave de première 
main. Là d'elles ont voyagé en bateau à vapeur vers le haut du 
fleuve du Mississippi à l'Illinois. Beaucoup d'immigrés -- 
puis et maintenant -- éprouvent le genre de crainte et de confusion
qui le feutre de Burlends sur l'arrivée à ce qui a regardé à elles
comme un désert abandonné. Après les "beaucoup de 
difficultés" du titre du livre, la famille s'est établie avec 
succès dans l'Illinois. Rebecca Burlend a écrit ce livre avec 
l'aide de son fils, de l'auteur et du professeur Edouard Burlend,
pendant une visite de retour en Angleterre en 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ano Rebecca velho Burlend de Thirty-eight e sua 
família sairam de Inglaterra em 1831 por uma vida nova no condado do 
pique, Illinois. Dirigido para emigrate pela pobreza, esperaram 
a própria sua própria terra nos estados unidos e escolheram o 
condado do pique baseado nas letras do "Sr. B.," um settler que fosse 
antes delas. Após mais de dois meses no mar, a família aterrou
em Nova Orleães, onde Burlend observou os horrors do comércio do 
escravo firsthand. Lá dos viajaram pelo steamboat acima do rio 
de Mississippi a Illinois. Muitos immigrants -- então e agora 
-- experimentam o tipo do medo e da confusão que o feltro de Burlends
em chegar em o que lhe olhou como uma região selvagem deserted. 
Após "muitas dificuldades" do título do livro, a família 
estabeleciu-se com sucesso em Illinois. Rebecca Burlend escreveu
este livro com o auxílio de seu filho, do autor e do professor Edward
Burlend, durante uma visita do retorno a Inglaterra em 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anni Rebecca Burlend di Thirty-eight e la sua 
famiglia hanno lasciato l'Inghilterra in 1831 per una nuova vita nella
contea del luccio, l'Illinois. Guidato per emigrare da povertà,
hanno sperato alla propria loro propria terra in unito Dichiarano
e scelto la contea del luccio basata sulle lettere "del sig. B.," un 
settler che era andato prima di loro. Dopo più di due mesi in 
mare, la famiglia ha atterrato a New Orleans, in cui Burlend ha 
osservato firsthand gli orrori del commercio dello schiavo. Là 
dai hanno viaggiato da steamboat sul fiume del Mississippi 
all'Illinois. Molti immigranti -- allora ed ora -- avvertono il 
genere di timore e di confusione che il feltro di Burlends 
sull'arrivare a che cosa ha osservato a loro come una selva deserted. 
Dopo "le molte difficoltà" del titolo del libro, la famiglia si
è depositata con successo nell'Illinois. Rebecca Burlend ha 
scritto questo libro con l'assistenza del suo figlio, dell'autore e 
dell'insegnante Edward Burlend, durante la chiamata di ritorno in 
Inghilterra in 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τριάντα οκτώ έτος η ηλικίας Rebecca Burlend και 
η οικογένειά της άφησαν την Αγγλία το 1831 για μια νέα ζωή 
στο νομό λούτσων, Ιλλινόις. Οδηγημένοι για να 
μεταναστεύσουν από την ένδεια, ήλπισαν να είναι κύριοι του 
εδάφους τους στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες και επέλεξαν το νομό 
λούτσων βασισμένο στις επιστολές "του κ. Β.," ένας άποικος που 
πηγαίνω πριν από τους. Μετά από περισσότερο από δύο 
μήνες εν πλω, η οικογένεια προσγειώθηκε στη Νέα Ορλεάνη, όπου 
Burlend παρατήρησε τις φρίκες του εμπορίου σκλάβων από πρώτο 
χέρι. Από εκεί ταξίδεψαν με το ατμόπλοιο επάνω τον ποταμό
του Μισισιπή στο Ιλλινόις. Πολλοί μετανάστες -- έπειτα και 
τώρα -- δοκιμάζουν το είδος φόβου και σύγχυσης που το Burlends
αισθάνθηκε στην άφιξη σε αυτό που κοίταξε σε τους όπως μια 
εγκαταλειμμένη αγριότητα. Μετά από τις "πολλές δυσκολίεσ" 
του τίτλου του βιβλίου, η οικογένεια εγκατέστησε επιτυχώς στο 
Ιλλινόις. Η Rebecca Burlend έγραψε αυτό το βιβλίο με 
τη βοήθεια του γιου της, του συντάκτη και του δασκάλου Edward 
Burlend, κατά τη διάρκεια μιας επιστροφής επίσκεψης στην 
Αγγλία το 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El año viejo Rebecca Burlend de Thirty-eight y su
familia salieron de Inglaterra en 1831 por una nueva vida en el 
condado del lucio, Illinois. Conducido para emigrar por
pobreza, esperaban a propia su propia pista en los Estados Unidos y 
eligieron el condado del lucio basado en las cartas de "Sr. B.," un 
colono que había ido antes de ellas. Después de más de dos 
meses en el mar, la familia aterrizó en New Orleans, en donde Burlend
observó los horrores del comercio del esclavo de primera mano. 
Allí de ellos viajaron por el steamboat encima del río de 
Mississippi a Illinois. Muchos inmigrantes -- entonces y ahora 
-- experimentan la clase de miedo y de confusión que el fieltro de 
Burlends en llegar qué miraba a él como un yermo abandonado. 
Después de las "muchas dificultades" del título del libro, la 
familia colocó con éxito en Illinois. Rebecca Burlend 
escribió este libro con la ayuda de su hijo, del autor y del profesor
Edward Burlend, durante una visita de vuelta a Inglaterra en 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086343</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105600</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/is-this-america-an-english-family-travels-up-the-mississippi-to-their-new-home-in-illinois-1831</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
