<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206670</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">North American Slave Narratives</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nordamerikanische Sklavendarstellungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Récits Slaves Américains du nord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Narrativas Slave Norte-americanas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Descrizioni Slave Nordamericane</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βορειοαμερικανικά αφηγήματα σκλάβων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Narrativas Auxiliares Norteamericanas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers more than 250 memoirs, autobiographies, and narratives from individuals who were slaves. An African king who was sold into slavery, the dress maker for Mary Todd Lincoln, the servant of Robert E. Lee during the Civil War, and the nurse of George Washington are included, as are stories of Sojourner Truth, George Washington Carver, Booker T. Washington, and others. These firsthand accounts describe the conditions and sufferings of slaves and a number of escapes to freedom.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet mehr als 250 Abhandlungen, Autobiographien 
und Darstellungen von den Einzelpersonen an, die Sklaven waren. 
Ein afrikanischer König, der in Sklaverei, der Kleidhersteller 
für Mary Todd Lincoln, der Bedienstete von Robert E. Lee während des
Bürgerkrieges und der Krankenschwester von George Washington verkauft
wurde, sind enthalten sind, wie Geschichten der Sojourner Wahrheit, 
George Washington Tranchiermesser, Booker T. Washington, und andere. 
Diese berechnet aus erster Hand beschreiben die Zustände und 
die Sufferings der Sklaven und eine Anzahl von Entweichen zur 
Freiheit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre plus de 250 mémoires, autobiographies, et 
récits des individus qui étaient des esclaves. Un roi africain
qui a été vendu dans l'esclavage, le générateur de robe pour Mary 
Todd Lincoln, l'domestique de Robert E. Lee pendant la guerre civile, 
et l'infirmière de George Washington sont inclus, de même que 
des histoires de la vérité de Sojourner, tailleur de George 
Washington, Booker T. Washington, et d'autres. Celles-ci rend 
compte de première main décrivent les conditions et les douleurs des
esclaves et d'un certain nombre d'évasions à la liberté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece mais de 250 memoirs, autobiographies, e 
narrativas dos indivíduos que eram escravos. Um rei africano 
que seja vendido no slavery, o fabricante do vestido para Mary Todd 
Lincoln, empregado de Robert E. Lee durante a guerra civil, e a 
enfermeira de George Washington é incluído, como são histórias da 
verdade de Sojourner, carver de George Washington, Booker T. 
Washington, e outro. Estes explicam firsthand descrevem as 
condições e os sofrimentos dos escravos e de um número dos escapes 
à liberdade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre più di 250 memorie, autobiographies e 
descrizioni dagli individui che erano schiavi. Un re africano 
che è stato venduto in slavery, il creatore del vestito per Mary Todd
Lincoln, il servo di Robert E. Lee durante la guerra civile e 
l'infermiera di George Washington è incluso, come sono storia della 
verità di Sojourner, il carver di George Washington, Booker il T. 
Washington ed altri. Questi spiegano firsthand descrivono i 
termini ed i sufferings degli schiavi e di un certo numero di fughe 
alla libertà.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τα περισσότερα από 250 απομνημονεύματα, 
αυτοβιογραφίες, και αφηγήματα από τα άτομα που ήταν σκλάβοι. 
Ένας αφρικανικός βασιλιάς που πωλήθηκε στη σκλαβιά, ο 
κατασκευαστής φορεμάτων για Mary Todd Λίνκολν, ο υπάλληλος 
Robert E. Lee κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου πολέμου, και 
η νοσοκόμα George Ουάσιγκτον συμπεριλαμβάνεται, όπως είναι οι 
ιστορίες της αλήθειας Sojourner, του τροχιστή George 
Ουάσιγκτον, Booker Τ. Ουάσιγκτον, και άλλα. Αυτοί οι από
πρώτο χέρι απολογισμοί περιγράφουν τους όρους και τα βάσανα των 
σκλάβων και διάφορων διαφυγών στην ελευθερία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece más de 250 memorias, autobiografías, y 
narrativas de los individuos que eran esclavos. Un rey africano 
que fue vendido en la esclavitud, el fabricante de la alineada para 
Maria Todd Lincoln, el criado de Roberto E. Lee durante la guerra 
civil, y la enfermera de George Washington es incluido, al igual que 
historias de la verdad de Sojourner, carver de George Washington, 
Booker T. Washington, y otros. Éstos consideran de primera mano
describen las condiciones y los sufrimientos de esclavos y de un 
número de escapes a la libertad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206670</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106128</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/north-american-slave-narratives</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
