<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105685</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105685</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086930</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Dutch Arrive on Manhattan Island: An Indian Perspective</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Holländer kommen auf Manhattan Insel an: 
Eine Indische Perspektive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Néerlandais arrivent sur l'île de Manhattan 
: Une Perspective Indienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os dutch chegam no console de Manhattan: Um 
Perspective Indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I dutch arrivano sull'isola de Manhattan: 
Una Prospettiva Indiana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι Ολλανδοί φθάνουν στο νησί του Μανχάτταν: Μια 
ινδική προοπτική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los holandeses llegan en la isla de Manhattan: 
Una Perspectiva India</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Henry Hudson, employed by the Dutch India Company, anchored off of Manhattan in 1609 and traded with local Indians. Hudson then headed up the river (later named the Hudson River) seeking Northwest Passage to Asia. Other Dutch settlers soon followed. Delawares and Mahicans, who had been living along the coast of New Jersey and up the Hudson River when the Dutch arrived, were driven westward by expanding European settlements. The Reverend John Heckwelder, a Moravian missionary in the Ohio Valley, took down this particular narrative in the 1760s "as it was related to me by aged and respected" Delawares and Mahicans. Indian stories of the first encounters between Indians and Europeans often depicted the Europeans as "the great Mannitoo" or Supreme Being. This account went on to describe the trading and hospitality that followed the first encounter and the Europeans' eventual desire for land above all else.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Henry Hudson, eingesetzt durch Dutch India 
Company, weg befestigt von Manhattan 1609 und mit lokalen Indern 
gehandelt. Hudson geht dann herauf den der Fluß (später 
benannt den Hudson Fluß) suchenden Nordwestdurchgang nach Asien 
voran. Andere holländische Siedleren bald gefolgt. 
Delawares und Mahicans, die entlang der Küste von Neu-Jersey 
gelebt und den Hudson Fluß als holländische angekommen up hatten, 
wurden nach Westen durch die Erweiterung der europäischen Regelungen 
angetrieben. Das Reverend John Heckwelder, ein Moravian 
Missionar in der Ohio Senke, nahm diese bestimmte Darstellung im 1760s
"herunter, während es mit mir durch gealtertes und respektiertes" 
Delawares und Mahicans zusammenhing. Indische Geschichten des 
ersten Treffens zwischen Indern und Europäern stellten häufig die 
Europäer als "das große Mannitoo" oder Oberstes Wesen bildlich dar. 
Dieses Konto fuhr fort, das Handeln und die Gastfreundschaft zu 
beschreiben, die dem ersten Treffen und dem der Europäer etwaigen 
Wunsch nach Land vor allem sonst folgten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Henry Hudson, utilisé par Dutch India Company, 
ancré hors fonction de Manhattan en 1609 et commercé avec les 
Indiens locaux. Hudson se dirige alors vers le haut du passage 
du nord-ouest recherchant de fleuve (plus tard nommé le fleuve de 
Hudson) en Asie. D'autres colons hollandais bientôt suivis. 
Delawares et Mahicans, qui avaient vécu le long de la côte de 
New Jersey et lèvent le fleuve de Hudson quand arrivée hollandaise,
ont été pilotés à l'ouest en augmentant des règlements 
européens. Le Révérend John Heckwelder, un missionnaire de 
Moravian dans la vallée de l'Ohio, a pris vers le bas ce récit 
particulier dans le 1760s "pendant qu'il était lié à moi par" 
Delawares âgé et respecté et des Mahicans. Les histoires 
indiennes de la première rencontre entre les Indiens et les 
Européens ont souvent dépeint les Européens en tant que "le grand 
Mannitoo" ou être suprême. Ce compte a continué pour décrire
le commerce et l'hospitalité qui ont suivi la première rencontre et 
le désir certain des Européens pour la terre surtout autrement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Henry Hudson, empregado pelos Holandês India 
Companhia, escorado fora de Manhattan em 1609 e negociado com os 
indians locais. Hudson dirige então acima da passagem noroeste 
procurando do rio (nomeado mais tarde o rio de Hudson) a Ásia. 
Outros settlers holandeses seguidos logo. Delawares e os 
mahicans, que têm vivido ao longo da costa de Novo-Jersey e levantam 
o rio de Hudson quando chegado holandês, foram dirigidos para o oeste
expandindo estabelecimentos europeus. O Reverend John 
Heckwelder, um missionário de Moravian no vale de Ohio, fêz exame 
para baixo desta narrativa particular no 1760s "enquanto me foi 
relacionado" por Delawares envelhecido e respeitado e mahicans. 
As histórias indian do primeiro encontro entre indians e 
Europeus descreveram frequentemente os Europeus como "o Mannitoo 
grande" ou ser supremo. Este cliente foi sobre descrever 
negociar e o hospitality que seguiram o primeiro encontro e o desejo 
eventual dos Europeus para a terra sobretudo mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Henry Hudson, impiegato dagli Dutch India Company,
ancorato fuori di Manhattan in 1609 e commerciato con indiani locali. 
Hudson allora dirige sul passaggio di nord-ovest di ricerca del 
fiume (più successivamente chiamato il fiume di Hudson) in Asia. 
Altri settlers olandesi presto seguiti. Delawares ed i 
mahicans, che stavano vivendo lungo il litorale della Nuovo-Jersey ed 
aumentano il fiume di Hudson quando arrivato olandese, sono stati 
guidati verso ovest espandendo gli stabilimenti europei. Il 
Reverend John Heckwelder, un missionario di Moravian nella valle 
dell'Ohio, ha preso giù questa descrizione particolare nel 1760s 
"mentre è stato collegato con me" da Delawares invecchiato e 
rispettato e mahicans. Le storia indiane del primo incontro fra 
gli indiani ed Europei hanno descritto spesso gli Europei come "il 
Mannitoo grande" o supremo. Questo cliente ha continuato a 
descrivere il commercio e l'ospitalità che hanno seguito il primo 
incontro ed il desiderio finale degli Europei per terra soprattutto 
altrimenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Χενρυ Hudson, που χρησιμοποιείται από την 
ολλανδική επιχείρηση της Ινδίας, που δένεται μακριά του 
Μανχάτταν το 1609 και που κυκλοφορεί στο εμπόριο με τοπικούς 
Ινδούς. Το Hudson διεύθυνε έπειτα επάνω τον ποταμό (που 
ονομάζεται αργότερα τον ποταμό Hudson) που επιδιώκει τη 
βορειοδυτική μετάβαση στην Ασία. Αλλοι ολλανδικοί άποικοι 
ακολουθούμενοι σύντομα. Το Delawares και Mahicans, που 
ζούσαν κατά μήκος της ακτής του Νιου Τζέρσευ! και επάνω του 
ποταμού Hudson όταν έφθασαν οι Ολλανδοί, οδηγήθηκαν δυτικά με
την επέκταση των ευρωπαϊκών τακτοποιήσεων. Ο Αιδεσιμότατος 
John Heckwelder, ένας ιεραπόστολος Moravian στην κοιλάδα 
του Οχάιου, πήρε κάτω από αυτό το ιδιαίτερο αφήγημα στο 
1760s "όπως αφορούσε με από ηλικίας και σεβαστά" Delawares 
και Mahicans. Οι ινδικές ιστορίες του πρώτου 
αντιμετωπίζουν μεταξύ Ινδών και οι Ευρωπαίοι απεικόνισαν συχνά 
τους Ευρωπαίους ως "μεγάλο Mannitoo" ή ανώτατη ύπαρξη. 
Αυτός ο απολογισμός πήγε για να περιγραφούν οι εμπορικές 
συναλλαγές και η φιλοξενία που ακολούθησαν την πρώτη σύγκρουση 
και την ενδεχόμενη επιθυμία των Ευρωπαίων για το έδαφος προ 
πάντων αλλιώς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Henrio Hudson, empleado por los Dutch la India 
Company, asegurado apagado de Manhattan en 1609 y negociado con los 
indios locales. Hudson entonces dirigió encima del paso del 
noroeste que busca del río (más adelante nombrado el río de Hudson)
a Asia. Otros colonos holandeses pronto seguidos. 
Delawares y a los mahicans, que habían estado viviendo a lo 
largo de la costa de Nuevo-Jersey y suben el río de Hudson cuando 
haber llegado holandés, condujeron hacia el oeste ampliando 
establecimientos europeos. El Reverend Juan Heckwelder, 
misionario de Moravian en el valle de Ohio, tomó abajo esta narrativa
determinada en el 1760s "mientras que fue relacionado con mí por" 
Delawares envejecido y respetado y los mahicans. Las historias 
indias del primer encuentro entre los indios y europeos representaron 
a menudo a europeos como "el gran Mannitoo" o supremo. Esta 
cuenta continuó describir negociar y la hospitalidad que siguieron el
primer encuentro y el deseo eventual de los europeos para la pista 
sobretodo .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086930</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105685</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-dutch-arrive-on-manhattan-island-an-indian-perspective</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
