<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105857</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105857</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209874</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Heron's formula for the area of a triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Formel des Reihers für den Bereich eines 
Dreiecks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La formule du héron pour la zone d'une triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fórmula do heron para a área de um triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Formula del heron per la zona di un triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τύπος ερωδιού για την περιοχή ενός τριγώνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fórmula del heron para el área de un triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate how Herons Formula can be used to find the area of a triangle when you know all three sides. A triangle is shown where the user can drag any vertex to reshape it. In real time while dragging, the side lengths change and the formula is recalculated on the screen. The formula can be turned off to facilitate class work. The text on the web page gives the full formula and discusses where is can be applied. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die zeigen, wie Reiher-Formel verwendet werden kann, um den 
Bereich eines Dreiecks zu finden, wenn Sie alle drei Seiten kennen. 
Ein Dreieck wird gezeigt, wo der Benutzer jeden möglichen 
Gipfel schleppen kann, um ihn umzugestalten. In der Istzeit, 
beim Schleppen, ändern die seitlichen Längen und die Formel wird auf
dem Bildschirm nachgerechnet. Die Formel kann abgestellt werden,
um Kategorie Arbeit zu erleichtern. Der Text auf der Webseite 
gibt die volle Formel und behandelt, wo kann zugetroffen werden ist. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent comment la formule de hérons peut être employée 
pour trouver la zone d'une triangle quand vous connaissez chacun des 
trois côtés. Une triangle est montrée où l'utilisateur peut 
traîner n'importe quel sommet pour le restructurer. En temps 
réel tout en traînant, les longueurs latérales changent et la 
formule est recalculée sur l'écran. La formule peut être 
arrêtée pour faciliter le travail de classe. Le texte sur la 
page Web donne la pleine formule et discute où est peut être 
appliqué. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein 
écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le 
après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui 
accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou 
dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstre como a fórmula dos herons pode ser usada encontrar a área 
de um triângulo quando você souber todos os três lados. Um 
triângulo é mostrado onde o usuário pode arrastar todo o vertex 
para reshape o. No tempo real ao arrastar, os comprimentos 
laterais mudam e a fórmula recalculated na tela. A fórmula 
pode ser desligada para facilitar o trabalho da classe. O texto 
no Web page dá a fórmula cheia e discute onde está pode ser 
aplicado. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostra come la formula dei herons può essere usata per trovare la 
zona di un triangolo quando conoscete tutti e tre i lati. Un 
triangolo è indicato dove l'utente può trascinare tutto il vertice 
per rimodellarlo. In tempo reale mentre si trascinano, le 
lunghezze laterali cambiano e la formula è ricalcolata sullo schermo.
La formula può essere spenta per facilitare il lavoro del 
codice categoria. Il testo sul Web page dà la formula completa 
e discute dove è può essere applicato. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν πώς ο τύπος ερωδιών μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για 
να βρεί την περιοχή ενός τριγώνου όταν ξέρετε και τις τρεις 
πλευρές. Ένα τρίγωνο εμφανίζεται όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να
σέρει οποιοδήποτε vertex για να το αναδιαμορφώσει. Στον 
πραγματικό χρόνο σέρνοντας, τα δευτερεύοντα μήκη αλλάζουν και ο 
τύπος υπολογίζεται εκ νέου στην οθόνη. Ο τύπος μπορεί να 
κλειθεί για να διευκολύνει την εργασία κλάσης. Το κείμενο 
στον Ιστό η σελίδα δίνει τον πλήρη τύπο και συζητά πού είναι 
μπορεί να εφαρμοστεί. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο 
πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. 
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestra cómo el fórmula de los herons se puede utilizar para 
encontrar el área de un triángulo cuando usted sabe las tres caras. 
Se muestra un triángulo donde el utilizador puede arrastrar 
cualquier cima para restructurarla. En tiempo real mientras que 
arrastran, las longitudes laterales cambian y el fórmula se recalcula
en la pantalla. El fórmula se puede dar vuelta apagado para 
facilitar el trabajo de la clase. El texto en el Web page da el 
fórmula completo y discute donde está puede ser aplicado. El 
applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el 
uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la
sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier 
web browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida.
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209874</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105857</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/herons-formula-for-the-area-of-a-triangle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
