<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107119</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107119</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213189</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Wind Surge Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wind-Stromstoss-Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité De Montée subite de Vent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Do Surge Do Vento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Dell'Impulso Del Vento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δραστηριότητα κύματος αέρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad De la Oleada Del Viento</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Wind surge is a JAVA based applet for exploring how water level on the windward and leeward side of a basin depends on wind speed, basin length, water depth, and boundary type. A mathematical discussion of how water behaves with respect to a variety of variables is included in the exercise. Students are asked to use the JAVA applet to study a variety of effects including the effect of varying the wind speed on the surge elevations for a given basin geometry and do the same with the water depth and basin length for a fixed wind speed. This Applet can be useful when studying Hurricanes and storm surges in an introductory geoscience course. This site also provides teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Windstromstoß ist ein JAVA gegründeter applet 
für das Erforschen, wie Wasserstufe auf der windzugewandten und 
Leeseite eines Bassins von der Windgeschwindigkeit, von der 
Bassinlänge, von der Wassertiefe und vom Grenztypen abhängt. 
Eine mathematische Diskussion über, wie Wasser in Bezug auf 
eine Vielzahl von Variablen sich benimmt, ist in der Übung 
eingeschlossen. Kursteilnehmer werden gebeten, den JAVA applet 
zu benutzen, um eine Vielzahl von Effekten einschließlich den Effekt 
des Veränderns der Windgeschwindigkeit auf den Stromstoßaufzügen 
für eine gegebene Bassingeometrie zu studieren und dasselbe mit der 
Wassertiefe und der Bassinlänge für eine örtlich festgelegte 
Windgeschwindigkeit zu tun. Dieser applet kann nützlich sein, 
wenn man Hurrikane studiert und Sturmstromstöße in einem 
einleitenden geoscience kursieren. Diese Site liefert auch 
unterrichtende Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, Einschätzung 
Ideen. Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil der 
Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La montée subite de vent est un applet basé par 
JAVA pour explorer comment le niveau d'eau du côté au vent et sous 
le vent d'un bassin dépend de la vitesse de vent, de la longueur de 
bassin, de la profondeur de l'eau, et du type de borne. Une 
discussion mathématique de la façon dont l'eau se comporte en ce qui
concerne une variété de variables est incluse dans l'exercice. 
Des étudiants sont invités à employer le Java applet Pour 
étudier une variété d'effets comprenant l'effet de changer la 
vitesse de vent sur les altitudes de montée subite pour une 
géométrie donnée de bassin et pour faire la même chose avec la 
profondeur de l'eau et la longueur de bassin pour une vitesse de vent 
fixe. Cet applet peut être utile en étudiant des ouragans et 
donne l'assaut à des montées subites dans un cours préliminaire de 
geoscience. Ce site fournit également les notes et les 
extrémités d'enseignement, matériel didactique, idées 
d'évaluation. Cette activité fait partie de la collection de 
point de départ : http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O surge do vento é um applet baseado JAVA para 
explorar como o nível de água no lado de barlavento e leeward de uma
bacia depende da velocidade de vento, do comprimento da bacia, da 
profundidade da água, e do tipo do limite. Uma discussão 
matemática de como a água se comporta com respeito a uma variedade 
das variáveis é incluída no exercício. Os estudantes são 
pedidos para usar o Java applet Estudar uma variedade dos efeitos 
including o efeito de variar a velocidade de vento nas elevações do 
surge para uma geometria dada da bacia e fazer o mesmo com a 
profundidade da água e o comprimento da bacia para uma velocidade de 
vento fixa. Este applet pode ser útil ao estudar furacões e os
surges da tempestade em um geoscience introdutório percorrem. 
Este local fornece também notas e pontas ensinando, materiais 
de ensino, idéias da avaliação. Esta atividade é parte da 
coleção do ponto começar: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'impulso del vento è un applet basato JAVA per 
l'esplorazione come il livello d'acqua dal lato esposto al vento e 
leeward di un bacino dipende da velocità di vento, dalla lunghezza 
del bacino, dalla profondità dell'acqua e dal tipo di contorno. 
Una discussione matematica su come l'acqua si comporta riguardo 
ad una varietà di variabili è inclusa nell'esercitazione. Gli 
allievi sono chiesti di usare il Java applet Per studiare una varietà
di effetti compreso l'effetto di variazione della velocità di vento 
sulle altezze dell'impulso per la data geometria del bacino e per fare
lo stesso con la profondità dell'acqua e la lunghezza del bacino per 
una velocità di vento fissa. Questo applet può essere utile 
quando studia gli uragani e gli impulsi della tempesta in un 
geoscience introduttivo scorrono. Questo luogo egualmente 
fornisce le note e le punte d'istruzione, i materiali didattici, idee 
di valutazione. Questa attività fa parte dell'accumulazione del
punto di partenza: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κύμα αέρα είναι ένα βασισμένο στην ΙΑΒΑ applet 
για την εξερεύνηση πώς η στάθμη ύδατος στην προσήνεμη και 
leeward πλευρά μιας λεκάνης εξαρτάται από την ταχύτητα αέρα, 
το μήκος λεκανών, το βάθος ύδατος, και τον τύπο ορίου. Μια
μαθηματική συζήτηση για το πώς το ύδωρ συμπεριφέρεται όσον 
αφορά ποικίλες μεταβλητές συμπεριλαμβάνεται στην άσκηση. Οι
σπουδαστές καλούνται να χρησιμοποιήσουν το applet της ΙΑΒΑΣ για 
να μελετήσουν ποικίλα αποτελέσματα συμπεριλαμβανομένης της 
επίδρασης της ποικιλίας της ταχύτητας αέρα στις ανυψώσεις 
κύματος για μια δεδομένη γεωμετρία λεκανών και να κάνουν το ίδιο
πράγμα με το βάθος ύδατος και το μήκος λεκανών για μια σταθερή 
ταχύτητα αέρα. Αυτό το Applet μπορεί να είναι χρήσιμο 
κατά το μελέτη των τυφώνων και των κυμάτων θύελλας σε μια 
εισαγωγική σειρά μαθημάτων geoscience. Αυτή η περιοχή 
παρέχει επίσης τις σημειώσεις διδασκαλίας και τις άκρες, 
εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, ιδέες αξιολόγησης. Αυτή η 
δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La oleada del viento es un applet basado JAVA para
explorar cómo el nivel del agua en la cara de barlovento y de 
sotavento de un lavabo depende de velocidad del viento, de longitud 
del lavabo, de profundidad del agua, y de tipo del límite. Una 
discusión matemática de cómo el agua se comporta con respecto a una
variedad de variables se incluye en el ejercicio. Piden los 
estudiantes utilizar el Java applet Para estudiar una variedad de 
efectos incluyendo el efecto de variar la velocidad del viento en las 
elevaciones de la oleada para una geometría dada del lavabo y para 
hacer igual con la profundidad del agua y la longitud del lavabo para 
una velocidad del viento fija. Este applet puede ser útil al 
estudiar huracanes y las oleadas de la tormenta en un geoscience 
introductorio cursan. Este sitio también proporciona a las 
notas y a las extremidades de enseñanza, materiales didácticos, 
ideas del gravamen. Esta actividad es parte de la colección del
punto de partida: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213189</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107119</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/wind-surge-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
