<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107745</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107745</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205226</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Active Learning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aktives Lernen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude Active</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem Ativa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparare Attivo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενεργός εκμάθηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Aprender Activo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The aim of this lesson is to enable students to take control of their learning in a positive way. It is the third lesson in the study skills series and is intended to support adult learners who are embarking on a course of study and need to acquire skills which will help them to be successful. The lessons are designed as a package with key skills reinforced in each subsequent lesson so that a study culture is developed over time. They can be delivered sequentially or used individually, as a whole or in part, to support other programs of study.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel dieser Lektion ist, Kursteilnehmer zu 
aktivieren, Steuerung ihres Lernens in einer positiven Methode zu 
nehmen. Es ist die dritte Lektion in den Studie Fähigkeiten 
Serie und soll Erwachsenanfänger unterstützen, die auf einem 
Bildungsweg sich einschiffen und Fähigkeiten erwerben müssen, die 
ihnen helfen, erfolgreich zu sein. Die Lektionen sind während 
ein Paket mit den Schlüsselfähigkeiten konzipiert, die in jeder 
folgenden Lektion verstärkt werden, damit eine Studie Kultur über 
Zeit entwickelt wird. Sie können sequentiell geliefert werden 
oder, als Ganzes oder im Teil einzeln benutzt werden, um andere 
Programme der Studie zu unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cette leçon est de permettre à des 
étudiants de prendre la commande de leur étude d'une voie positive. 
C'est la troisième leçon dans les qualifications série 
d'étude et est destiné pour supporter les étudiants d'adulte qui 
s'embarquent sur un cours d'étude et doivent saisir les 
qualifications qui les aideront à être réussies. Les leçons 
sont conçues pendant qu'un module avec les qualifications principales
renforcées dans chaque leçon ultérieure de sorte qu'une culture 
d'étude soit développée avec le temps. Elles peuvent être 
livrées séquentiellement ou employées individuellement, dans 
l'ensemble ou en partie, pour supporter d'autres programmes d'étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O alvo desta lição é permitir estudantes de 
fazer exame do controle da sua aprendizagem em uma maneira positiva. 
É a terceira lição nas habilidades série do estudo e é 
pretendido suportar os learners do adulto que embarking em um curso de
estudo e necessitam adquirir as habilidades que lhes ajudarão ser bem
sucedidas. As lições são projetadas enquanto um pacote com as
habilidades chaves reforçadas em cada lição subseqüente de modo 
que uma cultura do estudo esteja desenvolvida sobre o tempo. 
Podem ser entregados sequencialmente ou usado individualmente, 
ao todo ou na parte, suportar outros programas do estudo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo di questa lezione è permettere agli 
allievi di prendere il controllo del loro imparare in un modo 
positivo. È la terza lezione nelle abilità serie di studio ed 
è inteso sostenere i principianti dell'adulto che stanno 
intraprendendo un corso dello studio e devono acquistare le abilità 
che le aiuteranno a riuscire. Le lezioni sono progettate mentre 
un pacchetto con le abilità chiave di rinforzo in ogni lezione 
successiva in moda da sviluppare una coltura di studio col tempo. 
Possono essere trasportate in sequenza o essere usate 
individualmente, nell'insieme o in parte, per sostenere altri 
programmi dello studio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του μαθήματος είναι να επιτραπούν οι 
σπουδαστές για να πάρει τον έλεγχο της εκμάθησής τους με έναν 
θετικό τρόπο. Είναι το τρίτο μάθημα στη σειρά δεξιοτήτων 
μελέτης και προορίζεται να υποστηρίξει τους ενήλικους αρχαρίους 
που αρχίζουν σπουδές και πρέπει να αποκτήσουν τις δεξιότητες που 
θα τους βοηθήσουν για να είναι επιτυχείς. Τα μαθήματα 
σχεδιάζονται ως συσκευασία με τις βασικές δεξιότητες που 
ενισχύονται σε κάθε επόμενο μάθημα έτσι ώστε ένας πολιτισμός 
μελέτης αναπτύσσεται κατά τη διάρκεια του χρόνου. Μπορούν 
να παραδοθούν διαδοχικά ή να χρησιμοποιηθούν χωριστά, συνολικά 
ή εν μέρει, για να υποστηρίξουν άλλα προγράμματα της μελέτης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La puntería de esta lección es permitir a 
estudiantes tomar control de su aprender de una manera positiva. 
Es la tercera lección en las habilidades serie del estudio y se
piensa apoyar a los principiantes del adulto que están emprendiendo 
un curso del estudio y necesitan adquirir las habilidades que les 
ayudarán a ser acertadas. Se diseñan las lecciones mientras 
que un conjunto con las habilidades dominantes reforzadas en cada 
lección subsecuente para desarrollar una cultura del estudio en un 
cierto plazo. Pueden ser entregadas secuencialmente o ser 
utilizadas individualmente, en su totalidad o en parte, para utilizar 
otros programas del estudio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205226</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107745</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/active-learning-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
