<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103102</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103102</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tips for Parents on Keeping Children Drug Free</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neigt für Eltern auf dem Halten der Kind-Droge 
frei</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Incline pour des parents sur maintenir la drogue 
d'enfants libre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Derruba para pais em manter a droga das crianças 
livre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Si capovolge per i genitori sul mantenere la droga
dei bambini libera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακρες για τους γονείς στην κράτηση του φαρμάκου 
παιδιών ελεύθερου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Inclina para los padres en mantener la droga de 
los niños libre</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells what your children should know about drugs by the time they reach the third grade, ways to help your child stay drug free in the middle and junior high school years, and how to ensure that your child's school is keeping students drug free.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt, was Ihre Kinder über Drogen kennen 
sollten, bis sie den dritten Grad, Methoden, Ihrer Kindaufenthaltdroge
zu helfen erreichen, die in den mittlere und Juniorhigh School Jahren 
frei ist, und wie man sichergeht, daß Schule Ihres Kindes 
Kursteilnehmerdroge frei hält.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit ce que vos enfants devraient connaître des 
drogues avant qu'ils atteignent la troisième catégorie, voies 
d'aider votre drogue de séjour d'enfant libre en années de lycée 
moyen et junior, et comment s'assurer que l'école de votre enfant 
maintient la drogue d'étudiants libre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz o que suas crianças devem saber sobre drogas 
pelo tempo onde alcançam a terceira classe, maneiras ajudar a sua 
droga da estada da criança livre nos anos da High School média e 
júnior, e como se assegurar de que a escola da sua criança esteja 
mantendo a droga dos estudantes livre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a che cosa i vostri bambini dovrebbero 
conoscere circa le droghe per il momento in cui raggiungano il terzo 
grado, modi aiutare la vostra droga di soggiorno del bambino libera 
durante gli anni della 'junior high school'centrale ed ed a come 
accertarsi che scuola del vostro bambino stia mantenendo la droga 
degli allievi libera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει τι τα παιδιά σας πρέπει να ξέρουν για τα φάρμακα
ώσπου να φθάνουν στην τρίτη τάξη, τρόποι να ενισχυθεί το 
φάρμακο παραμονής παιδιών σας ελεύθερο στα μέσα και κατώτερα 
έτη γυμνασίου, και πώς να εξασφαλίσουν ότι το σχολείο του 
παιδιού σας κρατά το φάρμακο σπουδαστών ελεύθερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice lo que deben saber sus niños sobre las 
drogas para el momento en que alcancen el tercer grado, maneras de 
ayudar a su droga de la estancia del niño libre en los años de la 
High School secundaria media y menor, y cómo asegurarse de que la 
escuela de su niño está manteniendo la droga de los estudiantes 
libre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103102</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tips-for-parents-on-keeping-children-drug-free</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
