<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107676</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107676</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212891</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tundra maps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tundrakarten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cartes de toundra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mapas da tundra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programmi della tundra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Tundra χάρτες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Correspondencias de la tundra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This webpage shows the extent of global tundra on a map of the world. The map is part of the Windows to the Universe, a user-friendly learning system covering the Earth and Space sciences for use by the general public. The goal of the Windows to the Universe project is to build an internet site that includes a rich array of documents, including images, movies, animations, and data sets, that explore the Earth and Space sciences and the historical and cultural ties between science, exploration, and the human experience.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Webseite zeigt den Umfang der globalen 
Tundra auf einer Karte der Welt. Die Karte ist ein Teil 
Windows zum Universum, ein benutzerfreundliches erlernensystem, 
welches die Masse und Platzwissenschaften für Gebrauch durch die 
Öffentlichkeit umfaßt. Das Ziel Windows zum Universumprojekt 
ist, eine Internet-Site aufzubauen erforschen, die eine reiche Reihe 
Dokumente, einschließlich Bilder, Filme, Animationen und Dateien 
einschließt, die die Masse und Platzwissenschaften und das 
historische und kulturelle Gleichheit zwischen Wissenschaft, 
Erforschung, und die menschliche Erfahrung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette page Web montre l'ampleur de la toundra 
globale sur une carte du monde. La carte fait partie de Windows 
à l'univers, un système d'étude convivial couvrant les sciences de 
la terre et de l'espace à l'usage du grand public. Le but de 
Windows au projet d'univers est de construire un site Internet qui 
inclut un choix riche de documents, y compris des images, des films, 
des animations, et les Modem, qui explorent la terre et les sciences 
de l'espace et l'historique et les cravates culturelles entre la 
science, exploration, et l'expérience humaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web page mostra a extensão da tundra global 
em um mapa do mundo. O mapa é parte de Windows ao universo, um 
sistema de aprendizagem user-friendly que cobre as ciências da terra 
e do espaço para o uso pelo público geral. O objetivo de 
Windows ao projeto do universo é construir um local de Internet que 
inclua uma disposição rica dos originais, including imagens, filmes,
animations, e as séries de dados de, que exploram a terra e ciências
do espaço e o histórico e laços cultural entre a ciência, 
exploração, e a experiência humana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web page mostra il limite della tundra 
globale su un programma del mondo. Il programma fa parte di 
Windows all'universo, un sistema imparante facile da usare che 
riguarda le scienze dello spazio e della terra ad uso di grande 
pubblico. L'obiettivo di Windows al progetto dell'universo è di
costruire un luogo di Internet che include un allineamento ricco dei 
documenti, compreso le immagini, film, animazioni ed insiemi 
di dati, che esplorano la terra e le scienze dello spazio e lo storico
e legami culturali fra la scienza, esplorazione e l'esperienza umana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το webpage εμφανίζει την έκταση σφαιρικό 
tundra σε έναν χάρτη του κόσμου. Ο χάρτης είναι μέρος 
των Windows στον κόσμο, ένα φιλικό προς το χρήστη σύστημα 
εκμάθησης που καλύπτει τη γη και τις διαστημικές επιστήμες προς 
χρήση από το ευρύ κοινό. Ο στόχος των Windows στο 
πρόγραμμα κόσμου είναι να χτιστεί ένας χώρος διαδικτύου που 
περιλαμβάνει μια πλούσια σειρά εγγράφων, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
εικόνων, των κινηματογράφων, των ζωτικοτήτων, και των συνόλων 
στοιχείων, οι οποίοι ερευνούν τη γη και τις διαστημικές επιστήμες
και τους ιστορικούς και πολιτιστικούς δεσμούς μεταξύ της 
επιστήμης, της εξερεύνησης, και της ανθρώπινης εμπειρίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web page muestra el fragmento de la tundra 
global en una correspondencia del mundo. La correspondencia es 
parte de Windows al universo, un sistema que aprende convivial que 
cubre las ciencias de la tierra y del espacio para el uso del público
en general. La meta de Windows al proyecto del universo es 
construir un sitio de Internet que incluya un arsenal rico de 
documentos, incluyendo imágenes, las películas, las animaciones, y 
los modems, que exploran la tierra y las ciencias del espacio y el 
histórico y los lazos culturales entre la ciencia, exploración, y la
experiencia humana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212891</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107676</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tundra-maps</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
