<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106148</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106148</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209928</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Definition of a Square</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Definition eines Quadrats</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Définition d'une place</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Definição de um quadrado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Definizione di un quadrato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθορισμός ενός τετραγώνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Definición de un cuadrado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the properties and behavior of a square. The applets shows a square with all vertices draggable. As you drag any one, the others move to ensure the figure remains a square. It can be seen that the sides remain parallel and congruent, and the interior angles remain 90 degrees Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Eigenschaften und das Verhalten eines Quadrats 
zeigen. Die applet zeigt ein Quadrat mit allen draggable 
Gipfeln. Da Sie irgendein schleppen, bleibt die anderen 
Bewegung, die Abbildung sicherzustellen ein Quadrat. Es kann 
gesehen werden, daß die Seiten parallel und übereinstimmend bleiben 
und die Innenwinkel 90 Grad bleiben, die applet zum vollen Bildumfang 
für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden 
kann. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es 
von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne 
den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist 
ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les propriétés et le comportement d'une place. 
Les applet montre une place avec tous les sommets draggable. 
Car vous traînez n'importe quel, les autres mouvement d'assurer
la figure reste une place. Il peut voir que les côtés 
demeurent parallèles et conformes, et les angles intérieurs 
demeurent de 90 degrés que l'applet peut être agrandi à la taille 
de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. 
Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut 
lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison 
ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem as propriedades e o comportamento de um quadrado. Os 
applet mostram um quadrado com todos os vertices draggable. 
Porque você arrasta qualquer, o outro movimento assegurar a 
figura remanesce um quadrado. Pode-se ver que os lados 
remanescem paralelos e congruent, e os ângulos interior remanescem 90
graus que o applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o 
uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano le proprietà ed il comportamento di un quadrato. I 
applet mostra un quadrato con tutti i vertici draggable. Poichè
trascinate qualunque, gli altri movimento accertare la figura 
rimangono un quadrato. Può essere visto che i lati rimangono 
paralleli e conformi e gli angoli interni rimangono di 90 gradi che il
applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con 
un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, 
allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o 
nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa 
risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della 
geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τις ιδιότητες και τη συμπεριφορά ενός τετραγώνου. 
Τα applets εμφανίζουν ένα τετράγωνο με όλα vertices 
draggable. Δεδομένου ότι σέρνετε οποιου δήποτε, άλλα 
κίνηση για να εξασφαλίσουν τον αριθμό παραμένουν ένα τετράγωνο. 
Μπορεί να δει ότι οι πλευρές παραμένουν 
παράλληλες και σύμφωνες, και οι εσωτερικές γωνίες παραμένουν ότι
90 βαθμοί Applet μπορούν να διευρυνθούν στο πλήρες μέγεθος 
οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη 
χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον 
πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran las características y el comportamiento de un cuadrado. 
Los applet muestran un cuadrado con todas las cimas draggable. 
Pues usted arrastra, los otros movimiento de asegurar la figura 
siguen siendo un cuadrado. Puede ser visto que las caras siguen 
siendo paralelas y congruentes, y los ángulos interiores siguen 
siendo 90 grados que el applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209928</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106148</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/definition-of-a-square</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
