<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106662</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106662</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087041</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Ruins of Their Postwar Dream Homes": Housing Reform Advocates Testify before Congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Ruinen ihrer Nachkriegstraumhäuser": 
Verbesserung-Fürsprecher unterbringend, bezeugen Sie vor 
Kongreß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les ruines de leurs maisons rêveuses 
d'après-guerre" : En logeant des avocats de réforme témoignez
devant le congrès</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"as ruínas de suas HOME ideais postwar": 
Abrigando advogados da reforma testify antes do congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"le rovine delle loro sedi di sogno dopoguerra": 
Alloggiando i fautori di riforma testimoni prima del congresso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι καταστροφές των μεταπολεμικών"Οικιαών ονείρου τους
": Οι συνήγοροι μεταρρύθμισης κατοικίας πιστοποιούν πριν 
από το συνέδριο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"las ruinas de sus hogares ideales de la 
posguerra": Conteniendo a abogados de la reforma atestigüe 
antes de congreso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">New home construction declined dramatically during the Great Depression as rents rose, reaching an all-time high in 1940. A persistent housing shortage continuing into the early 1950s forced families to separate and apartment dwellers to "double-up." The housing reform movement, largely ineffectual in the 1920s and 1930s, gathered strength in the postwar period. Labor and veteran groups pressured Congress and the White House to enact a comprehensive housing policy with money for public housing and continued wartime rent control. President Harry S. Truman, echoing reformers, wrote to Congress, "A decent standard of housing for all is one of the irreducible obligations of modern civilization." Despite opposition from real estate interests, the Housing Act of 1949 passed. Although the Act called for the construction of 810,000 units of public housing over six years--and two additional housing acts in 1961 and 1965 promised substantial increases--by the mid-1960s, more people lived in substandard housing than in 1949. In addition, many blamed public housing itself for destroying neighborhoods and fostering social problems. In the following 1947 testimony before a joint Congressional committee created by anti-housing reform legislators to stall action, four spokespersons for housing reform--including social worker Mary K. Simkhovitch, a leading reform advocate since the 1920s--presented views and proposals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neuer Hauptaufbau sank drastisch während des 
großen Tiefstands, während Mieten stiegen und erreichte eine 
all-time Höhe 1940. Ein hartnäckiger Gehäusemangel, der in 
die frühen fünfziger Jahre fortfährt, erzwang Familien sich zu 
trennen und die Wohnung Bewohner "doppelt-oben." Die 
Gehäusereformbewegung, das groß wirkungslos in den zwanziger Jahren 
und in den dreißiger Jahren, erfaßte Stärke in der Nachkriegszeit. 
Arbeit und Veterangruppen drueckten Kongreß und das Weiße 
Haus, um eine komplette Gehäusepolitik mit Geld für Gasthaus zu 
verordnen und setzten Kriegmietesteuerung fort. Alle Präsident 
Harry S. Truman, Echo ausgeben Reformer, schrieb dem Kongreß, 
"ein annehmbarer Standard der Unterbringung für ist eine der nicht 
reduzierbaren Verpflichtungen der modernen Zivilisation." Trotz 
der Opposition von den Immobilieninteressen, überschritt die 
Gehäuse-Tat von 1949. Obgleich die Tat den Aufbau von 810.000 
Maßeinheiten allgemeinem Gehäuse über sechs Jahren -- und zwei 
zusätzliche Gehäusetaten 1961 und 1965 versprachen erhebliche 
Zunahmen -- bis zum den Mid-1960s verlangte, lebten mehr Leute im 
nicht der Norm entsprechenden Gehäuse als 1949. Zusätzlich 
tadelten viele allgemeines Gehäuse selbst für zerstörende 
Nachbarschaften und das Fördern von von Sozialproblemen. Im 
folgenden Zeugnis 1947 vor einem gemeinsamen Kongreßausschuß 
erstellt von den Anti-Gehäuse Verbesserunggesetzgebern, um 
Tätigkeit, vier Sprecher für Gehäuseverbesserung -- einschließlich
Sozialarbeiter Mary K. Simkhovitch, ein führender 
Verbesserungfürsprecher seit den zwanziger Jahren -- dargestellte 
Ansichten und Anträge festzuklemmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La nouvelle construction à la maison a diminué 
excessivement pendant la grande dépression pendant que les loyers 
montaient, atteignant une haute absolue en 1940. Un manque de 
logement persistant continuant dans le début des années 50 a forcé 
des familles à séparer et des habitants d'appartement "doubles-vers 
le haut." Le mouvement de réforme de logement, en grande partie
inefficaces dans les années 20 et les années 30, force recueillie 
dans l'après-guerre. Les groupes de travail et de vétéran ont
pressurisé le congrès et la Maison Blanche  pour décréter une 
politique de logement complète avec de l'argent pour la taverne et 
ont continué le contrôle des loyers de temps de guerre. Le 
Président Harry S. Truman, réformateurs de faire écho, a écrit au 
congrès, "un niveau décent de loger pour tout est l'un des 
engagements irréductibles de la civilisation moderne." En 
dépit de l'opposition des intérêts de immobiliers, la Loi de 
logement de 1949 a passé. Bien que l'acte ait nécessité la 
construction de 810.000 unités de logement public sur six ans -- et 
deux actes supplémentaires de logement en 1961 et 1965 ont promis des
augmentations substantielles -- par le milieu des années 60, plus de 
personnes ont vécu dans le logement inférieur qu'en 1949. En 
outre, beaucoup ont blâmé le logement public lui-même des 
voisinages détruisants et de stimuler des problèmes sociaux. 
Dans le témoignage 1947 suivant devant un comité 
congressionnel commun créé par des législateurs de réforme 
d'anti-logement pour caler l'action, quatre porte-parole pour la 
réforme de logement -- comprenant l'ouvrier social Mary K. 
Simkhovitch, un principal avocat de réforme depuis les années 20 -- 
vues présentées et les propositions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A construção home nova declinou dramàtica 
durante o depression grande enquanto os aluguéis se levantaram, 
alcançando uma elevação absoluta em 1940. Uma falta de 
carcaça persistente que continua nos 1950s adiantados forçou 
famílias a separar e moradores do apartamento "dobro-acima." O 
movimento de reforma da carcaça, pela maior parte ineffectual nos 
1920s e nos 1930s, força recolhida no período postwar. Os 
grupos do trabalho e do veteran exerceram pressão sobre o congress e 
a casa branca para decretar uma política de carcaça detalhada com 
dinheiro para a carcaça pública e continuaram o controle de aluguel 
do wartime. O presidente Harry S. Truman, reformers ecoando, 
escreveu ao congress, "um padrão decent de abrigar para todo é uma 
das obrigações irreducible da civilização moderna." Apesar 
da oposição dos interesses da propriedade real, o ato da carcaça de
1949 passou. Embora o ato se chamasse para a construção de 
810.000 unidades da carcaça pública sobre seis anos em -- e dois 
atos adicionais da carcaça em 1961 e em 1965 prometeram aumentos 
substanciais -- pelos mid-1960s, mais povos viveram na carcaça 
substandard do que em 1949. Além, muitos responsabilizaram a 
carcaça pública própria vizinhanças destruindo e promover 
problemas sociais. No seguinte testimony 1947 antes de um 
comitê congressional comum criado por legislators da reforma da 
anti-carcaça para parar a ação, os quatro spokespersons para a 
reforma da carcaça -- including o trabalhador social Mary K. 
Simkhovitch, um advogado principal da reforma desde os 1920s -- vistas
apresentadas e as propostas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La nuova costruzione domestica ha declinato 
drammaticamente durante la depressione grande mentre gli affitti sono 
aumentato, raggiungente un high assoluto in 1940. Una carenza 
edilizia persistente che continua nell'inizio degli anni cinquanta ha 
forzato le famiglie separare e gli abitanti dell'appartamento 
"doppi-in su." Il movimento di riforma dell'alloggiamento, in 
gran parte inefficaci negli anni 20 e nei 1930s, resistenza 
riunita nel periodo. I gruppi del veterano e di 
lavoro pressured il congresso e la Casa Bianca per promulgare una
politica edilizia completa con soldi per osteria ed hanno continuato 
il controllo dei canoni d'affitto di wartime. Il presidente 
Harry S. Truman, reformers echeggianti, ha scritto al congresso, "un 
livello decent di alloggio per tutto è uno degli obblighi 
irriducibili di civilizzazione moderna." Malgrado opposizione 
dagli interessi del bene immobile, la legge sugli alloggi di 1949 ha 
passato. Anche se la Legge ha richiesto la costruzione di 
810.000 unità di edilizia popolare in sei anni in -- e le due leggi 
sugli alloggi supplementari in 1961 ed in 1965 hanno promesso gli 
aumenti notevoli -- entro i mid-1960s, più gente ha vissuto in 
alloggiamento inferiore alla media che in 1949. In più, molti 
hanno incolpato dell'edilizia popolare in se distruggere le 
vicinanze e la promozione dei problemi sociali. Nella seguente 
testimonianza 1947 prima di un comitato congressuale unito creato dai 
legislatori di riforma dell'anti-alloggiamento per arrestarsi azione, 
quattro spokespersons per la riforma dell'alloggiamento -- compreso 
l'operaio sociale Mary K. Simkhovitch, un fautore principale di 
riforma dagli anni 20 -- viste presentate e le proposte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα βασική κατασκευή μειώθηκε εντυπωσιακά κατά τη 
διάρκεια της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης καθώς τα μισθώματα 
αυξήθηκαν, φθάνοντας όλων των εποχών σε έναν υψηλό το 1940. 
Μια επίμονη έλλειψη κατοικίας που συνεχίζεται στην πρόωρη 
δεκαετία του '50 ανάγκασε τις οικογένειες για να χωρίσει και τους 
κατοίκους διαμερισμάτων "διπλός-επάνω." Το κίνημα 
μεταρρύθμισης κατοικίας, κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος άκαρπο στη 
δεκαετία του '20 και τη δεκαετία του '30, μαζευμένη δύναμη στη 
μεταπολεμική περίοδο. Οι ομάδες εργασίας και παλαιμάχων 
πίεσαν το συνέδριο και το λευκό οίκο για να θεσπίσουν μια 
περιεκτική στεγαστική πολιτική με τα χρήματα για τη δημόσια 
κατοικία και συνέχισαν τον εν καιρώ πολέμου έλεγχο μισθώματος. 
Ο Πρόεδρος Harry S. Truman, αντηχώντας 
μεταρρυθμιστές, έγραψε στο συνέδριο, "κόσμιος ένας πρότυπος της 
κατοικίας για όλους είναι μια από τις αμείωτες υποχρεώσεις του 
σύγχρονου πολιτισμού." Παρά την αντίθεση από τα 
ενδιαφέροντα ακίνητων περιουσιών, ο νόμος κατοικίας του 1949 
πέρασε. Αν και ο νόμος απαίτησε την κατασκευή 810.000 
μονάδων της δημόσιας κατοικίας πάνω από έξι έτη -- και 
πρόσθετη κατοικία δύο ενεργούν το 1961 και οι το 1965 
υποσχεμένες ουσιαστικές αυξήσεις -- μέχρι τα μέσα τησδεκαετίας 
του '60, περισσότεροι άνθρωποι έζησαν στην κάτω του μετρίου 
κατοικία απ'ό,τι το 1949. Επιπλέον, πολλοί κατηγόρησαν 
τηνμέσος δημόσια κατοικία η ίδια για την καταστροφή των 
γειτονιών και την ενθάρρυνση κοινωνικών των προβλημάτων. 
Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση του 1947 ενώπιον μιας μικτής του 
Κογκρέσου επιτροπής που δημιουργήθηκε με την αντι-στέγαση των 
νομοθετών μεταρρύθμισης στην ενέργεια στάβλων, τέσσερις 
εκπρόσωποι για τη μεταρρύθμιση κατοικίας -- συμπεριλαμβανομένου 
του κοινωνικού λειτουργού Mary K. Simkhovitch, ένας 
κορυφαίος συνήγορος μεταρρύθμισης από τη δεκαετία του '20 -- 
υπέβαλαν τις όψεις και τις προτάσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La nueva construcción casera declinó 
dramáticamente durante la gran depresión como se levantaron los 
alquileres, alcanzando un colmo absoluto en 1940. Una escasez de
cubierta persistente que continuaba en los comienzos de los años 50 
forzó a las familias separarse y a habitantes del apartamento 
"dobles-para arriba." El el movimiento de reforma de la 
cubierta, en gran parte ineficaces en los años 20 y los años 30, 
fuerza recolectada en la posguerra. Los grupos del trabajo y del
veterano ejercieron presión sobre el congreso y la casa blanca para 
decretar una política de cubierta comprensiva con el dinero para la 
cubierta pública y continuaron el control de alquileres del tiempo de
guerra. Presidente Harry S. Truman, reformadores el producir eco,
escribió al congreso, "un estándar decente de contener para todo es 
una de las obligaciones irreducibles de la civilización moderna." 
A pesar de la oposición de intereses de las propiedades 
inmobiliarias, el acto de la cubierta de 1949 pasó. Aunque el 
acto llamó para la construcción de 810.000 unidades de cubierta 
pública sobre seis años -- y dos actos adicionales de la cubierta en
1961 y 1965 prometieron aumentos substanciales -- por los mediados de 
los años sesenta, más gente vivió en la cubierta inferior al nivel 
normal que en 1949. Además, muchos culparon la cubierta 
pública sí mismo por vecindades que destruían y fomentar problemas 
sociales. En el testimonio siguiente 1947 ante un comité del 
congreso común creado por los legisladores de la reforma de la 
contra-cubierta para atascar la acción, cuatro portavoces para la 
reforma de la cubierta -- incluyendo el trabajador social Maria K. 
Simkhovitch, abogado principal de la reforma desde los años 20 -- 
actuales visiónes y ofertas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087041</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106662</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-ruins-of-their-postwar-dream-homes-housing-reform-advocates-testify-before-congress</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
