<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108466</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108466</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086898</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Big Strike : A Journalist Describes the 1934 San Francisco Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Grosse Schlag: Ein Journalist beschreibt
den San Francisco Schlag 1934</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Grande Grève : Un journaliste décrit la
grève 1934 de San Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Batida Grande: Um journalist descreve a 
batida 1934 do San Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Colpo Grande: Un giornalista descrive il 
colpo 1934 de San Francisco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μεγάλη απεργία: Ένας δημοσιογράφος περιγράφει
την απεργία του Σαν Φρανσίσκο του 1934</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Huelga Grande: Un periodista describe la 
huelga 1934 de San Francisco</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On May 9, 1934, International Labor Association (ILA) leaders called a strike of all dockworkers on the West Coast who were joined a few days later by seamen and teamsters, effectively stopping all shipping from San Diego to Seattle. San Francisco would become the scene of the strike's most dramatic and widely known incidents, aptly described in one headline as "War in San Francisco!" On Bloody Thursday, July 5, 1934, two strikers were killed by the San Francisco police. A mass funeral march of tens of thousands of strikers and sympathizers four days later and the general strike that followed effectively shut down both San Francisco and Oakland (across the bay). Mike Quin, a self-described "rank-and-file journalist," offered a sympathetic picture of the striking workers actions in  The Big Strike , a collection of his published articles. Here, Quin described the events leading up to Bloody Thursday, and what happened in its aftermath.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An Mai 9, 1934, benannten internationale 
Arbeitsverbindung (ILA) Führer einen Schlag aller dockworkers auf der
Westküste, die einige Tage später durch Matrosen und teamsters 
verbunden wurden und effektiv stoppten alles Verschiffen von San Diego
nach Seattle. San Francisco würde die Szene des Schlages am 
drastischsten ist und weit bekannteste Ereignisse werden, passend 
beschrieben in einer Schlagzeile als "Krieg in San Francisco!" 
An blutigem Donnerstag Juli 5, 1934, wurden zwei Schlaggeräte 
von der San Francisco Polizei beendet. Ein Begräbnis- 
Massenmärz von 10 Tausenden Schlaggeräten und Gleichgesinnten vier 
Tage später und der Generalstreik daß gefolgtes effektiv 
abgeschaltetes San Francisco und Oakland (über der Bucht). 
Mike Quin, ein Selbst-beschriebener "Ordnen-unddatei 
Journalist," bot eine sympatische Abbildung der auffallenden 
Arbeitertätigkeiten im grossen Schlag, eine Ansammlung seiner 
erschienenen Artikel an. Hier beschrieb Quin die Fälle, die bis
zu blutigem Donnerstag führen, und was in seiner Nachmahd geschah.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">9 mai 1934, les amorces de travail 
internationales de l'association (ILA) ont appelé une grève de tous 
les dockworkers sur la côte occidentale qui ont été joints quelques
jours plus tard par des marins et des teamsters, arrêtant 
pertinemment toute l'expédition de San Diego à Seattle. San 
Francisco deviendrait la scène de la grève les incidents les plus 
excessifs et largement les plus connus, convenablement décrite dans 
un titre en tant que "guerre dans San Francisco!" Jeudi 
sanglant, 5 juillet 1934, deux butées ont été détruites par la 
police de San Francisco. Une marche funèbre de masse des 
dizaines de milliers de grèvistes et de sympathisants quatre jours 
plus tard et la grève que San pertinemment arrêté suivi Francisco
et Oakland (à travers le compartiment). Mike Quin, un 
art de l'auto-portrait-described "journaliste de ranger-et-fichier," a offert une 
image sympathique des actions saisissantes d'ouvriers dans la grande 
grève, une collection de ses articles édités. Ici, Quin a 
décrit les événements amenant au jeudi sanglant, et ce qui s'est 
produit dans sa conséquence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Maio em 9, 1934, os líderes labor internacionais 
da associação (ILA) chamaram uma batida de todos os dockworkers na 
costa ocidental que foram juntados alguns dias mais tarde por seamen e
por teamsters, parando eficazmente todo o transporte de San Diego a 
Seattle. O San Francisco transformar-se-ia a cena da batida os 
incidents os mais dramáticos e extensamente os mais sabidos, descrita
aptly em um headline como a "guerra em San Francisco!" Em 
quinta-feira sangrenta, julho 5, 1934, dois grevistas foram matados 
pelas polícias do San Francisco. Uma marcha da morte maciça 
dos dez dos milhares dos grevistas e dos sympathizers quatro dias mais
tarde e a batida geral que seguiu eficazmente fechou abaixo  San 
Francisco e Oakland (através da baía). O microfone Quin, da 
"um journalist self-descrito espesso-e-lima," ofereceu um retrato 
sympathetic das ações impressionantes dos trabalhadores na batida 
grande, uma coleção de seus artigos publicados. Aqui, Quin 
descreveu os eventos que conduzem a quinta-feira sangrenta, e o que 
aconteceu em seu aftermath.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Maggio su 9, 1934, i capi Di lavoro 
internazionali di associazione (ILA) hanno chiamato un colpo di tutti 
i dockworkers sul litorale ad ovest che si sono uniti più 
successivamente alcuni giorni dai marinai e dai teamsters, arrestante 
efficacemente tutto il trasporto da San Diego a Seattle. San 
Francisco si transformerebbe in nella scena del colpo avvenimenti più
drammatici ed ampiamente più conosciuti, descritta a proposito in un 
titolo come "guerra a San Francisco!" Il giovedì sanguinante, 5
luglio 1934, due percussori sono stati uccisi dalla polizia de San 
Francisco. Un procedere funereo totale dei dieci dei migliaia 
dei percussori e dei simpatizzanti quattro giorni successivamente ed 
il colpo generale che sia San Francisco che Oakland efficacemente 
interrotte seguite (attraverso la baia). Il microfono Quin, "un 
giornalista auto-descritto dell'alline-e-archivio," ha offerto 
un'immagine simpatica delle azioni notevoli degli operai nel colpo 
grande, una collezione di suoi articoli pubblicati. Qui, Quin ha
descritto gli eventi che portano a giovedì sanguinante e che cosa è 
accaduto nel relativo guaime.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε Μάιος 9 ..1934, οι διεθνείς ηγέτες ένωσης 
εργασίας (ILA) κάλεσαν μια απεργία όλων των dockworkers στη 
δυτική ακτή που ενώθηκαν μερικές ημέρες αργότερα από τους 
ναυτικούς και τα teamsters, σταματώντας αποτελεσματικά όλων 
από το Σαν Ντιέγκο στο Σιάτλ. Το Σαν Φρανσίσκο θα γινόταν η
σκηνή της απεργίας πιό δραματικά και ευρέως γνωστά γεγονότα, 
που περιγράφεται καταλλήλως σε έναν τίτλο ως "πόλεμος στο Σαν 
Φρανσίσκο!" Την αιματηρή Πέμπτη, 5 Ιουλίου ..1934, δύο 
απεργοί σκοτώθηκαν από την αστυνομία του Σαν Φρανσίσκο. Μια
μάζα νεκρικός Μάρτιος των δεκάδων χιλιάδων απεργοί και 
υποστηρικτές τέσσερις ημέρες αργότερα και η γενική απεργία που 
ακολούθησαν το αποτελεσματικά διακομμένα και Σαν Φρανσίσκο και το 
Όουκλαντ (πέρα από τον κόλπο). Ο Mike Quin, ένας 
μόνος-περιγραμμένος "δημοσιογράφος πυκνός-και-αρχείων," πρόσφερε
μια συμπονετική εικόνα των εντυπωσιακών ενεργειών εργαζομένων στη
μεγάλη απεργία, μια συλλογή των δημοσιευμένων άρθρων του. 
Εδώ, Quin περιέγραψε τα γεγονότα που καταλήγουν στην 
αιματηρή Πέμπτη, και τι συνέβη στη συνέπειά του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">9 de mayo de 1934, los arranques de cinta de 
trabajo internacionales de la asociación (ILA) convocaron una huelga 
de todos los dockworkers en la costa del oeste que fueron ensamblados 
algunos días más adelante por los marineros y los teamsters, parando
con eficacia todo el envío de San Diego a Seattle. San 
Francisco se convirtió en la escena de la huelga los incidentes más 
dramáticos y extensamente sabidos, descrita conveniente en un título
como "guerra en San Francisco!" El jueves sangriento, de julio 
el 5 de 1934, dos huelguistas fueron matados por el policía de San 
Francisco. Un marzo fúnebre total de diez de millares de 
huelguistas y de simpatizantes cuatro días más adelante y la huelga 
general que San Francisco y Oakland con eficacia cerrados seguidos (a 
través de la bahía). Mike Quin, "periodista uno 
mismo-descrito del alinear-y-fichero," ofreció un cuadro comprensivo 
de las acciones llamativas de los trabajadores en la huelga grande, 
una colección de sus artículos publicados. Aquí, Quin 
describió los acontecimientos que conducían a jueves sangriento, y 
qué sucedió en sus consecuencias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086898</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108466</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-big-strike-a-journalist-describes-the-1934-san-francisco-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
