<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108212</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108212</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Women Wanting to Work</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frauen, die arbeiten wünschen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Femmes voulant travailler</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mulheres que querem trabalhar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Donne che desiderano funzionare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γυναίκες που θέλουν να εργαστεί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mujeres que desean trabajar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Worldwide, women are influencing businesses and economies on an unprecedented scale. WIDE ANGLE's '1-800-INDIA' (2005) and 'Pickles, Inc.' (2005) give us insight into two instances of economic and social shifts being wrought by the entry of women into local and international economies. In this lesson, students will begin by examining historic photographs to determine how economic roles for women have changed in the United States. They will then look at contemporary examples of women entering the workforce for the first time: in India's outsourcing sector; and in small business in Israel. They will explore how these women's entry into the economic sphere often involves negotiation and the overcoming of obstacles, but can bring about larger social and behavioral changes as well. As a Culminating Activity, students will apply the knowledge gained in this lesson toward a response to a Document-Based Question.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weltweit beeinflussen Frauen Geschäfte und 
Wirtschaftssysteme auf einer beispiellosen Skala. Weitwinkel' 
1-800-INDIA ' (2005) und ' Essiggurken, Inc..' (2005) geben uns 
Einblick in zwei Fälle der ökonomischen und Sozialschichten, die 
durch den Eintrag der Frauen in die lokalen und internationalen 
Wirtschaftssysteme wrought sind. In dieser Lektion fangen 
Kursteilnehmer an, indem sie historische Fotographien überprüfen, um
festzustellen, wie ökonomische Rollen für Frauen in den Vereinigten 
Staaten geändert haben. Sie betrachten dann zeitgenössische 
Beispiele der Frauen, welche zum ersten Mal die Mannschaft anmelden: 
im Outsourcingsektor Indiens; und im Kleinbetrieb in 
Israel. Sie erforschen, wie Eintrag dieser Frauen in den 
ökonomischen Bereich häufig Vermittlung und die Überwindung von 
Hindernissen miteinbezieht, aber können ungefähr größere Sozial- 
und Verhaltensänderungen außerdem holen. Als kulminierende 
Aktivität wenden Kursteilnehmer das Wissen an, das in dieser Lektion 
in Richtung zu einer Antwort zu einer Dokument-Gegründeten Frage 
gewonnen wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le monde entier, les femmes influencent des 
entreprises et des économies sur une échelle sans précédent. 
'1-800-INDIA 'grand-angulaire (2005) et 'conserves au vinaigre, 
inc..' (2005) nous donnent l'perspicacité dans deux exemples 
des décalages économiques et sociaux étant travaillés par 
l'entrée des femmes dans des économies locales et internationales. 
Dans cette leçon, les étudiants commenceront en examinant les 
photographies historiques pour déterminer comment les rôles 
économiques pour des femmes ont changé aux Etats-Unis. Ils 
regarderont alors des exemples contemporains des femmes présentant la
main d'oeuvre pour la première fois : dans le secteur 
externalisant de l'Inde ; et dans la petite entreprise en 
Israel. Ils exploreront comment l'entrée de ces femmes dans la 
sphère économique implique souvent la négociation et surmonter des 
obstacles, mais peuvent provoquer des changements sociaux et 
comportementaux plus grands aussi bien. Comme activité 
culminante, les étudiants appliqueront la connaissance gagnée dans 
cette leçon vers une réponse à une question Document-Basée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Worldwide, as mulheres estão influenciando 
negócios e economias em uma escala unprecedented. ' 1-800-INDIA
' do ângulo LARGO (2005) e ' pickles, Inc.' (2005) dão-nos a 
introspecção em dois exemplos das SHIFT econômicas e sociais que 
são feitas pela entrada das mulheres em economias locais e 
internacionais. Nesta lição, os estudantes começarão 
examinando fotografias historic para determinar como os papéis 
econômicos para mulheres mudaram nos estados unidos. Olharão 
então exemplos contemporary das mulheres que inscrevem o workforce 
para a primeira vez: no setor do outsourcing de India; e 
na empresa de pequeno porte em Israel. Explorarão como a 
entrada destas mulheres na esfera econômica envolve frequentemente a 
negociação e superar dos obstáculos, mas podem trazer mudanças 
sociais e behavioral aproximadamente maiores também. Como uma 
atividade culminando, os estudantes aplicarão o conhecimento ganho 
nesta lição para uma resposta a uma pergunta Original-Baseada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Universalmente, le donne stanno influenzando i 
commerci e le economie su una scala senza precedente. 
'1-800-INDIA 'grandangolare (2005) e 'sottaceti, inc.' 
(2005) ci dà la comprensione in due casi degli spostamenti 
economici e sociali che sono modellati dall'entrata delle donne nelle 
economie locali ed internazionali. In questa lezione, gli 
allievi cominceranno esaminando le fotografie storiche per determinare
come i ruoli economici per le donne sono cambiato in unito 
Dichiara. Allora guarderanno gli esempi contemporanei 
delle donne che entrano per la prima volta nella mano d'opera: 
nel settore di outsourcing dell'India; e nella piccola 
impresa nell'Israele. Esploreranno come entrata di queste donne 
nella sfera economica coinvolge spesso la trattativa e sormontare 
degli ostacoli, ma possono determinare i cambiamenti sociali e del 
comportamento più grandi pure. Come attività di culminazione, 
gli allievi applicheranno la conoscenza guadagnata in questa lezione 
verso una risposta ad una domanda Documento-Basata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παγκοσμίως, οι γυναίκες επηρεάζουν τις επιχειρήσεις 
και τις οικονομίες σε μια πρωτοφανή κλίμακα. WIDE ΑΝΓΛΕΣ 
"1-800-ΙΝΔΙΑ" (2005) και "τουρσιά, INC." (2005) μας 
δώστε τη διορατικότητα σε δύο περιπτώσεις οικονομικών και 
κοινωνικών μετατοπίσεων που είναι επεξεργασμένων από την είσοδο 
των γυναικών μέσα σε τις τοπικές και διεθνείς οικονομίες. 
Σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές θα αρχίσουν με την εξέταση
των ιστορικών φωτογραφιών για να καθορίσουν πώς οι οικονομικοί 
ρόλοι για τις γυναίκες αλλάζω στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Θα 
εξετάσουν έπειτα τα σύγχρονα παραδείγματα των γυναικών που 
εισάγουν το εργατικό δυναμικό για πρώτη φορά: στον τομέα 
της μεταφοράς της Ινδίας  και στη μικρή επιχείρηση στο 
Ισραήλ. Θα εξερευνήσουν πώς η είσοδος αυτών των γυναικών 
μέσα σε την οικονομική σφαίρα περιλαμβάνει συχνά τη 
διαπραγμάτευση και την υπερνίκηση των εμποδίων, αλλά μπορούν να 
επιφέρουν τις μεγαλύτερες κοινωνικές και συμπεριφοριστικές 
αλλαγές επίσης. Σαν καταλήγοντας δραστηριότητα, οι 
σπουδαστές θα εφαρμόσουν τη γνώση που αποκτιέται σε αυτό το 
μάθημα προς μια απάντηση σε μια έγγραφο-βασισμένη ερώτηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Por todo el mundo, las mujeres están 
influenciando negocios y economías en una escala sin precedente. 
' 1-800-INDIA granangular ' (2005) y ' salmueras, inc..' 
(2005) nos da la penetración en dos casos de las rotaciones 
económicas y sociales que son labradas por la entrada de mujeres en 
economías locales e internacionales. En esta lección, los 
estudiantes comenzarán examinando las fotografías históricas para 
determinarse cómo los papeles económicos de mujeres han cambiado en 
los Estados Unidos. Entonces mirarán ejemplos contemporáneos 
de las mujeres que inscriben a la mano de obra para la primera vez: 
en el sector del outsourcing de la India; y en pequeña 
empresa en Israel. Explorarán cómo la entrada de estas mujeres
en la esfera económica implica a menudo la negociación y la 
superación de obstáculos, pero pueden traer cambios sociales y del 
comportamiento alrededor de más grandes también. Como 
actividad que culmina, los estudiantes aplicarán el conocimiento 
ganado en esta lección hacia una respuesta a una pregunta 
Documento-Basada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:HEATHER AULETTA
FN:HEATHER AULETTA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108212</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/women-wanting-to-work</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
