<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105257</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105257</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206822</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Findings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Entdeckungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Résultats</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Findings</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risultati</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συμπεράσματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Resultados</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">profiles scientists doing cutting-edge medical research. Learn about the work of a biologist who is tracking thousands of genes in living cells, an anesthesiologist whose questions about body temperature led to improvements for surgery patients, a natural de-icer, healing wounds with air, and more. Read the website or order the free magazine.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erstellt die Wissenschaftler ein Profil, die 
Ausschnitt-Rand medizinische Forschung tun. Erlernen Sie über 
die Arbeit eines Biologen, der Tausenden Gene in lebenden Zellen 
aufspürt, des Anästhesiologen dessen Fragen über Körpertemperatur 
zu Verbesserungen für Chirurgiepatienten, ein natürlicher Enteiser, 
heilende Wunden mit Luft führten, und mehr. Lesen Sie die Web 
site oder bestellen Sie die freie Zeitschrift.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">profile des scientifiques faisant la recherche 
médicale de découpage-bord. Renseignez-vous sur le travail 
d'un biologiste qui dépiste des milliers de gènes en cellules 
vivantes, d'un anesthésiste dont les questions au sujet de la 
température de corps ont mené aux améliorations pour des patients 
de chirurgie, un dégivreur normal, blessures curatives avec de l'air,
et de plus. Lisez le site Web ou commandez le magasin libre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">perfila os cientistas que fazem a pesquisa médica
da corte-borda. Aprenda sobre o trabalho de um biólogo que 
esteja seguindo milhares dos genes em pilhas vivas, de um 
anesthesiologist cujas as perguntas sobre a temperatura de corpo 
conduzam às melhorias para pacientes da cirurgia, um de-icer natural,
feridas healing com ar, e de mais. Leia o Web site ou requisite 
o compartimento livre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">profila gli scienziati che fanno la ricerca medica
del taglio-bordo. Impari circa il lavoro di un biologo che sta 
rintracciando le migliaia dei geni in cellule viventi, di un 
anesthesiologist di cui le domande circa la temperatura corporea hanno
condotto ai miglioramenti per i pazienti di chirurgia, un de-icer 
naturale, ferite healing con aria e di più. Legga il Web site o
ordini lo scomparto libero.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επιστήμονες σχεδιαγραμμάτων που κάνουν την ιατρική 
έρευνα τέμνων-ακρών. Μάθετε για την εργασία ενός βιολόγου
που ακολουθεί χιλιάδες γονίδια στα ζωντανά κύτταρα, ένα 
anesthesiologist οι του οποίου ερωτήσεις για τη θερμοκρασία 
σωμάτων οδήγησαν στις βελτιώσεις για τους ασθενείς χειρουργικών 
επεμβάσεων, φυσικό de-icer, που θεραπεύει τις πληγές με τον 
αέρα, και περισσότερους. Διαβάστε τον ιστοχώρο ή διατάξτε 
το ελεύθερο περιοδικό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">perfila a científicos que hacen la investigación
médica del corte-borde. Aprenda sobre el trabajo de un biólogo
que esté siguiendo millares de genes en células vivas, de un 
anesthesiologist que preguntas sobre temperatura del cuerpo condujeron
a las mejoras para los pacientes de la cirugía, un de-icer natural, 
heridas curativas con aire, y más. Lea el Web site o pida el 
compartimiento libre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206822</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105257</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/findings</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
