<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104014</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104014</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086901</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Black Star Line": Singing a Song of Garveyism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Schwarze Stern-Zeile": Singen eines 
Lieds von Garveyism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Noir Tiennent le premier rôle La Ligne" : Chant 
d'une chanson de Garveyism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"A Linha Preta Da Estrela": Cantando uma 
canção de Garveyism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Riga Nera Della Stella": Canto della 
canzone di Garveyism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η μαύρη γραμμή αστεριών": Τραγούδι ενός 
τραγουδιού Garveyism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"La Línea Negra De la Estrella": Cantar una
canción de Garveyism</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">African-American soldiers returned from World War I to face intensified discrimination, segregation, and racial violence. Drawing on this frustration, Marcus Garvey attracted thousands of disillusioned black working-class and lower middle-class followers to his Universal Negro Improvement Association (UNIA). The UNIA, committed to notions of racial purity and separatism, insisted that salvation for African Americans meant building an autonomous, black-led nation in Africa. By the mid-1920s, the UNIA boasted more than 700 branches in 38 states and more than 200 offices outside the United States. The Black Star Line, an all-black shipping company chartered by the UNIA, was the movement's boldest and most important project. To many of Garvey's supporters, it represented the promise of economic autonomy and escape from prejudice and discrimination in America. The UNIA vigorously promoted the sale of Black Star Line stock with advertisements and colorful stock certificates in Garvey's popular newspaper, the  Negro World . It also celebrated the shipping line in poems and songs, such as "The Black Star Line."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Soldaten kamen vom 
Ersten Weltkrieg zu Gesicht verstärkter Unterscheidung, zur 
Abtrennung und zur rassischen Gewalttätigkeit zurück. 
Zeichnend auf diese Frustration, zog Marcus Garvey Tausenden der
ernüchterten schwarzen Arbeiterklasse und der untereren 
Mittelklassenachfolger zu seiner Universalschwarze-Verbesserung 
Verbindung an (UNIA). Das UNIA, festgelegt an den Begriffen der 
rassischen Reinheit und des Separatismus, beharrte, daß Rettung 
für afrikanische Amerikaner das Aufbauen einer autonomen bedeutete, 
schwarz-führenden Nation in Afrika. Bis zum den Mid-1920s 
rühmte sich das UNIA mehr als 700 Zweige in 38 Zuständen und mehr 
als 200 Büros außerhalb der Vereinigten Staaten. Die schwarze 
Stern-Zeile, eine all-schwarze Verschiffenfirma, die durch das UNIA 
gechartert wurde, war das fetteste und wichtigste Projekt der 
Bewegung. Zu vielen von Verfechtern Garveys, stellte sie die 
Versprechung der ökonomischen Autonomie und Entweichen vom Vorurteil 
und Unterscheidung in Amerika dar. Das UNIA förderte kräftig 
den Verkauf der schwarzen Stern-Zeile Vorrat mit Reklameanzeigen und 
bunten Aktienzertifikaten Garveys in der populären Zeitung, die 
Schwarze-Welt. Es feierte auch die Schiffslinie in den Gedichten
und in den Lieden, wie "der schwarzen Stern-Zeile."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les soldats afro-américains sont revenus de la 
Première Guerre Mondiale à la discrimination intensifiée par 
visage, à la ségrégation, et à la violence raciale. 
Dessinant sur cet anéantissement, Marcus Garvey a attiré des 
milliers de classe ouvrière noire désillusionnée et de sectateurs 
inférieurs de classe moyenne à son association universelle 
d'amélioration de nègre (UNIA). L'UNIA, commis aux notions de 
la pureté et du séparatisme raciaux, a insisté sur le fait que le 
salut pour les Américains africains a signifié établir une nation 
autonome et noir-menée en Afrique. Par le milieu des années 
20, l'UNIA a revendiqué plus de 700 branchements dans 38 états et 
plus de 200 bureaux en dehors des Etats-Unis. Le noir 
Tiennent le premier rôle la ligne, une compagnie maritime tout-noire 
privilégiée par l'UNIA, étaient le projet le plus gras et le plus 
important du mouvement. À plusieurs des défenseurs de Garvey, 
il a représenté la promesse de l'autonomie économique et l'évasion
du préjudice et la discrimination en Amérique. L'UNIA a 
vigoureusement favorisé la vente du noir Tient le premier rôle la ligne 
actions avec des annonces et des certificats d'actions colorés en 
journal populaire de Garvey, le monde de nègre. Il a également
célébré la ligne maritime en poésies et les chansons, telles que 
"le noir Tiennent le premier rôle la ligne."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os soldados Africano-Americanos retornaram do 
world.war.i à discriminação intensified cara, ao segregation, e à 
violência racial. Desenhando nesta frustração, Marcus Garvey 
atraiu milhares do working-class preto disillusioned e de uns 
seguidores mais baixos do middle-class a sua associação universal da
melhoria do negro (UNIA). O UNIA, cometido às noções do 
purity e do separatism raciais, insistiu que o salvation para 
americanos africanos significou construir uma nação autônoma, 
preto-conduzida em África. Pelos mid-1920s, o UNIA boasted mais
de 700 filiais em 38 estados e em parte externa de mais de 200 
escritórios os estados unidos. A linha preta da estrela, uma 
companhia de transporte todo-preta fretada pelo UNIA, era o projeto o 
mais bold(realce) e o mais importante do movimento. A muitos de 
supporters de Garvey, representou a promessa da autonomia econômica e
o escape do preconceito e a discriminação em América. O UNIA 
promoveu vigorosa a venda da linha preta estoque da estrela com 
propagandas e os certificados conservados em estoque coloridos no 
jornal popular de Garvey, o mundo do negro. Comemorou também a 
linha de transporte nos poemas e nas canções, tais como "a linha 
preta da estrela."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I soldati Africano-Americani hanno ritornato dal 
world.war.i a distinzione intensificata faccia, alla segregazione ed 
alla violenza razziale. Dissipando su questa frustrazione, 
Marcus Garvey ha attratto i migliaia della classe operaia nera 
disillusa e dei seguicamme più bassi della classe media alla sua 
associazione universale di miglioramento del negro (UNIA). Il 
UNIA, impegnato nelle nozioni della purezza e del separatism razziali,
ha insistito che la salvezza per gli Americani africani ha 
significato lo sviluppo della nazione autonoma e nero-condotta in 
Africa. Entro i mid-1920s, il UNIA si è vantato più di 700 
rami in 38 dichiara e più di 200 della parte esterna degli 
uffici uniti Dichiarano. La riga nera della stella, 
un'azienda di trasporto tutto-nera istituita dal UNIA, era il progetto
più GRASSETTO e più importante del movimento. A molti dei 
sostenitori del Garvey, ha rappresentato la promessa di autonomia 
economica e la fuga dal pregiudizio e la distinzione in America. 
Il UNIA ha promosso vigoroso la vendita della riga nera azione 
della stella con le pubblicità ed i certificati di riserva colorful 
in giornale popolare del Garvey, il mondo del negro. Egualmente 
ha celebrato la linea marittima nei poems e nelle canzoni, quale "la 
riga nera della stella."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά οι στρατιώτες επέστρεψαν από 
τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι ενταμένη στην πρόσωπο διάκριση, το 
διαχωρισμό, και τη φυλετική βία. Επισύροντας την προσοχή σε
αυτήν την απογοήτευση, ο Marcus Garvey προσέλκυσε χιλιάδες 
απογοητευμένη μαύρη εργατική τάξη και χαμηλότεροι οπαδοί 
μεσαίων τάξεων στην καθολική ένωση βελτίωσης νέγρων του 
(UNIA). Το UNIA, δεσμευμένο στις έννοιες της φυλετικών 
αγνότητας και του αυτονομισμού, επέμεινε ότι η σωτηρία για 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς σήμανε ένα αυτόνομο, μαύρος-οδηγημένο 
έθνος στην Αφρική. Μέχρι τα μέσα τησδεκαετίας του '20, το 
UNIA καυχήθηκε περισσότεροι από 700 κλάδος σε 38 κράτη 
και περισσότερα από 200 γραφεία έξω από τις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες. Η μαύρη γραμμή αστεριών, μια όλος-μαύρη 
ναυτιλιακή εταιρία που ναυλώθηκε από το UNIA, ήταν το pjo' 
ψολδεστ και σημαντικότερο πρόγραμμα της μετακίνησης. Σε 
πολλοί από τους υποστηρικτές Garvey, αντιπροσώπευσε την 
υπόσχεση της οικονομικών αυτονομίας και της διαφυγής από την 
προκατάληψη και τη διάκριση στην Αμερική. Το UNIA 
προώθησε σθεναρά την πώληση του μαύρου αποθέματος γραμμών 
αστεριών με τις διαφημίσεις και τα ζωηρόχρωμα πιστοποιητικά 
αποθεμάτων στη δημοφιλή εφημερίδα Garvey, ο κόσμος νέγρων. 
Γιόρτασε επίσης την ακτοπλοϊκή γραμμή στα ποιήματα και τα 
τραγούδια, όπως "η μαύρη γραμμή αστεριών."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los soldados Africano-Americanos volvieron de 
Primera Guerra Mundial a la discriminación intensificada cara, a la 
segregación, y a la violencia racial. Trazando en esta 
frustración, Marcus Garvey atrajo a millares de clase obrera negra 
desilusionada y de seguidores más bajos de la clase media a su 
asociación universal de la mejora del negro (UNIA). El UNIA, 
confiado a las nociones de la pureza y del separatism raciales, 
insistió que la salvación para los americanos africanos significó 
la construcción de una nación autónoma, negro-conducida en África.
Por los mediados de los años veinte, el UNIA se jactó más de 
700 ramificaciones en 38 estados y más de 200 oficinas fuera de los 
Estados Unidos. La línea negra de la estrella, una compañía 
de envío todo-negra cargada por el UNIA, era el proyecto más en 
negrilla y más importante del movimiento. A muchos de los 
partidarios de Garvey, representó la promesa de la autonomía 
económica y el escape del prejudicar y la discriminación en 
América. El UNIA promovió vigoroso la venta de la línea negra
acción de la estrella con los anuncios y los certificados comunes 
coloridos en el periódico popular de Garvey, el mundo del negro. 
También celebró la línea de envío en poemas y canciones, 
tales como "la línea negra de la estrella."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086901</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104014</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-black-star-line-singing-a-song-of-garveyism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
