<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104394</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104394</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087129</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">To Save China: "New York Hand Laundry Alliance Intensifies Anti-Japanese Work"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">China Sichern: "New York 
Handwäscherei-Bündnis Verstärkt Anti-Japanische Arbeit"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour Sauvegarder La Chine : "l'Alliance de 
Blanchisserie de Main de New York Intensifie Le Travail 
Anti-Japonais"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para conservar China: De "O Alliance Da 
Lavanderia Da Mão New York Intensifies O Trabalho Anti-Japonês"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per salvare La Cina: "L'Alleanza Della 
Lavanderia Della Mano De New York Intensifica Il Lavoro 
Anti-Giapponese"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για να σώσει την Κίνα: "Η συμμαχία πλυντηρίων 
χεριών της Νέας Υόρκης εντείνει την αντι-ιαπωνική εργασία"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para salvar China: "La Alianza Del Lavadero 
De la Mano De Nueva York Intensifica El Trabajo Contra-Japone's"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Japan invaded China in 1931. The ruling Kuomintang Party (KMT) in China, led by Chiang Kai-shek, initially adopted a nonresistance policy toward the Japanese. Many overseas Chinese, including members of New York City's Chinese Hand Laundry Alliance (CHLA), opposed the KMT's passive position and organized "Save China" campaigns to raise money for a strong China. The CHLA sent letters and telegrams to American politicians urging them to adopt policies to support China against Japan. But the CHLA's main strategy was to appeal directly to the American public by approaching their customers, residents of New York City. This 1938 article in the  Chinese Vanguard  reported on the CHLA's anti-Japanese work and efforts to mobilize support for China.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Japan eingedrungenes China 1931. Die 
regierende Kuomintang Partei (KMT) in China, geführt von 
Chiang Kai-shek, nahm zuerst eine nonresistance Politik in Richtung 
zum Japaner an. Viele Überseechinesen, einschließlich Bauteile
wäscherei-Bündnisses der New York Stadt des chinesischen Hand(CHLA),
setzten der des KMTs passiven Position entgegen und organisierten 
"außer China" Kampagnen, um Geld für ein starkes Porzellan 
anzuheben. Das CHLA schickte den amerikanischen Politikern 
Briefe und Telegramme, die sie drängen, politische Richtlinien 
anzunehmen, um China gegen Japan zu unterstützen. Aber die 
CHLA's Hauptstrategie war, direkt der amerikanischen Öffentlichkeit 
zu gefallen, indem sie ihren Kunden, Bewohnern von New York City sich 
näherte. Dieser Artikel 1938 in der chinesischen Avantgarde
berichtete über die CHLA's Anti-Japanische Arbeit und die 
Bemühungen, Support für China zu mobilisieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Chine envahie par Japon en 1931. La 
partie régnante de Kuomintang (KMT) en Chine, menée par Chiang 
Kai-shek, a au commencement adopté une politique de nonresistance 
vers le Japonais. Beaucoup de Chinois d'outre-mer, y compris des
membres de l'alliance chinoise de blanchisserie de la main de la ville
de New York (CHLA), se sont opposés à la position passive du KMT et 
ont organisé des campagnes "économiser Chine" pour soulever l'argent
pour la Chine forte. Le CHLA a envoyé des lettres et des 
télégrammes aux politiciens américains les invitant à adopter des 
politiques pour supporter la Chine contre le Japon. Mais la 
stratégie principale de CHLA's était de faire directement appel au 
public américain en approchant leurs clients, résidants de New York 
City. Cet article 1938 dans la tête d'avant-garde chinoise a 
rendu compte du travail et des efforts anti-Japonais de CHLA's de 
mobiliser le soutien de la Chine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">China invadida Japão em 1931. O partido 
governando de Kuomintang (KMT) em China, conduzida por Chiang 
Kai-shek, adotou inicialmente uma política do nonresistance para o 
japonês. Muitos chineses ultramarinos, including membros do 
alliance chinês da lavanderia da mão da cidade de New York (CHLA), 
opuseram a posição passiva do KMT e organizaram "excepto campanhas 
de China" para levantar o dinheiro para uma China forte. O CHLA 
emitiu letras e telegramas aos políticos americanos que incitam os 
adotar políticas para suportar China de encontro a Japão. Mas 
a estratégia principal de CHLA's era apelar diretamente ao público 
americano aproximando seus clientes, residentes de New York City. 
Este artigo 1938 no vanguard chinês relatou no trabalho e nos 
esforços anti-Japoneses de CHLA's mobilize a sustentação para 
China.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Cina invasa il Giappone in 1931. Il 
partito di regolamento di Kuomintang (KMT) in Cina, condotta da Chiang
Kai-shek, inizialmente ha adottato una politica di nonresistance verso
il giapponese. Molto cinese d'oltremare, compreso i membri
dell'alleanza cinese della lavanderia della mano della città de 
New York (CHLA), ha opposto la posizione passiva del KMT ed ha 
organizzato "risparmi le campagne della Cina" per alzare i soldi per 
la Cina forte. Il CHLA ha trasmesso le lettere ed i telegrammi 
ai politici americani che li invitano ad adottare le politiche per 
sostenere la Cina contro il Giappone. Ma la strategia principale
di CHLA's era di fare appello direttamente al pubblico americano 
avvicinandosi ai loro clienti, residenti di New York City. 
Questo articolo 1938 nell'avanguardia cinese ha segnalato 
sul lavoro e sugli sforzi anti-Giapponesi di CHLA's mobilitare il 
sostegno la Cina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Ιαπωνία Κίνα το 1931. Το κυβερνών κόμμα 
Kuomintang (KMT) στην Κίνα, που οδηγήθηκε από Chiang 
Kai-shek, υιοθέτησε αρχικά μια πολιτική nonresistance προς 
τους Ιάπωνες. Πολλά υπερπόντια κινεζικά, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των μελών της κινεζικής συμμαχίας πλυντηρίων 
χεριών της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης (CHLA), αντέταξε την 
παθητική θέση του KMT και οργάνωσε τις εκστρατείες "εκτός από
της Κίνασ" για να συγκεντρώσει τα χρήματα για μια ισχυρή Κίνα. 
Το CHLA έστειλε τις επιστολές και τα τηλεγραφήματα στους 
αμερικανικούς πολιτικούς που ωθούν τους για να υιοθετήσει τις 
πολιτικές για να υποστηρίξει την Κίνα ενάντια στην Ιαπωνία. 
Αλλά η βασική στρατηγική του CHLA ήταν να απευθυνθεί 
άμεσα στο αμερικανικό κοινό με την προσέγγιση των πελατών τους, 
κάτοικοι της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης. Αυτό το άρθρο του 
1938 στην κινεζική εμπροσθοφυλακή που αναφέρεται στην 
αντι-ιαπωνικές εργασία και τις προσπάθειες του CHLA να 
κινητοποιηθεί η υποστήριξη για την Κίνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">China invadida Japón en 1931. El partido 
predominante de Kuomintang (KMT) en China, conducida por Chiang 
Kai-shek, adoptó inicialmente una política del nonresistance hacia 
el japonés. Muchos chinos de ultramar, incluyendo miembros de 
la alianza china del lavadero de la mano de la ciudad de Nueva York 
(CHLA), opusieron la posición pasiva del KMT y ordenaron "excepto las
campañas de China" para levantar el dinero para una China fuerte. 
El CHLA envió letras y telegramas a los políticos americanos 
que los impulsaban adoptar políticas para utilizar China contra 
Japón. Pero la estrategia principal de CHLA's era abrogar 
directamente al público americano acercando a sus clientes, 
residentes de New York City. Este artículo 1938 en la 
vanguardia china señaló sobre el trabajo y los esfuerzos 
contra-Japoneses de CHLA's de movilizar la ayuda para China.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087129</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104394</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/to-save-china-new-york-hand-laundry-alliance-intensifies-anti-japanese-work</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
