<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107593</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107593</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086695</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"One Third of a Nation": FDR's Second Inaugural Address</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Drittel einer Nation": FDR An zweiter 
Stelle Eröffnungsadresse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un tiers d'une nation" : Adresse En second 
lieu Inaugurale de FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um third de uma nação": Endereço Em 
segundo Inaugural Dos FDR's</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un terzo di nazione": Indirizzo In secondo 
luogo Inaugurale Di FDR's</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα τρίτο ενός έθνουσ": Δεύτερη εναρκτήρια 
διεύθυνση FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un tercio de una nación": Direccionamiento
En segundo lugar Inaugural De los FDR's</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although President Franklin Delano Roosevelt neither came from the working and lower classes nor always acted in their interests, he did, at significant moments, speak for and to the "forgotten man." One of those key moments came in January 1937 when he was inaugurated for his second term--the first time that the presidential inauguration was held on January 20 rather than March 4 (a change brought about by the twentieth amendment). Roosevelt's stirring words help explain why that one-third of the nation went to the polls in November 1936 and reelected him in one of the great landslides in American political history.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich Präsident Franklin Delano Roosevelt 
weder von der Funktion und von den untereren Kategorien kam noch immer
in ihren Interessen fungierte, sprach er, an den bedeutenden Momenten,
für und mit den "vergessenen Mann." Einer jener 
Schlüsselmomente kam im Januar 1937, als er für seine zweite 
Bezeichnung eröffnet wurde -- das erste mal, die die 
Präsidenteneinweihung an Januar 20 anstatt März 4 angehalten wurde 
(eine Änderung hervorgebracht durch die zwanzigste Änderung). 
Roosevelts rührende Wörter helfen, zu beschreiben, warum 
dieses Drittel der Nation zu den Abstimmungen im November 1936 ging 
und ihn in einem der großen Erdrutsche in der amerikanischen 
politischen Geschichte wiederwählte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que le Président Franklin Delano Roosevelt 
ni ne soit venu du fonctionnement et des classes inférieures ni ait 
toujours agi dans leurs intérêts, il, aux moments significatifs, a 
parlé pour et "à l'homme oublié." Un de ces moments 
principaux est venu en janvier 1937 où il a été inauguré pour sa 
deuxième limite -- la première fois que l'inauguration 
présidentielle a été tenue janvier 20 plutôt que mars 4 (un 
changement provoqué par le vingtième amendement). Les mots 
d'agitation de Roosevelt aident à expliquer pourquoi cet un tiers de 
la nation est allé aux balayages en novembre 1936 et l'a réélu dans
un des grands éboulements dans l'histoire politique américaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora o presidente Franklin Delano Roosevelt nem 
viesse do funcionamento e das classes mais baixas nem agisse sempre em
seus interesses, em momentos significativos, falou para e "ao homem 
esquecido." Um daqueles momentos chaves veio em janeiro 1937 em 
que inaugurated para seu segundo termo -- a primeira vez que o 
inauguration presidencial foi prendido janeiro em 20 melhor que março
em 4 (uma mudança causada pela vigésima emenda). As palavras 
agitando de Roosevelt ajudam explicar porque esse um terço da nação
foram às votações em novembro 1936 e reelected o em um dos 
landslides grandes no history político americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se il presidente Franklin Delano Roosevelt 
nè è venuto dal funzionamento e dai codici categoria più bassi nè 
sempre si è comportato nei loro interessi, ai momenti significativi, 
ha parlato per e "all'uomo dimenticato." Uno di quei momenti 
chiave è venuto nel mese di gennaio del 1937 in cui è stato 
inaugurato per il suo secondo termine -- la prima volta che 
l'inaugurazione presidenziale è stata tenuta il 20 gennaio piuttosto 
che 4 marzo (un cambiamento determinato tramite la ventesima 
correzione). Le parole di mescolatura del Roosevelt 
contribuiscono a spiegare perchè quell'un terzo della nazione è 
andato alle urne nel mese di novembre del 1936 e lo ha rieletto in uno
dei landslides grandi nella storia politica americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και ο Πρόεδρος Franklin Delano Roosevelt 
ούτε προήλθε από την εργασία και τις χαμηλότερες κλάσεις ούτε 
ενέργησε πάντα στα ενδιαφέροντά τους, στις σημαντικές στιγμές, 
μίλησε για και στο "ξεχασμένο άτομο." Μια από εκείνες τις 
βασικές στιγμές ήρθε τον Ιανουάριο του 1937 όταν 
εγκαινιάστηκε για το δεύτερο όρο του -- την πρώτη φορά ότι η 
προεδρική εγκαινίαση διοργανώθηκε στις 20 Ιανουαρίου παρά τις 4 
Μαρτίου (μια αλλαγή που επέρχεται από την εικοστή τροποποίηση). 
Οι ανακατώνοντας λέξεις του Roosevelt βοηθούν να 
εξηγήσουν γιατί εκείνο το ένα τρίτο του έθνους πήγε στις 
ψηφοφορίες τον Νοέμβριο του 1936 και τον επανεξέλεξε σε μια από
τις μεγάλες καθιζήσεις εδάφους στην αμερικανική πολιτική 
ιστορία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque presidente Franklin Delano Roosevelt ni 
vino del funcionamiento y de las clases más bajas ni actuaba siempre 
en sus intereses, él, en los momentos significativos, habló para y 
al "hombre olvidado." Uno de esos momentos dominantes vino en 
enero de 1937 en que lo inauguraron para su segundo término -- la 
primera vez que la inauguración presidencial fue sostenida de enero 
el 20 más bien que de marcha la 4 (un cambio causado por la vigésima
enmienda). Las palabras de revolvimiento de Roosevelt ayudan a 
explicar porqué ese una mitad de la nación fue a las encuestas en 
noviembre de 1936 y lo reeligió en uno de los grandes derrumbamientos
en historia política americana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086695</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107593</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/one-third-of-a-nation-fdrs-second-inaugural-address</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
