<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105710</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105710</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207040</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Harry Truman and Independence, Missouri:</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Harry Truman und Unabhängigkeit, Missouri:</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Harry Truman et indépendance, Missouri :</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Harry Truman e independência, Missouri:</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Harry Truman ed indipendenza, Missouri:</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Χαρρυ Truman και ανεξαρτησία, Μισσούρι:</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Harry Truman e independencia, Missouri:</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features the home and story of our thirty-third President. Upon returning home after World War I, Truman married his childhood sweetheart, started a clothing store that failed, and was elected to a judgeship and later the U.S. Senate. He was Vice President 82 days when President Roosevelt died. As President, he used the atomic bomb to end World War II, instituted the Marshall Plan, and sent troops to defend South Korea when the North invaded.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet das Haus und die Geschichte unseres 
thirty-third Präsidenten. Nach nach dem Ersten Weltkrieg nach 
Hause zurückgehen, heiratete Truman seinen Kindheitschatz, begonnen 
einem Bekleidungsgeschäft, das ausfiel, und wurde zu einem Richteramt
und später zum VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senat gewählt. Er war 
Vizepräsident 82 Tage, als Präsident Roosevelt starb. Als 
Präsident benutzte er die Atombombe, um den Zweiten Weltkrieg zu 
beenden, eingeleitet dem Marschall-Plan und gesendeten Truppen, um 
Südkorea zu verteidigen, als der Norden eindrang.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte la maison et l'histoire de notre 
trente-troisième président. Lors du renvoi à la maison après
la Première Guerre Mondiale, Truman a épousé son amoureux 
d'enfance, commencé une mémoire d'habillement qui a échoué, et a 
été élu à une fonction de juge et plus tard au sénat des 
ETATS-UNIS. Il était vice-président pendant 82 jours où le 
Président Roosevelt est mort. Comme président, il avait 
l'habitude la panne atomique pour terminer la deuxième guerre 
mondiale, instituée le plan de maréchal, et les troupes envoyées 
pour défendre la Corée du sud quand le nord a envahi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza a HOME e a história de nosso trigésimo 
terceiro presidente. Em cima do retorno para casa após o 
world.war.i, Truman casou seu sweetheart da infância, começado uma 
loja de roupa que falhasse, e foi elegido a um judgeship e mais tarde 
ao senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Era vice-presidente 82 dias em que 
o presidente Roosevelt morreu. Como o presidente, usou a bomba 
atômica terminar a segunda guerra mundial, instituída a planta do 
marshall, e tropas emitidas para defender Coreia sul quando o norte 
invadiu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza la sede e la storia del nostro trentatreesimo
presidente. Sul ritorno a casa dopo il world.war.i, Truman ha 
sposato il suo innamorato di infanzia, iniziato un deposito di vestiti
che è venuto a mancare ed è stato scelto ad un judgeship e più 
successivamente al senato degli STATI UNITI. Era vice presidente
82 giorni in cui il presidente Roosevelt è morto. Come 
presidente, ha usato la bomba atomica per concludere la seconda guerra
mondiale, istituita il programma del marshall e truppe trasmesse per 
difendere la Corea del sud quando il nord ha invaso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει το σπίτι και την ιστορία του 
τριάντα-τρίτου Προέδρου μας. Επάνω στο σπίτι επιστροφής 
μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, Truman παντρεμένο τον 
αγαπημένο παιδικής ηλικίας του, άρχισε ένα κατάστημα ιματισμού 
που απέτυχε, και εκλέχτηκε σε ένα judgeship και αργότερα την 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ Σύγκλητο. Ήταν αντιπρόεδρος 82 ημέρες όταν 
πέθανε ο Πρόεδρος Roosevelt. Δεδομένου ότι Πρόεδρος, 
χρησιμοποίησε την ατομική βόμβα για να τελειώσει τον παγκόσμιο 
πόλεμο ΙΙ, καθιέρωσε το Marshall σχέδιο, και έστειλε τα 
στρατεύματα για να υπερασπίσει τη Νότια Κορέα όταν ο Βορράς που 
εισβλήθηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece el hogar y la historia de nuestro trig'simo tercer 
presidente. Sobre volver a casa después de Primera Guerra 
Mundial, Truman casó a su amor de la niñez, comenzado un almacén de
ropa que falló, y fue elegido a un judgeship y más adelante al 
senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Él era vice presidente 82 días en 
que presidente Roosevelt murió. Como presidente, él utilizó 
la bomba atómica para terminar la Segunda Guerra Mundial, instituida 
el plan del ordenar, y las tropas enviadas para defender Corea del sur
cuando el norte invadió.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207040</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105710</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/harry-truman-and-independence-missouri</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
