<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103717</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103717</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087451</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Bryan's Mental Condition:" One Psychiatrist's View</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Bryans Geisteszustand:" Eine 
Psychiater-Ansicht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"L'État Mental de Bryan :" Une Vue du 
Psychiatre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">De "Condição Mental Bryan:" Uma Opinião 
Do Psychiatrist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Stato Mentale Del Bryan:" Un Punto di vista
Dello Psychiatrist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Διανοητική κατάσταση του Bryan:" Μια όψη του 
ψυχιάτρου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Condición Mental De Bryan:" Una Opinión 
Del Siquiatra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Professional psychiatry was only in its infancy at the end of the 19th century and many physicians disputed its scientific basis. In 1892, the Association of Medical Superintendents of American Institutions for the Insane was reorganzied as the American Medico-Pyschological Association. Four years later, psychiatrists--or alienists as they were then called--hurled their opinions into the political arena in a controversy over the sanity of Democratic presidential candidate William Jennings Bryan. Bryan was heartily disliked by many middle-class urban professionals, precisely the sort of people who became alienists. In this letter to the New York  Times  of September 27, 1896, a self-identified anonymous "Alienist" declared that Bryan was of a "mind not entirely sound." While it seems unlikely that this attack had much impact on the outcome of the election (the paper's readers were already unlikely to vote for Bryan), this would not be the last time that elites would seek to discredit radical opponents of the status quo by branding them "crazy."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Professionelle Psychiatrie war nur in seiner 
Kindheit am Ende des 19. Jahrhunderts und viele Ärzte diskutierten 
seine wissenschaftliche Grundlage. 1892 war die Verbindung der 
medizinischen Betriebsleiter der amerikanischen Anstalten für das 
geisteskranke reorganzied als die amerikanische 
Medico-Pyschological-Pyschologicalverbindung. Vier Jahre 
später, schleuderten Psychiater -- or alienists, während sie 
dann angerufen wurden -- ihre Meinungen in die politische Arena in 
einer Kontroverse über der validité des demokratischen 
Präsidentenanwärters William Jennings Bryan. Bryan wurde 
herzlich von vielen Mittelklassestädtischen Fachleuten, genau die 
Sortierung von den Leuten abgelehnt, die alienists wurden. In 
diesem Zeichen zu den New York Zeiten von September 27, 1896, ein 
self-identified anonymes "Alienist" erklärte, daß Bryan war von 
einem "Verstand nicht völlig stichhaltig." Während zu wählen,
daß dieser Angriff viel Auswirkung auf das Resultat der Wahl hatte 
(die Leser des Papiers war bereits unwahrscheinlich, für Bryan) 
unwahrscheinlich scheint, würde dieses nicht das letzte Mal sein, 
daß Auslesen suchen würden, radikale Konkurrenten des Status Quo zu 
diskreditieren, indem sie einbrannten sie "verrückt."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La psychiatrie professionnelle était seulement 
dans sa petite enfance à la fin du 19ème siècle et beaucoup de 
médecins ont contesté sa base scientifique. En 1892, 
l'association des surveillants médicaux des établissements 
américains pour l'aliéné avait lieu reorganzied comme association 
américaine de Medico-pyschological. Quatre ans après, les 
psychiatres -- ou les aliénistes pendant qu'ils s'appelaient alors 
-- ont lancé leurs avis dans l'arène politique dans une polémique 
au-dessus de la validité du candidat présidentiel démocratique 
William Jennings Bryan. Bryan a été chaleureusement détesté 
par beaucoup de professionnels urbains de classe moyenne, avec 
précision le tri des personnes qui sont devenues des aliénistes. 
Dans cette lettre aux temps de New York septembre de 27, 1896, 
un "Aliéniste" anonyme de art de l'auto-portrait-identified a déclaré que 
Bryan était d'un "esprit pas entièrement sain." Tandis qu'il 
semble peu probable que cette attaque a eu beaucoup d'impact sur les 
résultats de l'élection (les lecteurs du papier étaient déjà peu 
susceptible de voter pour Bryan), ce ne serait pas la dernière fois 
que les élites rechercheraient à critiquer les adversaires radicaux 
du statu quo en stigmatisant d'eux "fous."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O psychiatry profissional estava somente em seu 
infancy no fim do 1ø século e muitos médicos disputaram sua base 
científica. Em 1892, a associação de superintendentes 
médicos de instituições americanas para o insano realizava-se 
reorganzied como a associação americana do 
medico-Pyschological-Pyschological. Quatro anos mais tarde, os 
psychiatrists -- ou os alienists enquanto foram chamados então -- 
hurled suas opiniões na arena política em uma controvérsia sobre o 
sanity do candidato presidencial democrático William Jennings Bryan. 
Bryan foi não gostado heartily por muitos profissionais urbanos
do middle-class, precisamente a sorte dos povos que se transformaram 
alienists. Nesta letra aos tempos de New York setembro de 27, 
1896, um "Alienist anonymous self-identified" declarou que Bryan era 
de uma "mente não inteiramente sadia." Quando parecer 
improvável que este ataque teve muito impacto no resultado da 
eleição (os leitores do papel era já improvável votar para Bryan),
esta não seria a última vez que os elites procurariam desacreditar 
oponentes radicais do quo do status marcando os "loucos."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La psichiatria professionale era soltanto nella 
relativa infanzia alla conclusione del diciannovesimo secolo e molti 
medici hanno disputato la relativa base scientifica. In 1892, 
l'associazione dei soprintendenti medici delle istituzioni americane 
per l'insano aveva luogo reorganzied come l'associazione americana del
medico-Pyschological-Pyschological. Quattro anni più 
successivamente, gli psychiatrists -- o alienists mentre allora sono 
stati chiamati -- hanno lanciato i loro pareri nell'arena politica in 
una polemica sopra il sanity del candidato presidenziale democratico 
William Jennings Bryan. Bryan caloroso è stato avuto antipatia 
per da molti professionisti urbani della classe media, precisamente 
l'ordinamento della gente che si è transformata in in alienists. 
In questa lettera ai tempi de New York de 27 settembre 1896, "un
Alienist" anonimo self-identified ha dichiarato che Bryan era "di una 
mente non interamente sana." Mentre sembra improbabile che 
questo attacco abbia molto effetto sul risultato dell'elezione (i 
lettori della carta era già improbabile da votare per Bryan), questa 
non sarebbe l'ultima volta che le elite cercherebbero di screditare 
gli avversari radicali dello status quo marcandoli a caldo 
"pazzeschi."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η επαγγελματική ψυχιατρική ήταν μόνο στα σπάργανα στο
τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα και πολλοί παθολόγοι αμφισβήτησαν την 
επιστημονική βάση του. Το 1892, η ένωση των ιατρικών 
επιθεωρητών των αμερικανικών Οργάνων για τον παράφρονα 
ήταν ως αμερικανική ένωση ιατρο- Pyschological. Τέσσερα 
έτη αργότερα, οι ψυχίατροι -- ή ψυχίατροι όπως κλήθηκαν έπειτα
-- ηκσφενδόνισαν τις απόψεις τους στον πολιτικό χώρο σε μια 
διαμάχη πέρα από τη λογικότητα του δημοκρατικού προεδρικού 
υποψηφίου William Jennings Bryan. Ο Bryan 
αντιπαθήθηκε εγκάρδια από πολλούς αστικούς επαγγελματίες 
μεσαίων τάξεων, ακριβώς το είδος των ανθρώπων που έγιναν 
ψυχίατροι. Σε αυτήν την επιστολή στους New York 
Times της 27ης Σεπτεμβρίου ..1896, ένας 
μόνος-προσδιορισμένος ανώνυμος "ψυχίατροσ" δήλωσε ότι ο Bryan
ήταν ενός "μυαλού όχι εξ ολοκλήρου υγιής." Ενώ φαίνεται 
απίθανο ότι αυτή η επίθεση άσκησε πολλή επίδραση στην έκβαση 
της εκλογής (οι αναγνώστες του εγγράφου ήταν ήδη απίθανο να 
ψηφίσουν για το Bryan), αυτό δεν θα ήταν η τελευταία φορά που 
elites θα επιδίωκε να δυσφημήσει τους ριζικούς αντιπάλους του 
καθεστώτος με το μαρκάρισμα τους "τρελλών."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La psiquiatría profesional estaba solamente en su
infancia en el final del diecinueveavo siglo y muchos médicos 
disputaron su base científica. En 1892, la asociación de los 
superintendentes médicos de las instituciones americanas para el 
insano era reorganzied como la asociación americana del Apodo a los 
estudiantes de medicina-Pyschological. Cuatro años más 
adelante, los siquiatras -- o los alienists mientras que les entonces 
llamaron -- lanzaron sus opiniones en la arena política en una 
controversia sobre la cordura del candidato presidencial democrático 
Guillermo Jennings Bryan. Bryan caluroso fue tenido aversión 
por muchos profesionales urbanos de la clase media, exacto la clase de
la gente que hizo alienists. En esta carta a los tiempos de 
Nueva York del de septiembre 27 de 1896, un "Alienist anónimo 
autodefinido" declaró que Bryan estaba de una "mente no enteramente 
sana." Mientras que se parece inverosímil que este ataque 
tenía mucho impacto en el resultado de la elección (los programas de
lectura del papel era ya poco probable votar por Bryan), ésta no 
sería la vez última que las élites intentarían desacreditar a 
opositores radicales del status quo calificándolos "locos."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087451</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103717</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bryans-mental-condition-one-psychiatrists-view</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
