<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104310</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104310</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206696</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">James Madison Papers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">James Madison Papiere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Papiers de James Madison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Papéis De James Madison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Carte Da James Madison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">James Μάντισον έγγραφα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Papeles De James Madison</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site includes 12,000 letters, notes, legislation, and other documents from the man considered the Father of the Constitution. These documents (1723-1836), including an autobiography, help illuminate Madison's pivotal role in the Constitutional Convention as well as his nine years in the House of Representatives, his tenure as Secretary of State, and his two terms as our fourth President. Essays discuss Madison's life and his role at the Constitutional Convention.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site schließt 12.000 Zeichen, Anmerkungen, 
Gesetzgebung ein, und andere Dokumente vom Mann betrachteten den Vater
der Beschaffenheit. Diese Dokumente (1723-1836), einschließlich
eine Autobiographie, helfen, Madisons Angelrolle in der 
konstitutionellen Versammlung sowie seine neun Jahre im 
Repräsentantenhaus, seinen Besitz als Staatssekretär und seine zwei 
Bezeichnungen zu belichten als unser vierter Präsident. 
Versuche behandeln das Leben und seine Rolle Madisons an der 
konstitutionellen Versammlung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site inclut 12.000 lettres, notes, 
législation, et d'autres documents de l'homme ont considéré le 
père de la constitution. Ces documents (1723-1836), y compris 
une autobiographie, aident à illuminer le rôle pivotal de Madison 
dans la convention constitutionnelle aussi bien que ses neuf années 
dans la chambre des représentants, sa tenure comme secrétaire 
d'état, et ses deux limites en tant que notre quatrième président. 
Les essais discutent la vie et son rôle de Madison à la 
convention constitutionnelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local inclui 12.000 letras, notas, 
legislação, e outros originais do homem consideraram o pai do 
constitution. Estes originais (1723-1836), including um 
autobiography, ajudam iluminar o papel pivotal de Madison na 
convenção constitutional as.well.as seus nove anos na casa de 
representantes, o seu tenure como a secretária de estado, e os seus 
dois termos como nosso quarto presidente. Os essays discutem o 
seu papel de Madison a vida e na convenção constitutional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo include 12.000 lettere, le note, 
legislazione ed altri documenti dall'uomo hanno considerato il padre 
della costituzione. Questi documenti (1723-1836), compreso un 
autobiography, contribuiscono ad illuminare il ruolo chiave de Madison
nella convenzione costituzionale così come i suoi nove anni nella 
Camera dei rappresentanti, il suo possesso come segretaria di 
Dichiara ed i suoi due termini come nostro presidente di 
quarto. I saggi discutono la vita ed il suo ruolo de 
Madison alla convenzione costituzionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει 12.000 επιστολές, 
σημειώσεις, νομοθεσία, και άλλα έγγραφα από το άτομο εξέτασαν 
τον πατέρα του συντάγματος. Αυτά τα έγγραφα (1723-1836), 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης μιας αυτοβιογραφίας, οδηγίες φωτίζουν 
κεντρικό ρόλο του Μάντισον στη συνταγματική Συνθήκη καθώς 
επίσης και εννέα έτη του στον οίκο των αντιπροσώπων, διάρκειας 
αξιώματός του ως γραμματέα του κράτους, και δύο όρων του ως 
τέταρτο Πρόεδρό μας. Τα δοκίμια συζητούν τη ζωή του 
Μάντισον και το ρόλο του στη συνταγματική Συνθήκη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio incluye 12.000 cartas, notas, 
legislación, y otros documentos del hombre consideraban a padre de la
constitución. Estos documentos (1723-1836), incluyendo una 
autobiografía, ayudan a iluminar el papel giratorio de Madison en la 
convención constitucional así como sus nueve años en la cámara de 
representantes, su arrendamiento como secretaria del estado, y sus dos
términos como nuestro cuarto presidente. Los ensayos discuten 
la vida y su papel de Madison en la convención constitucional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206696</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104310</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/james-madison-papers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
