<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104924</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104924</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086864</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Suffrage in Print: Alice Duer Miller's Satiric Journalism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stimmrecht im Druck: Alice Duer Miller 
Satiric Journalismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Suffrage dans la copie : Journalisme 
Satirique de Alice Duer Miller</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Suffrage na cópia: Journalism Satiric De 
Alice Duer Moleiro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Suffrage in stampa: Giornalismo Satiric 
Della Alice Duer Mugnaio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψήφος στην τυπωμένη ύλη: Satiric 
δημοσιογραφία της Alice Duer Miller's</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sufragio en la impresión: Periodismo 
Satírico De Alicia Duer Molinero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1920, after more than seventy years of struggle, the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. While nineteenth-century suffrage campaigns gained partial voting rights for women in twenty states, beginning in 1910 the push for suffrage took on a new urgency under the National American Woman Suffrage Association (NAWSA) and the more radical National Woman's Party (NWP). Their campaigns reached wide audiences, in part because suffragists had learned to spread their messages through imaginative use of various media. Supporters held old-fashioned pageants and street parades as well as statewide tours, thanks to the relatively new technology of automobiles. Suffragists also reached large audiences through newspapers. In Alice Duer Miller's "Unauthorized Interviews," originally published as newspaper columns in the  New York Tribune , the pro-suffrage writer spoofed male legislators with clever reversals of gender stereotypes: the men were petulant and irrational, while the women suffragists remained cool and logical.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1920 nachdem mehr als siebzig Jahre Kampf, die 
19.änderung zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit Frauen das Recht 
bewilligte zu wählen. Während 19.-Jahrhundert Stimmrecht die 
gewonnenen teilweisen wählenden Rechte für Frauen in Zwanzig 
Zuständen wirbt, anfangend in 1910 nahm der Stoß für Stimmrecht auf
einer neuen Dringlichkeit unter der nationalen amerikanischen 
Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung (NAWSA) und der radikaleren nationalen 
Partei der Frau (NWP). Ihre Kampagnen erreichten breite 
Publikum, im Teil, weil suffragists erlernt hatten, ihre Meldungen 
durch phantasiereichen Gebrauch von verschiedenen Media zu verbreiten.
Verfechter hielten altmodische Pageants und Straße Paraden 
sowie Nationaltouren, dank die verhältnismäßig neue Technologie der
Automobile an. Suffragists erreichte auch große Publikum durch 
Zeitungen. In Alice Duer Miller "nicht autorisierten Interviews"
ursprünglich veröffentlicht als Zeitung Spalten in der New York 
Tribüne, spoofed der Pro-Stimmrecht Verfasser männliche 
Gesetzgeber mit gescheiten Umlenkungen der Geschlechtstereotypen: 
die Männer waren gereizt und vernunftwidrig, während die 
Frauen suffragists kühl und logisch blieben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1920, après que plus de soixante-dix ans de 
lutte, le dix-neuvième amendement à la constitution des ETATS-UNIS 
ait accordé à des femmes la droite de voter. Tandis que le 
suffrage de dix-neuvième-siècle fait campagne droit de vote partiel 
gagné pour des femmes dans vingt états, commençant dans 1910 la 
poussée pour le suffrage a pris une nouvelle urgence sous 
l'association américaine nationale de suffrage de femme (NAWSA) et la
partie de la femme nationale plus radicale (NWP). Leurs 
campagnes ont atteint les assistances larges, en partie parce que les 
suffragettes avaient appris à écarter leurs messages par 
l'utilisation imaginative de divers medias. Les défenseurs ont 
tenu des reconstitutions historiques et des défilés démodés de rue
aussi bien que les excursions par état, grâce à la technologie 
relativement nouvelle des automobiles. Les suffragettes ont 
également accédé de grandes assistances par des journaux. En 
entrevues non autorisées de Alice Duer Miller "," initialement 
édité comme colonnes de journal à New York Tribune, l'auteur de
pro-suffrage a charrié les législateurs mâles avec des 
inversions intelligentes des stéréotypes de genre : les hommes
étaient irritables et irrationnels, alors que les suffragettes de 
femmes restaient fraîches et logiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1920, depois que mais de setenta anos do 
esforço, a décima nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
concedeu a mulheres a direita votar. Quando um suffrage de 
décimo-século fizer campanha as direitas votando parciais ganhas 
para mulheres em vinte estados, começando em 1910 o impulso para o 
suffrage fêz exame em um urgency novo sob a associação americana 
nacional do suffrage da mulher (NAWSA) e o partido da mulher nacional 
mais radical (NWP). Suas campanhas alcançaram audiências 
largas, na parte porque os suffragists tinham aprendido espalhar suas 
mensagens com o uso imaginative de vários media. Os supporters 
prenderam pageants e paradas old-fashioned da rua as.well.as as 
excursões statewide, agradecimentos à tecnologia relativamente nova 
dos automóveis. Suffragists alcançou também audiências 
grandes através dos jornais. Em entrevistas desautorizadas de 
Alice Duer Moleiro "," publicado originalmente como colunas do jornal 
na New York Tribune, o escritor do pro-pro-suffrage spoofed os 
legislators masculinos com reversões inteligentes de stereotypes do 
gender: os homens eram petulant e irrational, quando os 
suffragists das mulheres remanesceram frescos e lógicos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1920, dopo che più di settanta anni di lotta, 
la diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI UNITI 
assegni a donne la destra votare. Mentre il suffrage di 
diciannovesimo-secolo fa una campagna diritti di voto parziali 
guadagnati per le donne in venti dichiara, cominciando in 1910
la spinta per suffrage ha intrapreso una nuova urgenza sotto 
l'associazione americana nazionale di suffrage della donna (NAWSA) ed 
il partito della donna nazionale più radicale (NWP). Le loro 
campagne hanno raggiunto i pubblici larghi, in parte perché i 
suffragists avevano imparato spargere i loro messaggi con uso 
immaginativo di vari media. I sostenitori hanno tenuto gli 
spettacoli e le parate antiquati della via così come i giri in 
tutto lo stato, grazie alla tecnologia relativamente nuova delle 
automobili. Suffragists egualmente ha raggiunto di vasto 
pubblico attraverso i giornali. Nelle interviste non autorizzate
della Alice Duer Mugnaio "," originalmente pubblicato come colonne del
giornale a New York Tribune, il produttore di pro-pro-suffrage spoofed
i legislatori maschii con le inversioni intelligenti degli stereotipi 
di genere: gli uomini erano petulant ed irrazionali, mentre i 
suffragists delle donne sono rimasto freddi e logici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1920, μετά από περισσότερο από εβδομήντα έτη 
προσπάθειας, τη δέκατη έννατη τροποποίηση στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
σύνταγμα που χορηγείται τις γυναίκες το δικαίωμα να ψηφίσει. 
Ενώ οι εκστρατείες ψήφου δέκατος-αιώνα κέρδισαν τα μερικά
δικαιώματα ψήφου για τις γυναίκες σε είκοσι κράτη, αρχίζοντας το
1910 η ώθηση για την ψήφο πήρε μια νέα επείγουσα ανάγκη κάτω
από την εθνική αμερικανική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών (NAWSA) και 
το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος περισσότερης ριζικής εθνικής γυναίκας 
(NWP). Οι εκστρατείες τους έφθασαν στα ευρέα ακροατήρια, 
εν μέρει επειδή suffragists είχαν μάθει να διαδίδουν τα 
μηνύματά τους μέσω της επινοητικής χρήσης των διάφορων μέσων. 
Οι υποστηρικτές κράτησαν τις ντεμοντέ παρελάσεις θεαμάτων 
και οδών καθώς επίσης και τους εθνικούς γύρους, χάρι στη 
σχετικά νέα τεχνολογία των αυτοκινήτων. Suffragists 
έφθασαν επίσης στα μεγάλα ακροατήρια μέσω των εφημερίδων. 
Στην Alice Duer Miller's "αναρμόδιες συνεντεύξεις," 
αρχικά δημοσιευμένος ως στήλες εφημερίδων στο βήμα της Νέας 
Υόρκης, ο συγγραφέας υπέρ-ψήφου οι αρσενικοί νομοθέτες με τις 
έξυπνες αντιστροφές των στερεοτύπων γένους: οι άνδρες ήταν
νευρικοί και παράλογοι, ενώ suffragists γυναικών παρέμειναν 
δροσεροί και λογικοί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1920, después de que más de setenta años de 
lucha, la diecinueveavo enmienda a la constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
concediera a mujeres la derecha de votar. Mientras que el 
sufragio del diecinueveavo-siglo hace campaña los derechos al voto 
parciales ganados para las mujeres en veinte estados, comenzando en 
1910 el empuje para el sufragio adquirió una nueva urgencia bajo la 
asociación americana nacional del sufragio de la mujer (NAWSA) y 
partido de la mujer nacional más radical (NWP). Sus campañas 
alcanzaron a audiencias anchas, en parte porque los suffragists 
habían aprendido separar sus mensajes con el uso imaginativo de 
varios media. Los partidarios llevaron a cabo desfiles y 
desfiles pasados de moda de la calle así como los viajes estatales, 
gracias relativamente a la nueva tecnología de automóviles. 
Suffragists también alcanzó a mucho público a través de los 
periódicos. En las entrevistas desautorizadas de Alicia Duer 
Molinero "," publicado originalmente como columnas del periódico en 
la Nueva York Tribune, el programa de escritura del favorable-sufragio
spoofed a legisladores masculinos con revocaciones listas de los 
estereotipos del género: los hombres eran petulant e 
irracionales, mientras que los suffragists de las mujeres seguían 
siendo frescos y lógicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086864</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104924</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/suffrage-in-print-alice-duer-millers-satiric-journalism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
