<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104124</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104124</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770210037</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Force, Momentum and Impulse - Grade 11</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kraft, Momentum und Antrieb - Grad 11</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Force, élan et impulsion - catégorie 11</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Força, momentum e impulso - classe 11</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Forza, quantità di moto ed impulso - grado 11</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δύναμη, ορμή και ώθηση - βαθμός 11</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fuerza, ímpetu e impulso - grado 11</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Grade 11: Force, Momentum and Impulse. In Grade 10, we studied motion, but not what caused the motion. In this chapter we will learn that a net force is needed to cause motion. We recall what a force is and learn about how force and motion are related. We are introduced to two new concepts (momentum and impulse) and we learn more about the force of gravity.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">Africa</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grad 11: Kraft, Momentum und Antrieb. 
In Grad 10, studierten wir Bewegung, aber nicht, was die 
Bewegung verursachte. In diesem Kapitel erfahren wir, daß eine 
Nettokraft erforderlich ist, Bewegung zu verursachen. Wir rufen 
wieder auf, was eine Kraft ist und erlernen über, wie Kraft und 
Bewegung in Verbindung stehend sind. Wir werden zu zwei neuen 
Konzepten (Momentum und Antrieb) eingeführt und wir erlernen mehr 
über die Kraft von Schwerkraft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Catégorie 11 : Force, élan et impulsion. 
Dans la catégorie 10, nous avons étudié le mouvement, mais 
pas ce qui a causé le mouvement. En ce chapitre nous 
apprendrons qu'une force nette est nécessaire pour causer le 
mouvement. Nous nous rappelons ce qu'est une force et nous 
renseignons sur la façon dont la force et le mouvement sont connexes.
Nous sommes présentés à deux nouveaux concepts (élan et 
impulsion) et nous apprenons plus au sujet de la force de la 
pesanteur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Classe 11: Força, momentum e impulso. 
Na classe 10, nós estudamos o movimento, mas não o que causou 
o movimento. Neste capítulo nós aprenderemos que uma força 
líquida é needed causar o movimento. Nós recordamos o que uma
força é e aprendemo-los sobre como a força e o movimento são 
relacionados. Nós somos introduzidos a dois conceitos novos 
(momentum e impulso) e nós aprendemos mais sobre a força da 
gravidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Grado 11: Forza, quantità di moto ed 
impulso. Nel grado 10, abbiamo studiato il movimento, ma non che
cosa ha causato il movimento. In questo capitolo impareremo che 
una forza netta è necessaria causare il movimento. Ricordiamo 
che cosa una forza è ed impariamo circa come la forza ed il movimento
sono relativi. Siamo introdotti a due nuovi concetti (quantità 
di moto ed impulso) ed impariamo più circa la forza di gravità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βαθμός 11: Δύναμη, ορμή και ώθηση. Στο 
βαθμό 10, μελετήσαμε την κίνηση, αλλά όχι τι προκάλεσε την 
κίνηση. Σε αυτό το κεφάλαιο θα μάθουμε ότι μια καθαρή 
δύναμη απαιτείται για να προκαλέσει την κίνηση. 
Υπενθυμίζουμε τι μια δύναμη είναι και μαθαίνει για το πώς η
δύναμη και η κίνηση συσχετίζονται. Εισαγόμαστε σε δύο νέες
έννοιες (ορμή και ώθηση) και μαθαίνουμε περισσότερων για τη 
δύναμη της βαρύτητας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Grado 11: Fuerza, ímpetu e impulso. 
En el grado 10, estudiamos el movimiento, pero no qué causó el
movimiento. En este capítulo aprenderemos que una fuerza neta 
es necesaria causar el movimiento. Recordamos cuáles es una 
fuerza y aprendemos sobre cómo la fuerza y el movimiento son 
relacionados. Nos introducen a dos nuevos conceptos (ímpetu e 
impulso) y aprendemos más sobre la fuerza de la gravedad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770210037</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104124</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/force-momentum-and-impulse</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
