<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108137</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108137</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Building of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Gebäude des Chesapeakes und des Ohio Kanals</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le bâtiment du chesapeake et du canal de l'Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O edifício do chesapeake e do canal de Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La costruzione del chesapeake e del canale 
dell'Ohio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η οικοδόμηση chesapeake και του καναλιού του Οχάιου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El edificio del chesapeake y del canal de Ohio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students realize the role canals played in western expansion and in the evolution of transportation by focusing on the construction of the Chesapeake and Ohio Canal. Students can read about George Washington's influence on the C &amp; O Canal and the men and women who worked on or lived near canal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer verwirklichen die Rolle 
Kanäle, die in der westlichen Expansion und in der Geschichte des 
Transportes gespielt werden, indem sie auf den Aufbau des Chesapeakes 
und des Ohio Kanals konzentrieren. Kursteilnehmer können über 
George Washingtons Einfluß auf den C u. O Kanal und die Männer und 
die Frauen lesen, die an oder gelebt nahe Kanal arbeiteten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les étudiants d'aides réalisent les canaux de 
rôle joués dans l'expansion occidentale et dans l'évolution du 
transport en se concentrant sur la construction du chesapeake et du 
canal de l'Ohio. Les étudiants peuvent avoir connaissance de 
l'influence de George Washington sur le canal de C et de O et les 
hommes et les femmes qui ont fonctionné en fonction ou vécu près du
canal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os estudantes das ajudas realizam os canais do 
papel jogados na expansão ocidental e na evolução do transporte 
focalizando na construção do chesapeake e do canal de Ohio. Os
estudantes podem ler sobre a influência de George Washington no canal
de C &amp; de O e nos homens e nas mulheres que trabalharam sobre ou 
vivido perto do canal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli allievi di aiuti realizzano i canali di ruolo 
giocati nell'espansione occidentale e nello sviluppo di trasporto 
mettendo a fuoco sulla costruzione del chesapeake e del canale 
dell'Ohio. Gli allievi possono leggere su influenza di George 
Washington sul canale della O &amp; di C e sugli uomini e sulle donne che 
hanno lavorato sopra o vivo vicino al canale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να πραγματοποιήσουν τα κανάλια 
ρόλου που παίζονται στη δυτική επέκταση και στην εξέλιξη της 
μεταφοράς με την εστίαση στην κατασκευή chesapeake και του 
καναλιού του Οχάιου. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να διαβάσουν για
την επιρροή George Ουάσιγκτον στο κανάλι γ &amp; ο και τους άνδρες 
και τις γυναίκες που ελειτούργησαν ή έζησαν κοντά στο κανάλι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los estudiantes de las ayudas realizan los canales
del papel jugados en la extensión occidental y en la evolución del 
transporte centrándose en la construcción del chesapeake y del canal
de Ohio. Los estudiantes pueden leer sobre la influencia de 
George Washington en el canal de C y de O y los hombres y las mujeres 
que funcionaron encendido o vivido cerca del canal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207048</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108137</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-building-of-the-chesapeake-and-ohio-canal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
