<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104600</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104600</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205608</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Comprehensive Study of North Carolina Indian Tribes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine komplette Studie der Nord-Carolina 
Inder-Stämme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une étude complète des tribus du nord 
d'Indien de la Caroline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um estudo detalhado de tribes do indian de 
North.carolina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Uno studio completo delle tribù dell'indiano del 
North.carolina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια περιεκτική μελέτη των ινδικών φυλών της βόρειας 
Καρολίνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un estudio comprensivo de las tribus del indio de 
Carolina del Norte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students will apply their research skills of gathering and validating information to study the eight state recognized American Indian tribes of North Carolina in order to create an Honors U.S. History Project. Students then will create a comprehensive study of those tribes to be compiled into a notebook to be copied and shared with the eighth grade teachers of North Carolina History in our county.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer wenden ihre Forschung Fähigkeiten 
der Erfassung an und die validiereninformationen, zum des Zustandes 
acht zu studieren erkannten indianische Stämme von Nord-Carolina, um 
ein Ehre-VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte Projekt zu erstellen. 
Kursteilnehmer dann erstellen eine komplette Studie jener in ein
mit den achten Gradlehrern der Nord-Carolina Geschichte in unserer 
Grafschaft kopiert zu werden und geteilt worden Notizbuch kompiliert 
zu werden Stämme,.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants appliqueront leurs qualifications 
de recherches de la collecte et l'information validante pour étudier 
l'état huit a identifié les tribus indiennes de la Caroline 
du nord afin de créer un projet d'histoire des ETATS-UNIS 
d'honneurs. Les étudiants alors créeront une étude complète 
de ces tribus à compiler dans un cahier à copier et être partagé 
avec les huitième professeurs de catégorie de l'histoire du nord
de la Caroline dans notre comté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes aplicarão suas habilidades da 
pesquisa do recolhimento e a informação de validação para estudar 
o estado oito reconheceu tribes indian americanos de North.carolina a 
fim criar um projeto do history de ESTADOS UNIDOS das honras. Os
estudantes então criarão um estudo detalhado daqueles tribes a ser 
compilados em um caderno a ser copí e compartilhado com os oitavos 
professores da classe do history de North.carolina em nosso condado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi applicheranno le loro abilità di 
ricerca di riunire e le informazioni di convalidazione per 
studiare gli otto dichiarano hanno riconosciuto le tribù indiane
americane di North.carolina per creare un progetto di storia degli 
STATI UNITI di honors. Gli allievi allora creeranno uno studio 
completo di quelle tribù da compilare in un taccuino da copiare e 
ripartire con gli ottavi insegnanti del grado di storia del 
North.carolina nella nostra contea.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα εφαρμόσουν τις ερευνητικές 
δεξιότητές τους συγκέντρωσης και επικύρωσης των πληροφοριών για 
να μελετήσουν τις οκτώ αναγνωρισμένες κράτος αμερικανικές 
ινδικές φυλές της βόρειας Καρολίνας προκειμένου να δημιουργηθεί 
ένα πρόγραμμα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ ιστορίας τιμών. Οι σπουδαστές 
έπειτα θα δημιουργήσουν μια περιεκτική μελέτη εκείνων των φυλών 
που μεταγλωττίζονται σε ένα σημειωματάριο που αντιγράφεται και που
μοιράζεται με τους όγδοους δασκάλους βαθμού της ιστορίας της 
βόρειας Καρολίνας στο νομό μας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes aplicarán sus habilidades de la 
investigación de la acopio y la información que validaba para 
estudiar el estado ocho reconoció las tribus indias americanas de 
Carolina del Norte para crear un proyecto de la historia de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS de los honores. Los estudiantes entonces crearán un 
estudio comprensivo de esas tribus que se compilarán en un cuaderno 
que se copiará y compartido con los octavos profesores del grado de 
la historia de Carolina del Norte en nuestro condado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WANDA TAYLOR
FN:WANDA TAYLOR
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205608</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104600</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-comprehensive-study-of-north-carolina-indian-tribes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
