<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104648</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104648</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202667</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Survival! A Lesson for Language Arts and Novice ESL Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überleben! Eine Lektion für 
Sprachenkünste und Kursteilnehmer des Anfänger-ESL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Survie ! Une leçon pour des arts de langage
et des étudiants du débutant ESL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sobrevivência! Uma lição para artes da 
língua e estudantes do novice ESL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sopravvivenza! Una lezione per le arti di 
linguaggio e gli allievi del debuttante ESL</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιβίωση! Ένα μάθημα για τις γλωσσικές τέχνες 
και τους σπουδαστές του ESL αρχαρίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Supervivencia! Una lección para los artes 
del lenguaje y los estudiantes del principiante ESL</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students brainstorm to orally identify and agree upon ten elements necessary for survival. Students will create a categorized chart of the items necessary for survival. Using the chart and working within groups, students will use the chart to create a Survival board game. This lesson serves well as an introductory activity for students who will read a novel with a setting in another country or culture, or as the basis of comparing two different time periods or cultures. It is modified for the Novice High English Language Learner.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer lösen gedanklich, um 10 Elemente 
mündlich zu kennzeichnen und zu vereinbaren, die für Überleben 
notwendig sind. Kursteilnehmer erstellen ein kategorisiertes 
Diagramm der Einzelteile, die für Überleben notwendig sind. 
Mit dem Diagramm und innerhalb der Gruppen arbeitend, benutzen 
Kursteilnehmer das Diagramm, um ein Überleben Brettspiel zu 
erstellen. Diese Lektion dient gut als einleitende Aktivität 
für Kursteilnehmer, die einen Roman mit einer Einstellung in einem 
anderen Land oder in Kultur lesen, oder als die Grundlage des 
Vergleichens von von von von zwei unterschiedlichen Zeitabschnitten 
oder Kulturen. Sie wird für den Anfänger-hohen englische 
Sprachenanfänger geändert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants font un brainstorm oralement pour 
identifier et convenir de dix éléments nécessaires pour la survie. 
Les étudiants créeront un diagramme classé par catégorie des
éléments nécessaires pour la survie. En utilisant le 
diagramme et travaillant chez des groupes, les étudiants emploieront 
le diagramme pour créer un jeu de panneau de survie. Cette 
leçon sert bien comme activité préliminaire pour les étudiants qui
liront un roman avec une configuration dans un pays ou une culture 
différent, ou de base de comparer deux périodes ou cultures de temps
différentes. Elle est modifiée pour le haut étudiant 
d'anglais de débutant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes brainstorm para identificar e 
concordar oral em dez elementos necessários para a sobrevivência. 
Os estudantes criarão uma carta categorizada dos artigos 
necessários para a sobrevivência. Usando a carta e trabalhando
dentro dos grupos, os estudantes usarão a carta criar um jogo de 
placa da sobrevivência. Esta lição serve bem como uma 
atividade introdutória para os estudantes que lerão uma novela com 
um ajuste em um outro país ou cultura, ou como a base de comparar 
duas períodos ou culturas diferentes de tempo. É modificada 
para o learner de língua inglesa elevado do novice.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi brainstorm per identificare e 
accosentire oralmente su dieci elementi necessari per la 
sopravvivenza. Gli allievi creeranno una tabella categorizzata 
degli articoli necessari per la sopravvivenza. Usando la tabella
e funzionando presso i gruppi, gli allievi useranno la tabella per 
creare un gioco del bordo di sopravvivenza. Questa lezione
serve bene come attività introduttiva per gli allievi che leggeranno 
un romanzo con una regolazione in un altro paese o coltura, o da base 
di confrontare due periodi o colture di tempo differenti. È 
modificata per l'alto studente di lingue inglese del debuttante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καταιγισμός ιδεών σπουδαστών για να προσδιορίσει 
προφορικά και να συμφωνήσει σχετικά με δέκα στοιχεία απαραίτητα 
για την επιβίωση. Οι σπουδαστές θα δημιουργήσουν ένα 
ταξινομημένο διάγραμμα των αντικειμένων απαραίτητων για την 
επιβίωση. Χρησιμοποιώντας το διάγραμμα και εργαζόμενος μέσα
στις ομάδες, οι σπουδαστές θα χρησιμοποιήσουν το διάγραμμα για να 
δημιουργήσουν ένα παιχνίδι πινάκων επιβίωσης. Αυτό το 
μάθημα χρησιμεύει καλά ως μια εισαγωγική δραστηριότητα για τους 
σπουδαστές που θα διαβάσουν ένα μυθιστόρημα με μια τιμή τών 
παραμέτρων σε μια άλλη χώρα ή τον πολιτισμό, ή ως βάση δύο 
διαφορετικούς χρονικά διαστήματα ή πολιτισμούς. 
Τροποποιείται για τον υψηλό αρχάριο αγγλικής γλώσσας 
αρχαρίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes se inspiran para identificar y 
para convenir en oral diez elementos necesarios para la supervivencia.
Los estudiantes crearán una carta categorizada de los items 
necesarios para la supervivencia. Usando la carta y trabajando 
dentro de grupos, los estudiantes utilizarán la carta para crear un 
juego de tarjeta de la supervivencia. Esta lección sirve bien 
como actividad introductoria para los estudiantes que leerán una 
novela con una configuración en otro país o cultura, o como la base 
de comparar dos diversos períodos o culturas. Se modifica para 
el principiante de lenguaje inglés alto del principiante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CYNTHIA MORETZ
FN:CYNTHIA MORETZ
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202667</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104648</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/survival-a-lesson-for-language-arts-and-novice-esl-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
