<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107831</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107831</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086119</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Embryo Courtezans and Felons": New York Police Chief George W. Matsell Describes the City's Vagrant and Delinquent Children, 1849</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Embryo Courtezans und Täter": New York 
Polizei hauptsächlich George W. Matsell Describes die Vagabund-und 
Delinquent-Kinder der Stadt, 1849</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"embryon Courtezans et criminels" : Police de
New York en chef George W. Matsell Describes les enfants errants 
et contrevenants de la ville, 1849</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"embrião Courtezans e criminosos": Polícias
de New York principais George W. Matsell Descrição crianças vagrant
e delinquent da cidade, 1849</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"embrione Courtezans e felons": Polizia de 
New York principale George W. Matsell Describes bambini vagrant e 
delinquenziali della città, 1849</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έμβρυο Courtezans και εγκληματίεσ": Αστυνομία
Προϊστάμενος George W. Matsell Describes της Νέας Υόρκης 
το vagrant της πόλης και τα εγκληματικά παιδιά, 1849</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"embrión Courtezans y criminales": Policía 
de Nueva York principal George W. Matsell Describes niños vagabundos 
y delincuentes de la ciudad, 1849</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1849, New York's chief of police, George W. Matsell, chose to devote most of his semi-annual report to the problem of vagrant and delinquent children. By mid-century New York was crowded with immigrants from Ireland and Germany. Adult immigrants took jobs once occupied by child apprentices and, despite Matsell's reference to the city's public schools, schooling was not compulsory in New York State until 1874. The result was an excess of poor children on the streets earning money however they could, sometimes, Matsell suggests, in unsavory occupations. Matsell's anxiety about the city's street children cut two ways: he was concerned about the harm these children were doing to themselves, but he also worried that they would grow up to join a "dangerous class" of criminals that would terrorize the city. In these sentiments he was joined by Charles Loring Brace. In 1853 Brace formed the Children's Aid Society that initiated the "orphan trains." These trains transported poor children out of the city to farms in the west.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1849 beschloß Leiter New York der Polizei, George 
W. Matsell, sich die meisten seines halbjährlichen Reports dem 
Problem Vagabund- und Delinquentkindern zu widmen. Bis zum 
Mid-century wurde New York mit Immigranten aus Irland und Deutschland 
gedrängt. Erwachsenimmigranten nahmen die Jobs, die einmal von 
den Kindlehrlingen besetzt wurden und, trotz der Referenz Matsells auf
den allgemeinen Schulen der Stadt, war das Schulen nicht im Staat 
New-York bis 1874 obligatorisch. Das Resultat war ein Überfluß
der armen Kinder auf den Straßen Geld erwerbend jedoch, das sie 
konnten manchmal Matsell vorschlägt, in den unsavory Besetzungen. 
Angst Matsells um die Kinder Straße der Stadt schnitt zwei 
Möglichkeiten: er wurde über den Schaden betroffen, den diese 
Kinder zu selbst taten, aber er sorgte auch, sich daß sie bis 
verbinden eine "gefährliche Kategorie" Verbrecher wachsen würden, 
die terrorize die Stadt wurden. In diesen Gefühlen wurde er 
durch Charles Loring Klammer verbunden. In der Klammer 1853 
gebildet der Hilfsmittel-Gesellschaft der Kinder, das initialisiert 
die "orphan Serien." Diese Serien transportierten arme Kinder 
aus der Stadt heraus zu den Bauernhöfen im Westen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1849, le chef de New York de la police, 
George W. Matsell, a choisi de consacrer la majeure partie de son 
état de semi-finale-annual au problème des enfants errants et 
contrevenants. Par la moitié du siècle New York a été serré
des immigrés d'Irlande et d'Allemagne. Les immigrés d'adulte 
ont pris les travaux une fois occupés par des apprentis d'enfant et, 
en dépit de la référence de Matsell aux écoles de l'Etat de la 
ville, instruire n'était pas forcé dans l'état de New-York jusqu'en
1874. Le résultat était un excès de pauvres enfants sur les 
rues gagnant l'argent cependant qu'elles pourraient, parfois, Matsell 
suggère, dans des métiers désagréables. L'inquiétude de 
Matsell au sujet des enfants de la rue de la ville a coupé deux voies
: il a été préoccupé par le mal que ces enfants faisaient à
eux-mêmes, mais il s'est également inquiété qu'ils se développent
jusqu'à joignent "une classe dangereuse" de criminels qui 
terroriseraient la ville. Dans ces sentiments il a été joint 
par le croisillon de Charles Loring. Dans le croisillon 1853 
formé la société de l'aide des enfants qui lance "les trains 
orphelins." Ces trains ont transporté de pauvres enfants hors 
de la ville aux fermes dans l'ouest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1849, o chefe das polícias, George W. Matsell 
de New York, escolheu devotar a maioria de seu relatório semi-annual 
ao problema de crianças vagrant e delinquent. Pelo mid-century 
New York foi aglomerada com os immigrants de Ireland e de Germany. 
Os immigrants do adulto fizeram exame dos trabalhos ocupados uma
vez por aprendizes da criança e, apesar da referência de Matsell às
escolas públicas da cidade, educar não era compulsório no estado de
New York até 1874. O resultado era um excesso das crianças 
deficientes nas ruas que ganham o dinheiro entretanto que poderiam, 
às vezes, Matsell sugere, em ocupações unsavory. A ansiedade 
de Matsell sobre as crianças da rua da cidade cortou duas maneiras: 
foi concernido sobre o dano que estas crianças se faziam, mas 
preocupou-se também que cresceriam até juntam "uma classe perigosa" 
dos criminosos que  terrorize a cidade. Nestes sentiments foi 
juntado pela cinta de Charles Loring. Na cinta 1853 dada forma a
sociedade do dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) das crianças 
que inicía "os trens orphan." Estes trens transportaram 
crianças deficientes fora da cidade às fazendas no oeste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1849, il capo della polizia, George W. Matsell 
de New York, ha scelto dedicare la maggior parte del suo rapporto 
semi-annual al problema dei bambini vagrant e delinquenziali. 
Entro la metà del secolo New York si è ammucchiata con gli 
immigranti dall'Irlanda e dalla Germania. Gli immigranti 
dell'adulto hanno preso i lavori occupati una volta dagli apprendisti 
del bambino e, malgrado riferimento del Matsell alle "public school" 
della città, istruire non era obbligatoria a New York Dichiara
fino al 1874. Il risultato era un eccesso di poveri bambini 
sulle vie che guadagnano i soldi tuttavia che potrebbero, a volte, 
Matsell suggerisce, nelle occupazioni unsavory. L'ansia del 
Matsell circa i bambini della via della città ha tagliato due modi: 
è stato interessato circa il danno che questi bambini stavano 
facendo a se stesso, ma egualmente si è preoccupato che si 
svilupperebbero fino a uniscono "un codice categoria pericoloso" dei 
criminali che terrorize la città. In questi sentimenti si è 
unito dal sostegno del Charles Loring. In sostegno 1853 formato 
la società del sussidio dei bambini che inizia "i treni orphan." 
Questi treni hanno trasportato i poveri bambini dalla città
ai poderi nell'ovest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1849, η Νέα Υόρκη προϊστάμενος της αστυνομίας, 
George W. Matsell, επέλεξε να αφιερώσει την μεγαλύτερη 
μέρος της ημιετήσιας έκθεσής του στο πρόβλημα του vagrant και 
των εγκληματικών παιδιών. Μέχρι mid-century η Νέα Υόρκη 
συσσωρεύθηκε με τους μετανάστες από την Ιρλανδία και τη Γερμανία.
Οι ενήλικοι μετανάστες ανάλαβαν δουλειές μόλις καταληφθούν
από τους μαθητευόμενους παιδιών και, παρά την αναφορά Matsell 
στα δημόσια σχολεία της πόλης, η εκπαίδευση δεν ήταν υποχρεωτική
στο κράτος της Νέας Υόρκης μέχρι 1874. Το αποτέλεσμα 
ήταν μια υπερβολή των φτωχών παιδιών στις οδούς που κερδίζουν τα
χρήματα εντούτοις θα μπορούσαν, μερικές φορές, Matsell 
προτείνουν, στα άνοστα επαγγέλματα. Η ανησυχία του 
Matsell για τα παιδιά που ζουν στους δρόμους της πόλης έκοψε 
δύο τρόπους: ανησύχησε για τη ζημιά που αυτά τα παιδιά 
έκαναν σε τους, αλλά επίσης ανησύχησε ότι θα μεγάλωναν για να 
ενώσουν μια "επικίνδυνη κλάση" των εγκληματιών που θα 
τρομοκρατούσαν την πόλη. Σε αυτά τα συναισθήματα ενώθηκε 
από Charles Loring Brace. Το 1853 το στήριγμα 
διαμόρφωσε την κοινωνία ενίσχυσης των παιδιών που άρχισε τα 
"ορφανά τραίνα." Αυτά τα τραίνα μετέφεραν τα φτωχά παιδιά
από την πόλη στα αγροκτήματα στη δύση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1849, el jefe del policía, George W. Matsell de
Nueva York, eligió dedicar la mayoría de su informe semestral al 
problema de niños vagabundos y delincuentes. Por mediados de 
siglo Nueva York fue apretada con los inmigrantes de Irlanda y de 
Alemania. Los inmigrantes del adulto tomaron los trabajos 
ocupados una vez por los aprendices del niño y, a pesar de la 
referencia de Matsell a las escuelas públicas de la ciudad, el 
enseñar no era obligatorio en el estado de Nueva York hasta 1874. 
El resultado era un exceso de los niños pobres en las calles 
que ganaban el dinero sin embargo que podrían, a veces, Matsell 
sugiere, en ocupaciones unsavory. La ansiedad de Matsell sobre 
los niños de la calle de la ciudad cortó dos maneras: él fue 
referido sobre el daño que estos niños hacían a sí mismos, pero 
él también se preocupó que crecerían hasta ensamblan una "clase 
peligrosa" de los criminales que terrorize la ciudad. En estos 
sentimientos la paréntesis de Charles Loring lo ensambló. En 
la paréntesis 1853 formada la sociedad de la ayuda de los niños que 
inició los "trenes huérfanos." Estos trenes transportaron a 
niños pobres de la ciudad a las granjas en el oeste.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086119</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107831</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/embryo-courtezans-and-felons-new-york-police-chief-george-w-matsell-describes-the-citys-vagrant-and-delinquent-children-1849</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
