<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106885</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106885</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206585</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Alexander Graham Bell's Patent for the Telephone and Thomas Edison's Patent for the Electric Lamp</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alexander Graham Bell Patent für das Telefon und 
Thomas Edisons Patent für die elektrische Lampe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Brevet d'Alexandre Graham Bell pour le téléphone
et brevet de Thomas Edison pour la lampe électrique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Patente de Alexander Graham Bell para o telefone e
patente de Thomas Edison para a lâmpada elétrica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Brevetto del Alexander Graham Bell per il telefono
e brevetto del Thomas Edison per la lampada elettrica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δίπλωμα ευρεσιτεχνίας του Αλεξάνδρου Graham 
Bell's για το τηλέφωνο και δίπλωμα ευρεσιτεχνίας του Thomas 
Edison's για τον ηλεκτρικό λαμπτήρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Patente de Alexander Graham Bell para el teléfono
y patente de Thomas Edison para la lámpara eléctrica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">introduces students to significant inventions of the late 19th century and examines the power of Congress to pass laws related to the granting of patents. It correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences. It also has cross-curricular connections with history, government, language arts, and science.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Kursteilnehmer zu den bedeutenden 
Erfindungen des des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhunderts vor und 
überprüft die Energie des Kongresses, die Gesetze zu verabschieden, 
die auf dem Bewilligen von Patenten in Verbindung gestanden werden. 
Sie bezieht mit den nationalen Geschichte Standards und den 
nationalen Standards für Gemeinschaftskunde und Sozialwissenschaften 
aufeinander. Sie hat auch Kreuzlehrplananschlüsse mit 
Geschichte, Regierung, Sprachenkünsten und Wissenschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente des étudiants aux inventions 
significatives de la fin du 19me siècle et examine la puissance du 
congrès de passer des lois liées à l'octroi des brevets. Elle
se corrèle avec les normes nationales d'histoire et les normes 
nationales pour l'éducation civique et les sciences sociales. 
Elle a également les connexions croix-curriculaires avec 
l'histoire, le gouvernement, les arts de langage, et la science.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">introduz estudantes às invenções significativas
do 1ø século atrasado e examina a potência do congress passar as 
leis relacionadas a conceder das patentes. Correlaciona aos 
padrões nacionais do history e aos padrões nacionais para o civics e
ciências sociais. Tem também conexões cruz-cross-curricular 
com o history, o governo, as artes da língua, e a ciência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">introduce gli allievi alle invenzioni 
significative di fine del 19esimo secolo ed esamina l'potenza del 
congresso approvare le leggi relative all'assegnazione dei brevetti. 
Correla agli standard nazionali di storia ed agli standard 
nazionali per civics e le scienze sociali. Egualmente ha 
collegamenti traversa-d'insegnamento con storia, il governo, le arti 
di linguaggio e la scienza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εισάγει τους σπουδαστές στις σημαντικές εφευρέσεις του
πρόσφατου 19$ου αιώνα και εξετάζει τη δύναμη του συνεδρίου να 
περαστούν οι νόμοι σχετικοί με τη χορήγηση των διπλωμάτων 
ευρεσιτεχνίας. Συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας και 
τα εθνικά πρότυπα για Civics και τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες. 
Έχει επίσης τις διαγώνιος-διδακτικές συνδέσεις με την 
ιστορία, την κυβέρνηση, τις γλωσσικές τέχνες, και την επιστήμη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">introduce a estudiantes a las invenciones 
significativas de la a fines del siglo XIX y examina la potencia del 
congreso de aprobar los leyes relacionados con conceder de patentes. 
Correlaciona a los estándares nacionales de la historia y a los
estándares nacionales para el civics y las ciencias sociales. 
También tiene conexiones cruz-del plan de estudios con 
historia, el gobierno, artes del lenguaje, y ciencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206585</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106885</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/alexander-graham-bells-patent-for-the-telephone-and-thomas-edisons-patent-for-the-electric-lamp</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
