<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105120</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105120</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086478</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Mob Rule Cannot Be Allowed to Override the Decisions of Our Courts": President Dwight D. Eisenhower"s 1957 Address on Little Rock, Arkansas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Pöbel-Richtlinie kann nicht über die 
Entscheidungen unserer Gerichte ausser Kraft setzen gelassen werden": 
Präsident Dwight D. Eisenhower"s 1957 Adresse auf Little Rock, 
Arkansas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">à la "on ne peut pas permettre règle de foule 
d'ignorer les décisions de nos cours" : Adresse du Président 
Dwight D. Eisenhower"s 1957 sur peu de roche, Arkansas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">do "a régua mob não pode ser permitida cancelar 
as decisões de nossas cortes": Endereço em pouca rocha, 
Arkansas do presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower"s 1957</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la regola del mob non può essere permessa 
escludere le decisioni delle nostre corti": Indirizzo su poca 
roccia, Arkansas del presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower"s 1957</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο "κανόνας όχλου δεν μπορεί να επιτραπεί για να 
υπερισχύσει τις αποφάσεις των δικαστηρίων μασ": Πρόεδρος 
Dwight D. Eisenhower"s 1957 διεύθυνση σε λίγο βράχο, 
Αρκάνσας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "regla de la multitud no se puede permitir 
reemplazar las decisiones de nuestras cortes": Direccionamiento 
en poca roca, Arkansas de presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower"s 1957</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1954, the Supreme Court unanimously decided in  Brown  v.  Board of Education  that public schools segregated according to race were "inherently unequal." State laws requiring school segregation therefore conflicted with the equal protection clause of the Fourteenth Amendment. The ruling challenged traditional attitudes and threatened a segregated way of life in the South validated in 1896 by the Court's ruling in  Plessy  v.  Ferguson.  The 1896 ruling permitted "separate but equal" public accommodations. In 1955, the Court ordained that desegregation of public schools should proceed "with all deliberate speed;" yet in many parts of the South, reactionary forces resisted. In Little Rock, Arkansas, Governor Orval Faubus challenged efforts by the school board to institute a gradual school desegregation process and ordered state National Guard troops to defy Federal law and stop nine African-American students from attending an all-white high school. As television spread images of the subsequent mob violence around the world, President Dwight D. Eisenhower, in the following radio and television address on September 24, 1957, announced his reluctant response. Despite his disapproval of the  Brown  decision, Eisenhower, couching his address in the language of law and order, Cold War propaganda, and national pride, became the first president since Reconstruction to send Federal troops to protect the rights of African Americans. Although the nine students enrolled, resistance to desegregation continued as Faubus closed Little Rock high schools the following year and the number of desegregated schools in the South dropped precipitously in the ensuing years.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1954 waren das Höchste Gericht, das einmütig im 
braunen v. Brett der Ausbildung entschieden wurde, das allgemeine 
Schulen entsprechend Rennen trennten, "in sich selbst ungleich." 
Die Zustandgesetze, die Schuleabtrennung widersprachen 
benötigen folglich, mit der gleichen Schutzklausel der vierzehnten 
Änderung. Die regierende herausgeforderte traditionelle Haltung
und bedroht einer getrennten Lebensart im Süden validiert 1896 durch 
das Gericht, das in Plessy V. Ferguson anordnet. Das 1896 
Anordnen die Erlaubnis gehabt "trennen, aber entsprechen" allgemeine 
Anpassungen. 1955 ordinierte das Gericht, daß desegregation der
allgemeinen Schulen "mit allen fortfahren sollte überlegte 
Geschwindigkeit;" dennoch in vielen Teilen des Südens, 
widerstanden Reaktionärkräfte. In Little Rock verschalt 
Arkansas, Regler Orval Faubus herausgeforderte Bemühungen durch die 
Schule, um einen stufenweisen Schule desegregation Prozeß und 
bestellte Zustand Truppen des nationalen Schutzes einzuleiten, um 
Bundesgesetz herauszufordern und neun Afrikanisch-Amerikanische 
Kursteilnehmer vom Bedienen einer all-weißen High School zu stoppen. 
Da Fernsehen Bilder der folgenden Pöbelgewalttätigkeit um die 
Welt, Präsident Dwight D. Eisenhower, in der folgenden Radio- und 
Fernsehenadresse an September 24 verbritt, 1957, verkündete seine 
widerstrebende Antwort. Trotz seiner Mißbilligung der braunen 
Entscheidung, stand Eisenhower, seine Adresse in der Sprache des 
Gesetzes und der Ordnung, in der Propaganda des kalten Krieges und im 
nationalen Stolz hinlegend, dem ersten Präsidenten da Rekonstruktion,
um Bundestruppen zu senden, um die Rechte der afrikanischen Amerikaner
zu schützen. Obgleich die neun Kursteilnehmer einschrieben, 
fuhr Widerstand zum desegregation fort, während Faubus High School 
des Little Rock das folgende Jahr schloß und die Zahl von Schulen im 
Süden fiel jäh in die folgenden Jahre desegregated.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1954, la cour suprême unanimement décidée 
dans le panneau brun de v. de l'éducation que les écoles d'Etat ont 
isolé selon la course étaient "en soi inégale." Les lois 
d'état exigeant la ségrégation d'école étaient en conflit donc 
avec la clause égale de protection du quatorzième amendement. 
Les attitudes traditionnelles défiées régnantes et menacé 
une façon de vivre isolée dans les Sud validés en 1896 par 
la cour régnant dans Plessy v. Ferguson. 1896 régner 
autorisés "séparent mais égalent" le logement public. En 
1955, la cour a ordonné que la déségrégation des écoles d'Etat devrait 
se poursuivre "par tous vitesse délibérée;" pourtant dans 
beaucoup de parties des Sud, les forces réactionnaires ont 
résisté. Dans peu de roche, l'Arkansas, le Gouverneur Orval 
Faubus des efforts défiés par l'école embarque pour instituer un 
processus progressif de déségrégation d'école et des troupes commandées
de garde nationale d'état pour défier la loi fédérale et pour 
arrêter neuf étudiants afro-américains de aller à un lycée 
tout-blanc. Car la télévision a écarté des images de la 
violence ultérieure de foule autour du monde, le Président Dwight D.
Eisenhower, dans l'adresse suivante de radio et de télévision 
24 septembre 1957, a annoncé sa réponse réticente. En dépit
de sa désapprobation de la décision brune, Eisenhower, couchant son 
adresse dans le langage de la loi et de la commande, la propagande de 
guerre froide, et la fierté nationale, est allé bien au premier 
président puisque reconstruction pour envoyer les troupes fédérales
pour protéger les droites des Américains africains. Bien que 
les neuf étudiants se soient inscrits, la résistance à la 
déségrégation a continué pendant que Faubus fermait les lycées de 
petite roche l'année suivante et le nombre de desegregated des 
écoles dans les Sud relâchait précipitamment en années 
suivantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1954, a corte suprema decidida unânimemente na
placa marrom do v. da instrução que as escolas públicas segregaram 
de acordo com a raça era "inerente desigual." As leis do estado
que requerem o segregation da escola opuseram conseqüentemente à 
cláusula igual da proteção da décima quarta emenda. As 
atitudes tradicionais desafiadas governando e ameaçado uma maneira de
vida segregada no sul validado em 1896 pela corte que governa em 
Plessy v. Ferguson. 1896 governar permitidos "separam mas 
igualam" acomodações públicas. Em 1955, a corte ordained que 
o desegregation de escolas públicas deve proseguir "com tudo 
velocidade deliberada;" contudo em muitas partes do sul, as 
forças reactionary resistiram. Em pouca rocha, Arkansas, 
regulador Orval Faubus esforços desafiados pela escola board para 
instituir um processo gradual do desegregation da escola e umas tropas
requisitadas do protetor nacional do estado para defy a lei federal e 
para parar nove estudantes Africano-Americanos de atender a uma High 
School todo-branca. Porque a televisão espalhou imagens da 
violência subseqüente do mob em torno do mundo, presidente Dwight D.
Eisenhower, no seguinte endereço do rádio e da televisão setembro 
em 24, 1957, anunciou sua resposta relutante. Apesar de sua 
desaprovação da decisão marrom, Eisenhower, couching seu endereço 
na língua da lei e da ordem, no propaganda da guerra fria, e no 
orgulho nacional, assentou bem no primeiro presidente desde que 
reconstruction para emitir tropas federais para proteger as direitas 
de americanos africanos. Embora os nove estudantes se 
registrassem, a resistência ao desegregation continuou enquanto 
Faubus fechou High Schools de rocha pequena o seguinte ano e o número
de desegregated escolas no sul deixou cair precipitously nos anos 
seguindo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1954, la Corte suprema decisa all'unanimità 
nel Bordo marrone del v. di formazione che le "public school" 
hanno segregato secondo la corsa era "inerentemente disuguale." 
Dichiari le leggi che richiedono la segregazione della 
scuola quindi ha stato in conflitto con la clausola uguale di 
protezione della fourteenth correzione. Gli atteggiamenti 
tradizionali sfidati di regolamento e minacciato un modo di vivere 
segregato nel sud convalidato in 1896 dalla corte che regola in Plessy
v. Ferguson. I 1896 regolamenti consentiti "separano ma sono 
uguali" le sistemazioni pubbliche. In 1955, la corte ordained 
che il desegregation delle "public school" dovrebbe procedere "a tutti
velocità intenzionale;" tuttavia in molte parti del sud, le 
forze reactionary hanno resistito a. In poca roccia, l'Arkansas,
il regolatore Orval Faubus sforzi sfidati dal bordo della scuola
istituire un processo graduale di desegregation della scuola ed 
ordinato dichiara le truppe della protezione nazionale per 
sfidare alla legge federale e per arrestare nove allievi 
Africano-Americani dall'assistere ad una High School tutto-bianca. 
Poichè la televisione ha sparso le immagini della violenza 
successiva del mob intorno al mondo, il presidente Dwight D. 
Eisenhower, nel seguente indirizzo della televisione e della radio il 
24 settembre 1957, ha annunciato la sua risposta riluttante. 
Malgrado la sua disapprovazione della decisione marrone, 
Eisenhower, coricantesi il suo indirizzo nel linguaggio di legge e di 
ordine, nella propaganda di guerra fredda e nell'orgoglio nazionale, 
ha stato bene al primo presidente poiché ricostruzione per 
trasmettere le truppe federali per proteggere i diritti degli 
Americani africani. Anche se i nove allievi si sono iscritti, la
resistenza al desegregation è continuato mentre le High Schooi 
chiuse della roccia piccola di Faubus il seguente anno ed il 
numero di desegregated le scuole nel sud sono caduto precipitosamente 
durante gli anni seguenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1954, το ανώτατο δικαστήριο αποφάσισε ομόφωνα 
Brown V. Board της εκπαίδευσης ότι τα δημόσια σχολεία που
διαχωρίστηκαν σύμφωνα με τη φυλή ήταν "εγγενώς άνισα." Οι 
κρατικοί νόμοι που απαιτούν το σχολικό διαχωρισμό επομένως 
συγκρούστηκαν με την ίση πρόταση προστασίας της δέκατης τέταρτης
τροποποίησης. Η απόφαση προκάλεσε τις παραδοσιακές 
τοποθετήσεις και απείλησε έναν διαχωρισμένο τρόπο της ζωής στο 
νότο που επικυρώθηκε το 1896 με την απόφαση του δικαστηρίου 
Plessy V. Ferguson. Οι 1896 απόφαση επιτρεπόμενες 
"χωριστές αλλά ίσεσ" δημόσιες στεγάσεις. Το 1955, το 
δικαστήριο ορισμένος ότι ο διαχωρισμός των δημόσιων σχολείων 
πρέπει να συνεχίσει "με όλη τη σκόπιμη ταχύτητα" ακόμα σε 
πολλά μέρη του νότου, αντιδραστικές δυνάμεις που επικρίνονται. 
Σε λίγο βράχο, Αρκάνσας, ο κυβερνήτης Orval Faubus 
προκάλεσε τις προσπάθειες από το σχολικό πίνακα να καθιερώσει 
μια βαθμιαία διαδικασία σχολικού διαχωρισμού και διέταξε 
στρατεύματα κρατικής τα εθνικά φρουράς για να προκαλέσει τον 
ομοσπονδιακό νόμο και να σταματήσει εννέα 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικούς σπουδαστές από την παρουσία ενός 
όλος-άσπρου γυμνασίου. Δεδομένου ότι η τηλεόραση διέδωσε 
τις εικόνες της επόμενης βίας όχλου σε όλο τον κόσμο, Πρόεδρος 
Dwight D. Eisenhower, στην ακόλουθη διεύθυνση ραδιοφώνων 
και τηλεόρασης στις 24 Σεπτεμβρίου ..1957, ανήγγειλε την 
απρόθυμη απάντησή του. Παρά την αποδοκιμασία του της 
καφετιάς απόφασης, Eisenhower, που ξαπλώνει τη διεύθυνσή του 
στη γλώσσα του νόμου και της τάξης, την προπαγάνδα ψυχρού 
πολέμου, και την εθνική υπερηφάνεια, έγινε ο πρώτος Πρόεδρος 
από την αναδημιουργία για να στείλει τα ομοσπονδιακά στρατεύματα 
για να προστατεύσει τα δικαιώματα αφρικανικών Αμερικανών. Αν
και οι εννέα σπουδαστές που εγγράφηκαν, αντίσταση στο διαχωρισμό 
συνέχισαν ως Faubus τα κλειστά γυμνάσια λίγου βράχου το 
επόμενο έτος και ο αριθμός τα σχολεία στο νότο που έπεσαν 
precipitously στα επόμενα έτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1954, el Tribunal Supremo decidido 
unánimemente en la tarjeta marrón del v. de la educación que las 
escuelas públicas segregaron según la raza era "intrínsecamente 
desigual." Los leyes del estado que requerían la segregación 
de la escuela por lo tanto estuvieron en conflicto con la cláusula 
igual de la protección de la catorcena enmienda. Las actitudes 
tradicionales desafiadas predominantes y amenazado una manera de la 
vida segregada en el sur validado en 1896 por la corte que gobierna en
Plessy v. Ferguson. Las 1896 decisiones permitidas "separan pero
igualan" comodidades públicas. En 1955, la corte ordained que 
el desegregation de escuelas públicas debe proceder "con todos 
velocidad deliberada;" con todo en muchas partes del sur, las 
fuerzas reaccionarias resistieron. En poca roca, Arkansas, 
gobernador Orval Faubus los esfuerzos desafiados por la escuela sube 
para instituir un proceso gradual del desegregation de la escuela y a 
tropas pedidas del protector nacional del estado para desafiar ley 
federal y para parar a nueve estudiantes Africano-Americanos de 
atender a una High School secundaria todo-blanca. Pues la 
televisión separó imágenes de la violencia subsecuente de la 
multitud alrededor del mundo, presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower, en el 
direccionamiento siguiente de la radio y de la televisión de 
septiembre el 24 de 1957, anunció su respuesta renuente. A 
pesar de su desaprobación de la decisión marrón, Eisenhower, 
acostando su direccionamiento en el lenguaje de la ley y de la orden, 
la propaganda de la guerra fría, y el orgullo nacional, sintió bien 
al primer presidente puesto que reconstrucción para enviar a tropas 
federales para proteger las derechas de americanos africanos. 
Aunque los nueve estudiantes alistaron, la resistencia al 
desegregation continuó mientras que Faubus cerró High Schools 
secundarias de la pequeña roca el año siguiente y el número de 
desegregated escuelas en el sur cayó empinado en los años que 
sobrevenían.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086478</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105120</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/mob-rule-cannot-be-allowed-to-override-the-decisions-of-our-courts-president-dwight-d-eisenhower-s-1957-address-on-little-rock-arkansas</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
