<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108646</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108646</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206263</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Built in America: Historic American Buildings Survey/Historic American Engineering Record, 1933-Present</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aufgebaut worden in Amerika: Historischer 
Amerikanischer Amerikanischer Technik-Satz Der 
Gebäude-Survey/Historic, 1933-Present</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Construit en Amérique : Enregistrement 
Américain Américain Historique d'Ingénierie des Bâtiments 
Survey/Historic, 1933-Present</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Construído em América: Registro Americano 
Americano Historic Da Engenharia Dos Edifícios Survey/Historic, 
1933-Present</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Costruito in America: Record Americano 
Americano Storico Di Ingegneria Delle Costruzioni Survey/Historic, 
1933-Present</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χτισμένος στην Αμερική: Ιστορική αμερικανική 
έρευνα κτηρίων/ιστορικό αμερικανικό αρχείο εφαρμοσμένης 
μηχανικής, 1933-παρόν</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Construido en América: Expediente Americano
Americano Histórico De la Ingeniería De los Edificios 
Survey/Historic, 1933-Present</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">documents the achievements in architecture, engineering, and design in the U.S., including examples as diverse as windmills, one-room schoolhouses, the Golden Gate Bridge, and buildings designed by Frank Lloyd Wright. The site offers searches to thousands of drawings, large-format photographs, and written histories for more than 35,000 historic structures and sites dating from the 17th to the 20th century.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">dokumentiert die Ausführungen in der Architektur,
in der Technik und im Design in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, 
einschließlich die Beispiele, die wie Windmühlen, Einraum 
Schulhäuser, die Golden- Gatebrücke und die Gebäude konzipiert 
sind von Frank Lloyd Wright so verschieden sind. Die Site bietet
Suchen Tausenden Zeichnungen, Großformat Fotographien und 
schriftlichen Geschichten für mehr als 35.000 historische Strukturen 
und Sites an, die vom 17. bis 20. Jahrhundert datieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">documente les accomplissements dans 
l'architecture, l'ingénierie, et la conception aux ETATS-UNIS, y 
compris des exemples aussi divers que des moulins à vent, des écoles
d'un-pièce, le pont en porte d'or, et des bâtiments conçus par 
Frank Lloyd Wright. Le site offre des recherches aux milliers de
schémas, de photographies de grand-format, et d'histoires écrites 
pour plus de 35.000 structures et sites historiques datant du 17ème 
à 20ème siècle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">documenta as realizações na arquitetura, na 
engenharia, e no projeto nos ESTADOS UNIDOS, including os exemplos 
tão diversos como moinhos de vento, schoolhouses do um-quarto, a 
ponte da porta dourada, e os edifícios projetados por Frank Lloyd 
Wright. O local oferece buscas aos milhares dos desenhos, das 
fotografias do grande-formato, e de histories escritos para mais de 
35.000 estruturas e locais historic que datam do 17o a 20o século.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">documenta i successi nell'architettura, 
nell'ingegneria e nel disegno negli STATI UNITI, compreso gli esempi 
vari come mulini a vento, scuole della un-stanza, il ponticello del 
cancello dorato e costruzioni progettate da Frank Lloyd Wright. 
Il luogo offre le ricerche alle migliaia delle illustrazioni, 
delle fotografie di gran-formato e dei dati storici scritti per più 
di 35.000 strutture e luoghi storici che datano dal diciassettesimo - 
ventesimo secolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τεκμηριώνει τα επιτεύγματα στην αρχιτεκτονική, την 
εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική, και το σχέδιο στις ΗΠΑ, συμπεριλαμβανομένων 
των παραδειγμάτων τόσο διαφορετικών όσο οι ανεμόμυλοι, τα 
σχολεία ένας-δωματίων, τη χρυσή γέφυρα πυλών, και τα κτήρια που
σχεδιάζονται από το Frank Lloyd Wright. Η περιοχή 
προσφέρει τις αναζητήσεις σε χιλιάδες σχέδια, φωτογραφίες 
μεγάλος-μορφής, και γραπτές ιστορίες περισσότερων από 35.000 
ιστορικών δομών και περιοχών που χρονολογούν από το 17$ο στο 20ό
αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">documenta los logros en la configuración, la 
ingeniería, y el diseño en los ESTADOS UNIDOS, incluyendo los 
ejemplos tan diversos como los molinos de viento, las escuelas del 
uno-cuarto, el puente de la puerta de oro, y los edificios diseñados 
por Frank Lloyd Wright. El sitio ofrece búsquedas a los 
millares de gráficos, de fotografías del grande-formato, y de 
historias escritas para más de 35.000 estructuras y sitios 
históricos que fechan a partir del 17mo a vigésimo siglo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206263</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108646</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/built-in-america-historic-american-buildings-survey-historic-american-engineering-record-1933-present</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
