<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106795</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106795</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201370</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Visualizing Carbon Pathways</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: Sichtbar 
machende Carbon-Bahnen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Voies de Visualisation de Carbone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Pathways Visualizando Do Carbono</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Vie Di Visualizzazione Del Carbonio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: 
Διαβάσεις άνθρακα απεικόνισης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Caminos Del Carbón Que visualizan</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This EET Chapter will introduce you to visualization capabilities available through NASA's Earth Observatory. You'll build several animations of satellite data that illustrate carbon pathways through the Earth system. For instance, you'll build animations of fire images that indicate carbon is being released into the atmosphere. You'll also make animations of plant productivity images that indicate carbon is being removed from the atmosphere and locked into the biosphere. After you've built animations, you'll access another visualization tool to compare sets of other carbon-related data images by controlling their transparency.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses EET Kapitel stellt Sie 
Sichtbarmachungfähigkeiten zur Sternwarte Masse der vorhandenen 
durchgehenden NASAS vor. Sie bauen einige Animationen von 
Satellitendaten auf, die Carbonbahnen durch das Masse System 
veranschaulichen. Zum Beispiel bauen Sie Animationen der 
Feuerbilder auf, die anzeigen, daß Carbon in die Atmosphäre 
freigegeben wird. Sie bilden auch Animationen von den 
Betriebsproduktivitätbildern, die anzeigen, daß Carbon von der 
Atmosphäre gelöscht wird und in die Biosphäre gesperrt. 
Nachdem Sie Animationen aufgebaut haben, greifen Sie auf ein 
anderes Sichtbarmachunghilfsmittel zu, um Sets anderer Carbon-in 
Verbindung stehender Datenbilder zu vergleichen, indem Sie ihr 
Transparent steuern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce chapitre d'EET vous présentera à 
l'observatoire de la terre de la NASA traversante disponible de 
capacités de visualisation. Vous établirez plusieurs 
animations des données satellites qui illustrent des voies de carbone
par le système de la terre. Par exemple, vous établirez des 
animations des images du feu qui indiquent que le carbone est 
déchargé dans l'atmosphère. Vous ferez également des 
animations des images de productivité végétale qui indiquent que le
carbone est enlevé de l'atmosphère et verrouillé sur la biosphère.
Après que vous ayez établi des animations, vous accéderez à 
un autre outil de visualisation pour comparer des ensembles d'autres 
images carbone-connexes de données en contrôlant leur transparent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este capítulo de EET introduzi-lo-á ao 
obervatório da terra da NASA direta disponível das potencialidades 
do visualization. Você construirá diversos animations dos 
dados satellite que ilustram pathways do carbono através do sistema 
da terra. Por exemplo, você construirá animations das imagens 
do fogo que indicam que o carbono está sendo liberado na atmosfera. 
Você fará também animations das imagens da produtividade de 
planta que indicam que o carbono está sendo removido da atmosfera e 
travado no biosphere. Depois que você construiu animations, 
você alcançará uma outra ferramenta do visualization para comparar 
jogos de outras imagens carbono-relacionadas dos dados controlando sua
transparência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo capitolo di EET li introdurrà 
all'osservatorio della terra della NASA diretta disponibile di 
possibilità di visualizzazione. Svilupperete parecchie 
animazioni dei dati satelliti che illustrano le vie del carbonio 
attraverso il sistema della terra. Per esempio, svilupperete le 
animazioni delle immagini del fuoco che indicano che il carbonio sta 
scaricando nell'atmosfera. Egualmente farete le animazioni delle
immagini di rendimento di pianta che indicano che il carbonio sta 
rimuovendo dall'atmosfera e sta bloccando nella biosfera. Dopo 
che sviluppiate le animazioni, accederete ad un altro strumento di 
visualizzazione per confrontare gli insiemi di altre immagini 
carbonio-relative di dati gestendo il loro acetato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το κεφάλαιο EET θα σας εισαγάγει στις 
ικανότητες απεικόνισης διαθέσιμες μέσω του γήινου παρατηρητήριου
της NASA. Θα χτίσετε διάφορες ζωτικότητες των δορυφορικών
στοιχείων που επεξηγούν τις διαβάσεις άνθρακα μέσω του γήινου 
συστήματος. Παραδείγματος χάριν, θα χτίσετε τις ζωτικότητες
των εικόνων πυρκαγιάς που δείχνουν ότι ο άνθρακας εκδίδεται στην
ατμόσφαιρα. Θα κάνετε επίσης τις ζωτικότητες των εικόνων 
παραγωγικότητας εγκαταστάσεων που δείχνουν ότι ο άνθρακας 
αφαιρείται από την ατμόσφαιρα και κλειδώνεται στη βιόσφαιρα. 
Αφότου έχετε χτίσει τις ζωτικότητες, έχετε πρόσβαση σε 
ένα άλλο εργαλείο απεικόνισης για να συγκρίνετε τα σύνολα άλλων
άνθρακας-σχετικών με το εικόνων στοιχείων με τον έλεγχο της 
διαφάνειάς τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este capítulo de EET le introducirá al 
observatorio de la tierra de la NASA directa disponible de las 
capacidades de la visualización. Usted construirá varias 
animaciones de los datos basados en los satélites que ilustran 
caminos del carbón a través del sistema de la tierra. Por 
ejemplo, usted construirá animaciones de las imágenes del fuego que 
indican que el carbón release/versión en la atmósfera. Usted 
también hará animaciones de las imágenes de la productividad de 
planta que indican que el carbón se está quitando de la atmósfera y
que está siendo bloqueado en la biosfera. Después de que usted
haya construido animaciones, usted tendrá acceso a otra herramienta 
de la visualización para comparar los conjuntos de otras imágenes 
carbo'n-relacionadas de los datos controlando su transparencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ALI WHITMER
FN:ALI WHITMER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LUANN DAHLMAN
FN:LUANN DAHLMAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201370</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106795</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-visualizing-carbon-pathways</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
