<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107241</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107241</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205851</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bellini, Giorgione, Titian, and the Renaissance of Venetian Painting</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bellini, Giorgione, Titian und die Renaissance des
venetianischen Anstriches</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bellini, Giorgione, Titian, et la Renaissance de 
la peinture vénitienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bellini, Giorgione, Titian, e o renascimento da 
pintura venetian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bellini, Giorgione, Titian e la rinascita della 
pittura veneziana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Bellini, Giorgione, Titian, και η αναγέννηση 
της ενετικής ζωγραφικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bellini, Giorgione, Titian, y el renacimiento de 
la pintura veneciana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines a phase of the Renaissance in Venice when three great masters were working side by side (1500 to 1530). The innovations of Bellini, Giorgione, Titian and their contemporaries influenced European art for centuries. Learn about the historical climate, sacred images and stories, allegories and mythologies, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft eine Phase der Renaissance in Venedig,
als drei große Meister nebeneinander arbeiteten (1500 bis 1530). 
Die Innovationen von Bellini, von Giorgione, von Titian und von 
ihren Zeitgenossen beeinflußten europäische kunst für Jahrhunderte.
Erlernen Sie über das historische Klima, heiligen die Bilder 
und die Geschichten, die Allegorien und die Mythologien und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine une phase de la Renaissance à Venise 
quand trois grands maîtres fonctionnaient côte à côte (1500 à 
1530). Les innovations de Bellini, de Giorgione, de Titian et de
leurs contemporains ont influencé l'art européen pendant des 
siècles. Renseignez-vous sur le climat historique, les images 
et les histoires sacrées, les allégories et les mythologies, et les 
plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina uma fase do renascimento em Veneza quando 
três mestres grandes estavam trabalhando de lado a lado (1500 a 
1530). As inovações de Bellini, de Giorgione, de Titian e de 
seus comtemporâneos influenciaram a arte européia por séculos. 
Aprenda sobre o clima histórico, as imagens e as histórias 
sacred, os allegories e os mythologies, e o mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina una fase della rinascita a Venezia quando 
tre supervisori grandi stavano funzionando parallelamente (1500 - 
1530). Le innovazioni di Bellini, di Giorgione, di Titian e dei 
loro contemporanei hanno influenzato l'arte europea per i secoli. 
Impari circa il clima storico, le immagini e le storia sacred, i
allegories e le mitologie ed il più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει μια φάση της αναγέννησης στη Βενετία όταν 
εργάζονταν δίπλα-δίπλα τρεις μεγάλοι κύριοι (1500 έως 
1530). Οι καινοτομίες Bellini, Giorgione, Titian 
και των συγχρόνων τους επηρέασαν την ευρωπαϊκή τέχνη για αιώνες.
Μάθετε για το ιστορικό κλίμα, τις ιερές εικόνες και τις 
ιστορίες, τις αλληγορίες και τις μυθολογίες, και περισσότερους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina una fase del renacimiento en Venecia 
cuando tres grandes amos trabajaban de lado a lado (1500 a 1530). 
Las innovaciones de Bellini, de Giorgione, de Titian y de sus 
contemporáneos influenciaron el arte europeo por siglos. 
Aprenda sobre el clima histórico, las imágenes y las historias
sagradas, las alegorías y las mitologías, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205851</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107241</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/bellini-giorgione-titian-and-the-renaissance-of-venetian-painting</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
