<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105078</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105078</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205975</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">MyMoney.gov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">MyMoney.gov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">MyMoney.gov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">MyMoney.gov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">MyMoney.gov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">MyMoney.gov</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">MyMoney.gov</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the U.S. government's website dedicated to teaching all Americans the basics about financial education. Whether you're buying a home, balancing your checkbook, or investing in your 401k, MyMoney.gov can help you do it better. Throughout the site, you'll see important information from 20 federal agencies. Find out if you have financial smarts: take the MyMoney interactive quiz. Read the national strategy for financial literacy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Web site der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung,
die dem Beibringen allen Amerikanern der Grundlagen über finanzielle 
Ausbildung eingesetzt wird. Ob Sie ein Haupt kaufen, Ihr 
Scheckheft ausgleichend oder in Ihrem 401k investierend, kann 
MyMoney.gov Ihnen helfen es verbessern. In der Site sehen Sie 
wichtige Informationen von 20 Bundesämtern. Finden Sie heraus, 
wenn Sie finanzielle smarts haben: nehmen Sie dem MyMoney 
interaktiven Quiz. Lesen Sie die nationale Strategie für 
finanziellen Bildungsgrad.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le site Web du gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS 
consacré à enseigner à tous les Américains les fondations au sujet
de l'éducation financière. Si vous achetez un à la maison, 
équilibrant votre chéquier, ou l'investissant dans votre 401k, 
MyMoney.gov peut vous aider il améliore. Dans tout le site, 
vous verrez l'information importante de 20 agences fédérales. 
Découvrez si vous avez les smarts financiers : prenez au 
MyMoney le jeu interactif. Lisez la stratégie nationale pour 
l'instruction financière.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o Web site do governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
dedicado a ensinar a todos os americanos os princípios sobre a 
instrução financeira. Se você está comprando um home, 
balançando seu checkbook, ou investing em seu 401k, MyMoney.gov pode 
ajudar-lhe ele melhora. Durante todo o local, você verá a 
informação importante de 20 agências federais. Encontre para 
fora se você tiver smarts financeiros: faça exame o MyMoney do
quiz interativo. Leia a estratégia nacional para o literacy 
financeiro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il Web site del governo degli STATI UNITI 
dedicato ad insegnare a tutti gli Americani i principi fondamentali 
circa formazione finanziaria. Se state comprando un domestico, 
equilibrando il vostro checkbook, o investendo nel vostro 401k, 
MyMoney.gov può aiutarlo esso migliora. Durante il luogo, 
vedrete le informazioni importanti da 20 enti federali. Scopra 
se avete smarts finanziari: prenda al MyMoney il quiz 
interattivo. Legga la strategia nazionale per literacy 
finanziario.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ο ιστοχώρος της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης που 
αφιερώνεται στη διδασκαλία σε όλους τους Αμερικανούς των βασικών 
για την οικονομική εκπαίδευση. Εάν αγοράζετε ένα σπίτι, 
ισορροπείτε το καρνέ επιταγών σας, ή επενδύετε 401k σας, 
MyMoney.gov μπορεί να βοηθήσει εσείς αυτό καλύτερα. Σε 
όλη την περιοχή, θα δείτε τις σημαντικές πληροφορίες 
από 20 ομοσπονδιακές αντιπροσωπείες. Ανακαλύψτε εάν έχετε 
τα οικονομικά smarts: πάρτε το διαλογικό διαγωνισμό 
γνώσεων MyMoney. Διαβάστε την εθνική στρατηγική για την 
οικονομική βασική εκπαίδευση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el Web site del gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
dedicado a enseñar a todos los americanos los fundamentos sobre la 
educación financiera. Si usted está comprando un casero, 
balanceando su talonario de cheques, o invirtiéndolo en su 401k, MyMoney.gov 
puede ayudarle él mejora. A través del sitio, usted verá la 
información importante a partir de 20 agencias federales. 
Descubra si usted tiene smarts financieros: tome a MyMoney
el concurso interactivo. Lea la estrategia nacional para la 
instrucción financiera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205975</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105078</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mymoney.gov</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
