<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105023</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105023</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087010</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Omaha Platform: Launching the Populist Party</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Omaha Plattform: Ausstoßen der 
VolksPartei</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Plateforme d'Omaha : Lancement de la 
partie populiste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Plataforma De Omaha: Lançando o partido 
populist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Piattaforma De Omaha: Lancio del partito 
populistico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πλατφόρμα της Ομάχα: Προώθηση του λαϊκιστικού
συμβαλλόμενου μέρους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Plataforma De Omaha: Lanzar el partido 
populista</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although historians often speak of a "Populist movement" in the 1880s, it wasn't until 1892 that the People's or Populist Party was formally organized. The Omaha Platform, adopted by the founding convention of the party on July 4, 1892, set out the basic tenets of the Populist movement. The movement had emerged out of the cooperative crusade organized by the Farmer's Alliance in the 1880s. The preamble was written by Minnesota lawyer, farmer, politician, and novelist Ignatius Donnelly. Delegates to the convention embraced the platform with great enthusiasm. Many of the specific proposals urged by the Omaha Platform--the graduated income tax, the secret ballot, the direct election of Senators, the eight-hour day--won enactment in the progressive and New Deal eras of the next century. Yet at least one historian has argued that the fundamental cooperative and democratic spirit of the agrarian radicals was lost along the way.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich Historiker häufig von einer 
"Volksbewegung" im 1880s sprechen, war es nicht bis 1892, das der 
Leute oder der VolksPartei formal organisiert wurden. 
Die Omaha Plattform, angenommen von der gründenversammlung der 
Partei an Juli 4, 1892, legte die grundlegenden Lehren
der Volksbewegung dar. Die Bewegung war aus dem kooperativen 
Kreuzzug heraus aufgetaucht, der durch das Bündnis des Landwirts im 
1880s organisiert wurde. Die Präambel wurde vom Minnesota 
Rechtsanwalt, dem Landwirt, dem Politiker und dem Novelist Ignatius 
Donnelly geschrieben. Delegierte zur Versammlung umfaßten die 
Plattform mit großer Begeisterung. Viele der spezifischen 
Anträge drängten durch die Omaha Plattform -- die abgestufte 
Einkommenssteuer, der geheime Stimmzettel, die direkte Wahl der 
Senatoren, der Achtstundentag -- gewonnener Erlaß in den Ären des 
progressiven und neuen Abkommens des folgenden Jahrhunderts. 
Dennoch mindestens hat ein Historiker argumentiert, daß der 
grundlegende kooperative und demokratische Geist der 
landwirtschaftlichen Radikale entlang der Methode verloren war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que les historiens parlent souvent "d'un 
mouvement populiste" dans le 1880s, il n'avait pas lieu jusqu'en 1892 
que le peuple ou la partie populiste a été formellement organisé. 
La plateforme d'Omaha, adoptée par la convention de fondation 
de la partie 4 juillet 1892, a visé les principes de base du 
mouvement populiste. Le mouvement avait émergé hors de la 
croisade coopérative organisée par l'alliance du fermier dans le 
1880s. Le préambule a été écrit par l'avocat, le fermier, le
politicien, et le romancier Ignatius Donnelly du Minnesota. Les 
délégués à la convention ont embrassé la plateforme avec grand 
enthousiasme. Plusieurs des propositions spécifiques ont 
recommandé par la plateforme d'Omaha -- l'impôt sur le revenu 
gradué, le vote secret, l'élection directe des sénateurs, le jour 
de huit heures -- établissement gagné dans les ères d'affaire 
progressive et nouvelle du siècle à venir. Pourtant au moins 
un historien a argué du fait que l'esprit coopératif et 
démocratique fondamental des radicaux agraires a été détruit le 
long de la voie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora os historians falassem frequentemente "de 
um movimento populist" no 1880s, não se realizava até 1892 que o 
pessoa ou o partido populist foram organizados formalmente. A 
plataforma de Omaha, adotada pela convenção fundando do partido 
julho em 4, 1892, ajustou-se para fora dos tenets básicos do 
movimento populist. O movimento tinha emergido fora do crusade 
cooperativo organizado pelo alliance do fazendeiro no 1880s. O 
preamble foi escrito pelo advogado, pelo fazendeiro, pelo político, e
pelo novelist Ignatius Donnelly de Minnesota. Os delegados à 
convenção embraced a plataforma com entusiasmo grande. Muitas 
das propostas específicas incitaram pela plataforma de Omaha -- o 
imposto de renda graduado, a cédula secreta, a eleição direta dos 
senators, o dia eight-hour -- enactment ganhado nas eras do negócio 
progressivo e novo do século seguinte. Contudo ao menos um 
historian discutiu que o espírito cooperativo e democrático 
fundamental dos radicais agrarian estêve perdido ao longo da maneira.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se gli storici parlano spesso "di un 
movimento populistico" nel 1880s, non aveva luogo fino al 1892 che la 
gente o il partito populistico è stato organizzato formalmente. 
La piattaforma de Omaha, adottata dalla convenzione fondante del
partito il 4 luglio 1892, ha precisato i tenets di base del movimento 
populistico. Il movimento era emerso dal crusade cooperativo 
organizzato dall'alleanza del coltivatore nel 1880s. La premessa
è stata scritta dall'avvocato, dal coltivatore, dal politico e dal 
romanziere Ignatius Donnelly del Minnesota. I delegati alla 
convenzione hanno abbracciato la piattaforma con entusiasmo grande. 
Molte delle proposte specifiche hanno sollecitato dalla 
piattaforma de Omaha -- l'imposta sul reddito graduata, la scheda 
elettorale segreta, l'elezione diretta dei senatori, il giorno di otto
ore -- la promulgazione vinta nelle ere di affare progressivo e nuovo 
del secolo venturo. Tuttavia almeno uno storico ha sostenuto che
lo spirito cooperativo e democratico fondamentale dei radicali agrari 
è stato perso lungo il modo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και οι ιστορικοί μιλούν συχνά για μια "λαϊκιστική 
μετακίνηση" στο 1880s, ήταν όχι πριν από 1892 ότι οι 
άνθρωποι ή το λαϊκιστικό συμβαλλόμενο μέρος οργανώθηκαν 
τυπικά. Η πλατφόρμα της Ομάχα, που υιοθετήθηκε από την 
ιδρύοντας σύμβαση του συμβαλλόμενου μέρους στις 4 Ιουλίου 
..1892, καθόρισε τις βασικές αρχές της λαϊκιστικής 
μετακίνησης. Η μετακίνηση είχε προκύψει από τη 
συνεταιριστική σταυροφορία που οργανώθηκε από τη συμμαχία του 
αγρότη στο 1880s. Ο πρόλογος γράφτηκε από το δικηγόρο, 
τον αγρότη, τον πολιτικό, και το μυθιστοριογράφο Ignatius 
Donnelly Μινεσότας. Οι εκπρόσωποι στη σύμβαση αγκαλίασαν 
την πλατφόρμα με το μεγάλο ενθουσιασμό. Πολλές από τις 
συγκεκριμένες προτάσεις που ωθήθηκαν με την πλατφόρμα της Ομάχα 
-- ο κλιμακωτός φόρος εισοδήματος, η μυστική ψήφος, η άμεση 
εκλογή των γερουσιαστών, η οκτώ ωρών ημέρα -- κέρδισαν τη 
θέσπιση στις προοδευτικές και νέες εποχές διαπραγμάτευσης του 
επόμενου αιώνα. Ακόμα τουλάχιστον ένας ιστορικός έχει 
υποστηρίξει ότι το θεμελιώδες συνεταιριστικό και δημοκρατικό 
πνεύμα των αγροτικών ριζοσπαστών χάθηκε κατά μήκος του τρόπου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque los historiadores hablan a menudo de un 
"movimiento populista" en el 1880s, no era hasta 1892 que ordenaron la
gente o el partido populista formalmente. La plataforma de 
Omaha, adoptada por la convención de fundación del partido de julio 
el 4 de 1892, precisó los tenets básicos del movimiento populista. 
El movimiento había emergido fuera de la cruzada cooperativa
ordenada por la alianza del granjero en el 1880s. El preámbulo 
fue escrito por el abogado, el granjero, el político, y el novelista 
Ignatius Donnelly de Minnesota. Los delegados a la convención 
abrazaron la plataforma con gran entusiasmo. Muchas de las 
ofertas específicas impulsaron por la plataforma de Omaha -- el 
impuesto sobre la renta graduado, la balota secreta, la elección 
directa de senadores, el día de ocho horas -- promulgación ganada en
las eras del reparto progresivo y nuevo del siglo próximo. Con 
todo por lo menos un historiador ha discutido que el alcohol 
cooperativo y democrático fundamental de los radicales agrarios fue 
perdido a lo largo de la manera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087010</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105023</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-omaha-platform-launching-the-populist-party</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
