<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104087</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104087</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200344</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Activity: Is There Really Life on Mars?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aktivität: Gibt es wirklich Leben auf Mars?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité : Y a-t-il vraiment la vie sur 
Mars ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade: Há realmente vida em Marte?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività: È ci realmente vita su Marte?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δραστηριότητα: Υπάρχει πραγματικά ζωή στον Αρη;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad: ¿Hay realmente vida en Marte?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Public Broadcasting Service (PBS) activity explores the controversy over whether or not there is life on Mars. Part of the Mysteries of Deep Space Program that originally aired in April 1997, the activity includes instructional objectives, background information, and discussion/essay questions related to life on Mars. It also features an activity where students can grow microorganisms, examine them under a microscope, and analyze their observations with the aid of follow-up questions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese allgemeine Aktivität des Sendedienstes (PBS) 
erforscht den Kontroverseüberschuß, ob oder nicht es Leben auf Mars 
gibt. Zerteilen Sie von den Geheimnissen des Weltraum-Programms,
die ursprünglich im April 1997 lüfteten, die Aktivität einschließt
anweisenden Lernziele, Hintergrundinformationen und die 
discussion/essay Fragen, die auf dem Leben auf Mars in Verbindung 
gestanden werden. Er kennzeichnet auch eine Aktivität, in der 
Kursteilnehmer Mikroorganismen wachsen, sie unter einem Mikroskop 
überprüfen, und ihre Beobachtungen mit dem Hilfsmittel der 
Anschlußfragen analysieren können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité publique du service de radiodiffusion 
(PBS) explore l'excédent de polémique s'il y a la vie sur Mars. 
Partie des mystères du programme de l'espace profond qui ont 
initialement aéré en avril 1997, l'activité inclut des objectifs, 
l'information de fond, et des questions d'instruction de 
discussion/essay liées à la vie sur Mars. Il comporte 
également une activité où les étudiants peuvent accroître des 
micro-organismes, les examiner sous un microscope, et analyser leurs 
observations à l'aide des questions de suivi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade pública do serviço de transmissão (PBS) 
explora o excesso da controvérsia se ou há uma vida em Marte. 
Parte dos mistérios do programa do espaço profundo que 
arejaram originalmente em abril 1997, a atividade inclui objetivos, a 
informação de fundo, e as perguntas instrutivos de discussion/essay 
relacionadas à vida em Marte. Caracteriza também uma atividade
onde os estudantes possam crescer microorganisms, os examinar sob um 
microscópio, e analisar suas observações com o dae (dispositivo 
automático de entrada) de perguntas da continuação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività pubblica di servizio di broadcasting 
(PBS) esplora l'eccedenza di polemica se o non c'è vita su Marte. 
Parte dei misteri del programma dello spazio profondo che 
originalmente hanno ventilato nel mese di aprile del 1997, l'attività
include gli obiettivi, le informazioni di base e le domande didattici 
di discussion/essay relative a vita su Marte. Egualmente 
caratterizza un'attività dove gli allievi possono sviluppare i 
microorganismi, esaminarli sotto un microscopio ed analizzare le loro 
osservazioni con l'aiuto delle domande di aggiornamento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δημόσια δραστηριότητα υπηρεσιών ραδιοφωνικων 
αναμεταδόσεων (PBS) ερευνά τη διαμάχη πέρα από εάν υπάρχει 
ή όχι ζωή στον Αρη. Μέρος των μυστηρίων του βαθιού 
διαστημικού προγράμματος που αέρισε αρχικά τον Απρίλιο του 
1997, η δραστηριότητα περιλαμβάνει τους εκπαιδευτικούς στόχους,
τις βασικές πληροφορίες, και τις ερωτήσεις συζήτησης/δοκίμιου 
σχετικές με τη ζωή στον Αρη. Χαρακτηρίζει επίσης μια 
δραστηριότητα όπου οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να αυξηθούν τους 
μικροοργανισμούς, να τους εξετάσουν κάτω από ένα μικροσκόπιο, 
και να αναλύσουν τις παρατηρήσεις τους με την ενίσχυση των 
ακόλουθων ερωτήσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad pública del servicio de difusión (PBS) 
explora el excedente de la controversia si o hay vida en Marte. 
Parte de los misterios del programa del espacio profundo que 
ventilaron originalmente en abril de 1997, la actividad incluye 
objetivos, la información de fondo, y las preguntas educacionales de 
discussion/essay relacionadas con la vida en Marte. También 
ofrece una actividad donde los estudiantes pueden crecer 
microorganismos, examinarlos bajo un microscopio, y analizar sus 
observaciones con la ayuda de las preguntas de la carta recordativa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SERVICE
FN:PUBLIC BROADCASTING SERVICE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200344</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104087</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/activity-is-there-really-life-on-mars</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
