<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104688</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104688</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087111</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"This Is What the Union Done": The Story of the United Mine Workers of America in Song</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"dieses ist, was der Anschluß getan": Die 
Geschichte der vereinigten Grube Arbeiter von Amerika im Lied</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"c'est ce qui l'union faite" : L'histoire 
des mineurs unis de l'Amérique dans la chanson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"este é que a união feita": A história 
dos trabalhadores de mina unidos de América na canção</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"questo è che cosa l'unione fatta": La 
storia dei minatori uniti dell'America nella canzone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτό είναι τι η ένωση που γίνεται": Η ιστορία 
των ενωμένων εργαζομένων ορυχείου της Αμερικής στο τραγούδι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"esto es lo que la unión hecha": La 
historia de los trabajadores de mina unidos de América en la 
canción</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The sudden revival of the United Mine Workers of America in 1933 was a remarkable story. In late 1932 the UMWA was practically defunct, yet by the fall of 1933 it was in the strongest position in its history. Perhaps the best historical narrative of the revival of UMWA was penned in lyrical form by an African-American former coal miner called "Uncle George" Jones. Jones had started working as a miner in 1889 at age seventeen but in 1914 blindness forced him out of the Alabama mines. Long known for his singing in church choirs, down in the mines, and on the picket line. Jones' "This Is What the Union Done" not only expressed the miners' sense of the role that Roosevelt and Lewis played in the union revival; it also beautifully captures a sense of the transformation when miners "got the union back again!"</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die plötzliche Wiederbelebung der vereinigten 
Grube Arbeiter von Amerika 1933 war eine bemerkenswerte Geschichte. 
In späten 1932 war das UMWA praktisch verstorben, dennoch bis 
zum dem Fall von 1933 war es in der stärksten Position in seiner 
Geschichte. Möglicherweise wurde die beste historische 
Darstellung der Wiederbelebung von UMWA in der lyrical Form von einem 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen ehemaligen Kohlebergmann eingesperrt, das 
"Onkel George" Jones angerufen wurde. Jones hatte das Arbeiten 
als Bergmann 1889 an Alter siebzehn begonnen, aber 1914 erzwang 
Blindheit ihn aus den Alabama Gruben heraus. Sehnen Sie sich 
gewußt nach seinem, das in den Kirchechören, unten in den Gruben und
auf der Pfostenzeile singt. Jones "dieses ist, was der getane 
Anschluß" nicht nur die Richtung der Bergmänner der Rolle 
ausdrückte, daß Roosevelt und Lewis in der Anschlußwiederbelebung 
spielten; es auch erfaßt schön eine Richtung der 
Transformation, als Bergmänner "zurückbekamen den Anschluß wieder!"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La renaissance soudaine des mineurs unis de 
l'Amérique en 1933 était une histoire remarquable. Dans 1932 
en retard l'UMWA était pratiquement ancien, pourtant par la chute de 
1933 il était en position la plus forte dans son histoire. 
Peut-être le meilleur récit historique de la renaissance 
d'UMWA a été parqué en forme lyrique par un ancien mineur 
afro-américain appelé l'"oncle George" Jones. Jones avait 
commencé travailler en tant que mineur en 1889 à l'âge dix-sept 
mais en 1914 la cécité l'a expulsé des mines de l'Alabama. 
Désirez ardemment connu pour le sien qui chante dans des 
choeurs d'église, vers le bas dans les mines, et sur le piquet de 
grève. Est ce de Jones "ce qui l'union faite" a non seulement 
exprimé le sens des mineurs du rôle que Roosevelt et Lewis ont joué
dans la renaissance des syndicats ; il capture également 
admirablement un sens de la transformation quand les mineurs "ont 
récupéré l'union encore!"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O revival repentino dos trabalhadores de mina 
unidos de América em 1933 era uma história notável. Em 1932 
atrasados o UMWA era praticamente defunct, contudo pela queda de 1933 
estava na posição a mais forte em seu history. Talvez a mais 
melhor narrativa histórica do revival de UMWA penned no formulário 
lyrical por um mineiro de carvão anterior Africano-Americano chamado 
"tio George" Jones. Jones tinha começado trabalhar como um 
mineiro em 1889 na idade dezessete mas em 1914 o blindness forçou-o 
fora das minas de Alabama. Long sabido para his que canta em 
choirs da igreja, para baixo nas minas, e na linha de piquete. 
Este de Jones "é que a união feita" expressado não somente o 
sentido dos mineiros do papel que Roosevelt e Lewis jogaram no revival
da união; também captura belamente um sentido da 
transformação quando os mineiros "começaram a união para trás 
outra vez!"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La rinascita improvvisa dei minatori uniti 
dell'America in 1933 era una storia notevole. In 1932 ritardati 
il UMWA era praticamente defunct, tuttavia entro la caduta di 1933 era
nella posizione più forte nella relativa storia. Forse la 
descrizione storica migliore della rinascita di UMWA si è rinchiusa 
nella forma lyrical da un ex minatore delle miniere di carbone 
Africano-Americano chiamato "zio George" Jones. Jones aveva 
iniziato il funzionamento come minatore in 1889 all'età diciassette 
ma in 1914 la cecità lo ha espulso dalle miniere dell'Alabama. 
Desideri saputo suo che canta nei choirs della chiesa, giù 
nelle miniere e sulla riga di picchetto. Questo del Jones "è 
che cosa l'unione fatta" non soltanto espresso il senso dei minatori 
del ruolo che Roosevelt e Lewis hanno giocato nella rinascita del 
sindacato; egualmente blocca in modo bello un senso della 
trasformazione quando i minatori "hanno ottenuto ancora l'unione 
indietro!"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ξαφνική αναγέννηση των ενωμένων εργαζομένων 
ορυχείου της Αμερικής το 1933 ήταν μια αξιοπρόσεκτη ιστορία. 
Στα τέλη του 1932 το UMWA ήταν σχεδόν defunct, όμως
από το φθινόπωρο του 1933 ήταν στην ισχυρότερη θέση στην 
ιστορία του. Ίσως το καλύτερο ιστορικό αφήγημα της 
αναγέννησης UMWA περιφράχτηκε με λυρική μορφή από έναν 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικό προηγούμενο ανθρακωρύχο αποκαλούμενο 
"θείο George" Jones. Το Jones είχε αρχίσει την 
εργασία ως ανθρακωρύχο το 1889 στην ηλικία δεκαεπτά αλλά το 
1914 η τύφλωση τον ανάγκασε από τα ορυχεία της Αλαμπάμα. 
Πολύ γνωστός για το τραγούδι του στις χορωδίες εκκλησιών, 
κάτω από στα ορυχεία, και στη γραμμή στύλων. Αυτό των 
Jones "είναι τι η ένωση που έγινε" όχι μόνο εξέφρασε την 
αίσθηση των ανθρακωρύχων του ρόλου που Roosevelt και Lewis 
διαδραμάτισαν στην αναγέννηση ένωσης  επίσης υπέροχα 
συλλαμβάνει μια αίσθηση του μετασχηματισμού όταν πήραν οι 
ανθρακωρύχοι "την ένωση πίσω πάλϊ"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El renacimiento repentino de los trabajadores de 
mina unidos de América en 1933 era una historia notable. En 
finales de 1932 el UMWA era prácticamente difunto, con todo por la 
caída de 1933 estaba en la posición más fuerte de su historia. 
Quizás la mejor narrativa histórica del renacimiento de UMWA 
fue encerrada en forma lírica por un minero de carbón anterior 
Africano-Americano llamado "tío George" Jones. Jones había 
comenzado el trabajo como minero en 1889 en la edad diecisiete pero en
1914 la ceguera lo forzó fuera de las minas de Alabama. Desee 
sabido el suyo que canta en coros de la iglesia, abajo en las minas, y
en la línea de piquete. Esto de Jones "es lo que la unión 
hecha" no solamente expresado el sentido de los mineros del papel que 
Roosevelt y Lewis jugaron en el renacimiento de la unión; 
también captura maravillosamente un sentido de la 
transformación cuando los mineros "consiguieron la unión detrás 
otra vez!"</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087111</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104688</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/this-is-what-the-union-done-the-story-of-the-united-mine-workers-of-america-in-song</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
