<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105807</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105807</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087138</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Traveler John Ball Visits Hawaii in 1833.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reisend-John Kugel besichtigt Hawaii 1833.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La boule de John de voyageur visite Hawaï en 1833.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A esfera de John do viajante visita Havaí em 1833.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La sfera del John del viaggiatore visita l'Hawai in
1833.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ταξιδιώτης John Ball Visits Χαβάη το 1833.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La bola de Juan de las hojas de ruta (traveler) 
visita Hawaii en 1833.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">John Ball was a lawyer, businessman, educator, civic leader, and traveler who was born on the Vermont frontier in 1794. Ball escaped the life of his father's farm to study at Dartmouth College. He then practiced law, taught, and eventually settled in Grand Rapids and became a Michigan state legislator and a founder of the state's school system. Before settling down, however, he led a life of great adventure. In 1832 Ball joined an expedition to Oregon, but tiring of Oregon--and suffering from the "ague"he mentions here--he boarded a Hudson Bay Company ship bound for Hawaii (or the Sandwich Islands, as they were called then). He landed in Honolulu on December 22, 1833. In Hawaii Ball observed the interactions among the native Hawaiians, Chinese, Japanese, and American missionaries, merchants and diplomats. This selection comes from an autobiography Ball wrote at age eighty.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">John Kugel war ein Rechtsanwalt, ein Geschäftsmann, ein 
Erzieher, ein bürgerlicher Führer und ein Reisendes, das auf der 
Vermont Grenze 1794 getragen wurde. Kugel entging der 
Lebensdauer des Bauernhofes seines Vaters zur Studie an der Dartmouth 
Hochschule. Er dann übte Gesetz, unterrichtete und schließlich
rechnete in großartigem Rapids ab und wurde ein Michigan 
Zustandgesetzgeber und ein Gründer des Schulsystems des Zustandes. 
Bevor er unten jedoch vereinbarte führte er eine Lebensdauer 
des großen Abenteuers. die Kugel 1832, die einer Expedition 
nach Oregon, aber Ermüden von Oregon verbunden wurde -- und unter den
"ague"he Erwähnungen hier leiden -- er, verschalte ein Hudson- 
Bayfirmaschiff, das für Hawaii gesprungen wurde (oder die 
Sandwich-Inseln, wie sie dann benannt wurden). Er landete in 
Honolulu an Dezember 22, 1833. In Hawaii beobachtete Kugel die 
Interaktionen unter den gebürtigen Hawaiianern, der Chinese, der 
Japaner und amerikanischen die Missionare, die Kaufleute und die 
Diplomaten. Diese Auswahl kommt von einer Autobiographie Kugel 
schrieb an Alter achtzig.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La boule de John était un avocat, un homme d'affaires, un
éducateur, une amorce civique, et un voyageur qui a été soutenu sur
la frontière du Vermontn en 1794. La boule a échappé à la 
vie de la ferme de son père à l'étude à l'université de 
Dartmouth. Il a alors pratiqué la loi, l'a enseigné, et par la
suite a soldé le compte dans Rapids grand et est devenue un 
législateur d'état du Michigan et un fondateur du système scolaire 
d'état. Avant de se fixer, cependant, il a mené une vie de 
grande aventure. En la boule 1832 jointive une expédition en 
Orégon, mais fatiguer de l'Orégon -- et souffrance des "mentions de 
fièvre paludéenne ici -- il a monté à bord d'un bateau de compagnie de 
compartiment de Hudson lié pour Hawaï (ou les îles de sandwich, 
comme ils se sont appelés alors). Il a débarqué à Honolulu 
22 décembre 1833. En Hawaï la boule a observé les 
interactions parmi les Hawaïens indigènes, le Chinois, le Japonais, 
et les missionnaires, les négociants et les diplomates américains. 
Cette sélection vient d'une boule d'autobiographie a écrit à 
l'âge quatre-vingts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A esfera de John era um advogado, um homem de negócios, 
um educador, um condutor civil, e um viajante que fosse carregado na 
fronteira de Vermont em 1794. A esfera escapou da vida da 
fazenda do seu pai ao estudo na faculdade de Dartmouth. Então 
praticou a lei, ensinou-a, e eventualmente estabeleciu-se em Rapids 
grande e transformou-se um legislator do estado de Michigan e um 
founder do sistema de escola de estado. Antes de estabelecir-se 
para baixo, entretanto, conduziu a uma vida da aventura grande. 
Na esfera 1832 juntada uma expedição a Oregon, mas cansar-se 
de Oregon -- e sofrer do "dos mentions ague"he aqui -- boarded um 
navio da companhia da baía de Hudson limitado para Havaí (ou os 
consoles do sanduíche, como foram chamados então). Aterrou em 
Honolulu dezembro em 22, 1833. Em Havaí a esfera observou as 
interações entre os hawaiians nativos, o chinês, o japonês, e os 
missionários, os comerciantes e os diplomatas americanos. Esta 
seleção vem de uma esfera do autobiography escreveu na idade eighty.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La sfera del John era un avvocato, un uomo d'affari, un 
educatore, un capo civico e un viaggiatore che è stato 
riguardato la frontiera del Vermont in 1794. La sfera ha 
fuoriuscito la durata del podere del suo padre allo studio 
all'università di Dartmouth. Allora si è esercitato nella 
legge, ha insegnato e finalmente si è depositato in grande Rapids e 
si è transformato in nel Michigan dichiara il legislatore e un
fondatore del sistema scolastico di dichiarare. Prima della 
sedimentazione giù, tuttavia, ha condotto una durata dell'avventura 
grande. In sfera 1832 unita una spedizione nell'Oregon, ma 
stancarsi dell'Oregon -- e soffrire "dalle menzioni del ague"he qui --
si è imbarcato su una nave dell'azienda della baia di Hudson limitata
per l'Hawai (o le isole del panino, come allora sono stati chiamati). 
Ha atterrato a Honolulu il 22 dicembre 1833. In Hawai la 
sfera ha osservato le interazioni fra i hawaiians natali, il 
cinese, il giapponese ed i missionari americani, i commercianti 
ed i diplomatici. Questa selezione viene da una sfera del 
autobiography ha scritto all'età ottanta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ιοχν Ball ήταν δικηγόρος, επιχειρηματίας, 
εκπαιδευτικός, πολιτικός ηγέτης, και ταξιδιώτης που γεννήθηκε στα
σύνορα του Βερμόντ στη σφαίρα 1794, που δραπέτευσαν η ζωή του 
αγροκτήματος του πατέρα του στη μελέτη στο κολλέγιο Dartmouth. 
Ασκησε έπειτα το νόμο, δίδαξε, και εγκατέστησε τελικά σε 
μεγάλο Rapids και έγινε κρατικός νομοθέτης του Μίτσιγκαν και 
ιδρυτής του συστήματος κρατικών σχολείων. Πρίν εγκαθιστά 
κάτω από, εντούτοις, οδήγησε μια ζωή της μεγάλης περιπέτειας. 
Το 1832 η σφαίρα ένωσε μια αποστολή στο Όρεγκον, αλλά 
κούραση του Όρεγκον -- και να πάσσει από το "ague"he αναφέρει 
εδώ -- επιβιβάστηκε σε ένα σκάφος επιχείρησης κόλπου Χάντσον 
που δεσμεύθηκε για τη Χαβάη (ή τα νησιά σάντουιτς, όπως 
κλήθηκαν έπειτα). Προσγειώθηκε στη Χονολουλού στις 22 
Δεκεμβρίου, 1833. Στη Χαβάη η σφαίρα παρατήρησε τις 
αλληλεπιδράσεις μεταξύ των εγγενών κατοίκων της Χαβάης, των 
Κινέζων, των Ιαπώνων, και των αμερικανικών ιεραποστόλων, των 
εμπόρων και των διπλωματών. Αυτή η επιλογή προέρχεται από 
μια σφαίρα αυτοβιογραφιών έγραψε στην ηλικία ογδόντα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La bola de Juan era abogado, un hombre de negocios, 
educador, un arranque de cinta cívico, y las hojas de ruta (traveler)
que nacieron en la frontera de Vermont en 1794. La bola escapó 
la vida de la granja de su padre al estudio en la universidad de 
Dartmouth. Él después practicó ley, la enseñó, y eventual 
colocó en Rapids magnífico e hizo legislador del estado de Michigan 
y un fundador del sistema de la escuela pública. Antes de 
colocar abajo, sin embargo, él condujo una vida de la gran aventura. 
En la bola 1832 unida una expedición a Oregon, pero cansancio 
de Oregon -- y sufrimiento de las "menciones del ague"he aquí -- él 
subió a una nave de la compañía de la bahía de Hudson limitada 
para Hawaii (o las islas del emparedado, como entonces fueron 
llamados). Él aterrizó en Honolulu 22 de diciembre de 1833.
En Hawaii la bola observó las interacciones entre los hawaiians
nativos, el chino, el japonés, y los misionarios, los comerciantes y 
los diplomatas americanos. Esta selección viene de una bola de 
la autobiografía escribió en la edad ochenta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087138</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105807</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/traveler-john-ball-visits-hawaii-in-1833</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
