<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104274</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104274</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202542</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">See How They Run! The 100 Meter Dash</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sehen Sie, Wie Sie Laufen! Der 100 
Meter-Gedankenstrich</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voyez Comment Elles Fonctionnent ! Le Tiret 
De 100 Mètres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Veja Como Funcionam! O Traço De 100 
Medidores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Veda Come Funzionano! Il Precipitare Dei 100
Tester</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δείτε πώς τρέχουν! Η εξόρμηση 100 
μέτρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Vea Cómo Se ejecutan! La Rociada De 100 
Contadores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Middle level students will collect times as they run the 100 meter dash. These times will be depicted through various graphic representations (bar, circle, histogram). Times will be compared to current world records for the 100 meters. Students will decide which Math class ran fastest and support that choice in short essay form. They will also try to determine the faster gender based on the data collected. This lesson plan is a unit filled with related lesson plans. One or two parts of this project could be completed as a stand-alone lesson, or the entire set of activities and extensions could be completed for an involved, integrated unit.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mittlere waagerecht ausgerichtete Kursteilnehmer 
sammeln Zeiten, wie sie den 100-Meter-Gedankenstrich laufen lassen. 
Diese Zeiten werden durch verschiedene graphische Darstellungen 
bildlich dargestellt (Stab, Kreis, Histogramm). Zeiten werden 
mit aktuellen Weltrekorden für die 100 Meter verglichen. 
Kursteilnehmer entscheiden, welche Mathekategorie am schnellsten
und Support diese Wahl in der kurzen Versuchform lief. Sie 
versuchen auch, das schnellere Geschlecht festzustellen, das auf den 
gesammelten Daten basiert. Dieser Lektionplan ist eine 
Maßeinheit, die mit in Verbindung stehenden Lektionplänen gefüllt 
wird. Ein oder zwei Teile dieses Projektes konnten als 
unabhängige Lektion durchgeführt werden, oder das gesamte Set von 
Aktivitäten und von Extensionen könnte für eine beteiligte, 
integrierte Maßeinheit durchgeführt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants de niveau moyens rassembleront des 
périodes comme ils exécutent le tiret de 100 mètres. Ces 
temps seront dépeints par de diverses représentations graphiques 
(barre, cercle, histogramme). Des temps seront comparés aux 
enregistrements actuels du monde pour les 100 mètres. Les 
étudiants décideront quelle classe de maths a fonctionné le plus 
rapidement et support ce choix sous la forme courte d'essai. Ils
essayeront également de déterminer le genre plus rapide basé sur 
les données rassemblées. Ce plan de leçon est une unité 
remplie de plans relatifs de leçon. Un ou deux parts de ce 
projet pourraient être terminées comme leçon autonome, ou 
l'ensemble entier d'activités et d'extensions pourrait être terminé
pour une unité impliquée et intégrée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes nivelados médios coletarão épocas
como funcionam o traço de 100 medidores. Estes tempos serão 
descritos através das várias respresentações gráficas (barra, 
círculo, histograma). Os tempos serão comparados aos registros
de mundo atuais para os 100 medidores. Os estudantes 
decidir-se-ão que classe do math funcionou o mais rapidamente e 
sustentação essa escolha no formulário curto do essay. 
Tentarão também determinar o gender mais rápido baseado nos 
dados coletados. Esta planta da lição é uma unidade enchida 
com as plantas relacionadas da lição. Uma ou dois porções 
deste projeto poderiam ser terminadas como uma lição autônoma, ou o
jogo inteiro das atividades e das extensões poderia ser terminado 
para uma unidade involvida, integrada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi livellati centrali raccoglieranno i 
periodi come fanno funzionare il precipitare dei 100 tester. 
Questi tempi saranno descritti attraverso le varie 
rappresentazioni grafiche (barra, cerchio, istogramma). I tempi 
saranno confrontati ai record di mondo correnti per i 100 tester. 
Gli allievi decideranno quale codice categoria di per la 
matematica ha funzionato il più velocemente e supporto quella scelta 
nella forma corta di saggio. Egualmente proveranno a determinare
il genere più veloce basato sui dati raccolti. Questo programma
di lezione è un'unità riempita di programmi relativi di lezione. 
Una o due parte di questo progetto potrebbe essere completata 
come lezione autonoma, o l'intero insieme delle attività e delle 
estensioni potrebbe essere completato per un'unità implicata e 
integrata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι μέσοι σπουδαστές επιπέδων θα συλλέξουν τους 
χρόνους καθώς τρέχουν την εξόρμηση 100 μέτρων. Αυτοί οι
χρόνοι θα απεικονιστούν μέσω των διάφορων γραφικών 
αντιπροσωπεύσεων (ράβδος, κύκλος, ιστόγραμμο). Οι χρόνοι θα
συγκριθούν με τα παρόντα παγκόσμια αρχεία για τα 100 μέτρα. 
Οι σπουδαστές θα αποφασίσουν ποια κλάση Math έτρεξε ο 
γρηγορότερα και υποστήριξη που η επιλογή δοκιμάζει εν ολίγοις τη 
μορφή. Θα προσπαθήσουν επίσης να καθορίσουν γρηγορότερο το 
βασισμένο στο φύλο στα στοιχεία συλλεχθέντα. Αυτό το 
σχέδιο μαθήματος είναι μια μονάδα που γεμίζουν με τα σχετικά 
σχέδια μαθήματος. Ένα ή δύο μέρη αυτού του προγράμματος 
θα μπορούσαν να ολοκληρωθούν ως αυτόνομο μάθημα, ή ολόκληρο 
σύνολο δραστηριοτήτων και οι επεκτάσεις θα μπορούσαν να 
ολοκληρωθούν για μια περιληφθείσα, ενσωματωμένη μονάδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes llanos medios recogerán épocas 
como ejecutan la rociada de 100 contadores. Estos tiempos serán
representados a través de las varias representaciones gráficas 
(barra, círculo, histograma). Los tiempos serán comparados a 
los expedientes de mundo actuales para los 100 contadores. Los 
estudiantes decidirán qué clase de la matemáticas se ejecutó lo 
más rápidamente posible y ayuda esa opción en forma corta del 
ensayo. También intentarán determinar el género más rápido 
basado en los datos recogidos. Este plan de la lección es una 
unidad llenada de planes relacionados de la lección. Una o dos 
porciones de este proyecto se podrían terminar como lección 
independiente, o el conjunto entero de actividades y de extensiones se
podría terminar para una unidad implicada, integrada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:HOLLY SMITH
FN:HOLLY SMITH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202542</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104274</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/see-how-they-run-the-100-meter-dash</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
