<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104300</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104300</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205909</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Portraits, Visual and Written</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Portraits, sichtlich und geschrieben</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Verticales, visuel et écrit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Retratos, visual e escrito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ritratti, visivo e scritto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πορτρέτα, οπτικός και γραπτός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Retratos, visual y escrito</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features Louisa May Alcott and Samuel Clemens. See excerpts from Alcott's girlhood journal and Little Women. Read Clemens' explanation of his white suit in Mark Twain's Autobiography and the last chapter of Tom Sawyer, where Huck Finn has fled the Widow Douglas's civilizing influence. Help students see that their own lives and views can be a basis for creative writing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Louisa mögen Alcott und Samuel Clemens. 
Sehen Sie Excerpts vom girlhood Alcotts zu lagern und von den 
kleinen Frauen. Lesen Sie Erklärung Clemens' seiner weißen 
Klage in der Autobiographie und im letzten Kapitel Markierung Twains 
von Tom Sawyer, in dem Huck Finn den des Witwe Douglas zivilisierenden
Einfluß geflohen hat. Hilfe Kursteilnehmer sehen, daß ihre 
eigenen Lebensdauern und Ansichten eine Grundlage für kreatives 
Schreiben sein können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les dispositifs Louisa peuvent Alcott et Samuel 
Clemens. Voir les extraits du girlhood d'Alcott inscrire et des 
petites femmes. Lisez l'explication de Clemens de son costume 
blanc dans l'autobiographie et le dernier chapitre de Twain de marque 
de Tom Sawyer, où la toile à grain d'orge Finn s'est 
sauvée l'influence de civilisation de la Douglas de veuve. Les 
étudiants d'aide voient que les leurs propres vies et vues peuvent 
servir de base à l'écriture créatrice.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as características Louisa podem Alcott e Samuel 
Clemens. Veja excerpts do girlhood de Alcott journal e das 
mulheres pequenas. Leia a explanação de Clemens' de seu terno 
branco no autobiography e no último capítulo de Twain da marca de 
Tom Sawyer, onde o huck Finn fujiu a influência civilizing do Douglas
da viúva. Os estudantes da ajuda vêem que suas próprias vidas
e vistas podem ser uma base para a escrita creativa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le caratteristiche Louisa possono Alcott e Samuel 
Clemens. Veda i brani dal girlhood del Alcott imperniare e dalle
donne piccole. Legga la spiegazione del Clemens del suo vestito 
bianco nel autobiography e nell'ultimo capitolo del Twain del 
contrassegno di Tom Sawyer, dove il huck Finn ha fuggito l'influenza 
di civilizzazione della Douglas della vedova. Gli allievi di 
aiuto vedono che le loro propri vite e punti di vista possono essere 
una base per scrittura creativa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα Louisa Μάιος Alcott
και Samuel Clemens. Δείτε τα αποσπάσματα από 
το περιοδικό girlhood Alcott και τις μικρές γυναίκες. 
Διαβάστε την εξήγηση Clemens του άσπρου κοστουμιού του 
στην αυτοβιογραφία Mark Twain και το τελευταίο κεφάλαιο του 
Tom Sawyer, όπου Huck φινλανδικά έχει φύγει την επιρροή 
εκπολιτισμού του Ντάγκλας χηρών. Οι σπουδαστές οδηγιών 
βλέπουνε ότι οι ζωές και οι όψεις τους μπορούν να είναι 
μια βάση για το δημιουργικό γράψιμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las características Louisa pueden Alcott y Samuel
Clemens. Vea los extractos del girlhood de Alcott meter en 
diario y de pequeñas mujeres. Lea la explicación de Clemens de
su juego blanco en la autobiografía y el capítulo pasado de Twain de
la marca de Tom Sawyer, donde el huck Finn ha huido la influencia de 
civilización de la Douglas de la viuda. Los estudiantes de la 
ayuda ven que sus propias vidas y opiniones pueden ser una base para 
la escritura creativa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205909</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104300</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/portraits-visual-and-written</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
