<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106568</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106568</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205599</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Slavery and Childhood</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sklaverei und Kindheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Esclavage et enfance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Slavery e infância</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Slavery ed infanzia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκλαβιά και παιδική ηλικία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esclavitud y niñez</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson is designed to extend student understanding of the experiences of slaves living in the American, antebellum south. The chosen samples and excerpts from the Documenting the American South collection reflect the childhood of two enslaved people born in America, Harriet Jacobs and Frederick Douglas, and two people born in Africa, Oloudah Equiano and Omar Bin Said. Two knew what it was like to be free before being captured and placed into servitude, and longed to be free again; two were born into slavery and like the two native born Africans had aspirations of freedom. Students are invited to compare their childhood memories with the lives of these children in an effort to make history more human.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion ist konzipiert, um 
Kursteilnehmerverständnis der Erfahrungen der Sklaven auszudehnen, 
die im amerikanischen, antebellum Süden leben. Die gewählten 
Proben und die Excerpts vom Dokumentieren der amerikanischen 
Südansammlung reflektieren die Kindheit von zwei versklavten Leuten, 
die in Amerika, in Harriet Jacobs und in Frederick Douglas und in zwei
Leuten geboren sind in Afrika geboren sind, in Oloudah Equiano und im 
gesagten Omar Sortierfach. Wußten zwei, was es wie frei sein 
sollte, bevor es und plaziert in Versklavung erfaßt wurde, und wieder
gesehnt, um frei zu sein; zwei wurden in Sklaverei getragen und 
wie die zwei gebürtigen geborenen Afrikaner hatte Aspirationen der 
Freiheit. Kursteilnehmer werden eingeladen, ihre 
Kindheitspeicher mit den Leben dieser Kinder in einer Bemühung zu 
vergleichen, Geschichte menschlicher zu bilden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon est conçue pour étendre 
l'arrangement d'étudiant des expériences des esclaves vivant dans 
les sud américains et d'avant-guerre. Les 
échantillons et les extraits choisis provenant de documenter la 
collection du sud américaine reflètent l'enfance de deux 
personnes asservies nées en Amérique, Harriet Jacobs et Frederick 
Douglas, et deux personnes nées en Afrique, Oloudah Equiano et coffre
d'Omar dit. Deux ont su comme ce qu'il devait être 
libre avant d'être capturé et placé dans la servitude, et 
désiré ardemment pour être libre encore ; deux ont été 
soutenus dans l'esclavage et comme les deux Africains nés indigènes 
a eu des aspirations de la liberté. Des étudiants sont 
invités à comparer leurs mémoires d'enfance aux vies de ces enfants
dans un effort de rendre l'histoire plus humaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição é projetada estender a compreensão 
do estudante das experiências dos escravos que vivem no sul 
americano, antebellum. As amostras e os excerpts escolhidos de 
documentar a coleção sul americana refletem a infância de dois 
povos enslaved carregados em América, em Harriet Jacobs e em 
Frederick Douglas, e em dois povos carregados em África, em Oloudah 
Equiano e em escaninho de Omar dito. Dois souberam o que devia 
como estar livre antes de ser capturado e colocado no servitude, e 
longed para estar livre outra vez; dois foram carregados no 
slavery e como os dois africanos carregados nativos teve aspirations 
da liberdade. Os estudantes são convidados comparar suas 
memórias da infância com as vidas destas crianças em um esforço 
fazer o history mais humano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione è destinata per estendere la 
comprensione dell'allievo delle esperienze negli schiavi che vivono 
nel sud americano e antebellum. I campioni ed i brani scelti 
dalla documentazione dell'accumulazione del sud americana riflettono 
l'infanzia di due genti asservite sopportate in America, Harriet 
Jacobs e Frederick Douglas e due genti sopportate in Africa, Oloudah 
Equiano e lo scomparto di Omar detto. Due hanno conosciuto che 
cosa doveva come essere libero prima di essere bloccato e disposto nel
servitude e desiderato ancora per essere libero; due sono stati 
sopportati in slavery e come i due Africani sopportati natali ha avuto
aspirazioni della libertà. Gli allievi sono invitati a 
paragonare le loro memorie di infanzia alle vite di questi bambini in 
uno sforzo rendere la storia più umana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα έχει ως σκοπό να επεκτείνει την 
κατανόηση σπουδαστών της εμπειρίας των σκλάβων που ζουν στον 
αμερικανικό, προπολεμικό νότο. Τα επιλεγμένα δείγματα και 
τα αποσπάσματα από την τεκμηρίωση η αμερικανική νότια συλλογή 
απεικονίζουν την παιδική ηλικία δύο υποδουλωμένων ανθρώπων 
γεννημένων στην Αμερική, το Harriet Jacobs και Frederick 
Ντάγκλας, και δύο ανθρώπους γεννημένους στην Αφρική, Oloudah 
Equiano και Omar Bin Said. Δύο ήξεραν τι που 
επρόκειτο όπως να είσαι ελεύθερο πρίν συλλαμβάνεται και 
τοποθέτηση στη δουλεία, και για να είναι ελεύθερα πάλι  
δύο γεννήθηκαν στη σκλαβιά και όπως τους δύο εγγενείς 
γεννημένους Αφρικανούς είχε τις φιλοδοξίες της ελευθερίας. 
Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται για να συγκρίνουν τις μνήμες 
παιδικής ηλικίας τους με τις ζωές αυτών των παιδιών σε μια 
προσπάθεια να κατασταθεί η ιστορία πιό ανθρώπινη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección se diseña para ampliar la 
comprensión del estudiante de las experiencias de los esclavos que 
viven en el sur americano, antebellum. Las muestras y los 
extractos elegidos de documentar la colección del sur americana 
reflejan la niñez de dos personas esclavizadas llevadas en América, 
Harriet Jacobs y Frederick Douglas, y dos personas llevadas en 
África, Oloudah Equiano y el compartimiento de Omar dicho. Dos 
sabían como cuál debía estar libre antes de ser capturado y 
colocado en servidumbre, y deseado para estar libre otra vez; 
dos fueron llevados en esclavitud y como los dos africanos 
llevados nativos tenía aspiraciones de la libertad. Se invita a
los estudiantes que comparen sus memorias de la niñez con las vidas 
de estos niños en un esfuerzo de hacer historia más humana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MEGHAN MCGLINN
FN:MEGHAN MCGLINN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205599</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106568</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/slavery-and-childhood</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
