<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105123</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105123</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086248</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hot Chocolate: A World War I "Canteen Girl" Writes Home</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Heiße Schokolade: Ein Erster Weltkrieg 
"Kantine-Mädchen" Schreibt Nach Hause</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chocolat Chaud : Une Première Guerre 
Mondiale "Fille de Cantine" Écrit À la maison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Chocolate Quente: Um World.war.i Da "Menina 
Cantina" Escreve Para casa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cioccolato Caldo: Un World.war.i "Ragazza 
Dello Spaccio di bevande" Scrive A casa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καυτή σοκολάτα: Ένας παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι 
"κορίτσι καντίνων" γράφει τη "Οικία"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Chocolate Caliente: Una Primera Guerra 
Mundial "Muchacha De la Cantina" Escribe A casa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The canteen girl stood as symbol of American volunteerism and femininity in World War I. Sponsored by the YMCA and other charitable organizations, canteens were efforts to maintain soldiers' morale and to keep them from vice. In Uncensored Letters of a Canteen Girl , Kathleen Morse described the challenges of dispensing hot chocolate and planning entertainments with sparse supplies. At the same time, her letters revealed the less tangible work of the canteen girls: to boost morale by providing reminders of the comforts of home and by representing the sweethearts, sisters, and mothers left behind.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Kantinemädchen, das als Symbol des 
amerikanischen volunteerism und der Weiblichkeit im Weltkrieg I. 
Sponsored durch das YMCA und andere barmherzige Organisationen 
gestanden wurde, Kantinen waren Bemühungen, Moral der Soldaten 
beizubehalten und sie vom Laster zu halten. In unzensierten 
Zeichen eines Kantine-Mädchens, beschrieb Kathleen Morse die 
Herausforderungen des Zuführens der heißen Schokolade und der 
Planung von von Unterhaltungen mit spärlichem Zubehör. 
Gleichzeitig deckte sie Zeichen die weniger fühlbare Arbeit der
Kantinemädchen auf: um Moral indem sie Anzeigen des Komforts 
des Hauses und indem das Darstellen der Schatze aufzuladen verließ, 
Schwestern und Mütter nach zur Verfügung stellten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La fille de cantine tenue comme symbole de 
volontarisme et de féminité américains dans la guerre mondiale I. 
Sponsored à côté du YMCA et d'autres organismes charitables, 
cantines étaient des efforts de mettre à jour le moral des soldats 
et de les garder du vice. Dans les lettres non censurées d'une 
fille de cantine, Kathleen Morse a décrit les défis de distribuer le
chocolat chaud et de projeter des divertissements avec les 
approvisionnements clairsemés. En même temps, elle des lettres
a indiqué le travail moins réel des filles de cantine : pour 
amplifier le moral en fournissant des rappels des conforts de la 
maison et en représentant les amoureux, les soeurs, et les mères ont
laissé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A menina da cantina estada como o símbolo do 
volunteerism e do femininity americanos na guerra de mundo I. 
Patrocinar pelo YMCA e por outras organizações charitable, cantinas 
era esforços manter o morale dos soldados e mantê-los do vice. 
Em letras uncensored de uma menina da cantina, Kathleen Morse 
descreveu os desafios de dispensar o chocolate quente e de planear 
entertainments com fontes escassas. Ao mesmo tempo, letras 
revelou o trabalho mais menos tangible das meninas da cantina: 
para impulsionar o morale fornecendo lembretes dos confortos da 
HOME e representando os sweethearts, as irmãs, e as matrizes sairam 
atrás.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La ragazza dello spaccio di bevande partecipata 
come il simbolo del volunteerism e della femminilità americani nella 
guerra mondiale I. Sponsored dal YMCA e da altre organizzazioni 
caritatevoli, spacci di bevande era sforzi effettuare il morale dei 
soldati e mantenerli da vizio. Nelle lettere non censurate di 
una ragazza dello spaccio di bevande, Kathleen Morse ha descritto le 
sfide di erogazione del cioccolato caldo e di progettazione degli 
intrattenimenti con i rifornimenti sparsi. Allo stesso tempo, 
lei lettere ha rivelato il lavoro meno definito delle ragazze dello 
spaccio di bevande: per amplificare il morale fornendo i ricordi
delle comodità della sede e rappresentando gli innamorati, le sorelle
e le madri hanno lasciato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">_ ο καντίνα κορίτσι στέκομαι ως σύμβολο αμερικανικός 
εθελοντισμός και θηλυκότητα κόσμοσπόλεμοσΙ. Υποστηρίζω από ο 
ΥΜΘΑ και άλλος φιλανθρωπικός οργάνωση, καντίνα είμαι προσπάθεια 
να διατηρώ στρατιώτης ηθικό και να κρατώ αυτός από κακία. 
Στις μη λογοκρηθείσες επιστολές ενός κοριτσιού καντίνων, η 
Kathleen Morse περιέγραψε τις προκλήσεις της διανομής της 
καυτής σοκολάτας και του προγραμματισμού των ψυχαγωγιών με τις 
αραιές προμήθειες. Συγχρόνως, οι επιστολές της αποκάλυψαν 
τη λιγότερο απτή εργασία των κοριτσιών καντίνων: για να 
ωθηθεί το ηθικό με την παροχή των υπενθυμίσεων των ανέσεων του 
σπιτιού και με την αντιπροσώπευση των αγαπημένων, οι αδελφές, και 
οι μητέρες έφυγαν πίσω.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La muchacha de la cantina parada como símbolo del
volunteerism y de la feminidad americanos en la guerra mundial I. 
Sponsored por el YMCA y otras organizaciones caritativas, cantinas era
esfuerzos de mantener la moral de los soldados y de guardarlas de 
vicio. En cartas no censuradas de una muchacha de la cantina, 
Kathleen Morse describió los desafíos de dispensar el chocolate 
caliente y de planear hospitalidades con las fuentes escasas. En
el mismo tiempo, ella las cartas reveló el trabajo menos tangible de 
las muchachas de la cantina: para alzar moral proporcionando a 
los recordatorios de las comodidades del hogar y representando a los 
amores, las hermanas, y las madres se fueron detrás.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086248</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105123</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hot-chocolate-a-world-war-i-canteen-girl-writes-home</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
