<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104489</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104489</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1651176672</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AP Physics B</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AP Physik B</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Physique B de AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Física B do Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fisica B di Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φυσική β AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Física B del Ap</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This curriculum covers all of the material outlined by the College Board as necessary to prepare students to pass the AP Physics B exam. This course is divided into two semesters and is designed to acquaint you with topics in classical and modern physics. The first semester discusses topics in Newtonian mechanics including: kinematics, laws of motion, work and energy, systems of particles, momentum, circular motion, oscillations, and gravitation. The first semester concludes with topics in fluid mechanics, thermal physics, and kinetic theory. The second semester discusses the topics of electricity and magnetism, waves and optics, and atomic and nuclear physics. The course emphasizes problem solving, and there are numerous interactive examples throughout. You will also gain laboratory experience through interactive lab simulations and wet labs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Lehrplan umfaßt die ganze Material, das 
durch das Hochschulgremium wie benötigt, Kursteilnehmer 
vorzubereiten, die Prüfung der AP Physik zu führen B umrissen wird. 
Dieser Kurs ist in zwei Semester geteilt und ist konzipiert, um 
Sie mit Themen in der klassischen und modernen Physik mitzuteilen. 
Das erste Semester behandelt Themen in den newtonischen 
Mechanikern einschließlich: Kinematik, Gesetze der Bewegung, 
Arbeit und Energie, Systeme der Partikel, Momentum, kreisförmige 
Bewegung, Pendelbewegungen und Gravitation. Das erste Semester 
folgert mit Themen in den flüssigen Mechanikern, in der thermischen 
Physik und in der kinetischen Theorie. Das zweite Semester 
behandelt die Themen von Elektrizität und Magnetismus, Wellen und 
Optik und Atom- und Kernphysik. Der Kurs hebt das Lösen von 
Problemen hervor, und es gibt zahlreiche interaktive Beispiele 
gänzlich. Sie gewinnen auch Laborerfahrung durch interaktive 
Laborsimulationen und nasse Labors.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce programme d'études couvre tout le matériel 
tracé les grandes lignes par le conseil d'université selon les 
besoins pour préparer des étudiants passer l'examen de la physique B
de AP. Ce cours est divisé en deux semestres et est conçu pour
vous mettre au courant des sujets dans la physique classique et 
moderne. Le premier semestre discute des sujets dans la 
mécanique newtonienne comprenant : cinématique, lois de 
mouvement, travail et énergie, systèmes des particules, élan, 
mouvement circulaire, oscillations, et attraction universelle. 
Le premier semestre conclut avec des sujets dans la mécanique 
liquide, la physique thermique, et la théorie cinétique. Le 
deuxième semestre discute les sujets de l'électricité et 
magnétisme, des vagues et systeme optique, et physique atomique et 
nucléaire. Le cours souligne la résolution des problèmes, et 
il y a de nombreux exemples interactifs partout. Vous acquerrez 
également l'expérience de laboratoire par des simulations 
interactives de laboratoire et des laboratoires humides.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este curriculum cobre todo o material esboçado 
pela placa de faculdade como necessário preparar estudantes para 
passar o exam da física B do AP. Este curso é dividido em dois
semesters e projetado familiarizá-lo com os tópicos na física 
classical e moderna. O primeiro semester discute tópicos nos 
mecânicos newtonian including: kinematics, leis do movimento, 
trabalho e energia, sistemas das partículas, momentum, movimento 
circular, oscilações, e gravitação. O primeiro semester 
concli com tópicos nos mecânicos fluidos, na física térmica, e na 
teoria cinética. O segundo semester discute os tópicos da 
eletricidade e o magnetismo, ondas e sistema ótico, e física 
atômica e nuclear. O curso emfatiza resolver de problema, e há
uns exemplos interativos numerosos throughout. Você ganhará 
também a experiência do laboratório através das simulações 
interativas do laboratório e dos laboratórios molhados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma di studi tratta tutto il 
materiale descritto dal Bordo dell'università come necessario 
preparare gli allievi per passare il exam di fisica B di AP. 
Questo corso è diviso in due semestri ed è destinato per 
informarlo dei soggetti nella fisica classica e moderna. Il 
primo semestre discute i soggetti in meccanici newtoniani compreso: 
cinematica, leggi di movimento, lavoro ed energia, sistemi delle
particelle, quantità di moto, movimento circolare, oscillazioni e 
gravitazione. Il primo semestre conclude con i soggetti in 
meccanici fluidi, nella fisica termica e nella teoria cinetica. 
Il secondo semestre discute i soggetti di elettricità e 
magnetismo, onde ed ottica e la fisica atomica e nucleare. Il 
corso dà risalto alla soluzione dei problemi e ci sono esempi 
interattivi numerosi dappertutto. Egualmente guadagnerete 
l'esperienza del laboratorio attraverso le simulazioni interattive del
laboratorio ed i laboratori bagnati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το πρόγραμμα σπουδών καλύπτει όλο το υλικό που 
περιγράφεται από τον πίνακα κολλεγίου για να προετοιμάσει 
ανάλογα με τις ανάγκες τους σπουδαστές για να περάσει το 
διαγωνισμό φυσικής β AP. Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων 
διαιρείται σε δύο εξάμηνα και σχεδιάζεται για να σας εξοικειώσει 
με τα θέματα στην κλασσική και σύγχρονη φυσική. Το πρώτο 
εξάμηνο συζητά τα θέματα στους νευτώνειους μηχανικούς 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου: kinematics, νόμοι της κίνησης, της 
εργασίας και της ενέργειας, των συστημάτων των μορίων, της ορμής,
της κυκλικής κίνησης, των ταλαντώσεων, και της βαρύτητας. Το
πρώτο εξάμηνο ολοκληρώνει με τα θέματα στους ρευστούς 
μηχανικούς, τη θερμική φυσική, και την κινητική θεωρία. Το 
δεύτερο εξάμηνο συζητά τα θέματα της ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας και 
του μαγνητισμού, τα κύματα και την οπτική, και την ατομική και 
πυρηνική φυσική. Η σειρά μαθημάτων υπογραμμίζει την 
επίλυση προβλήματος, και υπάρχουν πολυάριθμα διαλογικά 
παραδείγματα. Θα αποκτήσετε επίσης την εργαστηριακή 
εμπειρία μέσω των διαλογικών προσομοιώσεων εργαστηρίων και των 
υγρών εργαστηρίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de estudios cubre todo el material 
contorneado por la tarjeta de universidad como necesaria para preparar
a estudiantes para aprobar el examen de la física B del AP. 
Este curso se divide en dos semestres y se diseña para 
conocerle de asuntos en la física clásica y moderna. El primer
semestre discute asuntos en los mecánicos neutonianos incluyendo: 
cinemática, leyes del movimiento, trabajo y energía, sistemas 
de partículas, ímpetu, movimiento circular, oscilaciones, y 
gravitación. El primer semestre concluye con asuntos en los 
mecánicos flúidos, la física termal, y la teoría cinética. 
El segundo semestre discute los asuntos de la electricidad y 
magnetismo, las ondas y la óptica, y física atómica y nuclear. 
El curso acentúa solucionar de problema, y hay ejemplos 
interactivos numerosos en todas partes. Usted también ganará 
experiencia del laboratorio a través de simulaciones interactivas del
laboratorio y de laboratorios mojados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNKNOWN
FN:UNKNOWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1651176672</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104489</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ap-physics-b</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
