<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106046</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106046</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205661</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Literature and Poetry Community Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Literatur-und Poesie-Einkaufszentrum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre social de littérature et de poésie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro de comunidade da literatura e da poesia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ritrovo comunale di poesia e della letteratura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λογοτεχνία και κοινοτικό κέντρο ποίησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro de comunidad de la literatura y de la 
poesía</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a collection of resources about poetry, literature, and writers -- William Blake, Stephen Crane, Mark Twain, Walt Whitman, Langston Hughes, Zora Neale Hurston, and others. Hear Allen Ginsberg, Rita Dove, and Stanley Kunitz talk about their work. Watch videos of Americans discussing their favorite poems. Read a weekly column featuring an American poem. Use the guide to streaming video literature to find webcasts of writers discussing their work.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Ansammlung Betriebsmittel über Poesie, 
Literatur und Verfasser -- William Blake, Stephen Kran, Markierung 
Twain, Walt Whitman, Langston Hughes, Zora Neale Hurston und andere. 
Hören Sie Allen Ginsberg, Rita Taube und Stanley Kunitz sich 
befassen mit ihrer Arbeit. Überwachen Sie videos der 
Amerikaner, die ihre Lieblingsgedichte behandeln. Lesen Sie eine
wöchentliche Spalte, die ein amerikanisches Gedicht kennzeichnet. 
Benutzen Sie die Anleitung zu strömender videoliteratur zu den 
Entdeckung webcasts der Verfasser, die ihre Arbeit behandeln.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une collection de ressources au sujet de la 
poésie, de la littérature, et des auteurs -- William Blake, grue de 
Stephen, marque Twain, Walt Whitman, Langston Hughes, Zora Neale 
Hurston, et d'autres. Entendez Allen Ginsberg, colombe de Rita, 
et Stanley Kunitz parlent de leur travail. Observez les 
videos des Américains discutant leurs poésies préférées. 
Lisez une colonne hebdomadaire comportant une poésie 
américaine. Utilisez le guide de la littérature visuelle 
coulante aux webcasts de trouvaille des auteurs discutant leur 
travail.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma coleção dos recursos sobre a poesia, a 
literatura, e os escritores -- William Blake, guindaste de Stephen, 
marca Twain, Walt Whitman, Langston Hughes, Zora Neale Hurston, e 
outro. Ouça a conversa de Allen Ginsberg, de pomba de Rita, e 
de Stanley Kunitz sobre seu trabalho. Preste atenção a videos 
dos americanos que discutem seus poemas favoritos. Leia uma 
coluna semanal que caracteriza um poema americano. Use a guia à
literatura video fluindo aos webcasts do achado dos escritores que 
discutem seu trabalho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una collezione di risorse circa la poesia, la 
letteratura ed i produttori -- William Blake, gru di Stephen, il 
contrassegno Twain, Walt Whitman, Langston Hughes, Zora Neale Hurston 
ed altri. Senta Allen Ginsberg, colomba di Rita e Stanley Kunitz
parlano del loro lavoro. Guardi i videos degli Americani che 
discutono i loro poems favoriti. Legga una colonna settimanale 
che caratterizza un poem americano. Usi la guida a video 
letteratura effluente ai webcasts del ritrovamento dei produttori che 
discutono il loro lavoro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια συλλογή των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς για την 
ποίηση, τη λογοτεχνία, και τους συγγραφείς -- William Blake, 
stephen Crane, Mark Twain, Walt Whitman, Langston
Hughes, Zora Neale Hurston, και άλλες. Ακούστε 
Αλλεν Ginsberg, τη Ρίτα Dove, και τη συζήτηση του Stanley 
Kunitz για την εργασία τους. Προσέξτε τα βίντεο 
Αμερικανών που συζητούν τα αγαπημένα ποιήματά τους. 
Διαβάστε μια εβδομαδιαία στήλη που χαρακτηρίζει ένα 
αμερικανικό ποίημα. Χρησιμοποιήστε τον οδηγό στη ρέοντας 
τηλεοπτική λογοτεχνία για να βρείτε webcasts των συγγραφέων που
συζητούν την εργασία τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una colección de recursos sobre poesía, 
literatura, y programas de escritura -- Guillermo Blake, grúa de 
Stephen, marca Twain, Walt Whitman, Langston Hughes, Zora Neale 
Hurston, y otros. Oiga Allen Ginsberg, paloma de Rita, y Stanley
Kunitz hablan de su trabajo. Mire los videos de los americanos 
que discuten sus poemas preferidos. Lea una columna semanal que 
ofrece un poema americano. Utilice la guía a la literatura 
video que fluye a los webcasts del hallazgo de los programas de 
escritura que discuten su trabajo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205661</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106046</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/literature-and-poetry-community-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
