<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105392</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105392</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203526</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">ISEE Systems: Why STELLA for Education?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ISEE Systeme: Warum STELLA für Ausbildung?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Systèmes d'ISEE : Pourquoi STELLA pour 
l'éducation ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sistemas de ISEE: Por que STELLA para a 
instrução?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sistemi di ISEE: Perchè STELLA per 
formazione?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συστήματα ISEE: Γιατί ΣΤΕΛΛΑ για την 
εκπαίδευση;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sistemas de ISEE: ¿Por qué STELLA para la 
educación?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This product site established by isse systems outlines STELLA software and the advantages of using it in the classroom. The STELLA software is specifically designed to build students' skills in building understanding. STELLA modeling and graphing software can help engage students more deeply in course material, build deeper and richer understanding of material, develop critical thinking skills, and exercise student's collaborative and communication skills. The site offers a downloadable demonstration of STELLA 8.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Produktsite hergestellt durch Software der isse 
Systeme umreißen STELLA und die Vorteile des Verwendens sie im 
Klassenzimmer. Die STELLA Software ist spezifisch konzipiert, um
Fähigkeiten der Kursteilnehmer im Gebäudeverständnis aufzubauen. 
STELLA, das Software formt und graphisch darstellt, kann helfen,
Kursteilnehmer im Kursmaterial, im tieferen und reicheren Verständnis
des Baus des Materials tiefer sich zu engagieren, kritische denkende 
Fähigkeiten, und des gemeinschaftlichen Übung Kursteilnehmers und 
die Kommunikation Fähigkeiten zu entwickeln. Die Site bietet 
eine downloadabledemonstration von STELLA 8 an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site de produit établi par le logiciel d'ensembles 
STELLA de systèmes d'isse et les avantages de l'utiliser dans la 
salle de classe. Le logiciel de STELLA est spécifiquement 
conçu pour établir les qualifications des étudiants dans 
l'arrangement de bâtiment. STELLA modelant et représentant 
graphiquement le logiciel peut aider à engager des étudiants plus 
profondément dans le matériel de cours, l'arrangement plus profond 
et plus riche de construction du matériel, développer les 
qualifications de pensée critiques, et l'étudiant d'exercice de 
collaboration et les qualifications de transmission. Le site 
offre une démonstration downloadable de STELLA 8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local do produto estabelecido pelo software dos 
esboços STELLA dos sistemas do isse e pelas vantagens de usá-lo na 
sala de aula. O software de STELLA é projetado especificamente 
construir habilidades dos estudantes na compreensão do edifício. 
STELLA que modela e que representa graficamente o software pode 
ajudar acoplar mais profundamente estudantes no material do curso, em 
uma compreensão mais profunda e mais rica da configuração do 
material, para desenvolver habilidades pensando críticas, e estudante
do exercício collaborative e habilidades de uma comunicação. 
O local oferece uma demonstração downloadable de STELLA 8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo del prodotto stabilito dal software dei 
profili STELLA dei sistemi del isse e dai vantaggi di usando 
nell'aula. Il software di STELLA specificamente è destinato per
sviluppare le abilità degli allievi nella comprensione della 
costruzione. STELLA che modella e che rappresenta graficamente 
il software può contribuire ad agganciare gli allievi più 
profondamente nel materiale di corso, nella comprensione più profonda
e più ricca di configurazione del materiale, sviluppare le abilità 
pensanti critiche e l'allievo di esercitazione di collaborazione e le 
abilità di comunicazione. Il luogo offre una dimostrazione 
downloadable di STELLA 8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή προϊόντων που καθιερώνονται από το 
λογισμικό της ΣΤΕΛΛΑ περιγραμμάτων συστημάτων isse και τα 
πλεονεκτήματα το στην τάξη. Το λογισμικό της ΣΤΕΛΛΑ 
σχεδιάζεται συγκεκριμένα για να χτίσει τις δεξιότητες των 
σπουδαστών στην οικοδόμηση της κατανόησης. Η ΣΤΕΛΛΑ που 
διαμορφώνει και που δίνει με γραφική παράσταση το λογισμικό 
μπορεί να βοηθήσει να συμμετέχει τους σπουδαστές πιό βαθειά στο 
υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων, να χτίσουν τη βαθύτερη και πλουσιότερη 
κατανόηση του υλικού, να αναπτύξει τις κρίσιμες δεξιότητες 
σκέψης, και επικοινωνίας του σπουδαστή άσκησης τις συνεργάσιμες 
και δεξιότητες. Η περιοχή προσφέρει μια τηλεκατεγραφόμενη 
επίδειξη της ΣΤΕΛΛΑ 8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio del producto establecido por el software de los
contornos STELLA de los sistemas del isse y las ventajas de usarlo en 
la sala de clase. El software de STELLA se diseña 
específicamente para construir las habilidades de los estudiantes en 
la comprensión del edificio. STELLA que modela y que representa
software gra'ficamente puede ayudar a contratar a estudiantes más 
profundamente a material del curso, a una comprensión más profunda y
más rica de la estructura del material, desarrollar habilidades de 
pensamiento críticas, y el estudiante del ejercicio de colaboración 
y habilidades de la comunicación. El sitio ofrece una 
demostración downloadable de STELLA 8.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203526</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105392</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/isee-systems-why-stella-for-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
