<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106419</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106419</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205915</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Now What a Time: Blues, Gospel, and the Fort Valley Arts Festivals, 1938-1943</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jetzt was eine Zeit: Blau, Evangelium und 
die Fort-Senke-kunst-Festivals, 1938-1943</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Maintenant ce qui un moment : Bleus, 
evangile, et les festivals d'arts de vallée de fort, 1938-1943</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Agora que um momento: Azuis, gospel, e os 
festivals das artes do vale do fort, 1938-1943</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ora che cosa un momento: Azzurri, gospel ed
i Festival Forte di arti della valle, 1938-1943</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τώρα τι ένας χρόνος: Μπλε, Ευαγγέλιο, και τα 
φεστιβάλ τεχνών κοιλάδων οχυρών, 1938-1943</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ahora qué una época: Azul, Evangelio, y 
los festivales de los artes del valle de la fortaleza, 1938-1943</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">consists of sound recordings, primarily blues and gospel songs, and related documentation created by John Wesley Work III in 1941 and by Lewis Jones and Willis Laurence James in March, June, and July 1943 at the folk festival at Fort Valley College (now Fort Valley State University), Fort Valley, Georgia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">besteht aus Tonaufnahmen, hauptsächlich Blau und
Evangeliumliede und die in Verbindung stehenden Unterlagen, die durch 
John Wesley Arbeit III 1941 und durch Lewis Jones und Willis Laurence 
James im März, Juni und Juli 1943 am Volksfestival an der 
Fort-Senke-Hochschule erstellt werden (jetzt 
Fort-Senke-Landesuniversität), Fort-Senke, Georgia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">se compose des enregistrements sonores, 
principalement bleus et chansons d'evangile, et documentation relative
créée par le travail III de John Wesley de 1941 et par Lewis Jones 
et Willis Laurence James en mars, juin, et juillet 1943 au 
festival folklorique à l'université de vallée de fort (maintenant 
université de l'Etat de vallée de fort), vallée de fort, la 
Géorgie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">consiste em gravações sadias, primeiramente 
azuis e canções do gospel, e documentação relacionada criada pelo 
trabalho III de John Wesley em 1941 e por Lewis Jones e por Willis 
Laurence James em março, em junho, e em julho 1943 no festival 
popular na faculdade do vale do fort (agora universidade de estado), 
vale do vale do fort do fort, Geórgia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiste delle registrazioni del suono, 
soprattutto azzurri e canzoni del gospel e documentazione relativa 
creata tramite il lavoro III del John Wesley di 1941 e da Lewis Jones 
e da Willis Laurence James in marzo, giugno e luglio del 1943 al 
festival piega all'università Forte della valle (ora la 
valle Forte Dichiara l'università), la valle 
Forte, la Georgia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποτελείται από τις υγιείς καταγραφές, πρώτιστα μπλε 
και τραγούδια Ευαγγέλιου, και σχετική τεκμηρίωση που 
δημιουργείται από John Wesley Work III το 1941 και 
από Lewis Jones και Willis Laurence james το Μάρτιο, 
τον Ιούνιο, και τον Ιούλιο του 1943 στο λαϊκό φεστιβάλ στο 
κολλέγιο κοιλάδων οχυρών (τώρα κρατικό πανεπιστήμιο κοιλάδων 
οχυρών), κοιλάδα οχυρών, Γεωργία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">consiste en las grabaciones de sonidos, sobre 
todo azul y canciones del evangelio, y documentación relacionada 
creada por el trabajo III de Juan Wesley de 1941 y por Lewis Jones y 
Willis Laurence James en marcha, junio, y julio de 1943 en el festival
popular en la universidad del valle de la fortaleza (ahora universidad
de estado del valle de la fortaleza), valle de la fortaleza, Georgia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205915</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106419</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/now-what-a-time-blues-gospel-and-the-fort-valley-arts-festivals-1938-1943</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
