<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103217</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103217</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206647</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Memory</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Speicher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mémoire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Memória</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Memoria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μνήμη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Memoria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">dissects a sheep brain to show us the anatomy of memory. See works of an artist who paints entirely from memory. (Compare his paintings to photos of places.) Play interactive games that test your memory -- learn ways to improve it. Discover why some things are easier to remember than others (droodles game). Which facial features help us remember a face? Which image of the penny is correct? Try a mnemonic device called elaborative encoding.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zergliedert ein Schafgehirn, um uns die Anatomie 
des Speichers zu zeigen. Sehen Sie Arbeiten eines Künstlers, 
der völlig vom Speicher malt. (vergleichen Sie seine Anstriche 
mit Fotos der Plätze.) Spielen Sie interaktive Spiele, die 
Ihren Speicher prüfen -- erlernen Sie Methoden, ihn zu verbessern. 
Entdecken Sie, warum einige Sachen einfacher sich als andere zu 
erinnern sind (droodles Spiel). Welche Gesichtsmerkmale helfen 
uns, an ein Gesicht uns zu erinnern? Welches Bild des Pennys ist
korrekt? Versuchen Sie eine mnemotechnische Einheit, die 
elaborative kodierung genannt wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dissèque un cerveau de moutons pour nous montrer 
l'anatomie de la mémoire. Voir les travaux d'un artiste qui 
peint entièrement de la mémoire. (comparez ses peintures aux 
photos des endroits.) Jouez les jeux interactifs qui testent 
votre mémoire -- apprenez les voies de l'améliorer. Découvrez
pourquoi il est plus facile se rappeler quelques choses que d'autres 
(jeu de droodles). Quels dispositifs faciaux nous aident à nous
rappeler un visage ? Quelle image du penny est correcte ? 
Essayez un dispositif mnémonique appelé le codage elaborative.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">dissects um cérebro dos carneiros para 
mostrar-nos o anatomy da memória. Veja trabalhos de um artista 
que pinte inteiramente da memória. (compare suas pinturas às 
fotos dos lugares.) Jogue os jogos interativos que testam sua 
memória -- aprenda maneiras melhorá-la. Descubra porque 
algumas coisas são mais fáceis de recordar do que outras (jogo dos 
droodles). Que características facial nos ajudam recordar uma 
cara? Que imagem da moeda de um centavo está correta? 
Tente um dispositivo mnemônico chamado encoding elaborative.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">disseca un cervello delle pecore per mostrarci 
l'anatomia della memoria. Veda gli impianti di un artista che 
vernicia interamente dalla memoria. (confronti le sue pitture 
alle foto dei posti.) Gioc i giochi interattivi che verificano 
la vostra memoria -- impari i modi migliorarla. Scopra perchè 
alcune cose sono più facili da ricordarsi di che altre (gioco dei 
droodles). Quali caratteristiche facciali li aiutano a 
ricordarsi di una faccia? Quale immagine del penny è corretta? 
Provi un dispositivo mnemonico chiamato la codifica elaborative.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τεμαχίζει έναν εγκέφαλο προβάτων για να μας εμφανίσει
την ανατομία της μνήμης. Δείτε τις εργασίες ενός 
καλλιτέχνη που χρωματίζει εξ ολοκλήρου από τη μνήμη. 
(Συγκρίνετε τα έργα ζωγραφικής του με τις φωτογραφίες των 
θέσεων.) Παίξτε τα διαλογικά παιχνίδια που εξετάζουν τη 
μνήμη σας -- μάθετε τους τρόπους να βελτιωθεί. Ανακαλύψτε 
γιατί μερικά πράγματα είναι ευκολότερα να θυμηθούν από άλλα 
(droodles παιχνίδι). Ποια του προσώπου χαρακτηριστικά 
γνωρίσματα μας βοηθούν να θυμηθούμε ένα πρόσωπο; Ποια 
εικόνα της πένας είναι σωστή; Δοκιμάστε μια μνημονική 
συσκευή αποκαλούμενη επεξεργαστική κωδικοποίηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">diseca un cerebro de las ovejas para mostrarnos la
anatomía de la memoria. Vea los trabajos de un artista que 
pinte enteramente de memoria. (compare sus pinturas a las fotos 
de lugares.) Juegue los juegos interactivos que prueban su 
memoria -- aprenda las maneras de mejorarla. Descubra porqué 
algunas cosas son más fáciles de recordar que otras (juego de los 
droodles). ¿Qué características faciales nos ayudan a recordar
una cara? ¿Qué imagen del penique está correcta? Intente
un dispositivo mnemónico llamado codificación elaborative.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206647</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103217</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/memory</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
