<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103644</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103644</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202673</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Teaching Point of View</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterrichtender Gesichtspunkt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Point de vue d'enseignement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ponto ensinando da vista</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Punto di vista d'istruzione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποψη διδασκαλίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Punto de vista de enseñanza</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students will learn point of view by comparing and contrasting the views of slaves and a doctor in The People Could Fly retold by Virginia Hamilton and The Passing Cloud -- The Southern Negro by David Morrill. I strongly suggest the teacher previews The Passing Cloud -- The Southern Negro by David Morrill. The entire text is not needed in order for students to form an opinion or to learn point of view. Some students and parents may find the language offensive. I found the text interesting because it allows students to actually read the historical views of some people who lived in the area during the 1800's and early 1900's.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer erlernen, daß Gesichtspunkt, indem
er die Ansichten der Sklaven und des Doktors in den Leuten verglich 
und kontrastierte, fliegen könnte wiedergeholt durch Virginia 
Hamilton und die überschreitene Wolke -- der südliche Schwarze durch
David Morrill. Ich schlage stark die Lehrervorbetrachtungen die 
überschreitene Wolke -- der südliche Schwarze durch David Morrill 
vor. Der gesamte Text ist nicht damit Kursteilnehmer, eine 
Meinung zu bilden erforderlich oder Gesichtspunkt zu erlernen. 
Einige Kursteilnehmer und Eltern können die Sprache beleidigend
finden. Ich fand den Text zu interessieren, weil er 
Kursteilnehmern erlaubt, die historischen Ansichten einiger Leute 
wirklich zu lesen, die im Bereich während des 1800's und des frühen 
1900's lebten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants apprendront que le point de vue en 
comparant et en contrastant les vues des esclaves et d'un docteur dans
le peuple pourrait voler raconté de nouveau par le Virginie Hamilton et 
le nuage de dépassement -- le nègre méridional par David Morrill. 
Je suggère fortement les prévisions de professeur le nuage de 
dépassement -- le nègre méridional par David Morrill. Le 
texte entier n'est pas nécessaire afin des étudiants pour former une
opinion ou pour apprendre le point de vue. Quelques étudiants 
et parents peuvent trouver le langage blessant. J'ai trouvé le 
texte intéresser parce qu'il permet à des étudiants de lire 
réellement les vues historiques de certains qui ont vécu dans la 
zone pendant le 1800's et le 1900's tôt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes aprenderão que o ponto da vista 
comparando e contrastando as opiniões os escravos e um doutor nos 
povos poderia voar retold por Virgínia Hamilton e a nuvem de passagem
-- negro do sul por David Morrill. Eu sugiro fortemente as 
inspecções prévias do professor a nuvem de passagem -- negro do sul
por David Morrill. O texto inteiro não é needed para que 
estudantes dar forma a uma opinião ou aprender o ponto da vista. 
Alguns estudantes e pais podem encontrar a língua ofensiva. 
Eu encontrei o texto interessar porque permite que os estudantes
leiam realmente as opiniões históricas alguns povos que viveram na 
área durante o 1800's e o 1900's adiantado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi impareranno che il punto di vista 
confrontando e contrapponendo i punti di vista degli schiavi e di un 
medico nella gente potrebbe volare retold dalla Virginia Hamilton e la
nube passante -- il negro del sud da David Morrill. Suggerisco 
fortemente le previsioni dell'insegnante la nube passante -- il negro 
del sud da David Morrill. L'intero testo non è necessario 
nell'ordine affinchè gli allievi formi un'opinione o per imparare il 
punto di vista. Alcuni allievi e genitori possono trovare il 
linguaggio offensivo. Ho scoperto il testo interessa perché 
permette che gli allievi realmente leggano i punti di vista storici 
qualche gente che ha vissuto nella zona durante il 1800's ed il 1900's
iniziale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν την άποψη με τη σύγκριση και 
την αντιπαράθεση των όψεων των σκλάβων και ένας γιατρός στους 
ανθρώπους θα μπορούσε να πετάξει επαναλήφθείτε από τη Βιρτζίνια
Χάμιλτον και το περνώντας σύννεφο -- ο νότιος νέγρος από το 
Δαβίδ Morrill. Προτείνω έντονα τις επιδείξεις δασκάλων 
το περνώντας σύννεφο -- ο νότιος νέγρος από το Δαβίδ Morrill.
Το ολόκληρο κείμενο δεν απαιτείται για οι σπουδαστές 
διαμορφώνουν μια άποψη ή μαθαίνουν την άποψη. Μερικοί 
σπουδαστές και γονείς μπορούν να βρούν τη γλωσσική επίθεση. 
Βρήκα το κείμενο επειδή επιτρέπει στους σπουδαστές για να 
διαβάσει πραγματικά τις ιστορικές όψεις μερικών ανθρώπων που 
έζησαν στην περιοχή κατά τη διάρκεια του 1800's και των 
πρόωρων δεκαετιών του 20ου αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes aprenderán que el punto de vista 
comparando y poniendo en contraste las opiniones esclavos y un doctor 
en la gente podría volar retold por Virginia Hamilton y la nube que 
pasaba -- el negro meridional de David Morrill. Sugiero 
fuertemente las inspecciones previoes del profesor la nube que pasa --
el negro meridional de David Morrill. El texto entero no se 
necesita en la orden para que a los estudiantes formen una opinión o 
aprendan punto de vista. Algunos estudiantes y padres pueden 
encontrar el lenguaje ofensivo. Encontré el texto el interesar 
porque permite que los estudiantes lean realmente las opiniones 
históricas alguna gente que vivió en el área durante el 1800's y el
1900's temprano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ANGELA STROTHER
FN:ANGELA STROTHER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202673</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103644</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/teaching-point-of-view</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
