<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104777</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104777</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086273</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Believe in the Divinity of Labor": George Ripley Tries to Convince Ralph Waldo Emerson to Join Brook Farm, Boston, 1840</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich glaube an die Göttlichkeit der Arbeit": 
George Ripley Versuche, zum von von Ralph Waldo Emerson zu 
überzeugen, um Bach-Bauernhof, Boston, 1840 zu verbinden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je crois en divinité de travail" : Essais 
de George Ripley pour convaincre Ralph Waldo Emerson pour joindre
la ferme de ruisseau, Boston, 1840</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu acredito no divinity do trabalho": 
Tentativas de George Ripley para convencer Ralph Waldo Emerson 
para juntar a fazenda do ribeiro, Boston, 1840</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"credo nel divinity del Lavoro": Prove 
di George Ripley per convincere Ralph Waldo Emerson per unire il 
podere del ruscello, Boston, 1840</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"πιστεύω στη θεότητα της εργασίασ": Θ*Γεοργε 
Ripley Tries να πειστεί ο Ralph Waldo Emerson για να 
ενώσει το αγρόκτημα ρυακιών, Βοστώνη, 1840</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"creo en el divinity del trabajo": Intentos 
de George Ripley para convencer a Ralph Waldo Emerson que ensamble la 
granja del arroyo, Boston, 1840</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1840, Unitarian minister George Ripley wrote to the Transcendentalist author Ralph Waldo Emerson in an (unsuccessful) effort to convince him to join, or at least invest in, his planned utopian community, Brook Farm. Founders of antebellum utopian communities attempted to withdraw from what they saw as the hypocrisies and excesses of partisan politics, the inequities inherent in marriage and factory work, the evils of the slave system, and the corruption of cities and to create, in small scale, a more perfect place. Brook Farm began operations in 1841 in West Roxbury, Massachusetts. The Brook farmers lived and dined communally, and divided their time between farm work and artistic and scholarly pursuits. Although other utopian communities, such as Oneida in upstate New York, and Amana, in Iowa, achieved self-sufficiency, Brook Farm ultimately failed. The community never recovered from a devastating fire in 1846, and it closed its doors in 1847.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1840 schrieb Unitarian Minister George Ripley dem 
Transcendentalist Autor Ralph Waldo Emerson in eine (erfolglose) 
Bemühung, ihn zu überzeugen zu verbinden oder investiert mindestens 
innen, seine geplante utopische Gemeinschaft, Bach-Bauernhof. 
Gründer der antebellum utopischen Gemeinschaften versuchten 
zurückzutreten von was sie als die Hypokrisien sahen und 
Überflüsse der parteigängerischen Politiken, die Ungerechtigkeiten,
die in der Verbindung zugehörig sind und die Fabrik arbeiten, die 
Übel des Untersystems und die Korruption der Städte und, im Klein, 
einen vollkommeneren Platz zu erstellen. Bach-Bauernhof fing 
Operationen 1841 in Westroxbury, Massachusetts an. Die 
Bachlandwirte lebten und speisten kommunal und teilten ihre Zeit 
zwischen Bauernhofarbeit und den künstlerischen und gelehrten 
Verfolgungen. Obgleich andere utopische Gemeinschaften, wie 
Oneida im upstate New York und Amana, in Iowa, Selbstüberhebung 
erzielten, fiel Bach-Bauernhof schließlich aus. Die 
Gemeinschaft erholte nie von einem verheerenden Feuer 1846, und es 
schloß seine Türen 1847.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1840, le ministre unitarien George 
Ripley a écrit à l'auteur Ralph Waldo Emerson de Transcendentalist 
dans un effort (non réussi) de le convaincre de se joindre, ou 
investit au moins dedans, sa communauté utopique prévue, ferme de 
ruisseau. Les fondateurs des communautés utopiques 
d'avant-guerre ont essayé de se retirer de ce qu'ils ont vu comme 
hypocrisies et les excès de la politique partisane, les injustices 
inhérentes au mariage et l'usine fonctionnent, les maux du système 
slave, et la corruption des villes et de créer, dans la petite 
échelle, un endroit plus parfait. La ferme de ruisseau a 
commencé des exécutions en 1841 dans Roxbury occidental, le 
Massachusetts. Les fermiers de ruisseau ont vécu et ont diné 
communalement, et ont divisé leur temps entre le travail de ferme et 
les poursuites artistiques et savantes. Bien que d'autres 
communautés utopiques, telles que l'oneida à New York hors de la ville, 
et Amana, en Iowa, aient réalisé art de l'auto-portrait-sufficiency, la ferme de 
ruisseau a finalement échoué. La communauté n'a jamais 
récupéré d'un feu dévastateur en 1846, et il a fermé ses portes 
en 1847.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1840, o ministro George Ripley de Unitarian 
escreveu ao autor Ralph Waldo Emerson de Transcendentalist em um 
esforço (mal sucedido) convencê-lo juntar, ou invest ao menos 
dentro, sua comunidade utópica de planeamento, fazenda do ribeiro. 
Os founders das comunidades utópicas antebellum tentaram 
retirar-se de o que viram como os hypocrisies e os excessos da 
política partisan, os inequities inerentes na união e a fábrica 
trabalham, os evils do sistema slave, e o corruption das cidades e 
criar, na escala pequena, um lugar mais perfeito. A fazenda do 
ribeiro começou operações em 1841 em Roxbury ocidental, 
Massachusetts. Os fazendeiros do ribeiro viveram e jantaram 
communally, e dividiram seu tempo entre o trabalho da fazenda e 
perseguições artísticas e scholarly. Embora outras 
comunidades utópicas, tais como o oneida no upstate New York, e 
Amana, em Iowa, conseguissem o self-sufficiency, a fazenda do ribeiro 
falhou finalmente. A comunidade nunca recuperou de um fogo 
devastating em 1846, e fechou suas portas em 1847.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1840, il ministro George Ripley di Unitarian
ha scritto all'autore Ralph Waldo Emerson di Transcendentalist in uno 
sforzo (infruttuoso) convincerlo unirsi, o almeno investe dentro, la 
sua Comunità utopian prevista, podere del ruscello. I fondatori
delle Comunità utopian antebellum hanno tentato di ritirarsi da che 
cosa hanno visto come le ipocrisie e gli eccessi di politiche 
partigiane, le ingiustizie inerenti all'unione e la fabbrica 
funzionano, le malvagità del sistema slave e la corruzione delle 
città e di creare, in a scala ridotta, un posto più perfetto. 
Il podere del ruscello ha cominciato i funzionamenti in 1841 in 
Roxbury ad ovest, Massachusetts. I coltivatori del ruscello 
hanno vissuto in modo comunitario e pranzato ed hanno diviso il loro 
tempo fra il lavoro dell'azienda agricola e gli inseguimenti artistici
e da studioso. Anche se altre Comunità utopian, quale oneida 
nel upstate New York ed Amana, nello Iowa, hanno realizzato 
l'autosufficienza, il podere del ruscello infine è venuto a mancare. 
La Comunità non ha recuperato mai da un fuoco devastating in 
1846 e da esso chiuso i relativi portelli in 1847.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1840, ο ενωτικός υπουργός George Ripley 
έγραψε στο Transcendentalist συντάκτη Ralph Waldo 
Emerson σε μια (ανεπιτυχή) προσπάθεια να πειστεί για να ενώσει,
ή να επενδύσει τουλάχιστον, η προγραμματισμένη ουτοπιστική 
κοινότητά του, αγρόκτημα ρυακιών. Οι ιδρυτές των 
προπολεμικών ουτοπιστικών κοινοτήτων προσπάθησαν να αποσύρουν 
από αυτό που εβλέίδαν ως υποκρισίες και οι υπερβολές 
της αντιστασιακής πολιτικής, οι αδικίες έμφυτες στο γάμο και το 
εργοστάσιο λειτουργούν, τα κακά του συστήματος σκλάβων, και η 
δωροδοκία των πόλεων και για να δημιουργήσουν, σε μικρής 
κλίμακας, μια τελειότερη θέση. Το αγρόκτημα ρυακιών άρχισε
τις διαδικασίες το 1841 στη δύση Roxbury, Μασαχουσέτη. 
Οι αγρότες ρυακιών έζησαν και δείπνησαν κοινοτικά, και 
διαίρεσαν το χρόνο τους μεταξύ της αγροτικής εργασίας και των 
καλλιτεχνικών και μορφωμένων αναζητήσεων. Αν και άλλες 
ουτοπιστικές κοινότητες, όπως Oneida στην εκτός κράτους Νέα 
Υόρκη, και Amana, στο Iowa, επέτυχαν την αυτάρκεια, 
αγρόκτημα ρυακιών αποτυχημένο τελικά. Η κοινότητα δεν 
ανάκτησε ποτέ από μια καταστρεπτική πυρκαγιά το 1846, και 
έκλεισε τις πόρτες της το 1847.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1840, el ministro George Ripley de Unitarian 
escribió al autor Ralph Waldo Emerson de Transcendentalist en un 
esfuerzo (fracasado) de convencerle a que ensamble, o invierte por lo 
menos adentro, su comunidad utópica prevista, granja del arroyo. 
Los fundadores de las comunidades utópicas antebellum 
procuraron retirarse de lo que vieron como las hipocresías y los 
excesos de políticas partisanas, las injusticias inherentes en la 
unión y la fábrica trabajan, los males del sistema auxiliar, y la 
corrupción de ciudades y crear, en escala pequeña, un lugar más 
perfecto. La granja del arroyo comenzó operaciones en 1841 en 
Roxbury del oeste, Massachusetts. Los granjeros del arroyo 
vivieron y cenaron comunal, y dividieron su tiempo entre el trabajo de
la granja y las búsquedas artísticas y de estudiante. Aunque 
otras comunidades utópicas, tales como oneida en el upstate Nueva 
York, y Amana, en Iowa, alcanzaron autosuficiencia, la granja del 
arroyo falló en última instancia. La comunidad nunca se 
recuperó de un fuego devastador en 1846, y cerró sus puertas en 
1847.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086273</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104777</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-believe-in-the-divinity-of-labor-george-ripley-tries-to-convince-ralph-waldo-emerson-to-join-brook-farm-boston-1840</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
