<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108216</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108216</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087277</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Call to Arms: McNeill's Unshakable Faith in Labor's Future</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Aufruf zu den Armen: McNeills 
Unerschütterlicher Glaube in der Zukunft der Arbeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un appel aux bras : Foi d'Unshakable de 
McNeill dans le futur du travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um atendimento aos braços: Fé de 
Unshakable de McNeill no futuro do trabalho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una chiamata all'Armi: Fede di 
Unshakable del McNeill in futuro Di lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια κλήση στα όπλα: Πίστη Unshakable 
McNeill's στο μέλλον της εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una llamada a los brazos: Fe de Unshakable 
de McNeill en el futuro del trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As the 19th century drew to a close, labor activists were forced to confront the implications of a long string of defeats suffered by their movement in recent years. One of the most venerable of labor editors, George McNeill, writing in the official journal of the American Federation of Labor (AFL) in December 1896, encouraged trade unionists to renew their commitment to a struggle that had not always been successful. At the same time, he accurately predicted an even more momentous battle in the next century between the trade unions and "the giant monopolies."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während das 19. Jahrhundert zu einem nahem 
zeichnete, wurden Arbeitsaktivisten erzwungen, die Implikationen einer
langen Zeichenkette der Niederlagen zu konfrontieren, die in den 
letzten Jahren durch ihre Bewegung erlitten wurden. Ein vom 
venerable der Arbeitsherausgeber, George McNeill, schreibend in das 
Amtsblatt der amerikanischen Vereinigung der Arbeit (AFL) im Dezember 
1896, regte Gewerkschaftler an, ihre Verpflichtung zu einem Kampf zu 
erneuern, der nicht immer erfolgreich gewesen war. Gleichzeitig 
sagte er genau eine sogar bedeutsamere Schlacht im folgenden 
Jahrhundert zwischen den Gewerkschaften und "den riesigen Monopolen." 
voraus</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant que le 19ème siècle prenait fin, des 
activistes de travail ont été forcés de confronter les implications
d'une longue chaîne de caractères des défaites souffertes par leur 
mouvement ces dernières années. Un du plus vénérable des 
éditeurs de travail, George McNeill, écrivant dans le Journal 
officiel de la fédération américaine du travail (AFL) en décembre 
1896, a encouragé les syndicalistes à remplacer leur engagement à 
une lutte qui n'avait pas toujours été réussie. En même 
temps, il a exactement prévu une bataille bien plus importante en 
siècle à venir entre les syndicats et "les monopoles géants."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enquanto o 1ø século desenhou a um próximo, as 
activistas labor foram forçadas a confrontar as implicações de uma 
corda longa das derrotas sofridas por seu movimento em anos recentes. 
Um do mais venerable de editores labor, George McNeill, 
escrevendo no jornal oficial do federation americano do trabalho (AFL)
em dezembro 1896, incentivou os unionists de comércio renovar seu 
compromisso a um esforço que não fosse sempre bem sucedido. Ao
mesmo tempo, predisse exatamente uma batalha mesmo mais momentous no 
século seguinte entre as uniões de comércio e "os monopólios 
gigantes."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre il diciannovesimo secolo ha volto al 
termine, gli attivisti di lavoro sono stati costretti a confrontare
le implicazioni di una serie lunga di sconfitte sofferte tramite il 
loro movimento negli ultimi anni. Uno del più venerable degli 
editori di lavoro, George McNeill, scrivente nella Gazzetta ufficiale
della federazione americana del Lavoro (AFL) nel mese di dicembre
del 1896, ha consigliato ai sindacalisti rinnovare il loro impegno ad 
una lotta che non era riuscita sempre. Allo stesso tempo, ha 
predetto esattamente una battaglia ancor più momentous nel secolo 
venturo fra i sindacati e "i monopolii giganti."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθώς ο 19$ος αιώνας πλησίασε στο τέλος, τα ενεργά 
στελέχη εργασίας αναγκάστηκαν να αντιμετωπίσουν τις επιπτώσεις 
μιας μακριάς συμβολοσειράς των ηττών που υποφέρονται από τη 
μετακίνησή τους τα τελευταία χρόνια. Ένας από τον πιό 
σεβάσμιο των επεξεργαστών εργασίας, George McNeill, που 
γράφουν στην Επίσημη Εφημερίδα της αμερικανικής ομοσπονδίας της 
εργασίας (AFL) τον Δεκέμβριο του 1896, ενθάρρυνε τους 
συνδικαλιστές για να ανανεώσει τη δέσμευσή τους για μια 
προσπάθεια που ήταν όχι πάντα επιτυχής. Συγχρόνως, 
πρόβλεψε ακριβώς μια ακόμα πιό βαρυσήμαντη μάχη στον επόμενο 
αιώνα μεταξύ των συνδικάτων και "των γιγαντιαίων μονοπωλίων."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que el diecinueveavo siglo trazó a un 
cercano, forzaron a los activistas de trabajo enfrentar las 
implicaciones de una cadena larga de derrotas sufridas por su 
movimiento en años recientes. Uno del ma's venerable de 
editores de trabajo, George McNeill, escribiendo en el diario oficial 
de la federación americana del trabajo (AFL) en diciembre de 1896, 
animó a unionistas comerciales que renovaran su consolidación a una 
lucha que no había sido siempre acertada. En el mismo tiempo, 
él predijo exactamente una batalla aún más trascendental en el 
siglo próximo entre los sindicatos y "los monopolios gigantes."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087277</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108216</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-call-to-arms-mcneills-unshakable-faith-in-labors-future</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
