<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104102</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104102</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201727</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fishing Game</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fischen-Spiel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeu de Pêche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogo Da Pesca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioco Di Pesca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδι αλιείας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juego De la Pesca</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Fishing Game is an activity that places students in the role of manager in the National Fish and Wildlife Service. They are charged with the responsibility of making policy suggestions regarding the management of a fishery surrounding national borders. Fishing is an important source of economic income for their country so their decisions must ensure the healthy maintenance of the fish population and fishing industry. Students learn introductory aspects of the use and modification of the Stella modeling environment, lessons and concepts related to systems dynamics, how models can be used to assess policy, about sustainable use of limited resources, and about the effectiveness of different environmental policy. This activity is likely to take 2 hours and it is a good lesson for introductory geoscience courses that have an Earth System approach and in which the instructor plans to make use of the Stella Modeling environment. This site also includes teaching notes and tips, necessary teaching materials, assessment ideas and additional resources. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Fischen-Spiel ist eine Aktivität, die 
Kursteilnehmer in die Rolle des Managers im nationalen Fisch-und 
Wildnis-Service legt. Sie werden mit der Verantwortlichkeit des 
Bildens der Politikvorschläge betreffend sind das Management einer 
Fischerei aufgeladen, die nationale Ränder umgibt. Fischen ist 
eine wichtige Quelle des ökonomischen Einkommens für ihr Land, also 
müssen ihre Entscheidungen die gesunde Wartung der Fischbevölkerung 
und der $fischindustrie sicherstellen. Kursteilnehmer erlernen 
einleitende Aspekte des Gebrauches und der Änderung des Stella, das 
Umgebung formt, die Lektionen und Konzepte, die auf Systeme Dynamik in
Verbindung gestanden werden, wie Modelle benutzt werden können, um 
Politik, über stützbaren Gebrauch von begrenzten Betriebsmitteln und
über die Wirksamkeit der unterschiedlichen Klimapolitik festzusetzen.
Diese Aktivität ist wahrscheinlich, 2 Stunden zu dauern und es 
ist eine gute Lektion für einleitende geoscience Kurse, in denen eine
Masse System Annäherung haben und, in welchem der Ausbilder plant, 
das Stella zu gebrauchen, das Umgebung formt. Diese Site 
schließt auch unterrichtende Anmerkungen und Spitzen, notwendige 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen und zusätzliche Betriebsmittel ein. 
Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le jeu de pêche est une activité qui place des 
étudiants dans le rôle du gestionnaire dans le service national de 
poissons et de faune. Ils sont chargés de la responsabilité de
faire des suggestions de politique concernant la gestion d'une pêche 
entourant les cadres nationaux. La pêche est une source 
importante de revenu économique pour leur pays ainsi leurs décisions
doivent assurer l'entretien sain de l'industrie de population et de la
pêche de poissons. Les étudiants apprennent des aspects 
préliminaires de l'utilisation et de la modification du Stella 
modelant l'environnement, des leçons et des concepts liés à la 
dynamique de systèmes, comment des modèles peuvent être employés 
pour évaluer la politique, au sujet de l'utilisation soutenable des 
ressources limitées, et au sujet de l'efficacité de la politique 
environnementale différente. Cette activité est susceptible de
prendre 2 heures et c'est une bonne leçon pour les cours 
préliminaires de geoscience qui ont une approche systématisée de la
terre et dans ce qui l'instructeur projette se servir du Stella 
modelant l'environnement. Ce site inclut également les notes et
les extrémités d'enseignement, le matériel didactique nécessaire, 
les idées d'évaluation et les ressources supplémentaires. 
Cette activité fait partie de la collection de point de départ
: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O jogo da pesca é uma atividade que coloque 
estudantes no papel do gerente no serviço nacional dos peixes e dos 
animais selvagens. São carregados com a responsabilidade de 
fazer as sugestões da política a respeito da gerência de um fishery
que cerca beiras nacionais. A pesca é uma fonte importante da 
renda econômica para seu país assim que suas decisões devem 
assegurar a manutenção saudável da população dos peixes e da 
indústria pescando. Os estudantes aprendem aspectos 
introdutórios do uso e da modificação do Stella que modela o 
ambiente, lições e conceitos relacionados à dinâmica dos sistemas,
como os modelos podem ser usados avaliar a política, sobre o uso 
sustainable de recursos limitados, e sobre a eficácia da política 
ambiental diferente. Esta atividade é provável fazer exame de 
2 horas e é uma lição boa para os cursos introdutórios do 
geoscience em que têm uma aproximação de sistema da terra e em qual
o instrutor planeia empregar o Stella que modela o ambiente. 
Este local inclui também notas e pontas ensinando, materiais de
ensino necessários, idéias da avaliação e recursos adicionais. 
Esta atividade é parte da coleção do ponto começar: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il gioco di pesca è un'attività che dispone gli 
allievi nel ruolo del gestore nel servizio nazionale della fauna 
selvatica e dei pesci. Sono caricati della responsabilità di 
formulare i suggerimenti di politica per quanto riguarda la gestione 
di un'industria della pesca che circonda i bordi nazionali. La 
pesca è una sorgente importante di reddito economico per il loro 
paese in modo da le loro decisioni devono accertare il mantenimento 
sano dell'industria della popolazione e della pesca dei pesci. 
Gli allievi imparano le funzioni introduttive dell'uso e della 
modifica dello Stella che modella l'ambiente, le lezioni ed i concetti
relativi al dynamics dei sistemi, come i modelli possono essere usati 
per valutare la politica, circa uso sostenibile delle risorse limitate
e circa l'efficacia della politica ambientale differente. Questa
attività è probabile occorrere 2 ore ed è una buona lezione per i 
corsi introduttivi di geoscience in che hanno un approccio sistematico
della terra ed in quale l'istruttore progetta usare lo Stella che 
modella l'ambiente. Questo luogo egualmente include le note e 
punte d'istruzione, materiali didattici necessari, idee di valutazione
e risorse supplementari. Questa attività fa parte 
dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το παιχνίδι αλιείας είναι μια δραστηριότητα που 
τοποθετεί τους σπουδαστές στο ρόλο του διευθυντή στα εθνικές 
ψάρια και την υπηρεσία άγριας φύσης. Χρεώνονται με την 
ευθύνη τις πολιτικές προτάσεις σχετικά με τη διαχείριση μιας 
αλιείας που περιβάλλει τα εθνικά σύνορα. Η αλιεία είναι 
μια σημαντική πηγή οικονομικού εισοδήματος για τη χώρα τους έτσι
οι αποφάσεις τους πρέπει να εξασφαλίσουν την υγιή συντήρηση του 
πληθυσμού ψαριών και της αλιευτικής βιομηχανίας. Οι 
σπουδαστές μαθαίνουν τις εισαγωγικές πτυχές της χρήσης και της 
τροποποίησης του περιβάλλοντος διαμόρφωσης της Στέλλα, τα 
μαθήματα και τις έννοιες σχετικά με τη δυναμική συστημάτων, πώς 
τα μοντέλα μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για να αξιολογήσουν την 
πολιτική, για τη βιώσιμη χρήση των περιορισμένων στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς, και για την αποτελεσματικότητα της διαφορετικής 
πολιτικής για το περιβάλλον. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι 
πιθανό να πάρει 2 ώρες και είναι ένα καλό μάθημα για τις 
εισαγωγικές σειρές μαθημάτων geoscience που έχουν μια 
προσέγγιση γήινων συστημάτων και στις οποίες ο εκπαιδευτικός 
προγραμματίζει να χρησιμοποιήσει το περιβάλλον της Στέλλα 
Modeling. Αυτή η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις 
σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα απαραίτητα εκπαιδευτικά 
υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης και τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι μέρος της 
συλλογής αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El juego de la pesca es una actividad que coloca a
estudiantes en el papel del encargado en el servicio nacional de los 
pescados y de la fauna. Los cargan con la responsabilidad de 
hacer sugerencias de la política con respecto a la gerencia de una 
industria pesquera que rodea las fronteras nacionales. La pesca 
es una fuente importante de la renta económica para su país así que
sus decisiones deben asegurar el mantenimiento sano de la industria de
la población y de pesca de los pescados. Los estudiantes 
aprenden los aspectos introductorios del uso y de la modificación del
Stella que modela el ambiente, las lecciones y los conceptos 
relacionados con la dinámica de los sistemas, cómo los modelos se 
pueden utilizar para evaluar la política, sobre el uso sostenible de 
recursos limitados, y sobre la eficacia de diversa política 
ambiental. Esta actividad es probable tomar 2 horas y es una 
buena lección para los cursos introductorios del geoscience que 
tienen un acercamiento de sistema de la tierra y en cuáles planea el 
instructor hacer uso el Stella que modela el ambiente. Este 
sitio también incluye notas y las extremidades de enseñanza, los 
materiales didácticos necesarios, las ideas del gravamen y los 
recursos adicionales. Esta actividad es parte de la colección 
del punto de partida: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201727</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104102</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fishing-game</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
