<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104291</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104291</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207074</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Explore the West with the Lewis and Clark Expedition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erforschen Sie den Westen mit der Lewis und Clark 
Expedition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorez l'ouest avec l'expédition de Lewis et de
Clark</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explore o oeste com a expedição de Lewis e de 
Clark</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esplori l'ovest con la spedizione del Clark e di 
Lewis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ερευνήστε τη δύση με την αποστολή Lewis και clark</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explore el oeste con la expedición de Lewis y de 
Clark</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site is a travel itinerary of 41 forts, Indian villages, mounds, mountain passes, trails, caves, and other sites along the 8,000-mile journey. The expedition -- launched from St. Charles, Missouri, on May 21, 1804 -- strengthened the U.S.'s knowledge and struggle for control of North America. It inspired many to move westward. The website includes essays on preparations for the journey, scientific encounters, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site ist ein Spielraumreiseweg von 41 Forts,
indische Dörfer, Dämme, überschreitet Berg, Spuren, Höhlen, und 
andere Sites entlang dem 8,000-mile reisen. Die Expedition -- 
ausgestoßen von Str. Charles, Missouri, an Mai 21, 1804 -- 
verstärkte das Wissen und Kampf der US zur Steuerung von Nordamerika.
Es spornte viele an, um nach Westen zu bewegen. Die Web 
site schließt Versuche auf Vorbereitungen für die Reise, das 
wissenschaftliche Treffen und mehr ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site est un itinéraire de voyage de 41 forts, 
villages indiens, monticules, la montagne passe, des traînées, 
cavernes, et d'autres sites le long du 8,000-mile voyagent. 
L'expédition -- lancée de la rue Charles, le Missouri, mai 21,
1804 -- a renforcé la connaissance et la lutte des États-Unis pour 
la commande de l'Amérique du nord. Elle a inspiré beaucoup
pour se déplacer à l'ouest. Le site Web inclut des essais sur 
des préparations pour le voyage, la rencontre scientifique, et les 
plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local é um itinerary do curso de 41 forts, 
vilas indian, montes, a montanha passa, fugas, cavernas, e outros 
locais ao longo do 8,000-mile viajam. A expedição -- lançada 
de St. Charles, Missouri, maio em 21, 1804 -- strengthened o 
conhecimento e o esforço dos E. U. para o controle de America do 
Norte. Inspirou muitos para mover-se para o oeste. O Web 
site inclui essays em preparações para a viagem, o encontro 
científico, e o mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo è un itinerario di corsa di 41 
forts, i villaggi indiani, monticelli, la montagna passa, tracce, 
caverne ed altri luoghi lungo il 8,000-mile viaggiano. La 
spedizione -- lanciata dalla st Charles, il Missouri, maggio su 21, 
1804 -- ha rinforzato la conoscenza e la lotta degli Stati Uniti per 
controllo dell'America del Nord. Ha ispirato molti per muoversi 
verso ovest. Il Web site include i saggi sulle preparazioni per 
il viaggio, l'incontro scientifico ed il più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή είναι μια περιήγηση ταξιδιού 41 
οχυρών, των ινδικών χωριών, των αναχωμάτων, των περασμάτων 
βουνών, των ιχνών, των σπηλιών, και άλλων περιοχών κατά μήκος 
του ταξιδιού 8.000-μιλίου. Η αποστολή -- που προωθείται από
το ST Charles, Μισσούρι, σε Μάιος 21 ..1804 -- 
ενίσχυσε την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΈΣ γνώση και την προσπάθεια για τον έλεγχο
της Βόρειας Αμερικής. Ενέπνευσε πολλοί που κινούνται 
δυτικά. Ο ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει τα δοκίμια στις 
προετοιμασίες για το ταξίδι, τις επιστημονικές συγκρούσεις, και 
περισσότερους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio es un itinerario del recorrido de 41 
fortalezas, aldeas indias, montones, la montaña pasa, los rastros, 
cuevas, y otros sitios a lo largo del 8,000-mile viajan. La 
expedición -- lanzada de St. Charles, Missouri, 21 de mayo de 1804
-- consolidó el conocimiento y la lucha de los E.E.U.U. para el 
control de Norteamérica. Inspiró a muchos que se movieran 
hacia el oeste. El Web site incluye ensayos en las preparaciones
para el viaje, el encuentro científico, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207074</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104291</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/explore-the-west-with-the-lewis-and-clark-expedition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
