<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105446</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105446</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087309</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Hungery Savage Look which was Truly Fearful": Samuel Chamberlain's Recollections of the Mexican War, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Hungery wilder Blick, der wirklich" 
ängstlich war: Samuel Chamberlains Erinnerungen des 
mexikanischen Krieges, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un regard sauvage de Hungery qui était vraiment 
craintif" : Souvenirs de Samuel Chamberlain de la guerre 
mexicaine, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um olhar selvagem de Hungery que fosse 
verdadeiramente temível": Recollections de Samuel Chamberlain 
da guerra mexicana, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"uno sguardo selvaggio di Hungery che era 
allineare spaventoso": Ricordi di Samuel Chamberlain della 
guerra messicana, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας άγριος Hungery κοιτάζει που ήταν αληθινά 
έντρομο": Αναμνήσεις του Samuel Chamberlain's του 
μεξικάνικου πολέμου, 1846</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una mirada salvaje de Hungery que era verdad 
temerosa": Recuerdos de Samuel Chamberlain de la guerra 
mexicana, 1846</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the mid-nineteenth century, many Americans were eager to acquire the Mexican land of California and New Mexico, enough to provoke a war with Mexico. In 1845 U.S. President James K. Polk sent envoys who offered to buy Mexican territory and stationed federal troops in the border areas. Naval forces patrolled the Gulf coast and American consuls in California stirred up annexation fever. When the presence of those troops brought an anti-American government to power in Mexico in 1846, Polk ordered General Zachary Taylor and his troops to the Rio Grande and declared war. Taylor pursued retreating Mexican forces 100 miles into Mexico to the heavily fortified city of Monterrey. New Englander Samuel Chamberlain was eager to do battle against the Mexicans and expand the American empire. This excerpt from his illustrated manuscript, "My Confessions: Recollections of a Rogue," described his participation in the fierce house-to-house battle for Monterrey in September 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im mittler-19.jahrhundert waren viele Amerikaner 
eifrig, das mexikanische Land von Kalifornien und von New-Mexico, 
genug zu erwerben, um einen Krieg mit Mexiko zu erregen. Im 1845
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Präsidenten sendete James K. Polk Abgesandte, die 
anboten, mexikanische Gegend zu kaufen und Bundestruppen in den 
Grenzgebieten stationierten. Marinekräfte patrouillierten die 
Golfküste und amerikanische Konsuln in Kalifornien rührten sich 
herauf Annexionfieber. Als die Anwesenheit jener Truppen eine 
Anti-Amerikanische Regierung zur Energie in Mexiko 1846 holte, 
bestellte Polk General Zachary Taylor und seine Truppen nach das Rio 
Grande und erklärte Krieg. Schneider übte Zurückziehen 
Mexikanerkräfte 100 Meilen in Mexiko zur schwer verstärkten Stadt 
von Monterrey aus. Neuer Engländer Samuel Chamberlain war 
eifrig, Schlacht gegen den Mexikaner zu tun und das amerikanische 
Reich zu erweitern. Dieses Excerpt von seinem erläuterten 
Manuskript, "meine Geständnisse: Erinnerungen eines 
Gauners, "beschrieben seine Teilnahme in der heftigen 
house-to-house Schlacht für Monterrey im September 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Au mi-dix-neuvième siècle, beaucoup 
d'Américains étaient désireux de saisir la terre mexicaine de la 
Californie et du Nouveau-Mexique, assez pour provoquer une guerre avec
le Mexique. Dans le président des 1845 ETATS-UNIS James K.
Polk a envoyé les délégués qui ont offert d'acheter le territoire 
mexicain et ont posté les troupes fédérales dans les zones 
frontalières. Les forces navales ont patrouillé la côte de 
Golfe et les consuls américains en Californie ont remué vers le haut
de la fièvre d'annexation. Quand la présence de ces troupes a 
apporté un gouvernement anti-Américain à la puissance au Mexique en
1846, Polk a commandé le Général Zachary Taylor et ses troupes à 
Rio Grande et a déclaré la guerre. Le tailleur a poursuivi des
forces de Mexicain de retraitement 100 milles en le Mexique à la 
ville fortement enrichie de Monterrey. Le nouvel Anglais Samuel 
Chamberlain était désireux de faire la bataille contre le Mexicain 
et d'augmenter l'empire américain. Cet extrait de son manuscrit
illustré, "mes confessions : Les souvenirs d'un Escroc, 
"ont décrit sa participation dans la bataille porte à porte féroce 
pour Monterrey en septembre 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No mid-décimo nono século, muitos americanos 
estavam ansiosos para adquirir a terra mexicana de Califórnia e de 
Novo México, bastante para provocar uma guerra com o México. 
No presidente de 1845 ESTADOS UNIDOS James K. Polk emitiu os 
envoys que ofereceram comprar o território mexicano e postaram tropas
federais nas áreas de beira. As forças navais patrulharam a 
costa do golfo e os cônsules americanos em Califórnia agitaram acima
da febre do annexation. Quando a presença daquelas tropas 
trouxe um governo anti-Americano à potência em México em 1846, Polk
requisitou o general Zachary Alfaiate e suas tropas ao Rio Grande e 
declarou a guerra. O alfaiate perseguiu forças do mexicano 
recuar 100 milhas em México à cidade pesadamente fortified de 
Monterrey. O englander novo Samuel Chamberlain estava ansioso 
para fazer a batalha de encontro ao mexicano e para expandir o 
império americano. Este excerpt de seu manuscrito ilustrado, 
"meus confessions: Os recollections de um Rogue, "descreveram 
sua participação na batalha house-to-house feroz para Monterrey em 
setembro 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel metà di-diciannovesimo secolo, molti 
Americani erano desiderosi di acquistare la terra messicana della 
California e del Nuovo Messico, abbastanza per provocare una guerra 
con il Messico. In un presidente dei 1845 STATI UNITI James K. 
Polk ha trasmesso i envoys che hanno offerto di comprare il territorio
messicano ed hanno disposto le truppe federali nelle zone di 
frontiera. Le forze navali hanno perlustrato il litorale del 
golfo ed i consuls americani nella California si sono mescolati su 
febbre di annexation. Quando la presenza di quelle truppe ha 
portato un governo anti-Americano ad potenza nel Messico in 1846, Polk
ha ordinato il General Zachary Taylor e le sue truppe a Rio Grande ed 
ha dichiarato la guerra. Il sarto ha perseguito le forze 
messicane di ritirata 100 miglia in Messico alla città pesante 
fortificata di Monterrey. Il nuovo englander Samuel Chamberlain 
era desideroso di fare la battaglia contro il mexicans e di espandere 
l'impero americano. Questo brano dal suo manoscritto illustrato,
"i miei confessions: I ricordi di un Rogue, "hanno descritto la 
sua partecipazione nella battaglia house-to-house feroce per Monterrey
nel mese di settembre del 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο μέσος-δέκατο έννατο αιώνα, πολλοί Αμερικανοί 
ήταν πρόθυμοι να αποκτήσουν το μεξικάνικο έδαφος Καλιφόρνιας και
του New Mexico, αρκετά να προκαλέσουν έναν πόλεμο με το 
Μεξικό. Το 1845 ΗΠΑ ο Πρόεδρος james K. Polk 
έστειλε envoys που πρόσφερε να αγοράσει το μεξικάνικο έδαφος 
και τοποθέτησε τα ομοσπονδιακά στρατεύματα στις παραμεθώριες 
περιοχές. Οι ναυτικές δυνάμεις επιτήρησαν την ακτή του 
Περσικού Κόλπου και οι αμερικανικοί πρόξενοι σε Καλιφόρνια 
ανακάτωσαν επάνω τον πυρετό προσάρτησης. Όταν η παρουσία 
εκείνων των στρατευμάτων έφερε μια αντι-αμερικανική κυβέρνηση στη
δύναμη στο Μεξικό το 1846, Polk διέταξε το στρατηγό 
Zachary Taylor και τα στρατεύματά του στο Ρίο Grande και 
κήρυξε τον πόλεμο. Taylor ακολούθησε τις υποχωρώντας 
μεξικάνικες δυνάμεις 100 μίλια στο Μεξικό στη βαριά 
ενισχυμένη πόλη του Μοντερρέυ. Νέο Englander Samuel 
Chamberlain ήταν πρόθυμο να κάνει τη μάχη ενάντια στους 
μεξικανούς και να επεκτείνει την αμερικανική αυτοκρατορία. 
Αυτό το απόσπασμα από το διευκρινισμένο χειρόγραφό του, 
"οι ομολογίες μου: Οι αναμνήσεις ενός απατεώνα, 
"περιέγραψαν τη συμμετοχή του στην άγρια από σπίτι σε σπίτι 
μάχη για το Μοντερρέυ τον Σεπτέμβριο του 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el mediados de-diecinueveavo siglo, muchos 
americanos eran impacientes adquirir la pista mexicana de California y
de New México, bastante para provocar una guerra con México. 
En el presidente de 1845 ESTADOS UNIDOS James K. Polk envió a 
envoys que ofrecieron comprar el territorio mexicano y colocaron a 
tropas federales en las zonas fronterizas. Las fuerzas navales 
patrullaron la costa del golfo y los cónsules americanos en 
California revolvieron encima de fiebre de la anexión. Cuando 
la presencia de esas tropas trajo un gobierno contra-Americano a la 
potencia en México en 1846, Polk pidió a general Zachary Taylor y 
sus tropas a la Río Grande y declaró guerra. La 
personalización persiguió fuerzas del mexicano el retirar 100 millas
en México a la ciudad pesadamente fortificada de Monterrey. El 
nuevo inglés Samuel Chamberlain era impaciente hacer batalla contra 
el mexicano y ampliar el imperio americano. Este extracto de su 
manuscrito ilustrado, "mis Confesiones: Los recuerdos de un 
Granuja, "describieron su participación en la batalla 
house-to-house feroz para Monterrey en septiembre de 1846.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087309</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105446</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-hungery-savage-look-which-was-truly-fearful-samuel-chamberlains-recollections-of-the-mexican-war-1846</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
