<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106303</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106303</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202650</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Differences Across the Curriculum: Part 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterschiede über dem Lehrplan: Teil 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Différences à travers le programme d'études : 
Partie 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Diferenças através do curriculum: Parte 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Differenze attraverso il programma di studi: 
Parte 1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαφορές πέρα από το πρόγραμμα σπουδών: Μέρος 
1</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diferencias a través del plan de estudios: 
Parte 1</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This set of lessons can be used with "Differences Across the Curriculum: Parts 2, 3, and 4" as an integrated approach to exploring diversity with eighth graders. The unit will revolve around the use of the drama version of "The Diary of Anne Frank." Students will learn how diversity creates bias which leads to conflict, where students confront their bias and practice tolerance. These parts reflect the four core curricula in an interwoven approach to teaching students to confront their biases, learn tolerance, and infer the impact of these on today's society. This activity, Part 1, is meant to serve as a pre-reading activity to the reading of the play form of "The Diary of Anne Frank." See attachment created on Inspiration software to gain insight to the organization of the entire unit.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Set Lektionen kann mit "Unterschieden über
dem Lehrplan verwendet werden: Teile 2, 3 und 4"als integrierte 
Annäherung an erforschende Verschiedenartigkeit mit achten 
Sortierern. Die Maßeinheit rotiert um den Gebrauch von der 
Dramaversion "des Tagebuchs des Anne Freivermerks." 
Kursteilnehmer erlernen, wie Verschiedenartigkeit schräg 
erstellt, die führt, um zu widersprechen, wo Kursteilnehmer ihre 
Vorspannung und Praxistoleranz konfrontieren. Diese Teile teilen
die vier Kernlehrpläne in einer verwobenen Annäherung an 
unterrichtende Kursteilnehmer mit, um ihre Vorspannungen zu 
konfrontieren, erlernen Toleranz und schließen die Auswirkung von 
diesen auf heutige Gesellschaft. Diese Aktivität, Teil 1, wird 
bedeutet, um als Vormesswertaktivität zum Messwert des Spielformulars
"des Tagebuchs von Anne Freivermerk zu dienen." Sehen Sie das 
Zubehör, das auf Inspirationsoftware hergestellt wird, um Einblick 
zur Organisation der gesamten Maßeinheit zu gewinnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet ensemble de leçons peut être utilisé avec 
des "différences à travers le programme d'études : Parties 2,
3, et 4"comme approche intégrée à la diversité l'explorant avec 
les huitième niveleuses. L'unité tournera autour de 
l'utilisation de la version de drame "de l'agenda du contreseing 
d'Anne." Les étudiants apprendront comment la diversité crée 
de biais qui mène à être en conflit, où les étudiants confrontent
leur tolérance de polarisation et de pratique. Ces pièces 
reflètent les quatre programmes d'études de noyau dans une approche 
entrelacée aux étudiants d'enseignement pour confronter leurs 
polarisations, apprennent la tolérance, et impliquent l'impact de ces
derniers sur la société d'aujourd'hui. Cette activité, la 
partie 1, est censée pour servir d'activité de pré-lecture à la 
lecture de la forme de jeu "de l'agenda du contreseing d'Anne." 
Voir la connexion créée sur le logiciel d'inspiration pour 
gagner l'perspicacité à l'organisation de l'unité entière.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este jogo das lições pode ser usado com 
"diferenças através do curriculum: Partes 2, 3, e 4"como uma 
aproximação integrada à diversidade explorando com oitavos 
graduadores. A unidade revolverá em torno do uso da versão do 
drama "do diário do franquia de Anne." Os estudantes 
aprenderão como a diversidade cría diagonalmente que conduz para 
opôr, onde os estudantes confrontam sua tolerância da polarização 
e da prática. Estas peças refletem os quatro curricula do 
núcleo em uma aproximação interwoven aos estudantes ensinando para 
confrontar suas polarizações, aprendem a tolerância, e infer o 
impacto destes na sociedade de hoje. Esta atividade, parte 1, é
significada servir como uma atividade da pre-leitura à leitura do 
formulário do jogo "do diário do franquia de Anne." Veja o 
acessório criado no software da inspiração para ganhar a 
introspecção à organização da unidade inteira.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo insieme delle lezioni può essere usato con
"le differenze attraverso il programma di studi: Parti 2, 3 e 
4"come metodo integrato a diversità d'esplorazione con gli ottavi 
selezionatori. L'unità girerà intorno all'uso della versione 
di dramma "del diario della firma di franchigia del Anne." Gli 
allievi impareranno come la diversità crea di sbieco che conduce per 
essere in conflitto, dove gli allievi confrontano la loro tolleranza 
di pratica e di polarizzazione. Queste parti riflettono i 
quattro programmi di studi di nucleo in un metodo intrecciato agli 
allievi d'istruzione per confrontare le loro polarizzazioni, imparano 
la tolleranza ed arguiscono l'effetto di questi sull'odierna società.
Questa attività, la parte 1, è significata per servire da 
attività della pre-lettura alla lettura della forma del gioco "del 
diario della firma di franchigia del Anne." Veda il collegamento
creato sul software di ispirazione per guadagnare la comprensione 
all'organizzazione di intera unità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σύνολο μαθημάτων μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί με 
"τις διαφορές πέρα από το πρόγραμμα σπουδών: Μέρη 2 
..3, και 4 "ως ολοκληρωμένη προσέγγιση να ερευνήσει την 
ποικιλομορφία με τα όγδοα γκρέιντερ. Η μονάδα θα 
περιστραφεί γύρω από τη χρήση της έκδοσης δράματος "του 
ημερολογίου Αννας Φρανκ." Οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν πώς η 
ποικιλομορφία δημιουργεί διαγωνίως που οδηγεί στη σύγκρουση, 
όπου οι σπουδαστές αντιμετωπίζουν την ανοχή τους πόλωσης και 
πρακτικής. Αυτά τα μέρη απεικονίζουν τα τέσσερα 
προγράμματα σπουδών πυρήνων σε μια αναμειγμένη προσέγγιση στους 
σπουδαστές διδασκαλίας για να αντιμετωπίσουν τις πολώσεις τους, να
μάθουν την ανοχή, και να συμπεράνουν τον αντίκτυπο αυτοί στη 
σημερινή κοινωνία. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα, μέρος 1, 
προορίζεται να χρησιμεύσει ως μια δραστηριότητα προανάγνωσης στην 
ανάγνωση της μορφής παιχνιδιού "του ημερολογίου Αννας Φρανκ." 
Δείτε τη σύνδεση που δημιουργείται στο λογισμικό 
έμπνευσης για να αποκτήσει την επίγνωση στην οργάνωση της 
ολόκληρης μονάδας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este conjunto de lecciones se puede utilizar con 
"diferencias a través del plan de estudios: Partes 2, 3, y el 
4"como acercamiento integrado a la diversidad que explora con los 
octavos graduadores. La unidad girará alrededor del uso de la 
versión del drama "del diario de la carta franca de Anne." Los 
estudiantes aprenderán cómo la diversidad crea al sesgo que conduce 
para estar en conflicto, donde los estudiantes enfrentan su tolerancia
del diagonal y de la práctica. Estas piezas reflejan los cuatro
planes de estudios de la base en un acercamiento entretejido a los 
estudiantes de enseñanza para enfrentar sus diagonales, aprenden 
tolerancia, y deducen el impacto de éstos en sociedad de hoy. 
Esta actividad, parte 1, se significa para servir como actividad
de la pre-lectura a la lectura de la forma del juego "del diario de la
carta franca de Anne." Vea la conexión creada en software de la
inspiración para ganar la penetración a la organización de la 
unidad entera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LYNN CARTER
FN:LYNN CARTER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202650</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106303</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/differences-across-the-curriculum-part-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
