<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106866</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106866</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087313</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Less Reliable Form of Birth Control": Miriam Allen deFord Describes Her Introduction to Contraception in 1914</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein weniger zuverlässiges Formular der 
Geburtenkontrolle": Miriam Allen deFord beschreibt ihre 
Einleitung zur Empfängnisverhütung 1914</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une forme moins fiable de contrôle des 
naissances" : Le deFord de Miriam Allen décrit son introduction
à la contraception en 1914</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um formulário mais menos de confiança do 
controle de nascimento": O deFord de Miriam Allen descreve sua 
introdução ao contraception em 1914</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una forma meno certa di controllo di nascita": 
Il deFord di Miriam Allen descrive la sua introduzione alla 
contraccezione in 1914</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια λιγότερο αξιόπιστη μορφή του ελέγχου γέννησησ": 
Το Miriam Αλλεν deFord περιγράφει την εισαγωγή της στην
αντισύλληψη το 1914</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una forma menos confiable de control de la 
natalidad": El deFord de Miriam Allen describe su introducción 
a la contracepción en 1914</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Despite major cultural, legal, and medical impediments the use of birth control, including abortion, by American women was widespread at the turn of the century. In their quest to control unwanted pregnancies, American women could be surprisingly resourceful in the methods they used. In this audio excerpt from a 1974 interview with historian Sherna Gluck, Miriam Allen deFord described methods of birth control in vogue in the 1910s, including spermicides, douches, the Dutch pessary (an early diaphragm), and the use of ergot pills to induce abortion.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Trotz hauptsächlichen kulturellen waren 
zugelassene und medizinische Behinderungen der Gebrauch von 
Geburtenkontrolle, einschließlich Abtreibung, durch American Frauen 
an der Jahrhundertwende weitverbreitet. In ihrer Suche, zum der 
unerwünschten Schwangerschaften zu steuern, konnten amerikanische 
Frauen in den Methoden überraschend reich an Hilfsquellen sein, die 
sie verwendeten. In diesem Audioexcerpt von einem Interview 1974
mit Historiker Sherna Gluck, Miriam Allen deFord beschrieb Methoden 
der Geburtenkontrolle in der Mode in den 1910s, 
einschließlich spermicides, in den douches, im holländischen Pessary
(eine frühe Membrane), und im Gebrauch der Mutterkornpillen, 
Abtreibung zu verursachen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En dépit de culturel principal, les empêchements
légaux et et médicaux l'utilisation du contrôle des naissances, y 
compris la suspension, par des femmes d'American étaient répandus à
la fin du siècle. À leur recherche pour contrôler des 
grossesses non désirées, les femmes américaines pourraient être 
étonnamment inventives dans les méthodes qu'elles ont utilisées. 
Dans cet extrait sonore d'une entrevue 1974 avec l'historien 
Sherna Gluck, deFord de Miriam Allen a décrit des méthodes de 
contrôle des naissances dans la mode dans les années 10, y 
compris des spermicides, les douches, le pessary hollandais (un 
diaphragme tôt), et l'utilisation des pillules d'ergot de seigle 
d'induire la suspension.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Apesar de cultural principal, os impediments 
legais, e médicos o uso do controle de nascimento, including o 
abortion, por mulheres de Americano eram difundidos na volta do 
século. Em seu quest para controlar gravidezes não desejadas, 
as mulheres americanas poderiam ser surprisingly resourceful nos 
métodos que se usaram. Neste excerpt audio de uma entrevista 
1974 com historian Sherna Gluck, deFord de Miriam Allen descreveu 
métodos do controle de nascimento no vogue nos 1910s, including 
spermicides, em douches, no pessary holandês (um diafragma 
adiantado), e no uso de pills do ergot induzir o abortion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Malgrado culturale importante, gli impedimenti 
legali e e medici l'uso di controllo di nascita, compreso aborto, 
dalle donne dell'American erano diffusi alla fine del secolo. 
Nella loro ricerca per gestire le gravidanze indesiderabili, le 
donne americane potrebbero essere sorprendentemente inventive nei 
metodi che hanno usato. In questo brano audio da un'intervista 
1974 con lo storico Sherna Gluck, deFord di Miriam Allen ha descritto 
i metodi di controllo di nascita nel vogue negli anni 10, compreso gli
spermicides, nei douches, nel pessary olandese (un diaframma in 
anticipo) e nell'uso delle pillole della segale cornuta indurre 
l'aborto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παρά τα σημαντικά πολιτιστικά, νομικά, και ιατρικά 
εμπόδια η χρήση του ελέγχου γέννησης, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της 
άμβλωσης, από τις αμερικανικές γυναίκες ήταν διαδεδομένη στο 
γύρισμα του αιώνα. Στην αναζήτησή τους για να ελέγξουν τις 
ανεπιθύμητες εγκυμοσύνες, οι αμερικανικές γυναίκες θα μπορούσαν 
να είναι εκπληκτικά πολυμήχανες στις μεθόδους που χρησιμοποίησαν.
Σε αυτό το ηχητικό απόσπασμα από μια συνέντευξη του 1974
με τον ιστορικό Sherna Gluck, Miriam Αλλεν deFord 
περιέγραψε τις μεθόδους ελέγχου γέννησης στη μόδα στο 1910s, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένου spermicides, douches, ολλανδικό τον 
pessary (ένα πρόωρο διάφραγμα), και τη χρήση ergot των 
χαπιών για να προκαλέσει την άμβλωση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A pesar de cultural importante, los impedimientos 
legales, y médicos el uso del control de la natalidad, incluyendo el 
aborto, por las mujeres american eran extensos al final del siglo. 
En su búsqueda para controlar embarazos indeseados, las mujeres
americanas podrían ser asombrosamente inventivas en los métodos que 
utilizaron. En este extracto audio de una entrevista 1974 con el
historiador Sherna Gluck, deFord de Miriam Allen describió métodos 
de control de la natalidad en vogue en los años 10, incluyendo 
spermicides, los douches, el pesario holandés (un diafragma 
temprano), y el uso de las píldoras del cornezuelo de centeno de 
inducir el aborto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087313</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106866</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-less-reliable-form-of-birth-control-miriam-allen-deford-describes-her-introduction-to-contraception-in-1914</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
