<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106199</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106199</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087328</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Pledge of Allegiance: Joining the Grange</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Versprochene der Untertanentreue: Verbinden 
des Gutshofs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un engagement d'allégeance : Joindre la 
grange</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um pledge do allegiance: Juntando o grange</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un impegno di allegiance: Unire il grange</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια υποχρέωση της υποταγής: Ένωση του Grange</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un compromiso de la lealtad: Ensamblar el 
grange</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When the National Grange of the Patrons of Husbandry was first organized in Minnesota in December 1867, its goals were primarily social and educational. The organization spread rapidly throughout the agricultural Midwest, attracting more than 850,000 members by 1875. The Grange's purpose also expanded--it experimented (unsuccessfully) with cooperatives, and, angered by hard times, tight money, and high railroad shipping rates, moved into politics. Members elected sympathetic state legislators who passed laws (most of them later declared unconstitutional) regulating railroad and grain elevator charges. When agricultural conditions in the Midwest improved in the 1880s, the Grange's membership dropped to 150,000. The Farmers Alliance (or Populists) soon replaced the Grange as the primary voice of radical agrarianism. Still, the Grange continued as a nationwide social organization. Like other fraternal organizations, its members took part in elaborate rituals and ceremonies, as reflected in the following excerpt from the 1895 Grange Manual.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als der nationale Gutshof der Gönner des 
Ackerbaus zuerst in Minnesota im Dezember 1867 organisiert wurde, 
waren seine Ziele hauptsächlich sozial und pädagogisch. Die 
Organisation verbritt schnell in dem landwirtschaftlichen Mittelwesten
und zog mehr als 850.000 Bauteile bis zum 1875 an. Der Zweck des
Gutshofs erweiterte auch -- er experimentierte (erfolglos) mit den 
Mitwirkenden und, verärgert bis zum harten Zeiten, knappem Geld und 
den hohen Eisenbahnverschiffenkinetik, verschoben in Politik. 
Bauteile wählten sympatische Zustandgesetzgeber, die regelnde 
Eisenbahn der Gesetze (die meisten ihnen später erklärte 
verfassungswidriges) führten und Kornaufzug auflädt. Als 
landwirtschaftliche Bedingungen im Mittelwesten im 1880s verbesserten,
fiel die Mitgliedschaft des Gutshofs auf 150.000 ab. Das 
Landwirt-Bündnis (oder die Populisten) ersetzten bald den Gutshof als
die Primärstimme des radikalen Agrarianism. Noch fuhr der 
Gutshof als allgemein Sozialorganisation fort. Wie andere 
brüderliche Organisationen nahmen seine Bauteile an den durchdachten 
Ritualen und an den Zeremonien teil, wie im folgenden Excerpt vom 
Gutshof-Handbuch 1895 reflektiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand la grange nationale des patrons de 
l'agriculture a été organisée la première fois au Minnesota en 
décembre 1867, ses buts étaient principalement sociaux et 
éducatifs. L'organisation a écarté rapidement dans l'ensemble
du Midwest agricole, attirant plus de 850.000 membres d'ici 1875. 
Le but de la grange a également augmenté -- il a expérimenté
(sans succès) avec les coopératives, et, irritées par des périodes
difficiles, l'argent rare, et les cadences élevées d'expédition de 
chemin de fer, entrées dans la politique. Les membres ont élu 
les législateurs bien disposés d'état qui ont passé le chemin de 
fer de régulation de lois (plus d'eux plus tard a déclaré 
inconstitutionnel) et ascenseur de grain charge. Quand les 
conditions agricoles dans le Midwest se sont améliorées dans le 
1880s, l'adhésion de la grange a chuté à 150.000. L'alliance 
de fermiers (ou les populistes) a bientôt substitué la grange comme 
voix primaire d'agrarianisme radical. Toujours, la grange a 
continué comme organisation sociale dans tout le pays. Comme 
d'autres organismes fraternels, ses membres ont participé aux rituels
et aux cérémonies raffinés, comme reflété dans l'extrait suivant 
du manuel 1895 de grange.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando o grange nacional dos patrons do husbandry 
foi organizado primeiramente em Minnesota em dezembro 1867, seus 
objetivos eram primeiramente sociais e educacionais. A 
organização espalhou ràpidamente durante todo o Midwest 
agricultural, atraindo mais de 850.000 membros por 1875. A 
finalidade do grange expandiu também -- experimentou (em vão) com os
cooperatives, e, irritados por épocas duras, o dinheiro apertado, e 
as taxas elevadas do transporte da estrada de ferro, movidas na 
política. Os membros elegeram os legislators sympathetic do 
estado que passaram a estrada de ferro regulando das leis (mais deles 
declarou mais tarde unconstitutional) e elevador da grão carrega. 
Quando as condições agriculturais no Midwest melhoraram no 
1880s, a sociedade do grange deixou cair a 150.000. O alliance 
dos fazendeiros (ou os populists) substituíram logo o grange como a 
voz preliminar do agrarianism radical. Ainda, o grange continuou
como uma organização social de âmbito nacional. Como outras 
organizações fraternal, seus membros fizeram exame da parte em 
rituals e em ceremonies elaborados, como refletido no seguinte excerpt
do manual 1895 do grange.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando il grange nazionale dei patroni 
dell'agricoltura in primo luogo è stato organizzato nel Minnesota nel
mese di dicembre del 1867, i relativi obiettivi erano soprattutto 
sociali ed educativi. L'organizzazione si è sparsa velocemente 
durante il Midwest agricolo, attraente più di 850.000 membri entro 
1875. Lo scopo del grange egualmente si è espanso -- ha 
sperimentato (senza successo) con le cooperative e, fatte arrabbiare 
entro i periodi duri, i soldi stretti e gli alti tassi di trasporto 
della ferrovia, entrati nella politica. I membri hanno scelto 
simpatico dichiarano i legislatori che hanno passato la ferrovia 
regolante di leggi (la maggior parte di loro più successivamente ha 
dichiarato inconstituzionale) ed elevatore del grano si carica. 
Quando i termini agricoli nel Midwest hanno migliorato nel 
1880s, l'insieme dei membri del grange è caduto a 150.000. 
L'alleanza dei coltivatori (o populists) presto ha sostituito il
grange come la voce primaria di agrarianism radicale. Eppure, il
grange è continuato come organizzazione sociale nazionale. Come
altre organizzazioni fraterne, i relativi membri hanno partecipato ai 
rituali ed alle cerimonie elaborati, come riflesso nel seguente brano 
dal manuale 1895 del grange.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν το εθνικό Grange των προστατών της γεωργίας 
οργανώθηκε αρχικά σε Μινεσότα τον Δεκέμβριο του 1867, οι 
στόχοι του ήταν πρώτιστα κοινωνικοί και εκπαιδευτικοί. Η 
οργάνωση διέδωσε γρήγορα σε όλο γεωργικό midwest, 
προσελκύοντας περισσότερα από 850.000 μέλη από 1875. 
Ο σκοπός του Grange που επεκτείνεται επίσης -- 
πειραματίστηκε (ανεπιτυχώς) με τους συνεταιρισμούς, και, θυμωμένος
μέχρι τους σκληρούς χρόνους, τα σφιχτά χρήματα, και τα υψηλά 
ποσοστά ναυτιλίας σιδηροδρόμου, κινήθηκαν στην πολιτική. Τα
μέλη εξέλεξαν τους συμπονετικούς κρατικούς νομοθέτες που πέρασαν
δαπάνες σιδηροδρόμου νόμων (οι περισσότεροι από τους που 
κηρύσσονται αργότερα αντισυνταγματικούς) τις ρυθμίζοντας και 
σιταποθηκών. Όταν οι γεωργικοί όροι midwest που 
βελτιώθηκε στο 1880s, η ιδιότητα μέλους του Grange μειώθηκαν
σε 150.000. Η συμμαχία αγροτών (ή Populists) σύντομα 
αντικατέστησε το Grange ως αρχική φωνή του ριζικού 
agrarianism. Ακόμα, το Grange συνεχίστηκε ως σε εθνικό 
επίπεδο κοινωνική οργάνωση. Όπως άλλες αδελφικές 
οργανώσεις, τα μέλη του συμμετείχαν στα επιμελημένες τελετουργικά
και τις τελετές, όπως απεικονίζονται στο ακόλουθο απόσπασμα από 
το εγχειρίδιο 1895 Grange.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando el grange nacional de los patrón de la 
agricultura primero fue ordenado en Minnesota en diciembre de 1867, 
sus metas eran sobre todo sociales y educativas. La 
organización se separó rápidamente a través del Cercano oeste 
agrícola, atrayendo a más de 850.000 miembros antes de 1875. 
El propósito del grange también se amplió -- experimentó 
(sin éxito) con las cooperativas, y, encolerizadas por épocas duras,
el dinero apretado, y las altas tarifas del envío del ferrocarril, 
movidas en política. Los miembros eligieron a legisladores 
comprensivos del estado que pasaron el ferrocarril de regulación de 
los leyes (de ellos declaró más más adelante inconstitucional) y 
elevador del grano carga. Cuando las condiciones agrícolas en 
el Cercano oeste mejoraron en el 1880s, la calidad de miembro del 
grange cayó a 150.000. La alianza de los granjeros (o los 
populists) pronto substituyó el grange como la voz primaria del 
agrarismo radical. No obstante, el grange continuó como 
organización social a nivel nacional. Como otras organizaciones
fraternales, sus miembros participaron en rituales y ceremonias 
elaborados, según lo reflejado en el extracto siguiente del manual 
1895 del grange.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087328</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106199</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-pledge-of-allegiance-joining-the-grange</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
