<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106595</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106595</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086730</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Picturesque America."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Malerisches Amerika."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'Amérique Pittoresque."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"América Pitoresca."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"L'America Picturesque."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γραφική Αμερική."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"América Pintoresca."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Illustrator Harry Grant Dart's vision of the increasingly aggressive and intrusive character of advertising in turn-of-the-century America appeared in a 1909 issue of  Life . During this period, the growth of mass production and mass marketing changed the way consumer goods were bought and sold. Information about products now came not from those who made or sold them, but from persuasive advertisements trying to create brand recognition and brand loyalty. Advertisements moved out of separate sections in the back of magazines, as the newest periodicals featured full-page ads and depended upon advertising, rather than subscriptions, for their revenue. Coordinated advertising campaigns using billboards, store displays, and electric signs, became common.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Illustrator-Harry Grant Anblick des Pfeiles des in 
zunehmendem Maße konkurrenzfähigen und aufdringlichen Zeichens des 
Bekanntmachens in der Jahrhundertwende Amerika erschien in einer Ausgabe
1909 des Lebens. Während dieser Periode, änderte das Wachstum 
Großserienfertigung und Masse des Marketings die Methode, den 
Verbrauchsgüter gekauft und verkauft wurden. Informationen 
über Produkte kamen jetzt nicht von denen, die sie bildeten oder 
verkauften, aber von den überzeugenden Reklameanzeigen, die 
versuchen, Markenbewußtsein und Markentreue zu erstellen. 
Reklameanzeigen bewogen aus unterschiedlichen Kapiteln in der 
Rückseite der Zeitschriften, während die neuesten Zeitschriften 
ganzseitiges ADS kennzeichneten und nach dem Bekanntmachen abhingen, 
anstatt Subskriptionen, für ihr Einkommen heraus. Koordinierte 
Werbekampagnen mit Anschlagtafeln, Speicherbildschirmanzeigen und 
elektrischen Zeichen, wurden geläufig.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vision du dard de Harry Grant d'illustrateur du 
caractère de plus en plus agressif et intrusif de la publicité en 
tourner-de-le-siècle Amérique est apparue dans une issue 1909 de la 
vie. Pendant cette période, la croissance du marketing de 
production en série et de masse a changé la voie que des biens de 
consommation ont été achetés et vendus. Les informations sur 
des produits sont maintenant venues pas de ceux qui les ont faites ou 
ont vendu, mais des annonces persuasives essayant de créer 
l'identification de marque et la fidélité de marque. Les 
annonces se sont déplacées hors des sections séparées dans le dos 
des magasins, pendant que les plus nouveaux périodiques comportaient 
l'ADS sur une page entière et dépendaient de la publicité, plutôt 
que des abonnements, pour leur revenu. Les campagnes 
publicitaires coordonnées en utilisant des panneaux-réclame, des 
affichages de mémoire, et des signes électriques, sont devenues 
communes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A visão do dart de Harry Grant do illustrator do caráter
cada vez mais aggressive e intrusive de anunciar no 
gir-$$$-$$$-SÉCULO América apareceu em uma introdução 1909 da 
vida. Durante este período, o crescimento do marketing da 
produção maciça e da massa mudou a maneira os bens de consumidor 
que foram comprados e vendidos. A informação sobre produtos 
veio agora não daquelas que os fizeram ou venderam, mas das 
propagandas persuasive que tentam criar o recognition de tipo e a 
lealdade de tipo. As propagandas moveram-se fora das seções 
separadas na parte traseira dos compartimentos, enquanto os 
periodicals os mais novos caracterizaram o ads full-page e dependeram 
em cima de anunciar, melhor que das subscrições, para seu 
rendimento. As campanhas anunciando coordenadas usando 
billboards, indicadores da loja, e sinais elétricos, tornaram-se 
comuns.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La visione del dardo del Harry Grant del illustrator del 
carattere sempre più aggressivo ed intrusivo di pubblicità nel 
gir-de-$$$-SECOLO America è comparso in un'emissione 1909 di vita. 
Durante questo periodo, lo sviluppo dell'introduzione sul 
mercato della massa e di fabbricazione in serie ha cambiato il modo le
merci di consumatore che sono state comprate e che venduto state. 
Le informazioni sui prodotti ora sono venuto non da coloro che 
le ha fatte o venduto, ma dalle pubblicità convincenti che provano a 
creare il riconoscimento di marca e la lealtà di marca. Le 
pubblicità si sono mosse dalle sezioni separate nella parte 
posteriore degli scomparti, mentre i più nuovi periodici hanno 
caratterizzato il ads fuori testo e dipendevano dalla pubblicità, 
piuttosto che dagli abbonamenti, per il loro reddito. Le 
campagne pubblicitarie coordinate usando i tabelloni per le 
affissioni, le visualizzazioni del deposito ed i segni elettrici, sono
diventato comuni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το όραμα Harry Grant Dart's εικονογράφων του 
όλο και περισσότερο επιθετικού και παρεισφρητικού χαρακτήρα της 
διαφήμισης στον στροφή-$$$-Ο-ΑΙΏΝΑ Αμερική εμφανίστηκε σε ένα 
ζήτημα του 1909 της ζωής. Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της 
περιόδου, η αύξηση της μαζικής παραγωγής και του μαζικού 
μάρκετινγκ άλλαξε τα καταναλωτικά αγαθά τρόπων αγοράστηκε και 
πωλήθηκε. Οι πληροφορίες για τα προϊόντα προήλθαν τώρα 
όχι από εκείνους που τους έκαναν ή πώλησαν, αλλά από τις 
πειστικές διαφημίσεις που προσπαθούν να δημιουργήσουν την 
αναγνώριση εμπορικών σημάτων και την πίστη εμπορικών σημάτων. 
Οι διαφημίσεις κινήθηκαν από τα χωριστά τμήματα στο πίσω 
μέρος των περιοδικών, δεδομένου ότι τα νεώτερα περιοδικά 
χαρακτήρισαν τις ολόκληρης σελίδας αγγελίες και εξαρτήθηκαν από 
τη διαφήμιση, παρά τις συνδρομές, για το εισόδημά τους. Οι 
συντονισμένες διαφημιστικές εκστρατείες που χρησιμοποιούν τους 
πίνακες διαφημίσεων, τις παρουσιάσεις καταστημάτων, και τα 
ηλεκτρικά σημάδια, έγιναν κοινές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La visión del dardo de Harry Grant del ilustrador del 
carácter cada vez más agresivo e intruso de la publicidad en el dar 
vuelta-de-$$$-SIGLO América apareció en una aplicación 1909 la 
vida. Durante este período, el crecimiento de la 
comercialización de la producción en masa y de la masa cambió la 
manera que los bienes de consumo fueron comprados y que vendidos. 
La información sobre productos ahora vino no de las que los 
hicieron o vendieron, pero de los anuncios persuasivos que intentaban 
crear el reconocimiento de marca de fábrica y la lealtad de marca de 
fábrica. Los anuncios se movieron de secciones separadas en la 
parte posteriora de compartimientos, mientras que los periódicos más
nuevos ofrecieron el ads full-page y dependieron de la publicidad, 
más bien que de suscripciones, para su rédito. Las campañas 
publicitarias coordinadas usando las carteleras, las visualizaciones 
del almacén, y las muestras eléctricas, llegaron a ser comunes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086730</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106595</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/picturesque-america</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
