<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104909</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104909</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086692</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"One of the Primitive Sort": Chester Harding Becomes an Artist in the Early 19th-Century Countryside</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein der ursprünglichen Sortierung": 
Chester Harding steht einem Künstler in der frühen Landschaft 
19th-Century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un du tri primitif" : Chester Harding va 
bien à un artiste dans la campagne 19th-Century tôt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma da sorte primitiva": Chester Harding 
assenta bem em um artista no campo 19th-Century adiantado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"uno dell'ordinamento primitivo": Chester 
Harding sta bene ad un artista nella campagna in anticipo 
19th-Century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα από το πρωτόγονο είδοσ": Το Τσέστερ 
Harding γίνεται καλλιτέχνης στην πρόωρη επαρχία 19$ος-αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"uno de la clase primitiva": Chester Harding
siente bien a un artista en el campo temprano 19th-Century</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Farming was not the only occupation in early nineteenth-century rural America. Many young entrepreneurs were able to take advantage of the countryside's increasing commercial activity and growing consumer desires by taking to the road to work. Chester Harding, born in Conway, Massachusetts, survived by working in a variety of country crafts as he related in his 1866 autobiography  My Egotistigraphy . His early skill in painting signs led to his painting faces, and he grew more expert in portraiture as he practiced on his business patrons, providing them with a rare likeness to display in their homes. Initially far more artisan than artist, Harding, unlike most of his fellow itinerant and self-taught colleagues, ended up one of the most renowned academic artists in antebellum America.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Bewirtschaften war nicht die einzige Besetzung
im frühen 19.-Jahrhundert landwirtschaftliches Amerika. Viele 
junge Unternehmer konnten, Nutzen aus der zunehmenden kommerziellen 
Aktivität der Landschaft zu ziehen und wachsender Verbraucher 
wünscht, indem er zur Straße zur Arbeit nimmt. Chester 
Harding, getragen in Conway, Massachusetts, überlebte, indem es in 
einer Vielzahl der Landfertigkeiten arbeitete, wie er in seiner 
Autobiographie 1866 mein Egotistigraphy in Verbindung stand. 
Seine frühe Fähigkeit in den Anstrichzeichen führte zu seine 
Anstrichgesichter, und er wuchs im portraiture sachverständiger, 
während er auf seinen Geschäft Gönnern übte und versah sie mit 
einer seltenen Gleichheit, um in ihren Häusern anzuzeigen. 
Zuerst wurde weit mehr Handwerker als Künstler, Harding, anders
als die meisten seinen Mitreisenden und self-taught Kollegen, herauf 
einen der berühmtesten akademischen Künstler in antebellum Amerika 
fertig.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'affermage n'était pas le seul métier en 
dix-neuvième-siècle tôt Amérique rurale. Beaucoup de jeunes 
entrepreneurs pouvaient tirer profit de l'activité commerciale 
croissante de la campagne et le consommateur grandissant désire par 
la prise à la route au travail. Chester Harding, soutenu dans 
Conway, le Massachusetts, a survécu en travaillant dans une variété
de métiers de pays comme il a rapporté en sa autobiographie 1866 mon
Egotistigraphy. Sa première compétence dans des signes de 
peinture a mené à ses visages de peinture, et il s'est développé 
plus expert en matière d'art du portrait pendant qu'il pratiquait sur ses
patrons d'affaires, leur fournissant une similarité rare pour 
afficher dans leurs maisons. Au commencement bien plus d'artisan
que l'artiste, Harding, à la différence de la plupart de son 
camarade ambulant et de collègues de art de l'auto-portrait-taught, a terminé vers
le haut d'un des artistes d'universitaire les plus renommés en 
Amérique d'avant-guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cultivar não era a única ocupação no 
décimo-século adiantado América rural. Muitos empreendedores 
novos podiam  fazer exame da vantagem da atividade comercial crescente
do campo e o consumidor crescente deseja fazendo exame à estrada ao 
trabalho. Chester Harding, carregado em Conway, Massachusetts, 
sobreviveu trabalhando em uma variedade de ofícios do país como 
relacionou em seu autobiography 1866 meu Egotistigraphy. Sua 
habilidade adiantada em sinais da pintura conduziu a suas caras da 
pintura, e cresceu mais perito no portraiture enquanto praticou em 
seus patrons do negócio, fornecendo os com um likeness raro para 
indicar em suas HOME. Inicialmente distante mais artisan do que 
o artista, Harding, ao contrário de a maioria de seus colegas 
itinerant e self-taught do companheiro, terminou acima de um dos 
artistas academic os mais renowned em América antebellum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'agricoltura non era l'unica occupazione nel 
diciannovesimo-secolo in anticipo America rurale. Molti 
imprenditori giovani potevano approfittare dell'attività commerciale 
aumentante della campagna ed il consumatore crescente vuole prendendo 
alla strada al lavoro. Chester Harding, sopportato in Conway, 
Massachusetts, è sopravvissuto funzionando in una varietà di 
mestieri del paese come ha riferito in suo autobiography 1866 il mio 
Egotistigraphy. La sua abilità iniziale nei segni della pittura
ha condotto alle sue facce della pittura e si è sviluppato più 
esperto in portraiture mentre si è esercitato in sui suoi patroni di 
affari, fornente loro una somiglianza rara per visualizzare nelle loro
sedi. Inizialmente molto più artigianale che l'artista, 
Harding, diverso di la maggior parte dei suoi colleghe ambulanti e 
self-taught del collega, si è concluso su uno degli artisti 
accademici più renowned in America antebellum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η καλλιέργεια δεν ήταν το μόνο επάγγελμα στον πρόωρο 
δέκατος-αιώνα αγροτική Αμερική. Πολλοί νέοι 
επιχειρηματίες ήταν σε θέση να εκμεταλλευθούν την αυξανόμενη 
εμπορική δραστηριότητα της επαρχίας και τις αυξανόμενες 
καταναλωτικές επιθυμίες με τη λήψη στο δρόμο στην εργασία. 
Τσέστερ Harding, γεννημένο σε Conway, Μασαχουσέτη, που 
επιζείται δουλεύοντας σε ποικίλες τέχνες χωρών δεδομένου ότι 
αφορούσε στην αυτοβιογραφία 1866 του το Egotistigraphy μου. 
Η πρόωρη ικανότητά του στη ζωγραφική των σημαδιών οδήγησε 
στα πρόσωπα ζωγραφικής του, και αυξήθηκε περισσότερο 
εμπειρογνώμονα στο πορτρέτο όπως άσκησε στους επιχειρησιακούς 
προστάτες του, που παρέχουν σε τους μια σπάνια ομοιότητα στην 
παρουσίαση στα σπίτια τους. Αρχικά πολύ πιό χειροτεχνικός 
από τον καλλιτέχνη, Harding, αντίθετα από τους περισσότερους 
από τους συντροφικούς πλανόδιους και αυτοδίδακτους συναδέλφους 
του, κατέληξε έναν από τους πιό διάσημους ακαδημαϊκούς 
καλλιτέχνες στην προπολεμική Αμερική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El cultivar no era la única ocupación en el 
diecinueveavo-siglo temprano América rural. Muchos empresarios 
jóvenes podían aprovecharse de la actividad comercial de aumento del
campo y el consumidor creciente desea llevando el camino al trabajo. 
Chester Harding, llevado en Conway, Massachusetts, sobrevivió 
trabajando en una variedad de artes del país como él relacionó en 
su autobiografía 1866 mi Egotistigraphy. Su habilidad temprana 
en muestras de la pintura condujo a sus caras de la pintura, y él 
creció más experto en el portraiture como él practicó en sus 
patrón del negocio, proveiendo de ellos una semejanza rara para 
visualizar en sus hogares. Inicialmente lejos más artesano que 
el artista, Harding, desemejante de la mayoría de sus colegas 
ambulantes y autodidactas del compañero, terminó encima de uno de 
los artistas académicos más renombrados de América antebellum.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086692</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104909</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/one-of-the-primitive-sort-chester-harding-becomes-an-artist-in-the-early-19th-century-countryside</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
