<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103705</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103705</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200401</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">All that Glitters...</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ganzes Funkeln...</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tout ce scintillements...</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Todo esse glitters...</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tutto quel scintilli...</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όλα αυτά ακτινοβολούν...</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Todo ese brillos...</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Ocean Explorer lesson plan (PDF) explores the questions: What colors, if any, are visible down in the deep sea? What is bioluminescence? Students will learn about white light (visible light), the quantity and quality of light as related to ocean depth, the difference in water penetration between red light and blue light, bioluminescent organisms, the color of most bioluminescent light, and why organisms bioluminesce. The lesson plan includes background information and keywords, a list of materials, teacher preparation instructions, learning procedures, related links, evaluation and extension ideas, and correlation to the national standards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Ozean-Forscherlektionplan (pdf) erforscht 
die Fragen: Was färbt, wenn irgendein, sind sichtbarer Abstieg 
im tiefen Meer? Was ist bioluminescence? Kursteilnehmer 
erlernen über weißes Licht (sichtbares Licht), die Quantität und 
die Qualität des Lichtes bezüglich der Ozeantiefe, den Unterschied 
bezüglich des Wasserdurchgriffes zwischen rotes Licht und blaues 
Licht, bioluminescent organismen, die Farbe des meisten bioluminescent
Lichtes und warum organismen bioluminesce. Der Lektionplan 
schließt Hintergrundinformationen und Schlüsselwörter, eine Liste 
der Materialien, Lehrervorbereitung Anweisungen, Lernenprozeduren, in 
Verbindung gestandene Links, Auswertung und Extension Ideen und 
Wechselbeziehung zu den nationalen Standards ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce plan de leçon d'explorateur d'océan (pdf) 
explore les questions : Que colore, le cas échéant, est bas 
visible en mer profonde ? Quel est bioluminescence ? Les 
étudiants se renseigneront sur la lumière blanche (lumière 
visible), la quantité et la qualité de la lumière par rapport à la
profondeur d'océan, la différence dans la pénétration de l'eau 
entre la lumière rouge et la lumière bleue, les organizations 
bioluminescent, la couleur de la plupart de lumière bioluminescent, 
et pourquoi bioluminesce d'organizations. Le plan de leçon 
inclut l'information de fond et les mots-clés, une liste de 
matériaux, des procédures d'instructions de préparation de 
professeur, d'étude, des liens associés, des idées d'évaluation et
d'extension, et corrélation aux normes nationales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta planta da lição do explorador do oceano 
(pdf) explora as perguntas: Que colore, se algum, é pena 
visível no mar profundo? Que é bioluminescence? Os 
estudantes aprenderão sobre a luz branca (luz visível), a quantidade
e a qualidade da luz como relacionado à profundidade do oceano, a 
diferença na penetração da água entre a luz vermelha e a luz azul,
organismos bioluminescent, a cor de a maioria de luz bioluminescent, e
porque bioluminesce dos organismos. A planta da lição inclui a
informação e os keywords de fundo, uma lista dos materiais, 
procedimentos das instruções da preparação do professor, da 
aprendizagem, as ligações relacionadas, as idéias da avaliação e 
da extensão, e a correlação aos padrões nacionais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma di lezione dell'esploratore 
dell'oceano (pdf) esplora le domande: Che cosa colora, 
all'occorrenza, è basso visibile nel mare profondo? Che cosa è
bioluminescence? Gli allievi impareranno circa luce bianca (luce
visibile), la quantità e la qualità di luce rispetto a profondità 
dell'oceano, la differenza nella penetrazione dell'acqua fra luce 
rossa e luce blu, organismi bioluminescent, il colore della maggior 
parte della luce bioluminescent e perchè bioluminesce degli 
organismi. Il programma di lezione include le informazioni di 
base e parole chiavi, una lista dei materiali, procedure di istruzioni
della preparazione dell'insegnante, imparare, collegamenti riferiti, 
idee di estensione e di valutazione e correlazione agli standard 
nazionali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το ωκεάνιο σχέδιο μαθήματος εξερευνητών (PDF)
ερευνά τις ερωτήσεις: Τί χρώματα είναι, ενδεχομένως, 
ορατά κάτω στα μεγάλα θαλάσσια βάθη; Τι είναι βιολογική 
ακτινοβολία; Οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν για το άσπρο φως 
(ορατό φως), την ποσότητα και την ποιότητα του φωτός σε σχέση με 
το ωκεάνιο βάθος, τη διαφορά στη διείσδυση ύδατος μεταξύ του 
κόκκινου φωτός και τους μπλε ελαφριούς, βιοφωτοβόλους 
οργανισμούς, το χρώμα του περισσότερου βιοφωτοβόλου φωτός, και 
γιατί οργανισμοί bioluminesce. Το σχέδιο μαθήματος 
περιλαμβάνει τις βασικές πληροφορίες και τις λέξεις κλειδιά, 
ένας κατάλογος υλικών, οδηγιών προετοιμασιών δασκάλων, 
διαδικασιών εκμάθησης, σχετικών συνδέσεων, ιδεών αξιολόγησης και
επέκτασης, και συσχετισμού στα εθνικά πρότυπα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de la lección del explorador del 
océano (pdf) explora las preguntas: ¿Qué colorea, si 
cualquiera, es llanura visible en el mar profundo? ¿Cuál es 
bioluminescence? Los estudiantes aprenderán sobre la luz blanca
(luz visible), la cantidad y la calidad de la luz con respecto a 
profundidad del océano, la diferencia en la penetración del agua 
entre la luz roja y la luz azul, organismos bioluminescent, el color 
de la mayoría de la luz bioluminescent, y porqué bioluminesce de los
organismos. El plan de la lección incluye la información y 
palabras claves de fondo, una lista de materiales, los procedimientos 
de las instrucciones de la preparación del profesor, el aprender, las
conexiones relacionadas, las ideas de la evaluación y de la 
extensión, y correlación a los estándares nacionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:OCEAN EXPLORER
FN:OCEAN EXPLORER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NOAA
FN:NOAA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200401</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103705</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/all-that-glitters</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
