<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103603</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103603</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086237</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Heterogeneous Grouping and High Standards in an Untracked Advanced English Class</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Heterogene Gruppierung und hohe Standards in 
einer Untracked hochentwickelten englischen Kategorie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Grouper hétérogène et niveaux élevés dans 
une classe anglaise avançée d'Untracked</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Agrupar heterogêneo e padrões elevados em uma 
classe inglesa avançada de Untracked</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Raggruppamento eterogeneo e livelli alti in un 
codice categoria inglese avanzato di Untracked</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ετερογενής ομαδοποίηση και τα υψηλά πρότυπα σε ένα 
Untracked προώθησαν την αγγλική κλάση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El agrupar heterogéneo y mayores niveles en una 
clase inglesa avanzada de Untracked</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website describes Joan Cone's teaching journey to address challenges of diversity, inequity, and achievement in her High School English classroom. At El Cerrito High School, Cone has been an integral part of an ongoing struggle to detrack the English curriculum. Over the past few years, her thinking has built from an investigation into the 'co-construction of low achievement,' to address what she's learned by developing essential practices to construct students as achievers in her classroom and the school.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site beschreibt Reise Unterricht des 
Joan Kegels, um Herausforderungen der Verschiedenartigkeit, der 
Ungerechtigkeit und der Ausführung in ihrem High School 
Englischklassenzimmer zu adressieren. EL Cerrito an der High 
School ist Kegel ein wesentlicher Bestandteil eines fortwährenden 
Kampfes zum detrack der englische Lehrplan gewesen. Während der
letzten Jahre hat sie denkend von einer Untersuchung in den ' 
Co-Aufbau der niedrigen Ausführung, ' aufgebaut, um zu adressieren, 
was ihr erlernt wird, indem man wesentliche Praxis entwickelt, 
Kursteilnehmer als Durchführer in ihrem Klassenzimmer und in der 
Schule zu konstruieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web décrit le voyage de l'enseignement 
du cône de Joan pour adresser des défis de diversité, d'injustice, 
et d'accomplissement dans sa salle de classe de l'anglais de lycée. 
Au lycée de EL Cerrito, le cône a été une partie intégrale 
d'une lutte continue au detrack le programme d'études anglais. 
Au cours de ces dernières années, elle pensant a construit 
d'une recherche sur la 'Co-construction du bas accomplissement, 'pour 
adresser ce qu'elle est apprise en développant des pratiques 
essentielles de construire des étudiants comme accomplisseuses dans 
sa salle de classe et l'école.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site descreve a viagem do ensino do cone
de Joan para dirigir-se a desafios da diversidade, do inequity, e da 
realização em sua sala de aula do inglês da High School. Na 
High School do EL Cerrito, o cone foi uma parte integral de um 
esforço ongoing ao detrack o curriculum inglês. Sobre o 
passado poucos anos, ela que pensa construíram de uma investigação 
' na co-construção da realização baixa, ' para dirigir-se a o que 
é aprendida desenvolvendo práticas essenciais construir estudantes 
como empreendedores em sua sala de aula e na escola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site descrive il viaggio di 
insegnamento del cono di Joan per richiamare le sfide della 
diversità, dell'ingiustizia e del successo nella sua aula di inglese 
della High School. Alla High School di EL Cerrito, il cono è 
stato una parte integrante di una lotta continua a detrack il 
programma di studi inglese. Durante questi ultimi anni, lei che 
pensa ha costruito da una ricerca 'sulla co-costruzione del successo 
basso, 'per richiamare che cosa è imparata sviluppando le pratiche 
essenziali costruire gli allievi come uomini d'azione nella sua aula e
nella scuola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος περιγράφει το ταξίδι διδασκαλίας 
του Joan Cone's για να εξετάσει τις προκλήσεις της 
ποικιλομορφίας, της αδικίας, και του επιτεύγματος στην αγγλική 
τάξη γυμνασίου της. Στο γυμνάσιο EL Cerrito, ο κώνος 
είναι ένα αναπόσπαστο τμήμα μιας τρέχουσας προσπάθειας στο 
detrack το αγγλικό πρόγραμμα σπουδών. Τα τελευταία 
χρόνια, η σκέψη της έχει χτίσει από μια έρευνα σχετικά με την 
"ομο-κατασκευή του χαμηλού επιτεύγματος," για να εξετάσει τι 
έμαθε με την ανάπτυξη των ουσιαστικών πρακτικών να κατασκευάσει 
τους σπουδαστές ως ολοκληρωτές στην τάξη της και σχολείο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site describe viaje de la enseñanza del
cono de Joan para tratar desafíos de la diversidad, de la injusticia,
y del logro en su sala de clase del inglés de la High School 
secundaria. En la High School secundaria del EL Cerrito, el cono
ha sido una parte integral de una lucha en curso al detrack el plan de
estudios inglés. Durante los últimos años, ella que pensaba 
ha construido de una investigación en la ' co-construccio'n del logro
bajo, ' para tratar lo que desarrollando le aprende prácticas 
esenciales de construir a estudiantes como cumplidores en su sala de 
clase y la escuela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOAN CONE
FN:JOAN CONE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086237</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103603</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/heterogeneous-grouping-and-high-standards-in-an-untracked-advanced-english-class-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
