<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104914</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104914</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087319</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Message to Garca": Elbert Hubbard's Paean to Perseverance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"eine Meldung zu Garca": Elbert Hubbards 
Lobrede zur Ausdauer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un message à Garca" : Péan d'Elbert 
Hubbard à la persévérance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma mensagem a Garca": Paean de Elbert 
Hubbard ao perseverance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un messaggio a Garca": Paean di Elbert 
Hubbard a perseveranza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα μήνυμα σε Garca": Παιάνας Hubbard 
Elbert στην εμμονή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un mensaje a Garca": Paean de Elbert 
Hubbard a la perseverencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The best-known image of America's 1898 war with Spain is that of Teddy Roosevelt on horseback charging with his Rough Riders up San Juan Hill in Cuba. While the Rough Riders fired the first shot in the war and were the first to raise the U.S. flag in Cuba, their exploits were greatly mythologized. Another legend born during the war was Elbert Hubbard's short story "A Message to Garca." Published as a book in 1898, 40 million copies had been printed by 1913. Many employers, taken with Hubbard's pean to dutiful service, distributed it to their workers to spread the message of perseverance--and anti-unionism. Hubbard's story described the activities of U.S. Army Lieutenant Andrew S. Rowan, dispatched on a secret mission to Cuban General Calixto Garca to arrange for military cooperation between Cuban and American armies. Hubbard's mythmaking distorted the story of the war by erasing the contribution of the Cubans from the history of their own war for independence. By 1898, Cubans had already been waging an armed struggle for independence from Spain for three years.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das bekannteste Bild von Amerikas 1898 Krieg mit 
Spanien ist das von Teddy Roosevelt auf mit seinen rauhen Mitfahrern 
herauf San Juan Hügel in Kuba zu Pferde aufladen. Während die 
rauhen Mitfahrer den ersten Schuß im Krieg abfeuerten und die ersten 
waren, zum der VEREINIGTEN STAATEN anzuheben kennzeichnen in Kuba, 
waren ihre Großtaten mythologized groß. Eine andere Legende, 
die während des Krieges getragen wurde, war Elbert Hubbards kurze 
Geschichte "eine Meldung zu Garca." Veröffentlicht als Buch 
1898, waren 40 Million Exemplare bis zum 1913 gedruckt worden. 
Viele Arbeitgeber, genommen mit Hubbards, das zum dutiful 
Service pean ist, verteilten ihn auf ihre Arbeiter, um die Meldung von
Ausdauer -- und von anti-unionism zu verbreiten. Geschichte 
Hubbards beschrieb die Aktivitäten des VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Armee-Leutnants Andrew S. Rowan, geschickt auf einer geheimen Mission 
zum kubanischen General Calixto Garca, um für militärische Mitarbeit
zwischen den kubanischen und amerikanischen Armeen zu ordnen. 
Hubbards, das mythmaking ist, verzerrte die Geschichte des 
Krieges, indem er den Beitrag der Kubaner von der Geschichte ihres 
eigenen Krieges für Unabhängigkeit löschte. Bis zum 1898 
hatten Kubaner bereits einen bewaffneten Kampf für Unabhängigkeit 
von Spanien für drei Jahre unternommen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'image la plus connue de la guerre de l'Amérique
1898 avec l'Espagne est celle du nounours Roosevelt chargeant à 
cheval de ses cavaliers approximatifs vers le haut de colline de San 
Juan au Cuba. Tandis que les cavaliers approximatifs 
mettaient le feu au premier projectile dans la guerre et étaient les 
premiers pour soulever les ETATS-UNIS diminuent au Cuba, leurs 
exploits étaient mythologized considérablement. Une autre 
légende soutenue pendant la guerre était histoire courte d'Elbert 
Hubbard "un message à Garca." Édité comme livre en 1898, 40 
millions de copies avaient été imprimées d'ici 1913. Beaucoup
d'employeurs, portés avec Hubbard pean au service dévoué, l'ont 
distribué à leurs ouvriers pour écarter le message de la 
persévérance -- et de l'anti-syndicalisme. L'histoire de Hubbard 
a décrit les activités de lieutenant Andrew S. Rowan d'armée des 
ETATS-UNIS, acheminées sur une mission secrète au Général cubain 
Calixto Garca pour assurer la coopération militaire entre les armées
cubaines et américaines. Hubbard mythmaking a tordu l'histoire 
de la guerre en effaçant la contribution des Cubains de l'histoire de
leur propre guerre pour l'indépendance. D'ici 1898, les Cubains
avaient déjà fait une lutte armée pour l'indépendance d'Espagne 
pendant trois années.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A imagem a mais best-known da guerra de América 
1898 com o Spain é aquela do teddy Roosevelt horseback em carregar 
com seus cavaleiros ásperos acima do monte do San Juan em Cuba. 
Quando os cavaleiros ásperos atearam fogo ao primeiro tiro na 
guerra e foram os primeiros para levantar os ESTADOS UNIDOS 
embandeiram em Cuba, suas façanhas eram mythologized extremamente. 
Uma outra legenda carregada durante a guerra era história curta
de Elbert Hubbard "uma mensagem a Garca." Publicado como um 
livro em 1898, 40 milhão cópias tinham sido imprimidas por 1913. 
Muitos empregadores, feitos exame com o Hubbard pean ao serviço
dutiful, distribuíram-no a seus trabalhadores para espalhar a 
mensagem do perseverance -- e do anti-unionism. A história de 
Hubbard descreveu as atividades do tenente Andrew S. Rowan do 
exército de ESTADOS UNIDOS, despachadas em uma missão secreta ao 
general cuban Calixto Garca para arranjar para a cooperação militar 
entre exércitos cuban e americanos. Hubbard que mythmaking 
distorceu a história da guerra apagando a contribuição dos cubanos 
do history de sua própria guerra para a independência. Por 
1898, os cubanos têm empreendido já um esforço armado para a 
independência de Spain por três anos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'immagine più nota della guerra dell'America 
1898 con la Spagna è quella del teddy Roosevelt a cavallo sul 
caricarsi dei suoi riders approssimativi sulla collina di San Juan in 
Cuba. Mentre i riders approssimativi hanno infornato il primo 
colpo nella guerra ed erano i primi per alzare gli STATI UNITI 
diminuiscono in Cuba, le loro imprese erano notevolmente mythologized.
Un'altra leggenda sopportata durante la guerra era storia corta 
di Elbert Hubbard "un messaggio a Garca." Pubblicato come libro 
in 1898, 40 milione copie erano state stampate entro 1913. Molti
datori di lavoro, presi con Hubbard pean a servizio dutiful, lo hanno 
distribuito ai loro operai per spargere il messaggio della 
perseveranza -- e del anti-unionism. La storia del Hubbard ha 
descritto le attività del tenente Andrew S. Rowan dell'esercito degli
STATI UNITI, spedite su una missione segreta al General cuban Calixto 
Garca per assicurare la cooperazione militare fra gli eserciti cuban 
ed americani. Hubbard che mythmaking ha storto la storia della 
guerra cancellando il contributo dei cubani dalla storia della loro 
propria guerra per indipendenza. Entro 1898, i cubani già 
stavano intraprendendo una lotta munita per indipendenza dalla Spagna 
per tre anni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πιό γνωστή εικόνα του πολέμου 1898 της Αμερικής 
με την Ισπανία είναι αυτή Teddy Roosevelt στην πλάτη αλόγου
που χρεώνει με τους τραχιούς αναβάτες του επάνω στο SAN Juan
Hill στην Κούβα. Ενώ οι τραχιοί αναβάτες έβαλαν φωτιά 
στο πρώτο πλάνο στον πόλεμο και ήταν το πρώτο για να αυξήσουν 
την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ σημαία στην Κούβα, οι άθλοι τους ήταν πολύ. 
Ένας άλλος μύθος γεννημένος κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου 
ήταν σύντομη ιστορία Elbert Hubbard "ένα μήνυμα σε 
Garca." Δημοσιευμένα ως βιβλίο το 1898 ..40 
εκατομμύριο αντίγραφα ήταν τυπωμένων από 1913, Πολλοί 
εργοδότες, που λήφθηκαν με Hubbard pean στην υπάκουα 
υπηρεσία, το διένειμαν στους εργαζομένους τους για να διαδώσουν το
μήνυμα της εμμονής -- και του αντι-συνδικαλισμού. Η ιστορία 
του Hubbard περιέγραψε τις δραστηριότητες του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ 
στρατού Lieutenant Andrew Θ*ς. Rowan, που αποστάλησαν σε 
μια μυστική αποστολή στον κουβανικό στρατηγό Calixto Garca 
που τακτοποιεί για στρατιωτική συνεργασία μεταξύ των κουβανικών 
και αμερικανικών στρατών. Του Hubbard διαστρέβλωσε την 
ιστορία του πολέμου με το σβήσιμο της συμβολής των Κουβανών από 
την ιστορία του πολέμου τους για την ανεξαρτησία. Από 
1898, Κουβανοί ήδη μια οπλισμένη προσπάθεια για την 
ανεξαρτησία από την Ισπανία για τρία έτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La imagen más conocida de la guerra de América 
1898 con España es la del teddy Roosevelt en a caballo la carga con 
sus jinetes ásperos encima de la colina del San Juan en Cuba. 
Mientras que los jinetes ásperos encendieron el primer tiro en 
la guerra y eran los primeros para levantar los ESTADOS UNIDOS 
señalan por medio de una bandera en Cuba, sus hazañas eran 
mythologized grandemente. Otra leyenda llevada durante la guerra
era historia corta de Elbert Hubbard "un mensaje a Garca." 
Publicado como libro en 1898, 40 millones de copias habían sido
impresas antes de 1913. Muchos patrones, llevados con Hubbard 
pean al servicio dutiful, lo distribuyeron a sus trabajadores para 
separar el mensaje de la perseverencia -- y del anti-unionism. 
La historia de Hubbard describió las actividades de teniente 
Andrew S. Rowan del ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS, enviadas en una 
misión secreta a general cubano Calixto Garca para arreglar para la 
cooperación militar entre los ejércitos cubanos y americanos. 
Hubbard mythmaking torció la historia de la guerra borrando la 
contribución de los cubanos de la historia de su propia guerra para 
la independencia. Antes de 1898, los cubanos habían estado 
emprendiendo ya una lucha armada para la independencia de España por 
tres años.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087319</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104914</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-message-to-garca-elbert-hubbards-paean-to-perseverance</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
