<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106643</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106643</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086413</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lincoln Steffens Exposes "Tweed Days in St. Louis"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lincoln Steffens stellt "Tweed-Tage in St. Louis" 
heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lincoln Steffens expose des "jours de tweed à St 
Louis"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lincoln Steffens expõe do "dias tweed em St. 
Louis"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lincoln Steffens espone "i giorni del tweed a St. 
Louis"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Λίνκολν Steffens εκθέτει τις "ημέρες τουίντ στο 
ST Louis"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lincoln Steffens expone "días del tweed en St. 
Louis"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The rise of mass circulation magazines combined with the reform impulses of the early 20th century to create the form of investigative journalism known as "muckracking" (so named by President Theodore Roosevelt after the muckrake in Bunyan's  Pilgrim's Progress  who could "look no way but downward, with a muckrake in his hands"). In the 1890s, changes in printing technology made possible inexpensive magazines that could appeal to a broader and increasingly more literate middle-class audience. In October 1902  McClure's   Magazine  published what many consider the first muckraking article, Lincoln Steffens' "Tweed Days in St. Louis." The "muckrakers" wrote on many subjects, including child labor, prisons, religion, corporations, and insurance companies. But urban political corruption remained a particularly popular target, perhaps because it was so blatant, and perhaps because the differences between the muckrakers (mostly middle class and of native Protestant stock) and the political bosses (mostly from Catholic and immigrant backgrounds) made the rule of the immigrant machine appear as an alien intrusion, a corruption of American citizenship.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anstieg der Massenzirkulation Zeitschriften 
kombinierte mit den Verbesserungantrieben des frühen 20. 
Jahrhunderts, um das Formular von Untersuchungsjournalismus zu 
erstellen bekannt als "muckracking" (also benannt durch Präsidenten 
Theodore Roosevelt nach dem muckrake im Fortschritt des Pilgrims 
Bunyans, der "keine Methode schauen könnte aber abwärts, mit einem 
muckrake in seinen Händen"). Im 1890s bildeten Änderungen in 
druckentechnologie mögliche billige Zeitschriften, die einem 
ausgedehnteren und in zunehmendem Maße gebildeteren 
Mittelklassepublikum gefallen konnten. Im Oktober 1902 McClures 
veröffentlichte Zeitschrift was viele für den ersten muckraking 
Artikel halten, Lincoln Steffens' "Tweed-Tage in St. Louis." Die
"muckrakers" schrieben auf viele Themen, einschließlich Kinderarbeit,
Gefängnisse, Religion, Korporationen und Versicherungsgesellschaften.
Aber städtische politische Korruption blieb ein besonders 
populäres Ziel, möglicherweise, weil sie so kraß war und 
möglicherweise, weil die Unterschiede zwischen den muckrakers 
(meistens mittlere Kategorie und des gebürtigen protestierenden 
Vorrates) und den politischen Chefs (meistens von den katholischen und
einwandernden Hintergründen) gebildet die Richtlinie der 
einwandernden Maschine als ausländisches Eindringen erscheinen, eine 
Korruption der amerikanischen Staatsbürgerschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élévation de magasins de masse de circulation 
a combiné avec les impulsions de réforme du début du 20ème siècle
pour créer la forme du journalisme investigateur connue sous le nom 
de "muckracking" (ainsi nommé par le Président Theodore Roosevelt 
après le muckrake dans le progrès du pélerin de Bunyan qui ne 
pourrait "regarder aucune voie mais en bas, avec un muckrake dans des 
ses mains"). Dans le 1890s, les changements de la technologie 
d'impression ont fait les magasins peu coûteux possibles qui 
pourraient faire appel à une plus large et de plus en plus plus 
instruite assistance de classe moyenne. En octobre 1902 McClure 
le magasin a édité ce que beaucoup considèrent le premier article 
muckraking, jours de tweed de Lincoln Steffens des "à St Louis." 
Les "muckrakers" ont écrit sur beaucoup de sujets, y compris le
travail des enfants, prisons, religion, sociétés, et compagnies 
d'assurance. Mais la corruption politique urbaine est demeurée 
une cible particulièrement populaire, peut-être parce qu'elle était
si flagrante, et peut-être parce que les différences entre les 
muckrakers (la plupart du temps la bourgeoisie et des actions 
protestantes indigènes) et les patrons politiques (la plupart du 
temps des milieux catholiques et immigrés) faits la règle de la 
machine immigrée apparaissent comme intrusion étrangère, une 
corruption de la citoyenneté américaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A ascensão de compartimentos maciços da 
circulação combinou com os impulsos da reforma do 20o século 
adiantado para criar o formulário do journalism investigative sabido 
como "muckracking" (assim que nomeado pelo presidente Theodore 
Roosevelt após o muckrake no progresso do pilgrim de Bunyan que não 
poderia "não olhar nenhuma maneira mas para baixo, com um muckrake em
suas mãos"). No 1890s, as mudanças na tecnologia imprimindo 
fizeram os compartimentos baratos possíveis que poderiam apelar a uma
audiência mais larga e cada vez mais mais literate do middle-class. 
Em outubro 1902 McClure o compartimento publicou o que muitos 
consideram o primeiro artigo muckraking, dias tweed de Lincoln 
Steffens' do "em St. Louis." Os "muckrakers" escreveram em 
muitos assuntos, including o trabalho de criança, em prisões, em 
religião, em corporation, e em companhias de seguro. Mas o 
corruption político urbano remanesceu um alvo particularmente 
popular, talvez porque era assim blatant, e talvez porque as 
diferenças entre os muckrakers (na maior parte classe média e do 
estoque protestant nativo) e as saliências políticas (na maior parte
dos fundos catholic e immigrant) feitas a régua da máquina immigrant
aparecem como um intrusion estrangeiro, um corruption do citizenship 
americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'aumento degli scomparti totali di circolazione 
ha unito con gli impulsi di riforma di inizio del 20esimo secolo per 
creare la forma di giornalismo investigativo conosciuta come 
"muckracking" (in modo da chiamato dal presidente Theodore Roosevelt 
dopo il muckrake nel progresso del pilgrim del Bunyan che non potrebbe
"non osservare modo ma verso il basso, con un muckrake in sue mani"). 
Nel 1890s, i cambiamenti nella tecnologia di stampa hanno fatto 
gli scomparti economici possibili che potrebbero fare appello ad un 
più vasto e pubblico sempre più più literate della classe media. 
Nel mese di ottobre 1902 McClure lo scomparto ha pubblicato che 
cosa molti considerano il primo articolo muckraking, giorni del tweed 
de Lincoln Steffens "a St. Louis." "i muckrakers" hanno scritto 
su molti oggetti, compreso il lavoro del bambino, sulle prigioni,
sulla religione, sulle società e sulle società di assicurazioni. 
Ma la corruzione politica urbana è rimasto un obiettivo 
particolarmente popolare, forse perché era così blatant e forse 
perché le differenze fra i muckrakers (principalmente codice 
categoria centrale e delle azione protestanti natali) e le sporgenze 
politiche (principalmente dagli ambiti di provenienza cattolici ed 
immigrati) rese alla regola della macchina immigrata compaiono come 
intrusione straniera, una corruzione di cittadinanza americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η άνοδος των περιοδικών μαζικής κυκλοφορίας συνδύασε 
με τις ωθήσεις μεταρρύθμισης του πρόωρου 20ού αιώνα να 
δημιουργήσει τη μορφή της εξεταστικής δημοσιογραφίας γνωστή όπως
"muckracking" (έτσι ονομασμένος από τον Πρόεδρο Theodore 
Roosevelt μετά από το muckrake στην πρόοδο του προσκυνητή 
Bunyan που δεν θα μπορούσε "να φανεί κανένας τρόπος αλλά προς 
τα κάτω, με ένα muckrake στα χέρια του"). Στο 1890s, οι
αλλαγές στην τεχνολογία εκτύπωσης έκαναν τα πιθανά ανέξοδα 
περιοδικά που θα μπορούσαν να απευθυνθούν σε ένα ευρύτερο και 
όλο και περισσότερο περισσότερο εγγράμματο ακροατήριο μεσαίων 
τάξεων. Στο περιοδικό McClure's Οκτωβρίου 1902 που 
δημοσιεύεται τι πολλοί θεωρούν το πρώτο muckraking άρθρο, 
ημέρες τουίντ του Λίνκολν Steffens "στο ST Louis." 
Τα "muckrakers" έγραψαν σε πολλά θέματα, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της παιδικής εργασίας, τις φυλακές, τη 
θρησκεία, τις εταιρίες, και τις ασφαλιστικές εταιρείες. 
Αλλά η αστική πολιτική δωροδοκία παρέμεινε ένας ιδιαίτερα
δημοφιλής στόχος, ίσως επειδή ήταν τόσο κραυγαλέος, και ίσως 
επειδή οι διαφορές μεταξύ των muckrakers (συνήθως μέση κλάση 
και του εγγενούς προτεσταντικού αποθέματος) και των πολιτικών 
προϊσταμένων (συνήθως από τα καθολικά και που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει υπόβαθρα) εκατάρτισαν τον κανόνα της που έχουν 
μεταναστεύσει μηχανής να εμφανιστεί ως αλλοδαπή παρείσφρυση, μια 
δωροδοκία της αμερικανικής υπηκοότητας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La subida de compartimientos totales de la 
circulación combinó con los impulsos de la reforma del vigésimo 
siglo temprano para crear la forma de periodismo investigador conocida
como "muckracking" (así que nombrado por presidente Theodore 
Roosevelt después del muckrake en el progreso del peregrino de Bunyan
que no podría "mirar ninguna manera pero hacia abajo, con un muckrake
en sus manos"). En el 1890s, los cambios en tecnología de 
impresión hicieron los compartimientos baratos posibles que podrían 
abrogar a una audiencia más amplia y cada vez más más que sabe leer
y escribir de la clase media. En octubre 1902 de McClure el 
compartimiento publicó lo que consideran muchos el primer artículo 
muckraking, días del tweed de Lincoln Steffens los "en St. Louis." 
Los "muckrakers" escribieron en muchos temas, incluyendo trabajo
de niño, prisiones, la religión, corporaciones, y compañías de 
seguros. Pero la corrupción política urbana seguía siendo una
blanco determinado popular, quizás porque era tan evidente, y quizás
porque las diferencias entre los muckrakers (sobre todo clase media y 
de la acción protestante nativa) y los jefes políticos (sobre todo 
de fondos católicos e inmigrantes) hechos la regla de la máquina 
inmigrante aparecen como intrusión extranjera, una corrupción de la 
ciudadanía americana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086413</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106643</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/lincoln-steffens-exposes-tweed-days-in-st-louis</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
