<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105482</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105482</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213102</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Waves Through Earth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bewegt Durch Masse Wellenartig</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ondule Par La Terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Acena Através Da Terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fluttua Attraverso Terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κύματα μέσω της γης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Agita A través De la Tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Waves Through the Earth JAVA activity allows students to vary the seismic P and S wave velocity through each of 4 concentric regions of Earth. Students match fabricated data for travel times versus angular distance around Earth's surface from the source to detector. Tables are available for P and S rays superimposed on the 4-region model. Tables of data for P and S wave velocities, graphs of fabricated data, models for P and S waves and help and instructions are also available. Students can explore the difference in P and S wave velocity, P wave and S wave shadows, refraction, the idea that S wave velocity must be zero for outer core to match observations and how to adjust model parameters to match observations. This activity takes roughly an hour to complete and it is a perfect activity for introductory geoscience courses with Solid Earth content. Students with a wide range of mathematical abilities can also participate in this activity. This site includes teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas and additional resources regarding waves through the earth. This activity is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Wellen durch die Masse JAVA Aktivität erlaubt
Kursteilnehmern, die seismische P und S Welle Geschwindigkeit durch 
jede von 4 konzentrischen Regionen von Masse zu verändern. 
Kursteilnehmer bringen fabrizierte Daten für Spielraumzeiten 
gegen eckigen Abstand um Oberfläche der Masse von der Quelle zum 
Detektor zusammen. Tabellen sind für P vorhanden und die S 
Strahlen, die auf dem 4-region gelegt werden, formen. Tabellen 
von Daten für P und S Welle Geschwindigkeiten, Diagramme der 
fabrizierten Daten, Modelle für P und S Wellen und Hilfe und 
Anweisungen sind auch vorhanden. Kursteilnehmer können den 
Unterschied bezüglich P und S der Welle Geschwindigkeit, P Welle und 
S Welle erforschen Schatten, Brechung, die Idee, daß S Welle 
Geschwindigkeit null sein muß, damit äußerer Kern Beobachtungen 
zusammenbringt und wie man vorbildliche Parameter auf Übereinstimmung
Beobachtungen justiert. Diese Aktivität dauert eine ungefähr 
Stunde, um durchzuführen und es ist eine vollkommene Aktivität für 
einleitende geoscience Kurse mit festem Masse Inhalt. 
Kursteilnehmer mit einer breiten Strecke der mathematischen 
Fähigkeiten können an dieser Aktivität auch teilnehmen. Diese
Site schließt unterrichtende Anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen und die zusätzlichen Betriebsmittel betreffend 
sind Wellen durch die Masse ein. Diese Aktivität ist ein Teil 
der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les vagues par l'activité de JAVA de la terre 
permet à des étudiants vitesse de changer de P et de S vague 
séismique par chacune de 4 régions concentriques de la terre. 
Les étudiants apparient des données fabriquées pendant des 
temps de voyage contre la distance angulaire autour de la surface de 
la terre de la source au détecteur. Les Tableaux sont 
disponibles pour P et les rayons de S superposés au 4-region 
modèlent. Les Tableaux des données les vitesses pour de P et 
de S vague, graphiques des données fabriquées, modèles pour des 
vagues de P et de S et l'aide et des instructions sont également 
disponibles. Les étudiants peuvent des ombres explorer la 
différence vitesse dans de P et de S vague, la vague de P et de S 
vague, réfraction, l'idée que la vitesse de vague de S doit être 
zéro pour que le noyau externe apparie des observations et comment 
ajuster les paramètres modèles sur des observations d'allumette. 
Cette activité prend rudement une heure pour se terminer et 
c'est une activité parfaite pour des cours préliminaires de 
geoscience avec le contenu plein de la terre. Les étudiants 
avec un éventail de capacités mathématiques peuvent également 
participer à cette activité. Ce site inclut les notes et les 
extrémités d'enseignement, le matériel didactique, les idées 
d'évaluation et les ressources supplémentaires concernant des vagues
par la terre. Cette activité fait partie de la collection de 
point de départ : http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As ondas com a atividade de JAVA da terra permitem
que os estudantes variem velocidade da onda seismic de P e de S com 
cada uma de 4 regiões concêntricas da terra. Os estudantes 
combinam dados fabricados por tempos do curso contra a distância 
angular em torno da superfície da terra da fonte ao detetor. As
tabelas estão disponíveis para P e os raios de S sobrepostos no 
4-region modelam. As tabelas dos dados para as velocidades da 
onda de P e de S, gráficos dos dados fabricados, modelos para ondas 
de P e de S e ajuda e instruções estão também disponíveis. 
Os estudantes podem explorar a diferença velocidade na onda de 
P e de S, a onda de P e da onda de S sombras, refraction, a idéia que
a velocidade da onda de S deve ser zero para que o núcleo exterior 
combine observações e como ajustar os parâmetros modelo às 
observações do fósforo. Esta atividade faz exame 
aproximadamente de uma hora para terminar e é uma atividade perfeita 
para cursos introdutórios do geoscience com índice contínuo da 
terra. Os estudantes com uma escala larga de abilidades 
matemáticas podem também participar nesta atividade. Este 
local inclui notas e pontas ensinando, materiais de ensino, idéias da
avaliação e os recursos adicionais a respeito das ondas através da 
terra. Esta atividade é parte da coleção do ponto começar: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le onde con l'attività del JAVA della terra 
permette che gli allievi varino velocità dell'onda sismica di S e di 
P con ciascuna di 4 regioni concentriche di terra. Gli allievi 
abbinano i dati fabbricati per i tempi di corsa contro la distanza 
angolare intorno alla superficie della terra fra la sorgente e il 
rivelatore. Le Tabelle sono disponibili per la P ed i raggi di S
sovrapposti sul 4-region modellano. Le Tabelle dei dati per 
velocità dell'onda di S e di P, grafici dei dati fabbricati, modelli 
per le onde di S e di P e l'aiuto e le istruzioni sono egualmente 
disponibili. Gli allievi possono esplorare la differenza 
velocità nell'onda di S e di P, l'onda di P ed ombre dell'onda di S, 
la rifrazione, l'idea che la velocità dell'onda di S deve essere zero
affinchè il nucleo esterno abbini le osservazioni e come registrare i
parametri di modello alle osservazioni della corrispondenza. 
Questa attività occorre approssimativamente un'ora per 
completare ed è un'attività perfetta per i corsi introduttivi di 
geoscience con il soddisfare solido della terra. Gli allievi con
una vasta gamma delle abilità matematiche possono anche partecipare a
questa attività. Questo luogo include le note e punte 
d'istruzione, materiali didattici, idee di valutazione e risorse 
supplementari per quanto riguarda le onde attraverso la terra. 
Questa attività fa parte dell'accumulazione del punto di 
partenza: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα κύματα μέσω της δραστηριότητας της γήινης ΙΑΒΑΣ 
επιτρέπουν στους σπουδαστές για ταχύτητα κυμάτων να ποικίλουν τη 
σεισμική του π και του s μέσω κάθε μιας από 4 ομόκεντρες 
περιοχές της γης. Οι σπουδαστές ταιριάζουν με τα 
κατασκευασμένα στοιχεία για τους χρόνους ταξιδιού εναντίον της 
γωνιακής απόστασης γύρω από τη γήινη επιφάνεια από την πηγή 
τον ανιχνευτή. Οι πίνακες είναι διαθέσιμοι για τις ακτίνες 
π και του s που επιβάλλονται στο μοντέλο 4-περιοχών. Οι 
πίνακες των στοιχείων για τις ταχύτητες κυμάτων π και του s, οι
γραφικές παραστάσεις των κατασκευασμένων στοιχείων, τα μοντέλα 
για το π και τα κύματα και τις οδηγίες του s και οι οδηγίες 
είναι επίσης διαθέσιμοι. Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να 
εξερευνήσουν τις σκιές διαφοράς στην ταχύτητα κυμάτων π και του 
s, κυμάτων π και κυμάτων του s, διάθλαση, η ιδέα ότι η 
ταχύτητα κυμάτων του s πρέπει να είναι μηδέν για τον 
εξωτερικό πυρήνα για να ταιριάξει με τις παρατηρήσεις και πώς να 
ρυθμίσει τις πρότυπες παραμέτρους στις παρατηρήσεις αντιστοιχιών.
Αυτή η δραστηριότητα διαρκεί μια κατά προσέγγιση ώρα που 
ολοκληρώνει και είναι μια τέλεια δραστηριότητα για τις 
εισαγωγικές σειρές μαθημάτων geoscience με τη στερεά γήινο 
περιεκτικότητα σε. Οι σπουδαστές με ένα ευρύ φάσμα των 
μαθηματικών δυνατοτήτων μπορούν επίσης να συμμετέχουν σε αυτήν 
την δραστηριότητα. Αυτή η περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τις 
σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις 
ιδέες αξιολόγησης και τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς σχετικά 
με τα κύματα μέσω της γης. Αυτή η δραστηριότητα είναι 
μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las ondas con la actividad de JAVA de la tierra 
permiten que los estudiantes varíen velocidad de la onda sísmica de 
P y de S con cada uno de 4 regiones concéntricas de la tierra. 
Los estudiantes corresponden con los datos fabricados por 
tiempos del recorrido contra distancia angular alrededor de la 
superficie de la tierra de la fuente al detector. Los vectores 
están disponibles para P y los rayos de S sobrepuestos en el 4-region
modelan. Los vectores de los datos para las velocidades de la 
onda de P y de S, gráficos de los datos fabricados, modelos para las 
ondas de P y de S y la ayuda y las instrucciones están también 
disponibles. Los estudiantes pueden explorar la diferencia en 
velocidad de la onda de P y de S, la onda de P y las sombras de la 
onda de S, refracción, la idea que la velocidad de la onda de S debe 
ser cero para que la base externa corresponda con observaciones y 
cómo ajustar los parámetros modelo a las observaciones del 
emparejamiento. Esta actividad toma áspero una hora para 
terminar y es una actividad perfecta para los cursos introductorios 
del geoscience con el contenido sólido de la tierra. Los 
estudiantes con una amplia gama de capacidades matemáticas pueden 
también participar en esta actividad. Este sitio incluye notas 
y las extremidades de enseñanza, los materiales didácticos, las 
ideas del gravamen y los recursos adicionales con respecto a ondas a 
través de la tierra. Esta actividad es parte de la colección 
del punto de partida: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213102</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105482</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/waves-through-earth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
