<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/2086699707</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>2086699707</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211832</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Radioactive Decay and Absolute Age Determinations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Radioaktiver Zerfall und absolute Alter 
Ermittlungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Affaiblissement radioactif et déterminations 
absolues d'âge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Deterioração radioativa e determinações 
absolutas da idade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Deperimento radioattivo e determinazioni assolute 
di età</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ραδιενεργός αποσύνθεση και απόλυτοι προσδιορισμοί 
ηλικίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Decaimiento radiactivo y determinaciones absolutas 
de la edad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides access to a number of visual resources and supporting material illustrating the concept of radioactive decay and its central role in radiometric dating. Visualizations include diagrams, graphs, static illustrations and photos. Resources found on this site are suitable for use in lectures and classes and may also be used as the basis for labs or other activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert Zugriff zu einer Zahl der 
Sichtbetriebsmittel und des Hilfsmaterials, die das Konzept des 
radioaktiven Zerfalls und seiner zentralen Rolle in der 
radiometrischen Datierung veranschaulicht. Sichtbarmachungen 
enthalten Diagramme, Diagramme, statische Abbildungen und Fotos. 
Die Betriebsmittel, die auf dieser Site gefunden werden, sind 
für Gebrauch in den Vorträgen und in den Kategorien verwendbar und 
können als die Grundlage für Labors oder andere Aktivitäten auch 
verwendet werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site permet d'accéder à un certain nombre de 
ressources et de matériel de support visuels illustrant le concept de
l'affaiblissement radioactif et de son rôle central dans dater 
radiométrique. Les visualisations incluent des diagrammes, des 
graphiques, des illustrations statiques et des photos. Les 
ressources trouvées sur ce site conviennent pour l'usage dans les 
conférences et les classes et peuvent également être utilisées 
comme base pour des laboratoires ou d'autres activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece o acesso a um número recursos 
visuais e de material suportando que ilustram o conceito da 
deterioração radioativa e de seu papel central em datar radiometric.
Os visualizations incluem diagramas, gráficos, ilustrações de
estática e fotos. Os recursos encontrados neste local são 
apropriados para o uso nos lectures e nas classes e podem também ser 
usados como a base para laboratórios ou outras atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce l'accesso ad un certo numero 
di ad risorse e di materiali visivi di sostegno che illustrano il 
concetto di deperimento radioattivo e del relativo ruolo centrale nel 
datare radiometrico. Le visualizzazioni includono gli schemi, i 
grafici, le illustrazioni statiche e le foto. Le risorse trovate
su questo luogo sono adatte ad uso nelle conferenze e nei codici 
categoria e possono anche essere usate come la base per i laboratori o
altre attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει την πρόσβαση σε διάφορα 
οπτικά στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και ενισχυτικό υλικό που επεξηγούν 
την έννοια της ραδιενεργού αποσύνθεσης και του κεντρικού ρόλου 
της στη ραδιομετρική χρονολόγηση. Οι απεικονίσεις 
περιλαμβάνουν τα διαγράμματα, τις γραφικές παραστάσεις, τις 
στατικές απεικονίσεις και τις φωτογραφίες. Τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς που βρίσκονται σε αυτήν την περιοχή είναι κατάλληλα
για τη χρήση στις διαλέξεις και τις κλάσεις και μπορούν επίσης να
χρησιμοποιηθούν ως βάση για τα εργαστήρια ή άλλες 
δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona al acceso a un número de 
recursos visuales y de material que utiliza que ilustran el concepto 
del decaimiento radiactivo y de su papel central en fechar 
radiométrico. Las visualizaciones incluyen diagramas, 
gráficos, ilustraciones estáticas y las fotos. Los recursos 
encontrados en este sitio son convenientes para el uso en conferencias
y clases y se pueden también utilizar como la base para los 
laboratorios u otras actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211832</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>2086699707</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/radioactive-decay-and-absolute-age-determinations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
