<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107830</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107830</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087663</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Knowledge Media Laboratory (Keep Toolkit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissen Media-Labor (Unterhalttoolkit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Laboratoire de Medias de la Connaissance 
(Trousse à outils de Subsistance)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Laboratório Dos Media Do Conhecimento (Toolkit Do
Sustento)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Laboratorio Di Media Di Conoscenza (Toolkit Di 
Conservazione)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εργαστήριο μέσων γνώσης (κουτί εργαλείων 
συντηρήσεων)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Laboratorio De los Media Del Conocimiento (Caja de
herramientas Del Mantiene)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Knowledge Media Laboratory works to create a future in which communities of teachers, faculty, programs, and institutions collectively advance teaching and learning by exchanging their educational knowledge, experiences, ideas, and reflections by taking advantage of various technologies and resources.

The KEEP toolkit is a set of web-based tools that help teachers, students and institutions quickly create compact and engaging knowledge representations on the Web.</string>
          </description>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Wissen Media-Labor arbeitet, um eine Zukunft 
zu erstellen, in der Gemeinschaften der Lehrer, der Lehrkörpers, der 
Programme und der Anstalten zusammen das Unterrichten vorrücken und 
erlernend, indem sie ihr pädagogisches Wissen austauschen, 
Erfahrungen, Ideen und Reflexionen, indem sie Nutzen aus verschiedenen
Technologien und resources.The UNTERHALT Toolkit ziehen, ein Set 
Web-gegründete Hilfsmittel, die Lehrern helfen, Kursteilnehmer ist 
und Anstalten erstellen schnell die kompakten und engagierenden Wissen
Darstellungen auf dem Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le laboratoire de medias de la connaissance 
travaille pour créer un futur l'où les communautés des professeurs,
du corps enseignant, des programmes, et des établissements avancent 
collectivement l'enseignement et apprenant en permutant leur 
connaissance éducative, les expériences, les idées, et les 
réflexions en tirant profit de diverses technologies et de 
trousse à outils de SUBSISTANCE de resources.The est un ensemble d'outils 
Web-basés qui aident des professeurs, des étudiants et les 
établissements créent rapidement les représentations compactes et 
s'engageantes de la connaissance sur le Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O laboratório dos media do conhecimento trabalha 
para criar um futuro em que as comunidades dos professores, da 
faculdade, dos programas, e das instituições avançam coletivamente 
ensinar e aprendendo trocando seu conhecimento educacional, as 
experiências, as idéias, e as reflexões fazendo exame da vantagem 
de várias tecnologias e de toolkit do SUSTENTO de resources.The são 
um jogo das ferramentas Web-baseadas que ajudam a professores, 
estudantes e as instituições críam rapidamente respresentações 
compactas e acoplando do conhecimento no Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il laboratorio di media di conoscenza funziona per
creare un futuro in où le Comunità degli insegnanti, della facoltà,
dei programmi e delle istituzioni avanzano collettivamente 
l'istruzione ed imparando scambiando la loro conoscenza educativa, le 
esperienze, le idee e le riflessioni approfittando di varie tecnologie
e del toolkit di CONSERVAZIONE di resources.The è un insieme degli 
strumenti Web-basati che aiutano gli insegnanti, allievi e le 
istituzioni creano rapidamente le rappresentazioni compatte e 
d'agganci di conoscenza sul Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εργαστήριο MEDIA γνώσης λειτουργεί για να 
δημιουργήσει το μέλλον στο οποίο οι κοινότητες των δασκάλων, της 
σχολής, των προγραμμάτων, και των οργάνων προωθούν 
συλλογικά τη διδασκαλία και την εκμάθηση με την ανταλλαγή της 
εκπαιδευτικών γνώσης, της εμπειρίας, των ιδεών, και των 
αντανακλάσεών τους με να εκμεταλλευθούν τις διάφορα τεχνολογίες 
και τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς Το κουτί εργαλείων ΣΥΝΤΗΡΗΣΕΩΝ 
είναι ένα σύνολο βασισμένων στο WEB εργαλείων που βοηθούν 
τους δασκάλους, οι σπουδαστές και τα όργανα δημιουργούν 
γρήγορα τις αντιπροσωπεύσεις συμπαγούς και γνώσης δέσμευσης στον 
Ιστό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El laboratorio de los media del conocimiento 
trabaja para crear un futuro en el cual las comunidades de profesores,
de la facultad, de programas, y de instituciones avancen 
colectivamente la enseñanza y aprendiendo intercambiando su 
conocimiento educativo, las experiencias, las ideas, y las reflexiones
aprovechándose de varias tecnologías y de la caja de herramientas 
del MANTIENE de resources.The son un conjunto de las herramientas 
Web-basadas que ayudan a profesores, los estudiantes y las 
instituciones crean rápidamente representaciones compactas y de 
acoplamientos del conocimiento en el Web.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087663</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107830</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/knowledge-media-laboratory-keep-toolkit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
