<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107414</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107414</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087276</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Bold Stroke for Freedom."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein fetter Anschlag für Freiheit."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une rappe grasse pour la liberté."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um curso bold(realce) para a liberdade."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un colpo GRASSETTO per libertà."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα έντονο κτύπημα για την ελευθερία."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un movimiento en negrilla para la libertad."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On Christmas Eve, 1855, patrollers finally caught up with a group of teenaged slaves who had escaped by wagon from Loudon County, Virginia. But the posse was driven off when Ann Wood, leader of the group, brandished weapons and dared the pursuers to fire. The fugitives continued on to Philadelphia. Although proponents of the Fugitive Slave Law hoped it would reduce the number of slaves escaping to the North, the law fueled abolitionist sentiment. Popular opposition in cities like Boston and Philidelphia, which at times led to the emancipation by force of captured slaves, at times made the law unenforceable.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf Weihnachtsabend teenaged 1855, die patrollers, die 
schließlich oben mit einer Gruppe von abgefangen wurden, Sklaven, die
mit dem Lastwagen von der Loudon Grafschaft entgangen waren, Virginia.
Aber die Gruppe wurde als Ann Holz, Führer der Gruppe, 
geschwungene Waffen und gewagt den Verfolgern abgetrieben, um 
abzufeuern. Die Flüchtlinge fuhren an nach Philadelphia fort. 
Obgleich Antragsteller des Flüchtling-Sklave Gesetzes hofften, 
würde es die Zahl den Sklaven verringern, die auf dem Norden, das 
Gesetz getankte abolitionist Gefühl entgehen. Populäre 
Opposition in den Städte mögen Boston und Philidelphia, die manchmal
zu die Emanzipation durch die Kraft der erfaßten Sklaven führten, 
manchmal gebildet das nicht einklagbare Gesetz.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La veille de Noël, 1855, patrollers finalement rattrapés
par rapport à un groupe de teenaged les esclaves qui s'étaient 
échappés en chariot du comté de Loudon, le Virginie. Mais la 
bande a été éliminée quand le bois d'Ann, amorce du groupe, armes 
brandies et osée les poursuivants pour mettre le feu. Les 
fugitifs ont continué en fonction à Philadelphie. Bien que les
partisans de la loi Slave de fugitif aient espéré elle 
ramènerait le nombre d'esclaves s'échappant au nord, le 
sentiment d'abolitionniste rempli de combustible par loi. 
L'opposition populaire dans les villes aiment Boston et 
Philidelphia, qui ont parfois mené à l'émancipation par la force 
des esclaves capturés, parfois faite la loi inapplicable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No eve de christmas, 1855, patrollers alcançados 
finalmente  um grupo de teenaged os escravos que se tinham escapado 
pelo vagão do condado de Loudon, Virgínia. Mas o posse foi 
dirigido fora quando a madeira de Ann, líder do grupo, armas 
brandished e ousado os pursuers para atear fogo. Os fugitives 
continuaram sobre a Filadélfia. Embora os proponents da lei do 
escravo do fugitive esperassem reduziria o número dos escravos que 
escapam-se ao norte, o sentiment abastecido lei do abolitionist. 
A oposição popular nas cidades gosta de Boston e de 
Philidelphia, que conduziram às vezes ao emancipation pela força de 
escravos capturados, feita às vezes a lei unenforceable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La vigilia di Natale, 1855, patrollers infine 
aggiornati con un gruppo di teenaged gli schiavi che avevano 
fuoriuscito in vagone dalla contea di Loudon, la Virginia. Ma il
posse è stato eliminato quando legno della Ann, il capo del 
gruppo, armi brandished ed è stato osato i pursuers per infornare. 
I fuggitivi sono continuato sopra a Filadelfia. Anche se i
fautori della legge dello schiavo del fuggitivo hanno sperato 
ridurrebbe il numero di schiavi che fuoriescono al nord, il sentimento
di abolitionist rifornito legge. L'opposizione popolare in 
città gradisce Boston e Philidelphia, che hanno condotto 
occasionalmente all'emancipazione da forza degli schiavi bloccati, 
occasionalmente resa alla legge inapplicabile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην παραμονή Χριστουγέννων, 1855, τα patrollers 
πρόφθασαν τελικά μια ομάδα οι σκλάβοι που είχαν δραπετεύσει με 
το βαγόνι εμπορευμάτων από Loudon το νομό, Βιρτζίνια. 
Αλλά το posse διώχτηκε όταν ANN Wood, ηγέτης της 
ομάδας, τα όπλα και τόλμησε οι διώκτες που απολύουν. Οι 
πρόσφυγες που συνεχίζονται προς τη Φιλαδέλφεια. Αν και οι 
υπερασπιστές του νόμου σκλάβων προσφύγων ήλπισαν θα μείωνε τον 
αριθμό σκλάβων που δραπετεύουν στο Βορρά, το τροφοδοτημένο νόμος
συναίσθημα ρεφορμιστών. Η δημοφιλής αντίθεση στις πόλεις 
όπως τη Βοστώνη και Philidelphia, που οδήγησαν κατά περιόδους 
στην χειραφέτηση από τη δύναμη των συλλήφθείων σκλάβων, 
κατέστησε κατά περιόδους το νόμο ανεκτέλεστο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El víspera de Navidad, 1855, patrollers finalmente 
cogidos para arriba con un grupo de teenaged a esclavos que se habían
escapado por el carro del condado de Loudon, Virginia. Pero 
eliminaron cuando la madera de Ana, arranque de cinta del grupo, armas
brandished y fueron atrevido al posse los pursuers para encender. 
Los fugitivos continuaron encendido a Philadelphia. Aunque
los autores de la ley del esclavo del fugitivo esperaban reduciría el
número de los esclavos que se escapan al norte, el sentimiento 
aprovisionado de combustible ley del abolitionist. La oposición
popular en ciudades tiene gusto de Boston y de Philidelphia, que 
condujeron ocasionalmente a la emancipación por la fuerza de esclavos
capturados, ocasionalmente hecha la ley inaplicable.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087276</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107414</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-bold-stroke-for-freedom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
