<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103343</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103343</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087244</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Women Without Men": The Pros and Cons of a "Man-Free Life"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Frauen Ohne Männer": Das Pro und die Cons 
einer "Mann-Freien Lebensdauer"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Femmes Sans Hommes" : Le pour et le contre 
"d'une vie Homme-Libre"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Mulheres Sem Homens": Os pros e os cons "de
uma vida Homem-Livre"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Donne Senza Uomini": I pro ed il contro "di
una vita Uomo-Libera"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Γυναίκες χωρίς άνδρεσ": Τα πλεονεκτήματα και τα
μειονεκτήματα μιας "άτομο-ελεύθερης ζωήσ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Mujeres Sin Los Hombres": Los pros y el 
contra de una "vida Hombre-Libre"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Writing about gender roles of the 1950s, Betty Friedan once defined the "suburban housewife" as "the dream image of the young American woman." Just as prescriptive literature of the 19th century geared to the middling classes emphasized women's "true" place in society as mother and wife, the 1950s saw an ideal perpetuated in books, magazines, movies, television, songs, and ads that depicted the white, middle-class woman fulfilled only by a happy marriage. The following article from a popular magazine of 1960 offered a sociological survey of the more than one-third of adult American women whose lives did not fit this domestic norm. Based on interviews with single, divorced, and widowed women, and a host of "experts", the author detailed the "frenzied" mating efforts of women who tried, but failed, to marry as well as the adverse psychological effects of being single. Despite the evidence presented that unmarried women could be happy--sometimes even happier than their married counterparts--the article's rhetorical emphasis on "frantic hordes of unwed women" relentlessly searching for husbands perpetrated a stereotypical depiction at odds with some of the statistics and testimonies quoted.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schreibend über Geschlechtrollen der fünfziger 
Jahre, definierte Betty Friedan einmal die "Vorstadthausfrau" als "das
Traumbild der jungen amerikanischen Frau." Gerade während 
vorschreibende Literatur des 19. Jahrhunderts zu den 
Mittelproduktkategorien hervorhob "zutreffenden" Platz der Frauen in 
der Gesellschaft als Mutter und Frau übersetzte, die fünfziger Jahre
sah ein ideales verewigt in den Büchern, in den Zeitschriften, in den
Filmen, im Fernsehen, in den Lieden und in ADS, das das Weiß bildlich
darstellte, die Mittelklassefrau erfüllt nur durch eine glückliche 
Verbindung. Der folgende Artikel von einer populären 
Zeitschrift von 1960 bot eine soziologische Übersicht des mehr als 
eines Drittels der amerikanischen Frauen des Erwachsenen an deren 
Lebensdauern nicht diese inländische Norm paßten. Gegründet 
auf Interviews mit einzelnem, geschieden und widowed Frauen, und ein 
Hauptrechner "der Experten", der Autor schilderte die "frenzied" 
fügenden Bemühungen der Frauen genau, die tried, aber, sowie die 
nachteiligen psychologischen Effekte des Seins verbinden nicht 
können, einzeln. Trotz des Beweises, der dargestellt wurde, 
daß unverheiratet Frauen glücklich sein konnten -- manchmal 
glücklicheres als ihre verbundenen Gegenstücke glätten -- das 
rhetorische Hauptgewicht des Artikels auf ", wild Horden von unwed die
Frauen" nach Ehemännern unnachgiebig suchend verübte eine 
stereotypische Beschreibung, die mit einigen der Statistiken uneins 
ist und Zeugnisse veranschlugen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Écrivant au sujet des rôles de genre des années
50, Betty Friedan a par le passé défini "la femme au foyer 
suburbaine" comme "image rêveuse de la jeune femme américaine." 
Juste comme la littérature préscriptive du 19ème siècle 
adaptait aux classes d'issue de blé soulignait la place "vraie" des 
femmes dans la société comme mère et épouse, les années 50 voyait
un idéal perpétuées dans les livres, les magasins, les films, la 
télévision, les chansons, et l'ADS qui a dépeint le blanc, femme de
classe moyenne accomplie seulement par un mariage heureux. 
L'article suivant d'un magasin populaire de 1960 a offert une 
étude sociologique plus de de l'un tiers de femmes américaines 
d'adulte dont les vies n'ont pas adapté cette norme domestique. 
Basé sur des entrevues avec simple, les femmes divorcées et et
veuves, et une foule d'"experts", l'auteur ont détaillé les 
efforts d'accouplement "frénétiques" des femmes qui éprouvé, mais,
ne se marient pas comme les effets psychologiques défavorables 
d'être célibataire. En dépit de l'évidence présentée que 
les femmes célibataires pourraient être heureuses -- parfois encore 
plus heureux que leurs contre-parties mariées -- l'emphase 
rhétorique de l'article sur "les hordes effrénées de unwed des 
femmes" recherchant implacablement des maris a commis une description 
stéréotypée en désaccord avec certaines des statistiques et les 
témoignages ont cité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escrevendo sobre papéis do gender dos 1950s, 
Betty Friedan definiu uma vez "o housewife suburbano" como "a imagem 
ideal da mulher americana nova." Apenas enquanto a literatura 
prescriptive do 1ø século engrenou às classes do middling emfatizou
o lugar "verdadeiro" das mulheres na sociedade como a matriz e a 
esposa, os 1950s viu um ideal perpetuated nos livros, nos 
compartimentos, nos filmes, na televisão, nas canções, e no ads que
descreveu o branco, mulher do middle-class cumprida somente por uma 
união feliz. O seguinte artigo de um compartimento popular de 
1960 ofereceu um exame sociological mais do de um terço das mulheres 
americanas do adulto cujas as vidas não couberam esta norma 
doméstica. Baseado em entrevistas com único, divorciado, e 
widowed mulheres, e um anfitrião de "peritos", o autor detalhou os 
esforços de acoplamento "frenéticos" das mulheres que experimentado,
mas, não se casam assim como os efeitos psicológicos adversos de ser
único. Apesar da evidência apresentada que as mulheres 
solteiras poderiam ser felizes -- às vezes para nivelar mais feliz do
que suas contrapartes casadas -- a ênfase rhetorical do artigo em 
"hordes frantic de unwed as mulheres" que procuraram relentlessly por 
maridos perpetrated um depiction stereotypical em probabilidades com 
alguns dos statistics e os testimonies citaram.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scrivendo circa i ruoli di genere degli anni 50, 
Betty Friedan ha definito una volta "la casalinga suburbana" come 
"l'immagine di sogno della donna americana giovane." Appena 
mentre la letteratura normativa del diciannovesimo secolo ha adattato 
ai codici categoria della semola ha dato risalto al posto "allineare" 
delle donne nella società come la madre e moglie, gli anni 50 ha 
visto un ideale perpetuati in libri, in scomparti, in film, 
nella televisione, nelle canzoni ed in ads che ha descritto il bianco,
donna della classe media soddisfacente soltanto da un'unione felice. 
Il seguente articolo da uno scomparto popolare di 1960 ha 
offerto un'indagine sociologica più di dell'un terzo delle donne 
americane dell'adulto di cui le vite non misura questa norma 
domestica. Sulla base delle interviste con singolo, divorziato e
widowed le donne e una miriade di "esperti", l'autore ha dettagliato 
gli sforzi accoppiamento "frenzied" delle donne che provato, ma non 
riuscito, a sposarsi come pure gli effetti psicologici avversi di 
essere singolo. Malgrado la prova presentata che le donne celibi
potrebbero essere felici -- a volte ancora più felice delle loro 
controparti sposate -- l'enfasi retorica dell'articolo su "i hordes 
frantic di unwed le donne" che cercano relentlessly i mariti 
perpetrated un depiction stereotypical in disaccordo con alcune delle 
statistiche e le testimonianze hanno citato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γράφοντας για τους ρόλους γένους της δεκαετίας του 
'50, η Betty Friedan καθόρισε μιά φορά τη "προαστιακή 
νοικοκυρά" ως "εικόνα ονείρου της νέας αμερικανικής γυναίκας." 
Ακριβώς ως καθοδηγητική λογοτεχνία του 19$ου αιώνα που 
συνδέθηκε με το εμπόρευμα οι κλάσεις υπογράμμισαν αληθινή "θέση 
των γυναικών τη" στην κοινωνία ως μητέρα και η σύζυγος, η 
δεκαετία του '50 εβλέίδε ένα ιδανικό που διαιωνίστηκε στα
βιβλία, τα περιοδικά, τους κινηματογράφους, την τηλεόραση, τα 
τραγούδια, και τις αγγελίες που απεικόνισαν το λευκό, γυναίκα 
μεσαίων τάξεων που εκπληρώθηκε μόνο από έναν ευτυχή γάμο. 
Το ακόλουθο άρθρο από ένα δημοφιλές περιοδικό του 1960 
πρόσφερε μια κοινωνιολογική έρευνα για περισσότερο από το ένα 
τρίτο των ενήλικων αμερικανικών γυναικών οι των οποίων ζωές δεν 
εγκατέστησαν αυτόν τον εσωτερικό κανόνα. Με βάση τις 
συνεντεύξεις με τις ανύπανδρες, διαζευγμένες, και χηρευάμενες 
γυναίκες, και ένας πλήθος "των εμπειρογνωμόνων", ο συντάκτης 
απαρίθμησε τις "φρενιτιώδεισ" προσπάθειες ζευγαρώματος των 
γυναικών που προσπάθησαν, αλλά απέτυχε, να παντρεψει καθώς 
επίσης και τα δυσμενή ψυχολογικά αποτελέσματα της ύπαρξης 
ενιαίος. Παρά τα στοιχεία που παρουσιάστηκαν ότι οι 
ανύπανδρες γυναίκες θα μπορούσαν να είναι ευτυχείς ότι -- 
μερικές φορές ακόμα ευτυχέστερος από τα παντρεμένα αντίστοιχά 
τους -- η ρητορική έμφαση του άρθρου στις "μανιώδεις ορδές οι 
γυναίκεσ" αδυσώπητα που ψάχνουν για τους συζύγους διέπραξαν μια 
stereotypical απεικόνιση σε διαφωνία με μερικές από τις 
στατιστικές και τις καταθέσεις που αναφέρθηκαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escribiendo sobre el papeles del género de los 
años 50, Betty Friedan definió una vez a "ama de casa suburbana" 
como "la imagen ideal de la mujer americana joven." Apenas 
mientras que la literatura preceptiva del diecinueveavo siglo engranó
a las clases del acemite acentuó el lugar "verdadero" de las mujeres 
en sociedad como madre y esposa, los años 50 consideró un ideal 
perpetuados en libros, compartimientos, películas, la televisión, 
canciones, y el ads que representó el blanco, mujer de la clase media
satisfecha solamente por una unión feliz. El artículo 
siguiente de un compartimiento popular de 1960 ofreció una encuesta 
sociológica de más el de una mitad de las mujeres americanas del 
adulto que vidas no cupieron esta norma doméstica. De acuerdo 
con entrevistas con solo, divorciado, y widowed a mujeres, y un 
ordenador principal de "expertos", el autor detalló los esfuerzos de 
acoplamiento "frenzied" de las mujeres que probado, pero no podido, 
casar tan bien como los efectos psicologicos adversos de ser solo. 
A pesar de la evidencia presentada que las mujeres solteras 
podrían ser felices -- a veces igualar más feliz que sus 
contrapartes casadas -- el énfasis retórico del artículo en los 
"hordes frenéticos de unwed a mujeres" que buscaban implacablemente 
para a maridos perpetrados una pintura stereotypical en 
desacuerdo con alguna de la estadística y los testimonios cotizaron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087244</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103343</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/women-without-men-the-pros-and-cons-of-a-man-free-life</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
