<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104413</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104413</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206765</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Joseph Bellamy House: The Great Awakening in Puritan New England</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Joseph Bellamy Haus: Das große Wecken 
in puritanischem Neu-England</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Chambre de Joseph Bellamy : Le grand 
réveil en Nouvelle Angleterre puritaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Casa De Joseph Bellamy: Awakening grande 
em Nova Inglaterra puritan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Camera Del Joseph Bellamy: Il risveglio 
grande in Nuova Inghilterra puritan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Joseph Bellamy House: Το μεγάλο ξύπνημα
στην πουριτανή Νέα Αγγλία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Casa De José Bellamy: El gran despertar 
en Nueva Inglaterra puritan</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the life and times of the Reverend Joseph Bellamy (1719-1790), a preacher, author, and educator in New England. At the age of 20, Bellamy became the minister in Bethlehem, Connecticut. He and other ministers, spent most of 1741-1742 riding about New England preaching sermons meant to bring sinners back to the fold of the church. The movement, known as the Great Awakening, appealed particularly to working class people and spread throughout the northern and central colonies.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft die Lebensdauer und die Zeiten des 
Reverend Joseph Bellamy (1719-1790), ein Prediger, ein Autor und ein 
Erzieher in Neu-England. Am Alter von 20, stand Bellamy dem 
Minister in Bethlehem, Connecticut. Er und andere Minister, die 
am meisten von 1741-1742 reiten über Neu-England predigende Predigten
verbraucht sind, bedeuteten, sinners zurück zu der Falte der Kirche 
zu holen. Die Bewegung, bekannt als das große Wecken, gefallen 
besonders zu den Funktion Kategorie Leuten und der Verbreitung in den 
Nord- und zentralen Kolonien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine la vie et les temps du Révérend Joseph 
Bellamy (1719-1790), d'un prédicateur, d'un auteur, et d'un 
éducateur en Nouvelle Angleterre. À l'âge de 20, Bellamy est 
allé bien au ministre à Bethlehem, le Connecticut. Lui et 
d'autres ministres, épuisés plus de 1741-1742 montant au sujet des 
sermons de prédication de la Nouvelle Angleterre ont voulu dire pour 
apporter des pécheurs de nouveau au pli de l'église. Le 
mouvement, connu sous le nom de grand réveil, en appelé en 
particulier aux personnes et à la diffusion de classe ouvrière dans 
toutes les colonies nordiques et centrales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina a vida e os tempos do Reverend Joseph 
Bellamy (1719-1790), um preacher, um autor, e um educador em Nova 
Inglaterra. Na idade de 20, Bellamy assentou bem no ministro em 
Bethlehem, Connecticut. E outros ministros, gastos mais de 
1741-1742 que montam sobre sermons preaching de Nova Inglaterra 
significaram trazer para trás sinners à dobra da igreja. O 
movimento, sabido como awakening grande, apelado particularmente aos 
povos e à propagação da classe de funcionamento durante todo as 
colônias do norte e centrais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina la durata ed i tempi del Reverend Joseph 
Bellamy (1719-1790), un preacher, un autore e un educatore in Nuova 
Inghilterra. All'età di 20, Bellamy ha stato bene al 
ministro a Bethlehem, Connecticut. Lui ed altro 
assistono, speso la maggior parte di 1741-1742 che 
guida circa i sermons di predica della Nuova Inghilterra significati 
per portare i sinners di nuovo al popolare della chiesa. Il 
movimento, conosciuto come il risveglio grande, ha fatto appello 
specialmente alla gente ed alla diffusione del codice categoria di 
funzionamento durante le colonie nordiche e centrali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τη ζωή και τους χρόνους του Αιδεσιμότατος 
Joseph Bellamy (1719-1790), ενός ιεροκήρυκα, ενός 
συντάκτη, και ενός εκπαιδευτικού στη Νέα Αγγλία. Στην 
ηλικία 20, Bellamy έγινε ο υπουργός στη Βηθλεέμ, Κοννέκτικατ. 
Αυτός και άλλοι υπουργοί, που ξοδεύτηκαν το μεγαλύτερο 
μέρος 1741-1742 που οδηγά για τα κηρύσσοντας κηρύγματα της 
Νέας Αγγλίας σήμαναν να φέρουν τους αμαρτωλούς πίσω στις πτυχές
της εκκλησίας. Η μετακίνηση, γνωστή ως μεγάλο ξύπνημα, 
απευθύνθηκε ιδιαίτερα στους ανθρώπους εργατικής τάξης και 
διέδωσε σε όλες τις βόρειες και κεντρικές αποικίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina la vida y los tiempos del Reverend José 
Bellamy (1719-1790), predicador, autor, y educador en Nueva 
Inglaterra. En la edad de 20, Bellamy sintió bien al ministro 
en Bethlehem, Connecticut. Él y otros ministros, gastados de 
1741-1742 que montaba sobre los sermones de predicación de Nueva 
Inglaterra significaron más traer sinners de nuevo al doblez de la 
iglesia. El movimiento, conocido como gran despertar, abrogado 
determinado a la gente y a la extensión de la clase obrera a través 
de las colonias norteñas y centrales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206765</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104413</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-joseph-bellamy-house-the-great-awakening-in-puritan-new-england</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
