<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105297</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105297</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212319</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Stromatolite Explorer: Investigation of a Microbial Mat Community</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stromatolite Forscher: Untersuchung einer 
matten durch Mikrobengemeinschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Explorateur de Stromatolite : Recherche sur 
une Communauté mate microbienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Explorador De Stromatolite: Investigação 
de uma comunidade mat microbial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esploratore Di Stromatolite: Indagine su una
Comunità mat microbica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξερευνητής Stromatolite: Έρευνα για μια 
μικροβιακή Κοινότητα χαλιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Explorador De Stromatolite: Investigación 
de una comunidad mat microbiana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This animated video takes students on a journey through a microbial mat. The assigned mission is to probe a microbial mat by following an imaginary 0.10 mm stromatolite explorer as it descends through the layers. On its route, the vehicle takes chemical readings and images of each layer. It addresses the history of microbial mats, their interest to NASA and astrobiology, and the different metabolic activities occurring at each level. The video is seven minutes in length. If you experience difficulty opening the video from the website, right-click and select "save target as." This will allow you to save it to your computer and it should easily open.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser lebhafte Bildschirm nimmt Kursteilnehmer 
auf einer Reise durch eine Mikrobenmatte. Die zugewiesene 
Mission ist, eine Mikrobenmatte zu prüfen, indem sie einem 
eingebildeten ein 0.10 Millimeter stromatolite Forscher folgt, wie sie
durch die Schichten absteigt. Auf seinem Weg nimmt der Träger 
chemische Messwerte und Bilder jeder Schicht. Er adressiert die 
Geschichte der Mikrobenmatten, ihr Interesse an die NASA und 
astrobiology und die unterschiedlichen metabolischen Aktivitäten, die
auf jeder Stufe auftreten. Der Bildschirm ist sieben Minuten in 
der Länge. Wenn Sie auf die Schwierigkeit stoßen, die den 
Bildschirm von der Web site öffnet, wählt Rechtklicken und "außer 
Ziel wie." aus Dieses erlaubt Ihnen, es zu Ihrem Computer zu 
sichern und es sollte leicht sich öffnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce vidéo animé prend des étudiants sur un 
voyage par une natte microbienne. La mission assignée est de 
sonder une natte microbienne en suivant un explorateur imaginaire de 
stromatolite de 0.10 millimètre car elle descend par les couches. 
Sur son itinéraire, le véhicule prend les lectures et les 
images chimiques de chaque couche. Il adresse l'histoire des 
nattes microbiennes, leur intérêt à la NASA et à l'astrobiology, 
et les différentes activités métaboliques se produisant à chaque 
niveau. Le vidéo est de sept minutes de longueur. Si vous
éprouvez la difficulté ouvrant le vidéo du site Web, right-clic
et choisissent "économiser la cible As." Ceci vous permettra de
la sauvegarder à votre ordinateur et il devrait facilement s'ouvrir.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este vídeo animated faz exame de estudantes em 
uma viagem através de uma esteira microbial. A missão 
atribuída é sondar uma esteira microbial seguindo um explorador 
imaginário do stromatolite de 0.10 milímetro porque desce com as 
camadas. Em sua rota, o veículo faz exame de leituras e de 
imagens químicas de cada camada. Dirige-se ao history de 
esteiras microbial, a seu interesse à NASA e ao astrobiology, e às 
atividades metabolic diferentes que ocorrem em cada nível. O 
vídeo é sete minutos no comprimento. Se você experimentar a 
dificuldade que abre o vídeo do Web site, o direito-clique e 
seleciona "excepto o alvo como." Isto permitirá que você 
conserve-o a seu computador e deve fàcilmente abrir.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo video animato prende gli allievi su un 
viaggio tramite una stuoia microbica. La missione assegnata è 
di sondare una stuoia microbica quanto segue un esploratore 
immaginario dello stromatolite da 0.10 millimetri poichè discende con
gli strati. Sul relativo itinerario, il veicolo prende le 
letture e le immagini chimiche di ogni strato. Richiama la 
storia delle stuoie microbiche, il loro interesse alla NASA ed al 
astrobiology e le attività metaboliche differenti che accadono ad 
ogni livello. Il video è sette minuti di lunghezza. Se 
incontrate la difficoltà che apre il video dal Web site, lo di 
destra-scatto e seleziona "risparmi l'obiettivo As." Ciò 
permetterà che lo salviate al vostro calcolatore e dovrebbe aprirsi 
facilmente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το ζωντανεψοντα βίντεο παίρνει τους σπουδαστές σε
ένα ταξίδι μέσω ενός μικροβιακού χαλιού. Η ανατεθειμένη 
αποστολή είναι να εξεταστεί ένα μικροβιακό χαλί με την 
ακολουθία ενός φανταστικού εξερευνητή 0,10 χιλ. stromatolite
καθώς κατεβαίνει μέσω των στρωμάτων. Στη διαδρομή του, το 
όχημα παίρνει τις χημικές αναγνώσεις και τις εικόνες κάθε 
στρώματος. Απευθύνει την ιστορία των μικροβιακών χαλιών, 
του ενδιαφέροντός τους στη NASA και το astrobiology, και των 
διαφορετικών μεταβολικών δραστηριοτήτων που εμφανίζονται σε κάθε 
επίπεδο. Το βίντεο είναι επτά λεπτά στο μήκος. Εάν 
αντιμετωπίζετε τη δυσκολία που ανοίγει το βίντεο από τον 
ιστοχώρο, σωστός-στιγμιαίο πάτημα και επιλέγετε "εκτός από το 
στόχο όπως." Αυτό θα επιτρέψει ότι τον σώζετε στον 
υπολογιστή σας και πρέπει εύκολα να ανοίξει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este vídeo animado toma a estudiantes en un viaje
a través de una estera microbiana. La misión asignada es 
sondar una estera microbiana siguiendo a un explorador imaginario del 
stromatolite de 0.10 milímetro pues desciende con las capas. En
su ruta, el vehículo toma lecturas e imágenes químicas de cada 
capa. Trata la historia de esteras microbianas, su interés a la
NASA y al astrobiology, y las diversas actividades metabólicas que 
ocurren en cada nivel. El vídeo es siete minutos en longitud. 
Si usted experimenta la dificultad que abre el vídeo del Web 
site, el derecho-tecleo y selecciona "excepto blanco como." Esto
permitirá que usted lo salve a su ordenador y debe abrirse 
fácilmente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BRAD BEBOUT
FN:BRAD BEBOUT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NASA AMES RESEARCH CENTER
FN:NASA AMES RESEARCH CENTER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212319</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105297</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/stromatolite-explorer-investigation-of-a-microbial-mat-community</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
