<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106694</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106694</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086206</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Gonna Miss President Roosevelt": The Blues for FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", Gehend Zum Fräulein Präsident Roosevelt": 
Das Blau für FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Allant À la Mlle Le Président Roosevelt" : 
Les bleus pour le FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Indo À Senhorita Presidente Roosevelt": Os
azuis para o FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Andando Alla Sig.na Presidente Roosevelt": 
Gli azzurri per il FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Gonna η Δεσποινίς Πρόεδρος Roosevelt": Τα 
μπλε για FDR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Yendo A la Srta. Presidente Roosevelt": Los
azul para el FDR</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The relationship between African Americans and Franklin D. Roosevelt presents something of a paradox. On the one hand, Roosevelt never endorsed anti-lynching legislation; he accepted segregation and disenfranchisement; and he condoned discrimination against blacks in federally funded relief programs. On the other hand, Roosevelt won the hearts and the votes of African Americans in unprecedented numbers. Many black Americans not only voted for Roosevelt; they made him into a hero. "Franklin," "Eleanor," "Delano," and even "Roosevelt" became popular first names for black children in the 1930s. And many African Americans hung the president's picture on their walls beside those of Christ and Lincoln. Another indication of the powerful impression that Roosevelt made in the black community was Big Joe Williams' recording of a blues tribute on the occasion of Roosevelt's death in 1945, "His Spirit Lives On."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Verhältnis zwischen afrikanischen Amerikaner-
und Franklind. Roosevelt Geschenken etwas eines Paradoxes. 
Einerseits indossierte Roosevelt nie Anti-lynchende 
Gesetzgebung; er nahm Abtrennung und disenfranchisement an; 
und er verzieh Diskriminierung gegen Schwarze in föderativ 
gefinanzierten Entlastung Programmen. Andererseits gewann 
Roosevelt die Inneren und die Stimmen der afrikanischen Amerikaner in 
beispiellosen Zahlen. Viele schwarze Amerikaner wählten nicht 
nur für Roosevelt; sie bildeten ihn in einen Held. 
"Franklin," "Eleanor," "Delano," und glätten "Roosevelt" wurde 
populäre Vornamen für schwarze Kinder in den dreißiger Jahren und 
viele afrikanische Amerikaner hingen die Abbildung des Präsidenten 
auf ihren Wänden neben denen von Christ und von Lincoln. Eine 
andere Anzeige über den leistungsfähigen Eindruck, den Roosevelt, 
das in der schwarzen Gemeinschaft gebildet wurde, grossen Joe Williams
Aufnahme eines Blautributs anläßlich des Todes Roosevelts 1945 war, 
"sein Geist lebt auf."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le rapport entre les présents africains 
d'Américains et de Franklin D. Roosevelt quelque chose d'un paradoxe.
D'une part, Roosevelt n'a jamais approuvé la législation 
anti-lynchante ; il a reçu la ségrégation et le 
disenfranchisement ; et il a pardonné la discrimination contre 
des noirs dans des programmes fédéralement placés de soulagement. 
D'autre part, Roosevelt a gagné les coeurs et les voix des 
Américains africains dans des nombres sans précédent. 
Beaucoup d'Américains noirs ont non seulement voté pour 
Roosevelt ; ils l'ont transformé en un héros. 
"Franklin," "Eleanor," "Delano," et égalisent "Roosevelt" est 
devenu des prénoms populaires pour les enfants noirs dans les années
30. Et beaucoup d'Américains africains ont arrêté l'image du 
président sur leurs murs près de ceux du Christ et de Lincoln. 
Une autre indication de l'impression puissante que Roosevelt 
fait dans la communauté noire était grand enregistrement de Joe 
Williams d'un hommage de bleus à l'occasion de la mort de Roosevelt 
en 1945, "son esprit vit sur."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O relacionamento entre presentes africanos dos 
americanos e do Franklin D. Roosevelt algo de um paradox. Na uma
mão, Roosevelt nunca endossou a legislação anti-anti-lynching; 
aceitou o segregation e o disenfranchisement; e desculpou 
a discriminação de encontro aos pretos em programas federal 
financiados do relevo. Na outra mão, Roosevelt ganhou os 
corações e os votos de americanos africanos em números 
unprecedented. Muitos americanos pretos votados não somente 
para Roosevelt; fizeram-no em um herói. "Franklin," 
"Eleanor," "Delano," e nivela "Roosevelt" transformou-se primeiros 
nomes populares para crianças pretas nos 1930s. e muitos americanos 
africanos penduraram o retrato do presidente em suas paredes ao lado 
daqueles de Christ e de Lincoln. Uma outra indicação da 
impressão poderosa que Roosevelt feito na comunidade preta era 
gravação de Joe Williams' grande de um tributo dos azuis na ocasião
da morte de Roosevelt em 1945, "seu espírito vive em."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il rapporto fra i presenti africani del Franklin e
degli Americani D. Roosevelt qualcosa di un paradosso. Sull'una 
mano, Roosevelt non ha firmato mai la legislazione anti-anti-lynching;
ha accettato la segregazione ed il disenfranchisement; ed 
ha perdonato la distinzione contro i neri nei programmi federalmente 
costituiti un fondo per di rilievo. D'altra parte, Roosevelt ha 
vinto i cuori ed i voti degli Americani africani nei numeri senza 
precedente. Molti Americani neri votati non soltanto per 
Roosevelt; lo hanno trasformato un hero. "Franklin," 
"Eleanor," "Delano," e perfino "Roosevelt" si è transformato in in 
nomi popolari per i bambini neri nei 1930s. e molti Americani africani
hanno appeso l'immagine del presidente sulle loro pareti al lato di 
quelle di Christ e di Lincoln. Un'altra indicazione 
dell'impressione potente che Roosevelt fatto nella Comunità nera era 
registrazione del Joe Williams grande di un tributo degli azzurri in 
occasione della morte del Roosevelt in 1945, "il suo spirito vive su."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σχέση μεταξύ αφρικανικοί Αμερικανών και Franklin 
Δ. Roosevelt παρουσιάζει κάτι ενός παραδόξου. Αφ' ενός, 
Roosevelt δεν επικύρωσε ποτέ τη νομοθεσία αντι-λυντσαρίσματος  
αποδέχθηκε το διαχωρισμό και το disenfranchisement  
και συγχώρησε τη διάκριση ενάντια στους Μαύρους στα 
ομοσπονδιακά χρηματοδοτημένα προγράμματα ανακούφισης. Αφ' 
ετέρου, Roosevelt κέρδισε τις καρδιές και τις ψηφοφορίες 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών στους πρωτοφανείς αριθμούς. Πολλοί 
μαύροι Αμερικανοί όχι μόνο ψήφισαν για Roosevelt  τον 
έκαναν σε έναν ήρωα. "Franklin," "Eleanor," 
"Delano," και ακόμη και "Roosevelt" έγινε δημοφιλή ονόματα 
για τα μαύρα παιδιά στη δεκαετία του '30 και πολλοί αφρικανικοί 
Αμερικανοί κρέμασαν την εικόνα του Προέδρου στους τοίχους τους 
εκτός από εκείνους Χριστού και του Λίνκολν. Μια άλλη 
ένδειξη της ισχυρής εντύπωσης ότι Roosevelt που κατασκευάστηκε
στη μαύρη κοινότητα ήταν μεγάλη καταγραφή Joe Williams' 
ενός φόρου μπλε επ' ευκαιρία του θανάτου Roosevelt το 1945, 
"το πνεύμα του ζει επάνω."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El lazo entre los presentes africanos de los 
americanos y de Franklin D. Roosevelt algo de una paradoja. En 
la una mano, Roosevelt nunca endosó la legislación 
contra-anti-lynching; él validó la segregación y el 
disenfranchisement; y él perdonó la discriminación contra 
negros en programas federal financiados de la relevación. Por 
otra parte, Roosevelt ganó los corazones y los votos de americanos 
africanos en números sin precedentes. Muchos americanos negros 
votados no solamente por Roosevelt; lo hicieron en un héroe. 
"Franklin," "Eleanor," "Delano," e iguala "Roosevelt" hizo 
nombres populares para los niños negros en los años 30 y muchos 
americanos africanos colgaron el cuadro del presidente en sus paredes 
al lado de los de Cristo y de Lincoln. Otra indicación de la 
impresión de gran alcance que Roosevelt hecho en la comunidad negra 
era grabación de Joe Williams grande de un tributo de los azul en 
ocasión de la muerte de Roosevelt en 1945, "su alcohol vive en."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086206</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106694</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/gonna-miss-president-roosevelt-the-blues-for-fdr</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
