<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107696</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107696</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200339</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Acids and Bases: Testing Rocket Cars</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Säuren und Unterseiten: Prüfenrakete 
Autos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Acides et bases : Voitures de Test de 
Fusée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ácidos e bases: Carros Testando Do Foguete</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Acidi e basi: Automobili Difficili Del 
Razzo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οξέα και βάσεις: Εξεταστικά αυτοκίνητα πυραύλων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ácidos y bases: Coches De prueba Del 
Cohete</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A car propelled by the reaction between lemon juice and baking soda has more in common with rockets and jet aircraft than one might think. In this video segment adapted from ZOOM, two cast members demonstrate the power of rocket-propelled vehicles and how to exploit the force produced by the carbon dioxide gas. Grades 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Auto, das durch die Reaktion zwischen 
Zitronesaft und Backensoda angetrieben wird, hat mehr im Common mit 
Raketen und Strahl Flugzeug, als man denken konnte. In diesem 
Bildschirm paßte sich Segment vom ZOOM an, demonstrieren zwei 
geworfene Bauteile die Energie der raketenangetriebenen Träger und 
wie man die Kraft ausnutzt, die durch das Kohlendioxydgas produziert 
wird. Grade 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une voiture propulsée par la réaction entre le 
jus de citron et le bicarbonate de soude a plus en commun avec des 
fusées et voyage en jet l'avion que l'on a pourrait penser. 
Dans ce vidéo le segment s'est adapté du ZOOM, deux membres 
moulés démontrent la puissance des véhicules à fusée propulsée 
et comment exploiter la force produite par le gaz d'anhydride 
carbonique. Catégories 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um carro propelido pela reação entre o suco da 
limão e a soda de baking tem mais na terra comum com foguetes e 
avião do jato do que se pôde pensar. Neste vídeo o segmento 
adaptou-se do ZOOM, dois membros moldados demonstram a potência de 
veículos rocket-propelled e como explorar a força produzida pelo 
gás do dióxido de carbono. Classes 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un automobile azionato dalla reazione fra la 
spremuta del limone ed il bicarbonato di sodio ha più il in comune 
con i razzi ed il velivolo del getto che si potrebbe pensare. In
questo video segmento si è adattato dallo ZOOM, due membri fusi 
dimostrano l'potenza dei veicoli rocket-propelled e come sfruttare la 
forza prodotta dal gas dell'anidride carbonica. Gradi 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα αυτοκίνητο που ωθείται από την αντίδραση μεταξύ 
του χυμού λεμονιών και της σόδας ψησίματος έχει περισσότερων 
από κοινού με τους πυραύλους και τα αεροσκάφη αεριωθούμενων 
αεροπλάνων από κάποιο να σκεφτεί. Σε αυτό το τηλεοπτικό 
τμήμα μνήμης που προσαρμόζεται από το ΖΟΥΜ, δύο χυτά μέλη 
καταδεικνύουν τη δύναμη των πύραυλος-ωθημένων οχημάτων και πώς 
να εκμεταλλευτούν τη δύναμη που παράγεται από το διοξείδιο του 
άνθρακα αέριο. Βαθμοί 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un coche propulsado por la reacción entre el jugo
del limón y el bicarbonato de sosa tiene más en campo común con los
cohetes y el avión del jet que uno pudo pensar. En este vídeo 
el segmento se adaptó de ZOOM, dos miembros echados demuestran la 
potencia de vehículos impulsados por un cohete y cómo explotar la 
fuerza producida por el gas del bióxido de carbono. Grados 3-8.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
FN:WGBH EDUCATIONAL FOUNDATION
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200339</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107696</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/acids-and-bases-testing-rocket-cars</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
