<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103382</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103382</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086947</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Great Prevalence of Sexual Inversion": Havelock Ellis on Gay Life in the American City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das große Vorherrschen der sexuellen 
Umstellung": Havelock Ellis auf homosexueller Lebensdauer in der
amerikanischen Stadt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la grande prédominance de l'inversion sexuelle" 
: Havelock Ellis la vie gaie dans la ville américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o prevalence grande do inversion sexual": 
Havelock Ellis na vida gay na cidade americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la prevalenza grande dell'inversione sessuale": 
Havelock Ellis su vita di Gay nella città americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η μεγάλη επικράτηση της σεξουαλικής αντιστροφήσ": 
Havelock Ellis στην ομοφυλοφιλική ζωή στην αμερικανική
πόλη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el gran predominio de la inversión sexual": 
Havelock Ellis en vida Gay en la ciudad americana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the Civil War through the 1920s, in New York and other American cities, there were numerous clubs, saloons, and dance halls known for transvestism (men or women dressing as the opposite sex), for male prostitution, or as places that catered to a "gay crowd"--meaning men and women interested in a less conventional evening's entertainment. In the 1920s, in part because of prohibition and the emergence of speakeasies, homosexuality became even more open. At the same time, psychologists, physicians, and social reformers had been at work attempting to study, classify, categorize, and label human sexual behavior. In an excerpt from his 1915 book, British physician and psychologist Havelock Ellis, a pioneer in the emerging field of human sexuality, mapped out for his readers the culture of "sexual inversion" in American cities, reflecting how practices that had long been common, or at least tolerated, were suddenly viewed as problematic.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vom Bürgerkrieg durch die zwanziger Jahre, in New
York und in anderen amerikanischen Städte, gab es zahlreichen 
Vereine, Saloons und die Tanzhallen, die für transvestism bekannt 
sind (die Männer oder Frauen, die als das gegenüberliegende 
Geschlecht ankleiden), für männliche Prostitution oder als Plätze, 
die einer "homosexuellen Masse" boten -- die Bedeutung Männer und 
Frauen, die an der Unterhaltung eines weniger herkömmlichen Abends 
interessiert wurden. In den zwanziger Jahren im Teil wegen des 
Verbots und im Hervortreten von Speakeasies, wurde Homosexualität 
sogar mehr geöffnet. Gleichzeitig waren Psychologen, Ärzte und
SozialReformer an der Arbeit gewesen, die versucht, menschliches
sexuelles Verhalten zu studieren, einzustufen, zu kategorisieren und 
zu beschriften. In einem Excerpt von seinem Buch 1915, von 
britischen Arzt und von Psychologen Havelock Ellis, fangen 
ein Pionier im Auftauchen von der menschlichen Sexualität auf, 
für seine Leser die Kultur "der sexuellen Umstellung" in den 
amerikanischen Städte heraus abgebildet und reflektieren, wie Praxis,
die lang geläufig gewesen war, oder mindestens zugelassen, plötzlich
angesehen wurde, wie problematisch.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">De la guerre civile par les années 20, à New 
York et d'autres villes américaines, il y avait de nombreux clubs, 
salles, et halls de danse connus pour le transvestism (des hommes ou 
des femmes s'habillant comme sexe opposé), pour la prostitution 
mâle, ou comme endroits qui ont approvisionné "à une foule gaie" --
des hommes et des femmes de signification intéressés au 
divertissement d'une soirée moins conventionnelle. Dans les 
années 20, en partie en raison de prohibition et l'apparition des 
bars clandestins, l'homosexualité est devenue bien plus ouverte. En
même temps, les psychologues, les médecins, et les réformateurs 
sociaux avaient été au travail essayant d'étudier, classifier, 
classer par catégorie, et étiqueter le comportement sexuel humain. 
Dans un extrait de son livre 1915, médecin britannique et 
psychologue Havelock Ellis, un pionnier dans le domaine naissant de la
sexualité humaine, tracé dehors pour ses lecteurs la culture "de 
l'inversion sexuelle" dans les villes américaines, reflétant comment
des pratiques qui avaient longtemps été communes, ou au moins 
toléré, ont été soudainement visualisées comme problématiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Da guerra civil com os 1920s, em New York e em 
outras cidades americanas, havia clubes, saloons, e salões numerosos 
da dança conhecidos para o transvestism (os homens ou as mulheres que
se vestem como o sexo oposto), para a prostituição masculina, ou 
como os lugares que catered "a uma multidão gay" -- os homens e as 
mulheres do meaning interessados no entertainment de uma noite mais 
menos convencional. Nos 1920s, na parte por causa da proibição
e no emergence dos speakeasies, o homosexuality transformou-se mesmo 
mais aberto. Ao mesmo tempo, os psicólogos, os médicos, e os 
reformers sociais tinham estado no trabalho que tenta estudar, 
classificar, categorizar, e etiquetar o comportamento sexual humano. 
Em um excerpt de seus livro 1915, médico britânico e 
psicólogo Havelock Ellis, um pioneiro no campo emergente do sexuality
humano, traçado para fora para seus leitores a cultura "do inversion 
sexual" em cidades americanas, refletindo como as práticas que tinham
sido por muito tempo comuns, ou tolerado ao menos, foram vistas de 
repente como problematic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dalla guerra civile con gli anni 20, a New York ed
altre città americane, ci erano randelli, saloni e corridoi numerosi 
di ballo conosciuti per il transvestism (uomini o donne che si vestono
come il sesso opposto), per prostituzione maschio, o come posti che 
hanno approvvigionato "ad una folla di gay" -- uomini e donne 
di significato interessati all'intrattenimento della sera meno 
convenzionale. Negli anni 20, in parte a causa della proibizione
e l'emersione degli speakeasies, l'omosessualità è diventato ancor 
più aperta. Allo stesso tempo, gli psicologi, i medici ed i 
reformers sociali erano stati sul lavoro che tenta di studiare, 
classificare, categorizzare ed identificare il comportamento sessuale 
umano. In un brano dal suoi libro 1915, medico britannico e 
psicologo Havelock Ellis, un pioniere nel campo d'emersione del 
sexuality umano, tracciato fuori per i suoi lettori la coltura 
"dell'inversione sessuale" in città americane, riflettente come le 
pratiche che lungamente erano state comuni, o tollerato almeno, sono 
state osservate improvvisamente come problematiche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο μέσω της δεκαετίας του '20, 
στη Νέα Υόρκη και άλλες αμερικανικές πόλεις, υπήρξαν 
πολυάριθμες λέσχες, αίθουσες, και αίθουσες χορού γνωστές για το 
διασεξουαλισμό (άνδρες ή γυναίκες που ντύνουν ως αντίθετο 
φύλο), για την αρσενική πορνεία, ή ως θέσεις που τροφοδότησαν σε
ένα "ομοφυλοφιλικό πλήθοσ" -- σημαίνοντας τους άνδρες και τις 
γυναίκες ενδιαφερόμενους στην ψυχαγωγία ενός λιγότερο συμβατικού
βραδιού. Στη δεκαετία του '20, εν μέρει λόγω της 
απαγόρευσης και την εμφάνιση των speakeasies, η ομοφυλοφυλία 
έγινε ακόμα ανοικτότερη. Συγχρόνως, οι ψυχολόγοι, οι 
παθολόγοι, και οι κοινωνικοί μεταρρυθμιστές ήταν στην εργασία που
προσπαθεί να μελετήσουν, να ταξινομήσουν, να ταξινομήσουν, και 
ονομάζουν την ανθρώπινη σεξουαλική συμπεριφορά. Σε ένα 
απόσπασμα από το βιβλίο του 1915, το βρετανικούς παθολόγο και 
τον ψυχολόγο του Havelock Ellis, ένας πρωτοπόρος στο 
αναδυόμενο πεδίο της ανθρώπινης σεξουαλικότητας, χάραξε για τους 
αναγνώστες του τον πολιτισμό της "σεξουαλικής αντιστροφήσ" στις 
αμερικανικές πόλεις, απεικονίζοντας πώς οι πρακτικές που ήταν 
από καιρό κοινές, ή ανεχθείς τουλάχιστον, εμφανίστηκαν ξαφνικά
όπως προβληματικές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De la guerra civil con los años 20, en Nueva York
y otras ciudades americanas, había clubs, salones, y pasillos 
numerosos de la danza conocidos para el transvestism (los hombres o 
las mujeres que visten como el sexo opuesto), para la prostitución 
masculina, o como lugares que abastecieron a una "muchedumbre 
gay" -- los hombres y las mujeres del significado interesados 
en la hospitalidad de una tarde menos convencional. En los años
20, en parte debido a la prohibición y la aparición de bares, la 
homosexualidad llegó a estar aún más abierta. En el mismo 
tiempo, los psicólogos, los médicos, y los reformadores sociales 
habían estado en el trabajo que procuraba estudiar, clasificar, 
categorizar, y etiquetar comportamiento sexual humano. En un 
extracto de su libro 1915, médico británico y psicólogo Havelock 
Ellis, un pionero en el campo que emerge de la sexualidad humana, 
asociado hacia fuera para sus programas de lectura la cultura de la 
"inversión sexual" en ciudades americanas, reflejando cómo las 
prácticas que habían sido de largo comunes, o tolerado por lo menos,
fueron vistas repentinamente como problemáticas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086947</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103382</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-great-prevalence-of-sexual-inversion-havelock-ellis-on-gay-life-in-the-american-city</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
