<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103088</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103088</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202750</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Eroded Land, Eroded Lives: Agriculture and The Grapes of Wrath (lesson 1 of 10)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abgefressenes Land, Abgefressen Worden Leben: 
Landwirtschaft und die Trauben des Zorns (Lektion 1 von
10)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Terre Érodée, Érodée Les Vies : 
Agriculture et les raisins de la colère (leçon 1 de 10)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Terra Corroída, Corroída Vidas: 
Agricultura e as uvas do wrath (lição 1 de 10)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Terra Corrosa, Corrosa Vite: Agricoltura e 
l'uva di wrath (lezione 1 di 10)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαβρωμένο έδαφος, που διαβρώνεται ζωές: 
Γεωργία και τα σταφύλια της οργής (μάθημα 1 10)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pista Erosionada, Erosionada Vidas: 
Agricultura y las uvas de la cólera (lección 1 de 10)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This description is of only the first lesson in the unit, to be taught before students read the novel; thus, its primary purpose is to put this novel in historical context. Toward that end, students will learn about the (unintentional) abuse of soil that allowed the Dust Bowl to be so devastating and extensive. They will also see photographs by Dorothea Lange and others depicting the wasted land and subsequent wasted dreams of thousands. See Supplemental Resources and Relevant Web Sites for material.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Beschreibung ist nur von der ersten Lektion 
in der Maßeinheit, unterrichtet zu werden, bevor Kursteilnehmer den 
Roman lesen; so ist sein Primärzweck, diesen Roman in 
historischen Kontext einzusetzen. In Richtung zu diesem Ende 
erlernen Kursteilnehmer über den (unbeabsichtigten) Mißbrauch des 
Bodens, der das Trockengebiet so verheerend und umfangreich sein 
ließ. Sie sehen auch Fotographien durch Dorothea Lange und 
andere, die das vergeudete Land und die folgenden vergeudeten Träume 
von Tausenden bildlich darstellen. Sehen Sie zusätzliche 
Betriebsmittel und relevante Web-Sites für Material.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette description est de la première leçon 
seulement dans l'unité, être enseigné avant que les étudiants 
lisent le roman ; ainsi, son but primaire est de mettre ce roman
dans le contexte historique. Vers cette extrémité, les 
étudiants se renseigneront sur l'abus (involontaire) du sol qui a 
permis à la cuvette de poussière d'être si dévastatrice et 
étendue. Ils verront également des photographies par Dorothea 
Lange et d'autres dépeignant la terre gaspillée et les rêves 
gaspillés ultérieurs des milliers. Voir les ressources 
supplémentaires et les sites appropriés de Web pour le 
matériel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta descrição é somente da primeira lição na
unidade, para ser ensinado antes que os estudantes leiam a novela; 
assim, sua finalidade preliminar é pôr esta novela no contexto
histórico. Para essa extremidade, os estudantes aprenderão 
sobre o abuso (involuntário) do solo que permitiu que a bacia de 
poeira fosse assim devastating e extensiva. Verão também 
fotografias por Dorothea Lange e outro que descrevem a terra 
desperdiçada e os sonhos desperdiçados subseqüentes dos milhares. 
Veja recursos suplementares e locais relevantes do Web para o 
material.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa descrizione è soltanto della prima lezione
nell'unità, essere insegnato prima che gli allievi leggano il 
romanzo; quindi, il relativo scopo primario è mettere questo 
romanzo nel contesto storico. Verso quell'estremità, gli 
allievi impareranno circa l'abuso (involontario) di terreno che ha 
permesso che la ciotola di polvere fosse così devastating e vasta. 
Inoltre vedranno le fotografie da Dorothea Lange ed altri che 
descrivono la terra sprecata ed i sogni sprecati successivi delle 
migliaia. Veda le risorse supplementari ed i luoghi relativi di 
Web per materiale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιγραφή είναι μόνο του πρώτου μαθήματος στη
μονάδα, που διδάσκεται προτού να διαβάσουν οι σπουδαστές το 
μυθιστόρημα  κατά συνέπεια, ο αρχικός σκοπός του είναι να 
βάλει αυτό το μυθιστόρημα στο ιστορικό πλαίσιο. Προς 
εκείνο το τέλος, οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν για τη (ακούσια) 
κατάχρηση του χώματος που επέτρεψε στο κύπελλο σκόνης για να 
είναι έτσι καταστρεπτικό και εκτενές. Θα δουν 
επίσης τις φωτογραφίες από Dorothea Lange και άλλες που 
απεικονίζουν το σπαταλημένο έδαφος και τα επόμενα σπαταλημένα 
όνειρα των χιλιάδων. Δείτε τα συμπληρωματικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και τους σχετικούς ιστοχώρους για το υλικό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta descripción está solamente de la primera 
lección en la unidad, ser enseñado antes de que los estudiantes lean
la novela; así, su propósito primario es poner esta novela en 
contexto histórico. Hacia ese extremo, los estudiantes 
aprenderán sobre el abuso (inintencional) del suelo que permitió que
el tazón de fuente de polvo fuera tan devastador y extenso. 
También verán las fotografías de Dorothea Lange y otros que 
representan la pista perdida y los sueños perdidos subsecuentes de 
millares. Vea los recursos suplementales y los sitios relevantes
del Web para el material.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ANNIE HENRY
FN:ANNIE HENRY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202750</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103088</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/eroded-land-eroded-lives-agriculture-and-the-grapes-of-wrath-lesson-1-of-10</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
