<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104046</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104046</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086916</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Civilizing Force of Birth Control": Margaret Sanger Becomes a Moderate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die zivilisierende Kraft der Geburtenkontrolle": 
Margaret Sanger wird ein gemäßigtes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la force de civilisation du contrôle des 
naissances" : Margaret Sanger devient un modéré</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a força civilizing do controle de nascimento": 
Margaret Sanger transforma-se um moderado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la forza di civilizzazione di controllo di 
nascita": Margaret Sanger si transforma in in un moderato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η δύναμη εκπολιτισμού του ελέγχου γέννησησ": 
Θ*Μαργαρετ Sanger Becomes ένας μέτριος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la fuerza de civilización del control de la 
natalidad": Margaret Sanger se convierte en un moderado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Margaret Sanger gained notoriety as an advocate for contraception, which she defined as essential for women's freedom. By the late 1920s, however, Sanger's radicalism had become muted. In "The Civilizing Force of Birth Control," she addressed middle-class constituencies with the argument that contraception would strengthen marriage. Like many liberal intellectuals of the time, Sanger was a eugenicist--she believed in managing human reproduction to improve "the race" through better breeding. Many eugenicists were concerned about declining fertility among college-educated and middle-class women, even as they also worried about what they saw as the excessive fertility of poorer women. However, unlike many eugenicists who urged elite women to have more children, Sanger argued that birth control for all women would serve the cause of eugenics. This essay appeared in  Sex in Civilization  (1929), a voluminous collection of commentary that suggested the emergence of a new species of expert--the sexologist.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Margaret Sanger gewann Allbekanntheit als 
Fürsprecher für Empfängnisverhütung, die sie definierte, wie 
wesentlich für Freiheit der Frauen. Bis zum den späten 
zwanziger Jahren jedoch war Radikalismus Sangers gedämpft geworden.
"in der zivilisierenden Kraft der Geburtenkontrolle," sprach sie
zu Mittelklassewahlkreisen mit dem Argument, daß 
Empfängnisverhütung Verbindung verstärken würde. Wie viele 
liberale Intellektuelle der Zeit, war Sanger ein eugenicist -- sie 
glaubte, an, menschliche Wiedergabe zu handhaben, um "das Rennen" 
durch besser züchten zu verbessern. Viele eugenicists wurden 
über abfallende Ergiebigkeit unter den Hochschule-gebildeten und 
Mittelklassefrauen betroffen, selbst als sie sich auch sorgten um, was
sie als die übermäßige Ergiebigkeit der ärmeren Frauen sahen. 
Jedoch anders als viele eugenicists, die Auslesefrauen 
drängten, mehr Kinder zu haben, argumentierte Sanger, daß 
Geburtenkontrolle für alle Frauen die Ursache von eugenics dienen 
würde. Dieser Versuch erschien im Geschlecht in Civilization 
(1929), eine umfangreiche Ansammlung des Kommentars, die das 
Hervortreten einer neuen Sorte Experte -- das sexologist vorschlug.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Margaret Sanger a gagné la notoriété en tant 
qu'avocat pour la contraception, qu'elle a définie comme essentiel 
pour la liberté des femmes. Par les années 20 en retard, 
cependant, le radicalisme de Sanger était devenu amorti. Dans 
"la force de civilisation du contrôle des naissances," elle s'est 
adressée à des collèges électoraux de classe moyen avec l'argument
que la contraception renforcerait le mariage. Comme beaucoup 
d'intellectuels libéraux du temps, Sanger était un eugenicist -- 
elle a cru qu'il faut parvenir la reproduction humaine pour améliorer
"la course" en multipliant mieux. Beaucoup d'eugenicists ont 
été préoccupés par la fertilité en baisse parmi les femmes 
université-instruites et de classe moyenne, même pendant qu'ils 
s'inquiétaient également de ce qu'ils ont vu comme fertilité 
excessive de plus pauvres femmes. Cependant, à la différence 
de beaucoup d'eugenicists qui ont invité des femmes d'élite à avoir
plus d'enfants, Sanger a argué du fait que le contrôle des 
naissances pour toutes les femmes servirait la cause de 
l'eugénie. Cet essai est apparu dans le sexe en 
Civilization (1929), une collection volumineuse de commentaire qui a 
suggéré l'apparition de l'de nouvelles espèces d'expert -- le 
sexologist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Margaret Sanger ganhou o notoriety como um 
advogado para o contraception, que definiu como essencial para a 
liberdade das mulheres. Pelos 1920s atrasados, entretanto, o 
radicalism de Sanger tinha-se tornado muted. "na força 
civilizing do controle de nascimento," dirigiu-se a círculos 
eleitorais do middle-class com o argumento que o contraception 
strengthen a união. Como muitos intelectuais liberais do tempo,
Sanger era um eugenicist -- acreditou em controlar a reprodução 
humana melhorar "a raça" com mais melhor produzir. Muitos 
eugenicists foram concernidos sobre a fertilidade declinando entre 
mulheres faculdade-educadas e do middle-class, mesmo enquanto se 
preocuparam também sobre o que viram como a fertilidade excessiva de 
umas mulheres mais deficientes. Entretanto, ao contrário de 
muitos eugenicists que incitaram mulheres do elite ter mais crianças,
Sanger discutiu que o controle de nascimento para todas as mulheres 
serviria à causa do eugenics. Este essay apareceu no sexo em 
Civilização (1929), uma coleção voluminous do commentary que 
sugerisse o emergence de uma espécie nova do perito -- o sexologist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Margaret Sanger ha guadagnato il notoriety come 
fautore per la contraccezione, che ha definito come essenziale per la 
libertà delle donne. Entro gli anni 20 tardi, tuttavia, il 
radicalism del Sanger era diventato muted. "nella forza di 
civilizzazione di controllo di nascita," ha parlato ai collegi 
elettorali della classe media con l'argomento che la contraccezione 
rinforzerebbe l'unione. Come molti intellettuali liberali del 
tempo, Sanger era un eugenicist -- ha creduto nel riuscire la 
riproduzione umana per migliorare "la corsa" con più meglio allevare.
Molti eugenicists sono stati interessati circa fertilità 
declinante fra le donne della classe media e università-istruite, 
proprio mentre egualmente si sono preoccupati per che cosa hanno visto
come la fertilità eccessiva di più povere donne. Tuttavia,
diverso di molti eugenicists che hanno invitato le donne dell'elite ad
avere più bambini, Sanger ha sostenuto che il controllo di nascita 
per tutte le donne servirebbe la causa del eugenics. Questo 
saggio è comparso nel sesso in Civilization (1929), una collezione 
voluminosa di commento che ha suggerito l'emersione di nuova specie di
esperto -- il sexologist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Margaret Sanger κέρδισε την κακή φήμη ως 
συνήγορο για την αντισύλληψη, την οποία όρισε ως ουσιαστική για 
την ελευθερία των γυναικών. Μέχρι την πρόσφατη δεκαετία του
'20, εντούτοις, η ριζοσπαστισμός Sanger είχε γίνει χαμηλωμένη.
"Στη δύναμη εκπολιτισμού του ελέγχου γέννησης," εξέτασε τις
εκλογικές περιφέρειες μεσαίων τάξεων με το όρισμα ότι η 
αντισύλληψη θα ενίσχυε το γάμο. Όπως πολλούς φιλελεύθερους
διανοούμενους του χρόνου, Sanger ήταν eugenicist -- πίστεψε 
να κατορθώσει την ανθρώπινη αναπαραγωγή για να βελτιωθεί "η φυλή"
μέσω της καλύτερης αναπαραγωγής. Πολλά eugenicists 
ανησύχησαν για τη μειωμένος γονιμότητα μεταξύ των 
κολλέγιο-εκπαιδευμένων και γυναικών μεσαίων τάξεων, ακόμη και 
όπως ανησύχησαν επίσης για αυτό που εβλέίδαν ως 
υπερβολική γονιμότητα των φτωχότερων γυναικών. Εντούτοις, 
αντίθετα από πολλά eugenicists που ώθησαν τις γυναίκες ελίτ 
για να έχουν περισσότερα παιδιά, Sanger υποστήριξε ότι ο 
έλεγχος γέννησης για όλες τις γυναίκες θα εξυπηρετούσε την αιτία
της ευγονικής. Αυτό το δοκίμιο εμφανίστηκε στο φύλο στον 
πολιτισμό (1929), μια ογκώδης συλλογή των σχολίων που πρότεινε
την εμφάνιση ενός νέου είδους εμπειρογνώμονα -- το sexologist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Margaret Sanger ganó notoriedad como abogado para
la contracepción, que ella definió como esencial para la libertad de
las mujeres. Por los últimos años 20, sin embargo, el 
radicalismo de Sanger había llegado a ser silenciado. En "la 
fuerza de civilización del control de la natalidad," ella se dirigió
a los distritos electorales de la clase media con el argumento que la 
contracepción consolidaría la unión. Como muchos 
intelectuales liberales del tiempo, Sanger era un eugenicist -- ella 
creyó en el manejo de la reproducción humana para mejorar "la raza" 
con mejor la crianza. Muchos eugenicists fueron referidos sobre 
fertilidad que declinaba entre mujeres universidad-educadas y de la 
clase media, incluso mientras que también se preocuparon de lo que 
vieron como la fertilidad excesiva de mujeres más pobres. Sin 
embargo, desemejante de muchos eugenicists que impulsaron a mujeres de
la élite tener más niños, Sanger discutió que el control de la 
natalidad para todas las mujeres sirviera la causa del eugenics. 
Este ensayo apareció en el sexo en Civilization (1929), una 
colección voluminosa del comentario que sugirió la aparición de una
nueva especie del experto -- el sexologist.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086916</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104046</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-civilizing-force-of-birth-control-margaret-sanger-becomes-a-moderate</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
