<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104740</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104740</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206249</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Science and Technology Week</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geowissenschaft und Technologie-Woche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Science de la terre et semaine de technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência de terra e semana da tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze della terra e settimana di tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εβδομάδα γήινων επιστήμης και τεχνολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Geología y semana de la tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">includes lesson plans on faults, groundwater movement, petroleum exploration, earthquakes, building a weather station, soil, floods, volcanoes, hurricane tracking, thunderstorms, lightning, sinkholes, disaster supplies kits, caves, mud fossils, global change, acid mine drainage, mineral identification, water filtration, water cycle, fresh water and sea water, watersheds, water use at home, wetlands, and ocean currents.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schließt Lektionpläne auf Störungen, 
Grundwasserbewegung, Erdölerforschung, die Erdbeben ein und baut eine
Wetterstation, Boden, Fluten, Vulkane auf, der zu Hause aufspürende 
Hurrikan, Thunderstorms, Blitz, Drecklöcher, 
Unfallversorgungsmaterialsätze, Höhlen, Schlammfossilien, globale 
Änderung, saure Grube Entwässerung, Mineralkennzeichen, 
Wasserfiltration, Wasserschleife, Süßwasser und Meereswasser, 
Wasserscheiden, Wassergebrauch, Sumpfgebiete und Ozeanströme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">inclut des plans de leçon sur des défauts, 
mouvement d'eaux souterraines, prospection pétrolière, tremblements 
de terre, établissant une station de survivre à, sol, inondations, 
volcans, ouragan dépistant, orages, foudre, effondrements, lots des 
consommables de désastre, cavernes, fossiles de boue, changement 
global, drainage acide de mine, identification minérale, filtration 
de l'eau, cycle de l'eau, eau doux et eau de mer, lignes de partage, 
utilisation de l'eau à la maison, marécages, et courants d'océan.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">inclui plantas da lição em falhas, movimento do 
groundwater, exploração de petróleo, terremotos, construindo uma 
estação de tempo, solo, inundações, vulcões, furacão que seguem,
thunderstorms, relâmpago, sinkholes, kits de suprimentos do disastre,
cavernas, fossils da lama, mudança global, drenagem ácida da mina, 
identificação mineral, filtration da água, ciclo da água, água 
fresca e água de mar, watersheds, uso da água na HOME, wetlands, e 
correntes do oceano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">include i programmi di lezione sui difetti, il 
movimento dell'acqua freatica, l'esplorazione di petrolio, terremoti, 
sviluppanti una stazione metereologica, terreno, inondazioni, vulcani,
uragano che rintracciano, thunderstorms, lampo, sinkholes, corredi 
iniziali di disastro, caverne, fossili del fango, cambiamento globale,
drenaggio acido della miniera, identificazione minerale, filtrazione 
dell'acqua, ciclo dell'acqua, acqua dolce ed acqua di mare, 
spartiacque, uso dell'acqua nel paese, wetlands e correnti 
dell'oceano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει τα σχέδια μαθήματος για τις βλάβες, 
μετακίνηση υπόγειων νερών, εξερεύνηση πετρελαίου, σεισμοί, που 
χτίζουν έναν καιρικό σταθμό, ένα χώμα, τις πλημμύρες, τα 
ηφαίστεια, την καταδίωξη τυφώνα, thunderstorms, την αστραπή, 
τις τρύπες αποχέτευσης, τις εξαρτήσεις προμηθειών καταστροφής, 
τις σπηλιές, τα απολιθώματα λάσπης, τη σφαιρική αλλαγή, την 
όξινη αποξήρανση ορυχείων, τον ορυκτό προσδιορισμό, τη διήθηση 
ύδατος, τον κύκλο ύδατος, το γλυκό νερό και το θαλάσσιο νερό, 
τους υδροκρίτες, τη χρήση ύδατος στο σπίτι, τους υγρότοπους, και 
τα ωκεάνια ρεύματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incluye planes de la lección en los incidentes, 
movimiento de la agua subterránea, explotación petrolera, 
terremotos, construyendo una estación meteorológica, suelo, las 
inundaciones, los volcanes, huracán que sigue, las tempestades de 
truenos, relámpago, los sinkholes, los kits de materiales consumibles
del desastre, las cuevas, los fósiles del fango, cambio global, 
drenaje ácido de la mina, identificación mineral, filtración del 
agua, ciclo del agua, agua dulce y agua de mar, las líneas divisoria 
de las aguas, uso del agua en el país, los wetlands, y las corrientes
del océano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206249</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104740</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-science-and-technology-week</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
