<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107677</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107677</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209919</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rhombus </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rhombus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Losange</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rhombus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rhombus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρόμβος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rombo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet showing the definition and properties of a rhombus. The applet shows a rhombus where the user can drag any vertex. The other points then move in such a way that the figure remains a rhombus at all times. A control to hide the details allows a classroom discussion where students can try to infer what the properties are as it is reshaped by the discussion leader. Text on the page has the formal definition and properties of the rhombus with links to related pages. A companion page is http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombusarea.html showing the ways to calculate the area of a rhombus Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, welche
die Definition und die Eigenschaften eines Rhombus zeigen. Der 
applet zeigt einem Rhombus, wo der Benutzer jeden möglichen Gipfel 
schleppen kann. Die anderen Punkte bewegen dann, so daß die 
Abbildung ein Rhombus ständig bleibt. Eine Steuerung, zum der 
Details zu verstecken erlaubt eine Klassenzimmerdiskussion, in der 
Kursteilnehmer versuchen können, zu schließen, was die Eigenschaften
sind, während es vom Diskussion Führer umgestaltet wird. Text 
auf der Seite hat die formale Definition und die Eigenschaften des 
Rhombus mit Links zu in Verbindung stehenden Seiten. Eine 
Begleiterseite ist darstellendes 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombusarea.html, daß die Methoden, den 
Bereich eines Rhombus applet zu errechnen zum vollen Bildumfang für 
Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden können.
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif montrant 
la définition et les propriétés d'un losange. L'applet 
montre à un losange où l'utilisateur peut traîner n'importe 
quel sommet. Les autres points se déplacent alors de telle 
manière que la figure demeure un losange à tout moment. 
Une commande pour cacher les détails permet une discussion de 
salle de classe où les étudiants peuvent essayer d'impliquer ce que 
les propriétés sont pendant qu'il est restructuré par l'amorce de 
discussion. Le texte à la page a la définition et les 
propriétés formelles du losange avec des liens aux pages 
relatives. Une page de compagnon est 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombusarea.html montrant que les voies de 
calculer la zone d'un applet de losange peuvent être agrandies à
la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que mostram a 
definição e as propriedades de um rhombus. O applet mostra a 
um rhombus onde o usuário pode arrastar todo o vertex. Os 
outros pontos movem-se então de tal maneira que a figura remanesce um
rhombus em todas as vezes. Um controle para esconder os detalhes
permite uma discussão da sala de aula onde os estudantes possam 
tentar infer o que as propriedades são enquanto reshaped pelo líder 
de discussão. O texto na página tem a definição e as 
propriedades formais do rhombus com ligações às páginas 
relacionadas. Uma página do companheiro é 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombusarea.html que mostra que as maneiras
calcular a área de um applet do rhombus podem ser ampliadas ao 
tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che mostrano 
la definizione e le proprietà di un rhombus. Il applet mostra 
ad un rhombus dove l'utente può trascinare tutto il vertice. 
Gli altri punti allora si muovono im modo tale che la figura 
rimane sempre un rhombus. Un controllo per nascondere i 
particolari permette una discussione dell'aula dove gli allievi 
possono provare ad arguire che cosa le proprietà sono mentre è 
rimodellato dal capo di discussione. Il testo alla 
pagina ha la definizione e le proprietà convenzionali del rhombus con
i collegamenti alle pagine relative. Una pagina del compagno è 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombusarea.html che mostra che i modi 
calcolare la zona di un applet del rhombus possono essere ingranditi 
al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. 
La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora 
da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio 
attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del 
progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto
di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που εμφανίζουν
τον καθορισμό και ιδιότητες ενός ρόμβου. Το applet 
εμφανίζει έναν ρόμβο όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει 
οποιοδήποτε vertex. Τα άλλα σημεία κινούνται έπειτα 
κατά τέτοιο τρόπο ώστε ο αριθμός παραμένει ένας ρόμβος πάντα.
Ένας έλεγχος για να κρύψει τις λεπτομέρειες επιτρέπει μια 
συζήτηση τάξεων όπου οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να προσπαθήσουν να 
συμπεράνουν τι οι ιδιότητες είναι όπως αναδιαμορφώνεται από τον 
ηγέτη συζήτησης. Το κείμενο στη σελίδα έχει τον επίσημους 
καθορισμό και τις ιδιότητες του ρόμβου με τις συνδέσεις με τις 
σχετικές σελίδες. Μια σελίδα συντρόφων είναι 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombusarea.html εμφανίζοντας ότι οι 
τρόποι να υπολογιστεί η περιοχή ενός ρόμβου Applet μπορούν να
διευρυνθούν στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que muestran 
la definición y las características de un rombo. El applet 
muestra a rombo donde el utilizador puede arrastrar cualquier cima. 
Las otras puntas entonces se mueven de una manera tal que la 
figura siga siendo un rombo siempre. Un control para ocultar los
detalles permite una discusión de la sala de clase donde los 
estudiantes pueden intentar deducir cuál son las características 
mientras que es restructurada por el arranque de cinta de discusión. 
El texto en la paginación tiene la definición y las 
características formales del rombo con conexiones a las paginaciones 
relacionadas. Una paginación del compañero es 
http://www.mathopenref.com/rhombusarea.html que muestra que las 
maneras de calcular el área de un applet del rombo se pueden agrandar
a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la 
sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante 
puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o 
en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209919</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107677</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rhombus</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
