<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102868</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102868</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203295</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Illuminations, National Council of Teachers of Mathematics' Vision for School Mathematics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ablichtungen, Nationalrat der Lehrer des Anblicks 
der Mathematik für Schule-Mathematik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Illuminations, le Conseil national des professeurs
de la vision des mathématiques pour des mathématiques d'école</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Iluminações, conselho nacional dos professores 
da visão das matemática para a matemática da escola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Illuminazioni, Consiglio nazionale degli 
insegnanti di visione della matematica per matematica della scuola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φωτισμοί, το εθνικό Συμβούλιο των δασκάλων του 
οράματος των μαθηματικών για τα σχολικά μαθηματικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Iluminaciones, consejo nacional de profesores de 
la visión de las matemáticas para las matemáticas de la escuela</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The National Council of Teachers of Mathematics Illuminations Web site is designed to illuminate the new vision for school mathematics as presented in NCTM 's Principles and Standards for School Mathematics. The site provides resources that will help improve the teaching and learning of mathematics for all students, from pre-school through high school.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Nationalrat der Lehrer von 
Mathematik-Ablichtungen Web site ist konzipiert, um den neuen Anblick 
für Schulemathematik zu belichten, wie in NCTM dargestellt ' s 
Grundregeln und Standards für Schule-Mathematik. Die Site 
stellt Betriebsmittel, die helfen, den Unterricht und das Lernen von 
Mathematik für alle Kursteilnehmer zu verbessern, vom Vortraining 
durch High School zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Conseil national des professeurs du site de 
Web d'illuminations de mathématiques est conçu pour illuminer
la nouvelle vision pour des mathématiques d'école comme présenté 
principes et normes de s dans NCTM des 'pour des mathématiques 
d'école. Le site fournit les ressources qui aideront à 
améliorer l'enseignement et l'étude des mathématiques pour tous les
étudiants, du précours par le lycée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O conselho nacional dos professores do Web site 
das iluminações da matemática é projetado iluminar a visão nova 
para a matemática da escola como apresentada princípios e padrões 
de s de NCTM ' para a matemática da escola. O local fornece os 
recursos que ajudarão melhorar o ensino e a aprendizagem da 
matemática para todos os estudantes, do pré-escolar através da High
School.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Consiglio nazionale degli insegnanti del Web 
site di illuminazioni di matematica è destinato per illuminare la 
nuova visione per la matematica della scuola come presentato principii
e standard di s in NCTM 'per la matematica della scuola. Il 
luogo fornisce le risorse che contribuiranno a migliorare 
l'insegnamento ed imparare della matematica per tutti gli allievi, 
dall'addestramento preliminare attraverso la High School.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εθνικό Συμβούλιο των δασκάλων του ιστοχώρου 
φωτισμών μαθηματικών έχει ως σκοπό να φωτίσει το νέο όραμα για 
τα σχολικά μαθηματικά όπως παρουσιάζονται αρχές και πρότυπα 
NCTM τα στις "s για τα σχολικά μαθηματικά. Η περιοχή 
παρέχει τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς που θα βοηθήσουν να βελτιώσουν 
τη διδασκαλία και την εκμάθηση των μαθηματικών για όλους τους 
σπουδαστές, από προσχολικό μέσω του γυμνασίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diseñan al consejo nacional de profesores del 
sitio del Web de las iluminaciones de las matemáticas para 
iluminar la nueva visión para las matemáticas de la escuela según 
lo presentado en principios y estándares de s de NCTM los ' para las 
matemáticas de la escuela. El sitio proporciona a los recursos 
que ayudarán a mejorar la enseñanza y aprender de las matemáticas 
para todos los estudiantes, del pre-entrenamiento a través de High 
School secundaria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203295</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102868</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/illuminations-national-council-of-teachers-of-mathematics-vision-for-school-mathematics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
