<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107641</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107641</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203648</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lessons in Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lektionen in der Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Leçons en technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lições na tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lezioni nella tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθήματα στην τεχνολογία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lecciones en tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Rutgers School of Engineering provides numerous laboratory and lessons for grades 5-8. Lessons fall into three categories Civil and Environmental Engineering, Biocomplexity and Biocomplexity and Microorganisms. Some lessons include objectives, standards, materials and other relevant information. Laboratories are well described and can be easily adjusted for higher grade levels.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rutgers Schule der Technik stellt zahlreiches 
Labor und Lektionen für Grade 5-8 zur Verfügung. Lektionen 
fallen in drei Zivil Kategorien und Klimatechnik, Biocomplexity und 
Biocomplexity und Mikroorganismen. Einige Lektionen schließen 
Lernziele, Standards, Materialien und andere relevante Informationen 
ein. Labors werden gut beschrieben und können auf höhere 
Gradstufen leicht eingestellt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'école de Rutgers de l'ingénierie fournit le 
nombreux laboratoire et les leçons pour des catégories 5-8. 
Les leçons entrent dans trois catégories civiles et 
ingénierie environnementale, Biocomplexity et Biocomplexity et 
micro-organismes. Quelques leçons incluent des objectifs, des 
normes, des matériaux et toute autre information appropriée. 
Des laboratoires sont bien décrits et peuvent être facilement 
ajustés à des niveaux plus élevés de catégorie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A escola de Rutgers da engenharia fornece o 
laboratório numeroso e as lições para classes 5-8. As 
lições caem em três categorias civis e engenharia ambiental, 
Biocomplexity e Biocomplexity e microorganisms. Algumas lições
incluem objetivos, padrões, materiais e a outra informação 
relevante. Os laboratórios bem são descritos e podem 
fàcilmente ser ajustados para uns níveis mais elevados da classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La scuola di Rutgers di ingegneria fornisce il 
laboratorio numeroso e le lezioni per i gradi 5-8. Le lezioni 
entrano in tre categorie civili ed ingegneria ambientale, 
Biocomplexity e Biocomplexity e microorganismi. Alcune lezioni 
includono gli obiettivi, gli standard, i materiali ed altre 
informazioni relative. I laboratori bene sono descritti e 
possono essere registrati facilmente per ottenere i livelli elevati 
del grado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σχολή Rutgers της εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής παρέχει 
το πολυάριθμο εργαστήριο και τα μαθήματα για τους βαθμούς 5-8, 
μαθήματα περιέρχονται στην αστική και περιβαλλοντική εφαρμοσμένη 
μηχανική τριών κατηγοριών, Biocomplexity και Biocomplexity 
και τους μικροοργανισμούς. Μερικά μαθήματα περιλαμβάνουν 
τους στόχους, τα πρότυπα, τα υλικά και άλλες σχετικές 
πληροφορίες. Τα εργαστήρια περιγράφονται καλά και μπορούν 
να ρυθμιστούν εύκολα για τα πιό υψηλά επίπεδα βαθμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La escuela de Rutgers de la ingeniería 
proporciona al laboratorio numeroso y a las lecciones para los grados 
5-8. Las lecciones bajan en tres categorías civiles e 
ingeniería ambiental, Biocomplexity y Biocomplexity y los 
microorganismos. Algunas lecciones incluyen los objetivos, los 
estándares, los materiales y la otra información relevante. 
Los laboratorios se describen y se pueden bien ajustar 
fácilmente según niveles más altos del grado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:RUTGERS SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING, DEPT. OF CHEMICAL AND BIOCHEMICAL ENGINEERING
FN:RUTGERS SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING, DEPT. OF CHEMICAL AND BIOCHEMICAL ENGINEERING
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203648</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107641</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lessons-in-technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
