<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108787</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108787</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206744</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Geography: U.S. Geological Survey</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geographie: VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geologische 
Übersicht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Géographie : Enquête Géologique des 
ETATS-UNIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Geografia: Exame Geological de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Geografia: Indagine Geologica degli STATI 
UNITI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεωγραφία: ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ Γεωλογική έρευνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Geografía: Encuesta sobre Geológica 
ESTADOS UNIDOS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides online maps and map tools. Find maps that are popular with teachers, tools for teaching students how to read maps (and make them), resources on land use (changing landscapes), satellite images related to the journey of Lewis and Clark. Design your own map to display boundaries, geographic names, transportation systems, water, land cover, climate, and geology.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Onlinekarten und Karte Hilfsmittel zur 
Verfügung. Finden Sie Karten, die mit den Lehrern, den 
Hilfsmitteln populär sind, für, die Kursteilnehmer beibringen, wie 
man Karten (und sie bilden), den Betriebsmitteln auf Flächennutzung 
(ändernde Landschaften), den Satellitenbildern, die auf der Reise von
Lewis in Verbindung gestanden werden und Clark liest. 
Konzipieren Sie Ihre eigene Karte, um Grenzen, geographische 
Namen, Transportsysteme, Wasser, Landabdeckung, Klima und Geologie 
anzuzeigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit les cartes et les outils en ligne de 
carte. Trouvez les cartes qui sont populaires avec des 
professeurs, des outils pour enseignant à des étudiants comment lire
des cartes (et les faire), des ressources sur l'utilisation de la 
terre (horizontaux changeants), des images satellites liées au voyage
de Lewis et Clark. Concevez votre propre carte pour afficher des
bornes, des noms géographiques, des systèmes de transport, l'eau, la
couverture de terre, le climat, et la géologie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece mapas e ferramentas em linha do mapa. 
Encontre os mapas que são populares com os professores, as 
ferramentas para ensinando a estudantes como ler mapas (e para os 
fazer), os recursos no uso de terra (paisagens em mudança), as 
imagens satellite relacionadas à viagem de Lewis e o Clark. 
Projete seu próprio mapa indicar limites, nomes geográficos, 
sistemas do transporte, água, tampa de terra, clima, e geologia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce i programmi e gli strumenti in linea del 
programma. Trovi i programmi che sono popolari con gli 
insegnanti, gli strumenti per d'istruzione agli allievi come leggere i
programmi (e farli), le risorse su utilizzazione delle terre (paesaggi
cambianti), le immagini satelliti relative al viaggio di Lewis e 
Clark. Progetti il vostro proprio programma per visualizzare i 
contorni, i nomi geografici, i sistemi del trasporto, l'acqua, i tipi 
di terreno, il clima e la geologia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τους σε απευθείας σύνδεση χάρτες και τα 
εργαλεία χαρτών. Βρείτε τους χάρτες που είναι δημοφιλείς 
με τους δασκάλους, τα εργαλεία για τους σπουδαστές πώς να 
διαβάσουν τους χάρτες (και να τους κάνουν), τα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς στη χρήση εδάφους (μεταβαλλόμενα τοπία), τις 
δορυφορικές εικόνες σχετικές με το ταξίδι Lewis και clark. 
Σχεδιάστε το χάρτη σας στα όρια παρουσίασης, τα γεωγραφικά 
ονόματα, τα συστήματα μεταφορών, το ύδωρ, την κάλυψη εδάφους, το
κλίμα, και τη γεωλογία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a correspondencias y a las 
herramientas en línea de la correspondencia. Encuentre las 
correspondencias que son populares entre los profesores, las 
herramientas para enseñando a los estudiantes cómo leer 
correspondencias (y hacerlas), los recursos en la utilización del 
suelo (paisajes que cambian), las imágenes basadas en los satélites 
relacionadas con el viaje de Lewis y Clark. Diseñe su propia 
correspondencia para visualizar límites, nombres geográficos, 
sistemas del transporte, el agua, la cubierta de pista, el clima, y la
geología.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206744</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108787</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geography-u-s-geological-survey</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
