<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105795</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105795</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Murder of Postmaster Baker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Mord am postmaster-Bäcker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le meurtre de Baker de postmaster</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O assassinato do padeiro do postmaster</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'omicidio del panettiere del postmaster</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η δολοφονία του διευθυντή ταχυδρομείου Baker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El asesinato del panadero del postmaster</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the eighteenth to the mid-nineteenth centuries, the term "lynching" did not have any racial implications. Targets included Tories, horse thieves, gamblers, and abolitionists. But starting in the 1880s, mob violence was increasingly directed at African Americans. Between 1882 and 1964, nearly five thousand people died from lynching, the majority African-American. The 1890s witnessed the worst period of lynching in U.S. history. The grim statistical record almost certainly understates the story. Many lynchings were not recorded outside their immediate locality, and pure numbers do not convey the brutality of lynching. Lynchings, which were often witnessed by large crowds of white onlookers, were the most extreme form of Southern white control over the African-American population, regularly meted out against African Americans who had been falsely charged with crimes but in fact were achieving a level of political or economic autonomy that whites found unacceptable. In April 1898, the Cleveland  Gazette , a black newspaper, reported on the lynching of the black postmaster of Lake City, South Carolina, who was burned out of his home and shot by a white mob incensed by his appointment to a federal post. The murder of Postmaster Baker galvanized the anti-lynching movement to seek federal intervention.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von den achtzehnten bis mittler-19.jahrhunderten 
hatte die "lynchende" Bezeichnung keine rassischen Implikationen. 
Ziele enthielten Tories, Pferd Diebe, Spieler und abolitionists.
Aber, beginnend im 1880s, wurde Pöbelgewalttätigkeit in 
zunehmendem Maße an den afrikanischen Amerikanern verwiesen. 
Zwischen 1882 und 1964 starben fast fünf tausend Leute am 
Lynchen, die Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Majorität. Das 1890s 
zeugte die falschste Periode des Lynchens in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Geschichte. Der grimmige statistische Satz understates fast 
zweifellos die Geschichte. Viele lynchings wurden nicht 
außerhalb ihrer sofortigen Stelle gespeichert, und reine Zahlen 
übermitteln nicht die Brutalitäten des Lynchens. Lynchings, 
die häufig von den großen Massen der weißen Zuschauer gezeugt 
wurden, waren das extremste Formular der südlichen weißen Steuerung 
über der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Bevölkerung, regelmäßig 
ausgeteilt heraus gegen afrikanische Amerikaner, die falsch mit 
Verbrechen aufgeladen worden waren, aber tatsächlich erzielten eine 
Stufe der politischen oder ökonomischen Autonomie, daß Weiß nicht 
annehmbar fand. Im April 1898, berichtete die Cleveland Zeitung,
eine schwarze Zeitung, über das Lynchen des schwarzen postmaster der 
See-Stadt, Südcarolina, das ausbrennen von seinem Haus und von Schuß
durch einen weißen Pöbel war, der durch seine Verabredung zu einem 
Bundespfosten verärgert wurde. Der Mord am postmaster-Bäcker 
galvanisierte die Anti-lynchende Bewegung, um Bundesintervention zu 
suchen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des dix-huitième à mi-dix-neuvième siècles, le
terme "lynchant" n'a eu aucune implication raciale. Les cibles 
ont inclus des Conservateurs, des voleurs de cheval, des joueurs, et 
des abolitionnistes. Mais commençant dans le 1880s, la violence 
de foule a été de plus en plus dirigée aux Américains africains. 
Entre 1882 et 1964, presque cinq mille personnes sont mortes de 
lyncher, l'Afro-Américain de majorité. Le 1890s était témoin de
la plus mauvaise période de lyncher dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS. 
L'enregistrement statistique sinistre minimise presque 
certainement l'histoire. Beaucoup de lynchings n'ont pas été 
enregistrés en dehors de leur localité immédiate, et les nombres 
purs ne donnent pas la brutalité de lyncher. Lynchings, qui 
étaient souvent étés témoin par de grandes foules des spectateurs 
blancs, étaient la forme la plus extrême du contrôle blanc 
méridional de la population afro-américaine, régulièrement 
distribuée dehors contre les Américains africains qui avaient été 
faussement chargés des crimes mais en fait réalisaient un niveau 
d'autonomie politique ou économique que les blancs ont trouvé 
inacceptable. En avril 1898, la gazette de Cleveland, un journal
noir, a rendu compte de lyncher du postmaster noir de la ville de lac,
Caroline du sud, qui était grillent de sa maison et projectile 
par une foule blanche exaspérée par sa nomination à un poteau 
fédéral. Le meurtre de Baker de postmaster a galvanisé le 
mouvement anti-lynchant pour rechercher l'intervention fédérale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dos décimos oitavos a mid-décimos nonos 
séculos, o termo "que lynching" não teve nenhumas implicações 
raciais. Os alvos incluíram tories, ladrões do cavalo, 
gamblers, e abolitionists. Mas começando no 1880s, a violência
do mob foi dirigida cada vez mais em americanos africanos. Entre
1882 e 1964, quase cinco mil povos morreram de lynching, maioria 
Africano-Americana. O 1890s testemunhou o período o mais mau de
lynching no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS. O registro estatístico 
grim suaviza quase certamente a história. Muitos lynchings não
foram gravados fora de seu locality imediato, e os números puros não
fazem saber ao brutality de lynching. Lynchings, que foram 
testemunhados frequentemente por multidões grandes dos espectadores 
brancos, era o formulário o mais extremo do controle branco do sul 
sobre a população Africano-Americana, meted regularmente para fora 
de encontro aos americanos africanos que tinham sido carregados falsa 
com os crimes mas no fato conseguia um nível da autonomia política 
ou econômica que os brancos encontraram inaceitável. Em abril 
1898, o gazette de Cleveland, um jornal preto, relatou no lynching do 
postmaster preto da cidade do lago, carolina sul, que foi queimado 
fora de seus HOME e tiro por um mob branco incensed por sua nomeação
a um borne federal. O assassinato do padeiro do postmaster 
galvanized o movimento anti-anti-lynching para procurar a 
intervenção federal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dai diciottesimi - metà di-diciannovesimi secoli,
il termine "che lynching" non ha avuto alcune implicazioni razziali. 
Gli obiettivi hanno incluso i tories, i ladri del cavallo, i 
gamblers ed i abolitionists. Ma cominciando nel 1880s, la 
violenza del mob sempre più è stata diretta agli Americani africani.
Fra 1882 e 1964, quasi cinque mila genti sono morto dal 
lynching, la maggioranza Africano-Americana. Il 1890s ha 
testimoniato il periodo più difettoso di lynching nella storia degli 
STATI UNITI. Il record statistico torvo quasi certamente 
minimizza la storia. Molti lynchings non sono stati registrati 
fuori della loro località immediata ed i numeri puri non trasportano 
il brutality di lynching. Lynchings, che sono stati testimoniati
spesso dalle grandi folle dei onlookers bianchi, era la forma più 
estrema di controllo bianco del sud sopra la popolazione 
Africano-Americana, meted regolarmente fuori contro gli Americani 
africani che erano stati caricati erroneamente dei crimini ma in 
effetti stava realizzando un livello di autonomia politica o economica
che i bianchi hanno trovato inaccettabile. Nel mese di aprile 
del 1898, il gazette de Cleveland, un giornale nero, ha segnalato sul 
lynching del postmaster nero della città del lago, Carolina del Sud, 
che era brucia della suoi sede e colpo da un mob bianco incensed dalla
sua nomina ad un alberino federale. L'omicidio del panettiere 
del postmaster ha galvanizzato il movimento anti-anti-lynching per 
cercare l'intervento federale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το δέκατο όγδοο στους μέσος-δέκατους έννατους 
αιώνες, ο όρος "που λυντσάρει" δεν είχε οποιεσδήποτε φυλετικές 
επιπτώσεις. Οι στόχοι περιέλαβαν tories, τους κλέφτες 
αλόγων, τους παίκτες, και τους ρεφορμιστές. Αλλά αρχικός 
στο 1880s, η βία όχλου κατευθύνθηκε όλο και περισσότερο σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. Μεταξύ 1882 και 1964, σχεδόν
πέντε χιλιάες άνθρωποι πέθαναν από το λυντσάρισμα, η πλειοψηφία
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός. Το 1890s βεβαίωσε τη χειρότερη 
περίοδο λυντσαρίσματος στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉ ιστορία. Το απαίσιο
στατιστικό αρχείο σχεδόν βεβαίως μειώνει την ιστορία. 
Πολλά λυντσαρίσματα δεν καταγράφηκαν έξω από την άμεση 
τοποθεσία τους, και οι καθαροί αριθμοί δεν μεταβιβάζουν τη 
βιαιότητα του λυντσαρίσματος. Τα λυντσαρίσματα, που 
βεβαιώθηκαν συχνά από τα μεγάλα πλήθη των λευκών θεατών, ήταν 
η πιό ακραία μορφή του νότιου άσπρου ελέγχου του 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού πληθυσμού, τακτικά έξω ενάντια σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς που ήταν χρεωμένων ψευδώς με τα 
εγκλήματα αλλά στην πραγματικότητα επετύγχαναν ένα επίπεδο 
πολιτικής ή οικονομικής αυτονομίας ότι λευκά που βρέθηκαν 
απαράδεκτα. Τον Απρίλιο του 1898, η εφημερίδα του 
Κλήβελαντ, μια μαύρη εφημερίδα, που αναφέρθηκε στο λυντσάρισμα 
του μαύρου διευθυντή ταχυδρομείου της πόλης λιμνών, νότια 
Καρολίνα, που καηκε από το σπίτι και το πλάνο του από έναν 
λευκό όχλο από το διορισμό του σε μια ομοσπονδιακή θέση. Η
δολοφονία του διευθυντή ταχυδρομείου Baker γαλβάνισε τη 
μετακίνηση αντι-λυντσαρίσματος για να επιδιώξει την ομοσπονδιακή 
επέμβαση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A partir de los décimo octavos a mediados 
de-diecinueveavo siglos, el término "lynching" no tenía ninguna 
implicaciones racial. Las blancos incluyeron tories, ladrones 
del caballo, jugadores, y abolitionists. Pero comenzando en el 
1880s, la violencia de la multitud fue dirigida cada vez más en los 
americanos africanos. Entre 1882 y 1964, casi cinco mil personas
murieron de lynching, la mayoría Africano-Americana. El 1890s 
atestiguó el período peor de lynching en la historia de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. El expediente estadístico severo minimisa casi 
ciertamente la historia. Muchos lynchings no fueron registrados 
fuera de su lugar inmediato, y los números puros no transportan la 
brutalidad de lynching. Lynchings, que fueron atestiguados a 
menudo por las muchedumbres grandes de los onlookers blancos, era la 
forma más extrema de control blanco meridional sobre la población 
Africano-Americana, meted regularmente hacia fuera contra los 
americanos africanos que habían sido cargados falso con los crímenes
pero en hecho alcanzaba un nivel de la autonomía política o 
económica que los blancos encontraron inaceptable. En abril de 
1898, la gaceta de Cleveland, un periódico negro, señaló sobre 
lynching del postmaster negro de la ciudad del lago, Carolina del Sur,
que era quema de su hogar y tiro de una multitud blanca incensed por 
su cita a un poste federal. El asesinato del panadero del 
postmaster galvanizó el movimiento contra-anti-lynching para buscar 
la intervención federal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105795</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-murder-of-postmaster-baker</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
