<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104836</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104836</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086229</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Hearty Big Strong Men All Died": The Lasting Impact of the Silicosis "Plague" in the 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Herzliche Grosse Starke Männer Ganz Gestorben": 
Die dauerhafte Auswirkung der Silikose "Pest" in den dreißiger 
Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Grands Hommes Forts Chaleureux Tout Morts" : 
L'impact durable de la silicose "peste" dans les années 30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Homens Fortes Grandes Hearty Morridos Toda": 
O impacto durável do silicosis "praga" nos 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Uomini Forti Grandi Calorosi Interamente Morti": 
L'effetto durevole della silicosi "peste" nei 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα "εγκάρδια μεγάλα ισχυρά άτομα όλα πέθαναν": 
Ο μόνιμος αντίκτυπος της πυριτίασης "πανούκλα" στη δεκαετία
του '30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Hombres Fuertes Grandes Calurosos Muertos Todo": 
El impacto duradero de la silicosis "plaga" en los años 30</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Silicosis, a deadly lung disease caused when workers inhale fine particles of silica dust (found in sand, quartz, and granite), became a national cause clbre during the Great Depression when it was recognized as a significant disease among lead, zinc, and silver miners, sandblasters, and foundry and tunnel workers. While silicosis was a crisis for the federal government, business, and insurance companies as well as labor organizations, its most devastating effects were on the workers who contracted the disease and the families and communities who watched previously healthy men waste away and die. The lasting impact that the silicosis "plague" had on individual workers' lives in the 1930s is evident here in Laurie Mercier's 1981 interview with Helen Raymond, who opened a tavern that catered to miners in Virginia City, Montana, in 1934.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Silikose, eine tödliche Lungenkrankheit, die 
verursacht wurde, wenn Arbeiter Feinpartikel des Silikonstaubes 
(gefunden im Sand, Quarz und Granit) inhalieren, wurde ein nationales 
Ursache clbre während des großen Tiefstands, als es als bedeutende 
Krankheit unter Leitung, Zink- und Silberergmänner, Sandstrahler und 
Gießerei- und Tunnelarbeiter erkannt wurde. Während Silikose 
eine Krise für die Bundesregierung, das Geschäft und die 
Versicherungsgesellschaften sowie Gewerkschaften war, waren seine 
verheerendsten Effekte auf den Arbeitern, die Vertrag Krankheit und 
die Familien und die Gemeinschaften abschlossen, die vorher gesunde 
Männer weg, zu vergeuden überwachten und zu sterben. Die 
dauerhafte Auswirkung, die die Silikose "Pest" auf den Leben der 
einzelnen Arbeiter in den dreißiger Jahren hatte, ist hier Laurie 
Merciers 1981 im Interview mit Helen Raymond, das einen Tavern 
öffnete, der Bergmännern in der Virginia Stadt bot, Montana, 1934 
offensichtlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La silicose, une affection pulmonaire mortelle 
causée quand les ouvriers inhalent les particules fines de la 
poussière de silice (trouvée en sable, quartz, et granit), est 
devenue un clbre national de cause pendant la grande dépression quand
on l'a identifié comme maladie significative parmi le fil de sortie, 
le zinc, et les mineurs argentés, les sableuses, et les ouvriers de 
fonderie et de tunnel. Tandis que la silicose était une crise 
pour le gouvernement fédéral, les affaires, et les compagnies 
d'assurance aussi bien que des organismes de travail, ses effets plus 
dévastateurs étaient sur les ouvriers qui ont contracté la maladie 
et les familles et les communautés qui ont observé les hommes 
précédemment en bonne santé gaspiller loin et mourir. 
L'impact durable que la silicose "peste" a eu les vies des 
différents ouvriers dans les années 30 est évident ici dans 
l'entrevue de Laurie Mercier 1981 avec Helen Raymond, qui a ouvert une
taverne qui a approvisionné aux mineurs dans la ville de la Virginie,
le Montana, en 1934.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O silicosis, uma doença de pulmão mortal causada
quando os trabalhadores inhale partículas finas da poeira de silicone
(encontrada na areia, o quartzo, e o granito), transformou-se um clbre
nacional da causa durante o depression grande quando se reconheceu 
como uma doença significativa entre a ligação, o zinco, e os 
mineiros de prata, os sandblasters, e os trabalhadores do foundry e do
túnel. Quando o silicosis era uma crise para o governo federal,
o negócio, e as companhias de seguro as.well.as organizações labor,
seus efeitos mais devastating estavam nos trabalhadores que 
contraíram a doença e as famílias e as comunidades que prestaram 
atenção a homens previamente saudáveis desperdiçar afastado e 
morrer. O impacto durável que o silicosis "praga" teve em vidas
dos trabalhadores individuais nos 1930s é evidente aqui na entrevista
de Laurie Mercier 1981 com Helen Raymond, que abriu um tavern que 
catered aos mineiros na cidade de Virgínia, Montana, em 1934.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La silicosi, un'affezione polmonare mortale 
causata quando gli operai inalano le particelle fini della polvere di 
silicone (trovata in sabbia, quarzo e granito), si è transformata in 
in un clbre nazionale di causa durante la depressione grande quando è
stato riconosciuto come malattia significativa fra cavo, zinco e 
minatori d'argento, sabbiatori ed operai del traforo e della fonderia.
Mentre la silicosi era una crisi per il governo federale, il 
commercio e le società di assicurazioni così come le organizzazioni 
di lavoro, i relativi effetti più devastating erano sugli operai che
hanno contratto la malattia e le famiglie e le Comunità che hanno 
guardato gli uomini precedentemente in buona salute sprecare via e 
morire. L'effetto durevole che la silicosi "peste" ha avuta 
sulle vite dei diversi operai nei 1930s è evidente qui 
nell'intervista di Laurie Mercier 1981 con Helen Raymond, che ha 
aperto una locanda che ha approvvigionato ai minatori nella città 
della Virginia, il Montana, in 1934.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πυριτίαση, μια θανάσιμη ασθένεια πνευμόνων 
προκάλεσε πότε οι εργαζόμενοι εισπνέουν τα λεπτά μόρια της 
σκόνης πυριτίου (που βρίσκεται στην άμμο, το χαλαζία, και το 
γρανίτη), έγινε μια εθνική αιτία clbre κατά τη διάρκεια της 
μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης όταν αναγνωρίστηκε ως σημαντική 
ασθένεια μεταξύ του μολύβδου, του ψευδάργυρου, και των ασημένιων 
ανθρακωρύχων, sandblasters, και των εργαζομένων χυτηρίων και 
σηράγγων. Ενώ η πυριτίαση ήταν μια κρίση για την 
ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση, η επιχείρηση, και οι ασφαλιστικές 
εταιρείες καθώς επίσης και οι οργανώσεις εργασίας, τα πιό 
καταστρεπτικά αποτελέσματά της ήταν στους εργαζομένους που 
συμβλήθηκαν την ασθένεια και τις οικογένειες και τις κοινότητες 
που πρόσεξαν τα προηγουμένως υγιή απόβλητα ατόμων μακριά και τον
κύβο. Μόνιμη επίδραση που η "πανούκλα" της πυριτίασης 
άσκησε στους μεμονωμένους εργαζομένους "ζει στη δεκαετία του '30 
είναι εμφανής εδώ στη συνέντευξη του 1981 Laurie Mercier 
με τη Helen Raymond, η οποία άνοιξε μια ταβέρνα που 
τροφοδότησε στους ανθρακωρύχους στην πόλη της Βιρτζίνια, Μοντάνα,
το 1934.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La silicosis, una enfermedad de la pulmón mortal 
causada cuando los trabajadores inhalan partículas finas del polvo de
silicona (encontrado en arena, cuarzo, y granito), se convirtió en un
clbre nacional de la causa durante la gran depresión cuando fue 
reconocido como enfermedad significativa entre el terminal de 
componente, cinc, y los mineros de plata, los sandblasters, y los 
trabajadores de la fundición y del túnel. Mientras que la 
silicosis era una crisis para el gobierno federal, el negocio, y las 
compañías de seguros así como organizaciones de trabajo, sus 
efectos más devastadores estaban en los trabajadores que contrajeron 
la enfermedad y las familias y las comunidades que miraron a hombres 
previamente sanos perder lejos y morir. El impacto duradero que 
la silicosis "plaga" tenía el las vidas de los trabajadores 
individuales en los años 30 es evidente aquí en la entrevista de 
Laurie Mercier 1981 con Helen Raymond, que abrió una taberna que 
abasteció a los mineros en la ciudad de Virginia, Montana, en 1934.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086229</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104836</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hearty-big-strong-men-all-died-the-lasting-impact-of-the-silicosis-plague-in-the-1930s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
