<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103745</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103745</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206563</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Creating Hypertext Dialogues Drawn from Narrative History Collections</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Hypertext-Dialoge erstellen gezeichnet von den
erzählenden Geschichte Ansammlungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Créant des dialogues d'hypertexte tirés des 
collections narratives d'histoire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Criando os diálogos do hypertext desenhados das 
coleções narrativas do history</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Creando i dialoghi di hypertext dissipati dalle 
collezioni narrative di storia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημιουργώντας τα διαλογικά παράθυρα υπερκειμένων που 
προέρχονται από τις αφηγηματικές συλλογές ιστορίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Creando los diálogos del hypertext trazados de 
colecciones narrativas de la historia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">invites students to use documents from California As I Saw It: First Person Narratives, 1849-1900, to create hyperscripts depicting the motivations, expectations, fears, and realizations of immigrants who settled California between 1849 and 1900. Students' hyperscripts are online written dialogues that include links to illustrative written materials, images, and sound files from American Memory collections.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">lädt Kursteilnehmer ein, Dokumente von 
Kalifornien zu benutzen, wie ich es sah: Erste 
Person-Darstellungen, 1849-1900, die hyperscripts, welche die 
Beweggründe bildlich darstellen, die Erwartungen, Furcht und 
Realisierungen der Immigranten erstellen, die Kalifornien zwischen 
1849 und 1900 vereinbarten. Hyperscripts der Kursteilnehmer sind
schriftliche Onlinedialoge, die Links zu den illustrativen 
schriftlichen Materialien, zu den Bildern und zu den stichhaltigen 
Dateien von den amerikanischen Speicheransammlungen einschließen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">invite des étudiants à utiliser des documents de
la Californie comme je l'ai vue : Premiers récits de personne, 
1849-1900, pour créer des hyperscripts dépeignant les motivations, 
des espérances, des craintes, et des réalisations des immigrés qui 
ont arrangé la Californie entre 1849 et 1900. Les hyperscripts 
des étudiants sont des dialogues écrits en ligne qui incluent des 
liens aux matériaux écrits d'illustration, aux images, et aux 
fichiers sains des collections américaines de mémoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">convida estudantes usar originais de Califórnia 
como eu a vi: Primeiras narrativas da pessoa, 1849-1900, para 
criar os hyperscripts que descrevem os motivations, as expectativas, 
os medos, e os realizations dos immigrants que estabeleciram 
Califórnia entre 1849 e 1900. Os hyperscripts dos estudantes 
são os diálogos escritos em linha que incluem as ligações aos 
materiais escritos ilustrativos, às imagens, e às limas sadias das 
coleções americanas da memória.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">invita gli allievi ad usare i documenti dalla 
California come la ho vista: Prime descrizioni della persona, 
1849-1900, creare i hyperscripts che descrivono le motivazioni, le 
aspettative, i timori e le realizzazioni degli immigranti che hanno 
depositato la California fra 1849 e 1900. I hyperscripts degli 
allievi sono dialoghi scritti in linea che includono i collegamenti ai
materiali scritti illustrativi, alle immagini ed agli archivi sani 
dalle collezioni americane di memoria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσκαλεί τους σπουδαστές για να χρησιμοποιήσει τα 
έγγραφα από Καλιφόρνια δεδομένου ότι Την εβλέίδα: 
Τα πρώτοι αφηγήματα, το 1849-1900, για να δημιουργήσουν 
hyperscripts την απεικόνιση των κινήτρων, οι προσδοκίες, οι 
φόβοι, και οι πραγματοποιήσεις προσώπων των μεταναστών που 
εγκατέστησαν Καλιφόρνια μεταξύ 1849 και 1900, σπουδαστών 
hyperscripts γράφονται on-line τα διαλογικά παράθυρα που 
περιλαμβάνουν τις συνδέσεις με τα επεξηγηματικά γραπτά υλικά, τις
εικόνες, και τα υγιή αρχεία από τις αμερικανικές συλλογές 
μνήμης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">invita a estudiantes que utilicen documentos de 
California como la vi: Primeras narrativas de la persona, 
1849-1900, crear los hyperscripts que representan las motivaciones, 
las expectativas, los miedos, y las realizaciones de los inmigrantes 
que colocaron California entre 1849 y 1900. Los hyperscripts de 
los estudiantes son los diálogos escritos en línea que incluyen 
conexiones a los materiales, a las imágenes, y a los ficheros 
escritos ilustrativos de los sonidos de colecciones americanas de la 
memoria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206563</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103745</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/creating-hypertext-dialogues-drawn-from-narrative-history-collections</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
