<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106164</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106164</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087191</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Feel as Though Our Country Spurned Us": Soldier James Henry Gooding Protests Unequal Pay for Black Soldiers, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir glauben, als wenn unser Land uns" 
verschmähte: Soldat James Henry Gooding protestiert ungleiche 
Bezahlung für schwarze Soldaten, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous nous sentons comme si notre pays nous a 
jetés" : Henry Gooding de James de soldat proteste le 
salaire inégal pour les soldats noirs, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós sentimos como se nosso país spurned nos": 
O Henry Gooding de James do soldado protesta o pagamento 
desigual para soldados pretos, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"riteniamo come se il nostro paese spurned noi": 
Il henry Gooding di James del soldato protesta la paga disuguale
per i soldati neri, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αισθανόμαστε σαν η χώρα μας μας απέρριψε": Ο 
στρατιώτης james Henry Gooding Protests Unequal 
πληρώνει για τους μαύρους στρατιώτες, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"nos sentimos como si nuestro país nos 
despreció": El Henrio Gooding de James del soldado protesta la 
paga desigual para los soldados negros, 1863</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In January, 1863--the month of Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation and the second year of the Civil War--the United States began allowing black soldiers to enlist in the Union army. The army needed more manpower or, as African-American soldier James Henry Gooding put it with bitter eloquence, "more food for its ravenous maw." By 1865 approximately one tenth of all Union soldiers and sailors were African-American, and about eighty percent of these came from the slave states. Black soldiers fought with notable valor. When captured they faced much greater brutality from Confederate soldiers than did their white comrades. Union service, however, was no guarantee of equal treatment. Black soldiers in the Union army served in segregated troops, often faced menial assignments, and received lower pay--$10 per month to white soldiers' $13. In this letter to President Lincoln, Gooding, writing on behalf of himself and his fellow black soldiers, protested these conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Januar 1863 -- der Monat der 
Emanzipation-Proklamation Lincolns und das zweite Jahr des 
Bürgerkrieges -- die Vereinigten Staaten fingen an, schwarzen 
Soldaten zu erlauben, in der Anschlußarmee einzutragen. Die 
Armee benötigte mehr menschliche Arbeitskraft oder, während 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischer Soldat James Henry Gooding sie mit bitterer
Beredsamkeit setzte, "mehr Nahrung für seinen ravenous Schlund." 
Durch waren 1865 ungefähr ein zehntes aller Anschlußsoldaten 
und -seeleute Afrikanisch-Amerikanisch, und ungefähr achtzig Prozent 
von diesen kamen von den Sklavenzuständen. Schwarze Soldaten 
kämpften mit bemerkenswertem valor. Als erfaßt sie viel 
grössere Brutalitäten von den verbündeten Soldaten als 
gegenüberstellten, ihre weißen Kameraden. Anschlußservice war
jedoch keine Garantie der gleichen Behandlung. Schwarze Soldaten
in der Anschlußarmee dienten in getrennten Truppen, in häufig 
gegenübergestellten menial Anweisungen und in empfangener niedrigerer
Bezahlung -- $10 pro Monat zu weißen Soldaten $13. In diesem 
Zeichen zum Präsidenten Lincoln, protestierte Gooding, schreibend im 
Namen und seiner Mitschwarzsoldaten, diese Bedingungen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En janvier, 1863 -- le mois de la proclamation de 
l'émancipation de Lincoln et la deuxième année de la guerre civile 
-- les Etats-Unis ont commencé à permettre aux soldats noirs de 
enrôler dans l'armée des syndicats. L'armée a eu besoin de 
plus de main d'oeuvre ou, pendant qu'Henry afro-américain Gooding de 
James de soldat la mettait avec l'éloquence amère, "plus de 
nourriture pour sa gueule vorace." D'ici 1865 
approximativement un dixièmes de tous les soldats et marins des 
syndicats étaient afro-américain, et environ quatre-vingts pour cent de
ces derniers sont venus des états slaves. Les soldats 
noirs ont combattu avec le valor notable. Une fois capturés ils
ont fait face à une brutalité beaucoup plus grande des soldats 
confédérés que  leurs camarades blancs. Le service des 
syndicats, cependant, n'était aucune garantie d'égalité de 
traitement. Les soldats noirs dans l'armée des syndicats ont 
servi dans les troupes isolées, les affectations serviles 
souvent faites face, et le salaire inférieur reçu -- $10 par mois 
aux soldats blancs $13. Dans cette lettre au Président Lincoln,
Gooding, écrivant au nom de se et de ses soldats de noir de camarade,
a protesté ces conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em janeiro, 1863 -- o mês do proclamation do 
emancipation de Lincoln e o segundo ano da guerra civil -- os estados 
unidos começaram a permitir que os soldados pretos alistem-se no 
exército de união. O exército necessitou mais manpower ou, 
enquanto o Henry Africano-Americano Gooding de James do soldado o pôs
com eloquence amargo, "mais alimento para seu maw ravenous." Por
1865 aproximadamente um décimo de todos os soldados e sailors da 
união eram Africano-Americano, e aproximadamente eighty por cento 
destes vieram dos estados slave. Os soldados pretos lutaram com 
valor notável. Quando capturados enfrentaram um brutality muito
mais grande dos soldados confederate do que  seus camaradas brancos. 
O serviço da união, entretanto, não era nenhuma garantia do 
tratamento igual. Os soldados pretos no exército de união 
serviram em tropas segregadas, em atribuições menial frequentemente 
enfrentadas, e no pagamento mais baixo recebido -- $10 por o mês aos 
soldados brancos $13. Nesta letra ao presidente Lincoln, 
Gooding, escrevendo em nome dhimself e de seus soldados do preto do 
companheiro, protestou estas circunstâncias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In gennaio, del 1863 -- il mese della 
proclamazione di emancipazione de Lincoln ed il secondo anno della 
guerra civile -- unito Dichiara ha cominciato a permettere che 
i soldati neri arruolino nell'esercito del sindacato. L'esercito
ha avuto bisogno di più forza di lavoro o, mentre il henry 
Africano-Americano Gooding di James del soldato la ha messa con il 
eloquence amaro, "più alimento per il relativo maw ravenous." 
Da 1865 circa un decimo di tutti i soldati e marinai del 
sindacato era Africano-Americano e circa ottanta per cento di questi 
sono venuto dallo schiavo dichiarano. I soldati neri hanno 
combattuto con il valor notevole. Una volta bloccati hanno 
affrontato il brutality molto più grande dai soldati confederati dei 
loro camerati bianchi. Il servizio del sindacato, tuttavia, era 
garanzia della parità di trattamento. I soldati neri 
nell'esercito del sindacato hanno servito in truppe segregate, nelle 
assegnazioni menial spesso affrontate e nella paga più bassa ricevuta
-- $10 al mese ai soldati bianchi $13. In questa lettera al 
presidente Lincoln, Gooding, scrivendo a nome sè e dei suoi soldati 
di nero del collega, ha protestato queste circostanze.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Ιανουάριο, 1863 -- ο μήνας της προκήρυξης 
Χειραφέτησης του Λίνκολν και το δεύτερο έτος του εμφύλιου 
πολέμου -- οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες άρχισαν στους μαύρους 
στρατιώτες στρατολογώ στο στρατό ένωσης. Ο στρατός 
χρειάστηκε περισσότερο εργατικό δυναμικό ή, καθώς ο 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικός στρατιώτης james Henry Gooding το
έβαλε με την πικρή ευγλωττία, "περισσότερα τρόφιμα για το 
αρπακτικό στομάχι του." Από 1865 περίπου ένα δέκατο 
όλων των στρατιωτών ένωσης και οι ναυτικοί ήταν 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά, και περίπου ογδόντα τοις εκατό αυτά 
προήλθαν από τα κράτη σκλάβων. Οι μαύροι στρατιώτες 
πάλεψαν με το ξεχωριστό valor. Όταν συλλαμβάνονται 
αντιμετώπισαν την πολύ μεγαλύτερη βιαιότητα από τους ομόσπονδους
στρατιώτες από οι λευκοί σύντροφοί τους. Η υπηρεσία 
ένωσης, εντούτοις, δεν ήταν καμία εγγύηση της ίσης 
μεταχείρισης. Οι μαύροι στρατιώτες στο στρατό ένωσης που 
εξυπηρετήθηκε στα διαχωρισμένα στρατεύματα, αντιμετώπισαν συχνά 
τις menial αναθέσεις, και λαμβανόμενος χαμηλότερος πληρώνει -- 
$10 το μήνα των λευκών στρατιωτών $13. Σε αυτήν την 
επιστολή στον Πρόεδρο Lincoln, Gooding, γράφοντας εξ 
ονόματος του και των συντροφικών μαύρων στρατιωτών του, 
διαμαρτυρήθηκε αυτούς τους όρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En enero de 1863 -- el mes de la proclamación de 
la emancipación de Lincoln y el segundo año de la guerra civil -- 
los Estados Unidos comenzaron a permitir que los soldados negros 
alisten en el ejército de unión. El ejército necesitó más 
mano de obra o, mientras que el Henrio Africano-Americano Gooding de 
James del soldado la puso con elocuencia amarga, "más alimento para 
su maw ravenous." Antes de 1865 aproximadamente un décimo de 
todos los soldados y marineros de la unión era Africano-Americano, y 
cerca de ochenta por ciento de éstos vinieron de los estados 
auxiliares. Los soldados negros lucharon con valor notable. 
Cuando estaban capturados hicieron frente a brutalidad mucho 
mayor de soldados confederados que sus camaradas blancos. El 
servicio de la unión, sin embargo, no era ninguna garantía de la 
igualdad de tratamiento. Los soldados negros en el ejército de 
unión desempen'aron servicios en tropas segregadas, asignaciones 
menial a menudo hechas frente, y la paga más baja recibida -- $10 por
mes a los soldados blancos $13. En esta carta a presidente 
Lincoln, Gooding, escribiendo a nombre de se y de sus soldados del 
negro del compañero, protestó estas condiciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087191</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106164</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-feel-as-though-our-country-spurned-us-soldier-james-henry-gooding-protests-unequal-pay-for-black-soldiers-1863</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
