<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104844</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104844</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209819</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Congruent Angles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Übereinstimmende Winkel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Angles Conformes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ângulos Congruent</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Angoli Conformi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύμφωνες γωνίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ángulos Congruentes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of congruent angles. Three angles are shown which always remain congruent as you drag any defining point on any angle. They all change together. This is designed to demonstrate that the angles are considered congruent even if they are in different orientations and the line segments making them up are different lengths. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept der übereinstimmenden Winkel zeigen. 
Drei Winkel werden gezeigt, welche immer übereinstimmend 
bleiben, während Sie irgendeinen definierenden Punkt auf jedem 
möglichem Winkel schleppen. Alle sie ändern zusammen. 
Dieses ist konzipiert, um zu zeigen, daß der Winkel als 
übereinstimmend gelten, selbst wenn sie in den unterschiedlichen 
Lagebestimmungen sind und die Striche, die sie bilden oben, 
unterschiedliche Längen sind. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang
für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept des angles conformes. Trois angles 
sont montrés ce qui restent toujours conformes pendant que vous 
traînez n'importe quel point définissant sur n'importe quel angle. 
Ils tous changent ensemble. Ceci est conçu pour 
démontrer que les angles sont considérés conformes même si ils 
sont dans différentes orientations et la ligne segments les faisant 
sont en hausse différentes longueurs. L'applet peut être 
agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur 
de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de 
classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito de ângulos congruent. Três ângulos 
estão mostrados quais remanescem sempre congruent enquanto você 
arrasta algum ponto definindo em todo o ângulo. Todos mudam 
junto. Isto é projetado demonstrar que os ângulos estão 
considerados congruent mesmo se estão em orientações diferentes e a
linha segmentos que fazem as está acima a uns comprimentos 
diferentes. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia 
para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na 
sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web 
browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão 
requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo 
do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto degli angoli conformi. Tre angoli sono 
indicati quale rimangono sempre conformi mentre trascinate qualsiasi 
punto di definizione su tutto l'angolo. Tutti cambiano insieme. 
Ciò è destinata per dimostrare che gli angoli sono considerati
conformi anche se sono negli orientamenti differenti e la riga 
segmenti che li fanno in su è lunghezze differenti. Il applet 
può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un 
proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo 
può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella 
libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è 
un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια των σύμφωνων γωνιών. Τρεις γωνίες 
εμφανίζονται όποιοι παραμένουν πάντα σύμφωνοι δεδομένου ότι 
σέρνετε οποιοδήποτε σημείο καθορισμού σε οποιαδήποτε γωνία. 
Όλοι αλλάζουν από κοινού. Αυτό έχει ως σκοπό να 
καταδείξει ότι οι γωνίες θεωρούνται σύμφωνος ακόμα κι αν είναι 
στους διαφορετικούς προσανατολισμούς και τα τμήματα μνήμης 
γραμμών που κάνουν τις είναι επάνω διαφορετικά μήκη. Το 
Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη 
χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην 
τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από 
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto de ángulos congruentes. Se muestran tres
ángulos cuáles siguen siendo siempre congruentes mientras que usted 
arrastra cualquier punta que define en cualquier ángulo. Todos 
cambian juntos. Esto se diseña para demostrar que los ángulos 
están considerados congruentes incluso si están en diversas 
orientaciones y la línea segmentos que las hacen para arriba es 
diversas longitudes. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de 
la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase.
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209819</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104844</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/congruent-angles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
