<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107388</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107388</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204022</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mississippi River Basin and Gulf of Mexico Hypoxia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mississippi Fluss-Bassin und Golf von Mexiko 
Hypoxie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bassin de fleuve du Mississippi et Golfe de 
l'hypoxie de Mexique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bacia do rio de Mississippi e golfo do hypoxia de 
México</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bacino del fiume del Mississippi e golfo di ipossia
di Messico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λεκάνη ποταμών του Μισισιπή και κόλπος hypoxia του 
Μεξικού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lavabo del río de Mississippi y golfo del hypoxia 
de México</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This EPA site provides links to introductory information about the Gulf of Mexico dead zone. It offers answers to questions such as: what is the hypoxic zone, how did it form, what strategies are being implemented to remedy it, and what is the government doing. It also features links to various regions within the Mississippi River Basin, allowing users to explore issues in their own area.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese EPA Site stellt Links zu den einleitenden 
Informationen über den Golf Mexiko der toten Zone zur Verfügung. 
Sie bietet Antworten Fragen wie an: was die hypoxic Zone 
ist, wie es sich bildeten, welche Strategien eingeführt werden, um es
zu beheben und was das Regierung Tun ist. Es kennzeichnet auch 
Links zu den verschiedenen Regionen innerhalb des Mississippi 
Fluss-Bassins und erlaubt Benutzern, Ausgaben in ihrem eigenen Bereich
zu erforschen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site d'EPA fournit des liens aux informations 
préliminaires sur le Golfe de la zone morte de Mexique. Il 
offre des réponses aux questions comme : ce qui est la zone 
hypoxique, comment il ont formé, des quels stratégies sont mises en 
application pour remédier à de lui, et ce qui est faire de 
gouvernement. Il comporte également des liens à de diverses 
régions dans le bassin de fleuve du Mississippi, permettant à des 
utilisateurs d'explorer des issues dans leur propre zone.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local de EPA fornece as ligações à 
informação introdutória sobre o golfo da zona inoperante de 
México. Oferece respostas às perguntas como: o que são 
a zona hypoxic, como ele deram forma, os que estratégias estão sendo
executadas para o remediar, e o que é fazer do governo. 
Caracteriza também as ligações às várias regiões dentro da
bacia do rio de Mississippi, permitindo que os usuários explorem 
edições em sua própria área.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo di EPA fornisce i collegamenti alle 
informazioni introduttive sul golfo della zona guasto di Messico. 
Offre le risposte alle domande come: che cosa è la zona 
hypoxic, come esso hanno formato, i che strategie stanno effettuande 
per rimediarle e che cosa è fare di governo. Egualmente 
caratterizza i collegamenti alle varie regioni all'interno del bacino 
del fiume del Mississippi, permettendo che gli utenti esaminare le 
edizioni nella loro propria zona.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή EPA παρέχει τις συνδέσεις με τις 
εισαγωγικές πληροφορίες για τον κόλπο της νεκρής ζώνης του 
Μεξικού. Προσφέρει τις απαντήσεις στις ερωτήσεις όπως: 
αυτό που είναι η hypoxic ζώνη, πώς διαμόρφωσε, ποιες 
στρατηγικές εφαρμόζονται για να το θεραπεύσουν, και ποιο είναι 
κυβερνητικό να κάνει. Χαρακτηρίζει επίσης τις συνδέσεις με 
τις διάφορες περιοχές μέσα στη λεκάνη ποταμών του Μισισιπή, που 
επιτρέπουν στους χρήστες για να ερευνήσει τα ζητήματα στην 
περιοχή τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio de EPA proporciona a conexiones a la 
información introductoria sobre el golfo de la zona muerta de 
México. Ofrece respuestas a las preguntas por ejemplo: 
cuál es la zona hypoxic, cómo él formaron, qué estrategias 
se están poniendo en ejecucio'n para remediarlo, y cuál es el hacer 
del gobierno. También ofrece conexiones a las varias regiones 
dentro del lavabo del río de Mississippi, permitiendo que los 
utilizadores exploren ediciones en su propia área.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY
FN:ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204022</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107388</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mississippi-river-basin-and-gulf-of-mexico-hypoxia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
