<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106593</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106593</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202533</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Creating Community in the Classroom: Part 4 (Rewarding Improvement)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erstellen der Gemeinschaft im Klassenzimmer: 
Teil 4 (Lohnende Verbesserung)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Créer la Communauté dans la salle de classe : 
Partie 4 (Amélioration Enrichissante)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Criando a comunidade na sala de aula: Parte 
4 (Melhoria Recompensando)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Creazione della Comunità nell'aula: Parte 4
(Miglioramento Ricompensante)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημιουργία της Κοινότητας στην τάξη: Μέρος 4 
(ανταμείβοντας βελτίωση)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Crear a comunidad en la sala de clase: Parte
4 (Mejora De Recompensa)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The fourth lesson in a series on improving classroom learning climate, this lesson provides an opportunity to evaluate student progress and to provide positive reinforcement for improvements in behavior. Using a one to ten continuum, students will subjectively evaluate class progress on the ten adjectives listed as class climate goals. After this process, students will publicly recognize those classmates who have helped the class improve or who have personally improved.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die vierte Lektion in einer Serie auf dem 
Verbessern des erlernenklimas des Klassenzimmers, diese Lektion 
liefert eine Gelegenheit, Kursteilnehmerfortschritt auszuwerten und 
positive Verstärkung für Verbesserungen im Verhalten zur Verfügung 
zu stellen. Mit dem bis 10 Kontinuum, werten Kursteilnehmer 
subjektiv Kategorie Fortschritt auf den 10 Adjektiven aus, die als 
Kategorie Klimaziele ausgedruckt werden. Nach diesem Prozeß 
erkennen Kursteilnehmer öffentlich jene Mitschüler, die der 
Kategorie geholfen haben zu verbessern, oder die persönlich 
verbessert haben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La quatrième leçon d'une série sur améliorer 
le climat d'étude de salle de classe, cette leçon fournit une 
occasion d'évaluer le progrès d'étudiant et de fournir le renfort 
positif pour des améliorations du comportement. En utilisant 
celui à dix continuum, les étudiants évalueront subjectivement le 
progrès de classe sur les dix adjectifs énumérés en tant que buts 
de climat de classe. Après ce processus, les étudiants 
identifieront publiquement ces camarades de classe qui ont aidé la 
classe pour s'améliorer ou qui se sont personnellement améliorés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A quarta lição em uma série em melhorar o clima
de aprendizagem da sala de aula, esta lição fornece uma oportunidade
de avaliar o progresso do estudante e de fornecer o reforço positivo 
para melhorias no comportamento. Usando esse a dez continuum, os
estudantes avaliarão subjetiva o progresso da classe nos dez 
adjetivos alistados como objetivos do clima da classe. Após 
este processo, os estudantes reconhecerão publicamente aqueles 
classmates que ajudaram à classe melhorar ou que melhoraram 
pessoalmente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La lezione di quarto in serie sul migliorare 
il clima imparante dell'aula, questa lezione fornisce un'occasione 
valutare il progresso dell'allievo e fornire il rinforzo positivo per 
i miglioramenti nel comportamento. Usando quello a dieci 
continuità, gli allievi valuteranno soggettivamente il progresso del 
codice categoria sui dieci aggettivi elencati come obiettivi di clima 
del codice categoria. Dopo questo processo, gli allievi 
riconosceranno pubblicamente quei classmates che hanno aiutato il 
codice categoria per migliorare o che hanno migliorato personalmente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το τέταρτο μάθημα σε μια σειρά στη βελτίωση του 
κλίματος εκμάθησης τάξεων, αυτό το μάθημα παρέχει μια ευκαιρία 
να αξιολογηθεί η πρόοδος σπουδαστών και να παρασχεθεί η θετική 
ενίσχυση για τις βελτιώσεις στη συμπεριφορά. Χρησιμοποιώντας
μια συνέχεια ένα έως δέκα, οι σπουδαστές θα αξιολογήσουν 
υποκειμενικά την πρόοδο κλάσης στα δέκα επίθετα που εμφανίζονται
λίστα ως στόχοι κλίματος κλάσης. Μετά από αυτήν την 
διαδικασία, οι σπουδαστές θα αναγνωρίσουν δημόσια εκείνους τους 
συμμαθητές που έχουν βοηθήσει την κλάση να βελτιωθεί ή που 
έχουν βελτιωθεί προσωπικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La cuarta lección en una serie en mejorar clima 
que aprende de la sala de clase, esta lección proporciona a una 
oportunidad de evaluar progreso del estudiante y de proporcionar al 
refuerzo positivo para las mejoras en comportamiento. Usando el 
que esta' a diez serie continua, los estudiantes evaluarán subjetivo 
progreso de la clase en los diez adjetivos enumerados como metas del 
clima de la clase. Después de este proceso, los estudiantes 
reconocerán público a esos classmates que han ayudado a la clase 
para mejorar o que han mejorado personalmente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAT NYSTROM
FN:PAT NYSTROM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202533</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106593</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/creating-community-in-the-classroom-part-4-rewarding-improvement</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
