<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107244</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107244</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204317</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">How Ironic!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wie Ironisch!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comment Ironique !</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como Ironic!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quanto Ironico!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πόσο ειρωνικός!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Cómo Es Irónico!</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson will introduce students to the concept of irony. Verbal, situational, and dramatic irony will be defined, but the focus of the lesson is situational irony. This lesson can be used prior to teaching longer, more complex short stories that contain situational irony. This lesson is modified for an English Language Learner (ELL) who reads at the Intermediate Low (IL) level.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion stellt Kursteilnehmer zum Konzept von Ironie
vor. Mündlich, und drastische Ironie wird definiert, aber der 
Fokus der Lektion ist umstandsbezogene Ironie umstandsbezogen. 
Diese Lektion kann vor länger unterrichten verwendet werden, 
kompliziertere kurze Geschichten, die umstandsbezogene Ironie 
enthalten. Diese Lektion wird für einen englische 
Sprachenanfänger (ELL) geändert der auf der niedrigen Zwischenstufe 
(IL) liest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon présentera des étudiants au concept de 
l'ironie. Verbale, situationnelle, et l'ironie excessive sera 
définie, mais le centre de la leçon est l'ironie situationnelle. 
Cette leçon peut être utilisée avant d'enseigner plus 
longtemps, des histoires courtes plus complexes qui contiennent 
l'ironie situationnelle. Cette leçon est modifiée pour un 
étudiant d'anglais (ELL) qui lit au niveau (IL) bas 
intermédiaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição introduzirá estudantes ao conceito do irony.
Verbal, situational, e o irony dramático será definido, mas o 
foco da lição é o irony situational. Esta lição pode ser 
usada antes de ensinar mais por muito tempo, umas histórias curtas 
mais complexas que contenham o irony situational. Esta lição 
é modificada para um learner de língua inglesa (ELL) que leia no 
nível (IL) baixo intermediário.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione introdurrà gli allievi al concetto 
dell'ironia. Verbale, situazionale e l'ironia drammatica sarà 
definita, ma il fuoco della lezione è l'ironia situazionale. 
Questa lezione può essere usata prima dell'istruzione più 
lungamente, storia corte più complesse che contengono l'ironia 
situazionale. Questa lezione è modificata per uno studente di 
lingue inglese (ELL) che legge al basso livello intermedio (IL).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα θα εισαγάγει τους σπουδαστές στην 
έννοια της ειρωνείας. Η λεκτική, περιστασιακή, και 
δραματική ειρωνεία θα καθοριστεί, αλλά η εστίαση του μαθήματος 
είναι περιστασιακή ειρωνεία. Αυτό το μάθημα μπορεί να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί πριν από τις πιό μακροχρόνιες, πιό σύνθετες 
σύντομες ιστορίες διδασκαλίας που περιέχουν την περιστασιακή 
ειρωνεία. Αυτό το μάθημα τροποποιείται για έναν αρχάριο 
αγγλικής γλώσσας (ELL) που διαβάζει στο ενδιάμεσο χαμηλό 
επίπεδο (IL).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección introducirá a estudiantes al concepto de la
ironía. Verbal, circunstancial, y la ironía dramática será 
definida, solamente el foco de la lección es la ironía 
circunstancial. Esta lección se puede utilizar antes de la 
enseñanza más de largo, historias cortas más complejas que 
contengan ironía circunstancial. Esta lección se modifica para
un principiante de lenguaje inglés (CODO) que lea en el nivel bajo 
intermedio (IL).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ANN GERBER
FN:ANN GERBER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TERICIA SUMMERS
FN:TERICIA SUMMERS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204317</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107244</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/how-ironic</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
