<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108396</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108396</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212042</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Scientific American Frontiers: Alien Invasion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaftliche Amerikanische Grenzen: 
Ausländische Invasion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Frontières Américaines Scientifiques : 
Invasion Étrangère</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fronteiras Americanas Científicas: Invasão
Estrangeira</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Frontiere Americane Scientifiche: Invasione 
Straniera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστημονικά αμερικανικά σύνορα: Αλλοδαπή 
εισβολή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fronteras Americanas Científicas: Invasión
Extranjera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Scientific American Frontiers program on PBS aired a special series on invasive alien species. This website is the central site for that program. Users can watch web video of each segment, access additional links on invasive species, email the scientists featured in each segment and read news articles about topics pertinent to invasive species. The America's Most Un-Wanted feature allows users to access interactive location data on several pervasive alien species. This site is a particularly accessible site with a wide variety of information regarding invasive species in the United States.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das wissenschaftliche amerikanische Grenzprogramm 
über PBS lüftete eine spezielle Serie auf ausländischen 
Angriffssorten. Diese Web site ist die zentrale Site für dieses
Programm. Benutzer können Web-Bildschirm jedes Segments, 
Zugriff zusätzliche Links auf Angriffssorten überwachen, email, das 
die Wissenschaftler in jedem Segment kennzeichneten und Nachrichten 
Artikel über die Themen lasen, die Angriffssorte passend sind. 
Das des Amerikas unerwünschteste Merkmal erlaubt Benutzern, auf
interaktive Standortdaten bezüglich einiger durchdringender 
ausländischer Sorten zuzugreifen. Diese Site ist eine besonders
zugängliche Site mit einer breiten Vielzahl der Informationen 
betreffend sind Angriffssorte in den Vereinigten Staaten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le programme américain scientifique de 
frontières sur PBS a aéré une série spéciale sur des espèces
étrangères invahissantes. Ce site Web est le lieu 
d'exploitation principal pour ce programme. Les utilisateurs 
peuvent observer le vidéo de Web de chaque segment, liens 
supplémentaires d'accès sur des espèces invahissantes, email 
que les scientifiques ont comporté dans chaque segment et ont lu des 
articles de nouvelles concernant des sujets concernant des 
espèces invahissantes. Le dispositif le plus non désiré 
de l'Amérique permet à des utilisateurs d'accéder à des données 
interactives d'emplacement sur plusieurs espèces étrangères 
dominantes. Ce site est un site particulièrement accessible 
avec une grande variété d'information concernant des espèces 
invahissantes aux Etats-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O programa americano científico das fronteiras em
PBS arejou uma série especial em espécies estrangeiras invasive. 
Este Web site é o local central para esse programa. Os 
usuários podem prestar atenção ao vídeo de cada segmento, 
ligações adicionais do Web do acesso em espécies invasive, email 
que os cientistas caracterizaram em cada segmento e leram artigos da 
notícia sobre os tópicos pertinentes à espécie invasive. A 
característica a mais não desejada da América permite que os 
usuários alcancem dados interativos da posição em diversas 
espécies estrangeiras pervasive. Este local é um local 
particularmente acessível com uma variedade larga da informação a 
respeito da espécie invasive nos estados unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il programma americano scientifico di frontiere su
PBS ha ventilato una serie speciale sulle specie straniere invasive. 
Questo Web site è il luogo centrale per quel programma. 
Gli utenti possono guardare il video di ogni segmento, 
collegamenti supplementari di Web di accesso sulle specie invasive, 
email che gli scienziati hanno caratterizzato in ogni segmento e che 
hanno letto gli articoli di notizie sui soggetti interessati alla 
specie invasive. La caratteristica più indesiderabile 
dell'America permette che gli utenti accedano ai dati interattivi di 
posizione su parecchie specie straniere dominanti. Questo luogo 
è un luogo particolarmente accessibile con un'ampia varietà di 
informazioni per quanto riguarda la specie invasive in unito 
Dichiara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το επιστημονικό αμερικανικό συνοριακό πρόγραμμα για 
PBS αέρισε μια ειδική σειρά στα της εισβολής αλλοδαπά είδη. 
Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος είναι η κεντρική περιοχή για εκείνο το 
πρόγραμμα. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να προσέξουν το βίντεο Ιστού
κάθε τμήματος μνήμης, πρόσθετες συνδέσεις πρόσβασης στα της 
εισβολής είδη, να στείλουν μήνυμα με το ηλεκτρονικό ταχυδρομείο 
τους επιστήμονες που χαρακτηρίζονται σε κάθε τμήμα μνήμης και να 
διαβάσουν τα άρθρα ειδήσεων για τα θέματα σχετικά με τα της 
εισβολής είδη. Το πιό ανεπιθύμητο χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα 
της Αμερικής επιτρέπει στους χρήστες για να έχει πρόσβαση στα 
διαλογικά στοιχεία θέσης όσον αφορά διάφορα κυρίαρχα αλλοδαπά 
είδη. Αυτή η περιοχή είναι μια ιδιαίτερα προσιτή περιοχή 
με μια ευρεία ποικιλία των πληροφοριών σχετικά με της εισβολής 
είδος στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El programa americano científico de las fronteras
sobre PBS ventiló una serie especial en especies extranjeras 
invasoras. Este Web site es el sitio central para ese programa. 
Los utilizadores pueden mirar el vídeo de cada segmento, 
conexiones adicionales del Web del acceso en especies invasoras, email
que los científicos ofrecieron en cada segmento y que leyeron los 
artículos de las noticias acerca de los asuntos pertinentes a la 
especie invasora. La característica más indeseada de la 
América permite que los utilizadores tengan acceso a datos 
interactivos de la localización sobre varias especies extranjeras 
penetrantes. Este sitio es un sitio determinado accesible con 
una variedad amplia de información con respecto a especie invasora en
los Estados Unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212042</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108396</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/scientific-american-frontiers-alien-invasion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
