<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104982</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104982</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206045</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Space Weather Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Platz-Meteorologiestation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Espace Survivent à Au Centre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Centro De Tempo Do Espaço</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Centro metereologico Dello Spazio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το διαστημικό καιρικό κέντρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Centro meteorológico Del Espacio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the solar cycle, solar wind, Earth's magnetic field, the ionosphere, auroras, states of matter, plasma (which makes up 99% of visible matter in the universe), and other sun-earth topics. Online games let students launch solar particles at Earth, bowl with protons, and watch charged particles move in magnetic fields. Information is provided on space weather research, space weather modeling and forecasting, and the National Space Weather Program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht die Solarschleife, Solarwind, bedeckte 
magnetisches auffangen, das ionosphere, auroras, Zustände 
des Stoffes, Plasma (das 99% vom sichtbaren Stoff im Universum bildet)
und andere Sonne-Masse Themen mit Erde. Onlinespiele lassen 
Kursteilnehmer Solarpartikel an der Masse, Schüssel ausstoßen mit 
Protonen, und Uhr belastete Partikel, in magnetisches zu bewegen 
fängt auf. Informationen werden auf 
Platzwetterforschung zur Verfügung gestellt, dem formenden und 
prognostizierenden Platzwetter und dem nationalen 
Platz-Wetter-Programm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore le cycle solaire, vent solaire, a mis à 
la terre le champ magnétique, l'ionosphère, des auroras, des états 
de matière, le plasma (qui compose 99% de la matière visible dans 
l'univers), et d'autres sujets de la soleil-terre. Les jeux en 
ligne ont laissé des étudiants lancer les particules solaires à la 
terre, à la cuvette avec des protons, et aux particules chargées par
montre pour se déplacer les champs magnétiques. Des 
informations sont fournies sur l'espace survivent à à la 
recherche, l'espace survivent à à modeler et à prévoir, et 
l'espace national Survivent à au programme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora o ciclo solar, vento solar, ligaram à 
terra o campo magnético, o ionosphere, auroras, estados da matéria, 
plasma (que faz acima 99% da matéria visível no universo), e outros 
tópicos da sol-terra. Os jogos em linha deixaram estudantes 
lançar partículas solares na terra, na bacia com protons, e em 
partículas carregadas relógio para mover-se em campos magnéticos. 
A informação é fornecida na pesquisa do tempo do espaço, no 
tempo do espaço que modelam e que prevêem, e no programa nacional do
tempo do espaço.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora il ciclo solare, vento solare, hanno 
interrato il campo magnetico, lo ionosphere, auroras, dichiarano 
della materia, del plasma (che compone 99% della materia visibile 
nell'universo) e di altri soggetti della sole-terra. I giochi in
linea hanno lasciato gli allievi lanciare le particelle solari a 
terra, alla ciotola con i protoni ed alle particelle caricate 
vigilanza per muoversi nei campi magnetici. Le informazioni sono
fornite su ricerca del tempo dello spazio, sul tempo dello spazio che 
modellano e che prevedono e sul programma nazionale del tempo dello 
spazio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά τον ηλιακό κύκλο, ηλιακός αέρας, γήινο 
μαγνητικό πεδίο, η ιονόσφαιρα, αυγές, καταστάσεις του θέματος, 
του πλάσματος (που αποτελούν 99% του ορατού θέματος στον 
κόσμο), και άλλων ήλιος-γήινων θεμάτων. Τα σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση παιχνίδια αφήνουν τους σπουδαστές να προωθήσουν τα 
ηλιακά μόρια στη γη, το κύπελλο με τα πρωτόνια, και χρεωμένη τη 
ρολόι κίνηση μορίων στα μαγνητικά πεδία. Οι πληροφορίες 
παρέχονται για τη διαστημική καιρική έρευνα, το διαστημικό καιρό
που διαμορφώνουν και που προβλέπουν, και το εθνικό διαστημικό 
καιρικό πρόγραμμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora el ciclo solar, viento solar, conectaron a
tierra el campo magnético, el ionosphere, auroras, estados de la 
materia, el plasma (que hace para arriba el 99% de materia visible en 
el universo), y otros asuntos de la sol-tierra. Los juegos en 
línea dejaron a estudiantes lanzar partículas solares en la tierra, 
el tazón de fuente con los protones, y las partículas cargadas reloj
para moverse en campos magnéticos. La información se 
proporciona en la investigación del tiempo del espacio, el tiempo del
espacio que modela y que pronostica, y el programa nacional del tiempo
del espacio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206045</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104982</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-space-weather-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
