<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106984</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106984</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206692</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Structures of Life</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Strukturen des Lebens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les structures de la vie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As estruturas da vida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le strutture di vita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι δομές της ζωής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las estructuras de la vida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">takes us into the world of structural biology -- a branch of molecular biology that focuses on the shape of nucleic acids and proteins (the molecules that do most of the work in our bodies). Learn about the structures and roles of proteins, tools used to study protein shapes, how proteins are used in designing new medications (for AIDS and arthritis), and what structural biology reveals about all life processes. Find out about careers in biomedical research.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">nimmt uns in die Welt der strukturellen Biologie 
-- ein Zweig der molekularen Biologie, die auf die Form der 
Nukleinsäuren und der Proteine konzentriert (die Moleküle, die die 
meisten der Arbeit in unseren Körpern erledigen). Erlernen Sie 
über die Strukturen und die Rollen der Proteine, die Hilfsmittel, die
benutzt werden, um Proteinformen zu studieren, wie Proteine benutzt 
werden, wenn man neue Medikationen (für AIDS und Arthritis) 
konzipiert, und welche strukturelle Biologie über alle Lebenprozesse 
aufdeckt. Finden Sie über Karrieren in der biomedizinischen 
Forschung heraus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">nous prend dans le monde de la biologie 
structurale -- un branchement de la biologie moléculaire qui se 
concentre sur la forme des acides nucléiques et des protéines (les 
molécules qui effectuent la majeure partie du travail dans nos 
corps). Renseignez-vous sur les structures et les rôles des 
protéines, outils utilisés pour étudier des formes de protéine, 
comment des protéines sont utilisées en concevant de nouveaux 
médicaments (pour le SIDA et l'arthrite), et quelle biologie 
structurale indique au sujet de tous les processus de la vie. 
Découvrez au sujet des carrières dans la recherche 
biomédicale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">faz exame de nos no mundo da biologia estrutural 
-- uma filial da biologia molecular que focaliza na forma de ácidos 
nucleic e de proteínas (as moléculas que fazem a maioria do trabalho
em nossos corpos). Aprenda sobre as estruturas e os papéis das 
proteínas, ferramentas usadas estudar formas da proteína, como as 
proteínas são usadas em projetar medications novos (para o AIDS e o 
arthritis), e que biologia estrutural revela sobre todos os processos 
da vida. Encontre para fora sobre carreiras na pesquisa 
biomedical.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">li prende nel mondo di biologia strutturale -- un 
ramo di biologia molecolare che mette a fuoco sulla figura degli acidi
nucleici e delle proteine (le molecole che fanno la maggior parte del 
lavoro nei nostri corpi). Impari circa le strutture ed i ruoli 
delle proteine, strumenti utilizzati per studiare le figure della 
proteina, come le proteine sono usate nella progettazione dei farmaci 
nuovi (per il AIDS e l'artrite) e che biologia strutturale rivela 
circa tutti i processi di vita. Scopra circa le carriere nella 
ricerca biomedica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μας παίρνει στον κόσμο της δομικής βιολογίας -- ένας 
κλάδος της μοριακής βιολογίας που εστιάζει στη μορφή των 
νουκλεϊνικών οξέων και των πρωτεϊνών (τα μόρια που κάνουν την 
μεγαλύτερη μέρος της εργασίας στους οργανισμούς μας). 
Μάθετε για τις δομές και τους ρόλους των πρωτεϊνών, 
εργαλεία που χρησιμοποιούνται στις πρωτεϊνικές μορφές μελέτης, 
πώς οι πρωτεϊ'νες χρησιμοποιούνται στο σχεδιασμό των νέων 
φαρμάκων (για το AIDS και την αρθρίτιδα), και ποια δομική 
βιολογία αποκαλύπτει για όλες τις διαδικασίες ζωής. 
Ανακαλύψτε για τις σταδιοδρομίες στη βιοϊατρική έρευνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">nos toma en el mundo de la biología estructural 
-- una ramificación de la biología molecular que se centra en la 
dimensión de una variable de los ácidos nucleic y de las proteínas 
(las moléculas que hacen la mayoría del trabajo en nuestros 
cuerpos). Aprenda sobre las estructuras y el papeles de las 
proteínas, herramientas usadas para estudiar dimensiones de una 
variable de la proteína, cómo las proteínas se utilizan en diseñar
medicaciones nuevas (para el SIDA y la artritis), y qué biología 
estructural revela sobre todos los procesos de la vida. Descubra
sobre carreras en la investigación biomédica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206692</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106984</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-structures-of-life</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
