<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105929</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105929</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086283</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Had to Break the Law to Force Him to Comply:" Lillian Roberts Recalls Organizing State Hospital Workers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich mußte das Gesetz brechen, um ihn zu 
erzwingen einzuwilligen:" Lillian Roberts Rückrufe, die 
Zustand-Krankenhaus-Arbeiter Organisieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai dû casser la loi pour le forcer à se 
conformer :" Rappels de Lillian Roberts Organisant des Ouvriers 
D'Hôpital D'État</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu tive que quebrar a lei para forçá-lo a 
comply:" Recordações De Lillian Roberts Que Organizam 
Trabalhadores Do Hospital Do Estado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho dovuto rompere la legge per forzarlo aderire:" 
L'Organizzazione Di Richiami Di Lillian Roberts Dichiara 
Gli Operai Dell'Ospedale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έπρεπε να παραβώ το νόμο για να τον αναγκάσω για να 
συμμορφωθώ:" Ανακλήσεις Roberts Lillian που οργανώνουν 
τους εργαζομένους κρατικών νοσοκομείων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tuve que romper la ley para forzarlo conformarse:"
Memorias De Lillian Roberts Que ordenan A Trabajadores Del 
Hospital Del Estado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Lillian Roberts came to New York in 1965 during a peak in labor militancy led by state and municipal government employees. Teachers, social workers, and sanitation workers all fought for better working conditions, improved pay scales, and reformed social services. Roberts, an African-American woman from Chicago, was an organizer for the American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), and helped AFSCME's local D.C. 37 win the right to represent thousands of hospital employees. She led series of strikes at New York State hospitals to protest Governor Nelson Rockefeller's opposition to unionization. Her efforts landed her in jail for a month, where she found it hard despite gestures of solidarity from her fellow prisoners.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lillian Roberts kam nach New York in 1965 während
einer Spitze im Arbeitsmilitancy, der vom Zustand und von den 
städtischen Beschäftigten im öffentlichen Dienst geführt wurde. 
Lehrer, Sozialarbeiter und Hygienearbeiter kämpften ganz für 
bessere Arbeitsbedingungen, verbesserte Bezahlung Skalen und 
verbesserten Sozialeinrichtungen. Roberts, eine 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Frau von Chicago, war ein Organisator für 
die amerikanische Vereinigung des Zustandes, der Grafschaft und der 
städtischen Angestellten (AFSCME) und des geholfenen AFSCME's lokalen
Gleichstrom 37 Gewinns das Recht, Tausenden Krankenhausangestellte 
darzustellen. Sie führte Reihe Schläge an den Staat 
New-Yorkkrankenhäusern Protest Regler-Nelson Rockefellers zur 
Opposition zum Unionization. Ihre Bemühungen landeten sie im 
Gefängnis für einen Monat, in dem sie es hart trotz der Gesten der 
solidarität von ihren Mitgefangenen fand.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lillian Roberts est venu à New York dans 1965 
pendant une crête dans le militantisme de travail mené par l'état 
et les employés de gouvernement municipaux. Les professeurs, 
les ouvriers sociaux, et les ouvriers d'hygiène ont tout combattu 
pour de meilleures conditions de travail, échelles de salaires 
améliorées, et ont reformé des services sociaux. Roberts, une
femme afro-américaine de Chicago, était un organisateur pour la 
fédération américaine de l'état, le comté, et les employés 
municipaux (AFSCME), et la victoire locale aidée de dc 37 d'AFSCME's 
la droite de représenter des milliers d'employés d'hôpital. 
Elle a mené la série de grèves aux hôpitaux de l'état de 
New-York à l'opposition du Nelson Rockefeller du Gouverneur de 
protestation à la syndicalisation. Ses efforts l'ont 
débarquée en prison pendant un mois, où elle l'a trouvé dur en 
dépit des gestes de la solidarité de ses prisonniers de camarade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lillian Roberts veio a New York em 1965 durante um 
pico no militancy labor conduzido pelo estado e por empregados de 
governo municipais. Os professores, os trabalhadores sociais, e 
os trabalhadores do sanitation lutaram toda por condições de 
funcionamento melhores, escalas de pagamento melhoradas, e reformaram 
serviços sociais. Roberts, uma mulher Africano-Americana de 
Chicago, era um organizer para o federation americano do estado, o 
condado, e os empregados municipais (AFSCME), e vitória local ajudada
da C.C. 37 de AFSCME's a direita representar milhares de empregados do
hospital. Conduziu à série das batidas em hospitais do estado 
de New York à oposição de Nelson Rockefeller do regulador do 
protesto ao unionization. Seus esforços aterraram-na na cadeia 
por um mês, onde encontrou duro apesar dos gestos do solidarity de 
seus prisioneiros do companheiro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lillian Roberts è venuto a New York in 1965 
durante il picco nella militanza di lavoro condotta vicino 
dichiara ed impiegati di governo comunali. Gli 
insegnanti, gli operai sociali e gli operai di risanamento interamente
hanno combattuto per le condizioni di lavoro migliori, scale di paga 
migliorate ed hanno riformato i servizi sociali. Roberts, una 
donna Africano-Americana da Chicago, era un organizzatore per la 
federazione americana di Dichiara, contea ed impiegati comunali
(AFSCME) e vittoria locale aiutata di dc 37 di AFSCME's la destra 
rappresentare i migliaia degli impiegati dell'ospedale. Ha 
condotto la serie di colpi a New York Dichiara gli ospedali per
protestare l'opposizione del Nelson Rockefeller del regolatore a 
unionization. I suoi sforzi la hanno atterrata in prigione per 
un mese, in cui lo ha trovato duro malgrado i gestures della 
solidarietà dai suoi prigionieri del collega.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Lillian Roberts ήρθε στη Νέα Υόρκη το 1965 
κατά τη διάρκεια μιας αιχμής στη μαχητικότητα εργασίας που 
οδηγήθηκε από το κράτος και τους δημοτικούς κυβερνητικούς 
υπαλλήλους. Οι δάσκαλοι, οι κοινωνικοί λειτουργοί, και οι 
εργαζόμενοι όλοι υγιεινής πάλεψαν για τις καλύτερες συνθήκες 
εργασίας, βελτιωμένος πληρώστε τις κλίμακες, και τις 
μεταρρυθμισμένες κοινωνικές υπηρεσίες. Το Roberts, μια 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανική γυναίκα από το Σικάγο, ήταν διοργανωτής
για την αμερικανική ομοσπονδία του κράτους, του νομού, και των 
δημοτικών υπαλλήλων (AFSCME), και βοήθησε το τοπικό ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ 
ΡΕΎΜΑ 37 AFSCME να κερδίσει το δικαίωμα να αντιπροσωπευθούν 
χιλιάδες υπάλληλοι νοσοκομείων. Οδήγησε τη σειρά απεργιών 
στα κρατικά νοσοκομεία της Νέας Υόρκης στην αντίθεση του 
Nelson Rockefeller κυβερνητών διαμαρτυρίας στη 
συνδικαλικοποίηση. Οι προσπάθειές της την προσγειώθηκαν στη 
φυλακή για έναν μήνα, όπου τον βρήκε σκληρά παρά τις 
χειρονομίες της αλληλεγγύης από τους συντροφικούς φυλακισμένους 
της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lillian Roberts vino a Nueva York en 1965 durante 
un pico en la militancia de trabajo conducida por el estado y los 
empleados de gobierno municipales. Los profesores, los 
trabajadores sociales, y los trabajadores del saneamiento lucharon 
todo para condiciones de trabajo mejores, escalas salariales 
mejoradas, y reformaron servicios sociales. Roberts, mujer 
Africano-Americana de Chicago, era un organizador para la federación 
americana del estado, condado, y los empleados municipales (AFSCME), y
triunfo local ayudado de dc 37 de AFSCME's la derecha de representar a
los millares de empleados del hospital. Ella condujo la serie de
huelgas en los hospitales del estado de Nueva York a la oposición de 
Nelson Rockefeller del gobernador de la protesta a la 
sindicalización. Sus esfuerzos la aterrizaron en la cárcel por
un mes, en donde ella encontró duro a pesar de gestos de la 
solidaridad de sus presos del compañero.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086283</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105929</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-had-to-break-the-law-to-force-him-to-comply-lillian-roberts-recalls-organizing-state-hospital-workers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
