<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103358</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103358</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086196</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Gibson girls.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gibson Mädchen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Filles de Gibson.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Meninas de Gibson.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ragazze di Gibson.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κορίτσια Gibson.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchachas de Gibson.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1890s, Charles Dana Gibson's magazine illustrations of fashionable young women gained wide popularity. The physical type he portrayed became the standard of beauty, a romantic ideal that suggested a new female independence while also celebrating the privileges and glamour of elite society. Within a few years, women who viewed Gibson's illustrations in magazines were more likely to work for wages. Growing opportunities for white collar work in stores and offices attracted white women who spoke English, although they were paid roughly half of what their male counterparts received and were often subjected to discrimination and harassment.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im 1890s Charles Dana Gibsons gewannen 
Zeitschriftabbildungen der modernen jungen Frauen breite Popularität.
Der körperliche Typ, den er schilderte, wurde der Standard der 
Schönheit, ein romantisches ideales, das eine neue weibliche 
Unabhängigkeit beim die Privilegien und den Zauber der 
Auslesegesellschaft auch feiern vorschlug. Innerhalb einiger 
Jahre waren Frauen, die ansahen, Abbildungen Gibsons in den 
Zeitschriften wahrscheinlicher, für Löhne zu arbeiten. 
Wachsende Gelegenheiten für weißen Stellring arbeiten in den 
Speichern und Büros zogen weiße Frauen an, die Englisch sprachen, 
obgleich sie ungefähr Hälfte gezahlt wurden von, was ihre 
männlichen Gegenstücke empfingen und häufig Unterscheidung und 
Belästigung unterworfen wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le 1890s, les illustrations de magazine de Charles 
Dana Gibson de jeunes femmes à la mode ont gagné la 
popularité large. Le type physique qu'il a dépeint est devenu 
le niveau de la beauté, un idéal romantique qui a suggéré une 
nouvelle indépendance femelle tout en également célébrant les 
privilèges et le charme de la société d'élite. Dans quelques
années, les femmes qui ont visualisé les illustrations de Gibson en 
magasins étaient pour travailler pour des salaires. Les 
occasions croissantes pour le collier blanc fonctionnent dans les 
mémoires et les bureaux ont attiré les femmes blanches qui ont 
parlé anglais, bien qu'ils aient été payés rudement la moitié de 
ce que leurs contre-parties mâles ont reçu et ont été souvent 
soumises à la discrimination et au harcèlement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 1890s, as ilustrações do compartimento de Charles 
Dana Gibson de mulheres novas fashionable ganharam a popularidade 
larga. O tipo que físico portrayed transformou-se o padrão da 
beleza, um ideal romântico que sugerisse uma independência fêmea 
nova ao também comemorar os privilégios e o glamour da sociedade do 
elite. Dentro de alguns anos, as mulheres que viram 
ilustrações de Gibson nos compartimentos eram mais prováveis 
trabalhar para salários. As oportunidades crescentes para o 
colar branco trabalham nas lojas e os escritórios atraíram as 
mulheres brancas que falaram o inglês, embora fosse pagado 
aproximadamente a metade de o que suas contrapartes masculinas 
receberam e foram sujeitadas frequentemente à discriminação e ao 
harassment.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel 1890s, le illustrazioni dello scomparto del Charles 
Dana Gibson delle donne giovani alla moda hanno guadagnato la 
popolarità larga. Il tipo che fisico ha ritratto si è 
transformato in nel livello della bellezza, un ideale romantico che ha
suggerito una nuova indipendenza femminile mentre però celebrando i 
privilegi ed il fascino della società dell'elite. In alcuni 
anni, le donne che hanno osservato illustrazioni del Gibson in 
scomparti erano più probabili funzionare per gli stipendi. Le 
occasioni crescenti per il collare bianco funzionano in depositi e gli
uffici hanno attratto le donne bianche che hanno parlato inglese, 
anche se sono stati pagati approssimativamente la metà di che cosa le
loro controparti maschii hanno ricevuto e spesso sono state sottoposte
a distinzione ed al harassment.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο 1890s, απεικονίσεις περιοδικών Charles Dana
Gibson's της μοντέρνης νέας κερδισμένης γυναίκες ευρείας 
δημοτικότητας. Ο φυσικός τύπος που απεικόνισε έγινε τα 
πρότυπα της ομορφιάς, ένα ρομαντικό ιδανικό που πρότεινε μια 
νέα θηλυκή ανεξαρτησία επίσης γιορτάζοντας τα προνόμια και τη 
γοητεία της κοινωνίας ελίτ. Μέσα σε μερικά έτη, οι 
γυναίκες που εμφάνισαν τις απεικονίσεις Gibson στα περιοδικά 
ήταν πιθανότερο να εργαστούν για τις αμοιβές. Οι 
αυξανόμενες ευκαιρίες για την άσπρη εργασία περιλαίμιων στα 
καταστήματα και τα γραφεία προσέλκυσαν τις λευκές γυναίκες που 
μίλησαν τα αγγλικά, αν και πληρώθηκαν κατά προσέγγιση οι μισό 
από αυτού που οι αντίστοιχοι άνδρες τους έλαβαν και υποβλήθηκαν 
συχνά στη διάκριση και την παρενόχληση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el 1890s, las ilustraciones del compartimiento de 
Charles Dana Gibson de mujeres jóvenes de moda ganaron renombre 
amplio. El tipo físico que él retrató se convirtió en el 
estándar de la belleza, un ideal romántico que sugirió una nueva 
independencia femenina mientras que también celebraba los privilegios
y el encanto de la sociedad de la élite. Dentro de algunos 
años, las mujeres que vieron las ilustraciones de Gibson en 
compartimientos eran más probables trabajar para los salarios. 
Las oportunidades cada vez mayor para el collar blanco trabajan 
en almacenes y las oficinas atrajeron a mujeres blancas que hablaron 
inglés, aunque él fue pagado áspero la mitad de lo que recibieron y
fueron sujetadas a menudo sus contrapartes masculinas a la 
discriminación y al hostigamiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086196</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103358</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/gibson-girls</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
