<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086369</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">John P. Parker, Conductor, on the Underground Railroad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">John P. Parker, Leiter, auf der unterirdischen 
Eisenbahn</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">John P. Parker, chef d'orchestre, sur le chemin 
de fer souterrain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">John P. Parker, maestro, na estrada de ferro 
subterrânea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">John P. Parker, conduttore, sulla ferrovia 
sotterranea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ιοχν P. Parker, αγωγός, στον υπόγειο 
σιδηρόδρομο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juan P. Parker, conductor, en el ferrocarril 
subterráneo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Underground Railroad was a network of free African Americans and sympathetic whites that concealed, clothed, and guided fugitive slaves to the North and freedom. The "railroad" comprised a series of stops often tended by local vigilance committees in northern communities. John P. Parker was born into slavery in Norfolk, Virginia, but became a freeman by 1845. He moved to Rowley, Ohio with its active abolitionist community and followed his trade as an iron master by day while rescuing fugitive slaves by night. Free blacks such as Parker supplied most of the needed labor and finances to help escaped slaves. Parker, it is believed, helped hundreds escape to freedom across the Ohio River from Kentucky along the busiest segment of the railroad. He then passed them on to another "conductor," braving significant dangers, as related in this excerpt from a recently published autobiography compiled from newspaper interviews with Parker in 1885.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die unterirdische Eisenbahn war ein Netz der 
freien afrikanischen Amerikaner und des sympatischen Weiß, die und 
geführte Flüchtlingsklaven zum Norden und zur Freiheit verbargen, 
kleideten. Die "Eisenbahn" enthielt eine Serie von den 
Anschlägen, die häufig von den lokalen Wachsamkeitausschüssen in 
den Nordgemeinschaften geneigt wurden. John P. Parker wurde in 
Sklaverei in Norfolk, Virginia getragen, aber wurde ein Ehrenbürger 
bis zum 1845. Er zog auf Rowley, Ohio mit seiner aktiven 
abolitionist Gemeinschaft um und übte sein Gewerbe als Eisenmeister 
bis zum Tag aus, während rettender Flüchtling bis zum Nacht 
schuftet. Freie Schwarze wie Parker, das die meisten der 
erforderlichen Arbeit und Finanzen zum zu helfen angegeben wurde, 
entgingen Sklaven. Parker, wird es, geholfene Hunderte entgeht 
zur Freiheit über dem Ohio Fluß von Kentucky entlang dem besetztsten
Segment der Eisenbahn geglaubt. Er führte sie dann an zu einem 
anderen "Leiter," braving bedeutende Gefahren, wie in diesem Excerpt 
von einer vor kurzem erschienenen Autobiographie in Verbindung 
gestanden, die von den Zeitung Interviews mit Parker 1885 kompiliert 
wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le chemin de fer souterrain était un réseau des
Américains africains libres et des blancs sympathiques qui ont 
caché, ont vêtu, et les esclaves guidés de fugitif au nord 
et à la liberté. Le "chemin de fer" a comporté une série des
arrêts souvent tendus par les comités locaux de vigilance dans les 
communautés nordiques. John P. Parker a été soutenu dans 
l'esclavage en Norfolk, la Virginie, mais est devenu un citoyen 
d'honneur d'ici 1845. Il s'est déplacé à Rowley, Ohio avec 
son communauté active d'abolitionniste et a suivi son commerce comme 
maître de fer de jour tandis que le fugitif de délivrance asservit 
par nuit. Les noirs libres tels que Parker fourni la plupart du 
travail et des finances nécessaires à aider ont échappé à des 
esclaves. Parker, on le croit, des centaines aidées 
s'échappent à la liberté à travers le fleuve de l'Ohio du Kentucky
le long du segment le plus occupé du chemin de fer. Il alors 
les a passées en fonction à un autre "conducteur," bravant
des dangers significatifs, comme associé dans cet extrait d'une 
autobiographie récemment éditée compilée des entrevues de journal 
avec Parker en 1885.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A estrada de ferro subterrânea era uma rede dos 
americanos africanos livres e dos brancos sympathetic que esconderam, 
se vestiram, e escravos guiados do fugitive ao norte e à liberdade. 
A "estrada de ferro" compreendeu uma série dos batentes 
tendidos frequentemente por comitês locais do vigilance em 
comunidades do norte. John P. Parker foi carregado no slavery em
Norfolk, Virgínia, mas transformou-se um freeman por 1845. 
Moveu-se para Rowley, Ohio com sua comunidade ativa do 
abolitionist e seguiu-se seu comércio como um mestre do ferro pelo 
dia quando o fugitive salvando slaves pela noite. Os pretos 
livres tais como Parker fornecido a maioria do trabalho e das 
finanças needed a ajudar escaparam de escravos. Parker, 
acredita-se, centenas ajudadas escapa-se à liberdade através do rio 
de Ohio de Kentucky ao longo do segmento o mais ocupado da estrada de 
ferro. Passou-os então sobre a um outro "condutor," perigos 
significativos braving, como relacionado neste excerpt de um 
autobiography recentemente publicado compilado das entrevistas do 
jornal com o Parker em 1885.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La ferrovia sotterranea era una rete degli 
Americani africani liberi e dei bianchi simpatici che hanno celato, 
coperto e schiavi guidati del fuggitivo al nord ed alla libertà. 
"la ferrovia" ha contenuto una serie gli arresti tesi spesso dai
comitati locali di vigilanza nelle Comunità nordiche. John P. 
Parker è stato sopportato in slavery in Norfolk, la Virginia, ma è 
diventato un freeman entro 1845. Si è mosso verso Rowley, Ohio 
con la relativa Comunità attiva di abolitionist ed ha seguito il suo 
commercio come supervisore del ferro di giorno mentre il fuggitivo di 
salvataggio assoggetta entro la notte. I neri liberi quale 
Parker fornito la maggior parte del lavoro e delle finanze 
necessari da aiutare hanno fuoriuscito gli schiavi. Parker, si 
crede, centinaia aiutate fuoriesce alla libertà attraverso il fiume 
dell'Ohio dal Kentucky lungo il segmento più occupato della ferrovia.
Allora le ha passate sopra ad un altro "conduttore," pericoli 
significativi braving, come riferito in questo brano da un 
autobiography recentemente pubblicato compilato dalle interviste del 
giornale con Parker in 1885.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο υπόγειος σιδηρόδρομος ήταν ένα δίκτυο ελεύθερων 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών και τα συμπονετικά λευκά που έκρυψαν, 
έντυσαν, και καθοδήγησαν τους σκλάβους προσφύγων στο Βορρά και 
την ελευθερία. Ο "σιδηρόδρομοσ" περιέλαβε μια σειρά στάσεων
που έτειναν συχνά από οι τοπικές επιτροπές επαγρύπνησης στις 
βόρειες κοινότητες. Θ*Ιοχν P. Parker γεννήθηκε στη 
σκλαβιά στο Norfolk, Βιρτζίνια, αλλά έγινε ελεύθερος πολίτης 
από 1845. Κινήθηκε προς Rowley, Οχάιο με την ενεργό 
κοινότητα ρεφορμιστών του και ακολούθησε το εμπόριό του ως κύριο
σιδήρου μέχρι την ημέρα διασώζοντας τους σκλάβους προσφύγων τή 
νύχτα. Οι ελεύθεροι Μαύροι όπως Parker παρεχόμενο την 
μεγαλύτερη μέρος της αναγκαίων εργασίας και των πόρων 
χρηματοδότησης που βοηθούν δραπέτευσαν τους σκλάβους. Το 
Parker, θεωρείται, βοήθησε τη διαφυγή εκατοντάδων στην 
ελευθερία πέρα από τον ποταμό του Οχάιου από το Κεντάκυ κατά 
μήκος του πιό απασχολημένου τμήματος μνήμης του σιδηροδρόμου. 
Τους μετέφερε έπειτα προς έναν άλλο "αγωγό," braving 
σημαντικοί κίνδυνοι, όπως σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από μια πρόσφατα
δημοσιευμένη αυτοβιογραφία που μεταγλωττίστηκε από τις 
συνεντεύξεις εφημερίδων με Parker το 1885.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ferrocarril subterráneo era una red de los 
americanos africanos libres y de los blancos comprensivos que 
encubrieron, arroparon, y los esclavos dirigidos del fugitivo al norte
y a la libertad. El "ferrocarril" abarcó una serie de las 
paradas tendidas a menudo por los comités locales de la vigilancia en
comunidades norteñas. Juan P. Parker nació en esclavitud en 
Norfolk, Virginia, pero hizo un freeman antes de 1845. Él se 
trasladó a Rowley, Ohio con su comunidad activa del abolitionist y 
siguió su comercio como amo del hierro por día mientras que el 
fugitivo de rescate esclaviza por noche. Los negros libres tales
como Parker provisto la mayoría del trabajo y de las finanzas 
necesarios a ayudar escaparon esclavos. Parker, se cree, los 
centenares ayudados se escapa a la libertad a través del río de Ohio
de Kentucky a lo largo del segmento más ocupado del ferrocarril. 
Él entonces los pasó encendido a otro "conductor," los 
peligros significativos braving, según lo relacionado en este 
extracto de una autobiografía recientemente publicada compilada de 
entrevistas del periódico con Parker en 1885.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086369</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106862</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/john-p-parker-conductor-on-the-underground-railroad</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
