<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105405</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105405</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200922</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">CLT: Exploring Climate Events and Human Development</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">CLT: Erforschende Klima-Fälle und 
menschliche Entwicklung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">CLT : Événements les explorant de climat 
et développement humain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">CLT: Eventos explorando do clima e 
desenvolvimento humano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">CLT: Eventi d'esplorazione di clima e 
sviluppo umano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">CLT: Να ερευνήσει τα γεγονότα κλίματος και 
την ανθρώπινη ανάπτυξη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">CLT: Acontecimientos del clima que exploran 
y desarrollo humano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This animation on the Climate TimeLine (CTL) site depicts changes in land cover due to land use over the past 100 years. Data is based on census data, tax records, land surveys, and historical geography estimates. This visualization is the work of the National Institute of Public Health and the Environment (RIVM, Netherlands) and the Center for Sustainability and the Global Environment (SAGE, USA).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Animation auf der Klima TimeLine (CTL) Site 
stellt Änderungen in der Landabdeckung wegen der Flächennutzung 
über den letzten 100 Jahren bildlich dar. Daten basieren auf 
Zählungdaten, Steuersätzen, Landübersichten und historischen 
Geographieschätzungen. Diese Sichtbarmachung ist die Arbeit des
nationalen Instituts des öffentlichen Gesundheitswesens und der 
Umgebung (RIVM, die Niederlande) und der Mitte für Sustainability und
die globale Umgebung (SALBEI, USA).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette animation sur le site de la Chronologie de 
climat (CTL) dépeint des changements de la couverture de terre due à
l'utilisation de la terre au cours des 100 dernières années. 
Des données sont basées sur des données de recensement, des 
enregistrements d'impôts, des enquêtes de terre, et des évaluations
historiques de géographie. Cette visualisation est le travail 
de l'institut national de la santé publique et de l'environnement 
(RIVM, Pays Bas) et du centre pour la Durabilité et 
l'environnement global (SAUGE, Etats-Unis).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este animation no local de TimeLine do clima (CTL)
descreve mudanças na tampa de terra  devido ao uso de terra sobre os 
100 anos passados. Os dados são baseados em dados de census, em
registros de imposto, em exames da terra, e em estimativas históricas
da geografia. Este visualization é o trabalho do instituto 
nacional da saúde pública e do ambiente (RIVM, Países Baixos) e do 
centro para Sustainability e o ambiente global (SÁBIO, EUA).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa animazione sul luogo di TimeLine di clima 
(CTL) descrive i cambiamenti nei tipi di terreno dovuto utilizzazione 
delle terre in questi ultimi 100 anni. I dati sono basati sui 
dati censuali, sulle registrazioni amministrative, sulle indagini 
della terra e sulle valutazioni storiche di geografia. Questa 
visualizzazione è il lavoro dell'istituto nazionale di sanità 
pubblica e dell'ambiente (RIVM, Paesi Bassi) e del centro per 
Sustainability e l'ambiente globale (SALVIA, S.U.A.).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ζωτικότητα στην περιοχή κλίματος TimeLine 
(CTL) απεικονίζει τις αλλαγές στην κάλυψη εδάφους λόγω στη 
χρήση εδάφους κατά τη διάρκεια των προηγούμενων 100 ετών. 
Το στοιχείο είναι βασισμένο στα στοιχεία απογραφής, τα 
φορολογικά μητρώα, τις έρευνες εδάφους, και τις ιστορικές 
εκτιμήσεις γεωγραφίας. Αυτή η απεικόνιση είναι η εργασία 
του εθνικού ιδρύματος δημόσιας υγείας και περιβάλλοντος (RIVM,
Κάτω Χώρες) και κέντρου για την ικανότητα υποστήριξης και 
παγκόσμιου περιβάλλοντος (ΦΑΣΚΟΜΗΛΙΑ, ΗΠΑ).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta animación en el sitio de TimeLine del clima 
(CTL) representa cambios en la cubierta de pista  debido a la 
utilización del suelo sobre los últimos 100 años. Los datos 
se basan en datos de censo, expedientes de impuesto, encuestas sobre 
la pista, y estimaciones históricas de la geografía. Esta 
visualización es el trabajo del instituto nacional de la salud 
pública y del ambiente (RIVM, Países Bajos) y del centro para 
Sustainability y el ambiente global (SABIO, los E.E.U.U.).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200922</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105405</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/clt-exploring-climate-events-and-human-development</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
