<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106034</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106034</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209901</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Convex Polygon </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Konvexes Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Polygone Convexe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Polygon Convexo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poligono Convesso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κυρτό πολύγωνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Polígono Convexo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the concept of a convex polygon - one where all interior angle are less than 180 degrees. The applet shows an irregular convex polygon initially. The user can drag any vertex, change the number of sides in the range 3..99, and make it regular or irregular. When the polygon is convex, the polygon is so flagged. It is shown that regular polygons are always convex. The goal is to show through experimentation what the concept of convexity really means. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die das Konzept eines konvexen Polygons - eins zeigen, wo 
aller Innenwinkel kleiner als 180 Grad sind. Der applet zeigt 
ein unregelmäßiges konvexes Polygon zuerst. Der Benutzer kann 
jeden möglichen Gipfel schleppen, die Zahl Seiten in der Strecke 
3..99 ändern, und sie regelmäßig oder unregelmäßig bilden. 
Wenn das Polygon konvex ist, ist das Polygon also 
gekennzeichnet. Es wird gezeigt, daß regelmäßige Polygone 
immer konvex sind. Das Ziel ist, durch Experimentieren zu 
zeigen, was das Konzept der Konvexität wirklich bedeutet. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent le concept d'un polygone convexe - un où tout l'angle
intérieur sont moins de 180 degrés. L'applet montre un 
polygone convexe irrégulier au commencement. L'utilisateur peut
traîner n'importe quel sommet, changer le nombre de côtés dans 
l'intervalle 3..99, et le rendre régulier ou irrégulier. Quand
le polygone est convexe, le polygone est ainsi diminué. On lui 
montre que les polygones réguliers sont toujours convexes. Le 
but est de montrer par l'expérimentation ce que signifie vraiment le 
concept de la convexité. L'applet peut être agrandi à la 
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem o conceito de um polygon convexo - um onde todo o ângulo 
interior é menos de 180 graus. O applet mostra um polygon 
convexo irregular inicialmente. O usuário pode arrastar todo o 
vertex, mudar o número dos lados na escala 3..99, e fazê-lo regular 
ou irregular. Quando o polygon é convexo, o polygon é assim 
que embandeirado. Mostra-se que os polygons regulares são 
sempre convexos. O objetivo é mostrar com a experimentação o 
que o conceito do convexity significa realmente. O applet pode 
ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da 
sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode 
alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca 
com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um 
componente do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da 
referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano il concetto di un poligono convesso - uno dove tutto 
l'angolo interno è meno di 180 gradi. Il applet mostra 
inizialmente un poligono convesso irregolare. L'utente può 
trascinare tutto il vertice, cambiare il numero di lati nella gamma 
3..99 e renderlo normale o irregolare. Quando il poligono è 
convesso, il poligono è in modo da diminito. È indicato che i 
poligoni normali sono sempre convessi. L'obiettivo è di 
mostrare con esperimento che cosa il concetto della convessità 
realmente significa. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato
di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια ενός κυρτού πολυγώνου - ένα όπου όλη 
η εσωτερική γωνία είναι λιγότερο από 180 βαθμοί. Το 
applet εμφανίζει ανώμαλο κυρτό πολύγωνο αρχικά. Ο 
χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει οποιοδήποτε vertex, να αλλάξει τον 
αριθμό πλευρών στη σειρά 3,,99, και να τον καταστήσει κανονικό
ή ανώμαλο. Όταν το πολύγωνο είναι κυρτό, το πολύγωνο 
σημαιοστολίζεται έτσι. Αποδεικνύεται ότι τα κανονικά 
πολύγωνα είναι πάντα κυρτά. Ο στόχος είναι να εμφανιστεί 
μέσω του πειραματισμού τι η έννοια convexity σημαίνει 
πραγματικά. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες 
μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά
από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε
τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη 
βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού 
προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού 
σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el concepto de un polígono convexo - uno donde está menos
todo el ángulo interior de 180 grados. El applet muestra un 
polígono convexo irregular inicialmente. El utilizador puede 
arrastrar cualquier cima, cambiar el número de caras en el rango 
3..99, y hacerlo regular o irregular. Cuando el polígono es 
convexo, el polígono es así que señalado por medio de una bandera. 
Se muestra que los polígonos regulares son siempre convexos. 
La meta es mostrar con la experimentación lo que significa el 
concepto de la convexidad realmente. El applet se puede agrandar
a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la 
sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante 
puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o 
en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209901</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106034</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/convex-polygon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
