<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103251</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103251</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087043</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The science of repetition.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Wissenschaft der Wiederholung.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La science de la répétition.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A ciência da repetição.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza di ripetizione.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η επιστήμη της επανάληψης.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La ciencia de la repetición.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A worker performs his job for efficiency experts with small lights attached to his arms and hands. This "cyclegraph," a photograph taken by an open-shutter still camera, was invented by time-and-motion specialist Frank Gilbreth to chart workers' movements in mass-production jobs. Gilbreth claimed that the device would help to eliminate useless movement and turn work into a rigid arrangement of "efficient" motions. Many managers embraced this and other techniques for "scientific management" in the early twentieth century to increase productivity by simplifying and standardizing the tasks of workers. Scientific management also gave managers better control over their workforce, since it meant that formerly skilled jobs could be broken into tasks and divided amongst several easily replaceable unskilled workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Arbeiter führt seinen Job für 
Rationalisierungsfachleute mit den kleinen Lichtern durch, die zu 
seinen Armen und zu Händen angebracht werden. Dieses 
"cyclegraph," eine Fotographie, die durch eine 
öffnen-Blendenverschluß ruhige Kamera genommen wurde, wurde durch 
Zeit-und-Bewegung Fachmann Freivermerk Gilbreth erfunden, um 
Bewegungen der Arbeiter in den Masse-Produktion Jobs zu entwerfen. 
Gilbreth behauptete, daß die Einheit helfen würde, 
unbrauchbare Bewegung zu beseitigen und Arbeit zu eine steife 
Anordnung für "leistungsfähige" Bewegungen zu machen. Viele 
Manager umfaßten dieses und andere Techniken für "wissenschaftliche 
Unternehmensführung" im frühen zwanzigsten Jahrhundert, um 
Produktivität zu erhöhen, indem sie die Aufgaben der Arbeiter 
vereinfachten und standardisierten. Wissenschaftliche 
Unternehmensführung gab Managern bessere Steuerung über ihrer 
Mannschaft, seit ihr auch bedeutete, daß früher erfahrene Jobs in 
Aufgaben gebrochen werden und unter einige leicht austauschbare 
unerfahrene Arbeiter geteilt werden konnten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un ouvrier exécute son travail pour des experts de 
l'efficience avec de petites lumières fixées à ses bras et mains. 
Ce "cyclegraph," une photographie prise par un appareil-photo 
immobile d'ouvrir-obturateur, a été inventé par contreseing 
Gilbreth de spécialiste en temps-et-mouvement pour dresser une carte 
les mouvements ouvriers dans les travaux de masse-production. 
Gilbreth a réclamé que le dispositif aiderait à éliminer le 
mouvement inutile et à transformer le travail en agencement rigide 
des mouvements "efficaces". Beaucoup de gestionnaires ont 
embrassé ceci et d'autres techniques pour "la gestion scientifique" 
au vingtième siècle tôt pour augmenter la productivité par la 
simplification et la normalisation charge des ouvriers. 
La gestion scientifique a également donné à des gestionnaires
un meilleur contrôle de leur main d'oeuvre, depuis elle a signifié 
qu'autrefois les travaux habiles pourraient être cassés en 
charge et s'est divisée parmi plusieurs ouvriers non 
qualifiés facilement remplaçables.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um trabalhador executa seu trabalho para peritos de 
eficiência com as luzes pequenas unidas a seus braços e mãos. 
Este "cyclegraph," uma fotografia feita exame por uma câmera 
imóvel do abr-obturador, foi inventado pelo franquia Gilbreth do 
specialist do tempo-e-movimento para fazer um mapa de movimentos de 
trabalhadores em trabalhos da massa-produção. Gilbreth 
reivindicou que o dispositivo ajudaria eliminar o movimento inútil e 
girar o trabalho em um arranjo rígido de movimentos "eficientes". 
Muitos gerentes embraced este e outras técnicas para "a 
gerência científica" no vigésimo século adiantado para aumentar a 
produtividade simplificando e estandardizando as tarefas dos 
trabalhadores. A gerência científica deu também a gerentes o 
controle melhor sobre seu workforce, desde ela significou que 
anteriormente os trabalhos hábeis poderiam ser quebrados em tarefas e
ser divididos amongst diversos trabalhadores inábeis fàcilmente 
substituíveis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un operaio effettua il suo lavoro per gli esperti di 
risparmio di temi con le piccole luci fissate alla sue armi e 
mani. Questo "cyclegraph," una fotografia presa da una macchina 
fotografica tranquilla dell'apr-otturatore, è stato inventato dalla 
firma di franchigia Gilbreth dell'esperto di tempo-e-movimento per 
progettare i movimenti degli operai nei lavori di massa-produzione. 
Gilbreth ha sostenuto che il dispositivo contribuirebbe ad 
eliminare il movimento inutile ed a trasformare nel lavoro una 
disposizione rigida dei movimenti "efficienti". Molti gestori 
hanno abbracciato questo ed altre tecniche per "la gestione 
scientifica" nel ventesimo secolo in anticipo per aumentare il 
rendimento facilitando e standardizzando le mansioni degli operai. 
La gestione scientifica egualmente ha dato a gestori il 
controllo migliore sopra la loro mano d'opera, da esso ha significato 
che precedentemente in lavori esperti potrebbero essere rotti nelle 
mansioni ed essere divisi fra parecchi operai non qualificati 
facilmente sostituibili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας εργαζόμενος εκτελεί την εργασία του για τους 
εμπειρογνώμονες αποδοτικότητας με τα μικρά φώτα που συνδέονται με
τα μπράτσα και τα χέρια του. Αυτό το "cyclegraph," μια 
φωτογραφία που λήφθηκε από μια ακίνητη φωτογραφική μηχανή 
ανοικτός-παραθυρόφυλλων, εφευρέθηκε από τον ειδικό Frank 
Gilbreth χρόνος-και-κινήσεων στις μετακινήσεις των εργαζομένων 
διαγραμμάτων στις εργασίες μαζικής παραγωγής. Το Gilbreth
υποστήριξε ότι η συσκευή θα βοηθούσε να αποβάλει την άχρηστη 
μετακίνηση και να μετατρέψει την εργασία σε άκαμπτη ρύθμιση των 
"αποδοτικών" κινήσεων. Πολλοί διευθυντές αγκαλίασαν αυτό 
και άλλες τεχνικές για τη "επιστημονική διαχείριση" στις αρχές 
του εικοστού αιώνα για να αυξήσουν την παραγωγικότητα με την 
απλούστευση και την τυποποίηση των στοιχειωδών εργασιών των 
εργαζομένων. Η επιστημονική διαχείριση έδωσε επίσης στους 
διευθυντές τον καλύτερο έλεγχο του εργατικού δυναμικού τους, 
δεδομένου ότι σήμανε ότι στο παρελθόν τις ειδικευμένες εργασίες
θα μπορούσαν να σπάσουν στις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες και να 
διαιρεθούν μεταξύ διάφορων εύκολα αναπληρώσιμων ανειδίκευτων 
εργαζομένων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un trabajador realiza su trabajo para los expertos de 
eficacia con las luces pequeñas asociadas a sus brazos y manos. 
Este "cyclegraph," una fotografía tomada por una cámara 
fotográfica inmóvil del abrir-obturador, fue inventado por la carta 
franca Gilbreth del especialista del tiempo-y-movimiento para planear 
los movimientos de trabajadores en trabajos de la masa-produccio'n. 
Gilbreth demandó que el dispositivo ayudaría a eliminar el 
movimiento inútil y a dar vuelta al trabajo en un arreglo rígido de 
movimientos "eficientes". Muchos encargados abrazaron esto y 
otras técnicas para la "gerencia científica" en el vigésimo siglo 
temprano para aumentar productividad simplificando y estandardizando 
las tareas de trabajadores. La gerencia científica también dio
a encargados un control mejor sobre su mano de obra, desde ella 
significó que los trabajos expertos se podrían romper en tareas y 
dividir antes entre varios trabajadores inexpertos fácilmente 
reemplazables.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087043</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103251</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-science-of-repetition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
