<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104313</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104313</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206463</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The United States Air Force Academy: Founding a Proud Tradition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Vereinigte Staaten Luftwaffe Akademie: 
Gründung einer stolzen Tradition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Académie de l'Armée de l'Air des Etats-Unis : 
Fondation d'une tradition fière</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Academy Unido Da Força aérea Dos Estados: 
Fundando uma tradição orgulhosa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unito Dichiara L'Accademia 
Dell'Aeronautica: Fondare una tradizione fiera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ακαδημία Ηνωμένης Πολεμικής Αεροπορίας: 
Ίδρυση μιας υπερήφανης παράδοσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Academia De la Fuerza aérea De Estados Unidos:
Fundación de una tradición orgullosa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts the history of aviation and the military: aviation's entry into the military during World War I, Germany's use of air power early in World War II, Pearl Harbor, the Berlin Airlift, Hiroshima and Nagasaki, and President Eisenhower's declaration that our first line of defense would be an air atomic strike force. The site examines the design of the Air Force Academy, authorized in 1954 after 30 years of struggle.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt die Geschichte von Luftfahrt und von 
Militär nach: Eintrag der Luftfahrt in das Militär während 
des Weltkrieg-, Deutschlandgebrauches von Luftmacht früh im Zweiten 
Weltkrieg, des Pearl Harbor, der Berlin Luftbrücke, Hiroschima und 
Nagasaki und Präsident Eisenhowers Erklärung, daß unsere erste 
Verteidigungslinie eine Luftatomschlagkraft sein würde. Die 
Site überprüft das Design der Luftwaffe Akademie, autorisiert 1954 
nach 30 Jahren Kampf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte l'histoire de l'aviation et des militaires
: l'entrée de l'aviation dans les militaires pendant 
l'utilisation de Première Guerre Mondiale, de l'Allemagne de la 
puissance de l'air tôt dans la deuxième guerre mondiale, le port de 
perle, la déclaration de transport aérien de Berlin, d'Hiroshima et 
de Nagasaki, et de Président Eisenhower's que notre première ligne 
de la défense serait une force atomique de grève d'air. Le 
site examine la conception de l'académie de l'Armée de l'Air, 
autorisée en 1954 après 30 ans de lutte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts o history da aviação e das forças 
armadas: entrada da aviação nas forças armadas durante o uso 
do world.war.i, do Germany da potência de ar cedo na segunda guerra 
mundial, o porto de pérola, a declaração do airlift de Berlim, do 
Hiroshima e do Nagasaki, e do presidente Eisenhower que nossa primeira
linha de defesa seria uma força atômica da batida do ar. O 
local examina o projeto do academy da força aérea, autorizado em 
1954 após 30 anos do esforço.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta la storia di aeronautica e dei militari: 
entrata dell'aeronautica nei militari durante uso della 
Germania, di world.war.i di potenza di aria presto nella seconda 
guerra mondiale, il porto di perla, la dichiarazione di airlift de 
Berlino, de Hiroshima e de Nagasaki e del presidente Eisenhower che la
nostra prima riga di difesa sarebbe una forza atomica di colpo 
dell'aria. Il luogo esamina il disegno dell'Accademia 
dell'aeronautica, autorizzato in 1954 dopo 30 anni di lotta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί την ιστορία της αεροπορίας και του 
στρατιωτικού: είσοδος αεροπορίας μέσα σε τους στρατιωτικούς
κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, της χρήσης της 
Γερμανίας της δύναμης αέρα νωρίς στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ, του 
λιμανιού μαργαριταριών, της αερογέφυρας του Βερολίνου, της 
Χιροσίμα και του Ναγκασάκι, και της δήλωσης Προέδρου Eisenhower
ότι η πρώτη γραμμή υπεράσπισής μας θα ήταν μια ατομική δύναμη 
απεργίας αέρα. Η περιοχή εξετάζει το σχέδιο της ακαδημίας 
Πολεμικής Αεροπορίας, που εγκρίνεται το 1954 μετά από 30 
έτη προσπάθειας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo la historia de la aviación y de 
los militares: entrada de la aviación en los militares durante 
el uso de la Primera Guerra Mundial, de Alemania de la potencia de 
aire temprano en la Segunda Guerra Mundial, el puerto de perla, el 
declaración del puente aéreo de Berlín, de Hiroshima y de Nagasaki,
y de presidente Eisenhower que nuestra primera línea de defensa 
sería una fuerza atómica de la huelga del aire. El sitio 
examina el diseño de la academia de la fuerza aérea, autorizado en 
1954 después de 30 años de lucha.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206463</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104313</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-united-states-air-force-academy-founding-a-proud-tradition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
