<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103066</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103066</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206072</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Centennial of Flight -- The Future of Flight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das hundertjährige des Fluges -- die Zukunft des 
Fluges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le centennal du vol -- le futur du vol</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O centennial do vôo -- o futuro do vôo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il centennale del volo -- il futuro del volo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο εκατονταετής της πτήσης -- το μέλλον της πτήσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El centenario del vuelo -- el futuro del vuelo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site is dedicated to the celebration of the 100th anniversary of the Wright Brothers' first powered flight and the development of aviation over the past century. It offers aerospace-related products and programs that help connect students and teachers to aeronautics and space flight.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site wird der Feier des 100. Jahrestages des 
ersten angeschalteten Fluges der Wright Brüder und der Entwicklung 
des Luftfahrtüberschusses das letzte Jahrhundert eingesetzt. 
Sie bietet Luftfahrt-in Verbindung stehende Produkte und 
Programme an, die helfen, Kursteilnehmer und Lehrer an Aeronautik- und
Platzflug anzuschließen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site est consacré à la célébration du 100th 
anniversaire vol actionné des frères de Wright du premier et du 
développement de l'excédent d'aviation le siècle passé. Il 
offre les produits aérospatial-connexes et les programmes qui aident 
à relier des étudiants et des professeurs à l'aéronautique et au 
vol spatial.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local é dedicado ao celebration do 100th 
anniversary do primeiro vôo powered dos irmãos de Wright e do 
desenvolvimento do excesso da aviação o século passado. 
Oferece os produtos aeroespacial-relacionados e os programas que
ajudam conectar estudantes e professores ao vôo da aeronáutica e de 
espaço.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo è dedicato alla celebrazione del 
100th anniversario del primo volo alimentato dei fratelli di Wright e 
dello sviluppo dell'eccedenza di aeronautica il secolo passato. 
Offre i prodotti aerospaziale-relativi ed i programmi che 
contribuiscono a collegare gli allievi e gli insegnanti 
all'aeronautica ed al volo spaziale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή αφιερώνεται στον εορτασμό της 100ής 
επετείου της πρώτης τροφοδοτημένης πτήσης των αδελφών Wright 
και της ανάπτυξης της αεροπορίας κατά τη διάρκεια του 
προηγούμενου αιώνα. Προσφέρει τα αεροδιαστημικός-σχετικά 
προϊόντα και τα προγράμματα που βοηθούν να συνδέσουν τους 
σπουδαστές και τους δασκάλους με την αεροναυτική και τη διαστημική
πτήση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio se dedica a la celebración del 100o 
aniversario del primer vuelo accionado de los hermanos de Wright y del
desarrollo del excedente de la aviación el último siglo. 
Ofrece los productos aeroespacial-relacionados y los programas 
que ayudan a conectar estudiantes y a profesores con la aeronáutica y
el vuelo espacial.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206072</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103066</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-centennial-of-flight-the-future-of-flight</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
