<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107885</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107885</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206196</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Environmental Literacy Council</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Klimabildungsgrad-Rat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Conseil Environnemental d'Instruction</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Conselho Ambiental Do Literacy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Consiglio Ambientale Di Literacy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το περιβαλλοντικό Συμβούλιο βασικής εκπαίδευσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Consejo Ambiental De la Instrucción</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features labs, projects, and activities for studying the air and climate, land, water, ecosystems, energy, food, and environment and society. Learn about the carbon cycle, forests, fossil fuels, nuclear energy, renewable energy, photosynthesis, soils, thermodynamics, waste management, water quality, weather, and more. Find out about legislation and treaties, resources in your state, and science in the news.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet Labors, Projekte und Aktivitäten 
für das Studieren der Luft und des Klimas, des Landes, des Wassers, 
der Oekosysteme, der Energie, der Nahrung und der Umgebung und der 
Gesellschaft. Erlernen Sie über die Carbonschleife, die 
Wälder, die Fossilbrennstoffe, die Atomenergie, die auswechselbare 
Energie, die Fotosynthese, den Boden, die Thermodynamik-, 
Abfallwirtschaft, die Wasserqualität, das Wetter und mehr. 
Finden Sie über Gesetzgebung und Verträge, Betriebsmittel in 
Ihrem Zustand und Wissenschaft in den Nachrichten heraus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte des laboratoires, des projets, et des 
activités pour étudier l'air et le climat, terre, eau, 
écosystèmes, énergie, nourriture, et environnement et société. 
Renseignez-vous sur le cycle de carbone, forêts, combustibles 
fossiles, énergie nucléaire, énergie renouvelable, photosynthèse, 
sols, thermodynamique, gestion des déchets, qualité de l'eau, 
survivez à, et plus. Découvrez au sujet de la 
législation et les traités, les ressources dans votre état, et la 
science dans les nouvelles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza laboratórios, projetos, e atividades 
para estudar o ar e o clima, terra, água, ecosystems, energia, 
alimento, e ambiente e sociedade. Aprenda sobre o ciclo de 
carbono, as florestas, os combustíveis fossil, a energia nuclear, a 
energia renewable, a fotossíntese, os solos, o thermodynamics, a 
gerência waste, a qualidade de água, o tempo, e o mais. 
Encontre para fora sobre a legislação e os tratados, os 
recursos em seu estado, e a ciência na notícia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza i laboratori, i progetti ed attività
per studiare l'aria ed il clima, terra, acqua, ecosistemi, energia, 
alimento ed ambiente e società. Impari circa il ciclo di 
carbonio, le foreste, i combustibili fossili, l'energia nucleare, 
l'energia rinnovabile, la fotosintesi, i terreni, la termodinamica, la
gestione dei rifiuti, la qualità dell'acqua, il tempo ed il più. 
Scopra circa legislazione ed i trattati, risorse in vostro 
dichiarano e la scienza nelle notizie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τα εργαστήρια, τα προγράμματα, και τις 
δραστηριότητες για τη μελέτη του αέρα και του κλίματος, του 
εδάφους, της ύδρευσης, των οικοσυστημάτων, της ενέργειας, των 
τροφίμων, και του περιβάλλοντος και της κοινωνίας. Μάθετε 
για τον κύκλο άνθρακα, τα δάση, τα απολιθωμένα καύσιμα, την 
πυρηνική ενέργεια, την ανανεώσιμη ενέργεια, τη φωτοσύνθεση, τα 
χώματα, τη θερμοδυναμική, τη διαχείριση των αποβλήτων, την 
ποιότητα νερού, τον καιρό, και περισσότερους. Ανακαλύψτε 
για τη νομοθεσία και τις συνθήκες, τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς στο 
κράτος σας, και την επιστήμη στις ειδήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece laboratorios, los proyectos, y las 
actividades para estudiar el aire y el clima, pista, agua, los 
ecosistemas, energía, alimento, y ambiente y sociedad. Aprenda 
sobre el ciclo de carbón, los bosques, los combustibles fósiles, la 
energía nuclear, la energía reanudable, la fotosíntesis, los 
suelos, la gestión del termodinámica, de desechos, la calidad del 
agua, el tiempo, y más. Descubra sobre la legislación y los 
tratados, los recursos en su estado, y ciencia en las noticias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206196</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107885</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/environmental-literacy-council</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
