<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212938</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">US Historical Climate: Excel Statistical</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">US Historisches Klima: Übertreffen Sie 
Statistisches</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Climat Historique des USA : Excelez 
Statistique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Clima Histórico dos E. U.: Excel 
Estatístico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Clima Storico degli Stati Uniti: Eccella 
Statistico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικό ιστορικό κλίμα: Θ*Εξθελ στατιστικό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Clima Histórico de los E.E.U.U.: Sobresalga
Estadístico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this intermediate Excel activity, students import US Historical Climate Network mean temperature data into Excel from a station of their choice. They are then guided through the activity on how to use Excel for statistical calculations, graphing, and linear trend estimates. The activity assumes some familiarity with Excel. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem Vermittler übertreffen Sie Aktivität, 
Kursteilnehmerimport US, die historische 
Klima-Netzmittel-Temperaturdaten in von einer Station ihrer Wahl 
übertreffen. Sie werden dann durch die Aktivität geführt auf,
wie man übertreffen für statistische Berechnungen, die graphischee 
Darstellung und die linearen Tendenzschätzungen verwendet. Die 
Aktivität nimmt an, daß etwas Vertrautheit mit übertreffen Sie. 
Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen
über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette intermédiaire excelez l'activité, 
l'importation USA d'étudiants les données qu'historiques de la 
température de moyen de réseau de climat dans excellent d'une 
station de leur choix. Elles sont alors guidées par l'activité
sur la façon dont utiliser excellent pour des calculs statistiques, 
le graphique, et des évaluations linéaires de tendance. 
L'activité suppose que de la connaissance de excelez. À 
cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux 
informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les 
extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste intermediário excel a atividade, 
importação E. U. que dos estudantes os dados históricos da 
temperatura do meio da rede do clima em excel de uma estação de sua 
escolha. São guiados então com a atividade em como usar-se 
excel para cálculos estatísticos, representar graficamente, e 
estimativas lineares da tendência. A atividade supõe que 
alguma familiaridade com excel. Nesta página do ponto começar,
os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de 
aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as
notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as 
referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo intermediario eccella l'attività, 
l'importazione Stati Uniti che degli allievi i dati storici di 
temperatura di media della rete di clima in eccellono da una stazione 
della loro scelta. Allora sono guidati con l'attività su come 
usare eccellono per i calcoli statistici, rappresentare graficamente e
le valutazioni lineari di tendenza. L'attività presuppone che 
una certa familiarità con eccella. A questa pagina del punto di
partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sugli 
obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di 
istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le idee di 
valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την ενδιάμεση δραστηριότητα Excel, δίκτυο 
αμερικανικού το ιστορικό κλίματος εισαγωγών σπουδαστών σημαίνει 
τα στοιχεία θερμοκρασίας σε Excel από έναν σταθμό της 
επιλογής τους. Καθοδηγούνται έπειτα μέσω της δραστηριότητας
στο πώς να χρησιμοποιήσουν Excel για τους στατιστικούς 
υπολογισμούς, να δώσουν με γραφική παράσταση, και τις γραμμικές 
εκτιμήσεις τάσης. Η δραστηριότητα υποθέτει κάποια 
οικειότητα με Excel. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι 
χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους 
στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις 
σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις 
ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En este intermedio sobresalga la actividad, 
importación los E.E.U.U. de los estudiantes que los datos históricos
de la temperatura del medio de la red del clima en sobresalen de una 
estación de su opción. Entonces se dirigen con la actividad en
cómo utilizar sobresalen para los cálculos estadísticos, 
representar gra'ficamente, y las estimaciones lineares de la 
tendencia. La actividad asume que una cierta familiaridad con 
sobresalga. En esta paginación del punto de partida, los 
utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre las metas que
aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la 
enseñanza las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las ideas del 
gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:R. MACKAY
FN:R. MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212938</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104990</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/us-historical-climate-excel-statistical</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
