<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108719</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108719</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205836</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Summer Workshops</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sommer-Werkstätten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ateliers D'Été</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Oficinas Do Verão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gruppi di lavoro Di Estate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θερινά εργαστήρια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Talleres Del Verano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides materials from dozens of teacher presentations on literacy, math, science, history, and the arts at the U.S. Department of Education's Teacher-to-Teacher Summer Workshops. Topics include reading, writing, English language learners, Chinese language and culture, algebra, computation, data, geometry, peer teaching, earth systems, cells, physical science, labs, science mysteries, historical literacy, arts and reading, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Materialien von den Dutzenden 
Lehrerdarstellungen auf Bildungsgrad, Mathe, Wissenschaft, Geschichte 
und den künsten am VEREINIGTE STAATEN Ministerium für Erziehung und 
Wissenschaft Sommer-Werkstätten Lehrer-zu-Lehrer zur Verfügung. 
Themen schließen Messwert, Schreiben, englische 
Sprachenanfänger, chinesische Sprache und Kultur, Algebra, 
Übertragen auf Lochkarten, Daten, Geometrie, Gleichunterricht, Masse 
Systeme, Zellen, körperliche Wissenschaft, Labors, Wissenschaft 
Geheimnisse, historischer Bildungsgrad, künste und Messwert und mehr 
ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des matériaux des douzaines de 
présentations de professeur sur l'instruction, les maths, la science,
l'histoire, et les arts au service des ETATS-UNIS des ateliers d'été
du Professeur-à-Professeur d'éducation. Les sujets incluent la
lecture, l'écriture, les étudiants d'anglais, la langue et la 
culture chinoise, l'algèbre, le calcul, les données, la géométrie,
l'enseignement de pair, les systèmes de la terre, les cellules, la 
science physique, les laboratoires, les mystères de la science, 
l'instruction historique, les arts et la lecture, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece materiais das dúzias de apresentações 
do professor no literacy, no math, na ciência, no history, e nas 
artes no departamento de ESTADOS UNIDOS de oficinas do verão do 
Professor-à-Professor de instrução. Os tópicos incluem a 
leitura, a escrita, os learners de língua inglesa, língua e cultura 
chinesa, álgebra, computação, dados, geometria, ensino do par, 
sistemas da terra, pilhas, ciência física, laboratórios, mistérios
da ciência, literacy histórico, artes e leitura, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce i materiali dalle dozzine delle 
presentazioni dell'insegnante su literacy, su per la matematica, sulla
scienza, sulla storia e sulle arti al reparto degli STATI UNITI dei 
gruppi di lavoro di estate dell'Insegnante-$$$-Insegnante della 
formazione. I soggetti includono la lettura, scrittura, studenti
di lingue inglesi, linguaggio cinese e coltura, algebra, calcolo, 
dati, la geometria, insegnamento del pari, sistemi della terra, 
cellule, la scienza fisica, laboratori, misteri di scienza, literacy 
storico, le arti e lettura e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα υλικά από τις δωδεκάδες των παρουσιάσεων 
δασκάλων για τη βασική εκπαίδευση, math, την επιστήμη, την 
ιστορία, και τις τέχνες στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ τμήμα θερινών εργαστηρίων
δάσκαλος-$$$-ΔΑΣΚΑΛΩΝ της εκπαίδευσης. Τα θέματα 
περιλαμβάνουν γλωσσικοί αρχάριοι ανάγνωσης, γραψίματος, αγγλικά,
κινεζικός γλώσσα και πολιτισμός, άλγεβρα, υπολογισμός, στοιχεία,
γεωμετρία, όμοια διδασκαλία, γήινα συστήματα, κύτταρα, φυσική 
επιστήμη, εργαστήρια, μυστήρια επιστήμης, ιστορική βασική 
εκπαίδευση, τέχνες και ανάγνωση, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a los materiales de docenas de 
presentaciones del profesor en la instrucción, la matemáticas, la 
ciencia, la historia, y los artes en el departamento de ESTADOS UNIDOS
de los talleres del verano del Profesor-a-Profesor de la educación. 
Los asuntos incluyen la lectura, escritura, los principiantes de
lenguaje inglés, lenguaje y cultura china, álgebra, cómputo, los 
datos, geometría, enseñanza del par, los sistemas de la tierra, las 
células, ciencia física, los laboratorios, los misterios de la 
ciencia, instrucción histórica, los artes y lectura, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205836</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108719</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/summer-workshops</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
