<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105612</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105612</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086356</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Will Require Much Time to Model the Manners and Morals of these Wild Peoples": Charles Woodmason Visits the Carolina Backcountry, 1768</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es benötigt viel Zeit, die Weise und die Moral 
dieser wilden Völker zu formen": Charles Woodmason besichtigt 
das Carolina Backcountry, 1768</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"elle aura besoin de beaucoup de temps pour 
modeler les façons et les morales de ces peuples sauvages" : 
Charles Woodmason visite la Caroline Backcountry, 1768</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"requererá muito tempo para modelar as maneiras e
as morais destes povos selvagens": Charles Woodmason visita o 
Carolina Backcountry, 1768</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"richiederà molto tempo di modellare i modi e le 
morali di questa gente selvaggia": Charles Woodmason visita la 
Carolina Backcountry, 1768</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Θα απαιτήσει πολύ χρόνο να διαμορφωθούν οι τρόποι 
και τα ήθη αυτών των άγριων λαών": Θ*Θχαρλες Woodmason 
Visits η Καρολίνα Backcountry, 1768</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"requerirá mucho tiempo para modelar las maneras 
y las moralejas de esta gente salvaje": Charles Woodmason visita
la Carolina Backcountry, 1768</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Charles Woodmason, a newly ordained Anglican minister, left the comforts of Charleston, South Carolina, in 1761 to travel for six years in the Carolina backcountry as an itinerant minister, seeking to bring the established church to areas where it had not taken hold. He also became a fierce partisan of the Regulator movement, a frontier rebellion attempting to obtain a greater voice and fairer claims for backcountry residents who resented the monopolization of power by the coastal leaders. Although Woodmason was hostile toward the colony's elite for their lack of concern over the political and especially religious life of the frontier, the British migrant held traditional beliefs about morality and social order. He was appalled by the immoral and irreligious behavior rampant on the frontier, as he made clear in this selection from his journal of 1768.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Charles Woodmason, ein eben ordinierter 
anglikanischer Minister, überließ dem Komfort von Charleston, 
Südcarolina, 1761 den Spielraum für sechs Jahre im Carolina, das als
reisender Minister backcountry ist und suchte, die hergestellte Kirche
zu den Bereichen zu holen, in denen sie nicht Einfluß genommen hatte.
Er wurde auch ein heftiger Parteigänger der Reglerbewegung, ein
Grenzaufstand, der versucht, eine grössere Stimme und angemessenere 
Ansprüche für backcountry Bewohner zu erreichen, die das 
monopolization der Energie durch die Küstenführer übelnahmen. 
Obgleich Woodmason in Richtung zur Auslese der Kolonie für 
ihren Mangel an Interesse über dem politischen und besonders der 
frommen Lebensdauer der Grenze, des britischen Wander- angehaltenen 
traditionellen Glaubens über Sittlichkeitsgefühl und der 
Sozialordnung feindlich war. Er wurde durch das unmoralische und
irreligious Verhalten entsetzt, das auf der Grenze zügellos ist, da 
er klar in dieser Auswahl von seinem Journal von 1768 bildete.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Charles Woodmason, un ministre Anglican 
nouvellement ordonné, a laissé les conforts de Charleston, Caroline 
Du sud, en 1761 au voyage pendant six années en Caroline 
backcountry en tant que ministre ambulant, recherchant à apporter 
l'église établie aux zones où elle n'avait pas pris la prise. 
Il est également devenu un partisan féroce du mouvement de 
régulateur, une rébellion de frontière essayant d'obtenir une plus 
grande voix et des réclamations plus justes pour les résidants 
backcountry qui étaient offensés par le monopolization de la 
puissance par les amorces côtières. Bien que Woodmason ait 
été hostile vers l'élite de la colonie par leur manque de souci au 
cours du politique et particulièrement de la vie religieuse de la 
frontière, de la croyance traditionnelle jugée migratrice 
britannique concernant la moralité et de la commande sociale. 
Il appalled par le comportement immoral et irréligieux 
effréné sur la frontière, car il a fait clairement dans cette 
sélection à partir de son journal de 1768.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Charles Woodmason, um ministro anglican 
recentemente ordained, deixou os confortos de Charleston, carolina 
sul, em 1761 ao curso por seis anos no Carolina backcountry como um 
ministro itinerant, procurando trazer a igreja estabelecida às áreas
onde não tinha feito exame da preensão. Transformou-se também
um partisan feroz do movimento do regulador, uma rebelião da 
fronteira que tenta obter uma voz mais grande e umas reivindicações 
mais justas para os residentes backcountry que se ressentiram pelo 
monopolization da potência pelos líderes litorais. Embora 
Woodmason fosse hostil para o elite da colônia para sua falta do 
interesse sobre o político e especial a vida religiosa da fronteira, 
da opinião tradicional prendida emigrante britânica sobre o morality
e da ordem social. Appalled pelo comportamento immoral e 
irreligious rampant na fronteira, porque fêz claramente nesta 
seleção de seu jornal de 1768.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Charles Woodmason, un ministro anglican 
recentemente ordained, ha lasciato le comodità di Charleston, 
Carolina del Sud, in 1761 alla corsa per sei anni in Carolina 
backcountry come ministro ambulante, cercante di portare la chiesa 
stabilita alle zone dove non aveva preso la stretta. Egualmente 
è diventato un partigiano feroce del movimento del regolatore, una 
ribellione di frontiera che tenta di ottenere una voce più grande ed
i reclami più giusti per i residenti backcountry che si sono 
risentiti del monopolization di potenza dai capi litoranei. 
Anche se Woodmason era ostile verso l'elite della colonia per la
loro mancanza di preoccupazione sopra il politico e particolarmente la
durata religiosa della frontiera, della credenza tradizionale tenuta 
migratore britannica circa la moralità e dell'ordine sociale. 
Appalled tramite il comportamento immorale ed irreligious 
sfrenato sulla frontiera, poichè ha fatto chiaramente in questa 
selezione dal suo giornale di 1768.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Θχαρλες Woodmason, ένας πρόσφατα ορισμένος 
αγγλικανικός υπουργός, άφησε τις ανέσεις του Τσάρλεστον, νότια 
Καρολίνα, το 1761 στο ταξίδι για έξι έτη στην Καρολίνα 
backcountry ως πλανόδιο υπουργό, που επιδιώκει να φέρει την 
καθιερωμένη εκκλησία στις περιοχές όπου δεν είχε πάρει τη λαβή.
Έγινε επίσης άγριος παρτιζάνος της μετακίνησης ρυθμιστών, 
μια συνοριακή εξέγερση που προσπαθεί να λάβει μια μεγαλύτερη 
φωνή και δικαιότερες αξιώσεις για τους backcountry κατοίκους 
που αγανάκτησαν με το monopolization της δύναμης από τους 
παράκτιους ηγέτες. Αν και Woodmason ήταν εχθρικό προς την
ελίτ της αποικίας για την έλλειψη ανησυχίας τους κατά τη 
διάρκεια της πολιτικής και ιδιαίτερα θρησκευτικής ζωής των 
συνόρων, οι βρετανικές αποδημητικές κρατημένες παραδοσιακές 
πεποιθήσεις για την ηθική και την κοινωνική τάξη. Ήταν από
την ανήθικη και άθρησκη συμπεριφορά ασυγκράτητη στα σύνορα, 
δεδομένου ότι κατάστησε σαφές σε αυτήν την επιλογή από το 
περιοδικό του 1768.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Charles Woodmason, ministro anglican nuevamente 
ordained, dejó las comodidades de Charleston, Carolina del Sur, en 
1761 al recorrido por seis años en la Carolina backcountry como 
ministro ambulante, intentando traer la iglesia establecida a las 
áreas donde no se había arraigado. Él también hizo un 
partidario feroz del movimiento del regulador, una rebelión de la 
frontera que procuraba obtener una mayor voz y demandas más justas 
para los residentes backcountry que se resentían el monopolization de
la potencia de los arranques de cinta costeros. Aunque Woodmason
era hostil hacia la élite de la colonia para su carencia de la 
preocupación por el político y especialmente la vida religiosa de la
frontera, de la creencia tradicional llevada a cabo migratoria 
británica por moralidad y de la orden social. Él era 
aterrado por el comportamiento inmoral e irreligioso desenfrenado en
la frontera, pues él hizo claramente en esta selección de su diario 
de 1768.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086356</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105612</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-will-require-much-time-to-model-the-manners-and-morals-of-these-wild-peoples-charles-woodmason-visits-the-carolina-backcountry-1768</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
