<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104679</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086154</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fibber McGee and Molly on Mileage Rationing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwindlerin McGee und Molly auf dem 
Meilenzahl-Rationieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Menteuse McGee et molly sur le rationnement de 
kilomètrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fibber McGee e molly em racionar da milhagem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fibber McGee e molly sul razionamento di distanza 
in miglia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Fibber McGee και Molly στη διανομή με δελτίο 
απόστασης σε μίλια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fibber McGee y molly en racionar del kilometraje</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The productive capacity of the United States during World War II surpassed all expectations. To boost that production and maintain supply levels for troops abroad, Americans at home were asked to conserve materials and to accept ration coupons or stamps that limited the purchase of certain products. Gasoline, rubber, sugar, butter, and some kinds of cloth were among the many items rationed. American responses to rationing varied from cheerful compliance to resigned grumbling to instances of black market subversion and profiteering. The drive to increase wartime production extended beyond rationing. Government-sponsored posters, ads, radio shows, and pamphlet campaigns urged Americans to contribute to scrap drives and accept rationing without complaint. A segment of the popular radio series  Fibber McGee and Molly  had Fibber shouldering his patriotic duty.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Produktionspotential der Vereinigten Staaten 
während des Zweiten Weltkrieges übertraf alle Erwartungen. Um 
diese Produktion aufzuladen und Zubehörstufen für Truppen auswärts 
beizubehalten, wurden Amerikaner zu Hause Materialien zu konservieren 
gebeten und Zuteilungkupons oder -stempel anzunehmen die den Erwerb 
bestimmter Produkte begrenzten. Benzin, Gummi, Zucker, Butter 
und einige Arten Tuch gehörten zu den vielen rationierten 
Einzelteilen. Amerikanische Antworten zum Rationieren schwankten
von der freundlichen Befolgung zum abgefundenen Murren zu den Fällen 
der Schwarzmarkt Subversion und des Profiteering. Das Laufwerk, 
zum von von Kriegproduktion zu erhöhen dehnte sich über dem 
Rationieren hinaus aus. Staatlich geförderte Plakate, ADS, 
Radioerscheinen und Flugschriftkampagnen drängten Amerikaner, zu den 
Schrottlaufwerken beizutragen und das Rationieren ohne Beanstandung 
anzunehmen. Ein Segment des populären Radioserie Schwindlerin 
McGee und des Molly hatte Schwindlerin, seine patriotische Aufgabe zu 
schultern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La capacité productive des Etats-Unis pendant la 
deuxième guerre mondiale a surpassé toutes les espérances. 
Pour amplifier cette production et mettre à jour des niveaux 
d'approvisionnement pour des troupes à l'étranger, des Américains 
à la maison ont été invités à économiser des matériaux et à 
recevoir les bons ou les timbres de ration qui ont limité l'achat de 
certains produits. L'essence, le caoutchouc, le sucre, le 
beurre, et quelques genres de tissu étaient parmi les nombreux 
éléments rationnés. Les réponses américaines au 
rationnement ont changé de la conformité gaie au maugrément 
démissionné aux exemples de la subversion et du mercantilisme de 
marché noir. Le lecteur pour augmenter la production de temps 
de guerre a étendu au delà du rationnement. Les affiches 
commanditées par le gouvernement, l'ADS, les expositions de radio, et
les campagnes de brochure ont invité des Américains à contribuer 
aux lecteurs de chute et à recevoir le rationnement sans plainte. 
Un segment de la menteuse par radio populaire McGee de série et
de molly a eu la menteuse épauler son devoir patriotique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A capacidade produtiva dos estados unidos durante 
a segunda guerra mundial surpassed todas as expectativas. Para 
impulsionar essa produção e para manter no exterior níveis da fonte
para tropas, os americanos na HOME foram pedidos para conservar 
materiais e para aceitar os coupons ou os selos da ração que 
limitaram a compra de determinados produtos. A gasolina, a 
borracha, o açúcar, a manteiga, e alguns tipos do pano eram entre 
muitos artigos racionados. As respostas americanas a racionar 
variaram da conformidade cheerful a grumbling renunciado aos exemplos 
do subversion e do profiteering do mercado preto. A 
movimentação para aumentar a produção do wartime estendeu além de
racionar. Os posteres government-sponsored, o ads, as mostras do
rádio, e as campanhas do panfleto incitaram americanos contribuir às
movimentações da sucata e aceitar racionar sem queixa. Um 
segmento do fibber de rádio popular McGee da série e do molly teve o
fibber empurrar seu dever patriotic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La capienza produttiva del unito Dichiara 
durante la seconda guerra mondiale sorpassava tutte le aspettative. 
Per amplificare quella produzione e per effettuare i livelli del
rifornimento per le truppe all'estero, gli Americani nel paese sono 
stati chiesti di conservare i materiali e di accettare i buoni o i 
bolli della razione che hanno limitato l'acquisto di determinati 
prodotti. La benzina, la gomma, lo zucchero, il burro ed alcuni 
generi di panno erano fra i molti articoli razionati. Le 
risposte americane al razionamento hanno variato da conformità 
cheerful a grumbling dimesso ai casi della sovversione e 
dell'affarismo del mercato nero. L'azionamento per aumentare la 
produzione di wartime si è esteso oltre razionare. I manifesti 
government-sponsored, il ads, le esposizioni della radio e le campagne
dell'opuscolo hanno invitato gli Americani a contribuire agli 
azionamenti dello scarto ed ad accettare il razionamento senza 
reclamo. Un segmento del fibber radiofonico popolare McGee di 
serie e del molly ha avuto fibber mettere il suo dovere sulle spalle 
patriotic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παραγωγική ικανότητα των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών κατά τη 
διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ ξεπέρασε όλες τις προσδοκίες.
Για να ωθήσει ότι η παραγωγή και διατηρεί τα επίπεδα 
ανεφοδιασμού για τα στρατεύματα στο εξωτερικό, Αμερικανοί στο 
σπίτι κλήθηκαν να συντηρήσουν τα υλικά και να αποδεχθούν τα 
δελτία ή τα γραμματόσημα δελτίων τροφίμων που περιόρισαν την 
αγορά ορισμένων προϊόντων. Η βενζίνη, το λάστιχο, η 
ζάχαρη, το βούτυρο, και μερικά είδη υφάσματος ήταν μεταξύ των 
πολλών αντικειμένων που διανεμήθηκαν. Αμερικανικές 
απαντήσεις στη διανομή με δελτίο που ποικίλλεται από την εύθυμη 
συμμόρφωση στην παραιτημένη από γκρίνια στις περιπτώσεις μαύρα 
ανατροπής και profiteering αγοράς. Η κίνηση στην εν καιρώ
πολέμου παραγωγή αύξησης επεκτάθηκε πέρα από τη διανομή με 
δελτίο. Οι χρηματοδοτούμενες από την κυβέρνηση αφίσες, 
αγγελίες, ραδιόφωνο εμφανίζουν, και τεύχος ωθημένοι εκστρατείες 
Αμερικανοί για να συμβάλουν στις κινήσεις απορρίματος και να 
γίνει αποδεκτή η διανομή με δελτίο χωρίς καταγγελία. Ένα 
τμήμα μνήμης δημοφιλής ραδιο fibber McGee και Molly 
σειράς είχε fibber που επωμίζεται το πατριωτικό καθήκον του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La capacidad productiva de los Estados Unidos 
durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial sobrepasó todas las expectativas. 
Para alzar esa producción y para mantener los niveles de la 
fuente para las tropas al exterior, pidieron los americanos en el 
país conservar los materiales y validar las cupones o los sellos de 
la ración que limitaron la compra de ciertos productos. La 
gasolina, el caucho, el azúcar, la mantequilla, y algunas clases de 
paño estaban entre los muchos items racionados. Las respuestas 
americanas a racionar variaron de conformidad alegre a quejarse 
dimitido a los casos de la subversión y del mercantilismo del mercado
negro. El mecanismo impulsor para aumentar la producción del 
tiempo de guerra extendió más allá de racionar. Los carteles 
government-sponsored, el ads, las demostraciones de la radio, y las 
campañas del folleto impulsaron a americanos contribuir a los 
mecanismos impulsores del desecho y validar racionar sin queja. 
Un segmento del fibber de radio popular McGee de la serie y del 
molly tenía fibber el llevar a hombros de su deber patriótico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086154</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104679</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/fibber-mcgee-and-molly-on-mileage-rationing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
