<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105956</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105956</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087718</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Visual Understanding Environment (VUE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verstehende Sichtumgebung (VUE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Environnement Visuel d'Arrangement (VUE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ambiente Compreensivo Visual (VUE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ambiente Capente Visivo (VUE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οπτικό καταλαβαίνοντας περιβάλλον (VUE)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ambiente Que entiende Visual (VUE)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Visual Understanding Environment (VUE) project at Tufts UIT Academic Technology is focused on creating flexible tools for integrating digital resources into teaching and learning. VUE provides a visual environment for structuring, presenting, and sharing digital information. Using VUE's concept mapping interface, faculty and students design semantic networks of digital resources drawn from digital libraries, local and remote file systems and the Web. The resulting content maps can then be viewed and exchanged online.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das verstehende Umgebung (VUE) Sichtprojekt 
akademischen der Technologie an der Büschel-UIT wird auf das 
Herstellen der flexiblen Hilfsmittel für die Integrierung der 
digitalen Betriebsmittel in das Unterrichten und in das Lernen 
gerichtet. VUE stellt eine Sichtumgebung für die 
Strukturierung, das Darstellen und das Teilen der numerischen 
Information zur Verfügung. Mit dem Konzept VUEs, das 
Schnittstelle abbildet, konzipieren Lehrkörper und Kursteilnehmer 
semantische Netze der digitalen Betriebsmittel, die von den digitalen 
Bibliotheken, lokale und Remotedateisysteme und das Web gezeichnet 
werden. Die resultierenden zufriedenen Karten können dann 
angesehen werden undWAREN online wert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le projet visuel de l'environnement d'Arrangement 
(VUE) à la technologie d'Universitaire des touffes UIT est concentré 
sur créer les outils flexibles pour intégrer les ressources 
digitales dans l'enseignement et l'étude. VUE fournit un 
environnement visuel pour structurer, présenter, et partager 
l'information digitale. En utilisant le concept de VUE traçant 
l'interface, le corps enseignant et les étudiants conçoivent les 
réseaux sémantiques des ressources digitales tirées des 
bibliothèques digitales, les systèmes de fichiers locaux et à 
distance et le Web. Les cartes contentes résultantes 
peuvent alors être visualisées et ont permuté en ligne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O projeto compreensivo visual do ambiente (VUE) na
tecnologia academic dos topetes UIT é focalizado em criar ferramentas
flexíveis para integrar recursos digitais em ensinar e na aprender. 
VUE fornece um ambiente visual estruturando, apresentando, e 
compartilhando da informação digital. Usando o conceito de VUE
que traça a relação, a faculdade e os estudantes projetam redes 
semânticas dos recursos digitais desenhados das bibliotecas digitais,
sistemas de lima locais e remotos e o Web. Os mapas satisfeitos 
resultantes podem então ser vistos e trocaram em linha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il progetto capente visivo dell'ambiente (VUE) a 
tecnologia Accademica dei trapuntare UIT è messo a fuoco sulla 
creazione degli strumenti flessibili per l'integrata delle risorse 
digitali nell'istruzione e nell'imparare. VUE fornisce un 
ambiente visivo per la struttura, presentare e la compartecipazione 
delle informazioni digitali. Usando il concetto del VUE che 
traccia l'interfaccia, la facoltà e gli allievi progettano le reti 
semantiche delle risorse digitali dissipate dalle librerie digitali, 
sistemi di archivio locali ed a distanza ed il Web. I programmi 
soddisfatti risultanti possono allora essere osservati ed hanno 
scambiato in linea.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το οπτικό πρόγραμμα περιβάλλοντος κατανόησης (VUE) 
στην ακαδημαϊκή τεχνολογία τουφών UIT στρέφεται στη 
δημιουργία των εύκαμπτων εργαλείων για τα ψηφιακά στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς στη διδασκαλία και την εκμάθηση. Το VUE 
παρέχει ένα οπτικό περιβάλλον για τη δόμηση, την παρουσίαση, και
τη διανομή των ψηφιακών πληροφοριών. Χρησιμοποιώντας τη 
διαπροσωπεία χαρτογράφησης έννοιας του VUE, η σχολή και οι 
σπουδαστές σχεδιάζουν τα σημασιολογικά δίκτυα των ψηφιακών 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς που προέρχονται από τις ψηφιακές 
βιβλιοθήκες, τα τοπικά και απομακρυσμένα συστήματα αρχείων και 
τον Ιστό. Οι προκύπτοντες ικανοποιημένοι χάρτες μπορούν 
έπειτα να εμφανιστούν και αντάλλαξαν on-line.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El proyecto visual del ambiente que entiende (VUE)
en la tecnología académica de los penachos UIT se centra en crear 
las herramientas flexibles para integrar recursos digitales en la 
enseñanza y aprender. VUE proporciona a un ambiente visual para
estructurar, presentar, y compartir la información digital. 
Usando el concepto de VUE que asocia el interfaz, la facultad y 
los estudiantes diseñan las redes semánticas de los recursos 
digitales trazados de bibliotecas digitales, los sistemas de ficheros 
locales y alejados y el Web. Las correspondencias 
contentas que resultan se pueden entonces ver e intercambiaron en 
línea.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TUFTS UNIVERSITY
FN:TUFTS UNIVERSITY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087718</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105956</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/visual-understanding-environment-vue</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
