<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104195</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104195</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205996</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Library of Virtual Manipulatives</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale Bibliothek von virtuellem Manipulatives</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bibliothèque nationale de Manipulatives virtuel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biblioteca nacional de Manipulatives virtual</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Libreria nazionale di Manipulatives virtuale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική βιβλιοθήκη εικονικού Manipulatives</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biblioteca nacional de Manipulatives virtual</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides interactive online math lessons, activities, and assessments. Topics include fractions, functions, geometric transformations, integer arithmetic, patterns and sequences, probability, right triangle trigonometry, slope, triangle geometry, and writing equations of lines. Calculate what an excavation company should charge for digging a hole. Analyze three pollution reduction plans. Determine the best rate for repaying a loan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt interaktive Onlinemathelektionen, 
-aktivitäten und -einschätzungen zur Verfügung. Themen 
enthalten Brüche, Funktionen, geometrische Transformationen, Ganzzahl
Arithmetik, Muster und Reihenfolgen, Wahrscheinlichkeit, rechte 
Dreiecktrigonometrie, Steigung, Dreieckgeometrie und Schreiben 
Gleichungen der Zeilen. Errechnen Sie, was eine Aushöhlungfirma
für das Graben einer Bohrung aufladen sollte. Analysieren Sie 
drei Verunreinigung Verkleinerung Pläne. Stellen Sie die beste 
Kinetik für das Zurückerstatten eines Darlehens fest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons, des activités, et des 
évaluations en ligne interactives de maths. Les sujets incluent
des fractions, des fonctions, des transformations géométriques, 
arithmétique de nombre entier, des configurations et des ordres, 
probabilité, bonne trigonométrie de triangle, pente, géométrie de 
triangle, et des équations d'écriture des lignes. Calculez ce 
qu'une compagnie d'excavation devrait facturer creuser un trou. 
Analysez trois plans de réduction de pollution. 
Déterminez la meilleure cadence pour rembourser un prêt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece lições, atividades, e avaliações em 
linha interativas do math. Os tópicos incluem frações, 
funções, transformações geométricas, aritmética do inteiro, 
testes padrões e seqüências, probabilidade, trigonometry direito do
triângulo, inclinação, geometria do triângulo, e equações da 
escrita das linhas. Calcule o que uma companhia da escavação 
deve carregar para escavar um furo. Analise três plantas da 
redução da poluição. Determine a mais melhor taxa para 
reembolsar um empréstimo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni, le attività e le valutazioni
in linea interattive di per la matematica. I soggetti includono 
le frazioni, funzioni, trasformazioni geometriche, aritmetica di 
numero intero, modelli e sequenze, probabilità, la giusta 
trigonometria del triangolo, pendio, la geometria del triangolo ed 
equazioni di scrittura delle righe. Calcoli che cosa un'azienda 
dello scavo dovrebbe addebitare la scavatura del foro. Analizzi 
tre programmi di riduzione di inquinamento. Determini il tasso 
migliore per il rimborso del prestito.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα διαλογικά σε απευθείας σύνδεση μαθήματα, 
τις δραστηριότητες, και τις αξιολογήσεις του math. Τα 
θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τα μέρη, τις λειτουργίες, τους γεωμετρικούς 
μετασχηματισμούς, την αριθμητική ακέραιων αριθμών, τα πρότυπα και
τις ακολουθίες, την πιθανότητα, σωστό trigonometry τριγώνων, 
την κλίση, τη γεωμετρία τριγώνων, και τις εξισώσεις γραψίματος 
των γραμμών. Υπολογίστε τι μια επιχείρηση ανασκαφής πρέπει 
να χρεώσει για το σκάψιμο μιας τρύπας. Αναλύστε τρία 
σχέδια μείωσης ρύπανσης. Καθορίστε το καλύτερο ποσοστό για
ένα δάνειο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a lecciones, a actividades, y a 
gravámenes en línea interactivos de la matemáticas. Los 
asuntos incluyen fracciones, las funciones, las transformaciones 
geométricas, aritmética del número entero, los modelos y las 
secuencias, probabilidad, trigonometría derecha del triángulo, 
cuesta, geometría del triángulo, y las ecuaciones de la escritura de
líneas. Calcule lo que debe cargar una compañía de la 
excavación para cavar un agujero. Analice tres planes de la 
reducción de la contaminación. Determine la mejor tarifa para 
compensar un préstamo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205996</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104195</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-library-of-virtual-manipulatives</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
