<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206407</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The U.S. Recognition of the State of Israel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Anerkennung des Zustandes 
von Israel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'identification des ETATS-UNIS de l'état de 
l'Israel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O recognition de ESTADOS UNIDOS do estado de 
Israel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il riconoscimento degli STATI UNITI del Dichiarare
dell'Israele</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ αναγνώριση του κράτους του Ισραήλ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El reconocimiento de ESTADOS UNIDOS del estado de 
Israel</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a lesson plan on the history, conflicts, and U.S. involvement surrounding Israel before and after its proclamation of statehood. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Social Sciences. It also has cross-curricular connections with history, government, geography, and language arts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Lektionplan auf der Geschichte, den 
$überschneidungen und DER VEREINIGTE STAATEN Miteinbeziehung, die 
vorher und nachher Israel seine Proklamation der Eigenstaatlichkeit 
umgibt. Diese Lektion bezieht mit den nationalen Geschichte 
Standards und den nationalen Standards für Sozialwissenschaften 
aufeinander. Sie hat auch Kreuzlehrplananschlüsse mit 
Geschichte, Regierung, Geographie und Sprachenkünsten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un plan de leçon sur l'histoire, les 
conflits, et l'intervention des ETATS-UNIS entourant l'Israel 
avant et après sa proclamation de statehood. Cette leçon se 
corrèle avec les normes nationales d'histoire et les normes 
nationales pour les sciences sociales. Elle a également les 
connexions croix-curriculaires avec l'histoire, le gouvernement, la 
géographie, et les arts de langage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma planta da lição no history, nos 
conflitos, e na participação de ESTADOS UNIDOS que cerca Israel 
before.and.after seu proclamation do statehood. Esta lição 
correlaciona aos padrões nacionais do history e aos padrões 
nacionais para ciências sociais. Tem também conexões 
cruz-cross-curricular com o history, o governo, a geografia, e as 
artes da língua.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un programma di lezione sulla storia, sui 
conflitti e sulla partecipazione degli STATI UNITI che circonda 
l'Israele prima e dopo la relativa proclamazione dello statehood. 
Questa lezione correla agli standard nazionali di storia ed agli
standard nazionali per le scienze sociali. Egualmente ha 
collegamenti traversa-d'insegnamento con storia, il governo, la 
geografia e le arti di linguaggio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα σχέδιο μαθήματος για την ιστορία, τις 
συγκρούσεις, και την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ συμμετοχή που περιβάλλει το 
Ισραήλ πριν και μετά από την προκήρυξη statehood του. 
Αυτό το μάθημα συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας και 
τα εθνικά πρότυπα για τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες. Έχει 
επίσης τις διαγώνιος-διδακτικές συνδέσεις με την ιστορία, την 
κυβέρνηση, τη γεωγραφία, και τις γλωσσικές τέχνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un plan de la lección en la historia, los 
conflictos, y la implicación de ESTADOS UNIDOS que rodea Israel antes
y después su proclamación del statehood. Esta lección 
correlaciona a los estándares nacionales de la historia y a los 
estándares nacionales para las ciencias sociales. También 
tiene conexiones cruz-del plan de estudios con historia, el gobierno, 
la geografía, y artes del lenguaje.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206407</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107321</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-u-s-recognition-of-the-state-of-israel</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
