<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105458</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105458</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086270</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Am Obliged to Reside in America": A Gay Immigrant Tells His Story in 1882</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich werde verbunden, mich in Amerika zu 
befinden": Ein homosexueller Immigrant erklärt seine Geschichte
1882</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je suis obligé de résider en Amérique" : 
Un immigré gai dit son histoire en 1882</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu sou obrigado residir em América": Um 
immigrant gay diz sua história em 1882</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sono obbligato a risedere in America": Un 
immigrante di Gay dice alla sua storia in 1882</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"είμαι υποχρεωμένου για να κατοικήσω στην Αμερική": 
Ένας ομοφυλοφιλικός μετανάστης λέει την ιστορία του το 
1882</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"me obligan a residir en América": Un 
inmigrante Gay cuenta su historia en 1882</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The reasons immigrants had for leaving their homelands and coming to America were as diverse as the backgrounds of the immigrants themselves. Although most immigrants came to the United States for economic reasons some sought a new home because of persecution based on their politics, religious beliefs, or even their sexual orientation. In this 1882 letter sent to medical writer and sexologist Dr. Richard von Krafft-Ebing, a thirty-eight-year-old German-born merchant explained how a homosexual arrest in his homeland forced him to emigrate to the United States.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Grundimmigranten hatten für das Verlassen 
ihrer Heimaten und kommend nach Amerika, waren so verschieden wie die 
Hintergründe der Immigranten selbst. Obgleich die meisten 
Immigranten in die Vereinigten Staaten aus ökonomischen Gründen 
kamen, suchten einige ein neues Haus wegen der Verfolgung, die auf 
ihrer Politik, frommen Glauben oder sogar ihrer sexuellen 
Lagebestimmung basierte. In diesem Brief 1882, der medizinischen
Verfasser und dem sexologist Dr. Richard von Krafft-Ebing geschickt 
wurde, erklärte ein dreißig-acht-Jahr-alter Deutsch-getragener 
Kaufmann, wie ein homosexuelles Anhalten in seiner Heimaten ihn 
erzwang, in die Vereinigten Staaten auszuwandern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les immigrés de raisons ont pris pour laisser 
leurs patries et venant en Amérique étaient aussi divers que les 
milieux des immigrés eux-mêmes. Bien que la plupart des 
immigrés soient venus aux Etats-Unis pour des raisons économiques 
certains ont recherché une nouvelle maison en raison de la 
persécution basée sur la leur politique, croyance religieuse, ou 
même leur orientation sexuelle. Dans cette lettre 1882 envoyée
au von Krafft-Ebing d'auteur médical et de Dr. Richard de 
sexologist, un trente-huit-année-vieux négociant Allemand-soutenu a 
expliqué comment une arrestation homosexuelle dans sa patrie l'a 
forcé à émigrer aux Etats-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os immigrants das razões tiveram saindo de seus 
homelands e vindo a América eram tão diverso quanto os fundos dos 
immigrants eles mesmos. Embora a maioria de immigrants viessem 
aos estados unidos para razões econômicas alguns procuraram uma HOME
nova por causa do persecution baseado em sua política, opinião 
religiosa, ou mesmo em sua orientação sexual. Nesta letra 1882
emitida ao escritor e ao Dr. médicos Richard von Krafft-Ebing do 
sexologist, um comerciante Alemão-carregado trinta-oito-ano-velho 
explicou como uma apreensão homosexual em seu homeland o forçou a 
emigrate aos estados unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli immigranti di motivi hanno avuti per lasciare 
le loro patrie e venendo in America erano vario quanto gli 
ambiti di provenienza degli immigranti essi stessi. Anche se la 
maggior parte dei immigranti sono venuto al unito Dichiara per
i motivi che economici alcuni hanno cercato una nuova sede a causa del
persecution basato sulla loro politica, la credenza religiosa, o 
persino il loro orientamento sessuale. In questa lettera 1882 
trasmessa al produttore ed al Dott. medici Richard von Krafft-Ebing di
sexologist, un trenta-otto-anno-vecchio commerciante 
Tedesco-sopportato ha spiegato come un arresto omosessuale nella sua 
patria lo ha forzato emigrare al unito Dichiara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι μετανάστες λόγων είχαν για την αναχώρηση των 
πατρίδων τους και ο ερχομός στην Αμερική ήταν τόσο διαφορετικός 
όσο τα υπόβαθρα των μεταναστών οι ίδιοι. Αν και οι 
περισσότεροι μετανάστες έρχομαι στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες για 
οικονομικούς λόγους μερικές επιδίωξαν ένα νέο σπίτι λόγω της 
δίωξης βασισμένης στην πολιτική, τις θρησκευτικές πεποιθήσεις 
τους, ή ακόμα και το σεξουαλικό προσανατολισμό τους. Σε 
αυτήν την επιστολή 1882 στέλνω στον ιατρικούς συγγραφέα και το
sexologist το Δρ Richard βον Krafft-Ebing, ένας 
τριάντα-οκτώ-χρονών γερμανικός-γεννημένος έμπορος 
εξήγησε πώς μια ομοφυλοφιλική σύλληψη στην πατρίδα του τον 
ανάγκασε για να μεταναστεύσει στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los inmigrantes de las razones tenían para salir 
de sus patrias y viniendo a América eran tan diverso como los fondos 
de los inmigrantes ellos mismos. Aunque la mayoría de los 
inmigrantes vinieron a los Estados Unidos por razones económicas 
algunos buscaron un nuevo hogar debido a la persecución basada en su 
política, creencia religiosa, o aún su orientación sexual. En
esta letra 1882 enviada al programa de escritura y al Dr. médicos 
Richard von Krafft-Ebing del sexologist, un treinta-ocho-año-viejo 
comerciante Alema'n-llevado explicó cómo una detención homosexual 
en su patria lo forzó emigrar a los Estados Unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086270</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105458</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-am-obliged-to-reside-in-america-a-gay-immigrant-tells-his-story-in-1882</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
