<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108548</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108548</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086798</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Sailor Wounds Spectator Disrespectful of Flag": The Red Scare, 1919-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Seemann verwundet Zuschauerdisrespectful der 
Markierungsfahne": Der Rote Schrecken, 1919-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">le "marin blesse irrespectueux spectaculaire de 
l'indicateur" : l'Alarme Rouge, 1919-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o "sailor fere disrespectful espectador da 
bandeira": O Scare Vermelho, 1919-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il marinaio fer disrespectful spectator della 
bandierina": Lo Spavento Rosso, 1919-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Θεατής πληγών ναυτικών ασεβής της σημαίασ": Ο 
κόκκινος τρόμος, 1919-1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el "marinero hiere irrespetuoso espectador del 
indicador": El Susto Rojo, 1919-1921</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The climate of repression established in the name of wartime security during World War I continued after the war as the U.S. government focused on communists, Bolsheviks, and "reds." The Red Scare reached its height in the years between 1919 and 1921. Encouraged by Congress, which had refused to seat the duly elected Wisconsin trade unionist and socialist Victor Berger, Attorney General A. Mitchell Palmer began a series of showy and well-publicized raids against radicals and leftists. Striking without warning and without warrants, Palmer's men smashed union offices and the headquarters of Communist and Socialist organizations. The  Washington Post  of May 7, 1919, noted approvingly that a sailor shot a Chicago man merely for failing to rise during the national anthem.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Klima der Unterdrückung hergestellt im Namen 
der Kriegsicherheit während des Ersten Weltkrieges fuhr nach dem 
Krieg als die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Regierung fort, die gerichtet wurde 
auf Kommunisten, Bolschewike und "Rottöne." Der rote Schrecken 
erreichte seine Höhe in den Jahren zwischen 1919 und 1921. 
Angeregt durch Congress, der abgelehnt hatte, das 
ordnungsgemäß gewählte Wisconsin zu setzen Gewerkschaftler und 
sozialistischer Victor Berger, fing Generalstaatsanwalt A. Mitchell 
Palmer eine Reihe auffällige und gut-publizierte Überfälle gegen 
Radikale und Leftists an. Anschlagend ohne WARNING und ohne 
Ermächtigungen, zertrümmerten Männer Palmers Anschlußbüros und 
die Hauptsitze der kommunistischen und sozialistischen 
Organisationen. Der Washington Pfosten von Mai 7, 1919, 
anerkennend beachtet, daß ein Seemann einen Chicago Mann bloß 
schoß, damit das Nicht können während der nationalen Hymne
steigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le climat de la répression établi au nom de la 
sécurité de temps de guerre pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale a 
continué après la guerre comme gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS 
concentré sur des communistes, des bolchéviques, et des "rouges." 
L'alarme rouge a atteint sa taille en années entre 1919 et 
1921. Encouragé par Congress, qui avait refusé de poser le 
Wisconsin dûment élu le syndicaliste et le vainqueur socialiste 
Berger, Général mandataire A. Mitchell Palmer a commencé une série
d'incursions voyantes et bien-données de la publicité contre des 
radicaux et des gauchistes. Frappant sans avertissement et sans 
garanties, les hommes de Palmer ont cassé des bureaux des syndicats 
et les sièges sociaux des organismes communistes et socialistes. 
Le poteau de Washington mai de 7, 1919, remarquable avec 
approbation qu'un marin a tiré un homme de Chicago simplement pour 
que ne se lève pas pendant le hymne national.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O clima do repression estabelecido no nome da 
segurança do wartime durante o world.war.i continuou após a guerra 
como o governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS focalizado em comunistas, em 
bolsheviks, e em "vermelhos." O scare vermelho alcançou sua 
altura nos anos entre 1919 e 1921. Incentivado por Congress, que
tinha recusado assentar o Wisconsin devida eleito o unionist de 
comércio e vencedor socialist Berger, advogado A. geral Mitchell 
Palmer começou uma série de invasões showy e bem-well-publicized de
encontro aos radicais e aos leftists. Golpeando sem aviso e sem 
autorizações, os homens de Palmer despedaçaram escritórios da 
união e as matrizes de organizações comunistas e socialist. O
borne de Washington maio de 7, 1919, notável approvingly que um 
sailor disparou em um homem de Chicago meramente para que não se 
levante durante o anthem nacional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il clima di repressione stabilito in nome di 
sicurezza di wartime durante il world.war.i è continuato dopo la 
guerra come il governo degli STATI UNITI messo a fuoco sui comunisti, 
sui bolsheviks e "sui colori rossi." Lo spavento rosso ha 
raggiunto la relativa altezza durante gli anni fra 1919 e 1921. 
Consigliato a da Congress, che aveva rifiutato di mettere il 
Wisconsin a sedere debitamente scelto sindacalista e victor socialista
Berger, l'avvocato A. Mitchell Palmer generale ha cominciato una serie
di incursioni showy e bene-divulg contro i radicali ed i leftists. 
Colpendo senza avvertimento e senza garanzie, gli uomini del 
Palmer hanno fracassato gli uffici del sindacato e le sedi delle 
organizzazioni comuniste e socialiste. L'alberino de Washington 
maggio di 7, 1919, celebre approvingly che un marinaio ha sparato un 
uomo del Chicago soltanto affinchè non riuscire aumenti durante il 
anthem nazionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κλίμα της καταστολής που καθιερώθηκε στο όνομα της 
εν καιρώ πολέμου ασφάλειας κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου συνεχίστηκα μετά από τον πόλεμο όπως η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ 
κυβέρνηση εστίασε στους κομμουνιστές, Bolsheviks, και "τα 
κόκκινα." Ο κόκκινος τρόμος έφθασε στο ύψος του στα έτη 
μεταξύ 1919 και 1921, που ενθαρρύνθηκαν από το συνέδριο, που
είχε αρνηθεί να καθίσει τον κατάλληλα εκλεγμένο συνδικαλιστή και
το σοσιαλιστικό Victor Berger του Wisconsin, γενικός 
εισαγγελέας Α. Mitchell Palmer άρχισαν μια σειρά ελκυστικών 
και καλά-κοινοποιημένων επιδρομών ενάντια στους ριζοσπάστες και 
τους αριστερούς. Εντυπωσιακά χωρίς προειδοποίηση και 
χωρίς εντάλματα, τα άτομα Palmer συνέθλιψαν τα γραφεία ένωσης
και την έδρα των κομμουνιστικών και σοσιαλιστικών οργανώσεων. 
Θ*Ωασχηνγτον Post Μάιος 7 ..1919, σημείωσε 
επιδοκιμαστικά ότι ένας ναυτικός πυροβόλησε ένα άτομο του 
Σικάγου μόνο για την αποτυχία να αυξηθεί κατά τη διάρκεια του 
εθνικού ύμνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El clima de la represión establecido en el nombre
de la seguridad del tiempo de guerra durante Primera Guerra Mundial 
continuó después de la guerra como el gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
centrado en comunistas, bolsheviks, y "rojos." El susto rojo 
alcanzó su altura en los años entre 1919 y 1921. Animado por 
Congress, que había rechazado asentar el Wisconsin debido elegido el 
unionista comercial y vencedor socialista Berger, abogado A. general 
Mitchell Palmer comenzó una serie de incursiones llamativas y 
bien-publicadas contra radicales e izquierdistas. Pulso sin la 
alerta y sin autorizaciones, los hombres de Palmer rompieron oficinas 
de la unión y las jefaturas de organizaciones comunistas y 
socialistas. El poste de Washington del de mayo 7 de 1919, 
conocido approvingly que un marinero tiró a un hombre de Chicago 
simplemente para que el no poder se levante durante el himno nacional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086798</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108548</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sailor-wounds-spectator-disrespectful-of-flag-the-red-scare-1919-1921</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
