<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108415</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108415</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087672</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Human Genome Research Institute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationales Menschliches Genom-Forschungsinstitut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Institut de recherche de Recherche Humain National
De Génome</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Instituto De Pesquisa Humano Nacional Do Genome</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Istituto di ricerca Umano Nazionale Del Genome</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικό ανθρώπινο ερευνητικό ίδρυμα γονιδιώματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Instituto De Investigación Humano Nacional Del 
Genoma</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The National Human Genome Research Institute began as the National Center for Human Genome Research (NCHGR), which was established in 1989 to carry out the role of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) in the International Human Genome Project (HGP). The HGP was developed in collaboration with the United States Department of Energy (DOE) and begun in 1990 to map the human genome. 

Now, with the human genome sequence complete since April 2003, scientists around the world have access to a database that greatly facilitates and accelerates the pace of biomedical research.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das nationale menschliche Genom-Forschungsinstitut
fing als die nationale Mitte für menschliche Genom-Forschung (NCHGR) 
an, die 1989 hergestellt wurde, um die Rolle der nationalen Institute 
der Gesundheit (NIH) im internationalen menschlichen Genom-Projekt 
(HGP) durchzuführen. Das HGP wurde gemeinsam mit der Vereinigte
Staaten Abteilung von Energie (DAMHIRSCHKUH) entwickelt und angefangen
1990, um das menschliche Genom abzubilden. Jetzt mit der 
menschlichen Genomreihenfolge, die seit April 2003 komplett ist, haben
Wissenschaftler um die Welt Zugriff zu einer Datenbank, die groß den 
Schritt der biomedizinischen Forschung erleichtert und beschleunigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'institut de recherche de recherche humain 
national de génome a commencé comme centre national pour la 
recherche humaine de génome (NCHGR), qui a été établie en 1989 
pour effectuer le rôle des instituts nationaux de la santé (NIH) 
dans le projet humain international de génome (HGP). Le HGP a 
été développé en collaboration avec le ministère de l'énergie 
des Etats-Unis (DAINE) et commencé en 1990 pour tracer le génome 
humain. Maintenant, avec l'ordre humain de génome complet 
depuis avril 2003, les scientifiques autour du monde ont accès à une
base de données qui considérablement facilite et accélère le pas 
de la recherche biomédicale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O instituto de pesquisa humano nacional do genome 
começou como o centro nacional para a pesquisa humana do genome 
(NCHGR), que foi estabelecida em 1989 para realizar o papel dos 
institutos nacionais da saúde (NIH) no projeto humano internacional 
do genome (HGP). O HGP foi desenvolvido na colaboração com o 
departamento dos estados de energia unido (CORÇA) e começado em 1990
a traçar o genome humano. Agora, com a seqüência humana do 
genome completa desde abril 2003, os cientistas em torno do mundo têm
o acesso a uma base de dados que extremamente facilite e acelere o 
ritmo da pesquisa biomedical.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'istituto di ricerca umano nazionale del genome 
ha cominciato come il centro nazionale per ricerca umana del genome 
(NCHGR), che è stata stabilita in 1989 per effettuare il ruolo degli 
istituti nazionali di salute (NIH) nel progetto umano internazionale 
del genome (HGP). Il HGP è stato sviluppato in collaborazione 
con unito Dichiara il Dipartimento per l'energia (DAINA) e 
cominciato in 1990 a tracciare il genome umano. Ora, con la 
sequenza umana del genome completa da aprile del 2003, gli scienziati 
intorno al mondo hanno accesso ad una base di dati che notevolmente 
facilita ed accelera il passo di ricerca biomedica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εθνικό ανθρώπινο ερευνητικό ίδρυμα γονιδιώματος 
άρχισε ως εθνικό κέντρο για την ανθρώπινη έρευνα γονιδιώματος 
(NCHGR), η οποία καθιερώθηκε το 1989 για να εκτελέσει το 
ρόλο των εθνικών ιδρυμάτων υγείας (NIH) στο διεθνές ανθρώπινο
πρόγραμμα γονιδιώματος (HGP). Το HGP αναπτύχθηκε σε 
συνεργασία με Ηνωμένο τμήμα ενέργειας (DOE) και άρχισαν το 
1990 για να χαρτογραφεί το ανθρώπινο γονιδίωμα. Τώρα, με 
την ανθρώπινη ακολουθία γονιδιώματος πλήρη από τον Απρίλιο του 
2003, οι επιστήμονες σε όλο τον κόσμο έχουν πρόσβαση σε μια 
βάση δεδομένων που διευκολύνει πολύ και επιταχύνει το ρυθμό της 
βιοϊατρικής έρευνας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El instituto de investigación humano nacional del
Genoma comenzó como el centro nacional para la investigación 
humana del Genoma (NCHGR), que fue establecida en 1989 para 
realizar el papel de los institutos nacionales de la salud (NIH) en el
proyecto humano internacional del Genoma (HGP). El HGP fue 
desarrollado en la colaboración con el Ministerio de Estados Unidos 
de Energía (GAMA) y comenzado en 1990 para asociar el genoma 
humano. Ahora, con la secuencia humana del genoma completa 
desde abril de 2003, los científicos alrededor del mundo tienen 
acceso a una base de datos que facilite y acelere grandemente el paso 
de la investigación biomédica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087672</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108415</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/national-human-genome-research-institute</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
