<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105611</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105611</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207051</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">American Landscape and Architectural Design, 1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikanische Landschaft und architektonisches 
Design, 1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Horizontal américain et conception 
architecturale, 1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Paisagem americana e projeto architectural, 
1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Paesaggio americano e disegno architettonico, 
1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανικό τοπίο και αρχιτεκτονικό σχέδιο, 
1850-1920</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paisaje americano y diseño arquitectónico, 
1850-1920</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">contains approximately 2,800 photographs, plans, maps, and models of American buildings and landscapes built during this period. The collection offers views of cities, buildings, parks, estates and gardens, including a complete history of Boston's Park System. Hundreds of private estates from all over the United States are shown in contemporary views of their houses, formal gardens, terraces, and arbors.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält ungefähr 2.800 Fotographien, Pläne, 
Karten, und Modelle der amerikanischen Gebäude und der Landschaften 
aufgebaut während dieser Periode. Die Ansammlung bietet 
Ansichten der Städte, Gebäude, Parks, Zustände und Gärten, 
einschließlich eine komplette Geschichte des Park-Systems Bostons an.
Hunderte der Privatbesitze von ganz über den Vereinigten 
Staaten werden in den zeitgenössischen Ansichten ihrer Häuser, 
formalen Gärten, Terrassen und Dorne gezeigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">contient approximativement 2.800 photographies, 
plans, cartes, et modèles des bâtiments américains et des 
horizontaux établis pendant cette période. La collection offre
des vues des villes, bâtiments, parcs, domaines et jardins, y compris
une histoire complète du système du parc de Boston. Des 
centaines de domaines privés partout des Etats-Unis sont montrées 
dans des vues contemporaines de leurs maisons, jardins formels, 
terrasses, et axes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">contem aproximadamente 2.800 fotografias, plantas,
mapas, e modelos de edifícios americanos e de paisagens construídos 
durante este período. A coleção oferece vistas das cidades, 
edifícios, parques, propriedades e jardins, including um history 
completo do sistema do parque de Boston. As centenas de 
propriedades confidenciais do excesso os estados unidos são mostradas
toda em vistas contemporary de seus casas, jardins formais, terraces, 
e mandris.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">contiene circa 2.800 fotografie, programmi, mappe 
e modelli delle costruzioni americane e dei paesaggi sviluppati 
durante questo periodo. L'accumulazione offre le viste delle 
città, costruzioni, parchi, proprietà e giardini, compreso una 
storia completa del sistema del parco de Boston. Le centinaia 
delle proprietà riservate dappertutto dal unito Dichiarano sono 
indicate nelle viste contemporanee delle loro case, giardini 
convenzionali, terrazzi e supporti conici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιέχει τις περίπου 2.800 φωτογραφίες, τα σχέδια, 
χάρτες, και μοντέλα των αμερικανικών κτηρίων και των τοπίων που 
χτίζονται κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της περιόδου. Η συλλογή 
προσφέρει τις όψεις των πόλεων, κτήρια, πάρκα, κτήματα και 
κήποι, συμπεριλαμβανομένης μιας πλήρους ιστορίας του συστήματος 
πάρκων της Βοστώνης. Οι εκατοντάδες των ιδιωτικών κτημάτων 
από όλες τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες εμφανίζονται κατά σύγχρονες 
όψη των σπιτιών, των επίσημων κήπων, των πεζουλιών, και των 
αξόνων τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contiene aproximadamente 2.800 fotografías, 
planes, correspondencias, y modelos de edificios americanos y de 
paisajes construidos durante este período. La colección ofrece
vistas de las ciudades, edificios, parques, estados y jardines, 
incluyendo una historia completa del sistema del parque de Boston. 
Los centenares de estados privados de todo sobre los Estados 
Unidos se muestran en vistas contemporáneas de sus casas, jardines 
formales, terrazas, y cenadores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207051</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105611</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/american-landscape-and-architectural-design-1850-1920</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
