<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107623</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107623</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085240</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Preservation of the West</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bewahrung des Westens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Conservation de l'ouest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Preservação do oeste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Conservazione dell'ovest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συντήρηση της δύσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Preservación del oeste</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the late 1800s, American industry's demand for more and more natural resources pushed Congress to recognize the need to explore and chart the geological characteristics and mineral wealth of the country. In 1864, William Brewer (seen third from the left in "Field Party of 1864"), chief botanist of the California Geological Survey, led the first state-sponsored expedition to survey, map, chart, document, and photograph vast, previously unexplored areas of California. The government sponsored several such expeditions to survey and map the territories of the United States. The many photographs taken on these expeditions were used to promote the geographic wonders and scenic beauty of the West to the rest of the country and led to a move to preserve areas of natural beauty and protect them against development. In 1871, photographer William H. Jackson traveled to Yellowstone with an expedition led by Ferdinand V. Hayden, a Civil War veteran and later head of the US Geological Survey (the USGS was officially established in 1879). Jackson took the stereoscopic views of the park included here. The following year, as a result of this expedition, Congress passed the Yellowstone Act of 1872 to protect over 2 million acres in northwest Wyoming, designating the Yellowstone area as the world?s first National Park. In California, naturalist and conservationist John Muir (shown seated on a boulder in one photograph) educated and informed the public about the beauty of the state and its need to be preserved. He was instrumental in the move to set aside Yosemite as a National Park. Muir was influential in convincing President Teddy Roosevelt of the need to conserve these lands. One photograph of the president's visit to Yosemite shows Muir and Roosevelt standing on a rock at Yosemite's Glacier Point. Another shows Roosevelt with a party of Secret Service men and government officials at Mariposa Grove. Carlton Watkins was among the first to photograph Yosemite. He became well known for his magnificent, large plate images of the park, including the images of Bridal Veil, El Capitan, and Nevada Fall, shown here. His images played a significant role in promoting the West to the rest of the country. An image of sheet music from 1873 called "Yosemite Waltzes" reflects how the park was quickly incorporated into popular culture. The logging industry, which began during the Gold Rush years, had gained a foothold in California and the Pacific Northwest. One 1872 photograph depicts loggers in Mammoth Forest about to cut down a massive tree (said to be 5,000 years old) that would later be reassembled for the World's Fair in order to show the rest of the world just how big things were in the West. But as logging and other industries grew, and it became clear that the West had a finite amount of natural wealth, the conservation movement gained momentum. In 1892, the Sierra Club began at the University of California, Berkeley, to promote conservation and involve people in the great outdoors by organizing hikes and outings. One photograph shows club members on an outing in Sequoia Forest in 1902. Other photographs picture two women hiking to Glacier Point, and a family camping in Yosemite in 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des späten 1800s drückte Nachfrage der 
amerikanischen Industrie nach immer Naturresourcen Kongreß, um die 
Notwendigkeit zu erkennen, die geologischen Eigenschaften und die 
Mineralfülle des Landes zu erforschen und zu entwerfen. 1864 
führte der William Brauer (an dritter Stelle gesehen vom links in 
"Fangen Sie Partei von 1864") auf, Hauptbotaniker 
der Kalifornien geologischen Übersicht, die erste Zustand-geförderte
Expedition, um zu überblicken, abzubilden, zu entwerfen, zu 
dokumentieren, und die beträchtliche Fotographie, vorher nicht 
erforschte Bereiche von Kalifornien. Die Regierung förderte 
einige solche Expeditionen, um die Gegenden der Vereinigten Staaten zu
überblicken und abzubilden. Die vielen Fotographien, die auf 
diesen Expeditionen genommen wurden, wurden benutzt, um die 
geographischen Wunder und die szenische Schönheit des Westens zum 
Rest des Landes zu fördern und geführt zu eine Bewegung, Bereiche 
der natürlichen Schönheit zu konservieren und sie gegen Entwicklung 
zu schützen. 1871 reiste Photograph William H. Jackson zu 
Yellowstone mit einer Expedition, die durch Ferdinand V. Hayden, ein 
Bürgerkriegveteran und neuerer Kopf von der US geologischen 
Übersicht geführt wurde (das USGS wurde offiziell 1879 hergestellt).
Jackson nahm die stereoskopischen Ansichten des Parks, der hier 
eingeschlossen war. Das folgende Jahr, resultierend aus dieser 
Expedition, führte Kongreß die Yellowstone Tat von 1872, um sich 
über 2 Million Morgen in Nordwestwyoming zu schützen und 
kennzeichnete den Yellowstone Bereich als der world?s erste 
Nationalpark. In Kalifornien erzogen Naturwissenschaftler und 
Naturschützer John Muir (gezeigt gesetzt auf einem Flußstein in 
einer Fotographie) und informierten die Öffentlichkeit über die 
Schönheit des Zustandes und seiner Notwendigkeit konserviert zu 
werden. Er war in der Bewegung, Yosemite als Nationalpark 
beiseite zu setzen instrumentell. Muir war einflußreich, wenn 
er Präsidenten Teddy Roosevelt der Notwendigkeit, diese Länder zu 
konservieren überzeugte. Eine Fotographie des Besuchs des 
Präsidenten zu Yosemite zeigt Muir und Roosevelt, die auf einem 
Felsen am Gletscher-Punkt Yosemites stehen. Eine anderen 
Erscheinen Roosevelt mit einer Partei der geheimen 
Service-Männer und der Regierungsbeamten an der Mariposa Waldung. 
Carlton Watkins gehörte zu dem ersten zur Fotographie Yosemite.
Er wurde für seine ausgezeichneten, großen Platte Bilder des 
Parks, einschließlich die Bilder des Brautschleiers, des EL Capitan 
und des Nevada Falles weithin bekannt, hier gezeigt. Seine 
Bilder spielten eine bedeutende Rolle, wenn sie den Westen zum Rest 
des Landes förderten. Ein Bild von Blattmusik von 1873 
benannten "Yosemite Waltzes" reflektiert, wie der Park schnell in 
populäre Kultur enthalten wurde. Die protokollierende 
Industrie, die während der Goldansturmjahre anfing, hatte eine 
Stellung in Kalifornien und im pazifischen Nordwesten gewonnen. 
Eine 1872 Fotographie stellt Logger im Mammutwald ungefähr 
bildlich dar, um hinunter einen massiven Baum zu schneiden (gesagt, um
alt zu sein 5.000 Jahre) der später für die Welt ehrlich neu 
zusammengestellt würde, um den Rest der Welt zu zeigen, gerade wie 
grosse Sachen im Westen waren. Aber als protokollierende und 
andere Industrien wuchs, und es wurde, daß der Westen eine begrenzte 
Menge natürliche Fülle hatte, das Erhaltung Bewegung gewonnene 
Momentum frei. 1892 fing die Sierra Verein an der Universität 
von Kalifornien, Berkeley an, Erhaltung zu fördern und Leute im 
großen Freien mit einzubeziehen, indem sie Wanderungen und Outings 
organisierte. Eine Fotographie zeigt Vereinsmitglieder auf einem
Outing im Mammutbaum-Wald 1902. Andere Fotographien stellen zwei
Frauen, zum Gletscher-Punkt zu wandern dar, und eine Familie in 
Yosemite 1906 zu kampieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant le 1800s en retard, la demande de 
l'industrie américaine les ressources naturelles de de plus en plus a
poussé le congrès pour identifier la nécessité d'explorer et 
dresser une carte les caractéristiques géologiques et la richesse 
minérale du pays. En 1864, le brasseur de William (vu 
troisièmement de la gauche en "partie de zone de 1864"), botaniste en
chef de l'enquête géologique de la Californie, a mené la première 
expédition état-commanditée pour examiner, tracer, dresser une 
carte, documenter, et la photographie vaste, des régions 
précédemment encore inconnues de la Californie. Le 
gouvernement a commandité plusieurs telles expéditions pour examiner
et tracer les territoires des Etats-Unis. Les nombreuses 
photographies prises sur ces expéditions ont été employées pour 
favoriser les merveilles géographiques et la beauté scénique de 
l'ouest au reste du pays et menées à un mouvement de préserver des 
zones de beauté normale et de les protéger contre le développement.
En 1871, le photographe William H. Jackson a voyagé à 
Yellowstone avec une expédition menée par Ferdinand V. Hayden, un 
ancien combattant civil et un plus défunt chef de l'enquête 
géologique des USA (l'USGS a été officiellement établi en 1879). 
Jackson a adopté les positions stéréoscopiques du parc inclus
ici. L'année suivante, en raison de cette expédition, le 
congrès a passé l'acte de Yellowstone de 1872 pour se protéger plus
de 2 millions d'acres au Wyoming du nord-ouest, indiquant la région 
de Yellowstone comme premier parc national de world?s. En 
Californie, le naturaliste et le protecteur de la nature John Muir 
(montré assis sur un rocher en une photographie) ont instruit et ont 
informé le public au sujet de la beauté de l'état et de son besoin 
d'être préservé. Il était instrumental dans le mouvement de 
mettre de côté Yosemite comme parc national. Muir était 
influent en convainquant le Président Teddy Roosevelt de la 
nécessité d'économiser ces terres. Une photographie de la 
visite du président à Yosemite montre Muir et Roosevelt se tenant 
sur une roche au point du glacier de Yosemite. Des autres 
expositions Roosevelt avec une partie des hommes de service et des 
fonctionnaires de gouvernement secrets à la plantation de Mariposa. 
Carlton Watkins était parmi le premier à la photographie 
Yosemite. Il est devenu bien connu pour ses images magnifiques 
et grandes de plat du parc, y compris les images du voile, du EL 
Capitan, et de l'automne nuptiales du Nevada, montré ici. Ses 
images ont joué un rôle significatif en favorisant l'ouest au reste 
du pays. Une image de la musique de feuille de 1873 "valses de 
Yosemite" appelées reflète comment le parc a été rapidement 
incorporé à la culture populaire. L'industrie 
d'enregistrement, qui a commencé pendant les années de 
précipitations d'or, avait gagné un équilibre en Californie et 
nord-ouest Pacifique. Une 1872 photographies dépeignent des 
enregistreurs automatiques dans la forêt gigantesque environ pour 
réduire un arbre massif (dit pour avoir 5.000 ans) qui plus tard 
serait rassemblé pour mondial afin de montrer le reste du monde juste
comme les grandes choses étaient dans l'ouest. Mais en tant 
qu'industries d'enregistrement et autres s'est développé, et il est 
apparu clairement que l'ouest a eu une quantité finie de richesse 
normale, l'élan gagné par mouvement d'économie. En 1892, la 
sierra club a commencé à l'université de la Californie, Berkeley, 
à favoriser l'économie et à faire participer des personnes dans le 
grand extérieur en organisant des hausses et des promenades. 
Une photographie montre des membres de club sur une promenade 
dans la forêt de séquoia en 1902. D'autres photographies 
décrivent deux femmes augmenter au point de glacier, et une famille 
camper dans Yosemite en 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o 1800s atrasado, a demanda da indústria 
americana para uns recursos mais e mais naturais empurrou o congress 
para reconhecer a necessidade explorar e fazer um mapa das 
características geological e da riqueza mineral do país. Em 
1864, o fabricante de cerveja de William (visto em terceiro lugar da 
esquerda do "em um partido campo de 1864"), botânico principal do 
exame geological de Califórnia, conduziu à primeira expedição 
estado-patrocinada para examinar, traçar, fazer um mapa, documentar, 
e à fotografia vasta, áreas previamente unexplored de Califórnia. 
O governo patrocinou diversas tais expedições para examinar e 
traçar os territórios dos estados unidos. Muitas fotografias 
feitas exame nestas expedições foram usadas promover as maravilhas 
geográficas e a beleza scenic do oeste ao descanso do país e 
conduzidas a um movimento preservar áreas de beleza natural e 
protegê-las de encontro ao desenvolvimento. Em 1871, o 
fotógrafo William H. Jackson viajou a Yellowstone com uma expedição
conduzida por Ferdinand V. Hayden, um veteran de guerra civil e uma 
cabeça mais atrasada do exame geological dos E. U. (o USGS foi 
estabelecido oficialmente em 1879). Jackson fêz exame das 
vistas stereoscopic do parque incluído aqui. O seguinte ano, em
conseqüência desta expedição, o congress passou o ato de 
Yellowstone de 1872 para proteger sobre 2 milhão acres em Wyoming 
noroeste, designando a área de Yellowstone como o primeiro parque 
nacional dos world?s. Em Califórnia, o naturalist e o 
conservationist John Muir (mostrado assentado em um pedregulho em uma 
fotografia) educaram e informaram o público sobre a beleza do estado 
e de sua necessidade ser preservado. Era instrumental no 
movimento reservar Yosemite como um parque nacional. Muir era 
influential em convencer o presidente Teddy Roosevelt da necessidade 
conservar estas terras. Uma fotografia da visita do presidente a
Yosemite mostra Muir e Roosevelt que estão em uma rocha no ponto da 
geleira de Yosemite. Umas outras mostras Roosevelt com um 
partido de homens do serviço e de oficiais de governo secretos no 
bosque de Mariposa. Carlton Watkins era entre o primeiro à 
fotografia Yosemite. Tornou-se sabido bem para suas imagens 
magníficas, grandes da placa do parque, including as imagens do véu,
do EL Capitan, e da queda bridal de Nevada, mostrada aqui. Suas 
imagens jogaram um papel significativo em promover o oeste ao descanso
do país. Uma imagem da música da folha de 1873 de "waltzes 
chamados Yosemite" reflete como o parque foi incorporado rapidamente 
na cultura popular. A indústria registrando, que começou 
durante os anos das arremetidas do ouro, tinha ganhado um foothold em 
Califórnia e no noroeste pacífico. Uma 1872 fotografias 
descrevem loggers na floresta mammoth aproximadamente para reduzir uma
árvore maciça (dita ter 5.000 anos velho) que seja remontada mais 
tarde para o mundo favoravelmente a fim mostrar o rest.of.the.world 
apenas como as coisas grandes estavam no oeste. Mas como 
indústrias registrando e outras cresceu, e tornou-se desobstruído 
que o oeste teve uma quantidade finita de riqueza natural, o momentum 
ganho movimento do conservation. Em 1892, o sierra clube 
começou na universidade de Califórnia, Berkeley, a promover o 
conservation e envolver povos no ar livre grande organizando hikes e 
outings. Uma fotografia mostra membros de clube em um outing na 
floresta do sequoia em 1902. Outras fotografias retratam duas 
mulheres hiking ao ponto da geleira, e uma família acampar em 
Yosemite em 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il 1800s ritardato, la richiesta 
dell'industria americana risorse naturali di più ed ha spinto il 
congresso per riconoscere la necessità di esplorare e progettare le 
caratteristiche geologiche e la ricchezza minerale del paese. In
1864, il fabbricante di birra del William (visto terzo dalla parte di 
sinistra "in un partito del campo di 1864"), botanico principale 
dell'indagine geologica della California, ha condotto la prima 
spedizione di dichiarare-sponsored per esaminare, tracciare, 
progettare, documentare e la fotografia ampia, regioni precedentemente
inesplorate della California. Il governo ha patrocinato 
parecchie tali spedizioni per esaminare e tracciare i territori del 
unito Dichiara. Le molte fotografie prese su queste 
spedizioni sono state usate per promuovere i wonders geografici e la 
bellezza scenica dell'ovest al resto del paese e sono state condotte 
ad un movimento conservare le zone della bellezza naturale e 
proteggerle da sviluppo. In 1871, il photographer William il H. 
Jackson ha viaggiato a Yellowstone con una spedizione condotta da 
Ferdinand V. Hayden, un veterano di guerra civile e testa successiva 
dell'indagine geologica degli Stati Uniti (il USGS è stato stabilito 
ufficialmente in 1879). Jackson ha considerare stereoscopici del
parco incluso qui. Il seguente anno, come conseguenza di questa 
spedizione, il congresso ha passato la Legge di Yellowstone di 1872 
per proteggere oltre 2 milione acri nel Wyoming di nord-ovest, 
indicante la zona di Yellowstone come il primo parco nazionale dei 
world?s. Nella California, il naturalista ed il conservationist 
John Muir (indicato messo su un masso in una fotografia) hanno 
istruito ed informato il pubblico circa la bellezza del dichiarare e 
della relativa necessità essere conservato. Era strumentale nel
movimento mettere Yosemite da parte come parco nazionale. Muir 
era influente nel convincere il presidente Teddy Roosevelt della 
necessità di conservare queste terre. Una fotografia della 
chiamata del presidente a Yosemite mostra Muir e Roosevelt che si 
levano in piedi su una roccia al punto del ghiacciaio del Yosemite. 
Lle altre esposizioni Roosevelt con un partito degli uomini di 
servizio e dei funzionari di governo segreti al boschetto di Mariposa.
Carlton Watkins era fra il primo alla fotografia Yosemite. 
È stato ben noto per le sue immagini magnifiche e grandi della 
piastra del parco, compreso le immagini del velare, del EL Capitan e 
della caduta bridal del Nevada, indicata qui. Le sue immagini 
hanno svolto un ruolo significativo nella promozione dell'ovest al 
resto del paese. Un'immagine di musica del foglio da 1873 
"waltzes di Yosemite" chiamati riflette come il parco è stato 
incorporato rapidamente in coltura popolare. L'industria 
annotante, che ha cominciato durante gli anni di sbalzi dell'oro, 
aveva guadagnato un appiglio nella California e nel nord-ovest 
pacifico. Una 1872 fotografie descrivono i registratori di dati 
atmosferici in foresta gigantesca circa per ridurre un albero 
voluminoso (detto per avere 5.000 anni) che più successivamente 
sarebbe riunito correttamente per il mondo per mostrare il resto del 
mondo appena come le cose grandi erano nell'ovest. Ma come 
industrie annotanti ed altre si è sviluppato ed è essere evidente 
che l'ovest ha avuto una quantità limitata di ricchezza naturale, la 
quantità di moto guadagnata movimento di conservazione. In 
1892, la sierra randello ha cominciato all'università di California, 
Berkeley, a promuovere la conservazione e fare partecipare la gente 
nell'aria aperta grande organizzando gli aumenti ed i outings. 
Una fotografia mostra i membri di randello su un outing nella 
foresta della sequoia in 1902. Altre fotografie descrivono due 
donne hiking al punto del ghiacciaio e una famiglia accamparsi in 
Yosemite in 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του πρόσφατου 1800s, η απαίτηση 
της αμερικανικής βιομηχανίας για τα όλο και περισσότερο φυσικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς ώθησε το συνέδριο για να αναγνωρίσει την 
ανάγκη να ερευνηθούν και να σχεδιαστούν τα γεωλογικά 
χαρακτηριστικά και ο ορυκτός πλούτος της χώρας. Το 1864, 
William Brewer (βλέπω τρίτο από το αριστερό στο 
"συμβαλλόμενο μέρος πεδίων 1864"), προϊστάμενος βοτανολόγος της 
γεωλογικής έρευνας Καλιφόρνιας, οδήγησε την πρώτη 
κράτος-υποστηριγμένη αποστολή στην έρευνα, το χάρτη, το 
διάγραμμα, το έγγραφο, και τις απέραντες, προηγουμένως 
ανεξερεύνητες περιοχές φωτογραφιών Καλιφόρνιας. Η κυβέρνηση
υποστήριξε διάφορες τέτοιες αποστολές στην έρευνα και 
χαρτογραφεί τα εδάφη των ενωμένων κρατών. Οι πολλές 
φωτογραφίες που λήφθηκαν σε αυτές τις αποστολές χρησιμοποιήθηκαν 
για να προαγάγουν το γεωγραφικό αναρωτιούνται και φυσική ομορφιά 
της δύσης στο υπόλοιπο της χώρας και οδήγησαν σε μια κίνηση για 
να συντηρηθούν οι τομείς της φυσικής ομορφιάς και να 
προστατευθούν από την ανάπτυξη. Το 1871, ο φωτογράφος 
William H. Τζάκσον ταξίδεψε σε Yellowstone μια αποστολή 
που οδηγήθηκε με από το Ferdinand V. Hayden, έναν 
παλαίμαχο εμφύλιου πολέμου και έναν πιό πρώην προϊστάμενο της 
αμερικανικής γεωλογικής έρευνας (το USGS καθιερώθηκε επίσημα 
σε 1879). Τζάκσον πήρε τις στερεοσκοπικές όψεις του πάρκου 
συμπεριλαμβανόμενου εδώ. Το επόμενο έτος, ως αποτέλεσμα 
αυτής της αποστολής, συνέδριο πέρασε το νόμο Yellowstone 
1872 για να προστατεύσει πάνω από 2 εκατομμύριο στρέμματα στο 
βορειοδυτικό Wyoming, υποδεικνύοντας την περιοχή Yellowstone 
ως πρώτο εθνικό πάρκο world?s. Σε Καλιφόρνια, ο 
φυσιοδίφης και ο μαχόμενος για τη διατήρηση του φυσικού 
περιβάλλοντος John Muir (που εμφανίζεται καθισμένος σε έναν 
λίθο σε μια φωτογραφία) εκπαίδευσαν και ενημέρωσαν το κοινό για 
την ομορφιά του κράτους και της ανάγκης του να συντηρηθεί. 
Συνέβαλε στην κίνηση για να θέσει κατά μέρος Yosemite ως
εθνικό πάρκο. Το Muir ήταν επιδρόν να πείσει τον 
Πρόεδρο Teddy Roosevelt της ανάγκης να συντηρηθούν αυτά τα 
εδάφη. Μια φωτογραφία της επίσκεψης του Προέδρου σε 
Yosemite εμφανίζει Muir και Roosevelt στεμένος σε έναν 
βράχο στο σημείο παγετώνων Yosemite. Αλλος εμφανίζει 
Roosevelt με ένα συμβαλλόμενο μέρος των μυστικών ατόμων 
υπηρεσιών και των κυβερνητικών ανώτερων υπαλλήλων στο άλσος 
Mariposa. Το Carlton Watkins ήταν μεταξύ του πρώτου 
για να φωτογραφίσει Yosemite. Έγινε καλά γνωστός για τις 
θαυμάσιες, μεγάλες εικόνες πιάτων του του πάρκου, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των εικόνων του νυφικού πέπλου, της EL 
Capitan, και της πτώσης της Νεβάδας, που εμφανίστηκε εδώ. 
Οι εικόνες του διαδραμάτισαν έναν σημαντικό ρόλο στην 
προώθηση της δύσης στο υπόλοιπο της χώρας. Μια εικόνα της 
μουσικής φύλλων από 1873 αποκαλούμενης "Yosemite Waltzes"
απεικονίζει πώς το πάρκο ενσωματώθηκε γρήγορα στο δημοφιλή 
πολιτισμό. Η βιομηχανία αναγραφών, που άρχισε κατά τη 
διάρκεια των χρυσών εσπευσμένων ετών, είχε κερδίσει μια βάση σε
Καλιφόρνια και τα ειρηνικά βορειοδυτικά. Μια φωτογραφία 
1872 απεικονίζει τους εμπόρους ξυλείας στο μαμμούθ δάσος για 
να περικόψει περίπου ένα ογκώδες δέντρο (που λέεται για να 
είναι 5.000 ετών) που θα συγκεντρωνόταν εκ νέου αργότερα για 
την παγκόσμια έκθεση προκειμένου να εμφανιστεί ο υπόλοιπος 
κόσμος ακριβώς πώς τα μεγάλα πράγματα ήταν στη δύση. 
Αλλά καθώς η αναγραφή και άλλες βιομηχανίες αυξήθηκαν, και
έγινε σαφές ότι η δύση είχε ένα πεπερασμένο ποσό φυσικού 
πλούτου, η κερδισμένη μετακίνηση ορμή συντήρησης. Το 
1892, η οροσειρά λέσχη άρχισε στο πανεπιστήμιο Καλιφόρνιας, 
Μπέρκλεϋ, να προωθεί τη συντήρηση και να περιλαμβάνει τους 
ανθρώπους στο μεγάλο υπαίθρια με την οργάνωση των πεζοπορώ και 
των εξόδων. Μια φωτογραφία εμφανίζει μέλη λεσχών σε μια 
έξοδο sequoia στο δάσος σε 1902, Αλλη εικόνα δύο 
φωτογραφιών γυναίκες που στο σημείο παγετώνων, και μια οικογένεια
που στρατοπεδεύει σε Yosemite το 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante el último 1800s, la demanda de la 
industria americana para recursos más y más naturales empujó a 
congreso para reconocer la necesidad de explorar y de planear las 
características geológicas y la abundancia mineral del país. 
En 1864, el cervecero de Guillermo (véase tercero de la 
izquierda en el "partido del campo de 1864"), principal botánico de 
la encuesta sobre geológica California, condujo la primera 
expedición estado-patrocinada para examinar, para asociar, para 
planear, para documentar, y la fotografía extensa, las áreas 
previamente inexploradas de California. El gobierno patrocinó a
varias tales expediciones para examinar y para asociar los territorios
de los Estados Unidos. Las muchas fotografías adquiridas estas 
expediciones fueron utilizadas para promover las maravillas 
geográficas y la belleza escénica del oeste al resto del país y 
conducidas a un movimiento de preservar áreas de la belleza natural y
de protegerlas contra el desarrollo. En 1871, el fotógrafo 
Guillermo H. Jackson viajó a Yellowstone con una expedición 
conducida por Ferdinand V. Hayden, veterano de guerra civil y un jefe 
más último de la encuesta sobre geológica los E.E.U.U. (el USGS fue
establecido oficialmente en 1879). Jackson tomó las vistas 
estereoscópicas del parque incluido aquí. El año siguiente, 
como resultado de esta expedición, el congreso pasó el acto de 
Yellowstone de 1872 para proteger sobre 2 millones de acres en Wyoming
del noroeste, señalando el área de Yellowstone como el primer parque
nacional de los world?s. En California, el naturalista y el 
conservationist Juan Muir (mostrado asentado en un canto rodado en una
fotografía) educaban e informaron a público sobre la belleza del 
estado y de su necesidad de ser preservado. Él era instrumental
en el movimiento de poner Yosemite a un lado como parque nacional. 
Muir era influyente en el convencimiento de presidente Teddy 
Roosevelt de la necesidad de conservar estas pistas. Una 
fotografía de la visita del presidente a Yosemite muestra Muir y 
Roosevelt que están parado en una roca en la punta del glaciar de 
Yosemite. Otras demostraciones Roosevelt con un partido de los 
hombres del servicio y de los oficiales del gobierno secretos en la 
arboleda de Mariposa. Carlton Watkins estaba entre el primer a 
la fotografía Yosemite. Él hizo bien conocido para sus 
imágenes magníficas, grandes de la placa del parque, incluyendo las 
imágenes del velo, del EL Capitan, y de la caída nupciales de 
Nevada, mostrada aquí. Sus imágenes desempeñaron un papel 
significativo en promover el oeste al resto del país. Una 
imagen de la música de la hoja a partir de 1873 "valses llamados de 
Yosemite" refleja cómo el parque fue incorporado rápidamente en 
cultura popular. La industria de registración, que comenzó 
durante los años de las acometidas del oro, había ganado un 
equilibrio en California y el noroeste pacífico. Una 1872 
fotografías representan los madereros en bosque gigantesco alrededor 
para reducir un árbol masivo (dicho para ser 5.000 años de viejo) 
que sería vuelto a montar más adelante para el mundo favorablemente 
para mostrar el resto del mundo apenas cómo las cosas grandes estaban
en el oeste. Sino como industrias de registración y otras 
creció, y llegó a estar claro que el oeste tenía una cantidad 
finita de abundancia natural, el ímpetu ganado movimiento de la 
conservación. En 1892, el sierra club comenzó en la 
universidad de California, Berkeley, a promover la conservación y a 
implicar a gente en el gran aire libre ordenando alzas y excursiones. 
Una fotografía muestra a miembros de club en una excursión en 
bosque de la secoya en 1902. Otras fotografías representan a 
dos mujeres el ir de excursión a la punta del glaciar, y a familia el
acampar en Yosemite en 1906.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085240</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107623</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/preservation-of-the-west</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
