<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103125</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103125</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086324</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">In the Hot Seat: Rockefeller Testifies on Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im heißen Sitz: Rockefeller bezeugt auf 
Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le siège chaud : Rockefeller témoigne
sur Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No assento quente: Rockefeller testifies em 
Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nella sede calda: Rockefeller testimonia su 
Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο καυτό κάθισμα: Το Rockefeller πιστοποιεί 
σε Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el asiento caliente: Rockefeller 
atestigua en Ludlow</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The violent labor struggles of the early 20th century engendered concern at all levels of society and led to the appointment of a federal Commission on Industrial Relations in early 1913. Headed by Kansas City lawyer-reformer Frank Walsh, the commission was in the midst of taking testimony from owners, workers, and reformers in dozens of industrial communities around the country when the southern Colorado coal strike erupted late in 1913. The killing of three women and eleven children at a mining encampment in Ludlow, Colorado, on Easter night, 1914, sent shock waves across the country. After the "Ludlow massacre," as it came to be known, the commission held public hearings in Colorado where they heard horror stories about the brutality and rapacity of the Rockefeller-owned Colorado Fuel and Iron Company, the region's largest operator of coal mines. These articles from the New York  Times  described the testimony of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., before the commission, where he denied any knowledge of his company's brutal actions against the Ludlow strikers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die heftigen Arbeitskämpfe des frühes 20. 
Jahrhundert erzeugten Interesses auf allen Stufen der Gesellschaft und
zu die Verabredung einer Bundeskommission auf industriellen 
Beziehungen zwischen den Sozialpartnern frühem 1913 geführt. 
Vorangegangen durch Kansas City lawyer-Reformer aufrichtiges 
Walsh, war die Kommission in der Mitte des Nehmens des Zeugnisses von 
den Inhabern, von den Arbeitern und von den Reformern in den 
Dutzenden der industriellen Gemeinschaften um das Land, als der 
südliche Kolorado Kohleschlag spät 1913 ausbrach. Die Tötung 
von drei Frauen und von elf Kindern an einem gewinnenlager in Ludlow, 
Kolorado, auf Ostern Nacht, 1914, geschickt Stoßwellen über dem 
Land. Nach dem "Ludlow Blutbad", während es kam bekannt, hielt 
die Kommission allgemeine Hörfähigkeiten in Kolorado, in dem sie 
Grausigkeitgeschichten über die Brutalitäten und das rapacity des 
Rockefeller-besessenen Kolorados Fuel und Iron Company hörten, den 
größten Bediener der Region der Kohlengruben an. Diese Artikel
von den New York Zeiten beschrieben das Zeugnis von John D. 
Rockefeller, jr., vor der Kommission, in der er jedes mögliches 
Wissen der brutalen Tätigkeiten seiner Firma gegen die Ludlow 
Schlaggeräte verweigerte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les luttes de travail violentes du souci engendré
début du 20ème par siècle de tous les niveaux de la société et 
menés à la nomination d'une Commission fédérale sur des relations 
industrielles début 1913. Dirigé par Kansas City 
lawyer-réformateur Walsh franc, la commission était au milieu de 
prendre le témoignage des propriétaires, des ouvriers, et des 
réformateurs dans les douzaines des communautés industrielles dans le
pays quand la grève méridionale de charbon du Colorado a éclaté 
tard en 1913. Le massacre des trois femmes et des onze enfants 
à un campement d'extraction dans Ludlow, le Colorado, la nuit de 
Pâques, 1914, envoyé ondes chocs à travers le pays. Après le
"massacre de Ludlow," pendant qu'il venait pour être connu, la 
commission a tenu les hearings publics dans le Colorado où elles ont 
entendu des histoires d'horreur au sujet de la brutalité et du 
rapacity du Colorado Rockefeller-possédé Fuel et de Iron Company, le
plus grand opérateur de la région des mines de houille. Ces 
articles des temps de New York ont décrit le témoignage de John D. 
Rockefeller, Jr., devant la commission, où il a nié n'importe quelle
connaissance des actions brutales de sa compagnie contre les butées 
de Ludlow.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os esforços labor violentos 20o século adiantado
do interesse engendered em todos os níveis da sociedade e conduzidos 
à nomeação de um commission federal em relações industriais em 
1913 adiantado. Dirigido pelo franquia Walsh do 
advogado-reformer da cidade de kansas, o commission estava no meio de 
fazer exame do testimony dos proprietários, dos trabalhadores, e dos 
reformers nas dúzias de comunidades industriais em torno do país 
quando a batida do sul de carvão de Colorado erupted tarde em 1913. 
A matança de três mulheres e de onze crianças em um 
encampment minando em Ludlow, Colorado, na noite de Easter, 1914, 
emitido ondas de choque através do país. Após de "o massacre 
Ludlow," enquanto veio ser sabido, o commission prendeu os hearings 
públicos em Colorado onde ouviu histórias do horror sobre o 
brutality e o rapacity do Colorado Rockefeller-possuído Combustível 
e de Ferro Companhia, operador o maior da região de minas de carvão.
Estes artigos dos tempos de New York descreveram o testimony de 
John D. Rockefeller, Jr., antes do commission, onde negou todo o 
conhecimento de ações brutais da sua companhia de encontro aos 
grevistas de Ludlow.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le lotte di lavoro violente della preoccupazione
generata inizio del 20esimo secolo a tutti i livelli della società e 
condotti alla nomina di una Commissione federale sulle relazione 
industriali all'inizio di 1913. Diretto dalla firma di 
franchigia Walsh dell'avvocato-reformer de Kansas City, la commissione
in mezzo a stava prendendo la testimonianza dai proprietari, dagli 
operai e dai reformers nelle dozzine delle Comunità industriali 
intorno al paese quando il colpo del sud del carbone del Colorado ha 
scoppiato in ritardo in 1913. L'uccisione di tre donne e
di undici bambini ad un encampment estraente in Ludlow, Colorado, 
sulla notte di Pasqua, 1914, trasmesso ad onde di scossa attraverso il
paese. Dopo "il massacre di Ludlow," mentre è venuto essere 
conosciuto, la commissione ha tenuto le udienze pubbliche in Colorado 
in cui hanno sentito le storia di orrore circa il brutality ed il 
rapacity del Colorado Rockefeller-posseduto Fuel e di Iron Company, il
più grande operatore della regione delle miniere di carbone. 
Questi articoli dai tempi de New York hanno descritto la 
testimonianza di John D. Rockefeller, Jr., prima della commissione, in
cui ha negato tutta la conoscenza delle azioni brutali della sua 
azienda contro i percussori di Ludlow.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι βίαιες προσπάθειες εργασίας του πρόωρου 20ού 
αιώνα προκάλεσαν την ανησυχία σε όλα τα επίπεδα της κοινωνίας 
και οδήγησαν στο διορισμό της ομοσπονδιακής Επιτροπής στις 
εργασιακές σχέσεις σε πρόωρα 1913, που διευθύνθηκαν από τον 
δικηγόρος-μεταρρυθμιστή Frank Walsh πόλεων του Κάνσας, η 
επιτροπή ήταν στη μέση της λήψης της κατάθεσης από τους 
ιδιοκτήτες, τους εργαζομένους, και τους μεταρρυθμιστές στις 
δωδεκάδες των βιομηχανικών κοινοτήτων γύρω από τη χώρα όταν 
εξερράγη η νότια απεργία άνθρακα του Κολοράντο στα τέλη του 
1913. Η δολοφονία τριών γυναικών και ένδεκα παιδιών σε 
μια στρατοπέδευση μεταλλείας σε Ludlow, Κολοράντο, στη νύχτα 
Πάσχας, 1914, έστειλε τα κύματα κλονισμού σε ολόκληρη τη 
χώρα. Μετά από τη "σφαγή Ludlow," καθώς ήρθε να 
μαθευτεί, η επιτροπή οργάνωσε τις δημόσιες ακροάσεις στο 
Κολοράντο όπου άκουσαν τις ιστορίες φρίκης για τη βιαιότητα και 
την αρπακτικότητα της ροθκεφελλερ-κύριας επιχείρησης καυσίμων και 
σιδήρου του Κολοράντο, ο μεγαλύτερος χειριστής της περιοχής των 
ορυχείων άνθρακα. Αυτά τα άρθρα από τους New York 
Times περιέγραψαν την κατάθεση John D. Rockefeller, 
νεώτερος, ενώπιον της επιτροπής, όπου αρνήθηκε οποιαδήποτε 
γνώση των βάναυσων ενεργειών της επιχείρησής του ενάντια στους 
απεργούς Ludlow.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las luchas de trabajo violentas vigésimo de la 
preocupación engendrada siglo temprano en todos los niveles de la 
sociedad y conducidos a la cita de una Comisión federal en relaciones
laborales a principios de 1913. Dirigido por la ciudad de Kansas
lawyer-reformador Walsh franco, la comisión estaba en el medio de tomar
testimonio de propietarios, de trabajadores, y de reformadores en 
docenas de comunidades industriales alrededor del país cuando la 
huelga meridional del carbón de Colorado entró en erupción tarde en
1913. La matanza de tres mujeres y de once niños en un 
campamento que mina en Ludlow, Colorado, el la noche de Pascua, 1914, 
enviado ondas expansivas a través del país. Después de que la
"masacre de Ludlow," como vino ser sabida, la comisión llevara a 
cabo audiencias públicas en Colorado en donde ella oyó historias del
horror sobre la brutalidad y el rapacity del Colorado 
Rockefeller-posei'do Fuel y de Iron Company, el operador más grande 
de la región de las minas de carbón. Estos artículos a partir
de los tiempos de Nueva York describieron el testimonio de Juan D. 
Rockefeller, Jr., ante la comisión, donde él negó cualquier 
conocimiento de las acciones brutales de su compañía contra los 
huelguistas de Ludlow.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086324</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103125</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/in-the-hot-seat-rockefeller-testifies-on-ludlow</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
