<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106484</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106484</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207143</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">America at Work, America at Leisure, 1894-1915</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerika an der Arbeit, Amerika an Freizeit, 
1894-1915</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Amérique au travail, Amérique aux loisirs, 
1894-1915</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">América no trabalho, América no lazer, 
1894-1915</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'America sul lavoro, America a svago, 1894-1915</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερική στην εργασία, Αμερική στον ελεύθερο χρόνο, 
1894-1915</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">América en el trabajo, América en el ocio, 
1894-1915</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features motion pictures that showcase work, school, and leisure activities in the U.S. in the late 19th and early 20th century. The site includes films of the U.S. Postal Service from 1903, cattle breeding, fire fighters, ice manufacturing, logging, calisthenics and gymnastic exercises in schools, amusement parks, boxing, expositions, football, parades, swimming, and other sporting events.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet Bewegung Abbildungen, die Arbeit, 
Schule und Freizeitaktivitäten in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN im des 
späten 19. jahrhunderts und früh 20. Jahrhundert zur Schau stellen. 
Die Site enthält Filme des VEREINIGTE STAATEN Postservices von 
1903, der Viehzucht, der Feuerkämpfer, der Eisherstellung, des 
Protokollierens, der Calisthenics und der gymnastic Übungen in den 
Schulen, der Vergnügungsparks, des Verpackens, der Ausstellungen, des
Fußballs, der Paraden, der Schwimmens und anderer sporting Fälle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte les films cinématographiques qui 
présentent le travail, l'école, et les activités de loisirs en les 
ETATS-UNIS vers la fin du 19ème et début du 20ème siècle. Le
site inclut des films du service postal des ETATS-UNIS de 1903, 
l'élevage de bétail, des combattants du feu, fabrication de glace, 
enregistrement, gymnastique suédoise et des exercices gymnastiques 
dans les écoles, des parcs d'amusement, boxe, des expositions, 
football, des défilés, natation, et d'autres événements sportifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza os retratos de movimento que showcase 
o trabalho, a escola, e as atividades de lazer nos ESTADOS UNIDOS no 
1øs atrasado e cedo no 20o século. O local inclui películas 
do serviço postal de ESTADOS UNIDOS de 1903, produzir de gado, 
lutadores do fogo, manufacturing do gelo, registrar, calisthenics e 
exercícios gymnastic nas escolas, parques de divertimento, boxing, 
exposições, football, paradas, natação, e outros eventos 
ostentando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza il cinema che montra il 
lavoro, la scuola e le attività di svago negli STATI UNITI verso la 
fine del diciannovesimo e l'inizio del 20esimo secolo. Il luogo 
include le pellicole del servizio postale degli STATI UNITI da 1903, 
allevamento di bestiami, combattenti del fuoco, manufacturing del 
ghiaccio, annotare, calisthenics ed esercitazioni gymnastic in scuole,
parchi di divertimento, boxing, esposizioni, il gioco del calcio, 
parate, swimming ed altri eventi di sport.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τις ταινίες που επιδεικνύουν την εργασία,
το σχολείο, και τις δραστηριότητες ελεύθερου χρόνου στις ΗΠΑ προς 
το τέλος του 19$ου και το 20ό νωρίς αιώνα. Η περιοχή 
περιλαμβάνει τις ταινίες της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ ταχυδρομικής υπηρεσίας 
από το 1903, της αναπαραγωγής βοοειδών, των πυροσβεστών, της 
κατασκευής πάγου, της καταγραφής, της σωματικής αγωγής και των 
γυμναστικών ασκήσεων στα σχολεία, των πάρκων διασκέδασης, του 
εγκιβωτισμού, των εκθέσεων, του ποδοσφαίρου, των παρελάσεων, της 
κολύμβησης, και άλλων αθλητικών γεγονότων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece las películas que showcase el trabajo, la 
escuela, y pasatiempos en los ESTADOS UNIDOS en los último 
diecinueveavo y temprano el vigésimo siglo. El sitio incluye 
las películas del servicio postal de ESTADOS UNIDOS a partir de 1903,
crianza de ganados, los combatientes del fuego, fabricación del 
hielo, registración, las calisténica y los ejercicios gimnásticos 
en escuelas, los parques de atracciones, boxeo, las exposiciones, 
balompié, los desfiles, natación, y otros acontecimientos que se 
divierten.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207143</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106484</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/america-at-work-america-at-leisure-1894-1915</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
