<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104592</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104592</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087015</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Pageant as a Form of Propaganda": Reviews of the Paterson Strike Pageant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Pageant als Formular von Propaganda": 
Zusammenfassungen des Paterson Schlagpageant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la reconstitution historique comme forme de la 
propagande" : Examens de la reconstitution historique de grève 
de Paterson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o pageant como um formulário do propaganda": 
Revisões do pageant da batida de Paterson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"lo Spettacolo come forma di propaganda": 
Rassegne dello Spettacolo di colpo di Paterson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το θέαμα ως μορφή της προπαγάνδασ": 
Αναθεωρήσεις του θεάματος απεργίας Paterson</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el desfile como forma de propaganda": 
Revisiones del desfile de la huelga de Paterson</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1913, silk workers in Paterson, New Jersey, went on strike. Journalist John Reed--one of the artists and intellectuals who made New York City's Greenwich Village a center of bohemian culture--decided to mount a massive public pageant to publicize the strike and raise money for the strikers. He won financial backing from art patron Mabel Dodge and enlisted artists such as John Sloan, who painted a ninety-foot backdrop depicting the Paterson silk mills. The pageant opened on June 7 in Madison Square Garden, ending with the workers and the audience triumphantly singing the "Internationale," the anthem of international socialism. Neither the pageant nor the strike were triumphant: the pageant lost money while the strike ended in defeat after five months. Nonetheless, the pageant represented an important moment in the alliance between modern art and labor radicalism. The pageant also focused media attention on the strike, as shown in these June 1913 articles from  Current Opinion  and  Survey .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1913 streikten silk Arbeiter in Paterson, 
Neu-Jersey. Journalist-John Schilf -- einer der Künstler und 
der Intellektuellen, die Greenwich Village Der New York Stadt eine 
Mitte von der böhmischen Kultur bildeten -- entschied, einen massiven
allgemeinen Pageant einzuhängen, um den Schlag zu publizieren und 
Geld für die Schlaggeräte anzuheben. Er gewann finanziellen 
Schutzträger vom kunstgönner Mabel raschen Ausweichen und trug 
Künstler wie John Sloan ein, der einen Neunzigfuß Hintergrund malte,
der die Paterson Seidetausendstel bildlich darstellt. Der 
Pageant öffnete sich an Juni 7 Madison im quadratischen Garten und 
beendete mit den Arbeitern und den Publikum, die triumphierend das 
"Internationale," die Hymne des internationalen sozialismus 
singen. Weder waren der Pageant noch der Schlag triumphierend: 
der Pageant verlor Geld, während der Schlag in der Niederlage 
nach fünf Monaten beendete. Nichtsdestoweniger stellte der 
Pageant einen wichtigen Moment im Bündnis zwischen moderner kunst und
Arbeit Radikalismus dar. Die fokussierte Mediaaufmerksamkeit 
des Pageant auch auf dem Schlag, wie in diesen Juni 1913 Artikeln von 
der aktuellen Meinung und von der Übersicht gezeigt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1913, les ouvriers en soie dans Paterson, 
New Jersey, ont fait la grève. Le roseau de John de journaliste
-- un des artistes et des intellectuels qui ont fait à village de 
Greenwich de la ville de New York un centre de la culture de Bohème 
-- a décidé de monter une reconstitution historique publique massive
pour donner de la publicité à la grève et pour soulever l'argent 
pour les butées. Il a gagné l'aide financière du détour de 
Mabel de patron d'art et a enrôlé des artistes tels que John Sloan, 
qui a peint un contexte de quatre-vingt-dix-pied dépeignant les 
moulins de soie de Paterson. La reconstitution historique s'est 
ouverte juin 7 dans le jardin carré de Madison, terminant avec les 
ouvriers et les assistances chantant triomphantement 
l'"Internationale," le hymne du socialisme international. 
Ni la reconstitution historique ni la grève n'étaient 
triomphante : la reconstitution historique a détruit l'argent 
tandis que la grève terminait dans la défaite après cinq mois. 
Néanmoins, la reconstitution historique a représenté un 
moment important dans l'alliance entre l'art et le radicalisme modernes
de travail. L'attention également focalisée de medias de 
reconstitution historique sur la grève, comme montré en ces articles
de juin 1913 d'opinion et d'étude actuelles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1913, os trabalhadores de seda em Paterson, 
Novo-Jersey, foram na batida. A lingüeta de John do journalist 
-- um dos artistas e dos intelectuais que fizeram a vila de Greenwich 
da cidade de New York um centro da cultura bohemian -- decidiu-se 
montar um pageant público maciço para publicize a batida e para 
levantar o dinheiro para os grevistas. Ganhou o revestimento 
protetor financeiro do rodeio de Mabel do patron da arte e alistou 
artistas tais como John Sloan, que pintou um backdrop de ninety-pé 
que descreve os moinhos da seda de Paterson. O pageant abriu 
junho em 7 no jardim quadrado de Madison, terminando com os 
trabalhadores e as audiências que cantam triunfante o 
"Internationale," o anthem do socialismo internacional. Nem o 
pageant nem a batida eram triunfante: o pageant perdeu o 
dinheiro quando a batida terminou na derrota após cinco meses. 
Nonetheless, o pageant representou um momento importante no 
alliance entre a arte e o radicalism modernos do trabalho. A 
atenção também focalizada dos media do pageant na batida, como 
mostrado nestes artigos de junho 1913 da opinião e do exame atuais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1913, gli operai di seta in Paterson, 
Nuovo-Jersey, sono andato sul colpo. La canna del John del 
giornalista -- uno degli artisti e degli intellettuali che hanno reso 
a villaggio di Greenwich della città de New York un centro di coltura
della Boemia -- ha deciso montare uno spettacolo pubblico voluminoso 
per divulg il colpo e per alzare i soldi per i percussori. Ha 
vinto la protezione finanziaria dall'espediente di Mabel del patrono 
di arte ed ha arruolato gli artisti quale John Sloan, che ha 
verniciato un contesto del novanta-piede che descrive i laminatoi 
della seta di Paterson. Lo spettacolo si è aperto il 7 giugno 
nel giardino quadrato de Madison, concludendosi con gli operai ed i 
pubblici che cantano trionfalmente "il Internationale," il anthem del 
socialism internazionale. Nè lo spettacolo nè il colpo era 
trionfante: lo spettacolo ha perso i soldi mentre il colpo si 
è concluso nella sconfitta dopo cinque mesi. Ciò nonostante, 
lo spettacolo ha rappresentato un momento importante nell'alleanza 
fra l'arte ed il radicalism moderni di lavoro. L'attenzione
anche messa a fuoco di media di spettacolo sul colpo, come indicato 
in questi articoli di giugno 1913 dall'opinione e dall'indagine 
correnti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1913, οι εργαζόμενοι μεταξιού σε Paterson, Νιου
Τζέρσεϋ, πήγαν στην απεργία. Ο δημοσιογράφος John 
Reed -- ένας από τους καλλιτέχνες και τους διανοούμενους που 
έκαναν το χωριό του Γκρήνουιτς της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης ένα 
κέντρο του Βοημίας πολιτισμού -- αποφάσισε να επικολλήσει ένα 
ογκώδες δημόσιο θέαμα για να κοινοποιήσει την απεργία και να 
συγκεντρώσει τα χρήματα για τους απεργούς. Κέρδισε την 
οικονομική υποστήριξη από το τέχνασμα Mabel προστατών τέχνης 
και στρατολόγησε τους καλλιτέχνες όπως John Sloan, ο οποίος 
χρωμάτισε ένα φόντο ενενήντα-ποδιών απεικονίζοντας τους μύλους 
μεταξιού Paterson. Το θέαμα άνοιξε στις 7 Ιουνίου στον 
τετραγωνικό κήπο του Μάντισον, που τελειώνει με τους εργαζομένους
και το ακροατήριο που τραγουδούν triumphantly το 
"Internationale," ο ύμνος του διεθνούς σοσιαλισμού. Ούτε 
το θέαμα ούτε η απεργία δεν ήταν θριαμβευτικό: το θέαμα 
έχασε τα χρήματα ενώ η απεργία τελείωσε στην ήττα μετά από 
πέντε μήνες. Εν τούτοις, το θέαμα αντιπροσώπευσε μια 
σημαντική στιγμή στη συμμαχία μεταξύ της μοντέρνων τέχνης και 
της ριζοσπαστισμού εργασίας. Το θέαμα έστρεψε επίσης την 
προσοχή μέσων στην απεργία, όπως φαίνεται σε αυτά τα άρθρα 
Ιουνίου 1913 από την παρούσες Γνώμη και την έρευνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1913, los trabajadores de seda en Paterson, 
Nuevo-Jersey, fueron en huelga. La caña de Juan del periodista 
-- uno de los artistas y de los intelectuales que hicieron aldea de 
Greenwich de la ciudad de Nueva York un centro de cultura bohemia -- 
decidía a montar un desfile público masivo para publicar la huelga y
para levantar el dinero para los huelguistas. Él ganó el forro
financiero del regate de Mabel el patrón del arte y alistó a 
artistas tales como Juan Sloan, que pintó un contexto del noventa-pie
que representaba los molinos de la seda de Paterson. El desfile 
se abrió 7 de junio en el jardín cuadrado de Madison, terminando 
con los trabajadores y las audiencias que cantaban triunfante el 
"Internationale," el himno del socialismo internacional. Ni el 
desfile ni la huelga era triunfante: el desfile perdió el 
dinero mientras que la huelga terminó en derrota después de cinco 
meses. No obstante, el desfile representó un momento importante
en la alianza entre el arte y el radicalismo modernos del trabajo. 
La atención también enfocada de los media del desfile en la 
huelga, según lo mostrado en estos artículos de junio 1913 de la 
opinión y de la encuesta actuales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087015</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104592</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-pageant-as-a-form-of-propaganda-reviews-of-the-paterson-strike-pageant</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
