<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107855</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107855</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086954</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Harlem Renaissance: Zora Neale Hurston's First Story</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Harlem Renaissance: Zora Neale Hurstons 
Erste Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Renaissance de Harlem : Première 
Histoire de Zora Neale Hurston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Renascimento De Harlem: Primeira História
De Zora Neale Hurston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Rinascita Di Harlem: Prima Storia Di Zora
Neale Hurston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αναγέννηση Harlem: Πρώτη ιστορία της Zora
Neale Hurston's</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Renacimiento De Harlem: Primera Historia 
De Zora Neale Hurston</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Hundreds of writers and artists lived in Harlem in the 1920s and 1930s and were part of a vibrant, creative community that found its voice in what came to be called the "Harlem Renaissance." Alain Locke's 1925 collection  The New Negro --a compilation of literature by and essays about "New Negro" artists and black culture--became a "manifesto" of the movement. Some of black America's foremost writers contributed stories and poems to the volume. The work of these artists drew upon the African-American experience and expressed a new pride in black racial identity and heritage. Zora Neale Hurston--novelist, folklorist, and anthropologist--was known during the Harlem Renaissance for her wit, irreverence, and folk writing style. She won second prize in the 1925 literary contest of the Urban League's journal,  Opportunity , for her short story "Spunk," which also appeared in  The New Negro .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hunderte Verfasser und Künstler wohnten in Harlem
in den zwanziger Jahren und in den dreißiger Jahren und waren ein 
Teil einer vibrant, kreativen Gemeinschaft, die seine Stimme fand in, 
was kam, genannt zu werden die "Harlem Renaissance." Alain 
Lockes 1925 Ansammlung die neue Schwarze --a Kompilation der Literatur
der vorbei und Versuche über Künstler "des neuen Schwarzen" und 
schwarze Kultur -- wurde ein "Manifest" der Bewegung. 
Einige von schwarzen Amerikas vordersten Verfassern trugen 
Geschichten und Gedichte zum Datenträger bei. Die Arbeit dieser
Künstler zeichnete nach der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Erfahrung und 
drückte einen neuen Stolz in der schwarzen rassischen Identität und 
im Erbe aus. Zora Neale Hurston -- Novelist, Folklorist und 
Anthropologe -- bekannt während der Harlem Renaissance für ihren 
Esprit, Respektlosigkeit und Volksschreibweise. Sie gewann 
zweiten Preis im 1925 literarischen Wettbewerb des städtischen 
Journals der Liga, Gelegenheit, für ihre kurze Geschichte "Spunk,", 
die auch im neuen Schwarzen erschien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les centaines d'auteurs et artistes ont habité 
dans Harlem dans les années 20 et les années 30 et faisaient 
partie d'une communauté vibrante et créatrice qui a trouvé sa 
voix dans ce qui est venu pour s'appeler la "Renaissance de 
Harlem." Collection d'Alain Locke 1925 la nouvelle 
compilation de --a de nègre de la littérature près et des essais au
sujet des artistes de "nouveau nègre" et de la culture noire -- est 
devenu un "manifeste" du mouvement. Certains des premiers 
auteurs de l'Amérique noire ont contribué des histoires et des 
poésies au volume. Le travail de ces artistes a utilisé 
l'expérience afro-américaine et a exprimé une nouvelle fierté en 
identité et héritage raciaux noirs. Zora Neale Hurston -- 
romancier, folkloriste, et anthropologue -- a été connu pendant la 
Renaissance de Harlem pour son esprit, irrévérence, et modèle 
d'écriture folklorique. Elle a gagné le deuxième prix dans 
1925 le concours littéraire du journal de la ligue urbaine, occasion,
pour sa histoire courte "Spunk," qui est également apparue dans le 
nouveau nègre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As centenas dos escritores e dos artistas viveram 
em Harlem nos 1920s e nos 1930s e foram parte de uma comunidade 
vibrant, creativa que encontrasse sua voz em o que veio ser chamado de
"o renascimento Harlem." Coleção de Alain Locke 1925 a 
compilação nova do --a do negro da literatura perto e dos essays 
sobre "artistas do negro novo" e a cultura preta -- tornou-se um 
"manifesto" do movimento. Alguns de escritores foremost de 
América preta contribuíram histórias e poemas ao volume. O 
trabalho destes artistas desenhou em cima da experiência 
Africano-Americana e expressou um orgulho novo na identidade e no 
heritage raciais pretos. Zora Neale Hurston -- novelist, 
folklorist, e antropólogo -- foi conhecido durante o renascimento de 
Harlem para seus sagacidade, irreverence, e estilo de escrita popular.
Ganhou o segundo prêmio 1925 na competição literária do 
jornal da liga urbana, oportunidade, para sua história curta "Spunk,"
que apareceu também no negro novo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I centinaia dei produttori e degli artisti hanno 
vissuto in Harlem negli anni 20 e nei 1930s e facevano parte di una 
Comunità vibrant e creativa che ha trovato la relativa voce in che 
cosa è venuto essere chiamato "la rinascita di Harlem." 
Accumulazione di Alain Locke 1925 la nuova compilazione di --a 
del negro di letteratura vicino e dei saggi circa "gli artisti del 
nuovo negro" e la coltura nera -- è diventato "un manifesto" del 
movimento. Alcuni di primi produttori dell'America nera hanno 
contribuito le storia ed i poems al volume. Il lavoro di questi 
artisti ha dissipato sull'esperienza Africano-Americana ed ha espresso
un nuovo orgoglio nell'identità e nell'eredità razziali nere. 
Zora Neale Hurston -- romanziere, folklorist ed antropologo -- è 
stato conosciuto durante la rinascita di Harlem per il suoi spirito, 
irreverence e stile di scrittura piega. Ha vinto il secondo 
premio 1925 nel concorso letterario del giornale della lega urbana, 
occasione, per la sua storia corta "Spunk," che egualmente è comparso
nel nuovo negro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εκατοντάδες των συγγραφέων και των καλλιτεχνών 
έζησαν σε Harlem στη δεκαετία του '20 και τη δεκαετία του '30 
και ήταν μέρος μιας δονούμενης, δημιουργικής κοινότητας που 
βρήκε τη φωνή της σε αυτό που ήρθε να κληθεί "αναγέννηση 
Harlem." Συλλογή του 1925 του Alain Locke's η νέα 
μεταγλώττιση νέγρων AA της λογοτεχνίας κοντά και των δοκίμιων 
για τους καλλιτέχνες "νέων νέγρων" και το μαύρο πολιτισμό -- 
έγινε ένα "μανιφέστο" της μετακίνησης. Μερικοί από τους 
πρώτιστους συγγραφείς της μαύρης Αμερικής συνέβαλαν τις ιστορίες
και τα ποιήματα στην ένταση του ήχου. Η εργασία αυτών των 
καλλιτεχνών βασίστηκε στην αφρικανικός-αμερικανική εμπειρία και 
εξέφρασε μια νέα υπερηφάνεια στη μαύρες φυλετικές ταυτότητα και 
την κληρονομιά. Η Zora Neale Hurston -- 
μυθιστοριογράφος, folklorist, και ανθρωπολόγος -- ήταν γνωστή 
κατά τη διάρκεια της αναγέννησης Harlem για το πνεύμα της, της 
ασέβειας, και του λαϊκού ύφους γραψίματος. Κέρδισε το 
δεύτερο βραβείο στο λογοτεχνικό διαγωνισμό του 1925 του 
περιοδικού της αστικής ένωσης, ευκαιρία, για τη σύντομη ιστορία 
της "Spunk," που εμφανίστηκε επίσης στο νέο νέγρο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los centenares de programas de escritura y de 
artistas vivieron en Harlem en los años 20 y los años 30 y eran 
parte de una comunidad vibrante, creativa que encontró su voz en 
qué vino ser llamada el "renacimiento de Harlem." Colección de
Alain Locke 1925 la nueva compilación del --a del negro de la 
literatura cerca y de los ensayos sobre artistas del "nuevo negro" y 
cultura negra -- se convirtió un "manifiesto" del movimiento. 
Algunos de los primeros programas de escritura de América negra
contribuyeron historias y los poemas al volumen. El trabajo de 
estos artistas trazó sobre la experiencia Africano-Americana y 
expresó un nuevo orgullo en identidad y herencia raciales negras. 
Zora Neale Hurston -- novelista, folklorist, y antropólogo -- 
era conocido durante el renacimiento de Harlem para su ingenio, 
irreverence, y estilo de escritura popular. Ella ganó el 
segundo premio en 1925 la competencia literaria del diario de la liga 
urbana, oportunidad, para su historia corta "Spunk," que también 
apareció en el nuevo negro.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086954</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107855</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-harlem-renaissance-zora-neale-hurstons-first-story</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
