<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103894</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103894</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086664</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"No Heat, No Water . . . and a Large Sign Reading 'Colored'": Inequality in "Separate but Equal" Railroad Accommodations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Keine Hitze, Kein Wasser. . . 
und ein großer Zeichen-Messwert ' gefärbt ' ": 
Verschiedenheit in "trennen, aber entsprechen" 
Eisenbahn-Anpassungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Aucune Chaleur, Aucune Eau. . . 
et une grande lecture de signe 'colorée '": L'inégalité
dans "séparent mais égalent" le logement de chemin de fer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nenhum Calor, Nenhuma Água. . . 
e uma leitura grande do sinal ' colorida ' ": O 
desigualdade em "separa mas iguala" acomodações da estrada de ferro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Nessun Calore, Nessun'Acqua. . . 
e una grande lettura del segno 'colorata '": La 
diseguaglianza in "separa ma è uguali" le sistemazioni della 
ferrovia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Καμία θερμότητα, κανένα ύδωρ. .. και μια 
ανάγνωση σημαδιών "που χρωματίζεται μεγάλη" ": Ανισότητα 
στις "χωριστές αλλά ίσεσ" στεγάσεις σιδηροδρόμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Ningún Calor, Ninguna Agua. . . 
y una lectura grande de la muestra ' coloreada ' ": La 
desigualdad en "separa pero iguala" comodidades del ferrocarril</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The first laws passed in the South to impose statewide segregation in public facilities, instituted in the 1880s and 1890s, applied to railroad car seating. During this period, railway lines spread rapidly from cities to rural communities. In 1896, the U.S. Supreme Court validated these early "Jim Crow" laws when it ruled in  Plessy  v.  Ferguson  that a Louisiana statute requiring "separate but equal" accommodations for white and black railroad passengers did not conflict with the Fourteenth Amendment clause guaranteeing all citizens equal protection of the laws. (Jim Crow, the colloquial term for segregation, referred to a blackface character popular on the minstrel stage.) Jim Crow legislation extended throughout the South to schools, hotels, restaurants, streetcars, buses, theaters, hospitals, parks, courthouses, and even cemeteries. Although the Supreme Court ruled in 1946 that a Virginia statute requiring segregated seating interfered with interstate commerce and was thus invalid, Jim Crow travel laws remained in effect in the South. The following letter submitted to a House committee holding hearings in 1954 on legislation to end segregated travel attested to the substandard condition of railroad cars for blacks. The bills under consideration never made it to the House floor for a vote. In 1956, following a boycott by the black community of Montgomery, Alabama, against the city's segregated bus system, the Supreme Court ruled segregation on buses unconstitutional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die ersten Gesetze überschritten in den Süden, 
um Nationalabtrennung in den allgemeinen Teildiensten aufzuerlegen, 
eingeleitet im 1880s und im 1890s, angewendet an den 
Eisenbahnautositzplätzen. Während dieser Periode verbritten 
Bahnlinien schnell von den Städte zu den landwirtschaftlichen 
Gemeinschaften. 1896 validierte das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchste 
Gericht diese frühen "Jim Krähe" Gesetze, als es in Plessy V. 
Ferguson anordnete, daß ein benötigendes Louisiana Gesetz "trennen, 
aber" Anpassungen für Weißes entsprechen und schwarze 
Eisenbahnpassagiere nicht mit der vierzehnte Änderung Klausel 
widersprachen, die allem gleichen Schutz der Bürger der Gesetze 
garantiert. (Jim Krähe, die mündliche Bezeichnung für 
Abtrennung, sprach ein blackface Zeichen an, das auf dem 
Minnesängerstadium. populär ist) Jim Krähegesetzgebung dehnte
sich während des Südens auf Schulen, Hotels, Gaststätten, 
streetcars, Busse, Theater, Krankenhäuser, Parks, Gerichte und sogar 
Kirchhöfe aus. Obgleich das Höchste Gericht 1946, daß ein 
Virginia Gesetzbenötigen trennte, Sitzplätze behinderte landesweiten
Handel und war folglich Invalides, Jim Krähe anordnete, Spielraum, 
dengesetze bestehen im Süden blieb. Das folgende Zeichen gab 
bei einem Hausausschuß ein, der Hörfähigkeiten 1954 für 
Gesetzgebung zum Ende getrennten Spielraum anhält, der zum nicht der 
Norm entsprechenden Zustand der Eisenbahnautos für Schwarze bezeugt 
wurde. Die Rechnungen in Erwägung bildeten es nie zum 
Hausfußboden für eine Stimme. 1956 einem Boykott von der 
schwarzen Gemeinschaft von Montgomery, Alabama, gegen das getrennte 
Bussystem der Stadt folgend, ordnete das Höchste Gericht Abtrennung 
auf den verfassungswidrigen Bussen an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les premières lois ont passé dans les 
Sud pour imposer la ségrégation par état dans les 
équipements publics, institués dans le 1880s et le 1890s, appliqués
à l'allocation des places de voiture de chemin de fer. Pendant 
cette période, les lignes ferroviaires ont écarté rapidement des 
villes aux communautés rurales. En 1896, la cour suprême des 
ETATS-UNIS a validé ces lois tôt "de corneille de Jim" quand elle a 
régné dans Plessy v. Ferguson qu'un statut de la Louisiane exigeant 
"séparent mais égalent" le logement pour blanc et les passagers 
noirs de chemin de fer n'étaient pas en conflit avec la clause du 
quatorzième amendement garantissant toute la protection égale de 
citoyens des lois. (la corneille de Jim, la limite familière 
pour la ségrégation, s'est rapportée à un caractère de blackface 
populaire sur l'étape de troubadour.) La législation de 
corneille de Jim a étendu dans tous les Sud aux écoles, aux 
hôtels, aux restaurants, aux tramways, aux bus, aux théâtres, 
aux hôpitaux, aux parcs, aux tribunaux, et même aux cimetières. 
Bien que la cour suprême ait régné en 1946 qu'une exigence de
statut de la Virginie a isolé allocations des places ait gêné le 
commerce entre Etats et ait été ainsi invalide, corneille de Jim que
des lois de voyage est demeurée en effet dans les Sud. 
La lettre suivante a soumis à un comité de Chambre tenant des 
auditions en 1954 sur la législation sur le voyage isolé par 
extrémité certifié à l'état inférieur des voitures de chemin de 
fer pour des noirs. Les factures à l'étude ne l'ont jamais 
fait au plancher de Chambre pour une voix. En 1956, suivant un 
boycott de la communauté noire de Montgomery, Alabama, contre le 
système isolé du bus de la ville, la cour suprême a régné la 
ségrégation sur des bus inconstitutionnels.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As primeiras leis passaram no sul para impo o 
segregation statewide nas facilidades públicas, instituídas no 1880s
e no 1890s, aplicados ao assento do carro da estrada de ferro. 
Durante este período, as linhas railway espalharam ràpidamente
das cidades às comunidades rurais. Em 1896, a corte suprema de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS validou estas de "leis adiantadas do corvo Jim" quando 
governou em Plessy v. Ferguson que um statute de Louisiana que requer 
"separa mas iguala" acomodações para branco e os passageiros pretos 
da estrada de ferro não opuseram à cláusula da décima quarta 
emenda que garante toda a proteção igual dos cidadãos das leis. 
(corvo de Jim, o termo colloquial para o segregation, consultado
a um caráter do blackface popular no estágio do minstrel.) A 
legislação do corvo de Jim estendeu durante todo o sul às escolas, 
aos hotéis, aos restaurantes, aos streetcars, às barras-ônibus, aos
teatros, aos hospitais, aos parques, aos tribunais, e mesmo aos 
cemeteries. Embora a corte suprema governasse em 1946 que reque 
do statute de Virgínia segregou assentos interferisse com o comércio
interstate e fosse assim invalid, corvo de Jim leis do curso que 
remanesceu de fato no sul. A seguinte letra submeteu-se a um 
comitê da casa que prende hearings em 1954 na legislação ao curso 
segregado extremidade atestado à condição substandard de carros da 
estrada de ferro para pretos. As contas sob a consideração 
nunca fizeram-na ao assoalho da casa para um voto. Em 1956, 
seguindo um boycott pela comunidade preta de Montgomery, Alabama, de 
encontro ao sistema segregado da barra-ônibus da cidade, a corte 
suprema governou o segregation nas barras-ônibus unconstitutional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le prime leggi hanno passato nel sud per imporre 
la segregazione in tutto lo stato nelle attrezzature pubbliche, 
istituite nel 1880s e nel 1890s, applicati alla disposizione dei posti
a sedere dell'automobile della ferrovia. Durante questo periodo,
le righe ferroviarie si sono sparse velocemente dalle città alle 
Comunità rurali. In 1896, la Corte suprema degli STATI UNITI ha
convalidato queste "leggi iniziali del corvo di Jim" quando ha 
regolato in Plessy v. Ferguson che uno statuto della Luisiana che 
richiede "separa ma è uguali" le sistemazioni per bianco ed i 
passeggeri neri della ferrovia non hanno stato in conflitto con la 
clausola di fourteenth correzione che garantisce tutta la protezione 
uguale dei cittadini delle leggi. (il corvo di Jim, il termine 
familiare per la segregazione, si è riferito ad un carattere del 
blackface popolare sulla fase del minstrel.) La legislazione del
corvo di Jim si è estesa durante il sud fino le scuole, gli hotel, i 
ristoranti, gli streetcars, i bus, i teatri, gli ospedali, i parchi, i
courthouses e perfino i cimiteri. Anche se la Corte suprema ha 
regolato in 1946 che richiedere dello statuto della Virginia ha 
segregato disposizioni dei posti a sedere ha interferito con il 
commercio da uno stato all'altro ed era così invalid, corvo di Jim 
leggi di corsa che è rimasto in effetti nel sud. La seguente 
lettera ha presentato alle udienze della Camera della tenuta del 
comitato in 1954 su legislazione alla corsa segregata estremità 
attestata allo stato inferiore alla media degli automobili della 
ferrovia per i neri. Le fatture allo studio non lo hanno fatto 
mai al pavimento della Camera per un voto. In 1956, seguendo un 
boicottaggio dalla Comunità nera di Montgomery, Alabama, contro il 
sistema segregato del bus della città, la Corte suprema ha regolato 
la segregazione sui bus inconstituzionali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι πρώτοι νόμοι που περνούν στο νότο για να επιβάλει 
τον εθνικό διαχωρισμό στις δημόσιες εγκαταστάσεις, που 
καθιερώνονται στο 1880s και το 1890s, που εφαρμόζονται στη 
διάταξη θέσεων αυτοκινήτων σιδηροδρόμου. Κατά τη διάρκεια 
αυτής της περιόδου, γραμμές σιδηροδρόμων που διαδίδονται γρήγορα
από τις πόλεις στις αγροτικές κοινότητες. Το 1896, το 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ανώτατο δικαστήριο επικύρωσε αυτούς τους πρόωρους 
"jim Crow" νόμους όταν κυβέρνησε Plessy V. Ferguson 
ότι ένα καταστατικό της Λουιζιάνας που απαιτεί τις "χωριστές 
αλλά ίσεσ" στεγάσεις για τους λευκούς και μαύρους επιβάτες 
σιδηροδρόμου δεν συγκρούστηκε με τη δέκατη τέταρτη πρόταση 
τροποποιήσεων εγγμένος σε όλους τους πολίτες την ίση προστασία 
των νόμων. (Jim Crow, ο κοινός όρος για το διαχωρισμό,
αναφέρθηκε σε έναν χαρακτήρα blackface δημοφιλή στο στάδιο 
τροβαδούρων.) Jim Crow η νομοθεσία επεκτάθηκε σε όλο 
το νότο στα σχολεία, τα ξενοδοχεία, τα εστιατόρια, τα τραμ, τους 
διαδρόμους, τα θέατρα, τα νοσοκομεία, τα πάρκα, τα δικαστήρια, 
και ακόμη και τα νεκροταφεία. Αν και το ανώτατο δικαστήριο 
διέταξε το 1946 ότι ένα καταστατικό της Βιρτζίνια που απαιτεί
τη διαχωρισμένη διάταξη θέσεων παρεμπόδισε το διακρατικό εμπόριο
και ήταν έτσι άκυρο, jim Crow οι νόμοι ταξιδιού παρέμειναν
ουσιαστικά στο νότο. Η ακόλουθη επιστολή που υποβλήθηκε 
στις ακροάσεις μιας σπιτιών επιτροπών εκμετάλλευσης το 1954 στη
νομοθεσία για να τελειώσει διαχώρισε το ταξίδι που βεβαιώθηκε 
στον κάτω του μετρίου όρο των αυτοκινήτων σιδηροδρόμου για τους 
Μαύρους. Οι λογαριασμοί υπό εξέταση δεν το έκαναν ποτέ στο
πάτωμα Βουλών για μια ψηφοφορία. Το 1956, μετά από ένα 
μποϊκοτάρισμα από τη μαύρη κοινότητα του Μοντγκόμερυ, Αλαμπάμα,
ενάντια στο διαχωρισμένο σύστημα διαδρόμων της πόλης, το ανώτατο
δικαστήριο διέταξε το διαχωρισμό στους διαδρόμους 
αντισυνταγματικούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los primeros leyes pasaron en el sur para imponer 
la segregación estatal en los recursos públicos, instituidos en el 
1880s y el 1890s, aplicados al asiento del coche del ferrocarril. 
Durante este período, las líneas ferroviarias se separaron 
rápidamente de ciudades a las comunidades rurales. En 1896, el 
Tribunal Supremo de ESTADOS UNIDOS validó estos "leyes tempranos del 
cuervo de Jim" cuando gobernó en Plessy v. Ferguson que un estatuto 
de Luisiana que requiere "separa pero iguala" las comodidades para 
blanco y los pasajeros negros del ferrocarril no estuvieron en 
conflicto con la cláusula de la catorcena enmienda que garantizaba 
toda la protección igual de los ciudadanos de los leyes. (el 
cuervo de Jim, el término familiar para la segregación, refirió a 
un carácter del blackface popular en la etapa del minstrel.) La
legislación del cuervo de Jim extendió a través del sur a las 
escuelas, a los hoteles, a los restaurantes, a los streetcars, a los 
megabuses, a los teatros, a los hospitales, a los parques, a los 
palacios de justicia, e incluso a los cementerios. Aunque el 
Tribunal Supremo gobernó en 1946 que el requerir del estatuto de 
Virginia segregó asientos interfirió con comercio de un estado a 
otro y era así invalid, cuervo de Jim que los leyes seguía habiendo 
del recorrido en efecto en el sur. La carta siguiente sometió a
un comité de la casa que llevaba a cabo audiencias en 1954 sobre la 
legislación al recorrido segregado extremo atestiguado a la 
condición inferior al nivel normal de los coches del ferrocarril para
los negros. Las cuentas bajo consideración nunca la hicieron al
suelo de la casa para un voto. En 1956, siguiendo un boicoteo de
la comunidad negra de Montgomery, Alabama, contra el sistema segregado
del megabus de la ciudad, el Tribunal Supremo gobernó la segregación
en los megabuses inconstitucionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086664</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103894</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/no-heat-no-water-and-a-large-sign-reading-colored-inequality-in-separate-but-equal-railroad-accommodations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
