<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105339</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105339</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205735</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Freer and Sackler Galleries: Education Programs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Freiere und Sackler Galerien: Ausbildung 
Programme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des galeries plus libres et de Sackler : 
Programmes D'Éducation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Galerias mais livres e de Sackler: Programas
Da Instrução</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gallerie di Sackler e più libere: Programmi
Di Formazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πιό ελεύθερος και στοές Sackler: Προγράμματα 
εκπαίδευσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Galerías más libres y de Sackler: 
Programas De la Educación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">feature two online activities about Asian Art, curriculum materials that can be purchased through the Freer and Sackler Galleries museum shop, and other resources that can be retrieved directly from the site. It has information about tours and workshops for school groups, and ImaginAsia, the weekly hands-on workshop designed in conjunction with the exhibitions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmal zwei Online-Dienst über asiatische kunst,
Lehrplanmaterialien, die durch das freiere und Sackler Galerie-Museum 
System gekauft werden können und andere Betriebsmittel, die direkt 
von der Site zurückgeholt werden können. Sie hat Informationen
über Touren und Werkstätten für Schulegruppen und ImaginAsia, die 
wöchentliche Blindeinschub Werkstatt, die in Verbindung mit den 
Ausstellungen konzipiert ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">activités en ligne du dispositif deux au sujet de
l'art asiatique, des matériaux de programme d'études qui peuvent 
être achetés par le système plus libre et de Sackler de galeries de
musée, et d'autres ressources qui peuvent être recherchées 
directement du site. Il a des informations sur des excursions et
des ateliers pour des groupes d'école, et ImaginAsia, l'atelier à 
commande manuelle hebdomadaire conçu en même temps que les 
expositions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">atividades em linha da característica dois sobre 
a arte asian, os materiais do curriculum que podem ser comprados 
através da loja mais livre e de Sackler das galerias do museu, e os 
outros recursos que podem ser recuperados diretamente do local. 
Tem a informação sobre excursões e oficinas para grupos da 
escola, e o ImaginAsia, a oficina hands-on semanal projetada 
conjuntamente com os exhibitions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">attività in linea della caratteristica due circa 
arte asiatica, i materiali di programma di studi che possono essere 
comprati attraverso il negozio di Sackler e più libero delle gallerie
del museo ed altre risorse che possono essere richiamate direttamente 
dal luogo. Ha le informazioni sui giri e sui workshop per i 
gruppi della scuola ed ImaginAsia, il workshop hands-on settimanale 
progettato insieme con le mostre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα δύο σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
δραστηριότητες για την ασιατική τέχνη, τα υλικά προγράμματος 
σπουδών που μπορούν να αγοραστούν μέσω του πιό ελεύθερου και 
στοών Sackler καταστήματος μουσείων, και άλλα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς που μπορούν να ανακτηθούν άμεσα από την περιοχή. 
Έχει τις πληροφορίες για τους γύρους και τα εργαστήρια για 
τις σχολικές ομάδες, και ImaginAsia, το εβδομαδιαίο εμπράγματο 
εργαστήριο που σχεδιάζεται από κοινού με τις εκθέσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">actividades en línea de la característica dos 
sobre el arte asiático, los materiales del plan de estudios que se 
pueden comprar a través del departamento más libre y de Sackler de 
las galerías del museo, y otros recursos que se pueden extraer 
directamente del sitio. Tiene la información sobre viajes y 
talleres para los grupos de la escuela, e ImaginAsia, el taller con 
manos semanal diseñado conjuntamente con las exposiciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205735</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105339</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/freer-and-sackler-galleries-education-programs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
