<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107756</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107756</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202563</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">ACC Basketball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AKKUMULATOR Basketball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Basket-ball d'ACCUMULATEUR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Basketball do ACUMULADOR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pallacanestro dell'ACCUMULATORE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καλαθοσφαίριση της ACC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Baloncesto del ACUMULADOR</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The students will use ACC basketball statistics to practice the process of converting fractions to decimals then to percents and will learn how to create and edit a spreadsheet. They will then use this spreadsheet to analyze their data. This unit is done during the basketball season which takes approximately 15 weeks from the middle of November to the middle of March. Teachers must have Clarisworks on their computers to open the attachment, which is an example of the spreadsheet.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kursteilnehmer verwenden 
AKKUMULATOR-Basketballstatistiken, um den Prozeß des Umwandelns der 
Brüche in Dezimalstriche dann zu den Prozenten zu üben und erlernen,
wie man eine Kalkulationstabelle erstellt und bearbeitet. Sie 
benutzen dann diese Kalkulationstabelle, um ihre Daten zu analysieren.
Diese Maßeinheit ist während der Basketballsaison erfolgt, die
ungefähr 15 Wochen von der Mitte von November zur Mitte von März 
dauert. Lehrer müssen Clarisworks auf ihren Computern haben, 
zum des Zubehörs zu öffnen, das ein Beispiel der Kalkulationstabelle
ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants emploieront des statistiques de 
basket-ball d'ACCUMULATEUR pour pratiquer le processus de convertir 
des fractions en décimales puis aux pour cent et apprendront comment 
créer et éditer un tableur. Ils utiliseront alors ce tableur 
pour analyser leurs données. Cette unité est faite pendant la 
saison de basket-ball qui prend approximativement 15 semaines du 
milieu de novembre au milieu de mars. Les professeurs doivent 
avoir Clarisworks sur leurs ordinateurs pour ouvrir la connexion, qui 
est un exemple du tableur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes usarão statistics do basketball do 
ACUMULADOR praticar o processo de converter frações aos decimais 
então aos por cento e aprenderão como criar e editar um spreadsheet.
Usarão então este spreadsheet analisar seus dados. Esta 
unidade é feita durante a estação de basketball que faz exame de 
aproximadamente 15 semanas do meio de novembro ao meio de março. 
Os professores devem ter Clarisworks em seus computadores para 
abrir o acessório, que é um exemplo do spreadsheet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi useranno le statistiche di 
pallacanestro dell'ACCUMULATORE per esercitarsi nel processo di 
convertire le frazioni in decimali allora ai percento ed impareranno 
come creare e stampare un foglio elettronico. Allora 
utilizzeranno questo foglio elettronico per analizzare i loro dati. 
Questa unità è fatta durante la stagione di pallacanestro che 
occorre circa 15 settimane dalla metà di novembre alla metà di 
marzo. Gli insegnanti devono avere Clarisworks sui loro 
calcolatori per aprire il collegamento, che è un esempio del foglio 
elettronico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα χρησιμοποιήσουν τις στατιστικές 
καλαθοσφαίρισης της ACC για να ασκήσουν τη διαδικασία τα μέρη 
στα δεκαδικά έπειτα στα percents και θα μάθουν πώς να 
δημιουργήσουν και να επιμεληθούν έναν υπολογισμό με λογιστικό 
φύλλο (spreadsheet). Θα χρησιμοποιήσουν έπειτα αυτόν τον 
υπολογισμό με λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet) για να αναλύσουν τα
στοιχεία τους. Αυτή η μονάδα γίνεται κατά τη διάρκεια της 
εποχής καλαθοσφαίρισης που διαρκεί περίπου 15 εβδομάδες από 
τα μέσα Νοεμβρίου στα μέσα Μαρτίου. Οι δάσκαλοι πρέπει να 
έχουν Clarisworks στους υπολογιστές τους για να ανοίξουν τη 
σύνδεση, η οποία είναι ένα παράδειγμα του υπολογισμού με 
λογιστικό φύλλο (spreadsheet).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes utilizarán estadística del 
baloncesto del ACUMULADOR para practicar el proceso de convertir 
fracciones a los decimales entonces a los por ciento y aprenderán 
cómo crear y corregir una hoja de balance. Entonces utilizarán
esta hoja de balance para analizar sus datos. Esta unidad se 
hace durante la estación de baloncesto que lleva aproximadamente 15 
semanas del centro de noviembre el centro de marcha. Los 
profesores deben tener Clarisworks en sus ordenadores para abrir la 
conexión, que es un ejemplo de la hoja de balance.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SUSAN DOUGHERTY
FN:SUSAN DOUGHERTY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202563</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107756</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/acc-basketball</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
