<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108785</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108785</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209903</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Polygon Exterior Angles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Polygon-Äußer-Winkel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Angles d'Extérieur de Polygone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ângulos Do Exterior Do Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Angoli Di Esterno Del Poligono</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξωτερικές γωνίες πολυγώνων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ángulos Del Exterior Del Polígono</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate that the exterior angles of a polygon always add to a constant (360 or 720 depending on your point of view). The applet shows a polygon where the user can drag the vertices to reshape it, alter the number of sides, make it convex or concave, regular or irregular. The applet shows the angle summation in real time, demonstrating that it is always constant. It also demonstrates how exterior angles are accounted for in concave polygons, where the exterior angle seems to be inside the figure. These are taken as negative angles and the sum demonstrably remains the same. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die zeigen, daß die Außenwinkel eines Polygons immer einer
Konstante hinzufügen (360 oder 720 abhängig von Ihrem 
Gesichtspunkt). Der applet zeigt einem Polygon, wo der Benutzer 
die Gipfel schleppen kann, um ihn umzugestalten, die Zahl Seiten 
ändert, sie konvex oder konkav bildet, regelmäßig oder 
unregelmäßig. Der applet zeigt die Winkelsummierung in der 
Istzeit und zeigt, daß er immer konstant ist. Er zeigt auch, 
wie Außenwinkel in konkave Polygone berechnet werden, in denen der 
Außenwinkel scheint, innerhalb der Abbildung zu sein. Diese 
werden genommen, während negative Winkel und die Summe demonstrierbar
dieselben bleibt. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für 
Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent que les angles extérieurs d'un polygone ajoutent 
toujours à une constante (360 ou 720 selon votre point de vue). 
L'applet montre à un polygone où l'utilisateur peut traîner 
les sommets pour le restructurer, modifie le nombre de côtés, le 
rend convexe ou concave, régulier ou irrégulier. L'applet 
montre l'addition d'angle en temps réel, démontrant qu'il est 
toujours constant. Il démontre également comment des angles 
extérieurs sont expliqués dans les polygones concaves, où l'angle 
extérieur semble être à l'intérieur de la figure. Ceux-ci 
sont pris pendant que les angles négatifs et la somme demeure de 
façon concluante les mêmes. L'applet peut être agrandi à la 
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstre que os ângulos exteriores de um polygon adicionam sempre a 
uma constante (360 ou 720 dependendo de seu ponto da vista). O 
applet mostra a um polygon onde o usuário pode arrastar os vertices 
para reshape o, altera o número dos lados, o faz convexo ou côncavo,
regular ou irregular. O applet mostra a soma do ângulo no tempo
real, demonstrando que é sempre constante. Demonstra também 
como os ângulos exteriores são explicados nos polygons côncavos, 
onde o ângulo exterior parece ser dentro da figura. Estes são 
feitos exame enquanto os ângulos negativos e a soma remanescem 
demonstrably os mesmos. O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de
tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois 
de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo 
o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma 
sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostra che gli angoli esterni di un poligono aggiungono sempre ad un
costante (360 o 720 secondo il vostro punto di vista). Il applet
mostra ad un poligono dove l'utente può trascinare i vertici per 
rimodellarlo, altera il numero di lati, lo rende convesso o concavo, 
normale o irregolare. Il applet mostra la sommatoria. di angolo 
in tempo reale, dimostrante che è sempre costante. Egualmente 
dimostra come gli angoli esterni sono rappresentati nei poligoni 
concavi, in cui l'angolo esterno sembra essere all'interno della 
figura. Questi sono presi mentre gli angoli negativi e la somma 
in modo dimostrabile rimane gli stessi. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν ότι οι εξωτερικές γωνίες ενός πολυγώνου 
προσθέτουν πάντα σε μια σταθερά (360 ή 720 ανάλογα με την 
άποψή σας). Το applet εμφανίζει ένα πολύγωνο όπου ο 
χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει vertices για να το αναδιαμορφώσει, να 
αλλάξει τον αριθμό πλευρών, να το καταστήσει κυρτό ή κοίλο, 
κανονικό ή ανώμαλο. Το applet εμφανίζει άθροισμα γωνίας
στον πραγματικό χρόνο, που καταδεικνύει ότι είναι πάντα 
σταθερό. Καταδεικνύει επίσης πώς οι εξωτερικές γωνίες 
αποτελούνται στα κοίλα πολύγωνα, όπου η εξωτερική γωνία 
φαίνεται να είναι μέσα στον αριθμό. Αυτοί λαμβάνονται ως 
αρνητικές γωνίες και το ποσό παραμένει ευαπόδεικτα το ίδιο. 
Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης
για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση 
στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestra que los ángulos exteriores de un polígono agregan siempre 
a una constante (360 o 720 dependiendo de su punto de vista). El
applet muestra a polígono donde el utilizador puede arrastrar las 
cimas para restructurarlo, altera el número de caras, lo hace convexo
o cóncavo, regular o irregular. El applet muestra la adición 
del ángulo en el tiempo real, demostrando que es siempre constante. 
También demuestra cómo los ángulos exteriores se consideran 
en los polígonos cóncavos, donde el ángulo exterior se parece estar
dentro de la figura. Se toman éstos mientras que los ángulos 
negativos y la suma demostrable sigue siendo iguales. El applet 
se puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con 
un proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209903</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108785</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/polygon-exterior-angles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
