<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103793</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103793</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086822</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Share the Wealth": Huey Long Talks to the Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"teilen Sie die Fülle": Huey lange 
Gespräche zur Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"partagez la richesse" : Longs entretiens de
Huey à la nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"compartilhe da riqueza": Conversas longas 
de Huey à nação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ripartisca la ricchezza": Colloqui 
lunghi di Huey alla nazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μερίδιο ο πλούτοσ": Μακροχρόνιες συζητήσεις 
Huey στο έθνος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"comparta la abundancia": Negociaciones 
largas de Huey a la nación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Huey Long first came to national attention as governor of Louisiana in 1928 and U.S. Senator in 1930. He ruled Louisiana as a virtual dictator, but he also initiated massive public works programs, improved public education and public health, and even established some restrictions on corporate power in the state. While Long was an early supporter of Franklin Roosevelt, by the fall of 1933 the Long-Roosevelt alliance had ruptured, in part over Long's growing interest in running for president. In 1934 Long organized his own, alternative political organization, the Share-Our-Wealth Society, through which he advocated a populist program for redistributing wealth through sharply graduated income and inheritance taxes. As his national recognition (and ambitions) grew, he spoke with increasing frequency to national radio audiences. No politician in this era--except Roosevelt himself and Long's sometime ally, Father Charles Coughlin--used radio as frequently and effectively. In this April 1935 radio address, Long sharply criticized FDR and the New Deal and then sketched out his alternative program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Huey langes erstes kam zur nationalen 
Aufmerksamkeit als Gouverneur von Louisiana 1928 und VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Senator 1930. Er ordnete Louisiana als virtueller 
Diktator an, aber er initialisiert auch massive Arbeitenprogramme, 
verbessertes Unterrichtswesen und öffentliches Gesundheitswesen, und 
sogar hergestellt einigen Beschränkungen auf korporativer Energie im 
Zustand. Wenn war ein früher Verfechter von Franklin Roosevelt,
bis zum dem Fall von 1933, die das Lange-Roosevelt Bündnis gebrochen 
hatte, im Teilüberschuß lang, der, lang Interesse wächst, an, für 
Präsidenten zu laufen. In 1934 lang organisiert seine Selbst, 
alternative politische Organisation, die Anteil-Unser-Fülle 
Gesellschaft, durch die er ein Volksprogramm für das Neuverteilen von
von Fülle durch scharf graduiertes Einkommen und Erbschaftssteuern 
befürwortete. Während seine nationale Anerkennung (und 
Ehrgeiz) wuchsen, sprach er bei Zunahme der Frequenz mit nationalen 
Radiopublikum. Kein Politiker in dieser Ära -- ausgenommen 
Roosevelt selbst und einmal sehnten sich Verbündeter, Vater Charles 
Coughlin -- benutzter Radio als häufig und effektiv. In dieser 
April 1935 Rundfunkansprache sehnen sich scharf kritisiertes FDR und 
das neue Abkommen und dann skizziert aus seinem Ersatzprogramm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le long premier de Huey est venu à une attention 
nationale comme gouverneur de la Louisiane en 1928 et sénateur des 
ETATS-UNIS en 1930. Il a régné la Louisiane en tant que 
dictateur virtuel, mais il lance également des programmes massifs de 
travaux publics, l'éducation publique améliorée et la santé 
publique, et même établi quelques restrictions à la puissance de 
corporation dans l'état. Tandis que long était un défenseur 
tôt de Franklin Roosevelt, par la chute de 1933 que la 
Longue-Roosevelt alliance s'était rompue, dans l'excédent de partie 
accroissant longtemps l'intérêt pour l'exécution pour le 
président. Dans 1934 longtemps organisés ses propres, 
organisation politique alternative, la société de 
Part-Notre-Richesse, par laquelle il a préconisé un programme 
populiste pour redistribuer la richesse par le revenu et les impôts 
sur les successions brusquement reçus un diplôme. Pendant que 
sa identification nationale (et ambitions) se développaient, il a 
parlé avec l'augmentation de la fréquence aux assistances par radio 
nationales. Aucun politicien dans cette ère -- excepté 
Roosevelt lui-même et ont désiré ardemment autrefois l'allié, 
père Charles Coughlin -- radio utilisée en tant que fréquemment et 
pertinemment. Dans cette adresse par radio d'avril 1935, 
désirent ardemment le FDR vivement critiqué et la nouvelle affaire 
et alors esquissé hors de son programme alternatif.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O primeiro longo de Huey veio à atenção 
nacional como o regulador de Louisiana em 1928 e o senator de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS em 1930. Governou Louisiana como um ditador virtual, mas 
inicía também programas de trabalhos públicos maciços, a 
instrução pública melhorada e a saúde pública, e estabelecido 
mesmo algumas limitações na potência incorporada no estado. 
Quando longo era um supporter adiantado de Franklin Roosevelt, 
pela queda de 1933 que o alliance Longo-Roosevelt tinha rompido, no 
excesso da parte que cresce por muito tempo o interesse em funcionar 
para o presidente. Em 1934 organizados por muito tempo seus 
próprios, organização política alternativa, sociedade da 
Parte-Nosso-Riqueza, através de que advogou um programa populist para
redistributing a riqueza com os impostos agudamente graduados da renda
e de inheritance. Enquanto seu recognition nacional (e as 
ambições) cresceram, falou com a freqüência crescente às 
audiências de rádio nacionais. Nenhum político nesta era -- 
exceto Roosevelt ele mesmo e long sometime o aliado, pai Charles 
Coughlin -- rádio usado como freqüentemente e eficazmente. 
Neste endereço de rádio de abril 1935, long o FDR agudamente 
criticado e o negócio novo e esboçado então para fora de seu 
programa alternativo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il primo lungo di Huey è venuto ad attenzione 
nazionale come il regolatore della Luisiana in 1928 e senatore degli 
STATI UNITI in 1930. Ha regolato la Luisiana come dictator 
virtuale, ma egualmente inizia i programmi voluminosi di lavori 
pubblici, la formazione pubblica migliorata e la sanità pubblica e 
perfino stabilito alcune limitazioni su potenza corporativa nel 
dichiarare. Mentre lungo era un sostenitore in anticipo di 
Franklin Roosevelt, entro la caduta di 1933 che l'alleanza 
Lunga-Roosevelt si era rotta, nell'eccedenza della parte lungamente 
che sviluppa l'interesse nel funzionare per il presidente. In 
1934 lungamente organizzati il suoi propri, organizzazione politica 
alternativa, la società di Parte-Nostro-Ricchezza, attraverso cui ha 
sostenuto un programma populistico per la ridistribuzione della 
ricchezza con reddito e le tasse di successione acutamente laureati. 
Mentre il suo riconoscimento nazionale (ed ambizioni) si sono 
sviluppati, ha parlato con l'aumento di frequenza ai pubblici 
radiofonici nazionali. Nessun politico in questa era -- tranne 
Roosevelt egli stesso ed ha desiderato un momento l'alleato, il padre 
Charles Coughlin -- radio usata come frequentemente ed efficacemente. 
In questo indirizzo radiofonico di aprile 1935, desiderano il 
FDR acutamente criticato ed il nuovo affare ed allora abbozzato verso 
l'esterno il suo programma alternativo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μακρύς ο πρώτος Huey ήρθε στην εθνική προσοχή ως 
κυβερνήτης της Λουιζιάνας το 1928 και ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ γερουσιαστής 
το 1930. Κυβέρνησε τη Λουιζιάνα ως εικονικό δικτάτορα, 
αλλά άρχισε επίσης τα ογκώδη προγράμματα δημόσιων έργων, τη 
βελτιωμένες δημόσιες εκπαίδευση και δημόσια την υγεία, και ακόμη
και καθιερωμένος μερικούς περιορισμούς στην εταιρική δύναμη στο 
κράτος. Ενώ πολύ ήταν πρώτος υποστηρικτής Franklin 
Roosevelt, από το φθινόπωρο του 1933 η συμμαχία μακρύς- 
Roosevelt είχε σπάσει, εν μέρει πέρα από το μακροχρόνιο 
αυξανόμενο ενδιαφέρον για το τρέξιμο για τον Πρόεδρο. Το 
1934 πολύ οργανωμένος δικοί δικοί του, εναλλακτική πολιτική 
οργάνωση, η κοινωνία μερίδιο-μας-πλούτου, μέσω της οποίας 
υποστήριξε ένα λαϊκιστικό πρόγραμμα για τον πλούτο μέσω των 
αισθητά βαθμολογημένων φόρων εισοδήματος και κληρονομιάς. 
Δεδομένου ότι η εθνική αναγνώρισή του (και φιλοδοξίες) 
αυξήθηκαν, μίλησε με την αυξανόμενη συχνότητα στα εθνικά ραδιο 
ακροατήρια. Κανένας πολιτικός σε αυτήν την εποχή -- εκτός 
από Roosevelt ο ίδιος και μακρύς κάποτε συνδέστε, πατέρας 
Charles Coughlin -- δεν χρησιμοποίησε το ραδιόφωνο όπως 
συχνά και αποτελεσματικά. Σε αυτήν την ραδιο διεύθυνση 
Απριλίου 1935, μακροχρόνιο αισθητά επικριμένο FDR και τη 
νέα διαπραγμάτευση και έπειτα σκιαγραφημένος έξω το εναλλακτικό 
πρόγραμμά του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El primer largo de Huey vino a la atención 
nacional como el gobernador de Luisiana en 1928 y senador de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS en 1930. Él gobernó Luisiana como dictador virtual, 
pero él también inició programas de trabajos públicos masivos, la 
educación pública mejorada y la salud pública, e incluso 
establecido algunas restricciones en potencia corporativa en el 
estado. Mientras que es largo era un partidario temprano de 
Franklin Roosevelt, por la caída de 1933 que la alianza 
Larga-Roosevelt había roto, en el excedente de la parte que crecía 
de largo interés en ejecutarse para el presidente. En 1934 de 
largo ordenados sus el propios, organización política alternativa, 
la sociedad de la Parte-Nuestro-Abundancia, a través de quien él 
abogó un programa populista para redistribuir abundancia con 
impuestos sostenidamente graduados de la renta y de herencia. 
Mientras que su reconocimiento nacional (y las ambiciones) 
crecieron, él habló con el aumento de frecuencia a las audiencias de
radio nacionales. Ningún político en esta era -- excepto 
Roosevelt mismo y deseó alguna vez el aliado, padre Charles Coughlin 
-- radio usada como con frecuencia y con eficacia. En este 
direccionamiento de radio de abril 1935, desean el FDR sostenidamente 
criticado y el nuevo reparto y entonces bosquejado fuera de su 
programa alternativo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086822</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103793</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/share-the-wealth-huey-long-talks-to-the-nation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
