<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106189</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106189</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206987</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Teaching with Historic Places</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterricht mit historischen Plätzen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enseignement avec les endroits historiques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ensino com lugares historic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Insegnamento con i posti storici</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διδασκαλία με τις ιστορικές θέσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Enseñanza con los lugares históricos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">uses properties listed in the National Park Service's National Register of Historic Places to enliven history, social studies, geography, civics, and other subjects. TwHP has created products and activities that help teachers bring historic places into the classroom. Lesson plans turn students into historians as they study primary sources, historical and contemporary photographs and maps, and other documents, and then search for the history around them in their own communities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">benutzt die Eigenschaften, die in der 
Einwohnermeldeliste des Nationalpark-Services der historischen Plätze
ausgedruckt werden, um Geschichte, Sozialstudien, Geographie, 
Gemeinschaftskunde und andere Themen zu beleben. TwHP hat 
Produkte und Aktivitäten erstellt, die Lehrern helfen, historische 
Plätze in das Klassenzimmer zu holen. Lektionplan-Umdrehung 
Kursteilnehmer in Historiker, da sie Primärquellen, historische und 
zeitgenössische Fotographien und Karten studieren und andere 
Dokumente und suchen dann nach der Geschichte um sie in ihren eigenen 
Gemeinschaften.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">utilise des propriétés énumérées dans le 
registre national du service de parc national des endroits historiques
pour animer l'histoire, les études sociales, la géographie, 
l'éducation civique, et d'autres sujets. TwHP a créé les 
produits et les activités qui aident des professeurs à introduire 
les endroits historiques dans la salle de classe. Les étudiants
de tour de plans de leçon dans des historiens car ils étudient des 
sources primaires, des photographies historiques et contemporaines et 
des cartes, et d'autres documents, et recherchent alors l'histoire 
autour d'elles dans leurs propres communautés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">usa as propriedades alistadas no registo nacional 
do serviço do parque nacional de lugares historic para enliven o 
history, estudos sociais, geografia, civics, e outros assuntos. 
TwHP criou os produtos e as atividades que ajudam a professores 
trazer lugares historic na sala de aula. Os estudantes da volta 
das plantas da lição em historians porque estudam fontes 
preliminares, fotografias históricas e contemporary e mapas, e outros
originais, e procuraram então pelo history em torno delas em suas 
próprias comunidades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">usa le proprietà elencate nel registro nazionale 
del servizio del parco nazionale dei posti storici per enliven la 
storia, gli studi sociali, la geografia, il civics ed altri oggetti. 
TwHP ha creato i prodotti e le attività che aiutano gli 
insegnanti ad introdurre i posti storici nell'aula. Gli allievi 
di girata di programmi di lezione negli storici poichè studiano le 
sorgenti primarie, fotografie storiche e contemporanee e programmi ed 
altri documenti ed allora cercano la storia intorno loro nelle loro 
proprie Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">οι ιδιότητες χρήσεων εμφάνισαν λίστα στον εθνικό 
κατάλογο των εθνικών υπηρεσιών πάρκων των ιστορικών θέσεων για 
να αναζωογονήσουν την ιστορία, τις κοινωνικές μελέτες, τη 
γεωγραφία, το civics, και άλλα θέματα. Το TwHP έχει 
δημιουργήσει τα προϊόντα και τις δραστηριότητες που βοηθούν τους 
δασκάλους να φέρουν τις ιστορικές θέσεις στην τάξη. Τα 
σχέδια μαθήματος μετατρέπουν τους σπουδαστές σε ιστορικούς 
δεδομένου ότι μελετούν τις αρχικές πηγές, τις ιστορικούς και 
σύγχρονους φωτογραφίες και τους χάρτες, και άλλα έγγραφα, και 
έπειτα την αναζήτηση της ιστορίας γύρω από τους στις κοινότητές
τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">utiliza las características enumeradas en el 
registro nacional del servicio del parque nacional de lugares 
históricos para enliven historia, estudios sociales, la geografía, 
el civics, y otros temas. TwHP ha creado los productos y las 
actividades que ayudan a profesores a traer lugares históricos en la 
sala de clase. Los estudiantes de la vuelta de los planes de la 
lección en historiadores como estudian fuentes primarias, las 
fotografías históricas y contemporáneas y las correspondencias, y 
otros documentos, y entonces buscan para la historia alrededor de 
ellas en sus propias comunidades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206987</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106189</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/teaching-with-historic-places</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
