<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105103</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105103</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200389</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AlgaeBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AlgaeBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">AlgaeBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">AlgaeBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">AlgaeBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">AlgaeBase</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">AlgaeBase</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">AlgaeBase is a comprehensive taxonomic database of information on algae that includes terrestrial, marine and freshwater organisms. Users may consult this resource to check taxonomies or nomenclature, obtain information pertaining to geographic distributions, and view or download images. The database can be browsed by taxon or searched by literature, genus, species, images, common names, distribution, and glossary.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AlgaeBase ist eine komplette taxonomische 
Datenbank der Informationen über Algen, die die terrestrischen, 
Marine- und Frischwasserorganismen einschließt. Benutzer 
können dieses Hilfsmittel beraten, um taxonomies oder Bezeichnung zu 
überprüfen, die Informationen einzuholen, die geographische 
Verteilungen und Ansicht- oder Downloadbilder betreffen. Die 
Datenbank kann durch Taxon durchgestöbert werden oder durch 
Literatur, Klasse, Sorte, Bilder, geläufige Namen, Verteilung und 
Glossar gesucht werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">AlgaeBase est une base de données taxonomique 
complète d'information sur des algues qui inclut les organizations 
terrestres, marines et d'eau douce. Les utilisateurs peuvent 
consulter cette ressource pour contrôler des taxonomies ou la 
nomenclature, obtenir l'information concernant des distributions 
géographiques, et des images de vue ou de téléchargement. La 
base de données peut être parcourue par taxon ou être 
recherchée par la littérature, le genre, les espèces, les 
images, les noms communs, la distribution, et le glossaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">AlgaeBase é uma base de dados taxonomic detalhada
da informação em algas que inclui organismos terrestrial, marinhos e
freshwater. Os usuários podem consultar este recurso para 
verificar taxonomies ou nomenclatura, para obter a informação que 
pertence às distribuições geográficas, e às imagens da vista ou 
do download. A base de dados pode browsed pelo táxon ou ser 
procurarada pela literatura, pelo genus, pela espécie, pelas imagens,
por nomes comuns, por distribuição, e por glossário.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">AlgaeBase è una base di dati tassonomica completa
delle informazioni sulle alghe che includono gli organismi terrestri, 
marini e d'acqua dolce. Gli utenti possono consultare questa 
risorsa per controllare i taxonomies o la nomenclatura, ottenere le 
informazioni che appartengono le distribuzioni geografiche e le 
immagini di trasferimento dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti o di 
vista. La base di dati può essere passata in rassegna dal taxon
o essere cercata da letteratura, dal genere, dalla specie, dalle 
immagini, dai nomi comuni, dalla distribuzione e dal glossario.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το AlgaeBase είναι μια περιεκτική ταξονομική βάση 
δεδομένων των πληροφοριών για τα άλγη που περιλαμβάνει τους 
επίγειους, θαλάσσιους και εσωτερικών υδάτων οργανισμούς. Οι
χρήστες μπορούν να συμβουλευθούν αυτήν την πηγή για να ελέγξουν 
τις ταξονομίες ή την ονοματολογία, να λάβουν τις πληροφορίες 
σχετικά με τις γεωγραφικές διανομές, και την όψη ή να 
μεταφορτώσουν τις εικόνες. Η βάση δεδομένων μπορεί να 
περιοδευθεί από το taxon ή να αναζητηθεί από τη λογοτεχνία, 
το γένος, τα είδη, τις εικόνες, τα κοινά ονόματα, τη διανομή, 
και το γλωσσάρι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">AlgaeBase es una base de datos taxonómica 
comprensiva de la información sobre algas que incluye organismos 
terrestres, marinas y de agua dulce. Los utilizadores pueden 
consultar este recurso para controlar taxonomies o nomenclatura, 
obtener la información que pertenece a las distribuciones 
geográficas, y a las imágenes de la visión o de la transferencia 
directa. La base de datos se puede hojear por la taxonomía o 
buscar por la literatura, el género, la especie, las imágenes, los 
nombres comunes, la distribución, y el glosario.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MIKE GUIRY
FN:MIKE GUIRY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200389</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105103</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/algaebase</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
