<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103502</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103502</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The  Maine  and the  World : Sailing into History</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Maine und die Welt: Segeln in 
Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Maine et le monde : Navigation dans 
l'histoire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Maine e o mundo: Sailing no history</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Maine ed il mondo: Navigando nella 
storia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Maine και ο κόσμος: Ναυσιπλοϊ'α στην 
ιστορία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Maine y el mundo: Navegación en 
historia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On February 15, 1898, an explosion ripped through the American battleship  Maine , anchored in Havana harbor, sinking the ship and killing 260 sailors. Americans responded with outrage, assuming that Spain, which controlled Cuba as a colony, had sunk the ship. Two months later, the slogan "Remember the  Maine " carried the U.S. into war with Spain. In the midst of the hysteria, few Americans paid much attention to the report issued two weeks before the U.S. entry into the war by a Court of Inquiry appointed by President McKinley. The report stated that the committee could not definitively assign blame to Spain for the sinking of the  Maine . Publishers such as William Randolph Hearst and Joseph Pulitzer used their many newspapers to stir public opinion over the sinking of the  Maine  into a frenzy, hastenening U.S. entry into the conflict. This February 17, 1898, front page story from Pulitzer's New York  World  suggested, on the basis of little evidence, the hand of the enemy in the destruction of the  Maine .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf Februar 15, 1898, einer Explosion zerrissen 
durch das amerikanische Linienschiff Maine, befestigt im Havana Hafen,
das Schiff sinkend und beenden 260 Seeleute. Amerikaner 
reagierten mit dem Verbrechen und nahmen dieses Spanien an, dem 
kontrolliertes Kuba als Kolonie, das Schiff gesunken hatte. Zwei
Monate später, erinnern sich der Slogan ", daß das Maine" die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN in Krieg mit Spanien trug. In der Mitte der 
Hysterie, lenkten wenige Amerikaner viel Aufmerksamkeit auf den 
Report herausgaben zwei Wochen bevor der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Eintrag in
den Krieg durch eine Untersuchungskommission ernannt vom Präsidenten 
McKinley. Der Report gab an, daß der Ausschuß nicht Schuld 
nach Spanien für das Sinken des Maines endgültig zuweisen könnte. 
Verleger wie William Randolph Hearst und Joseph Pulitzer 
benutzten ihre vielen Zeitungen, um Überschuß der öffentlichen 
Meinung zu rühren das Sinken des Maines in eine Raserei und 
hastenening VEREINIGTE STAATEN Eintrag in die $überschneidung. 
Dieser Februar 17, 1898, schlug Vorderseitegeschichte von der 
Welt New York Pulitzers, auf der Grundlage von wenig Beweis, die Hand 
des Feindes in der Zerstörung des Maines vor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">15 février 1898, une explosion déchirée par le
cuirassé américain Maine, ancré dans le port de La Havane, 
descendant le bateau et détruisant 260 marins. Les Américains 
ont répondu avec l'outrage, assumant la cette Espagne, que le Cuba 
commandé en tant que colonie, était descendu le bateau. 
Pendant deux mois plus tard, le slogan "se rappellent que le 
Maine" a porté les ETATS-UNIS dans la guerre avec l'Espagne. Au
milieu de l'hystérie, peu d'Américains ont prêté beaucoup 
d'attention à l'état ont émis deux semaines avant que l'entrée des
ETATS-UNIS dans la guerre par une cour d'enquête désignée par le 
Président McKinley. L'état a déclaré que le comité ne 
pourrait pas définitivement assigner le blâme en Espagne pour la 
descente du Maine. Les éditeurs tels que William Randolph 
Hearst et le Joseph Pulitzer avaient l'habitude leurs beaucoup de 
journaux pour remuer l'excédent d'opinion publique la descente du 
Maine dans une frénésie, hastenening l'entrée des ETATS-UNIS dans 
le conflit. Ce 17 février 1898, l'histoire de page avant du 
monde de New York de Pulitzer a suggéré, sur la base de peu 
d'évidence, la main de l'ennemi dans la destruction du Maine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fevereiro em 15, 1898, em uma explosão rasgada 
através do cruzador de batalha americano Maine, escorado no porto de 
Havana, afundando o navio e matando 260 sailors. Os americanos 
responderam com o ultraje, supondo esse Spain, que Cuba controlada 
como uma colônia, tinha afundado o navio. Dois meses mais 
tarde, o slogan "recorda que o Maine" carregou os ESTADOS UNIDOS na 
guerra com o Spain. No meio do hysteria, poucos americanos 
pagaram muita atenção ao relatório emitiram duas semanas antes que 
a entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS na guerra por uma corte de inquérito 
apontada pelo presidente McKinley. O relatório indicou que o 
comitê não poderia definitively atribuir a culpa a Spain para se 
afundar do Maine. Os publishers tais como William Randolph 
Hearst e Joseph Pulitzer usaram seus muitos jornais agitar o excesso 
da opinião pública afundar-se do Maine em um frenzy, hastenening a 
entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS no conflito. Este fevereiro 17, 1898, 
a história da página dianteira do mundo de New York de Pulitzer 
sugeriu, na base de pouca evidência, a mão do inimigo na 
destruição do Maine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 15 febbraio 1898, un'esplosione strappata 
tramite il battleship americano Maine, ancorata nel porto de Avana, 
affondante la nave e mortale 260 marinai. Gli Americani hanno 
risposto con l'oltraggio, ammettente la quella Spagna, che la Cuba 
controllata come colonia, aveva affondato la nave. Due mesi più
successivamente, lo slogan "si ricorda di che la Maine" ha trasportato
gli STATI UNITI nella guerra con la Spagna. In mezzo a il 
hysteria, pochi Americani ha prestato molta attenzione al rapporto ha 
pubblicato due settimane prima che l'entrata degli STATI UNITI nella 
guerra da una corte dell'inchiesta nominata dal presidente McKinley. 
Il rapporto ha dichiarato che il comitato non potrebbe 
definitivo assegnare la colpa in Spagna per l'abbassamento della 
Maine. Gli editori quale William Randolph Hearst e Joseph 
Pulitzer hanno usato i loro molti giornali per mescolare l'eccedenza 
di opinione pubblica l'abbassamento della Maine in un frenzy, 
hastenening l'entrata degli STATI UNITI nel conflitto. Questo 17
febbraio 1898, la storia della pagina anteriore dal mondo de New York 
del Pulitzer ha suggerito, in base a poca prova, la mano del nemico 
nella distruzione della Maine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 15 Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, μια έκρηξη που 
σχίζεται μέσω του αμερικανικού θωρηκτού Maine, που δένεται στο
λιμάνι της Αβάνας, που βυθίζει το σκάφος και που σκοτώνει 260 
ναυτικούς. Αμερικανοί αποκρίθηκαν με την προσβολή, 
υποθέτοντας ότι η Ισπανία, που έλεγξε την Κούβα ως αποικία, 
είχε βυθίσει το σκάφος. Δύο μήνες αργότερα, το σύνθημα 
"θυμάται ότι το Maine" έφερε τις ΗΠΑ στον πόλεμο με την 
Ισπανία. Στη μέση της υστερίας, λίγοι Αμερικανοί έδωσαν 
πολλή προσοχή στην έκθεση που παρουσιάστηκε δύο εβδομάδες πριν 
από την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ είσοδο μέσα σε τον πόλεμο από ένα 
δικαστήριο της έρευνας που διορίστηκε από τον Πρόεδρο 
McKinley. Η έκθεση δήλωσε ότι η επιτροπή δεν θα μπορούσε
να αναθέσει οριστικά την επίπληξη στην Ισπανία για τη βύθιση του 
Maine. Οι εκδότες όπως William Randolph Hearst και
Joseph Pulitzer χρησιμοποίησαν τις πολλές εφημερίδες τους για
να ανακατώσουν την κοινή γνώμη σχετικά με τη βύθιση του Maine 
σε έναν παροξυσμό, poy η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ είσοδος μέσα σε τη 
σύγκρουση. Αυτού του 17 Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, πρώτη σελίδα 
ιστορία από τον κόσμο της Νέας Υόρκης Pulitzer πρότεινε, 
βάσει λίγων στοιχείων, το χέρι του εχθρού στην καταστροφή του 
Maine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">15 de febrero de 1898, una explosión rasgada a
través del acorazado americano Maine, asegurado en el puerto de La 
Habana, hundiendo la nave y matando a 260 marineros. Los 
americanos respondieron con el ultraje, si se asume esa España, que 
Cuba controlada como colonia, había hundido la nave. Dos meses 
más adelante, el lema "recuerda que el Maine" llevó los ESTADOS 
UNIDOS en guerra con España. En el medio de la histeria, pocos 
americanos prestaron mucha atención al informe publicaron dos semanas
antes de que la entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la guerra por una corte 
de la pregunta designada por presidente McKinley. El informe 
indicó que el comité no podría asignar definitivo culpa a España 
para hundirse del Maine. Los editores tales como Guillermo 
Randolph Hearst y José Pulitzer utilizaron sus muchos periódicos 
para revolver el excedente de la opinión pública el hundirse del 
Maine en un frenesí, hastenening la entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS en el 
conflicto. Este 17 de febrero de 1898, la historia de la 
paginación delantera del mundo de Nueva York de Pulitzer sugirió, en
base de poca evidencia, la mano del enemigo en la destrucción del 
Maine.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103502</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-maine-and-the-world-sailing-into-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
