<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108638</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108638</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086877</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tales from the Saloon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichten vom Saloon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Contes de la salle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tales do saloon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Racconti dal salone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορίες από την αίθουσα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuentos del salón</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The fundamental appeal of the saloon to its working-class customers was social and recreational. The saloonkeeper presided over and fostered an atmosphere of good-hearted, informal socializing, in part by supplying jokes and stories. For those whose own supply of humor ran low, the   A. V. Newton's  Saloon Keeper's Companion  provided bar owners with about fifty pages of assorted jokes and stories with which to amuse their customers. The jokes most often ridiculed hypocritical temperance advocates, dishonest police and politicians, unsophisticated and easily fooled clergy and church-goers, and stupid or pompous judges. Included here are two brief excerpts from  The Saloon Keeper's Companion . The first, "The Use of Slander," expressed a cynical view of politicians that seems remarkably contemporary. The second, "Farmer and the Crow," wryly satirized the bartender's own profession. It also seems likely that bawdier, masculine humor circulated through nineteenth-century saloons, but genteel conventions probably prevented authors like A. V. Newton from publishing such jokes and stories.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der grundlegende Anklang des Saloon zu seinen 
Arbeiterklassekunden war sozial und entspannend. Das 
saloonkeeper saß rüber vor und förderte eine Atmosphäre des 
gutherzigen, formlosen Sozialisierens, im Teil, indem es Witze und 
Geschichten angab. Für die deren eigenes Zubehör Stimmung Tief
laufen ließ, versah der Begleiter des A. V. Newtons Saloon Wächters 
Stabinhaber mit ungefähr fünfzig Seiten der sortierten Witze und der
Geschichten, mit denen ihre Kunden unterhalten. Die Witze 
unehrlicher häufig der Polizei und der Politiker, unverfälschten und
leicht getäuschten Klerus lächerlich machten heuchlerisch der 
temperance Fürsprecher, und Kirchgängern und dummer oder 
bombastischer Richter. Hier geschlossen zwei kurze Excerpts vom 
Begleiter des Saloon-Wächters ein. Das erste, "der Gebrauch von
Verleumdung," drückte eine zynische Meinung der Politiker aus, die 
bemerkenswert zeitgenössisch scheint. Die Sekunde, "der 
Landwirt und die Krähe," satirized wryly eigenen Beruf des Barmixers.
Es scheint auch wahrscheinlich, daß groeber, die männliche 
Stimmung, die durch 19.-Jahrhundert Saloons verteilt wird, aber 
genteel Versammlungen hinderten vermutlich Autoren wie A. V. Newton am
Veröffentlichen solcher Witze und Geschichten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'appel fondamental de la salle à ses clients de 
classe ouvrier était social et récréationnel. Le saloonkeeper
a présidé plus d'et a stimulé une atmosphère d'avoir une vie 
sociale charitable et sans cérémonie, en partie en fournissant des 
plaisanteries et des histoires. Pour ceux dont le propre 
approvisionnement en humeur a exécuté le bas, le compagnon du garde 
de Saloon de A. V. Newton's a fourni à des propriétaires de barre 
environ cinquante pages des plaisanteries et des histoires assorties 
avec lesquelles pour amuser leurs clients. Les plaisanteries 
clergé malhonnête hypocrite ridiculed le plus souvent de modération
avocats, de police et de politiciens, et pratiquants peu sophistiqués
et facilement dupés, et juges stupides ou pompeux. Inclus ici 
sont deux brefs extraits du compagnon du garde de salle. Le 
premier, "l'utilisation de la calomnie," a exprimé une opinion 
cynique des politiciens qui semble remarquablement contemporaine. 
La seconde, le "fermier et la corneille," ont wryly 
satirisé la propre profession du barman. Il semble 
également probablement que plus baillard, humeur masculine 
distribuée par des salles de dix-neuvième-siècle, mais les 
conventions distinguées ont probablement empêché des auteurs comme 
A. V. Newton d'éditer de telles plaisanteries et histoires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A apelação fundamental do saloon a seus clientes
do working-class era social e recreacional. O saloonkeeper 
presided sobre e promoveu uma atmosfera de socializar good-hearted, 
informal, na parte fornecendo gracejos e histórias. Para 
aqueles cuja própria fonte do humor funcionou o ponto baixo, o 
companheiro do keeper de Saloon de A. V. Newton forneceu 
proprietários da barra com as aproximadamente cinqüênta páginas 
dos gracejos e das histórias assorted com que para divertir seus 
clientes. Os gracejos ridiculed o mais frequentemente clergy 
dishonest hypocritical dos advogados do temperance, das polícias e 
dos políticos, e church-goers unsophisticated e fàcilmente 
enganados, e juizes stupid ou pompous. São incluídos aqui dois
excerpts breves do companheiro do keeper do saloon. O primeiro, 
"o uso do slander," expressou uma opinião cínica os políticos que 
parecesse notàvelmente contemporary. O segundo, o "fazendeiro e
o corvo," satirized wryly própria profissão do bárman. Parece
também provavelmente que mais bawdier, humor masculine circulado 
através dos saloons de décimo-século, mas as convenções genteel 
impediram provavelmente que os autores como A. V. Newton publiquem 
tais gracejos e histórias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'appello fondamentale del salone ai relativi 
clienti della classe operaia era sociale e di ricreazione. Il 
saloonkeeper ha presieduto sopra ed ha promosso un atmosfera di 
socializzare good-hearted e informale, in parte fornendo gli scherzi e
le storia. Per quelli di cui il proprio rifornimento di umore ha
fatto funzionare il livello basso, il compagno del custode del Saloon 
del A. V. il Newton ha fornito ai proprietari della barra circa 
cinquanta pagine degli scherzi e delle storia assorted con cui 
divertire i loro clienti. Gli scherzi ridiculed il più spesso 
clergy dishonest hypocritical dei fautori di temperance, della polizia
e dei politici, e church-goers non sofisticati e facilmente 
imbrogliati e stupido o giudici pompous. Sono inclusi qui 
due brevi brani dal compagno del custode del salone. Il primo, 
"l'uso di calunnia," ha espresso un punto di vista cinico dei politici
che sembra notevolmente contemporaneo. Il secondo, "il 
coltivatore ed il corvo," wryly satirized la propria professione del 
barista. Egualmente sembra probabilmente che più bawdier, umore
maschile distribuito attraverso i saloni di diciannovesimo-secolo, ma 
le convenzioni genteel probabilmente hanno impedito agli autori come 
A. V. Newton di pubblicare tali scherzi e storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η θεμελιώδης έκκληση της αίθουσας στους πελάτες 
εργατικών τάξεών της ήταν κοινωνική και ψυχαγωγική. Το 
saloonkeeper προήδρευσε και ενθάρρυνε μια ατμόσφαιρα της 
good-hearted, άτυπης κοινωνικοποίησης, εν μέρει με την παροχή 
των αστείων και των ιστοριών. Για εκείνους ο των οποίων 
ανεφοδιασμός του χιούμορ έτρεξε χαμηλό, ο σύντροφος του φύλακα 
Α. Saloon Θ*Β. Newton παρείχε στους ιδιοκτήτες ράβδων 
περίπου πενήντα σελίδες των ανάμεικτων αστείων και των ιστοριών 
με τα οποία να διασκεδάσει τους πελάτες τους. Τα αστεία ο 
συχνότερα γελοιοποίησαν τους υποκριτικούς συνηγόρους 
μετριοπάθειας, την ανέντιμους αστυνομία και τους πολιτικούς, 
απλός και εύκολα η ιεροσύνη και τα εκκλησία- goers, και οι 
ηλίθιοι ή πομπώδεις δικαστές. Συμπεριλαμβανόμενα εδώ 
είναι δύο συνοπτικά αποσπάσματα από το σύντροφο του φύλακα 
αιθουσών. Ο πρώτος, "η χρήση της δυσφήμησης," εξέφρασε μια 
κυνική όψη των πολιτικών που φαίνεται εντυπωσιακά σύγχρονη. 
Ο δεύτερος, "ο αγρότης και ο κόρακας," wryly σατίρισαν το
bartender επάγγελμα. Φαίνεται επίσης πιθανό ότι το 
pjo' ψαωδηερ, αρσενικό χιούμορ που κυκλοφόρησαν μέσω των 
αιθουσών δέκατος-αιώνα, αλλά των καλοαναθρεμένων συμβάσεων 
απέτρεψε πιθανώς τους συντάκτες όπως Α. Θ*Β. Newton από την 
έκδοση τέτοιων αστείων και ιστοριών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La súplica fundamental del salón a sus clientes 
de la clase obrera era social y recreacional. El saloonkeeper 
presidió encima y fomentó una atmósfera de socializar de buen 
corazón, informal, en parte proveiendo bromas e historias. Para
los que propia fuente de humor ejecutó punto bajo, el compañero del 
encargado de Saloon de A. V. Newton's proveió de propietarios de la 
barra cerca de cincuenta paginaciones de las bromas y de las historias
clasificadas con las cuales divertir a sus clientes. Las bromas 
pusieron en ridículo lo más a menudo posible clero deshonesto 
hypocritical a abogados del temperance, del policía y de los 
políticos, y los church-goers sencillos y fácilmente engañados, y 
los jueces estúpidos o pompous. Se incluyen aquí dos extractos
abreviados del compañero del encargado del salón. El primer, 
"el uso del slander," expresó una opinión cínica políticos que se 
parece notable contemporánea. El segundo, el "granjero y el 
cuervo," wryly satirized propia profesión del camarero. 
También se parece probablemente que más indecente, humor 
masculino circulado a través de salones del diecinueveavo-siglo, pero
las convenciones genteel evitaron probablemente que los autores como 
A. V. Newton publicaran tales bromas e historias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086877</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108638</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/tales-from-the-saloon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
