<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102930</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102930</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206433</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Chemistry of Health</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Chemie der Gesundheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La chimie de la santé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O chemistry da saúde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La chimica di salute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η χημεία της υγείας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La química de la salud</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells how chemistry and biochemistry are increasing our understanding of human health. Learn how biochemical relays keep our organ systems operating, how food is broken down and used to build tissues and organs, and how tiny biological probes and instruments can track single molecules. Topics in the 60-page booklet include folic acid, sugars and fats, DNA, making medicines, harnessing biology's magic, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt, wie Chemie und Biochemie unser 
Verständnis der menschlichen Gesundheit erhöhen. Erlernen Sie,
wie biochemische Relais unsere Organsysteme halten zu funktionieren, 
wie Nahrung unterbrochener Abstieg und verwendet, Gewebe und Organe 
aufzubauen ist und wie kleine biologische Prüfspitzen und Instrumente
einzelne Moleküle aufspüren können. Themen in der Broschüre 
60-page enthalten Fol- Säure, Zucker und Fette, DNA und bilden 
Medizin und spannen Magie der Biologie und mehr vor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit que la chimie et la biochimie augmentent notre
arrangement de santé humaine. Apprenez comment les relais 
biochimiques continuent nos systèmes d'organe le fonctionnement, 
comment la nourriture est décomposée et employée pour établir des 
tissus et des organes, et comment les sondes et les instruments 
biologiques minuscules peuvent dépister les molécules simples. 
Les sujets dans le livret 60-page incluent l'acide, les sucres 
et les graisses foliques, ADN, faisant des médecines, armant la magie
de la biologie, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz como o chemistry e o biochemistry estão 
aumentando nossa compreensão da saúde humana. Aprenda como os 
relés biochemical mantêm nossos sistemas do órgão se operar, como 
o alimento é pena quebrada e usado construir tecidos e órgãos, e 
como as pontas de prova e os instrumentos biológicos minúsculos 
podem seguir únicas moléculas. Os tópicos no livreto 60-page 
incluem o ácido, os açúcares e as gorduras folic, DNA, fazendo 
medicinas, aproveitarando a mágica da biologia, e o mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a come la chimica e la biochimica stanno 
aumentando la nostra comprensione della salute umana. Impari 
come i relè biochimici mantengono i nostri sistemi dell'organo 
funzionare, come l'alimento è analizzato ed usato per sviluppare i 
tessuti e gli organi e come le sonde e gli strumenti biologici molto 
piccoli possono rintracciare le singole molecole. I soggetti nel
libretto 60-page includono l'acido, gli zuccheri ed i grassi folici, 
DNA, facendo le medicine, sfruttando la magia della biologia e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει πώς η χημεία και η βιοχημεία αυξάνουν την 
κατανόηση ανθρώπινης υγείας μας. Μάθετε πώς οι βιοχημικοί 
ηλεκτρονόμοι κρατούν τη λειτουργία συστημάτων οργάνων μας, πώς 
τα τρόφιμα χωρίζονται και χρησιμοποιούνται για να χτίσουν τους 
ιστούς και τα όργανα, και πώς οι μικροσκοπικοί βιολογικοί 
έλεγχοι και τα όργανα μπορούν να ακολουθήσουν τα ενιαία μόρια. 
Τα θέματα στο βιβλιάριο 60-σελίδων περιλαμβάνουν το φολικά 
οξύ, τα σάκχαρα και τα λίπη, DNA, κάνοντας τα φάρμακα, 
εκμεταλλεμένος της βιολογίας μαγικής, και περισσότερων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice cómo la química y la bioquímica están 
aumentando nuestra comprensión de la salud humana. Aprenda 
cómo los relais bioquímicos guardan nuestros sistemas del órgano el
funcionar, cómo se analiza y se utiliza el alimento para construir 
tejidos finos y órganos, y cómo las puntas de prueba y los 
instrumentos biológicos minúsculos pueden seguir las solas 
moléculas. Los asuntos en el librete 60-page incluyen el 
ácido, las azúcares y las grasas folic, DNA, haciendo medicinas, 
enjaezando la magia de la biología, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206433</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102930</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-chemistry-of-health</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
