<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104396</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104396</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206545</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Birthplace of John F. Kennedy: Home of the Boy Who Would Be President</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geburtsort von John F. Kennedy: Haus des 
Jungen, der Präsident sein würde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lieu de naissance de John F. Kennedy : 
Maison du garçon qui serait président</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Birthplace de John F. Kennedy: HOME do 
menino que seria presidente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luogo di nascita di John F. Kennedy: Sede 
del ragazzo che sarebbe presidente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τόπος γεννήσεως John F. Kennedy: "Οικία"
του αγοριού που θα ήταν Πρόεδρος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lugar de nacimiento de John F. Kennedy: 
Hogar del muchacho que sería presidente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">takes students to JFK's birthplace and to the neighborhood where he grew up. It was here that JFK's parents began instilling the high standards and ambition that would make the Kennedys one of America's most famous families. Students can investigate the Kennedy's family traditions, values, and interests to consider how family culture and community shapes one's character and personality.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nehmenkursteilnehmer zum Geburtsort JFKs und zur 
Nachbarschaft, in der er aufwuchs. Es war hier, daß Eltern JFKs
anfingen, die hohen Standards und den Ehrgeiz einzuflößen, die das 
Kennedys eins Amerikas von den berühmtesten Familien bilden würden. 
Kursteilnehmer können des die Traditionen Familie Kennedys, die
Werte und die Interessen nachforschen, zu betrachten, wie Familie 
Kultur und Gemeinschaft irgendjemandes Zeichen und 
Funktionseigenschaft formt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">étudiants de prises au lieu de naissance de 
JFK et au voisinage où il a grandi. C'était ici que 
les parents de JFK ont commencé à inculquer les 
niveaux élevés et l'ambition qui feraient le Kennedys un des 
familles les plus célèbres de l'Amérique. Les étudiants 
peuvent étudier les traditions de la famille de Kennedy, les 
valeurs, et les intérêts de considérer comment la culture et la 
communauté de famille forme son caractère et personnalité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">estudantes das tomadas ao birthplace de JFK e à 
vizinhança onde cresceu acima. Era aqui que os pais de JFK 
começaram a instilling os padrões elevados e a ambição que fariam 
o Kennedys um das famílias as mais famosas de América. Os 
estudantes podem investigar as tradições da família do Kennedy, os 
valores, e os interesses considerar como a cultura e a comunidade da 
família dão forma a one's caráter e personalidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">allievi degli introiti al luogo di nascita del JFK
ed alla vicinanza in cui si è sviluppato in su. Era qui che i 
genitori del JFK hanno cominciato ad infondere gli alti livelli e 
l'ambizione che farebbero il Kennedys uno delle famiglie più famose 
dell'America. Gli allievi possono studiare le tradizioni della 
famiglia del Kennedy, i valori e gli interessi considerare come la 
coltura e la Comunità della famiglia modella il suoi carattere e 
personalità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παίρνει τους σπουδαστές στον τόπο γεννήσεως JFK και
στη γειτονιά όπου μεγάλωσε. Ήταν εδώ ότι οι γονείς JFK
άρχισαν τα υψηλά πρότυπα και τη φιλοδοξία που θα έκαναν το 
Kennedys μια από τις διασημότερες οικογένειες της Αμερικής. 
Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να ερευνήσουν τις οικογενειακά 
παραδόσεις, τις τιμές, και τα ενδιαφέροντα του Kennedy να 
εξετάσουν πώς ο οικογενειακοί πολιτισμός και η κοινότητα 
διαμορφώνουν το χαρακτήρα και την προσωπικότητά κάποιου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">estudiantes de las tomas al lugar de nacimiento de
JFK y a la vecindad en donde él creció para arriba. Era aquí 
que los padres de JFK comenzaron a inculcar las mayores niveles y la 
ambición que harían el Kennedys uno de las familias más famosas de 
América. Los estudiantes pueden investigar las tradiciones de 
la familia del Kennedy, los valores, y los intereses de considerar 
cómo la cultura y la comunidad de la familia forma su carácter y 
personalidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206545</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104396</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/birthplace-of-john-f-kennedy-home-of-the-boy-who-would-be-president</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
