<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107920</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107920</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206852</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">America's First Look into the Camera: Daguerreotype Portraits and Views, 1839-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikas schaut zuerst in die Kamera: 
Daguerreotype Portraits und Ansichten, 1839-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Amérique regardent d'abord dans 
l'appareil-photo : Verticales de Daguerreotype et vues, 
1839-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">América olha primeiramente na câmera: 
Retratos de Daguerreotype e vistas, 1839-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'America in primo luogo esamina la macchina 
fotografica: Ritratti di Daguerreotype e viste, 1839-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο πρώτος της Αμερικής εξετάζει τη φωτογραφική μηχανή:
Πορτρέτα Daguerreotype και όψεις, 1839-1864</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">América primero mira en la cámara fotográfica: 
Retratos y opiniónes, 1839-1864 de Daguerreotype</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">consists of more than 650 photographs dating from 1839 to 1864. Portrait daguerreotypes produced by the Mathematics and Statisticsew Brady studio make up the major portion of the collection. The collection also includes early architectural views by John Plumbe, several Philadelphia street scenes, early portraits by pioneering daguerreotypist Robert Cornelius, and copies of painted portraits.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">aus mehr als 650 Fotographien besteht die 
Datierung von 1839 bis 1864. Portrait daguerreotypes 
produzierten durch die Mathematik und Statisticsew Brady Studio bilden
den Hauptteil von der Ansammlung. Die Ansammlung schließt auch 
frühe architektonische Ansichten durch John Plumbe, einige 
Philadelphia Straße Szenen, frühe Portraits, indem sie mit 
daguerreotypist Robert Cornelius vorangeht, und Exemplare der gemalten
Portraits ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">se compose de plus de 650 photographies datant de 
1839 à 1864. Les daguerreotypes de verticale ont produit par 
les mathématiques et le studio de Statisticsew Brady composent la 
partie principale de la collection. La collection inclut 
également des vues architecturales tôt par John Plumbe, plusieurs 
scènes de rue de Philadelphie, verticales tôt en frayant un chemin 
le daguerreotypist Robert Cornelius, et copies des verticales peintes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">consiste em mais de 650 fotografias que datam de 
1839 a 1864. Os daguerreotypes do retrato produziram pela 
matemática e o estúdio de Statisticsew Brady faz acima a parcela 
principal da coleção. A coleção inclui também vistas 
architectural adiantadas por John Plumbe, diversas cenas da rua de 
Filadélfia, retratos adiantados abrindo caminho o daguerreotypist 
Robert Cornelius, e cópias de retratos pintados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consiste di più di 650 fotografie che datano da 
1839 a 1864. I daguerreotypes del ritratto hanno prodotto 
dalla matematica e l'studio di Statisticsew Brady compone la parte 
principale dell'accumulazione. L'accumulazione egualmente 
include le viste architettoniche iniziali da John Plumbe, parecchie 
scene della via de Filadelfia, ritratti in anticipo aprendo la 
strada al daguerreotypist Robert Cornelius e copie dei ritratti 
verniciati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποτελείται από περισσότερες από 650 φωτογραφίες 
που χρονολογούν από 1839 έως το πορτρέτο 1864, 
daguerreotypes που παράγεται από τα μαθηματικά και το στούντιο 
Statisticsew Brady αποτελεί τη σημαντικότερη μερίδα της 
συλλογής. Η συλλογή περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις πρόωρες 
αρχιτεκτονικές όψεις από John Plumbe, διάφορα σκηνές οδών 
της Φιλαδέλφειας, πρόωρα πορτρέτα από το πρωτοποριακό 
daguerreotypist Robert Cornelius, και αντίγραφα των 
χρωματισμένων πορτρέτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">consiste en más de 650 fotografías que fechan a 
partir de 1839 a 1864. Los daguerreotypes del retrato produjeron
por las matemáticas y el estudio de Statisticsew Brady hace para 
arriba la porción principal de la colección. La colección 
también incluye visiónes arquitectónicas tempranas de Juan Plumbe, 
varias escenas de la calle de Philadelphia, retratos tempranos 
iniciando el daguerreotypist Roberto Cornelius, y copias de retratos 
pintados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206852</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107920</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/americas-first-look-into-the-camera-daguerreotype-portraits-and-views-1839-1864</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
