<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108044</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108044</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206723</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Smithsonian: History and Culture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Smithsonian: Geschichte und Kultur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Smithsonien : Histoire et culture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Smithsonian: History e cultura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Smithsonian: Storia e coltura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σμιθσονιτικός: Ιστορία και πολιτισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Smithsonian: Historia y cultura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the history of transportation in America, early history of mail service, the Civil War, West Point, profiles of U.S. presidents, Lakota winter counts, Lewis and Clark as naturalists, Japanese Americans during World War II, Brown v. Board of Education, athletes who broke social barriers, how voting systems have evolved, September 11, and America's wars.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft die Geschichte des Transportes in 
Amerika, Frühgeschichte von Post, der Bürgerkrieg, Westpunkt, 
Profile VEREINIGTE STAATEN Präsidenten, Lakota Winterder 
zählimpulse, des Lewis und des Clarks da Naturwissenschaftler, 
japanische Amerikaner während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, braunes v. 
Brett der Ausbildung, Athleten, die Sozialsperren, wie wählend 
Systeme entwickelt haben, September 11 und Amerikas Kriege brachen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine l'histoire du transport en Amérique, 
histoire des débuts de service de courrier, la guerre civile, le 
point occidental, profils des comptes de présidents des ETATS-UNIS, 
d'hiver de Lakota, de Lewis et de Clark car les naturalistes, 
Américains japonais pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, panneau 
brun de v. d'éducation, les athlètes qui ont cassé les barrières 
sociales, comment votant les systèmes ont évolué, des guerres 
septembre de 11, et de l'Amérique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina o history do transporte em América, 
history adiantado do serviço de correio, a guerra civil, ponto 
ocidental, perfis de contagens dos presidentes de ESTADOS UNIDOS, do 
inverno de Lakota, de Lewis e de Clark porque os naturalists, 
americanos japoneses durante a segunda guerra mundial, placa marrom da
instrução, os atletas do v. que quebraram barreiras sociais, como 
votando os sistemas evoluíram, guerras setembro de 11, e de América.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina la storia di trasporto in America, storia 
remota di servizio di posta, la guerra civile, il punto ad ovest, 
profili dei conteggi dei presidenti degli STATI UNITI, di inverno di 
Lakota, di Lewis e di Clark poichè naturalisti, Americani giapponesi 
durante la seconda guerra mondiale, il Bordo marrone di 
formazione, atleti del v. che hanno eliminare le barriere sociali, 
come votando i sistemi si sono evoluti, del 11 guerre settembre e 
dell'America.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την ιστορία της μεταφοράς στην Αμερική, 
πρόωρη ιστορία της υπηρεσίας ταχυδρομείου, ο εμφύλιος πόλεμος, 
δυτικό σημείο, σχεδιαγράμματα των ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ Προέδρων, 
αριθμήσεις χειμώνα Lakota, Lewis και clark ως φυσιοδίφες, 
ιαπωνικοί Αμερικανοί κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ,
Brown V. Board της εκπαίδευσης, αθλητές που έσπασαν τα 
κοινωνικά εμπόδια, πώς τα συστήματα ψηφοφορίας έχουν εξελιχθεί,
11 Σεπτεμβρίου, και πόλεμοι της Αμερικής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina la historia del transporte en América, 
historia temprana del servicio de correo, la guerra civil, punta del 
oeste, perfiles de las cuentas de los presidentes de ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
del invierno de Lakota, de Lewis y de Clark pues los naturalistas, 
americanos japoneses durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, tarjeta 
marrón de la educación, los atletas del v. que rompieron barreras 
sociales, cómo votan los sistemas se han desarrollado, las guerras de
septiembre del 11, y de América.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206723</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108044</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/smithsonian-history-and-culture</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
