<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105130</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105130</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211590</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Planetary Data System</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Planetarisches Daten-System</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Système de Données Planétaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sistema De Dados Planetário</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sistema Di Dati Planetario</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πλανητικό σύστημα στοιχείων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sistema De Datos Planetario</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">NASA's Planetary Data System (PDS) archives and distributes data from NASA planetary missions, astronomical observations, and laboratory measurements. The PDS serves different groups, from scientists to schoolteachers. The general public may use the site to access photographs and information gathered on NASA's many missions. Scientists can download data sets in PDS Catalogs, as well as references, dictionaries, and relevant software. Teachers can select from a collection of resources that are designed to be brought into the classroom.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Archiviert planetarisches Daten-System der NASAS 
(PDS) und verteilt Daten die NASA von den planetarischen Missionen, 
von den astronomischen Beobachtungen und von den Labormessen. 
Der PDS dient unterschiedliche Gruppen, von Wissenschaftler zu 
Schullehrer. Die Öffentlichkeit kann die Site benutzen, um 
die Fotographien und auf Informationen zuzugreifen, die auf vielen 
Missionen der NASAS erfaßt werden. Wissenschaftler können 
Dateien in den PDS Katalogen, sowie Referenzen downloaden, in den 
Verzeichnissen und in der relevanten Software. Lehrer können 
von einer Ansammlung Betriebsmitteln auswählen, die konzipiert sind, 
in das Klassenzimmer geholt zu werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le système de données planétaire de la NASA 
(PDS) archive et distribue des données des missions planétaires de 
la NASA, des observations astronomiques, et des mesures de 
laboratoire. Le PDS sert différents groupes, des scientifiques 
aux instituteurs. Le grand public peut employer le site pour 
accéder à des photographies et à l'information recueillies sur 
beaucoup de missions de la NASA. Les scientifiques peuvent 
télécharger des Modem dans des catalogues de PDS, aussi bien que des
références, des dictionnaires, et le logiciel approprié. Les 
professeurs peuvent choisir parmi une collection de ressources qui 
sont conçues pour être introduites dans la salle de classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O sistema de dados planetário da NASA (PDS) 
archives e distribui dados das missões planetárias da NASA, das 
observações astronômicas, e das medidas do laboratório. O 
PDS serve a grupos diferentes, dos cientistas aos schoolteachers. 
O público geral pode usar o local alcançar as fotografias e a 
informação recolhidas em muitas missões da NASA. Os 
cientistas podem download séries de dados de em catálogos do PDS, 
as.well.as referências, em dicionários, e no software relevante. 
Os professores podem selecionar de uma coleção dos recursos 
que são projetados ser trazidos na sala de aula.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il sistema di dati planetario della NASA (PDS) 
archivia e distribuisce i dati dalle missioni planetarie della NASA, 
dalle osservazioni astronomiche e dalle misure del laboratorio. 
Il PDS serve i gruppi differenti, dagli scienziati agli 
schoolteachers. Il grande pubblico può usare il luogo per 
accedere alle fotografie ed alle informazioni riunite su 
molte missioni della NASA. Gli scienziati possono trasferire gli
insiemi dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti di dati nei cataloghi 
di PDS, così come i riferimenti, in dizionari e nel software 
relativo. Gli insegnanti possono scegliere da una collezione di 
risorse che sono destinate per essere introdotte nell'aula.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πλανητικό σύστημα στοιχείων της NASA (PDS) 
αρχειοθετεί και διανέμει τα στοιχεία από τις πλανητικές 
αποστολές της NASA, τις αστρονομικές παρατηρήσεις, και τις 
εργαστηριακές μετρήσεις. Το PDS εξυπηρετεί τις 
διαφορετικές ομάδες, από τους επιστήμονες στους δασκάλους. 
Το ευρύ κοινό μπορεί να χρησιμοποιήσει την περιοχή στις 
φωτογραφίες πρόσβασης και τις πληροφορίες που συγκεντρώνονται για 
πολλές αποστολές της NASA. Οι επιστήμονες μπορούν να 
μεταφορτώσουν τα σύνολα στοιχείων στους καταλόγους PDS, καθώς 
επίσης και τις αναφορές, τα λεξικά, και το σχετικό λογισμικό. 
Οι δάσκαλοι μπορούν να επιλέξουν από μια συλλογή των 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς που σχεδιάζονται για να παρουσιαστούν στην 
τάξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El sistema de datos planetario de la NASA (PDS) 
archiva y distribuye datos de misiones planetarias de la NASA, de 
observaciones astronómicas, y de medidas del laboratorio. El 
PDS sirve a diversos grupos, de científicos a los maestros. 
El público en general puede utilizar el sitio para tener acceso
a las fotografías y a la información recopiladas en muchas misiones 
de la NASA. Los científicos pueden descargar modems en 
catálogos del PDS, así como referencias, diccionarios, y software 
relevante. Los profesores pueden seleccionar de una colección 
de los recursos que se diseñan para ser traídos en la sala de clase.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211590</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105130</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/planetary-data-system</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
