<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102905</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102905</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974049</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sunlight and the Seasons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tageslicht und die Jahreszeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lumière du soleil et les saisons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Luz solar e as estações</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luce solare e le stagioni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φως του ήλιου και οι εποχές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Luz del sol y las estaciones</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Children study seasonal change in sunlight in a global game of hide and seek. Students try to find 10 "mystery classes" hiding around the globe. The amount of sunlight is the central clue. Other clues link to each location's history, geography, culture, and more. Through these interrelated investigations, students discover that sunlight drives all living systems and they learn about the dynamic ecosystem that surrounds and connects them. This project reinforces a key concept: Changing sunlight drives all seasonal change. February-May. Weekly updates: Fridays. Guidelines, lessons, activities, reading connections, and interactive maps are included for each study.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kinder studieren Saisonänderung im Sonnenlicht in
einem globalen Spiel des Versteckens. Kursteilnehmer versuchen, 
10 zu finden "Geheimnis klassifiziert" das Verstecken um die Kugel. 
Die Menge des Tageslichtes ist der zentrale Anhaltspunkt. 
Andere Anhaltspunkte binden mit Geschichte, Geographie, Kultur 
und mehr jedes Standorts. Durch diese zusammenhängend 
Untersuchungen entdecken Kursteilnehmer, daß Tageslicht alle lebenden
Systeme antreibt und sie über das dynamische Oekosystem erlernen, das
sie umgibt und anschließt. Dieses Projekt verstärkt ein 
Schlüsselkonzept: Änderndes Tageslicht treibt alle 
Saisonänderung an. Februar-Mai. Wöchentliche 
Aktualisierungsvorgänge: Freitag. Korrekturlinien, 
Lektionen, Aktivitäten, Anschlüsse und interaktive Karten lesend 
sind für jede Studie enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les enfants étudient le changement saisonnier au 
soleil dans un jeu global d'à cache-cache. Les étudiants 
essayent de trouver 10 "mystère classe" se cacher autour du globe. 
La quantité de lumière du soleil est l'indice central. 
D'autres indices joignent à l'histoire, à la géographie, à 
la culture, et à plus de chaque emplacement. Par ces 
investigations en corrélation, les étudiants découvrent que la 
lumière du soleil pilote tous les systèmes vivants et ils se 
renseignent sur l'écosystème dynamique qui les entoure et relie. 
Ce projet renforce un concept principal : La lumière du 
soleil changeante pilote tout le changement saisonnier. 
Février-Mai. Mises à jour hebdomadaires : 
Vendredi. Les directives, leçons, activités, lisant des 
connexions, et des cartes interactives sont incluses pour chaque 
étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As crianças estudam a mudança seasonal na luz 
solar em um jogo global do hide e da busca. Os estudantes tentam
encontrar 10 "mistério classificam" esconder em torno do globo. 
A quantidade de luz solar é o indício central. Outros 
indícios ligam ao history, à geografia, à cultura, e a mais de cada
posição. Com estas investigações relacionadas, os estudantes
descobrem que a luz solar dirige todos os sistemas vivos e aprendem 
sobre o ecosystem dinâmico que os cerca e conecta. Este projeto
reforça um conceito chave: A luz solar em mudança dirige toda 
a mudança seasonal. Fevereiro-Maio. Updates semanais: 
Sextas-feiras. Os guidelines, lições, atividades, lendo 
conexões, e mapas interativos são incluídos para cada estudo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I bambini studiano il cambiamento stagionale al 
sole in un gioco globale del pellame e della ricerca. Gli 
allievi provano a trovare 10 "mistero classifica" nascondersi intorno 
al globo. La quantità di luce solare è l'indizio centrale. 
Altri indizii si collegano a storia, a geografia, alla coltura 
ed a più di ogni posizione. Con queste indagini correlate, gli 
allievi scoprono che la luce solare guida tutti i sistemi viventi ed 
imparano circa l'ecosistema dinamico che li circonda e collega. 
Questo progetto rinforza un concetto chiave: La luce 
solare cambiante guida tutto il cambiamento stagionale. 
Febbraio-Maggio. Aggiornamenti settimanali: 
Venerdì. La guida di riferimento, lezioni, attività, 
leggendo i collegamenti ed i programmi interattivi è inclusa per ogni
studio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα παιδιά μελετούν την εποχιακή αλλαγή στο φως του 
ήλιου σε ένα σφαιρικό παιχνίδι της δοράς και επιδιώκουν. 
Οι σπουδαστές προσπαθούν να βρούν 10 "κλάσεις μυστηρίου" σε
όλη την υδρόγειο. Το ποσό φωτός του ήλιου είναι η 
κεντρική ένδειξη. Αλλες ενδείξεις συνδέουν με την ιστορία,
τη γεωγραφία, τον πολιτισμό, και περισσότερους κάθε θέσης. 
Μέσω αυτών των αλληλένδετων ερευνών, οι σπουδαστές 
ανακαλύπτουν ότι το φως του ήλιου οδηγεί όλα τα συστήματα 
διαβίωσης και μαθαίνουν για το δυναμικό οικοσύστημα που τους 
περιβάλλει και συνδέει. Αυτό το πρόγραμμα ενισχύει μια 
βασική έννοια: Το μεταβαλλόμενο φως του ήλιου οδηγεί όλη 
την εποχιακή αλλαγή. Φεβρουάριος-Μάιος. 
Εβδομαδιαίες αναπροσαρμογές: Παρασκευές. Οι 
οδηγίες, μαθήματα, δραστηριότητες, διαβάζοντας τις συνδέσεις, και
τους διαλογικούς χάρτες συμπεριλαμβάνονται για κάθε μελέτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los niños estudian el cambio estacional en luz 
del sol en un juego global de la piel y de la búsqueda. Los 
estudiantes intentan encontrar 10 "misterio clasifican" ocultar 
alrededor del globo. La cantidad de luz del sol es la pista 
central. Otras pistas conectan a la historia, a la geografía, a
la cultura, y más de cada localización. Con estas 
investigaciones correlacionadas, los estudiantes descubren que la luz 
del sol conduce todos los sistemas vivos y aprenden sobre el 
ecosistema dinámico que los rodea y conecta. Este proyecto 
refuerza un concepto dominante: La luz del sol que cambia 
conduce todo el cambio estacional. Febrero-Mayo. 
Actualizaciones semanales: Viernes. Las guías de 
consulta, lecciones, actividades, leyendo conexiones, y 
correspondencias interactivas son incluidas para cada estudio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974049</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102905</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/sunlight-and-the-seasons</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
