<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103393</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103393</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202546</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Creating Community in the Classroom: Part 1 (Setting Goals )</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erstellen der Gemeinschaft im Klassenzimmer: 
Teil 1 (Ziele Einstellend)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Créer la Communauté dans la salle de classe : 
Partie 1 (Fixant des Objectifs)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Criando a comunidade na sala de aula: Parte 
1 (Que Ajusta Objetivos)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Creazione della Comunità nell'aula: Parte 1
(Che Regola Gli Obiettivi)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημιουργία της Κοινότητας στην τάξη: Μέρος 1 
(θέτοντας στόχοι)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Crear a comunidad en la sala de clase: Parte
1 (Que fija Metas)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This series of lessons is designed to help develop a sense of classroom community. Group goal-setting, brainstorming, peer feedback, group decision-making, positive reinforcement, and positive peer pressure are used to create a safe, supportive environment for learning in the classroom. In Part 1, students are introduced to the goal-setting process. They will practice the first step of the process as they set individual and class behavioral goals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Reihe Lektionen ist konzipiert, um zu 
helfen, eine Richtung der Klassenzimmergemeinschaft zu entwickeln. 
Gruppieren Sie die Ziel-Einstellung, Geistesstörung, 
Gleichfeedback, Gruppe Beschlußfassung, positive Verstärkung, und 
positiver Gleichdruck wird, eine sichere, unterstützende Umgebung 
für das Lernen im Klassenzimmer zu erstellen verwendet. In Teil
1, werden Kursteilnehmer zum Ziel-einstellenprozeß eingeführt. 
Sie üben den ersten Jobstep des Prozesses, wie sie Einzelperson
und Kategorie Verhaltensziele einstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette série de leçons est conçue pour aider à 
développer un sens de la communauté de salle de classe. 
Groupez le but-réglage, séance de réflexion, feedback de 
pair, prise de décision de groupe, renfort positif, et de la pression
positive de pair sont utilisées comme moyen de créer un 
environnement sûr et de support pour apprendre dans la salle de 
classe. Dans la partie 1, des étudiants sont présentés au 
processus deréglage. Ils pratiqueront la première étape du 
processus comme ils fixent des objectifs comportementaux d'individu et
de classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta série das lições é projetada ajudar 
desenvolver um sentido da comunidade da sala de aula. Agrupe o 
objetivo-ajuste, brainstorming, feedback do par, tomada de decisão do
grupo, reforço positivo, e a pressão positiva do par é usada criar 
um ambiente seguro, de suporte para aprender na sala de aula. Na
parte 1, os estudantes são introduzidos ao processo deajuste. 
Praticarão a primeira etapa do processo como ajustam objetivos 
behavioral do indivíduo e da classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa serie di lezioni è destinata per 
contribuire a sviluppare un senso della Comunità dell'aula. 
Raggruppi la obiettivo-regolazione, il "brainstorming", le 
risposte del pari, la risoluzione del gruppo, rinforzo positivo e la 
pressione positiva del pari è usata creare un ambiente sicuro e di 
appoggio per imparare nell'aula. Nella parte 1, gli allievi sono
introdotti al processo diregolazione. Si eserciteranno nel primo
punto del processo come regolano gli obiettivi del comportamento del 
codice categoria e dell'individuo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων έχει ως σκοπό να βοηθήσει να 
αναπτύξει μια αίσθηση της κοινότητας τάξεων. Η στόχος-τιμή
τών παραμέτρων ομάδας, το "brainstorming", η όμοια 
ανατροφοδότηση, η λήψη αποφάσεων ομάδας, η θετική ενίσχυση, και 
η θετική όμοια πίεση χρησιμοποιούνται για να δημιουργήσουν ένα 
ασφαλές, ενθαρρυντικό περιβάλλον για την εκμάθηση στην τάξη. 
Στο μέρος 1, οι σπουδαστές εισάγονται στη στόχος-θέτοντας 
διαδικασία. Θα ασκήσουν το πρώτο βήμα της διαδικασίας 
καθώς θέτουν μεμονωμένους και κλάση τους συμπεριφοριστικούς 
στόχους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta serie de lecciones se diseña para ayudar a 
desarrollar un sentido de la comunidad de la sala de clase. 
Agrupe meta-fijar, reunión de reflexión, feedback del par, 
toma de decisión del grupo, refuerzo positivo, y se utiliza la 
presión positiva del par de crear un ambiente seguro, de apoyo para 
aprender en la sala de clase. En la parte 1, introducen a los 
estudiantes al proceso meta-que fija. Practicarán el primer 
paso de progresión del proceso como fijan metas del comportamiento 
del individuo y de la clase.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAT NYSTROM
FN:PAT NYSTROM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202546</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103393</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/creating-community-in-the-classroom-part-1-setting-goals</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
