<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/1258154009</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>1258154009</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087108</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"This Is Not a Gay Issue. This Is a Human Issue": Early AIDS Patients Recount Their Experiences with the Disease</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"dieses ist nicht eine homosexuelle Ausgabe. 
Dieses ist eine menschliche Ausgabe ": Frühe AIDS 
Patienten zählen ihre Erfahrungen mit der Krankheit nach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"ce n'est pas une issue gaie. C'est une 
issue humaine ": Les premiers personnes atteints du SIDA 
racontent leurs expériences avec la maladie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"esta não é uma edição gay. Esta é uma 
edição humana ": Os pacientes de AIDS adiantados recount suas 
experiências com a doença</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"questa non è un'edizione di Gay. 
Ciò è un'edizione umana ": I pazienti di AIDS in 
anticipo raccontano le loro esperienze con la malattia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτό δεν είναι ένα ομοφυλοφιλικό ζήτημα. Αυτό
είναι ένα ανθρώπινο ζήτημα ": Οι πρώτοι ασθενείς του 
AIDS εξιστορούν την εμπειρία τους με την ασθένεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"esto no es una edición Gay. Esto 
es una edición humana ": Los pacientes de SIDA tempranos 
contaron de nuevo sus experiencias con la enfermedad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1981, the U.S. medical community noticed a significant number of gay men living in urban areas with rare forms of pneumonia, cancer, and lymph disorders. The cluster of ailments was initially dubbed Gay-Related Immune Disease (GRID), but when similar illnesses increased in other groups, the name changed to Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS). The mid-1980s saw a number of advances toward understanding and treating the disease, but no vaccine or cure was forthcoming. Gay advocacy and community-based organizations began providing services and pressuring government to increase funding for finding a cure and helping victims. Despite further drug therapy breakthroughs and prevention campaigns, in 1995 AIDS became the leading cause of death for Americans aged 25 to 44. By 2002, while the annual rate of new HIV cases dropped in the U.S. to 40,000 (from a 1980s high of 150,000), more than 20 million people worldwide had died from the disease, and 40 million were living with HIV. In the following 1983 testimony before a congressional committee, three AIDS patients described their personal experiences during the early years of the disease.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1981 beachtete die VEREINIGTE STAATEN medizinische
Gemeinschaft eine bedeutende Anzahl von den homosexuellen Männern, 
die in den städtischen Bereichen mit seltenen Formularen der 
Pneumonie, des Krebses und der Lymphestörungen leben. Der Block
von Unpäßlichkeiten war zuerst betitelte Homosexuell-In Verbindung 
stehende immune Krankheit (RASTERFELD), aber, als ähnliche 
Krankheiten anderer Gruppen sich erhöhten, der Name änderte zu 
erworbenem immunem Mangel-Syndrom (AIDS). Die Mitte der 80iger 
Jahre sah eine Anzahl von Fortschritten in Richtung zum Verstehen und 
zum Behandeln der Krankheit, aber kein Impfstoff oder Heilung waren 
bevorstehend. Homosexuelle Befürwortung und 
Gemeinschaft-gegründete Organisationen fingen, Dienstleistungen zur 
Verfügung zu stellen an und Regierung zu druecken, um die 
Finanzierung für das Finden einer Heilung und das Helfen der Opfer zu
erhöhen. Trotz der weiteren Drogetherapiedurchbrüche und der 
Verhinderungkampagnen in 1995 AIDS wurde die führende Ursache des 
Todes für gealterten Amerikaner 25 bis die 44. Bis zum 2002 
während die jährliche Kinetik der neuen HIV Fälle in die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN auf 40.000 (von einer achtziger Jahre Höhe von 
150.000) abfiel, waren mehr als 20 Million Leute weltweit an der 
Krankheit gestorben, und 40 Million lebten mit HIV. Im folgenden
Zeugnis 1983 vor einem Kongreßausschuß, beschrieben drei 
AIDS-Patienten ihre persönlichen Erfahrungen während der frühen 
Jahre der Krankheit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1981, la communauté médicale des ETATS-UNIS a
noté un nombre significatif d'hommes gais vivant dans des zones 
urbaines avec les formes rares de la pneumonie, du cancer, et des 
désordres de lymphe. La batterie des maux était au 
commencement la maladie immunisée Gai-Connexe doublée (GRILLE), mais
quand les maladies semblables ont augmenté dans d'autres groupes, le 
nom a changé en le syndrome immunisé saisi d'insuffisance (SIDA). 
Le milieu des années 80 a vu un certain nombre d'avances vers 
l'arrangement et traiter la maladie, mais aucun vaccin ou traitement 
n'était reçu. La recommandation gaie et les organismes 
communauté-basés ont commencé à fournir des services et à 
pressuriser le gouvernement pour augmenter le placement pour trouver 
un traitement et aider des victimes. En dépit d'autres de 
découvertes de thérapie de drogue et de campagnes d'empêchement, 
dans 1995 SIDAS est devenue la principale cause de la mort pour des 
Américains âgés 25 à 44. D'ici 2002, alors que la cadence 
annuelle de nouveaux cas d'HIV chutait aux ETATS-UNIS à 40.000 (d'une
haute des années 80 de 150.000), plus de 20 millions de personnes 
dans le monde entier étaient morts de la maladie, et 40 millions 
vivaient avec HIV. Dans le témoignage 1983 suivant devant un 
comité congressionnel, trois personnes atteintes du SIDA ont décrit 
leurs expériences personnelles pendant les premières années de la 
maladie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1981, a comunidade médica de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
observou um número significativo dos homens gay que vivem em áreas 
urbanas com formulários raros do pneumonia, do cancer, e dos 
disorders do lymph. O conjunto dos ailments era inicialmente 
doença imune Gay-Relacionada dubbed (GRADE), mas quando as doenças 
similares aumentaram em outros grupos, o nome mudou ao syndrome imune 
adquirido da deficiência (AIDS). Os mid-1980s viram um número 
de avanços para a compreensão e o tratamento da doença, mas nenhuma
vacina ou cura eram forthcoming. O advocacy gay e as 
organizações comunidade-baseadas começaram a fornecer serviços e 
exercer pressão sobre o governo para aumentar financiar para 
encontrar uma cura e ajudar a vítimas. Apesar de umas 
descobertas da terapia de droga e de umas campanhas mais adicionais da
prevenção, em 1995 AIDS tornou-se a causa principal da morte para os
americanos envelhecidos 25 a 44. Por 2002, quando a taxa anual 
de exemplos novos do HIV deixou cair nos ESTADOS UNIDOS a 40.000 (de 
uma elevação dos 1980s de 150.000), mais de 20 milhão povos 
worldwide tinham morrido da doença, e 40 milhões estavam vivendo com
HIV. No seguinte testimony 1983 antes de um comitê 
congressional, três pacientes de AIDS descreveram suas experiências 
pessoais durante os anos adiantados da doença.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1981, la Comunità medica degli STATI UNITI ha 
notato un numero significativo di uomini di gay che vivono 
nelle aree urbane con le forme rare di polmonite, di cancro e di 
disordini della linfa. La serie di ingranaggi dei ailments era 
inizialmente malattia immune dubbed di gay-related (GRIGLIA), ma
quando le malattie simili sono aumentato di altri gruppi, il nome è 
cambiato alla sindrome immune acquistata di mancanza (AIDS). I 
mid-1980s hanno visto un certo numero di avanzamenti verso capire e 
trattare la malattia, ma non c'era nessun vaccino o cura prossima. 
L'avvocatura di gay e le organizzazioni 
Comunità-basate hanno cominciato a fornire i servizi e pressuring il 
governo per aumentare costituire un fondo per per l'individuazione 
della cura e l'assistenza delle vittime. Malgrado le ulteriori 
innovazioni di terapia farmacologica e campagne di prevenzione, in 
1995 AIDS è diventato la causa principale della morte per gli 
Americani anziani 25 - 44. Entro 2002, mentre il tasso annuale 
di nuovi casi del HIV è caduto negli STATI UNITI a 40.000 (da un high
degli anni 80 di 150.000), più di 20 milione di persone 
universalmente erano morto dalla malattia e 40 milioni stavano vivendo
con il HIV. Nella seguente testimonianza 1983 prima di un 
comitato congressuale, tre pazienti di AIDS hanno descritto le loro 
esperienze personali durante i primi anni della malattia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1981, η ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιατρική κοινότητα παρατήρησε 
έναν σημαντικό αριθμό ομοφυλοφιλικών ατόμων που ζουν στις 
αστικές περιοχές με τις σπάνιες μορφές της πνευμονίας, του 
καρκίνου, και των αναταραχών λυμφών. Ο τομέας των ασθενειών
μεταγλωττίστηκε αρχικά την εύθυμος-σχετική άνοση ασθένεια 
(GRID), αλλά όταν άλλαξαν οι παρόμοιες ασθένειες που 
αυξήθηκαν σε άλλες ομάδες, το όνομα στο σύνδρομο επίκτητης 
ανοσολογικής ανεπάρκειας (AIDS). Η μέσος-δεκαετία του '80
εβλέίδε διάφορες προόδους προς την κατανόηση και τη 
θεραπεία της ασθένειας, αλλά καμία εμβόλιο ή θεραπεία δεν ήταν
προσεχές. Η ομοφυλοφιλική υπεράσπιση και οι σε κοινοτικό 
επίπεδο οργανώσεις άρχισαν τις υπηρεσίες και την κυβέρνηση για να
αυξήσουν τη χρηματοδότηση για την εύρεση μιας θεραπείας και τη 
βοήθεια των θυμάτων. Παρά τις περαιτέρω σημαντικές 
ανακαλύψεις θεραπείας φαρμάκων και τις εκστρατείες πρόληψης, το 
1995 το AIDS έγινε η κύρια αιτία του θανάτου για 
Αμερικανούς ηλικίας 25 έως 44. Μέχρι το 2002, ενώ 
το ετήσιο ποσοστό νέων υποθέσεων HIV μειώθηκε στις ΗΠΑ σε 
40.000 (από η δεκαετία του '80 υψηλή 150,000), περισσότεροι 
από 20 εκατομμύριο άνθρωποι παγκοσμίως είχαν πεθάνει από την 
ασθένεια, και 40 εκατομμύρια ζούσαν με το HIV. Στην 
ακόλουθη κατάθεση του 1983 ενώπιον μιας του Κογκρέσου 
επιτροπής, τρεις ασθενείς του AIDS περιέγραψαν την προσωπική 
εμπειρία τους κατά τη διάρκεια των πρώτων ετών της ασθένειας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1981, la comunidad médica de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
notó un número significativo de los hombres gays que vivían
en áreas urbanas con las formas raras de pulmonía, de cáncer, y de 
desórdenes de la linfa. El racimo de dolencias era inicialmente
enfermedad inmune doblada de gay-related (REJILLA), pero cuando 
las enfermedades similares aumentaron de otros grupos, el nombre 
cambió al síndrome inmune adquirido de la deficiencia (SIDA). 
Los a mediados de los años ochenta consideraron un número de 
avances hacia entender y tratar la enfermedad, pero no hay vacuna o 
curación próxima. La defensa gay y las organizaciones 
comunidad-basadas comenzaron a proporcionar a servicios y a ejercer 
presión sobre el gobierno para aumentar el financiamiento para 
encontrar una curación y ayudar a víctimas. A pesar de 
descubrimientos de la terapia de droga y campañas más futuros de la 
prevención, en 1995 SIDA se convirtió la causa principal de la 
muerte para los americanos envejecidos 25 a 44. Antes de 2002, 
mientras que el índice anual de los casos nuevos del VIH cayó en los
ESTADOS UNIDOS a 40.000 (de un colmo de los años 80 de 150.000), más
de 20 millones de personas de por todo el mundo habían muerto de la 
enfermedad, y 40 millones vivían con el VIH. En el testimonio 
siguiente 1983 ante un comité del congreso, tres pacientes de SIDA 
describieron sus experiencias personales durante los años de la 
enfermedad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087108</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>1258154009</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/this-is-not-a-gay-issue-this-is-a-human-issue-early-aids-patients-recount-their-experiences-with-the-disease</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
