<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104534</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104534</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207109</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Baseball: As American as Apple Pie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Baseball: So amerikanisch wie Apfelkuchen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Base-ball : Aussi américain que le pâté 
en croûte de Apple</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Baseball: Tão americano quanto a torta de 
Apple</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Baseball: Americano quanto la torta di 
Apple</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μπέιζ-μπώλ: Τόσο αμερικανικά όσο την πίτα 
μήλα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Béisbol: Tan americano como la empanada de 
Apple</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is an annotated collection of Library of Congress resources about America's pastime. It includes early baseball pictures, baseball songs and stories, baseball cards, the first all-professional baseball team in America (the Cincinnati Red Stockings, 1869), Cy Young, Ty Cobb, home run kings, and letters and speeches by Jackie Robinson, the first African American to play major league baseball.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine angemerkte Ansammlung der Bibliothek der 
Kongreßbetriebsmittel über Zeitvertreib Amerikas. Sie 
schließt frühe Baseballabbildungen, Baseballliede und Geschichten, 
Baseballkarten, das erste Allfachmann Baseballteam in Amerika (die 
Cincinnati roten Strümpfe, 1869), Cy Junge, Ty Cobb ein, lassen Haus 
Könige und Zeichen und Reden durch Jackie Robinson, der erste 
afrikanische Amerikaner laufen, um Hauptligabaseball zu spielen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une collection annotée de bibliothèque des 
ressources du congrès au sujet du passe-temps de l'Amérique. 
Elle inclut les images de base-ball, les chansons de base-ball 
et les histoires tôt, les cartes de base-ball, la première équipe 
de base-ball de tout-professionnel en Amérique (les bas rouges de 
Cincinnati, 1869), jeunes de Cy, Ty Cobb, la maison exécutent des 
rois, et des lettres et des discours par Jackie Robinson, le premier 
Américain africain pour jouer au base-ball principal de ligue.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma coleção anotada da biblioteca de recursos
do congress sobre o pastime de América. Inclui retratos do 
baseball, canções do baseball e histórias adiantados, cartões de 
baseball, a primeira equipe de baseball do todo-profissional em 
América (as meias vermelhas de Cincinnati, 1869), jovens de Cy, Ty 
Cobb, a HOME funciona reis, e letras e discursos por Jackie Robinson, 
primeiro americano africano para jogar o baseball principal da liga.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una collezione annotata di libreria delle 
risorse del congresso circa pastime dell'America. Include le 
immagini di baseball, canzoni di baseball e storia iniziali, schedi di
baseball, la prima squadra di baseball del tutto-professionista in 
America (le calze rosse de Cincinnati, 1869), giovani di Cy, Ty Cobb, 
la sede fa funzionare i re e lettere e discorsi da Jackie Robinson, il
primo americano africano per giocare il baseball principale della 
lega.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια σχολιασμένη συλλογή των στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς βιβλιοθήκης του συνεδρίου για το χόμπι της Αμερικής.
Περιλαμβάνει τις πρόωρες εικόνες μπέιζ-μπώλ, τα τραγούδια 
μπέιζ-μπώλ και τις ιστορίες, κάρτες μπέιζ-μπώλ, η πρώτη 
όλος-επαγγελματική ομάδα μπέιζ-μπώλ στην Αμερική (οι κόκκινες 
γυναικείες κάλτσες του Κινκινάτι, 1869), νεολαίες της Κύπρου, 
Ty Cobb, σπίτι τρέχουν τους βασιλιάδες, και τις επιστολές 
και τις ομιλίες της Jackie Robinson, ο πρώτος αφρικανικός 
Αμερικανός για να παίξουν σημαντικό μπέιζ-μπώλ ένωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una colección anotada de la biblioteca de los 
recursos del congreso sobre el pasatiempo de América. Incluye 
los cuadros del béisbol, las canciones y las historias tempranos, 
tarjetas de béisbol, el primer equipo del béisbol de béisbol del 
todo-profesional en América (las medias rojas de Cincinnati, 1869), 
jóvenes de Cy, Ty Cobb, el hogar ejecuta a reyes, y las cartas y los 
discursos de Jackie Robinson, el primer americano africano para jugar 
a béisbol importante de la liga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207109</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104534</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/baseball-as-american-as-apple-pie</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
