<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105378</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105378</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205873</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Captured Wisdom on Adult Literacy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erfaßte Klugheit auf Erwachsen-Bildungsgrad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sagesse capturée sur l'instruction d'adulte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sabedoria capturada no literacy do adulto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Saggezza bloccata su literacy dell'adulto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συλλήφθείη φρόνηση στην ενήλικη βασική εκπαίδευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sabiduría capturada en la instrucción del 
adulto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a series of stories about adult literacy teaching success. In one story, adults learning English use the Internet to find pictures and information about their home country for written and oral reports. In another, adult students act as consultants hired to save a failing restaurant and use technology to deal with irate customers, schedule work hours, and design new menus.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Reihe Geschichten über unterrichtenden 
Erfolg des Erwachsenbildungsgrades. In einer Geschichte benutzen
die Erwachsenen, die Englisch erlernen, das Internet, um Abbildungen 
und Informationen über ihr Heimatland für die geschriebenen und 
Mundreports zu finden. In anderen dienen Erwachsenkursteilnehmer
als die Berater, die angestellt werden, um eine ausfallende 
Gaststätte zu sichern und Technologie zu verwenden, um zornige 
Kunden, Zeitplanarbeit Stunden zu beschäftigen und konzipieren neue 
Menüs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une série d'histoires au sujet de succès 
d'enseignement d'instruction d'adulte. Dans une histoire, les 
adultes apprenant l'anglais emploient l'Internet pour trouver des 
images et des informations sur leur pays d'origine pour des états 
écrits et oraux. Dans des autres, les étudiants d'adulte 
agissent en tant que conseillers loués pour sauvegarder un restaurant
échouant et pour employer la technologie pour avoir affaire avec les 
clients furieux, heures de travail de programme, et conçoivent de 
nouveaux menus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma série das histórias sobre o sucesso 
ensinando do literacy do adulto. Em uma história, os adultos 
que aprendem o inglês usam o Internet encontrar retratos e 
informação sobre seu país home para relatórios escritos e orais. 
Em outros, os estudantes do adulto agem como os consultantes 
empregados para conservar um restaurante de falha e para usar a 
tecnologia tratar dos clientes irate, horas do trabalho da 
programação, e projetam menus novos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una serie di storia circa successo d'istruzione
di literacy dell'adulto. In una storia, gli adulti che imparano 
l'inglese usano il Internet per trovare le immagini e le informazioni 
sul loro pæse d'origine per i rapporti scritti ed orali. In un 
altro, gli allievi dell'adulto fungono da consulenti assunti per 
salvare un ristorante venente a mancare e per usare la tecnologia per 
trattare con i clienti irate, ore del lavoro di programma e progettano
i nuovi menu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια σειρά ιστοριών για την ενήλικη επιτυχία 
διδασκαλίας βασικής εκπαίδευσης. Σε μια ιστορία, αγγλική 
χρήση εκπαίδευσης ενηλίκων το Διαδίκτυο για να βρεί τις εικόνες 
και τις πληροφορίες για τη βασική χώρα τους για τις γραπτές και 
προφορικές εκθέσεις. Σε άλλος, οι ενήλικοι σπουδαστές 
ενεργούν ως σύμβουλοι που μισθώνονται για να σώσουν μια 
αποτυχούσα τεχνολογία εστιατορίων και χρήσης για να εξετάσουν 
τους οργισμένους πελάτες, ώρες εργασίας προγράμματος, και 
σχεδιάζουν τους νέους καταλόγους επιλογής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una serie de historias sobre éxito de 
enseñanza de la instrucción del adulto. En una historia, los 
adultos que aprenden inglés utilizan el Internet para encontrar 
cuadros y la información sobre su país de orígen para los informes 
escritos y orales. En otros, los estudiantes del adulto actúan 
como consultores empleados para salvar un restaurante que falla y para
utilizar tecnología para tratar de los clientes furiosos, horas del 
trabajo del horario, y diseñan nuevos menús.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205873</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105378</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/captured-wisdom-on-adult-literacy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
