<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105404</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105404</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203010</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">GPS Treasure Hunt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gps Schatz-Jagd</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chasse À Trésor de GPS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Caça Do Tesouro do Gps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Tesoro di Gps Cerca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κυνήγι θησαυρών ΠΣΤ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caza Del Tesoro del Gps</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This game is actually an on-campus field lab that has students using directions and a GPS receiver to make their way from one stop to the next. At each stop, they identify a building stone (or tree for an environmental studies or plant biology class). If possible, have the students work in small groups, taking turns using the GPS receiver and with each group having its own direction sheet. At the end, they collect a ticket for an edible prize. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Spiel ist wirklich auffangen Labor
on-campus, das Kursteilnehmer mit Richtungen und einem GPS Empfänger,
ihre Methode von einem Anschlag zum folgenden zu bilden hat. An 
jedem Anschlag kennzeichnen sie einen Baustein (oder Baum für 
errichten Klimastudien oder Biologieunterricht). Wenn möglich, 
haben Sie die Kursteilnehmer arbeiten in den kleinen Gruppen, dreht 
sich das Nehmen mit dem GPS Empfänger und mit jeder Gruppe, die sein 
eigenes Richtung Blatt hat. Am Ende sammeln sie eine Karte für 
einen eßbaren Preis. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können 
Benutzer auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext
für Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce jeu est réellement un laboratoire localisé de
zone qui a des étudiants en utilisant des directions et un récepteur
de GPS pour faire leur voie à partir d'un arrêt au prochain. 
À chaque arrêt, ils identifient une pierre de bâtiment (ou 
l'arbre pour les études environnementales ou plantent la classe de 
biologie). Si possible, ayez les étudiants travaillent dans de 
petits groupes, la prise tourne en utilisant le récepteur de GPS et 
avec chaque groupe ayant sa propre feuille de direction. À 
l'extrémité, ils rassemblent un billet pour un prix comestible. 
À cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent 
accéder aux informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, 
contexte pour les extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes
et, le matériel didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les 
références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este jogo é realmente um laboratório no local do
campo que tenha estudantes usando sentidos e um receptor do GPS fazer 
sua maneira de um batente ao seguinte. Em cada batente, 
identificam uma pedra de edifício (ou a árvore para os estudos 
ambientais ou plantam a classe de biologia). Se possível, tenha
os estudantes trabalham em grupos pequenos, fazer exame gira usando o 
receptor do GPS e com cada grupo que tem sua própria folha do 
sentido. Na extremidade, coletam um bilhete para um prêmio 
edible. Nesta página do ponto começar, os usuários podem 
alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do 
exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os 
materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as referências e os 
tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo gioco è realmente un laboratorio 
localizzato del campo che ha allievi usando i sensi e una ricevente di
GPS per fare il loro modo da un arresto al seguente. Ad ogni 
arresto, identificano una pietra da costruzione (o l'albero per gli 
studi ambientali o piantano il codice categoria di biologia). Se
possibile, abbia gli allievi funzionano nei piccoli gruppi, prendere 
gira usando la ricevente di GPS e con ogni gruppo che ha relativo 
proprio foglio di senso. All'estremità, raccolgono un biglietto
per un premio commestibile. A questa pagina del punto di 
partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sugli 
obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di 
istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le idee di 
valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το παιχνίδι είναι πραγματικά ένα εργαστήριο 
πεδίων-ΠΑΝΕΠΙΣΤΗΜΙΟΥΠΌΛΕΩΝ που έχει τους σπουδαστές που 
χρησιμοποιούν τις κατευθύνσεις και έναν δέκτη ΠΣΤ για να κάνει 
τον τρόπο τους από μια στάση στην επόμενη. Σε κάθε στάση, 
προσδιορίζουν μια πέτρα κτηρίου (ή το δέντρο για περιβαλλοντική 
μελέτες ή κλάση της βιολογίας φυτών). Εάν είναι δυνατόν,
έχει την εργασία σπουδαστών στις μικρές ομάδες, που αναλαμβάνουν
εκ περιτροπής που χρησιμοποιούν το δέκτη ΠΣΤ και με κάθε ομάδα 
που έχει το φύλλο κατεύθυνσής του. Στο τέλος, συλλέγουν 
ένα εισιτήριο για ένα εδώδιμο βραβείο. Σε αυτήν την 
σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις 
πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για 
τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα 
εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα 
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este juego es realmente un laboratorio localizado 
del campo que tiene estudiantes usando direcciones y un receptor del 
GPS para hacer su manera a partir de una parada al siguiente. En
cada parada, identifican una piedra de edificio (o el árbol para los 
estudios ambientales o plantan la clase de biología). Si es 
posible, tenga los estudiantes trabajan en grupos pequeños, el tomar 
da vuelta con el receptor del GPS y con cada grupo que tiene su propia
hoja de la dirección. En el extremo, recogen un boleto para un 
premio comestible. En esta paginación del punto de partida, los
utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre las metas que
aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la 
enseñanza las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las ideas del 
gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:REBECCA TEED
FN:REBECCA TEED
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203010</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105404</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/gps-treasure-hunt</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
