<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104271</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104271</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213485</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Professor And Pat Computer Technology eBooks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Professor-und Klaps-Computertechnologie eBooks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les eBooks d'informatique de professeur et de 
tapotement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os eBooks da informática do professor e do do pat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I eBooks di tecnologia dell'informatica del 
picchiettio e del professor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η τεχνολογία υπολογιστών καθηγητή και ελαφριού 
κτυπήματος eBooks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los eBooks de la informática del profesor y de la 
palmadita</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Professor And Pat series consists of free computer technology ebooks for the absolute beginner which teach technical subjects by telling a story.  Read how Pat learns about the Von Neumann architecture, machine language, and assembly language from Pat's friend the professor and use the same programming tools that Pat uses to develop your own programs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Professor- und Klapsserie besteht aus freien 
Computertechnologie ebooks für den absoluten Anfänger, die 
technische Themen unterrichten, indem sie eine Geschichte erklären. 
Gelesene, wie Klaps über die Von Neumann Architektur erlernt, 
Maschinensprache und Assemblersprache vom Freund des Klapses der 
Professor und benutzen die gleichen Programmierung Hilfsmittel, denen 
Klaps verwendet, Ihre eigenen Programme zu entwickeln.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La série de professeur et de tapotement consiste 
en ebooks libres d'informatique pour le débutant absolu qui 
enseignent les sujets techniques en disant une histoire. Le 
langage machine lue comment le tapotement se renseigne sur 
l'architecture de Neumann de Von, et le langage d'assemblage de
l'ami du tapotement le professeur et utilisent les mêmes outils de 
programmation que le tapotement utilise pour développer vos propres 
programmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A série do professor e do pat consiste nos ebooks
livres da informática de para o novato absoluto que ensinam assuntos 
técnicos dizendo uma história. A língua lida como o pat 
aprende sobre a arquitetura de Von Neumann, de máquina, e a língua 
de conjunto do amigo do pat o professor e usam as mesmas ferramentas 
de programação que o pat se usa desenvolver seus próprios 
programas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La serie del picchiettio e del professor consiste 
dei ebooks liberi di tecnologia dell'informatica per il principiante 
assoluto che insegnano gli oggetti tecnici dicendo ad una storia. 
Il linguaggio macchina e Neumann l'architettura del Von circa 
impara il picchiettio come colta ed il linguaggio Assembler dall'amico
del picchiettio il professore ed utilizzano gli stessi strumenti di 
programmazione che il picchiettio usa sviluppare i vostri propri 
programmi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σειρά καθηγητή και ελαφριού κτυπήματος αποτελείται 
από την ελεύθερη τεχνολογία υπολογιστών ebooks για τον απόλυτο
αρχάριο που διδάσκει τα τεχνικά θέματα με την αφήγηση μιας 
ιστορίας. Διαβάστε πώς το ελαφρύ κτύπημα μαθαίνει για τη 
Von Neumann αρχιτεκτονική, τη γλώσσα μηχανών, και τη 
Συμβολική γλώσσα (Assembly) από το φίλο του ελαφριού 
κτυπήματος ο καθηγητής και χρησιμοποιεί τα ίδια εργαλεία 
προγραμματισμού που το ελαφρύ κτύπημα χρησιμοποιεί για να 
αναπτύξει τα προγράμματά σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La serie del profesor y de la palmadita consiste 
en los ebooks libres de la informática para el principiante absoluto 
que enseñan temas técnicos contando una historia. La 
terminología leída cómo la palmadita aprende sobre la 
configuración de Von Neumann, de la informática, y el lenguaje 
ensamblador del amigo de la palmadita el profesor y utilizan las 
mismas herramientas de programación que la palmadita utiliza 
desarrollar sus propios programas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TED KOSAN
FN:TED KOSAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213485</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104271</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-professor-and-pat-computer-technology-ebooks</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
