<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105708</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105708</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203060</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Harmful Algae Digital Library</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schädliche Algen Digital Bibliothek</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bibliothèque Nocive de Digital d'Algues</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biblioteca Prejudicial De Digital Das Algas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Libreria Nociva Di Digital Delle Alghe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιβλαβής ψηφιακή βιβλιοθήκη αλγών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biblioteca Dañosa De Digital De las Algas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Harmful Algae Digital Library contains a collection of Sea Grant documents in digital format (primarily PDF) arranged by subject area: red tide/PSP, brown tide, ciguatera, killer algae, and Pfiesteria. This collection is part of the National Sea Grant Library (NSGL), which maintains over 36,000 searchable records dedicated to environmental stewardship, long-term economic development and responsible use of America's coastal, ocean and Great Lakes resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die schädliche Algen Digital Bibliothek enthält 
eine Ansammlung Seegrant Dokumente im digitalen Format (hauptsächlich
pdf) geordnet durch Bereich: rote Gezeiten, braune 
Gezeiten, ciguatera, Mörderalgen und Pfiesteria. Diese 
Ansammlung ist ein Teil der nationalen Seegrant Bibliothek (NSGL), die
über 36.000 auffindbaren Sätzen beibehält, die der 
KlimaFührung eingesetzt werden, langfristiger ökonomischer 
Entwicklung und verantwortlichen dem Gebrauch Amerikas Küsten, Ozean 
und Great Lakes Betriebsmittel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La bibliothèque nocive de Digital d'algues 
contient une collection de documents de Grant de mer dans le format 
digital (principalement pdf) disposé par domaine : tide/PSP 
rouge, marée brune, ciguatera, algues de tueur, et Pfiesteria. 
Cette collection fait partie de la bibliothèque nationale de 
Grant de mer (NSGL), qui met à jour plus de 36.000 enregistrements 
rechercheables consacrés à l'intendance environnementale, au 
développement économique à long terme et à l'utilisation 
responsable de l'Amérique côtiers, océan et ressources de Great 
Lakes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A biblioteca prejudicial de Digital das algas 
contem uma coleção de originais de Grant do mar no formato digital 
(primeiramente pdf) arranjado pela área sujeita: tide/PSP 
vermelho, maré marrom, ciguatera, algas do assassino, e Pfiesteria. 
Esta coleção é parte da biblioteca nacional de Grant do mar 
(NSGL), que mantem sobre 36.000 registros searchable dedicados ao 
stewardship ambiental, ao desenvolvimento econômico a longo prazo e 
ao uso responsável de América litorais, oceano e recursos de Great 
Lakes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La libreria nociva di Digital delle alghe contiene
una raccolta di documenti del Grant del mare nel formato digitale 
(soprattutto pdf) organizzato da settore: tide/PSP rosso, marea 
marrone, ciguatera, alghe dell'assassino e Pfiesteria. Questa 
accumulazione fa parte della libreria nazionale del Grant del mare 
(NSGL), che effettua oltre 36.000 record reperibili dedicati a 
stewardship ambientale, a sviluppo economico di lunga durata e ad uso 
responsabile dell'America litoranei, oceano e risorse dei Great Lakes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η επιβλαβής ψηφιακή βιβλιοθήκη αλγών περιέχει μια 
συλλογή των εγγράφων επιχορήγησης θάλασσας σε ψηφιακή μορφή 
(πρώτιστα PDF) που τακτοποιείται από τη θεματική περιοχή: 
κόκκινο παλίρροια/PSP, καφετιά παλίρροια, ciguatera, 
άλγη δολοφόνων, και Pfiesteria. Αυτή η συλλογή είναι 
μέρος της εθνικής βιβλιοθήκης επιχορήγησης θάλασσας (NSGL), η 
οποία διατηρεί πάνω από 36.000 εξερευνήσιμα αρχεία που 
αφιερώνονται στην περιβαλλοντική διαχείριση, τη μακροπρόθεσμη 
οικονομική ανάπτυξη και την αρμόδια χρήση των παράκτιων, 
ωκεάνιων και μεγάλων στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς λιμνών της Αμερικής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La biblioteca dañosa de Digital de las algas 
contiene una colección de los documentos de Grant del mar en el 
formato digital (sobre todo pdf) dispuesto por tema: tide/PSP 
rojo, marea marrón, ciguatera, algas del asesino, y Pfiesteria. 
Esta colección es parte de la biblioteca nacional de Grant del 
mar (NSGL), que mantiene sobre 36.000 expedientes investigables 
dedicados a la administración ambiental, al desarrollo económico a 
largo plazo y al uso responsable de América costeros, océano y los 
recursos de Great Lakes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL SEA GRANT LIBRARY
FN:NATIONAL SEA GRANT LIBRARY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNIVERSITY OF RHODE ISLAND-BAY CAMPUS, NOAA
FN:UNIVERSITY OF RHODE ISLAND-BAY CAMPUS, NOAA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203060</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105708</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/harmful-algae-digital-library</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
