<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106306</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106306</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086059</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">David Johnson Recalls the Shoemakers' Shops of Lynn, Massachusetts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">David Johnson Rückrufe die Systeme der Schuster 
von Lynn, Massachusetts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rappels de David Johnson les systèmes des 
cordonniers de Lynn, le Massachusetts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recordações de David Johnson as lojas de Lynn, 
Massachusetts dos shoemakers'</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Richiami di David Johnson i negozi di Lynn, 
Massachusetts dei calzolai</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δαβίδ Johnson Recalls τα καταστήματα των 
υποδηματοποιών Lynn, Μασαχουσέτη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Memorias de David Johnson los departamentos de 
Lynn, Massachusetts de los zapateros</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Traditional craft production centered around an independent master artisan, his journeymen, and the apprentice helpers who worked together in small shops. Apprentices worked alongside masters and received training in the "mysteries of the craft" in exchange for their labor. Journeymen looked forward to becoming proprietors when they accumulated sufficient capital and skill. In his  Sketches of Lynn  (1880), David Johnson recalled the masculine work culture and small-scale setting of the shoe industry in early-19th century Lynn, Massachusetts. With transportation improvements and growing commercial activity, manufacturing moved from small shops engaged in custom work to larger-scale production of ready-made goods. No area experienced greater dislocation than Lynn, where shops multiplied, the division of labor increased, and some masters opened larger central shops. Less skilled workers, including women and children, replaced journeymen, apprenticeship declined, and the world that Johnson described faded.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Traditionelle Fertigkeitproduktion zentrierte um 
einen unabhängigen Vorlagenhandwerker, seine Facharbeiter und die 
Lehrling Helfer, die zusammen in den kleinen Systemen arbeiteten. 
Lehrlinge arbeiteten neben Meistern und empfingen Training in 
den "Geheimnissen der Fertigkeit" gegen ihre Arbeit. 
Facharbeiter freuten zu werden Eigentümer, als sie genügendes 
Kapital und Fähigkeit akkumulierten. In seinen Skizzen von Lynn
(1880), erinnerte an David Johnson die männliche Arbeit Kultur und 
die kleinräumige Einstellung der Schuhindustrie im early-19th 
Jahrhundert Lynn, Massachusetts. Mit Transportverbesserungen und
-wachsens kommerzieller Aktivität bewog die Produktion von den 
kleinen Systemen, die an kundenspezifischer Arbeit teilnahmen, 
groß-einstufen Produktion der gebrauchsfertigen Waren. Kein 
Bereich erfuhr grössere Versetzung als Lynn, in dem Systeme 
multiplizierten, die Arbeitsteilung erhöht, und einige Meister 
öffneten größere zentrale Systeme. Weniger erfahrene 
Arbeiter, einschließlich Frauen und Kinder, ersetzten Facharbeiter, 
die gesunkene Lehre und die Welt, die Johnson verblassen beschrieb.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La production traditionnelle de métier s'est 
concentrée sur un artisan principal indépendant, ses compagnons, et 
les aides d'apprenti qui ont travaillé ensemble dans de petits 
systèmes. Les apprentis ont travaillé à côté des maîtres 
et ont reçu la formation dans les "mystères du métier" en échange 
de leur travail. Les compagnons ont attendu avec intérêt  des 
propriétaires devenir quand ils ont accumulé le capital et la 
compétence suffisants. Dans ses croquis de Lynn (1880), David 
Johnson a rappelé la culture masculine de travail et la 
configuration de petite taille de l'industrie de chaussure en siècle 
Lynn, le Massachusetts d'early-19th. Avec l'activité 
commerciale d'améliorations et de croissance de transport, la 
fabrication s'est déplacée de petits systèmes occupés dans le 
travail fait sur commande grand-mesurent la production des 
marchandises prêtes à l'emploi. Aucune zone n'a éprouvé une 
plus grande dislocation que Lynn, où les systèmes se sont 
multipliés, la division du travail accrue, et quelques maîtres ont 
ouvert de plus grandes boutiques centrales. Les ouvriers moins 
habiles, y compris les femmes et les enfants, ont substitué des 
compagnons, l'apprentissage diminué, et le monde que Johnson a 
décrit fané.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A produção tradicional do ofício centrou-se em 
torno de um artisan mestre independente, de seus journeymen, e dos 
ajudantes do aprendiz que trabalharam junto em lojas pequenas. 
Os aprendizes trabalharam ao lado dos mestres e receberam o 
treinamento nos "mistérios do ofício" na troca para seu trabalho. 
Os journeymen olharam para a frente aos proprietors tornar-se 
quando acumularam o capital e a habilidade suficientes. Em seus 
esboços de Lynn (1880), David Johnson recordou a cultura masculine do
trabalho e o ajuste small-scale da indústria da sapata no século 
Lynn de early-19th, Massachusetts. Com atividade comercial das 
melhorias e do crescimento do transporte, manufaturar moveu-se das 
lojas pequenas acopladas no trabalho feito sob encomenda grande-escala
a produção de bens ready-made. Nenhuma área experimentou um 
dislocation mais grande do que Lynn, onde as lojas multiplicaram, a 
divisão de trabalho aumentada, e alguns mestres abriram lojas 
centrais maiores. Os trabalhadores mais menos hábeis, including
mulheres e crianças, substituíram journeymen, apprenticeship 
declinado, e o mundo que Johnson descreveu desvanecido.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La produzione tradizionale del mestiere ha vertuto
su un artigianale matrice indipendente, sui suoi operai qualificati e 
sugli assistenti dell'apprendista che hanno lavorato insieme in 
piccoli negozi. Gli apprendisti hanno lavorato accanto ai 
supervisori ed hanno ricevuto l'addestramento "nei misteri del 
mestiere" in cambio del loro lavoro. Gli operai qualificati
hanno aspettato con impazienza di i proprietari diventare quando hanno
accumulato il capitale e l'abilità sufficienti. Nei suoi 
abbozzi di Lynn (1880), David Johnson ha ricordato la coltura maschile
del lavoro e la regolazione su scala ridotta dell'industria del 
pattino nel secolo Lynn, Massachusetts di early-19th. Con 
attività commerciale di miglioramenti e crescere del trasporto, 
produrre si è mossa dai piccoli negozi agganciati nel lavoro su 
ordinazione gran-regola la produzione delle merci di aspettare-made. 
Nessuna zona ha avvertito la dislocazione più grande che Lynn, 
dove i negozi si sono moltiplicati, la divisione del lavoro 
aumentata ed alcuni supervisori hanno aperto i più grandi negozi 
centrali. In operai meno esperti, compreso le donne ed i 
bambini, hanno sostituito gli operai qualificati, l'apprendistato 
ribassante ed il mondo che Johnson ha descritto sbiadito.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η παραδοσιακή παραγωγή τεχνών στράφηκε γύρω από 
ανεξάρτητο κύριο έναν χειροτεχνικό, τους τεχνίτες του, και τους 
αρωγούς μαθητευόμενων που ελειτούργησαν μαζί στα μικρά 
καταστήματα. Οι μαθητευόμενοι εργάστηκαν παράλληλα με τους 
κυρίους και έλαβαν την κατάρτιση στα "μυστήρια της τέχνησ" σε 
αντάλλαγμα της εργασίας τους. Οι τεχνίτες ανυπομόνησαν να 
γίνουν ιδιοκτήτες όταν συσσώρευσαν το ικανοποιητικό κεφάλαιο και
την ικανότητα. Στα σκίτσα Lynn του (1880), ο Δαβίδ 
Johnson υπενθύμισε τον αρσενικό πολιτισμό εργασίας και το 
μικρής κλίμακας καθορισμό της βιομηχανίας παπουτσιών στον 
πρόωρος-19$ο αιώνα Lynn, Μασαχουσέτη. Με τις βελτιώσεις 
μεταφορών και την αυξανόμενη εμπορική δραστηριότητα, η κατασκευή 
που κινείται από τα μικρά καταστήματα που συμμετέχονται στην 
εργασία συνήθειας στη μεγαλύτερης κλίμακας παραγωγή 
αναμένει τα αγαθά. Καμία περιοχή δεν δοκίμασε τη 
μεγαλύτερη εξάρθρωση από Lynn, όπου τα καταστήματα που 
πολλαπλασιάστηκαν, το τμήμα της εργασίας αυξήθηκαν, και μερικοί 
κύριοι άνοιξαν τα μεγαλύτερα κεντρικά καταστήματα. Οι 
λιγότερο ειδικευμένοι εργαζόμενοι, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
γυναικών και των παιδιών, αντικατέστησαν τους τεχνίτες, η 
μαθητεία μειώθηκε, και ο κόσμος που Johnson που περιγράφηκε 
εξασθένισε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La producción tradicional del arte se centró 
alrededor de un artesano principal independiente, de sus oficiales, y de 
los ayudantes del aprendiz que trabajaron juntos en departamentos 
pequeños. Los aprendices trabajaron junto a amos y recibieron 
el entrenamiento en los "misterios del arte" en el intercambio para su
trabajo. Los oficiales miraban adelante a los propietarios 
convertirse cuando acumularon el suficientes capital y habilidad. 
En sus bosquejos de Lynn (1880), David Johnson recordó la 
cultura masculina del trabajo y la configuración en reducida escala 
de la industria del zapato en el siglo Lynn, Massachusetts de 
early-19th. Con actividad comercial de las mejoras y del 
crecimiento del transporte, la fabricación se movió desde los 
departamentos pequeños contratados a trabajo de encargo grande-escala
la producción de mercancías confeccionadas. Ninguna área 
experimentó la mayor dislocación que Lynn, donde los departamentos 
se multiplicaron, la división del trabajo creciente, y algunos amos 
abrieron departamentos centrales más grandes. Los trabajadores 
menos expertos, incluyendo mujeres y niños, substituyeron oficiales, 
el aprendizaje declinado, y el mundo que Johnson describió 
descolorado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086059</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106306</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/david-johnson-recalls-the-shoemakers-shops-of-lynn-massachusetts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
