<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086077</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Diplomacy.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diplomatie.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Diplomatie.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Diplomacy.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Diplomazia.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διπλωματία.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diplomacia.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From its inception, the Confederacy sought international recognition from European nations. Support from Europe would help persuade the North to accept Southern independence, and, more immediately, secure a source of manufactured goods needed for the war effort. Southern efforts to gain recognition focused on England, the largest purchaser of southern cotton. This 1862 cartoon from the northern satirical weekly,  Vanity Fair , presented the Confederacy's president trying to gain diplomatic recognition from a skeptical Great Britain. I hardly think it will wash</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von seiner Gründung suchte die Konföderation 
internationale Anerkennung von den europäischen Nationen. 
Support von Europa würde helfen, den Norden zu überzeugen, um 
südliche Unabhängigkeit anzunehmen, und, sofort, eine Quelle der 
hergestellten Waren benötigte zu sichern für die Kriegbemühung. 
Südliche Bemühungen, Anerkennung zu gewinnen konzentrierten 
auf England, der größte Käufer der südlichen Baumwolle. 
Diese 1862 Karikatur von der satirical Nordwochenzeitung, die 
Eitelkeit, die angemessen ist, stellte den Präsidenten der 
Konföderation dar, der versucht, diplomatische Anerkennung von 
skeptischem Großbritannien zu gewinnen. Ich denke kaum, daß 
sie wäscht</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">De son commencement, la confédération a recherché 
l'identification internationale des nations européennes. Le 
support de l'Europe aiderait à persuader le nord pour recevoir
l'indépendance méridionale, et, plus immédiatement, fixer une 
source des produits manufacturés a eu besoin pour l'effort de guerre.
Les efforts méridionaux de gagner l'identification se sont 
concentrés sur l'Angleterre, le plus grand acheteur du coton 
méridional. Ce 1862 dessin animé de l'hebdomadaire satirique 
nordique, vanité juste, a présenté le président de la 
confédération essayant de gagner l'identification diplomatique de 
Grande-Bretagne sceptique. Je pense à peine qu'il lavera</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">De seu inception, o confederacy procurou o recognition 
internacional das nações européias. A sustentação de Europa
ajudaria persuadir o norte para aceitar a independência do sul, e, 
mais imediatamente, fixar uma fonte de bens manufactured necessitou 
para o esforço da guerra. Os esforços do sul ganhar o 
recognition focalizaram em Inglaterra, purchaser o maior do algodão 
do sul. Este 1862 cartoon do semanário satirical do norte, 
vanity justo, apresentou o presidente do confederacy que tenta ganhar 
o recognition diplomatic de uma Grâ Bretanha skeptical. Eu 
penso mal que se lavará</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dal relativo inizio, il confederacy ha cercato il 
riconoscimento internazionale dalle nazioni europee. Il supporto
da Europa contribuirebbe a persaudere il nord per accettare 
l'indipendenza del sud e, più immediatamente, assicurare una sorgente
delle merci manufactured ha avuto bisogno di per lo sforzo di guerra. 
Gli sforzi del sud guadagnare il riconoscimento hanno messo a 
fuoco sull'Inghilterra, il più grande acquirente di cotone del sud. 
Questo 1862 fumetto dal settimanale satirical nordico, vanità 
giusta, ha presentato il presidente del confederacy che prova a 
guadagnare il riconoscimento diplomatico dalla Gran Bretagna scettica.
Appena penso che si lavi</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από την έναρξή του, η επιδιωκόμενη συνομοσπονδία 
διεθνής αναγνώριση από τα ευρωπαϊκά έθνη. Η υποστήριξη 
από την Ευρώπη θα βοηθούσε να πείσει το Βορρά για να αποδεχθεί 
τη νότια ανεξαρτησία, και, πιό αμέσως, να εξασφαλίσει μια πηγή 
κατασκευασμένων αγαθών που απαιτούνται για την πολεμική 
προσπάθεια. Οι νότιες προσπάθειες να κερδηθεί η αναγνώριση 
εστίασαν στην Αγγλία, ο μεγαλύτερος αγοραστής του νότιου 
βαμβακιού. Αυτά τα κινούμενα σχέδια 1862 από τη βόρεια 
σατυρική εβδομαδιαία έκδοση, έκθεση ματαιοδοξίας, παρουσίασαν 
τον Πρόεδρο της συνομοσπονδίας που προσπαθεί να κερδίσουν τη 
διπλωματική αναγνώριση από μια δύσπιστη Μεγάλη Βρετανία. 
Σκέφτομαι μετά βίας ότι θα πλύνει</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De su inicio, el confederacy buscó el reconocimiento 
internacional de naciones europeas. La ayuda de Europa ayudaría
a persuadir el norte para validar independencia meridional, y, más 
inmediatamente, asegurar una fuente de productos manufacturados 
necesitó para el esfuerzo de la guerra. Los esfuerzos 
meridionales de ganar el reconocimiento se centraron en Inglaterra, el
comprador más grande del algodón meridional. Esta 1862 
historieta del semanario satírico norteño, vanidad justa, presentó 
a presidente del confederacy que intentaba ganar el reconocimiento 
diplomático de una Gran Bretaña escéptica. Pienso apenas que 
se lavará</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086077</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106335</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/diplomacy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
