<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107944</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107944</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086752</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Police conveying Sims to the vessel."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Polizei, die übermittelt Sims zum Behälter."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"police transportant Sims au navire."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"polícias que fazem saber a Sims à 
embarcação."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"polizia che trasporta Sims al vaso."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αστυνομία που μεταβιβάζει Sims στο σκάφος."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"policía que transporta Sims al recipiente."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Fugitive Slave Law of 1850 placed the full weight of the federal government behind the apprehension of runaway slaves. This fact was best illustrated by the arrest of Thomas Sims, who escaped slavery in Georgia. Sims was arrested in Boston in April 1851 and, under the Fugitive Slave Law, returned to his owner. The city's abolitionist movement agitated for his release and large crowds surrounded the courthouse in which Sims was incarcerated. But these efforts, which included plans to forcibly free the prisoner, did not succeed. This picture from a Boston illustrated weekly shows how Sims was conducted by three hundred armed police and marshals to a navy ship that carried him back to slavery. Upon his return south, Sims was sold to a new master in Mississippi. He escaped in 1863.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Flüchtling-Sklave Gesetz von 1850 plazierte das volle
Gewicht der Bundesregierung hinter die Befürchtung der 
Durchgehensklaven. Diese Tatsache wurde gut durch das Anhalten 
von Thomas Sims veranschaulicht, das Sklaverei in Georgia entging. 
Sims wurde in Boston im April 1851 und, unter dem 
Flüchtling-Sklave Gesetz festgehalten, zurückging zu seinem Inhaber.
Die Bewegung abolitionist der Stadt, die für seine Freigabe 
aufgeregt wurden und die großen Massen umgaben das Gericht, in dem 
Sims eingesperrt wurde. Aber diese Bemühungen, denen enthaltene
Pläne gewaltsam den Gefangenen freigeben, folgten nicht. Diese 
Abbildung von einem Boston veranschaulichte Wochenzeitungerscheinen, 
wie Sims von drei hundert bewaffneter Polizei geleitet wurde und 
Marschälle zu einer Marine versenden, daß getragen ihm zurück zu 
Sklaverei. Nach seinem Rückholsüden wurde Sims an einen neuen 
Meister in Mississippi verkauft. Er entging 1863.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La loi Slave de fugitif de 1850 a placé le plein 
poids du gouvernement fédéral derrière l'appréhension des esclaves
d'emballement. Ce fait mieux a été illustré par l'arrestation
de Thomas Sims, qui a échappé à l'esclavage en Géorgie. Sims
a été arrêté à Boston en avril 1851 et, en vertu de la loi 
Slave de fugitif, est revenu à son propriétaire. Le 
mouvement de l'abolitionniste de la ville agité pour sa version et les 
grandes foules ont entouré le tribunal dans lequel Sims a été 
incarcéré. Mais ces efforts, que les plans inclus libèrent de
force le prisonnier, n'ont pas réussi. Cette image de Boston a 
illustré des expositions d'hebdomadaire comment Sims a été conduit 
par trois cents polices armées et les maréchaux à une marine se 
transportent que porté lui de nouveau à l'esclavage. Sur ses 
sud de retour, Sims a été vendu à un nouveau maître au 
Mississippi. Il s'est échappé en 1863.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A lei do escravo do fugitive de 1850 colocou o peso cheio 
do governo federal atrás do apprehension de escravos do runaway. 
Este fato foi ilustrado melhor pela apreensão de Thomas Sims, 
que escapou do slavery em Geórgia. Sims foi prendido em Boston 
em abril 1851 e, sob a lei do escravo do fugitive, retornou a seu 
proprietário. O movimento do abolitionist da cidade agitado 
para sua liberação e as multidões grandes cercaram o tribunal em 
que Sims incarcerated. Mas estes esforços, que as plantas 
incluídas livram forçosamente o prisioneiro, não sucederam. 
Este retrato de uma Boston ilustrou mostras do semanário como 
Sims foi conduzido por três cem polícias armadas e os marshals a uma
marinha envíam que carregado lhe para trás ao slavery. Em cima
de seu sul do retorno, Sims foi vendido a um mestre novo em 
Mississippi. Escapou-se em 1863.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La legge dello schiavo del fuggitivo di 1850 ha disposto 
il peso completo del governo federale dietro l'apprensione degli 
schiavi di instabilità. Questo fatto è stato illustrato il 
più bene tramite l'arresto di Thomas Sims, che ha fuoriuscito lo 
slavery nella Georgia. Sims è stato arrestato a Boston nel mese
di aprile del 1851 e, secondo la legge dello schiavo del fuggitivo, ha
ritornato al suo proprietario. Il movimento di abolitionist 
della città agitato per la sua versione e le grandi folle hanno 
circondato il courthouse in cui Sims incarcerated. Ma questi 
sforzi, che i programmi inclusi con forza liberano il prigioniero, non
sono riuscito. Questa immagine da Boston ha illustrato le 
esposizioni del settimanale come Sims è stato condotto da trecento 
polizie munite ed i marshals ad un blu marino spediscono che 
trasportato lui di nuovo a slavery. Sul suo sud di ritorno, Sims
è stato venduto ad un nuovo supervisore nel Mississippi. Ha 
fuoriuscito in 1863.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο νόμος σκλάβων προσφύγων 1850 τοποθέτησε το 
πλήρες βάρος της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης πίσω από την ανησυχία
των σκλάβων δραπέτη. Αυτό το γεγονός εμφανίστηκε καλύτερα 
στη σύλληψη του Thomas Sims, ο οποίος δραπέτευσε τη σκλαβιά 
στη Γεωργία. Το Sims συλλήφθηκε στη Βοστώνη τον Απρίλιο 
του 1851 και, βάσει του νόμου σκλάβων προσφύγων, επέστρεψε 
στον ιδιοκτήτη του. Η μετακίνηση ρεφορμιστών της πόλης που 
ταράχτηκαν για την έκδοσή του και τα μεγάλα πλήθη περιέβαλαν το 
δικαστήριο στο οποίο Sims ήταν έγκλειστο. Αλλά αυτές οι
προσπάθειες, που περιέλαβαν τα σχέδια βίαια ελεύθερα ο 
φυλακισμένος, δεν πέτυχαν. Αυτή η εικόνα από μια Βοστώνη 
επεξήγησε ότι η εβδομαδιαία έκδοση επιδεικνύει πώς Sims 
διευθύνθηκε από την τριακόσια οπλισμένα αστυνομία και τα 
marshals σε ένα σκάφος ναυτικών που τον έφερε πίσω στη 
σκλαβιά. Επάνω στον επιστροφής νότο του, Sims πωλήθηκε 
σε έναν νέο κύριο στο Μισισιπή. Δραπέτευσε το 1863.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La ley del esclavo del fugitivo de 1850 puso el peso 
completo del gobierno federal detrás de la aprehensión de los 
esclavos del fugitivo. Este hecho fue ilustrado lo más mejor 
posible por la detención de Thomas Sims, que escapó esclavitud en 
Georgia. Sims fue arrestado en Boston en abril de 1851 y, bajo 
ley del esclavo del fugitivo, volvió a su propietario. El 
movimiento del abolitionist de la ciudad agitado para su desbloquear y
las muchedumbres grandes rodearon el palacio de justicia en el cual 
Sims incarcerated. Pero estos esfuerzos, que los planes 
incluidos fuertemente liberan a preso, no tuvieron éxito. Este 
cuadro de una Boston ilustró demostraciones del semanario cómo Sims 
fue conducido por tresciento policía armado y los mariscales a una 
marina de guerra envían que llevado le de nuevo a esclavitud. Sobre 
su sur de vuelta, Sims fue vendido a un amo nuevo en Mississippi. 
Él se escapó en 1863.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086752</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107944</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/police-conveying-sims-to-the-vessel</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
