<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108311</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108311</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087081</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The workingman between two fires."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Workingman zwischen zwei Feuern."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'ouvrier entre les deux feux."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o workingman entre dois fogos."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il workingman fra due fuochi."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο workingman μεταξύ δύο πυρκαγιών."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el workingman entre dos fuegos."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many nineteenth-century labor reformers rejected corrupt political machines like New York City's Tammany Hall, despite the tangible benefits they often presented to working-class citizens in the way of jobs and social services. To protest party machines, New York's Central Labor Union launched an independent labor party in 1886, choosing reformer and author Henry George as their candidate for mayor. During the campaign, many workingmen faced a dilemma when the Catholic Church hierarchy attacked George. As this cartoon from the humor weekly Judge indicates, although the ULP lost the election, the sizeable turnout for George (the figure on the left) showed that many Catholic voters had ignored the denunciations of Archbishop Michael A. Corrigan (the figure on the right).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele 19.-Jahrhundert Arbeit Reformer wiesen 
verdorbene politische Maschinen wie Tammany Hall der New York Stadt 
zurück, trotz der materiellen Leistungen stellten sich sie häufig 
Arbeiterklassebürgern in der Methode von Jobs und von 
Sozialeinrichtungen dar. Um Parteimaschinen zu protestieren,
New York stieß zentraler Arbeiterverband eine unabhängige 
ArbeitsPartei 1886, wählenden Reformer und Autor Henry 
George als ihr Anwärter für Bürgermeister aus. Während der 
Kampagne stellten viele Workingmen ein Dilemma gegenüber, als die 
Hierarchie der katholischen Kirche George in Angriff nahm. Da 
diese Karikatur vom Stimmung wöchentlichen Richter anzeigt, obgleich 
das ULP die Wahl verlor, zeigte die beträchtliche Beteiligung für 
George (die Abbildung auf dem links), daß viele katholische Wähler 
die Kündigungen des Erzbischofs Michael A. Corrigan ignoriert hatten 
(die Abbildung auf dem Recht).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup de réformateurs de travail de 
dix-neuvième-siècle ont rejeté les machines politiques altérées 
comme Tammany hall de la ville de New York, en dépit des avantages 
réels ils se sont souvent présentés aux citoyens de classe ouvrier 
de la voie des travaux et des services sociaux. Pour protester 
des machines de partie, le syndicat central de New York a lancé un 
parti travailliste indépendant en 1886, le réformateur de choix et 
l'Henry George d'auteur en tant que leur candidat pour le maire. 
Pendant la campagne, beaucoup d'ouvriers ont fait face à un 
dilemme quand la hiérarchie d'église catholique a attaqué 
George. Car ce dessin animé du juge hebdomadaire d'humeur 
indique, bien que l'ULP ait détruit l'élection, la importante 
assemblée pour George (la figure du côté gauche) a prouvé que
beaucoup d'électeurs catholiques avaient ignoré les dénonciations 
de l'archevêque Michael A. Corrigan (la figure du côté droit).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos reformers do trabalho de décimo-século rejeitaram
máquinas políticas corrupt como Tammany salão da cidade de New 
York, apesar dos benefícios tangible apresentaram-se frequentemente 
aos cidadãos do working-class na maneira dos trabalhos e de serviços
sociais. Para protestar máquinas do partido, a união labor 
central de New York lançou um partido labor independente em 1886, o 
reformer escolhendo e o Henry George do autor como seu candidato para 
o mayor. Durante a campanha, muitos workingmen enfrentaram um 
dilemma quando a hierarquia da igreja catholic atacou George. 
Porque este cartoon do juiz semanal do humor indica, embora o 
ULP perdesse a eleição, o turnout sizeable para George (a figura na 
esquerda) mostrou que muitos eleitores catholic tinham ignorado os 
denunciations do archbishop Michael A. Corrigan (a figura na direita).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti reformers di lavoro di diciannovesimo-secolo hanno
rifiutato le macchine politiche corrotte come Tammany corridoio della 
città de New York, malgrado i benefici definiti si sono presentati 
spesso ai cittadini della classe operaia nel modo dei lavori e dei 
servizi sociali. Per protestare le macchine del partito, 
l'unione Di lavoro centrale de New York ha lanciato un partito 
di lavoro indipendente in 1886, il reformer di scelta ed il henry 
George dell'autore come loro candidato per il sindaco. Durante 
la campagna, molti workingmen hanno affrontato un dilemma quando la 
gerarchia della chiesa cattolica ha attacato George. Poichè 
questo fumetto dal giudice settimanale di umore indica, anche se il 
ULP ha perso l'elezione, l'affluenza importante per George (la figura 
a sinistra) ha indicato che molti elettori cattolici avevano ignorato 
i denunciations dell'Arcivescovo Michael A. Corrigan (la figura a 
destra).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί μεταρρυθμιστές εργασίας δέκατος-αιώνα 
απορριφθέντες αλλοιώνουν τις πολιτικές μηχανές όπως την αίθουσα 
Tammany της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης, παρά τα απτά οφέλη 
παρουσίασαν συχνά στην εργατική τάξη τους πολίτες με τον τρόπο 
των εργασιών και των κοινωνικών υπηρεσιών. Για να 
διαμαρτυρηθεί τις μηχανές συμβαλλόμενων μερών, το κεντρικό 
εργατικό συνδικάτο της Νέας Υόρκης προώθησε ένα ανεξάρτητο 
εργατικό κόμμα το 1886, που επιλέγει το μεταρρυθμιστή και το 
συντάκτη Henry George ως υποψήφιό τους για το δήμαρχο. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια της εκστρατείας, πολλοί αντιμέτωπος ένα 
δίλημμα όταν επιτέθηκε η καθολική ιεραρχία εκκλησιών σε 
George. Όπως αυτά τα κινούμενα σχέδια από τον 
εβδομαδιαίο δικαστή χιούμορ δείχνουν, αν και το ULP έχασε την 
εκλογή, η αρκετά μεγάλη συγκέντρωση για George (ο αριθμός για 
το αριστερό) έδειξε ότι πολλοί καθολικοί ψηφοφόροι είχαν 
αγνοήσει τις καταγγελίες του Αρχιεπισκόπου michael A. 
Corrigan (ο αριθμός για το δικαίωμα).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos reformadores del trabajo del diecinueveavo-siglo 
rechazaron las máquinas políticas corruptas como Tammany pasillo de 
la ciudad de Nueva York, a pesar de los beneficios materiales 
presentaron a menudo a los ciudadanos de la clase obrera de la manera 
de trabajos y de servicios sociales. Para protestar las 
máquinas del partido, el sindicato central de Nueva York lanzó un 
partido laborista independiente en 1886, el reformador que elegía y el 
Henrio George del autor como su candidato a alcalde. Durante la 
campaña, muchos workingmen hicieron frente a un dilema cuando la 
jerarquía de la iglesia católica atacó George. Pues esta 
historieta del juez semanal del humor indica, aunque el ULP perdió la
elección, el séquito importante para George (la figura a la 
izquierda) mostró que muchos votantes católicos habían no hecho 
caso de las denuncias del Arzobispo Michael A. Corrigan (la figura a 
la derecha).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087081</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108311</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-workingman-between-two-fires</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
