<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106871</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106871</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086985</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The March of the Psychos": Measuring Intelligence in the Army</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der März des Psychos": Messende 
Intelligenz in der Armee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"mars du Psychos" : Intelligence de mesure 
dans l'armée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o março do Psychos": Inteligência de 
medição no exército</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"marzo dello Psychos": Intelligenza di 
misurazione nell'esercito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο Μάρτιος του Psychos": Μέτρηση της 
νοημοσύνης στο στρατό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la marcha del Psychos": Inteligencia que 
mide en el ejército</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"There is nothing about an individual as important as his IQ," declared psychologist Lewis M. Terman in 1922. To the extent that this is true, it is in large measure because of Terman himself and the opportunity that World War I afforded for the first widespread use of intelligence testing. The army's use of intelligence tests lent new credibility to the emerging profession of psychology, even as it sparked public debate about the validity of the tests and their implications for American democracy. Some contemporaries expressed skepticism about the broad claims of army intelligence testing. In this lighthearted, anonymous commentary, from the April 1918 issue of the army post newspaper  Camplife Chickamauga , a would-be poet mocked psychologists with gentle humor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es gibt nichts über eine Einzelperson, die," 
erklärter Psychologe Lewis M. Terman 1922 so wichtig ist wie sein IQ.
Soweit daß dieses zutreffend ist, ist es in großem Umfang 
wegen Terman selbst und der Gelegenheit, die der Erste Weltkrieg für 
den ersten weitverbreiteten Gebrauch von Intelligenzprüfung sich 
leistete. Der Gebrauch der Armee von Intelligenz prüft 
verliehene neue Glaubwürdigkeit zum auftauchenden Beruf von 
Psychologie, selbst als er allgemeine Debatte über die Gültigkeit 
der Tests und ihrer Implikationen für amerikanische Demokratie 
funkte. Einige Zeitgenossen drückten Skepsis über die 
ausgedehnten Ansprüche der Armeeintelligenzprüfung aus. In 
diesem lighthearted, anonymen Kommentar von der April 1918 Ausgabe der
Armeepfostenzeitung Camplife Chickamauga, verspottete ein angeblicher 
Dichter Psychologen mit leichter Stimmung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il n'y a rien au sujet d'un individu aussi 
important que son Q.I.," psychologue avoué Lewis M. Terman en 1922. 
Dans la mesure où c'est vrai, il est dans une large mesure en 
raison de Terman lui-même et de l'occasion que la Première Guerre 
Mondiale a eus les moyens pour le premier usage répandu du test 
d'intelligence. L'utilisation de l'armée de l'intelligence 
teste la nouvelle crédibilité prêtée à la profession naissante de
la psychologie, même pendant qu'elle étincelait discussion publique 
au sujet de la validité des essais et de leurs implications pour la 
démocratie américaine. Quelques contemporains ont exprimé le 
scepticisme au sujet des larges réclamations du test d'intelligence 
d'armée. Dans ce commentaire gai et anonyme, de l'issue d'avril
1918 du journal Camplife Chickamauga de poteau d'armée, un poèt 
potentiel a raillé des psychologues avec l'humeur douce.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não há nada sobre um indivíduo tão importante
quanto seu IQ," psicólogo declarado Lewis M. Terman em 1922. 
Até ao ponto em que isto é verdadeiro, está na medida grande 
por causa de Terman ele mesmo e na oportunidade que o world.war.i teve
recursos para para o primeiro uso difundido de testar da 
inteligência. O uso do exército da inteligência testa o 
credibility novo emprestado à profissão emergente do psychology, 
mesmo como ele acendeu debate público sobre a validez dos testes e de
suas implicações para a democracia americana. Alguns 
comtemporâneos expressaram o skepticism sobre as reivindicações 
largas de testar da inteligência do exército. Neste commentary
lighthearted, anonymous, da introdução de abril 1918 do jornal 
Camplife Chickamauga do borne do exército, um poeta would-be mocked 
psicólogos com humor delicado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ci è niente circa un individuo importante quanto
il suo quoziente d'intelligenza," psicologo dichiarato Lewis M. Terman
in 1922. Anche se questo è allineare, è in una larga misura a 
causa di Terman egli stesso e dell'occasione che il world.war.i si è 
permesso per il primo uso molto diffuso di prova di intelligenza. 
L'uso dell'esercito di intelligenza verifica la nuova 
credibilità prestata alla professione d'emersione della psicologia, 
proprio mentre ha scintillato dibattito pubblico circa la validità 
delle prove e delle loro implicazioni per la democrazia americana. 
Alcuni contemporanei hanno espresso lo scetticismo circa i vasti
reclami di prova di intelligenza dell'esercito. In questo 
commento lighthearted e anonimo, dall'emissione di aprile 1918 del 
giornale Camplife Chickamauga dell'alberino dell'esercito, un poet 
potenziale ha deriso gli psicologi con umore delicato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν υπάρχει τίποτα για ένα άτομο τόσο σημαντικό 
όπως ο ΔΕΙΚΤΗΣ ΝΟΗΜΟΣΎΝΗΣ του," δηλωμένος ψυχολόγος Lewis Μ. 
Terman σε 1922, μέχρι το σημείο που αυτό ισχύει, αυτό 
είναι σε μεγάλο βαθμό λόγω Terman ο ίδιος και της ευκαιρίας 
που ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος εγώ παρείχε για την πρώτη διαδεδομένη 
χρήση της δοκιμής νοημοσύνης. Η χρήση του στρατού των 
δοκιμών νοημοσύνης δάνεισε τη νέα αξιοπιστία στο αναδυόμενο 
επάγγελμα της ψυχολογίας, ακόμη και δεδομένου ότι προκάλεσε τη 
δημόσια συζήτηση για την ισχύ των δοκιμών και των επιπτώσεών 
τους στην αμερικανική δημοκρατία. Μερικοί σύγχρονοι 
εξέφρασαν το σκεπτικισμό για τις ευρείες αξιώσεις της δοκιμής 
νοημοσύνης στρατού. Σε αυτά τα ξέγνοιαστα, ανώνυμα σχόλια,
από το ζήτημα Απριλίου 1918 της μετα εφημερίδας Camplife 
Chickamauga στρατού, ένας δυνάμει ποιητής χλεύασε τους 
ψυχολόγους με το ευγενές χιούμορ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no hay nada sobre un individuo tan importante 
como su índice de inteligencia," psicólogo declarado Lewis M. Terman
en 1922. Hasta el punto de esto sea verdad, está en la medida 
grande debido a Terman misma y la oportunidad que la Primera Guerra 
Mundial produjo para el primer uso extenso de la prueba de la 
inteligencia. El uso del ejército de la inteligencia prueba 
nueva credibilidad prestada a la profesión que emerge de la 
psicología, incluso como él chispeó discusión público sobre la 
validez de las pruebas y de sus implicaciones para la democracia 
americana. Algunos contemporáneos expresaron escepticismo sobre
las amplias demandas de la prueba de la inteligencia del ejército. 
En este comentario alegre, anónimo, de la aplicación de abril 
1918 el periódico Camplife Chickamauga del poste del ejército, un 
poeta supuesto de imitación a psicólogos con humor apacible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086985</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106871</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-march-of-the-psychos-measuring-intelligence-in-the-army</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
