<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107023</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107023</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086128</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Evacuation Was a Mistake": Anger at Being Interned</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Evakuierung war ein Fehler": Zorn an 
interniert werden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'"évacuation était une erreur" : Colère 
à être interné</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">a "evacuação era um erro": Raiva em ser 
internado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'evacuamento era un errore": Rabbia 
all'internamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η εκκένωση ήταν ένα λάθοσ": Θυμός στη θέση 
υπό περιορισμό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "evacuación era un error": Cólera en 
ser internado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">America fought World War II to preserve freedom and democracy, yet that same war featured the greatest suppression of civil liberties in the nation's history. In an atmosphere of hysteria, President Roosevelt, encouraged by officials at all levels of the federal government, authorized the internment of tens of thousands of American citizens of Japanese ancestry and resident aliens from Japan. The federal government tried to monitor conditions inside the relocation camps and keep tabs on the feelings and attitudes of the internees. An interview conducted in the Manzanar, California, camp in July 1943 by a U.S. government employee with a man identified only as "an Older Nisei" (an American-born person whose parents were born in Japan) revealed the anger many internees felt toward the United States. Asserting his loyalty and his early willingness to support the war effort, the Older Nisei condemned the evacuation of Japanese Americans from the West Coast. He questioned why the government did not act similarly against citizens of German and Italian descent.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerika kennzeichnete der gekämpfte Zweite 
Weltkrieg, zum von von Freiheit und von von Demokratie zu 
konservieren, dennoch das der gleiche Krieg den größten Ausgleich 
von Zivilfreiheiten in der Geschichte der Nation. In einer 
Atmosphäre der Hysterie, autorisierte Präsident Roosevelt, 
angeregt von den Beamten auf allen Stufen der Bundesregierung, die 
Internierung von 10 Tausenden der amerikanischen Bürger japanischen 
Geschlechtes und der Residentausländer von Japan. Die 
Bundesregierung versucht, um Bedingungen innerhalb der Verschiebung 
Lager zu überwachen und Tabulatoren auf den Gefühlen und der Haltung
der Internees zu halten. Ein Interview, das in das Manzanar, 
Kalifornien, Lager im Juli 1943 durch einen VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Beschäftigten im öffentlichen Dienst mit einem Mann gekennzeichnet 
wurde nur als "älteres Nisei" geleitet wurde (eine 
Amerikanisch-getragene Person deren Eltern in Japan geboren waren), 
deckte den Zorn auf, den viele Internees in Richtung zu den 
Vereinigten Staaten fühlten. Seine Loyalität und seine frühe 
Bereitwilligkeit erklärend, die Kriegbemühung zu unterstützen, 
verurteilte das ältere Nisei die Evakuierung der japanischen 
Amerikaner von der Westküste. Er fragte, warum die Regierung 
ähnlich nicht gegen Bürger des deutschen und italienischen Abfalls 
fungierte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">ParAmérique la deuxième guerre mondiale 
combattue celle pour préserver la liberté et la démocratie, 
pourtant la même guerre a comporté la plus grande suppression des 
libertés civiles dans l'histoire de la nation. Dans une 
atmosphère d'hystérie, le Président Roosevelt, encouragé par des 
fonctionnaires à tous les niveaux du gouvernement fédéral, a 
autorisé l'internement des dizaines de milliers de citoyens 
américains d'ascendance japonaise et d'étrangers résidents du 
Japon. Le gouvernement fédéral essayé pour surveiller des 
conditions à l'intérieur des camps de réadressage et pour garder 
des tabulateurs sur les sentiments et les attitudes des internés. 
Une entrevue conduite dans le Manzanar, la Californie, camp en 
juillet 1943 par un employé de gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS avec un 
homme identifié seulement comme "Nisei plus ancien" (une personne 
Américain-soutenue dont les parents sont nés au Japon) a indiqué la
colère que beaucoup d'internés se sont sentie vers les Etats-Unis. 
Affirmant sa fidélité et sa bonne volonté tôt de supporter 
l'effort de guerre, le Nisei plus ancien a condamné l'évacuation des
Américains japonais de la côte occidentale. Il a interrogé 
pourquoi le gouvernement n'a pas agi pareillement contre des citoyens 
de descente allemande et italienne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">América a segunda guerra mundial lutada aquela 
para preservar a liberdade e a democracia, contudo a mesma guerra 
caracterizou a supressão a mais grande de liberdades civis no history
da nação. Em uma atmosfera do hysteria, o presidente 
Roosevelt, incentivado por oficiais em todos os níveis do governo 
federal, autorizou o internamento dos dez dos milhares de cidadãos 
americanos do ancestry japonês e dos estrangeiros residentes de 
Japão. O governo federal tentado monitorar condições dentro 
dos acampamentos do relocation e manter abas nos sentimentos e nas 
atitudes dos internees. Uma entrevista conduzida no Manzanar, 
Califórnia, acampamento em julho 1943 por um empregado de governo de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS com um homem identificado somente como "um Nisei mais 
velho" (uma pessoa Americano-carregada cujos os pais fossem carregados
em Japão) revelou a raiva feltro de muitos internees para os estados 
unidos. Afirmando sua lealdade e seu voluntariedade adiantado 
suportar o esforço da guerra, o Nisei mais velho condemned a 
evacuação de americanos japoneses da costa ocidental. 
Questionou porque o governo não agiu similarmente de encontro 
aos cidadãos da descida alemão e italiana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'America ha combattuto la seconda guerra mondiale
per conservare la libertà e la democrazia, tuttavia quella la stessa 
guerra ha caratterizzato la soppressione più grande delle libertà 
civili nella storia della nazione. In un atmosfera di hysteria, 
il presidente Roosevelt, consigliato a dai funzionari a tutti i 
livelli del governo federale, ha autorizzato l'internamento dei dieci 
dei migliaia dei cittadini americani dell'ascendenza giapponese e 
degli stranieri residenti dal Giappone. Il governo federale 
provato per controllare i termini all'interno degli accampamenti di 
rilocazione e per mantenere le tabulazione sulle sensibilità e sugli 
atteggiamenti dei internees. Un'intervista condotta nel 
Manzanar, la California, accampamento nel mese di luglio del 1943 da 
un impiegato di governo degli STATI UNITI con un uomo identificato 
soltanto come "più vecchio Nisei" (una persona Americano-sopportata 
di cui i genitori sono stati sopportati nel Giappone) ha rivelato la 
rabbia molti internees che feltro verso unito Dichiara. 
Asserendo la sua lealtà e la sua compiacenza iniziale sostenere
lo sforzo di guerra, il più vecchio Nisei ha condannato l'evacuamento
degli Americani giapponesi dal litorale ad ovest. Ha interrogato
perchè il governo non si è comportato similmente contro i cittadini 
della discesa tedesca ed italiana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Αμερική διεξήγαγε τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ για να 
συντηρήσει την ελευθερία και τη δημοκρατία, όμως εκείνος ο ίδιος
πόλεμος χαρακτήρισε τη μέγιστη καταστολή των αστικών ελευθεριών 
στην ιστορία του έθνους. Σε μια ατμόσφαιρα της υστερίας, ο 
Πρόεδρος Roosevelt, που ενθαρρύνθηκε από τους ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους σε όλα τα επίπεδα της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης, 
ενέκρινε τον περιορισμό των δεκάδων χιλιάδων αμερικανικοί 
πολίτες της ιαπωνικής καταγωγής και εδρεύοντες αλλοδαποί από την
Ιαπωνία. Η ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση προσπάθησε να ελέγξει 
τους όρους μέσα στα στρατόπεδα επαναμετάθεσης και να κρατήσει τις
ετικέττες στα συναισθήματα και τις τοποθετήσεις των internees. 
Μια συνέντευξη που πραγματοποιήθηκε στο Manzanar, 
Καλιφόρνια, στρατόπεδο τον Ιούλιο του 1943 από υπάλληλος 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης με ένα άτομο που προσδιορίστηκε μόνο 
δεδομένου ότι "ένα παλαιότερο Nisei" (ένα 
αμερικανικός-γεννημένο πρόσωπο οι του οποίου γονείς γεννήθηκαν 
στην Ιαπωνία) αποκάλυψε το θυμό πολλά internees αισθάνθηκε 
προς τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Βεβαιώνοντας την πίστη του και 
την πρόωρη προθυμία του να υποστηρίξει την πολεμική προσπάθεια, 
το παλαιότερο Nisei καταδίκασε την εκκένωση ιαπωνικών 
Αμερικανών από τη δυτική ακτή. Εξέτασε γιατί η κυβέρνηση 
δεν ενέργησε ομοίως ενάντια στους πολίτες της γερμανικής και 
ιταλικής καταγωγής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">América la Segunda Guerra Mundial de combate ésa
para preservar la libertad y la democracia, con todo la misma guerra 
ofreció la supresión más grande de libertades civiles en la 
historia de la nación. En una atmósfera de la histeria, 
presidente Roosevelt, alentador por los funcionarios en todos los 
niveles del gobierno federal, autorizó la internación de diez de 
millares de ciudadanos americanos de ascendencia japonesa y de 
extranjeros residentes de Japón. El gobierno federal intentado 
para vigilar condiciones dentro de los campos de la realocación y 
para guardar tabulaciones en las sensaciones y las actitudes de los 
internados. Una entrevista conducida en el Manzanar, California,
campo en julio de 1943 de un empleado de gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
con un hombre identificado solamente como "Nisei más viejo" (una 
persona Americano-llevada que padres nacieron en Japón) reveló la 
cólera que muchos internados se sentían hacia los Estados Unidos. 
Afirmando su lealtad y su buena voluntad temprana de utilizar el
esfuerzo de la guerra, el Nisei más viejo condenó la evacuación de 
americanos japoneses de la costa del oeste. Él preguntó 
porqué el gobierno no actuaba semejantemente contra ciudadanos de la 
pendiente alemana e italiana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086128</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107023</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/evacuation-was-a-mistake-anger-at-being-interned</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
