<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108765</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108765</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087185</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Chinese Are Viewed Like Thieves and Enemies": Pun Chi Appeals to Congress to Protect the Rights of Chinese, ca. 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir Chinese werden wie Diebe und Feinde" 
angesehen: Wortspiel-Chi gefällt Kongreß, um die Rechte des 
Chinesen, Ca zu schützen. 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous Chinois sommes visualisés comme des voleurs
et des ennemis" : Le chi de calembour fait appel au congrès 
pour protéger les droites du Chinois, ca. 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós chinês somos vistos como ladrões e 
inimigos": O chi do pun apela ao congress para proteger as 
direitas do chinês, ca. 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"cinese siamo osservati come i ladri ed i 
nemici": Il "chi" di pun fa appello al congresso per proteggere 
i diritti del cinese, ca. 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κινέζικα εμφανιζόμαστε όπως τους κλέφτες και τους 
εχθρούσ": Chi λογοπαίγνιου εκκλήσεις στο συνέδριο για να
προστατεύσει τα δικαιώματα των κινέζικων, περίπου 1860</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"nos chino ven como ladrones y enemigos": El
chi del retruécano abroga al congreso para proteger las derechas del 
chino, ca. 1860</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Nineteenth-century officials and businessmen eager for cheap labor for California's manufacturing, mining, and agricultural industries encouraged Chinese migrants to voyage to the United States. In the 1850s, however, as the Chinese population grew, an anti-Chinese movement mounted. The California legislature and courts restricted the rights of Chinese immigrants with the Foreign Miners Tax of 1852 and a California Supreme Court decision-- People  v.  Hall  (1854) --that excluded Chinese testimony from the courts, further sanctioning violence against Chinese residents. Pun Chi, a young Chinese merchant, wrote this appeal to Congress, sometime between 1856 and 1868, seeking help against growing anti-Chinese sentiments in the West. Reminding Congress that Chinese migration had been encouraged and that migrants deserved legal protection once in the United States, he gave graphic accounts of the mining tax collectors' abuses and the murder of Chinese miners. William Speer, a Presbyterian minister and missionary in San Francisco's Chinatown, translated Pun Chi's appeal from Chinese and published it in 1870.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">die 19.-Jahrhundert Beamten und Geschäftsmänner,
die für preiswerte Arbeit für Herstellung Kaliforniens, Bergbau und 
landwirtschaftliche Industrien eifrig sind, regten chinesische 
Wanderer voyage in die Vereinigten Staaten an. Im 1850s jedoch 
während die chinesische Bevölkerung wuchs, hing eine 
Anti-Chinesische Bewegung ein. Die Kalifornien Gesetzgebung und 
die Gerichte schränkten die Rechte der chinesischen Immigranten mit 
der fremden Bergmann-Steuer von 1852 und einer Kalifornien 
Gerichtentscheidung ein -- bevölkeren Sie v. Hall (1854) -- das 
chinesisches Zeugnis von den Gerichten ausschloß, weitere 
Sanktionierengewalttätigkeit gegen chinesische Bewohner. 
Wortspiel-Chi, ein junger chinesischer Kaufmann, schrieb dem 
Kongreß, einmal zwischen 1856 und 1868 diesen Anklang und suchte 
Hilfe gegen das Wachsen der Anti-Chinesischen Gefühle in den Westen. 
Erinnern des Kongresses, daß chinesische Migration angeregt 
worden war und daß Wanderer Rechtsschutz einmal in den vereinigten 
Zuständen verdienten, berichtete er graphische über den 
Mißbräuchen und dem Mord der gewinnensteuereinzieher an den 
chinesischen Bergmännern. William Speer, ein presbyterianischer
Minister und Missionar in Chinatown San Franciscos, Anklang des 
übersetzten Wortspiel-Chi vom Chinesen und veröffentlicht ihm 1870.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les fonctionnaires et les hommes d'affaires de 
Dix-neuvième-siècle désireux pour la main d'oeuvre à prix réduit 
pour la fabrication de la Californie, l'exploitation, et les 
industries agricoles ont encouragé les migrants chinois à voyager 
aux Etats-Unis. Dans le 1850s, cependant, pendant que la 
population chinoise se développait, un mouvement anti-Chinois a 
monté. La législature et les cours de la Californie ont 
limité les droites des immigrés chinois avec l'impôt étranger de 
mineurs de 1852 et une décision de cour suprême de la Californie -- 
peuplez v. Hall (1854) -- qui a exclu le témoignage chinois des 
cours, davantage de violence de sanction contre les résidants 
chinois. Le chi de calembour, un jeune négociant chinois, a 
écrit cet appel au congrès, autrefois entre 1856 et 1868, 
recherchant l'aide contre accroître des sentiments anti-Chinois dans 
l'ouest. Rappel du congrès que le transfert chinois avait été
encouragé et que les migrants ont mérité la protection légale par 
le passé aux Etats-Unis, il a fait des exposés graphiques des abus 
et du meurtre des percepteurs d'impôt d'extraction des mineurs 
chinois. William Speer, un ministre presbytérien et 
missionnaire dans Chinatown de San Francisco, l'appel du chi's 
traduit de calembour du Chinois et édité lui en 1870.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os oficiais e os homens de negócios de 
Décimo-século ansiosos para o trabalho barato para o manufacturing 
de Califórnia, a mineração, e indústrias agriculturais 
incentivaram emigrantes chineses viajar aos estados unidos. No 
1850s, entretanto, enquanto a população chinesa cresceu, um 
movimento anti-Chinês montou. A legislatura e as cortes de 
Califórnia restringiram as direitas de immigrants chineses com o 
imposto extrangeiro dos mineiros de 1852 e uma decisão da corte 
suprema de Califórnia -- povoe o v. Salão (1854) -- que excluiu o 
testimony chinês das cortes, violência mais adicional sanctioning de
encontro aos residentes chineses. O chi do pun, um comerciante 
chinês novo, escreveu esta apelação ao congress, sometime entre 
1856 e 1868, procurando a ajuda de encontro a crescer sentiments 
anti-Chineses no oeste. Lembrar o congress que a migração 
chinesa tinha sido incentivada e que os emigrantes mereceram a 
proteção legal uma vez nos estados unidos, deu clientes gráficos 
dos abusos e do assassinato de coletores de imposto minando de 
mineiros chineses. William Speer, um ministro presbyterian e 
missionário em Chinatown do San Francisco, apelação do chi 
traduzido do pun do chinês e publicada lhe em 1870.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i funzionari e gli uomini d'affari di 
Diciannovesimo-secolo desiderosi per il lavoro poco costoso 
affinchè manufacturing della California, estrazione mineraria ed i 
migranti cinesi consigliati a industrie agricole voyage al unito 
Dichiara. Nel 1850s, tuttavia, mentre la popolazione 
cinese si è sviluppata, un movimento di anti-cinese ha 
montato. La legislatura e le corti della California hanno 
limitato i diritti degli immigranti cinesi con la tassa straniera
dei minatori di 1852 e una decisione della Corte suprema della 
California -- popoli il v. Corridoio (1854) -- che ha escluso la 
testimonianza cinese dalle corti, ulteriore violenza sanctioning 
contro i residenti cinesi. Il "chi" di pun, un commerciante
cinese giovane, ha scritto questo appello al congresso, un 
momento fra 1856 e 1868, cercando l'aiuto contro la crescita dei 
sentimenti di anti-cinese nell'ovest. Ricordo del congresso 
che l'espansione cinese era stata consigliata a e che i migranti 
si sono meritati protezione legale in unito Dichiara una 
volta, ha fatto i resoconti grafici degli abusi e dell'omicidio dei 
collettori estraenti di imposta dei minatori cinesi. 
William Speer, un ministro presbyterian e missionario in 
Chinatown de San Francisco, appello del "chi" tradotto di pun dal 
cinese e pubblicato esso in 1870.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι και οι επιχειρηματίες 
δέκατος-αιώνα πρόθυμοι για τη φτηνή εργασία για την κατασκευή 
Καλιφόρνιας, να εξαγάγουν, και τις γεωργικές βιομηχανίες 
ενθαρρύνω τους κινεζικούς μετανάστες στο ταξίδι στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες. Στο 1850s, εντούτοις, ως της Κίνας πληθυσμό 
αυξήθηκε, μια αντι-κινεζική μετακίνηση που επικολλήθηκε. Το 
νομοθετικό σώμα και τα δικαστήρια Καλιφόρνιας περιόρισαν τα 
δικαιώματα των κινεζικών μεταναστών με τον ξένο φόρο 
ανθρακωρύχων 1852 και μια απόφαση ανώτατου δικαστηρίου 
Καλιφόρνιας -- άνθρωποι V. αίθουσα (1854) -- που απέκλεισαν 
την κινεζική κατάθεση από τα δικαστήρια, περαιτέρω εγκρίνοντας 
βία ενάντια στους κινεζικούς κατοίκους. Chi 
λογοπαίγνιου, ένας νέος κινεζικός έμπορος, έγραψε αυτήν την 
έκκληση στο συνέδριο, κάποτε μεταξύ 1856 και 1868, 
επιδιώκων τις οδηγίες ενάντια στην ανάπτυξη των αντι-κινεζικών 
συναισθημάτων στη δύση. Υπενθύμιση του συνεδρίου ότι η 
κινεζική μετανάστευση είχε ενθαρρυνθεί και ότι οι μετανάστες 
άξιζαν τη νομική προστασία μιά φορά στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, 
έδωσε τις γραφικές περιγραφές των καταχρήσεων των εισπρακτόρων 
φόρων μεταλλείας και δολοφονία των κινεζικών ανθρακωρύχων. 
Θ*Ωηλληαμ Speer, ένας Πρεσβυτεριανοί υπουργός και ένας 
ιεραπόστολος σε Chinatown του Σαν Φρανσίσκο, μετέφρασαν chi 
λογοπαίγνιου την έκκληση από τα κινέζικα και την δημοσίευσαν το 
1870.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los funcionarios y los hombres de negocios del 
Diecinueveavo-siglo impacientes para el trabajo barato para la 
fabricación de California, la explotación minera, y las industrias 
agrícolas animaron a nómadas chinos que viajaran a los Estados 
Unidos. En el 1850s, sin embargo, como la población china 
creció, un movimiento contra-Chino montó. La legislatura y las
cortes de California restringieron las derechas de inmigrantes chinos 
con el impuesto no nativo de los mineros de 1852 y una decisión del 
Tribunal Supremo de California -- pueble el v. Pasillo (1854) -- que 
excluyó testimonio chino de las cortes, violencia adicional de la 
sanción contra residentes chinos. El chi del retruécano, 
comerciante chino joven, escribió esta súplica al congreso, alguna 
vez entre 1856 y 1868, buscando ayuda contra el crecimiento de 
sentimientos contra-Chinos en el oeste. Recordar a congreso que 
la migración china había sido animada y que los nómadas merecieron 
la protección legal una vez en los Estados Unidos, él dio cuentas 
gráficas del asesinato de los colectores de impuesto que minaban de 
los abusos y de mineros chinos. Guillermo Speer, ministro 
presbyterian y misionario en Chinatown de San Francisco, súplica del 
chi traducido del retruécano del chino y publicada le en 1870.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087185</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108765</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-chinese-are-viewed-like-thieves-and-enemies-pun-chi-appeals-to-congress-to-protect-the-rights-of-chinese-ca-1860</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
