<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104078</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104078</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207169</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Women Pioneers in American Memory</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frau-Pioniere im amerikanischen Speicher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pionniers de femmes dans la mémoire américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pioneiros das mulheres na memória americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pionieri delle donne nella memoria americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρωτοπόροι γυναικών στην αμερικανική μνήμη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pioneros de las mujeres en memoria americana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features photographs of women throughout American history who have forged ahead to make a better life for themselves, their families, and their society. These women include pioneers who journeyed across the country to settle unknown western territories, as well as women who struggled for recognition as equals in politics, in the workforce, and in their communities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet Fotographien der Frauen während der 
amerikanischen Geschichte, die Führung übernahmen, um eine bessere 
Lebensdauer für selbst, ihre Familien und ihre Gesellschaft zu bilden
haben. Diese Frauen enthalten Pioniere, die über das Land 
reisten, um unbekannte westliche Gegenden, sowie Frauen zu 
vereinbaren, die für Anerkennung als Gleichgestellte in den 
Politiken, in der Mannschaft und in ihren Gemeinschaften kämpften.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte des photographies des femmes dans toute 
l'histoire américaine qui ont sont allées de l'avant pour faire une 
meilleure vie pour elles-mêmes, leurs familles, et leur société. 
Ces femmes incluent les pionniers qui ont voyagé à travers le 
pays pour arranger les territoires occidentaux inconnus, aussi bien 
que les femmes qui ont lutté pour l'identification en tant qu'égales
dans la politique, dans la main d'oeuvre, et dans leurs communautés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza fotografias das mulheres durante todo 
o history americano que forjaram adiante para fazer uma vida melhor 
para se, das suas famílias, e da sua sociedade. Estas mulheres 
incluem os pioneiros que viajaram através do país para estabelecir 
territórios ocidentais desconhecidos, as.well.as as mulheres que se 
esforçaram para o recognition como iguais na política, no workforce,
e em suas comunidades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza le fotografie delle donne durante 
storia americana che hanno forgiato avanti per fare loro una vita 
migliore per, delle loro famiglie e della loro società. Queste 
donne includono i pionieri che hanno viaggiato attraverso il paese per
depositare i territori occidentali sconosciuti, così come le donne 
che hanno lottato per riconoscimento come uguali nelle politiche, 
nella mano d'opera e nelle loro Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τις φωτογραφίες των γυναικών σε όλη την 
αμερικανική ιστορία που έχουν προχωρήσει σταθερά για να κάνουν 
μια καλύτερη ζωή για τους, τις οικογένειές τους, και την κοινωνία
τους. Αυτές οι γυναίκες περιλαμβάνουν τους πρωτοπόρους που 
ταξίδεψαν σε ολόκληρη τη χώρα για να εγκαταστήσουν τα άγνωστα 
δυτικά εδάφη, καθώς επίσης και τις γυναίκες που αγωνίστηκαν για 
την αναγνώριση όπως είναι ίσος με στην πολιτική, στο εργατικό 
δυναμικό, και στις κοινότητές τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece las fotografías de las mujeres a través 
de la historia americana que tienen avanzaron para hacer una vida 
mejor para sí mismos, sus familias, y su sociedad. Estas 
mujeres incluyen a pioneros que viajaron a través del país para 
colocar territorios occidentales desconocidos, así como las mujeres 
que lucharon para el reconocimiento como iguales en políticas, en la 
mano de obra, y en sus comunidades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207169</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104078</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/women-pioneers-in-american-memory</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
