<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107142</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107142</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086904</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Boston Massacre, ca. 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Boston Blutbad, Ca. 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Massacre de Boston, ca. 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O massacre de Boston, ca. 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il massacre de Boston, ca. 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σφαγή της Βοστώνης, περίπου 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Masacre de Boston, ca. 1868.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Boston Massacre became an important symbol for radicals who used the incident to build popular opposition to British rule. For thirteen years after the incident, Boston observed March 5, the anniversary of the incident, as a day of public mourning. Artists continued to redraw, repaint, and reinterpret the Boston Massacre long after it occurred. This engraving based on a painting by Alonzo Chappel was published in 1868. While the artist still omitted Crispus Attucks, a black sailor who was one of those killed in the Massacre, it showed the chaos of the confrontation and captured the horror of soldiers shooting down unarmed citizens.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Boston Blutbad wurde ein wichtiges Symbol für 
Radikale, die das Ereignis verwendeten, um populäre Opposition zur 
britischen Richtlinie aufzubauen. Für dreizehn Jahre nach dem 
Ereignis, beobachtete Boston März 5, der Jahrestag des Ereignisses, 
als Tag des allgemeinen Beklagens. Künstler fuhren redraw, neu 
zu streichen fort, und reinterpret das Boston Blutbad lang nach ihm 
trat auf. Dieser Stich, der auf einem Anstrich von Alonzo 
Chappel basierte, wurde 1868 veröffentlicht. Während der 
Künstler noch Crispus Attucks ausließ, beendete ein schwarzer 
Seemann, der einer von denen war, im Blutbad, es zeigte das Chaos der 
Konfrontation und erfaßte die Grausigkeit der Soldaten, die hinunter 
unbewaffnete Bürger schießen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Massacre de Boston est devenu un symbole important 
pour les radicaux qui ont employé l'incident pour établir 
l'opposition populaire à la règle britannique. Pendant treize 
années après l'incident, Boston a observé mars 5, l'anniversaire de
l'incident, comme jour du deuil public. Les artistes ont 
continué à redessiner, peindre, et réinterpréter le Massacre de
Boston longtemps après lui s'est produit. Cette gravure basée 
sur une peinture par Alonzo Chappel a été éditée en 1868. 
Tandis que l'artiste omettait toujours Crispus Attucks, un marin
noir qui était l'un de ceux a détruit dans le Massacre, il a 
montré le chaos de la confrontation et a capturé l'horreur des 
soldats tirant en bas des citoyens sans armes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O massacre de Boston transformou-se um símbolo importante
para os radicais que usaram o incident construir a oposição popular 
à régua britânica. Por treze anos após o incident, Boston 
observou março 5, o anniversary do incident, como um dia de mourning 
público. Os artistas continuaram a redesenhar, para repintar, e
reinterpret o massacre de Boston por muito tempo após ele ocorreu. 
Este engraving baseado em uma pintura por Alonzo Chappel foi 
publicado em 1868. Quando o artista omitiu ainda Crispus 
Attucks, um sailor preto que fosse um daqueles matou no massacre, ele 
mostrou o caos do confrontation e capturou o horror dos soldados que 
disparam abaixo cidadãos unarmed.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il massacre de Boston si è transformato in in un simbolo 
importante per i radicali che hanno usato l'avvenimento per sviluppare
l'opposizione popolare alla regola britannica. Per tredici anni 
dopo l'avvenimento, Boston ha osservato il 5 marzo, l'anniversario 
dell'avvenimento, come giorno di dolore pubblico. Gli artisti 
hanno continuato a ridisegnare, ridipingere ed interpretarle 
nuovamente il massacre de Boston lungamente ha accaduto. Questa 
incisione basata su una pittura da Alonzo Chappel è stata pubblicata 
in 1868. Mentre l'artista ancora ha omesso Crispus Attucks, un 
marinaio nero che era uno di quelli ha ucciso nel massacre, esso ha 
mostrato il caos del confronto ed ha bloccato l'orrore dei soldati che
sparano giù i cittadini unarmed.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σφαγή της Βοστώνης έγινε ένα σημαντικό σύμβολο για
τους ριζοσπάστες που χρησιμοποίησαν το γεγονός για να χτίσουν τη 
δημοφιλή αντίθεση στο βρετανικό κανόνα. Για δέκα τρία έτη
μετά από το γεγονός, η Βοστώνη παρατήρησε τις 5 Μαρτίου, η 
επέτειος του γεγονότος, ως ημέρα του δημόσιου πένθους. Οι 
καλλιτέχνες συνέχισαν να αποσύρουν, να ξαναβάφουν, και να 
επανερμηνεύουν τη σφαγή της Βοστώνης μακροχρόνια αφότου 
εμφανίστηκε. Αυτή η χάραξη βασισμένη σε μια ζωγραφική από 
Alonzo Chappel δημοσιεύθηκε το 1868. Ενώ ο 
καλλιτέχνης παρέλειψε ακόμα Crispus Attucks, ένας μαύρος 
ναυτικός που ήταν ένας από εκείνους που σκοτώθηκαν στη σφαγή, 
αυτό εμφάνισε το χάος της αντιμετώπισης και συνέλαβε τη φρίκη 
των στρατιωτών πυροβολισμός κάτω από τους άοπλους πολίτες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Masacre de Boston se convirtió en un símbolo 
importante para los radicales que utilizaron el incidente para 
construir la oposición popular a la regla británica. Por trece
años después del incidente, Boston observó de marcha la 5, el 
aniversario del incidente, como día del luto público. Los 
artistas continuaron rediseñando, repintar, y reinterpretar la 
Masacre de Boston después de ella ocurrió de largo. Este 
grabado basado en una pintura por Alonzo Chappel fue publicado en 
1868. Mientras que el artista todavía omitió Crispus Attucks, 
un marinero negro que era uno de ésos mató en la Masacre, él 
mostró el caos de la confrontación y capturó el horror de los 
soldados que tiraban abajo de ciudadanos desarmados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086904</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107142</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-boston-massacre-ca-1868</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
