<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105380</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105380</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Global Temperatures</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Globale Temperaturen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Températures Globales</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Temperaturas Globais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Temperature Globali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σφαιρικές θερμοκρασίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Temperaturas Globales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, students analyze the global temperature record from 1867 to the present. Long-term trends and shorter-term fluctuations are both evaluated. The data is examined for evidence of the impact of natural and anthropogenic climate forcing mechanisms on the global surface temperature variability. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität analysieren Kursteilnehmer 
den globalen Temperatursatz von 1867 zum Geschenk. Long-term 
neigt und kürzere Bezeichnung Fluktuationen werden beide ausgewertet.
Die Daten werden für Beweis der Auswirkung des natürlichen und
anthropogenic Klimas überprüft, das Einheiten auf die globale 
Oberflächentemperaturveränderlichkeit erzwingt. Auf dieser 
Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen über die 
erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les étudiants analysent 
l'enregistrement global de la température de 1867 au présent. 
Le long terme tend et des fluctuations plus courtes toutes les 
deux de limite sont évaluées. Les données sont examinées 
pour l'évidence de l'impact du climat normal et anthropogène 
forçant des mécanismes sur la variabilité globale de température 
de surface. À cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs 
peuvent accéder aux informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice,
contexte pour les extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes
et, le matériel didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les 
références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os estudantes analisam o registro
global da temperatura de 1867 ao presente. O prazo tende e umas 
flutuações mais curtas ambas do termo são avaliadas. Os dados
são examinados para a evidência do impacto do clima natural e 
anthropogenic que força mecanismos no variability global da 
temperatura de superfície. Nesta página do ponto começar, os 
usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os objetivos de 
aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do uso, ensinar as
notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da avaliação, as 
referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli allievi analizzano il 
record globale di temperatura da 1867 al presente. Il lungo 
termine tende e le fluttuazioni più corte entrambe di termine sono 
valutate. I dati sono esaminati per prova dell'effetto del clima
naturale ed anthropogenic che forza i meccanismi sulla variabilità 
globale di temperatura in superficie. A questa pagina del punto 
di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sugli 
obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di 
istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le idee di 
valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές αναλύουν το 
σφαιρικό αρχείο θερμοκρασίας από 1867 στο παρόν. Οι 
μακροπρόθεσμες τάσεις και οι μικρότερης περιόδου διακυμάνσεις και
οι δύο αξιολογούνται. Το στοιχείο εξετάζεται για τα 
στοιχεία του αντίκτυπου των φυσικών και ανθρωπογενών αναγκάζοντας
μηχανισμών κλίματος στη σφαιρική μεταβλητότητα θερμοκρασίας 
επιφάνειας. Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες 
μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους 
εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και 
τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες 
αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los estudiantes analizan el 
expediente global de la temperatura a partir de 1867 al presente. 
El largo plazo tiende y se evalúan fluctuaciones más a corto 
plazo ambas. Los datos se examinan para la evidencia del impacto
del clima natural y anthropogenic que fuerza mecanismos en la 
variabilidad global de la temperatura superficial. En esta 
paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso
a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto
para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los 
materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los 
asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY EARTH AND ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE FACULTY
FN:COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY EARTH AND ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE FACULTY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202982</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105380</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/global-temperatures</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
