<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107121</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107121</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086395</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Law and Order: William Law and the Power of Organization</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gesetz und Ordnung: William Gesetz und die 
Energie der Organisation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Loi et commande : Loi de William et la 
puissance de l'organisation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lei e ordem: Lei de William e a potência da
organização</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Legge ed ordine: Legge del William e 
l'potenza dell'organizzazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νόμος και τάξη: Θ*Ωηλληαμ Law και η δύναμη της
οργάνωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ley y orden: Ley de Guillermo y la potencia 
de la organización</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In order to challenge the emphasis on extreme economic individualism espoused by Gilded Age industrialists and laissez-faire theorists, labor writers drew on diverse historical and religious traditions. William Law, writing in the Detroit  Labor Leaf  in 1886, cited a variety of historical events, starting with the Magna Carta, to argue for collective organization. Law reminded his readers that some of history's most notable changes came about only as a result of organized effort on the part of the masses.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Um das Hauptgewicht auf dem extremen 
Wirtschaftsindividualismus herauszufordern, der von vergoldeten Alter 
Industriellen und von Laissez-Faire Theoretikern unterstützt wurde, 
zeichneten Arbeitsverfasser auf verschiedene historische und fromme 
Traditionen. Das William Gesetz, schreibend in das Detroit 
Arbeitsblatt 1886, zitierte eine Vielzahl der historischen Fälle, 
beginnend mit dem Magna Carta, um für Kollektivorganisation zu 
argumentieren. Gesetz erinnerte seine Leser, daß einige von 
bemerkenswertesten Änderungen der Geschichte ungefähr nur 
resultierend aus organisierter Bemühung von seiten der Massen kamen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Afin de défier l'emphase sur l'individualisme 
économique extrême embrassé par les industriels d'âge et les 
théoriciens dorés de laissez-faire, les auteurs de travail ont 
dessiné sur des traditions historiques et religieuses diverses. 
La loi de William, écrivant dans la feuille de travail de 
Detroit en 1886, a cité une variété d'événements historiques, 
commençant par la Magna Carta, pour plaider pour l'organisation 
collective. La loi a rappelé ses lecteurs que certains des 
changements les plus notables de l'histoire sont venus environ 
seulement en raison de l'effort organisé de la part des masses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A fim desafiar a ênfase no individualism 
econômico extremo espoused por industrialistas da idade e por 
theorists gilded do laissez-faire, os escritores labor desenharam em 
tradições históricas e religiosas diversas. A lei de William,
escrevendo na folha labor de Detroit em 1886, cited uma variedade de 
eventos históricos, começando com o magna Carta, discutir para a 
organização coletiva. A lei lembrou seus leitores que algumas 
das mudanças as mais notáveis do history vieram aproximadamente 
somente em conseqüência do esforço organizado na parte das massas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per sfidare l'enfasi su individualism economico 
estremo espoused dagli industriali di età e dai teorici gilded di 
"laissez faire", i produttori di lavoro hanno dissipato sulle 
tradizioni storiche e religiose varie. La legge del William, 
scrivente nel foglio Di lavoro de Detroit in 1886, ha citato una 
varietà di eventi storici, cominciando dal magna Carta, per parlare a
favore dell'organizzazione collettiva. La legge ha ricordato ai 
suoi lettori che alcuni dei cambiamenti più notevoli della storia 
sono venuto circa soltanto come conseguenza di sforzo organizzato da 
parte delle masse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προκειμένου να προκληθεί η έμφαση στον ακραίο 
οικονομικό ατομικισμό που παντρεύτηκε από τους επιχρυσωμένους 
βιομηχάνους ηλικίας και τους θεωρητικούς ελεύθερης οικονομίας, οι
συγγραφείς εργασίας επέσυραν την προσοχή στις διαφορετικές 
ιστορικές και θρησκευτικές παραδόσεις. Θ*Ωηλληαμ Law, που 
γράφει στο φύλλο εργασίας του Ντητρόιτ το 1886, ανέφερε 
ποικίλες ιστορικές εκδηλώσεις, αρχίζοντας από τη Magna 
Carta, για να υποστηρίξει τη συλλογική οργάνωση. Ο νόμος 
υπενθύμισε στους αναγνώστες του για τους οποίους μερικές από τις 
πιό ξεχωριστές αλλαγές της ιστορίας ήρθαν μόνο ως αποτέλεσμα 
της οργανωμένης προσπάθειας εκ μέρους των μαζών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para desafiar el énfasis en el individualismo 
económico extremo espoused por los industriales de la edad y los 
teóricos dorados del liberalismo, los programas de escritura de 
trabajo trazaron en tradiciones históricas y religiosas diversas. 
La ley de Guillermo, escribiendo en la hoja de trabajo de 
Detroit en 1886, citó una variedad de acontecimientos históricos, 
comenzando con el magna Carta, para discutir para la organización 
colectiva. La ley recordó a sus programas de lectura que 
algunos de los cambios más notables de la historia vinieron alrededor
solamente como resultado de esfuerzo ordenado de parte de las masas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086395</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107121</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/law-and-order-william-law-and-the-power-of-organization</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
