<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108514</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108514</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207037</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Freedom Timeline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Freiheit Timeline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Chronologie de Liberté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Liberdade Timeline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Libertà Timeline</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο ελευθερίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Libertad Timeline</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers stories on topics such as diplomacy and liberty. The timeline spans 1777 to 1948 and includes stories about a Quaker woman who, in 1777, learned of a sneak attack at Valley Forge and warned General Washington's troops; how Harriet Tubman liberated 300 slaves through the Underground Railroad; and U.S. efforts to provide humanitarian aid to the people of war-torn Berlin in 1948 by dropping food from airplanes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebotgeschichten auf Themen wie Diplomatie und 
Freiheit. Das timeline überspannt 1777 bis 1948 und schließt 
Geschichten über eine Quäkerfrau ein, die, 1777, von einem 
Sneakangriff an den Truppen der Senke-Schmiede und gewarnten des 
Generals Washingtons erlernte; wie Harriet Tubman 300 Sklaven 
durch die unterirdische Eisenbahn befreite; und VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Bemühungen, humanitäres Hilfsmittel zu den Leuten von 
Krieg-heftig gezerrissenem Berlin 1948 vom Fallenlassen der Nahrung 
von den Flugzeugen zur Verfügung zu stellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">histoires d'offres sur des sujets tels que la 
diplomatie et la liberté. La chronologie enjambe 1777 à 1948 
et inclut des histoires au sujet d'une femme de quaker qui, en 1777, a
appris d'une attaque de mouchard aux troupes de forge de vallée et de
Général Washington averti ; comment Harriet Tubman a libéré 
300 esclaves par le chemin de fer souterrain ; et efforts des 
ETATS-UNIS de fournir l'aide humanitaire aux habitants de Berlin 
déchiré par la guerre en 1948 en relâchant la nourriture des avions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">histórias das ofertas em tópicos tais como o 
diplomacy e a liberdade. O timeline mede 1777 a 1948 e inclui 
histórias sobre uma mulher do quaker que, em 1777, aprenda de um 
ataque do sneak em tropas da forja do vale e do general Washington 
advertido; como Harriet Tubman liberated 300 escravos através 
da estrada de ferro subterrânea; e esforços de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
fornecer o dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) humanitário aos 
povos de Berlim guerra-rasgada em 1948 deixando cair o alimento dos 
aviões.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">storia di offerte sui soggetti quali diplomazia e 
libertà. Il timeline misura 1777 - 1948 ed include le storia 
circa una donna del quaker che, in 1777, ha imparato di un attacco 
dello sneak alle truppe della forgia della valle e del General 
Washington avvertita; come Harriet Tubman ha liberato 300 
schiavi tramite la ferrovia sotterranea; e sforzi degli STATI 
UNITI fornire sussidio umanitario alla gente di Berlino 
guerra-strappata in 1948 cadendo alimento dagli aeroplani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ιστορίες προσφορών σχετικά με τα θέματα όπως η 
διπλωματία και η ελευθερία. Η υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο 
εκτείνεται 1777 έως το 1948 και περιλαμβάνει τις ιστορίες 
για μια κουάκερη γυναίκα που, το 1777, έμαθε γλιστρά την 
επίθεση στην κοιλάδα σφυρηλατεί και προειδοποίησε τα στρατεύματα 
στρατηγού Washington's  πώς ο Harriet Tubman 
ελευθέρωσε 300 σκλάβους μέσω του υπόγειου σιδηροδρόμου  
και ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΕΣ προσπάθειες να παρασχεθεί η ανθρωπιστική 
βοήθεια στους πληθυσμούς του πόλεμος-σχισμένου Βερολίνου το 
1948 με τη ρίψη των τροφίμων από τα αεροπλάνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">historias de las ofertas en asuntos tales como 
diplomacia y libertad. El timeline atraviesa 1777 a 1948 e 
incluye historias sobre una mujer del quaker que, en 1777, aprendió 
de un ataque del chivato en las tropas de la fragua del valle y de 
general Washington advertido; cómo Harriet Tubman liberó a 300
esclavos a través del ferrocarril subterráneo; y esfuerzos de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS de proporcionar a la ayuda humanitaria a la gente de 
Berlín guerra-rasgada en 1948 cayendo el alimento de los aeroplanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207037</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108514</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-freedom-timeline</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
