<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108662</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108662</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Violent Death in Every Form Imaginable": A Senate Committee Report Assesses "Crime and Horror" Comic Books</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"heftiger Tod in jeder Form erdenklich": Ein
Senat-Ausschuss-Report setzt "Verbrechen-und Grausigkeit-" komische 
Bücher fest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la mort violente sous chaque forme imaginable" : 
Un état du Comité de sénat évalue les livres comiques de 
"crime et d'horreur"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"morte violenta em cada formulário imaginable": 
Um relatório do comitê do senate avalia do "livros comic crime
e do horror"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"morte violenta in ogni forma immaginabile": 
Un rapporto del comitato del senato valuta "i libri comic di 
orrore e di crimine"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Βίαιος θάνατος με κάθε μορφή διανοητή": Μια 
έκθεση Επιτροπής Συγκλήτου αξιολογεί τα κωμικά βιβλία 
"εγκλήματος και φρίκησ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"muerte violenta en cada forma imaginable": 
Un informe del comité del senado evalúa los libros cómicos 
del "crimen y del horror"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Religious leaders, civic groups, educators, the press, and government officials have voiced concern since the 19th century over supposed deleterious effects on children of popular culture, from dime novels and motion pictures to comic books, and television. Anxiety over comic books grew as the pulp fiction crime and horror genre developed at the end of World War II. In 1948, psychologist Fredric Wertham advocated the prohibition of comic books to children under the age of 16, claiming that all of the delinquent children he studied had read them. Although the industry's trade organization devised a Code that year to regulate content, only one-third of the publishers subscribed to it. During the next few years many states debated, but did not adopt, bills to ban or regulate comic books, in part because of a 1948 Supreme Court decision that overturned a state statute banning the sale or distribution of crime literature. After the Senate Subcommittee on Juvenile Delinquency conducted hearings on comic books in 1954, the industry formed a new trade association and formulated a new Code to self-censor content. The Code symbol subsequently appeared on approved comic books, curtailing the crime and horror genre. In the following excerpts from the Subcommittee's report, Congress warned the industry that if self-regulation did not prove to be effective, "other ways and means" would be found to protect children. The Code, refined in 1971 and 1989, remains a regulatory instrument for association members.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fromme Führer, bürgerliche Gruppen, Erzieher, 
die Presse und die Regierungsbeamten haben Interesse seit den 19. 
gesollten gesundheitsschädlichen Effekten des Jahrhunderts 
Überschuß auf Kinder der populären Kultur, von billige Romane und 
Bewegung Abbildungen zu komische Bücher und Fernsehen geäußert. 
Komische Bücher des Angstüberschusses wuchsen als das Masse 
Erfindungverbrechen und das Grausigkeitgenre, die am Ende des Zweiten 
Weltkrieges entwickelt wurden. 1948 befürwortete Psychologe 
Fredric Wertham das Verbot der komischen Bücher zu den Kindern unter 
dem Alter von 16 und behauptete, daß alle straffälligen Kinder, die 
er studierte, sie gelesen hatten. Obgleich die 
Geschäftsorganisation der Industrie einen Code der Jahr plante, um 
Inhalt zu regeln, nur Drittel der Verleger zu ihm unterzeichnete. 
Während der nächsten Jahre nahmen viele debattierte Zustände,
aber nicht, die Rechnungen an, zum der komischen Bücher, im Teil 
wegen einer Entscheidung des Höchsten Gerichts zu verbieten oder zu 
regeln 1948, die ein Zustandgesetz umwarf, das den Verkauf oder die 
Verteilung der Verbrechenliteratur verbietet. Nachdem die 
Senat-Unterausschuß auf jugendlicher Gesetzesverletzung 
Hörfähigkeiten auf komischen Büchern 1954 leitete, bildete die 
Industrie eine neue Geschäftsverbindung und formulierte einen neuen 
Code Selbst-Zensor Inhalt. Das Codesymbol erschien nachher auf 
anerkannten komischen Büchern und beschränkte das Verbrechen und das
Grausigkeitgenren. In den folgenden Excerpts vom Report der 
Unterausschusses, warnte Kongreß die Industrie, die, wenn 
Self-regulation nicht wirkungsvoll war, "andere Mittel und" gefunden 
würde, um Kinder zu schützen. Der Code, verfeinert 1971 und 
1989, bleibt ein regelndes Instrument für Verbindung Bauteile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les amorces religieuses, les groupes civiques, les
éducateurs, la presse, et les fonctionnaires de gouvernement ont 
exprimé le souci depuis le 19ème les effets délétères supposés 
de siècle par excédent sur des enfants de culture populaire, des 
romans de dixième de dollar et des films cinématographiques aux 
livres comiques, et à la télévision. Les livres comiques 
d'excédent d'inquiétude se sont développés comme crime de fiction 
de pulpe et genre d'horreur développés à la fin de la deuxième 
guerre mondiale. En 1948, le psychologue Fredric Wertham a 
préconisé la prohibition des livres comiques aux enfants sous l'âge
de 16, réclamant que tous les enfants contrevenants qu'il a étudiés
les avaient lus. Bien que l'organisation commerciale de 
l'industrie ait conçu un code qui année pour régler le contenu, 
seulement un tiers des éditeurs a souscrit à lui. Pendant les 
années à venir beaucoup d'états discutés, mais n'ont pas adopté, 
des factures pour interdire ou régler les livres comiques, en partie 
en raison d'une décision de la cour 1948 suprême qui a retourné un 
statut d'état interdisant la vente ou la distribution de la 
littérature de crime. Après que le sous-comité de sénat sur 
la délinquance juvénile ait conduit des auditions sur les livres 
comiques en 1954, l'industrie a formé une nouvelle association 
commerciale et a formulé un nouveau code au contenu de 
art de l'auto-portrait-censor. Le symbole de code est ultérieurement apparu 
sur les livres comiques approuvés, raccourcissant le crime et le 
genre d'horreur. Dans les extraits suivants de l'état du 
sous-comité, le congrès a averti l'industrie qui si 
art de l'auto-portrait-regulation ne s'avérait pas pertinent, d'"autres moyens" 
s'avérerait pour protéger des enfants. Le code, raffiné en 
1971 et 1989, demeure un instrument de normalisation pour des membres 
d'association.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os líderes religiosos, os grupos civic, os 
educadores, a imprensa, e os oficiais de governo exprimiram o 
interesse desde 1ø os efeitos deleterious supostos do século excesso
em crianças da cultura popular, das novelas de moeda de dez centavos 
e dos retratos de movimento aos livros comic, e à televisão. 
Os livros comic do excesso da ansiedade cresceram como o crime 
do fiction da polpa e o genre do horror desenvolvidos no fim da 
segunda guerra mundial. Em 1948, o psicólogo Fredric Wertham 
advogou a proibição de livros comic às crianças sob a idade de 16,
reivindicando que todas as crianças que delinquent estudou as tinham 
lido. Embora a organização de comércio da indústria 
planejasse um código que ano para regular o índice, only um terço 
dos publishers lhe subscreveram. Durante poucos anos seguintes 
muitos estados debatidos, mas não adotaram, as contas para proibir ou
regular livros comic, na parte por causa de uma decisão da corte 1948
suprema que virasse um statute de estado que proíbe a venda ou a 
distribuição da literatura do crime. Depois que a subcomissão
do senate no delinquency juvenile conduziu hearings em livros comic em
1954, a indústria deu forma associação comercial novo e formulou um
índice novo do self-censor do código. O símbolo do código 
apareceu subseqüentemente em livros comic aprovados, curtailing o 
crime e o genre do horror. Nos seguintes excerpts do relatório 
da subcomissão, o congress advertiu a indústria que se o 
self-regulation não provasse ser eficaz, "outros maneiras e meios" 
seria encontrada para proteger crianças. O código, refinado em
1971 e em 1989, remanesce um instrumento regulatory para membros da 
associação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I capi religiosi, i gruppi civici, gli 
educatori, la pressa ed i funzionari di governo hanno espresso la 
preoccupazione diciannovesima dagli effetti deleteri supposti di 
secolo eccedenza sui bambini di coltura popolare, dai romanzi di 
moneta da dieci centesimi di dollaro e dal cinema ai libri comic ed 
alla televisione. I libri comic dell'eccedenza di ansia si sono 
sviluppati come il genere di crimine e di orrore di romanzo 
della polpa sviluppato alla conclusione della seconda guerra mondiale.
In 1948, lo psicologo Fredric Wertham ha sostenuto la 
proibizione dei libri comic ai bambini sotto l'età di 16, sostenente 
che tutti i bambini che delinquenziali ha studiato li avevano letti. 
Anche se l'organizzazione commerciale dell'industria ha 
inventato un codice che anno per regolare il soddisfare, solo un terzo
degli editori si è abbonato ad esso. Durante i prossimi anni 
molti dichiarano dibattuto, ma non hanno adottato, fatture per 
vietare o regolare i libri comic, in parte a causa di una decisione 
della Corte suprema 1948 che ha capovolto uno statuto di dichiarare 
che vieta la vendita o la distribuzione della letteratura di crimine. 
Dopo che il sottocomitato del senato sulla delinquenza giovanile
conduca le udienze sui libri comic in 1954, l'industria ha formato una
nuova associazione commerciale ed ha formulato un nuovo soddisfare del
auto-censore di codice. Il simbolo di codice successivamente è 
comparso sui libri comic approvati, accorciando il genere di 
orrore e di crimine. Nei seguenti brani dalla relazione del 
sottocomitato, il congresso ha avvertito l'industria che se 
l'autoregolazione non risultasse essere efficace, "altri mezzi" 
sarebbe trovata per proteggere i bambini. Il codice, raffinato 
in 1971 ed in 1989, rimane uno strumento regolatore per i membri di 
associazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι θρησκευτικοί ηγέτες, οι πολιτικές ομάδες, οι 
εκπαιδευτικοί, ο Τύπος, και οι κυβερνητικοί ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι 
έχουν εκφράσει την ανησυχία από το 19$ο αιώνα πέρα από τα 
υποτιθέμενα επιβλαβή αποτελέσματα στα παιδιά του δημοφιλούς 
πολιτισμού, από τα μυθιστορήματα δεκαρών και τις ταινίες στα 
κωμικά βιβλία, και την τηλεόραση. Η ανησυχία πέρα από τα 
κωμικά βιβλία αυξήθηκε ως ύφος εγκλήματος και φρίκης 
μυθιστοριογραφίας πολτού που αναπτύχθηκε στο τέλος του παγκόσμιου
πολέμου ΙΙ. Το 1948, ο ψυχολόγος Fredric Wertham 
υποστήριξε την απαγόρευση των κωμικών βιβλίων στα παιδιά κάτω 
από την ηλικία 16, υποστηρίζοντας ότι όλα τα εγκληματικά 
παιδιά που μελέτησε τα είχαν διαβάσει. Αν και η εμπορική 
οργάνωση της βιομηχανίας επινόησε έναν κώδικα εκείνο το έτος 
για να ρυθμίσει το περιεχόμενο, μόνο το ένα τρίτο των εκδοτών 
προσυπέγραψε σε το. Κατά τη διάρκεια των επόμενων μερικών 
ετών πολλά κράτη συζήτησαν, αλλά δεν υιοθέτησαν, λογαριασμοί 
για να απαγορεύσουν ή να ρυθμίσουν τα κωμικά βιβλία, εν μέρει 
λόγω μιας απόφασης ανώτατου δικαστηρίου του 1948 που ανέτρεψε 
ένα κρατικό καταστατικό απαγορεύοντας την πώληση ή τη διανομή 
της λογοτεχνίας εγκλήματος. Αφότου διεύθυνε η υποεπιτροπή 
Συγκλήτου στη νεανική εγκληματικότητα τις ακροάσεις στα κωμικά 
βιβλία το 1954, η βιομηχανία διαμόρφωσε μια νέα εμπορική 
ένωση και διατύπωσε μια νέα περιεκτικότητα σε μόνος-λογοκριτές 
κώδικα. Το σύμβολο κώδικα εμφανίστηκε στη συνέχεια στα 
εγκεκριμένα κωμικά βιβλία, περιορίζοντας το ύφος εγκλήματος και 
φρίκης. Στα ακόλουθα αποσπάσματα από την έκθεση της 
υποεπιτροπής, το συνέδριο προειδοποίησε τη βιομηχανία ότι εάν η 
αυτορύθμιση δεν αποδείχθηκε αποτελεσματική, "άλλα μέσα" θα 
βρίσκονταν για να προστατεύουν τα παιδιά. Ο κώδικας, που 
καθαρίζεται το 1971 και το 1989, παραμένει ένα ρυθμιστικό 
όργανο για τα μέλη ένωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los arranques de cinta religiosos, los grupos 
cívicos, los educadores, la prensa, y los oficiales del gobierno han 
expresado la preocupación desde diecinueveavo los efectos deletéreos
supuestos del siglo excedente sobre niños de la cultura popular, de 
las novelas de moneda de diez centavos y de las películas a los 
libros cómicos, y a la televisión. Los libros cómicos del 
excedente de la ansiedad crecieron como el género del crimen y del
horror de la ficción de la pulpa desarrollado en el final de la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial. En 1948, el psicólogo Fredric Wertham 
abogó la prohibición de libros cómicos a los niños bajo edad de 
16, demandando que todos los niños delincuentes que él estudió los 
habían leído. Aunque la organización comercial de la 
industria ideó un código que año para regular el contenido, sólo 
una mitad de los editores suscribió a él. Durante los años 
próximos muchos estados discutidos, pero no adoptaron, las cuentas 
para prohibir o para regular los libros cómicos, en parte debido a 
una decisión del Tribunal Supremo 1948 que volcó un estatuto de 
estado que prohibía la venta o la distribución de la literatura del 
crimen. Después de que el subcomité del senado en delincuencia
juvenil condujera audiencias en los libros cómicos en 1954, la 
industria formó una nueva asociación comercial y formuló un nuevo 
contenido del uno mismo-censor del código. El símbolo del 
código apareció posteriormente en los libros cómicos aprobados, 
acortando el género del crimen y del horror. En los 
extractos siguientes del informe del subcomité, el congreso advirtió
la industria que si la autoregulación no demostrara ser eficaz, 
"otros medios" sería encontrada para proteger a niños. El 
código, refinado en 1971 y 1989, sigue siendo un instrumento 
regulador para los miembros de la asociación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108662</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/violent-death-in-every-form-imaginable-a-senate-committee-report-assesses-crime-and-horror-comic-books</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
