<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104318</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104318</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086052</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Dam Hetch Hetchy!": John Muir Contests the Hetch-Hetchy Dam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Verdammung Hetch Hetchy!": John Muir 
wetteifert die Hetch-Hetchy Verdammung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Barrage Hetch Hetchy!" : John Muir conteste
le barrage de Hetch-Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Represa Hetch Hetchy!": John Muir contesta 
a represa de Hetch-Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Diga Hetch Hetchy!": John Muir contesta la 
diga di Hetch-Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Φράγμα Hetch Hetchy!": Θ*Ιοχν Muir 
Contests το φράγμα χετθχ- Hetchy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Presa Hetch Hetchy!": Juan Muir disputa la 
presa de Hetch-Hetchy</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Progressive Era's most controversial environmental issue was the 1908-1913 struggle over federal government approval for building the Hetch Hetchy dam in a remote corner of federally-owned land in California's Yosemite National Park. The city of San Francisco, rebuilding after the devastating 1906 earthquake, believed the dam was necessary to meet its burgeoning needs for reliable supplies of water and electricity. At Congressional hearings on Hetch Hetchy held in 1913, supporters of the plan like Gifford Pinchot, the first Chief Forester of the United States and a noted environmentalist, argued that conservation of natural resources was best achieved through management of the wilderness. Preservationist and Sierra Club founder John Muir did not testify before Congress, but he argued against the Hetch Hetchy plan in this excerpt from his 1912 book,  The Yosemite . In the end Congress chose management over aesthetics, voting 43-25 (with 29 abstentions) to allow the Hetch Hetchy dam on federal land.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die progressiven umstrittenste Klimaausgabe der 
Ära war die Bundesregierungzustimmung des Überschusses des Kampfes 
1908-1913 für das Aufbauen der Hetch Hetchy Verdammung in einer 
Remoteecke des Bundes-besessenen Landes in Yosemite Nationalpark 
Kaliforniens. Die Stadt von San Francisco, umbauend nach dem 
VerwüstenErdbeben 1906, glaubte, daß die Verdammung notwendig war, 
um seine sprießenden Bedürfnisse am zuverlässigen Zubehör Wasser 
und Elektrizität zu erfüllen. An den Kongreßhörfähigkeiten 
auf Hetch Hetchy, das 1913 angehalten wird, mögen Verfechter des 
Planes Gifford Pinchot, der erste Hauptförster der Vereinigten 
Staaten und einen beachteten Ökologen, argumentiert, daß Erhaltung 
der Naturresourcen gut durch Management der Wildnis erzielt wurde. 
Preservationist und Sierra Vereingründer John Muir bezeugten 
nicht vor Kongreß, aber er argumentierte gegen den Hetch Hetchy Plan 
in diesem Excerpt von seinem 1912 Buch, das Yosemite. Im Ende 
wählte wählte der Kongreß Management über der Ästhetik und 43-25 
(mit 29 Enthaltung) um die Hetch Hetchy Verdammung auf Bundesland zu 
erlauben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'issue environnementale la plus controversée de 
l'ère progressive était l'approbation de gouvernement fédéral 
d'excédent de la lutte 1908-1913 pour construire le barrage de Hetch 
Hetchy dans un coin à distance de terre fédéral-possédée en parc 
national de Yosemite de la Californie. La ville de San 
Francisco, reconstruisant après le tremblement de terre 1906 de 
dévaster, a cru que le barrage était nécessaire pour satisfaire ses
besoins bourgeonnants d'approvisionnements fiables en eau et 
électricité. Aux auditions congressionnelles sur Hetch Hetchy 
tenu en 1913, les défenseurs du plan aiment Gifford Pinchot, le 
premier forestier en chef des Etats-Unis et un écologiste 
remarquable, argués du fait que l'économie des ressources naturelles
mieux a été réalisée par la gestion du désert. 
Preservationist et sierra fondateur John Muir de club n'ont pas 
témoigné devant le congrès, mais il a discuté contre le plan de 
Hetch Hetchy dans cet extrait de son 1912 livre, le Yosemite. À
la fin le congrès a choisi la gestion au-dessus de l'esthétique, 
votant 43-25 (avec 29 abstentions) pour permettre le barrage de Hetch 
Hetchy sur la terre fédérale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A edição ambiental a mais controversa da era 
progressiva era a aprovaçã0 do governo federal do excesso do 
esforço 1908-1913 para construir a represa de Hetch Hetchy em um 
canto remoto da terra federal-possuída no parque nacional de Yosemite
de Califórnia. A cidade de San Francisco, reconstruindo após o
terremoto 1906 devastating, acreditou que a represa era necessária 
para se encontrar com suas necessidades burgeoning para fontes de 
confiança da água e da eletricidade. Em hearings 
congressionais em Hetch Hetchy prendido em 1913, os supporters da 
planta gostam de Gifford Pinchot, primeiro forester principal dos 
estados unidos e um ecólogo notável, discutidos que o conservation 
de recursos naturais estêve conseguido melhor através da gerência 
da região selvagem. Preservationist e o sierra founder John 
Muir do clube não testify antes do congress, mas discutiu de encontro
à planta de Hetch Hetchy neste excerpt de seu 1912 livro, o Yosemite.
Na extremidade o congress escolheu a gerência sobre o 
aesthetics, votando 43-25 (com 29 abstentions) para permitir a represa
de Hetch Hetchy na terra federal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'edizione ambientale più discutibile dell'era 
progressiva era l'approvazione di governo federale dell'eccedenza di 
lotta 1908-1913 per la costruzione della diga di Hetch Hetchy in un 
angolo a distanza di terra federale-posseduta nel parco nazionale di 
Yosemite della California. La città di San Francisco, 
ricostruente dopo il terremoto 1906 di devastazione, ha creduto che la
diga fosse necessaria da soddisfare le relative esigenze burgeoning 
dei rifornimenti certi di acqua e di elettricità. Alle udienze 
congressuali su Hetch Hetchy tenuto in 1913, i sostenitori del 
programma gradiscono Gifford Pinchot, il primo silvicoltore principale
del unito Dichiara e un ecologo celebre, sostenuto che la 
conservazione delle risorse naturali è stata realizzata il più bene 
attraverso la gestione della selva. Preservationist e la sierra 
fondatore John Muir del randello non hanno testimoniato prima del 
congresso, ma ha parlato contro il programma di Hetch Hetchy in questo
brano dal suo 1912 libro, il Yosemite. Alla fine il congresso ha
scelto la gestione sopra l'estetica, votante 43-25 (con 29 astensioni)
per permettere la diga di Hetch Hetchy su terra federale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πιό αμφισβητούμενο περιβαλλοντικό ζήτημα της 
προοδευτικής εποχής ήταν η προσπάθεια του 1908-1913 πέρα από 
την έγκριση ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης για την οικοδόμηση του 
φράγματος Hetch Hetchy σε μια απομακρυσμένη γωνία του 
ομοσπονδιακά-κύριου εδάφους στο εθνικό πάρκο Yosemite 
Καλιφόρνιας. Η πόλη του Σαν Φρανσίσκο, που επανοικοδομεί 
μετά από τον καταστρεπτικό σεισμό του 1906, εθεώρησε ότι το 
φράγμα ήταν απαραίτητο για να ικανοποιήσει τις φυτρώνοντας 
ανάγκες του για τις αξιόπιστες προμήθειες της ύδρευσης και της 
ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας. Στις του Κογκρέσου ακροάσεις σε 
Hetch Hetchy που πραγματοποιήθηκαν το 1913, οι υποστηρικτές
του σχεδίου όπως Gifford Pinchot, του πρώτου Προϊστάμενος 
δασοφύλακα των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών και ενός σημειωμένου 
οικολόγου, υποστήριξαν ότι η συντήρηση των φυσικών στοιχείων 
συμπεριφοράς επιτεύχθηκε καλύτερα μέσω διαχείριση της 
αγριότητας. Το Preservationist και η οροσειρά ιδρυτής 
John Muir λεσχών δεν πιστοποίησαν πριν από το συνέδριο, 
αλλά μίλησε ενάντια στο σχέδιο Hetch Hetchy σε αυτό το 
απόσπασμα από το βιβλίο του 1912 του, το Yosemite. Στο 
τέλος το συνέδριο επέλεξε τη διαχείριση πέρα από την αισθητική,
ψηφίζοντας 43-25 (με 29 αποχές) για να επιτρέψει το φράγμα 
Hetch Hetchy στο ομοσπονδιακό έδαφος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La edición ambiental más polémica de la era 
progresiva era la aprobación del gobierno federal del excedente de la
lucha 1908-1913 para construir la presa de Hetch Hetchy en una esquina
alejada de la pista federal-posei'da en el parque nacional de Yosemite
de California. La ciudad de San Francisco, reconstruyendo 
después del terremoto 1906 de la devastación, creyó que la presa 
era necesaria resolver sus necesidades burgeoning de fuentes 
confiables de agua y de electricidad. En las audiencias del 
congreso en Hetch Hetchy sostenido en 1913, los partidarios del plan 
tienen gusto de Gifford Pinchot, el primer principal silvicultor de 
los Estados Unidos y ecologista conocido, discutidos que la 
conservación de recursos naturales fue alcanzada lo más mejor 
posible a través de la gerencia del yermo. Preservationist y el
sierra fundador Juan Muir del club no atestiguaron antes de congreso, 
sino que él discutió contra el plan de Hetch Hetchy en este extracto
de su 1912 libro, el Yosemite. En extremo el congreso eligió a 
gerencia sobre la estética, votando 43-25 (con 29 abstenciones) para 
permitir la presa de Hetch Hetchy en pista federal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086052</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104318</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dam-hetch-hetchy-john-muir-contests-the-hetch-hetchy-dam</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
