<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104837</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104837</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Food riot, 1917.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nahrungsmittelaufstand, 1917.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Émeute de nourriture, 1917.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Motim do alimento, 1917.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tumulto dell'alimento, 1917.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ταραχή τροφίμων, 1917.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alboroto del alimento, 1917.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War I, wartime inflation severely taxed the limited budgets of working-class families. Although wages also rose during the war, they could not keep up with prices. On February 20, 1917, after confronting pushcart peddlers who were charging exorbitant rates for necessities, thousands of women marched to New York's City Hall to demand relief. The food riot" precipitated a boycott campaign that eventually forced pushcart prices down. Women in Boston and Philadelphia took similar action."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Ersten Weltkrieges besteuerte Krieginflation 
streng die begrenzten Etats der Arbeiterklassefamilien. Obgleich
Löhne auch während des Krieges stiegen, konnten sie nicht mit 
Preisen oben halten. An Februar 20, 1917, nach konfrontierenden 
pushcart Hausierern, die übertriebene Kinetik für Notwendigkeiten 
aufluden, Tausenden Frauen grenzte zu Hall New York City, um 
Entlastung zu verlangen. Der Nahrungsmittelaufstand "fällte 
eine Boykottkampagne aus, die schließlich pushcart Preise unten 
erzwang. Frauen in Boston und in Philadelphia ergriffen 
ähnliche Maßnahmen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale, l'inflation de temps
de guerre a sévèrement imposé les budgets limités des familles de 
classe ouvrier. Bien que les salaires aient également monté 
pendant la guerre, ils ne pourraient pas suivre des prix. 
20 février 1917, après les marchands ambulants de 
confrontation de chariot qui chargeaient des cadences exorbitantes
pour des nécessités, milliers de femmes a marché à Hall de New 
York City pour exiger le soulagement. L'émeute de nourriture "a
précipité une campagne de boycott qui par la suite a forcé des prix
de chariot vers le bas. Les femmes à Boston et à 
Philadelphie ont pris une mesure semblable."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o world.war.i, a inflação do wartime taxed 
severamente os orçamentos limitados de famílias do working-class. 
Embora os salários se levantassem também durante a guerra, 
não poderiam proseguir com preços. Fevereiro em 20, 1917, 
após os peddlers confrontando que carregavam taxas exorbitant para 
necessidades, milhares do pushcart das mulheres marchou a Salão de 
New York City para exijir o relevo. O motim do alimento 
"precipitated uma campanha do boycott que forçasse eventualmente 
preços do pushcart para baixo. As mulheres em Boston e em 
Filadélfia fizeram exame da ação similar."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il world.war.i, l'inflazione di wartime ha tassato
severamente i preventivi limitati delle famiglie della classe operaia.
Anche se gli stipendi egualmente sono aumentato durante la 
guerra, non potrebbero continuare con i prezzi. Il 20 febbraio 
1917, dopo i peddlers di confronto che stavano caricando i tassi 
exorbitant per le necessità, migliaia del pushcart delle donne ha 
marciato a Corridoio de New York City per richiedere il rilievo. 
Il tumulto dell'alimento "ha precipitato una campagna di 
boicottaggio che finalmente ha forzato i prezzi del pushcart giù. 
Le donne a Boston e Filadelfia hanno intrapreso l'azione 
simile."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι, ο εν καιρώ
πολέμου πληθωρισμός φορολόγησε σοβαρά τους περιορισμένους 
προϋπολογισμούς των οικογενειών εργατικών τάξεων. Αν και οι
αμοιβές αυξήθηκαν επίσης κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου, δεν θα 
μπορούσαν να συμβαδίσουν με τις τιμές. Στις 20 Φεβρουαρίου 
..1917, μετά από να αντιμετωπίσουν τους γυρολόγους χειραμαξών 
που χρέωναν τα υπερβολικά ποσοστά για τις ανάγκες, χιλιάδες 
γυναίκες βάδισαν στην αίθουσα πόλεων της Νέας Υόρκης στην 
ανακούφιση απαίτησης. Η ταραχή τροφίμων "κατακρήμνισε μια 
εκστρατεία μποϊκοταρίσματος που ανάγκασε τελικά τις τιμές 
χειραμαξών κάτω. Οι γυναίκες στη Βοστώνη και τη Φιλαδέλφεια
έλαβαν παρόμοια μέτρα."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante Primera Guerra Mundial, la inflación del tiempo 
de guerra gravó seriamente los presupuestos limitados de las familias
de la clase obrera. Aunque los salarios también se levantaron 
durante la guerra, no podrían continuar con precios. De febrero
el 20 de 1917, después de los vendedores ambulantes de enfrentamiento
que cargaban las tarifas desorbitadas para las necesidades, millares 
del pushcart de mujeres marchó a Pasillo de New York City para exigir
la relevación. El alboroto del alimento "precipitó una 
campaña del boicoteo que forzó eventual precios del pushcart abajo. 
Las mujeres en Boston y Philadelphia tomaron la acción 
similar."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086163</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104837</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/food-riot-1917</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
