<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105697</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105697</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206162</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τεχνολογία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">reports on how a car company is experimenting with nanotechnology in the quest for environmentally friendly vehicles, how a museum exhibit (created by an artist and a scientist) helps get the word out about the implications of nanotechnology for health care and other fields, and how GPS chips in some cell phones let businesses track delivery drivers and parents keep track of kids.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reports über, wie eine Autofirma mit 
nanotechnology in der Suche nach umweltsmäßig freundlichen Trägern 
experimentiert, wie Hilfen einer Museum Ausstellung (erstellt von 
einem Künstler und von einem Wissenschaftler) das Wort aus über den 
Implikationen von nanotechnology für Gesundheitspflege erhalten und 
anderes fängt auf, und wie GPS Chips in einigen Zelle 
Telefonen Geschäfte aufspüren lassen, verfolgen Anlieferung Treiber 
und Eltern Zicklein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les états sur la façon dont une compagnie de 
voiture expérimente avec le nanotechnology à la recherche pour les 
véhicules dans l'environnement amicaux, comment les aides d'un objet 
exposé de musée (créé par un artiste et un scientifique) 
obtiennent le mot hors de environ les implications du nanotechnology 
pour la santé et d'autres zones, et comment les puces de GPS dans des
quelques téléphones de cellules laissent des entreprises dépistent 
des gestionnaires de la livraison et des parents maintiennent des 
gosses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os relatórios em como uma companhia de carro 
está experimentando com o nanotechnology no quest para veículos 
ambiental amigáveis, como as ajudas de uma exibição do museu 
(criada por um artista e por um cientista) começam a palavra para 
fora sobre das implicações do nanotechnology para o cuidado de 
saúde e os outros campos, e como as microplaquetas do GPS em alguns 
telefones da pilha deixam negócios seguem excitadores da entrega e 
pais mantêm-se a par de miúdos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i rapporti su come un'azienda di automobile sta 
sperimentando con il nanotechnology nella ricerca per i veicoli in 
condizioni ambientali amichevoli, come gli aiuti dell'esposizione del 
museo (creata da un artista e da uno scienziato) ottengono la parola 
verso l'esterno circa le implicazioni del nanotechnology per sanità 
ed altri campi e come i circuiti integrati di GPS in alcuni telefoni 
delle cellule lasciano i commerci rintracciano i driver di consegna ed
i genitori si tengono al corrente dei capretti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εκθέσεις σχετικά με τον τρόπο με τον οποίο μια 
επιχείρηση αυτοκινήτων πειραματίζεται με τη νανοτεχνολογία στην 
αναζήτηση για τα φιλικά προς το περιβάλλον οχήματα, πώς οι 
οδηγίες μουσείων εκθεμάτων (που δημιουργούνται από έναν 
καλλιτέχνη και έναν επιστήμονα) βγαίνουν τη λέξη για τις 
επιπτώσεις της νανοτεχνολογίας για την υγειονομική περίθαλψη και 
άλλα πεδία, και πώς τα τσιπ ΠΣΤ σε μερικά τηλέφωνα κυττάρων 
αφήνουν τις επιχειρήσεις τους οδηγούς να ακολουθήσουν την 
παράδοση και οι γονείς παρακολουθούν των κατσικιών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los informes sobre cómo una compañía de coche 
está experimentando con nanotechnology en la búsqueda para los 
vehículos ambientalmente cómodos, cómo las ayudas de un objeto 
expuesto del museo (creado por un artista y un científico) consiguen 
la palabra fuera sobre de las implicaciones del nanotechnology para el
cuidado médico y otros campos, y cómo las virutas del GPS en algunos
teléfonos de la célula dejan negocios siguen a programas pilotos de 
la salida y a padres no pierden de vista a cabritos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206162</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105697</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
