<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104201</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087629</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Education Network Australia (EdNA)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausbildung Netz Australien (EdNA)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Réseau Australie (EdNA) D'Éducation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rede Austrália Da Instrução (EdNA)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rete Australia (EdNA) Di Formazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δίκτυο Αυστραλία εκπαίδευσης (EdNA)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Red Australia (EdNA) De la Educación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">EdNA Online is a service that aims to support and promote the benefits of the Internet for learning, education and training in Australia. It is organised around Australian curriculum, its tools are free to Australian educators, and it is funded by the bodies responsible for education provision in Australia - all Australian governments.</string>
          </description>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">Australia</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">EdNA online ist ein Service, der darauf abzielt zu
unterstützen und fördert den Nutzen des Internets für das Lernen, 
Ausbildung und die Ausbildung in Australien. Es wird um 
australischen Lehrplan organisiert, sind seine Hilfsmittel zu den 
australischen Erziehern frei, und er wird von den Körpern finanziert,
die für Ausbildung Bestimmung in Australien - alle australischen 
Regierungen verantwortlich sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">EdNA en ligne est un service qui vise à supporter
et favorise les avantages de l'Internet pour l'étude, l'éducation et
former en Australie. Il est organisé autour du programme 
d'études australien, ses outils sont libres aux éducateurs 
australiens, et il est placé par les corps responsables de la 
disposition d'éducation en Australie - tous les gouvernements 
australiens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">EdNA em linha é um serviço que aponte suportar e
promove os benefícios do Internet para a aprendizagem, a instrução 
e treinar em Austrália. É organizado em torno do curriculum 
australian, suas ferramentas estão livres aos educadores australian, 
e é financiado pelos corpos responsáveis para a provisão da 
instrução em Austrália - todos os governos australian.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">EdNA in linea è un servizio che mira a sostenere 
e promuove i benefici del Internet per imparare, istruzione e la 
formazione in Australia. È organizzato intorno al programma di 
studi australiano, i relativi strumenti sono liberi agli educatori 
australiani ed è costituito un fondo per dagli enti responsabili 
della misura di formazione in Australia - tutti i governi australiani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">EdNA είναι on-line υπηρεσία που στοχεύει να 
υποστηρίξει και να προωθήσει τα οφέλη του Διαδικτύου για την 
εκμάθηση, την εκπαίδευση και την κατάρτιση στην Αυστραλία. 
Οργανώνεται γύρω από το αυστραλιανό πρόγραμμα σπουδών, τα 
εργαλεία του είναι ελεύθερα στους αυστραλιανούς εκπαιδευτικούς, 
και χρηματοδοτείται από τους οργανισμούς αρμόδιους για την παροχή
εκπαίδευσης στην Αυστραλία - όλες οι αυστραλιανές κυβερνήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">EdNA en línea es un servicio que apunta utilizar 
y promueve las ventajas del Internet para aprender, la educación y 
entrenar en Australia. Se ordena alrededor de plan de estudios 
australiano, sus herramientas están libres a los educadores 
australianos, y es financiado por los cuerpos responsables de la 
disposición de la educación en Australia - todos los gobiernos 
australianos.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087629</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104201</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/education-network-australia-edna</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
