<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107859</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107859</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209861</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Angle measure - degrees.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Winkelmaß - Grad.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mesure d'angle - degrés.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Medida do ângulo - graus.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Misura di angolo - gradi.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέτρο γωνίας - βαθμοί.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Medida del ángulo - grados.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet that acts as a 'digital manipulative' for explaining angles measured in degrees. The applet has an angle formed from two segment that can be dragged around in a circle. The angle measure is shown against a 'clock face' calibrated in degrees. The measures can be turned off for class angle estimation discussions. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet, der als ein ' digitales 
Manipulations ' für das Erklären von von Winkeln dient, maß in den 
Grad. Der applet hat einen Winkel, der von Segment zwei gebildet
wird, das in einem Kreis herum geschleppt werden kann. Das 
Winkelmaß wird gegen ein ' Taktgebergesicht gezeigt ', das in den 
Grad kalibriert wird. Die Masse können für Kategorie 
Winkel-Schätzungdiskussionen abgestellt werden. Applet kann zum
vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif qui agit en tant que 'de manipulation
digital 'pour expliquer des angles a mesuré en degrés. 
L'applet a un angle formé du segment deux qui peut être 
traîné autour en cercle. La mesure d'angle est montrée contre
un 'visage d'horloge 'calibré dans les degrés. Les mesures 
peuvent être arrêtées pour des discussions d'évaluation d'angle de
classe. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran
pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo que agisse como ' um manipulativo 
digital ' para explicar ângulos mediu nos graus. O applet tem 
um ângulo dado forma do segmento dois que pode ser arrastado ao redor
em um círculo. A medida do ângulo é mostrada de encontro ' a 
uma face do relógio ' calibrada nos graus. As medidas podem ser
desligadas para discussões do estimation do ângulo da classe. 
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo che funge da 'manipolativo digitale 
'per spiegare gli angoli ha misurato nei gradi. Il applet ha un 
angolo formato dal segmento due che può essere trascinato intorno in 
un cerchio. La misura di angolo è indicata contro 'una faccia 
di orologio 'calibrata nei gradi. Le misure possono essere 
spente per le discussioni di valutazione di angolo del codice 
categoria. Il applet può essere ingrandito al formato di 
schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore dell'aula. La 
post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può accederle ancora da tutto 
il web browser nel paese o nella libreria senza l'inizio attività 
richiesto. Questa risorsa è un componente del progetto 
interattivo del manuale della geometria di riferimento aperto di per 
la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet που ενεργεί ως "ψηφιακός 
επεμβατικόσ" για την εξήγηση των γωνιών που μετριούνται στους 
βαθμούς. Το applet διαμορφώνει μια γωνία από δύο τέμνει
που μπορούν να σέρθούν γύρω σε έναν κύκλο. Το μέτρο 
γωνίας εμφανίζεται ενάντια σε ένα "πρόσωπο ρολογιών" που 
βαθμολογείται στους βαθμούς. Τα μέτρα μπορούν να κλειθούν 
για τις συζητήσεις εκτίμησης γωνίας κλάσης. Το Applet 
μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με 
έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo que actúa como ' manipulante 
digital ' para explicar ángulos midió grados. El applet tiene 
un ángulo formado a partir del segmento el dos que se puede arrastrar
alrededor en un círculo. La medida del ángulo se muestra 
contra una ' cara de reloj ' calibrada en grados. Las medidas se
pueden dar vuelta apagado para las discusiones de la valoración del 
ángulo de la clase. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de 
la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase.
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209861</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107859</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/angle-measure-degrees</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
