<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108052</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108052</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087299</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Friend of Their Minds: Capitalizing on the Oral Tradition of My African American Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Freund ihres Verstandes: Großschreibung
auf der Mundtradition meiner afrikanischen amerikanischen 
Kursteilnehmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un ami de leurs esprits : Profit de la 
tradition orale de mes étudiants américains africains</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um amigo de suas mentes: Capitalizing na 
tradição oral de meus estudantes americanos africanos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un amico delle loro menti: Capitalizzando 
sulla tradizione orale dei miei allievi americani africani</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας φίλος των μυαλών τους: Κεφαλαιοποίηση στην 
προφορική παράδοση αφρικανικών αμερικανικών σπουδαστών μου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un amigo de sus mentes: Capitalización en 
la tradición oral de mis estudiantes americanos africanos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Yvonne Divans Hutchinson is a National Board certified teacher who has focused for many years on developing strategies to engage all her students in substantive discussions of literary texts and the issues those texts raise for their own lives. In this approach, she builds on the oral traditions of her students African-American and Latino cultures and seeks to support the development of their literacy skills through high standards, explicit expectations, and rigorous literature experiences. Her online 'class anatomy' (a documentation and analysis of one instructional period) juxtaposes video clips with commentary and samples of classroom documents. In the video clips, Hutchinson reflects on her expectations for the class, a student orally presents the 'class scribe' notes from the previous day, the students engage in small group and large group discussion about a racially charged literary selection that had been assigned the night before, and after the class, four students reflect on their experiences in Hutchinson's classroom, and how her rigorous approach and emphasis on dialogue and diversity prepares them for other academic work.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Yvonne Liegesofas Hutchinson ist ein nationales 
Brett zugelassener Lehrer, der für viele Jahre auf sich entwickelnde 
Strategien konzentriert hat, um sich alle ihre Kursteilnehmer in den 
substantivischen Diskussionen über literarische Texte zu engagieren 
und die Ausgaben Erhöhung jener Texte für ihre Selbst lebt. In
dieser Annäherung baut sie auf den Mundtraditionen ihrer 
Kursteilnehmer Afrikanisch-Amerikanische und Latino Kulturen auf und 
sucht, die Entwicklung ihrer Bildungsgradfähigkeiten durch hohe 
Standards, ausdrückliche Erwartungen und rigorose 
Literaturerfahrungen zu unterstützen. Ihre Online' Kategorie 
Anatomie ' (Unterlagen und eine Analyse von einer anweisenden Periode)
hält videoclips mit Kommentar und Proben der Klassenzimmerdokumente 
gegeneinander. In den videoclips reflektiert sich Hutchinson auf
ihren Erwartungen für die Kategorie, stellt ein Kursteilnehmer 
mündlich die ' Kategorie Schreiber' Anmerkungen vom Vorabend dar, 
engagieren sich die Kursteilnehmer in der kleinen Gruppe und in der 
großen Gruppe Diskussion über eine rassisch belastete literarische 
Auswahl, die die Nacht zugewiesen worden war, bevor und nach der 
Kategorie, vier Kursteilnehmer auf ihren Erfahrungen im Klassenzimmer 
Hutchinsons sich reflektieren, und wie ihre rigorose Annäherung und 
Hauptgewicht auf Dialog und Verschiedenartigkeit sie für andere 
akademische Arbeit vorbereitet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les divans Hutchinson de Yvonne est un professeur 
certifié par office national qui s'est concentré pendant beaucoup 
d'années sur des stratégies se développantes pour engager tous ses 
étudiants au cours des discussions substantives des textes 
littéraires et les issues augmenter des ces textes pour leurs propres
vit. Dans cette approche, elle construit sur les traditions 
orales de ses cultures d'Afro-Américain et de Latino d'étudiants 
et recherche à supporter le développement de leurs qualifications 
d'instruction par des niveaux élevés, des espérances explicites, et
des expériences rigoureuses de littérature. Son 'anatomie de 
classe 'en ligne (une documentation et une analyse d'une période 
d'instruction) juxtapose les clips visuels avec le commentaire et les 
échantillons de documents de salle de classe. Dans les clips 
visuels, Hutchinson réfléchit sur ses espérances pour la classe, un
étudiant présente oralement les notes 'de pointe à tracer de classe
'de la veille, les étudiants s'engagent dans le petit groupe et la 
grande discussion de groupe au sujet d'une sélection littéraire 
racial chargée qui avait été assignée la nuit avant que, et après
la classe, quatre étudiants réfléchissent sur leurs expériences de
la salle de classe de Hutchinson, et de la façon dont sa approche et 
emphase rigoureuses sur le dialogue et la diversité les prépare pour
l'autre travail d'universitaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os divans Hutchinson de Yvonne são placa nacional
um professor certificado que focalize por muitos anos em estratégias 
se tornando para acoplar todos seus estudantes em discussões 
substantivas de textos literários e as edições aumento daqueles 
textos para seus próprios vivam. Nesta aproximação, constrói
nas tradições orais de seus estudantes culturas Africano-Americanas 
e de Latino e procura suportar o desenvolvimento de suas habilidades 
do literacy com os padrões elevados, as expectativas explícitas, e 
as experiências rigorous da literatura. Seu ' anatomy em linha 
da classe ' (uma documentação e uma análise de um período 
instrutivo) juxtaposes os grampos video com commentary e as amostras 
de originais da sala de aula. Nos grampos video, Hutchinson 
reflete em suas expectativas para a classe, um estudante apresenta 
oral ' as notas do escrevente da classe ' do dia precedente, os 
estudantes acoplam no grupo pequeno e na discussão grande do grupo 
sobre uma seleção literária racial carregada que esteja atribuída 
a noite antes que, e após a classe, quatro estudantes refletam em 
suas experiências na sala de aula de Hutchinson, e como suas 
aproximação e ênfase rigorous no diálogo e na diversidade os 
preparam para o outro trabalho academic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I divans Hutchinson di Yvonne è un insegnante 
certificato Bordo nazionale che ha messo a fuoco per molti anni 
sulle strategie di sviluppo per agganciare tutti gli suoi allievi 
durante le discussioni sostanziali sui testi letterari e le edizioni 
l'aumento di quei testi per il loro propri vive. In questo 
metodo, costruisce sulle tradizioni orali dei suoi allievi colture di 
Latino ed Africano-Americane e cerca di sostenere lo sviluppo delle 
loro abilità di literacy con gli alti livelli, le aspettative 
esplicite e le esperienze rigorose della letteratura. La sua 
'anatomia del codice categoria 'in linea (una documentazione e 
un'analisi di un periodo didattico) juxtaposes le video clip con il 
commento ed i campioni dei documenti dell'aula. Nelle video 
clip, Hutchinson riflette sulle sue aspettative per il codice 
categoria, un allievo presenta oralmente 'le note dello scrivano del 
codice categoria 'dal giorno precedente, gli allievi si agganciano nel
piccolo gruppo e nella grande discussione del gruppo circa una 
selezione letteraria razziale caricata che era stata assegnata la 
notte prima che e dopo il codice categoria, quattro allievi riflettano
sulle loro esperienze di aula del Hutchinson e come il suoi metodo ed 
enfasi rigorosi sul dialogo e sulla diversità li prepara per l'altro 
lavoro accademico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Yvonne Divans Hutchinson είναι επικυρωμένος 
δάσκαλος εθνικών συμβουλίων που έχει εστιάσει για πολλά έτη 
στην ανάπτυξη των στρατηγικών για να συμμετέχει όλους τους 
σπουδαστές της στις ουσιαστικές συζητήσεις των λογοτεχνικών 
κειμένων και των ζητημάτων που εκείνα τα κείμενα προκύπτουν για 
τις ζωές τους. Σε αυτήν την προσέγγιση, στηρίζεται στις 
προφορικές παραδόσεις αφρικανικός-αμερικανικών και λατίνων 
πολιτισμών σπουδαστών της και επιδιώκει να υποστηρίξει την 
ανάπτυξη των δεξιοτήτων βασικής εκπαίδευσής τους μέσω των 
υψηλών προτύπων, των ρητών προσδοκιών, και της αυστηρής 
εμπειρίας λογοτεχνίας. Η σε απευθείας σύνδεση "ανατομία 
κλάσης τησ" (μια τεκμηρίωση και μια ανάλυση μιας εκπαιδευτικής 
περιόδου) αντιπαραβαεται τους τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες με τα σχόλια
και τα δείγματα των εγγράφων τάξεων. _ ο τηλεοπτικός 
συνδετήρας, Χuτθχηνσον απεικονίζω της προσδοκία για ο κλάση, ένας
σπουδαστής προφορικά παρουσιάζω ο "κλάση γραφέασ" σημείωση από 
ο προηγούμενος ημέρα, ο σπουδαστής συμμετ:έχω μικρός ομάδα και 
μεγάλος ομάδα συζήτηση για ένας ραθηαλλυ χρεώνω λογοτεχνικός 
επιλογή που έχω είμαι ανα:θέτω ο νύχτα πριν, και μετά από ο 
κλάση, τέσσερις σπουδαστής εξετάζω τους εμπειρία Χuτθχηνσον 
τάξη, και πώς της αυστηρός προσέγγιση και έμφαση παράθυρο και 
ποικιλομορφία προετοιμάζω αυτός για άλλος ακαδημαϊκός εργασία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los divans Hutchinson de Yvonne son un profesor 
certificado tarjeta nacional que se ha enfocado por muchos años en 
estrategias que se convertían para contratar a todos sus estudiantes 
a discusiones substantivas de textos literarios y viven las ediciones 
aumento de esos textos para sus el propios. En este 
acercamiento, ella construye en las tradiciones orales de sus 
estudiantes las culturas Africano-Americanas y de Latino e intenta 
utilizar el desarrollo de sus habilidades de la instrucción con 
mayores niveles, expectativas explícitas, y experiencias rigurosas de
la literatura. Su ' anatomía en línea de la clase ' (una 
documentación y un análisis de un período educacional) juxtaposes 
los clips video con comentario y las muestras de los documentos de la 
sala de clase. En los clips video, Hutchinson refleja en sus 
expectativas para la clase, un estudiante presenta oral ' las notas 
del escribano de la clase ' a partir del día anterior, los 
estudiantes enganchan a grupo pequeño y a la discusión grande del 
grupo sobre una selección literaria racial cargada que había sido 
asignada la noche antes de que, y después de la clase, cuatro 
estudiantes reflejen en sus experiencias en la sala de clase de 
Hutchinson, y cómo su acercamiento y énfasis rigurosos en diálogo y
diversidad los prepara para el otro trabajo académico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:YVONNE DIVANS HUTCHINSON
FN:YVONNE DIVANS HUTCHINSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087299</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108052</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-friend-of-their-minds-capitalizing-on-the-oral-tradition-of-my-african-american-students-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
