<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108696</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108696</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Managing Critical Resources at Craters of the Moon National Monument: A Curriculum for High School Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Handhabende kritische Betriebsmittel an den 
Kratern des Mond-nationalen Denkmales: Ein Lehrplan für High 
School Kursteilnehmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ressources critiques de gestion aux cratères du 
monument national de lune : Un programme d'études pour des 
étudiants de lycée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recursos críticos controlando em crateras do 
monumento nacional da lua: Um curriculum para estudantes da High
School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risorse critiche di gestione ai crateri del 
monumento nazionale della luna: Un programma di studi per gli 
allievi della High School</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαχείριση των κρίσιμων στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς στους 
κρατήρες του εθνικού μνημείου φεγγαριών: Ένα πρόγραμμα 
σπουδών για τους σπουδαστές γυμνασίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recursos críticos de manejo en los cráteres del 
monumento nacional de la luna: Un plan de estudios para los 
estudiantes de la High School secundaria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lesson ideas for learning about the geology, history, and ecology of this national park near Arco, Idaho. A high school unit on Managing Critical Resources at Craters of the Moon focuses on degradation of geologic features, water and air quality, and the balance of life of lava. Craters of the Moon National Park offers one of the best examples of basaltic volcanism in the world.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lektionideen für das Lernen über die 
Geologie, die Geschichte und die Ökologie dieses Nationalparks nahe 
Arco, Idaho zur Verfügung. Eine High School Maßeinheit auf dem
Handhaben der kritischen Betriebsmittel an den Kratern des Mondes 
konzentriert auf Verminderung der geologischen Merkmale, der Wasser- 
und Luftqualität und der Balance des Lebens von Lava. Krater 
des Mond-Nationalparks bietet eins der besten Beispiele des 
Basaltvulkanismus in der Welt an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des idées de leçon pour se renseigner 
sur la géologie, l'histoire, et l'écologie de ce parc national près
d'Arco, Idaho. Une unité de lycée sur contrôler les 
ressources critiques aux cratères de la lune se concentre sur la 
dégradation des dispositifs géologiques, la qualité de l'eau et 
d'air, et l'équilibre de la vie de la lave. Les cratères du 
parc national de lune offre un des meilleurs exemples du volcanisme 
basaltique dans le monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece idéias da lição aprendendo sobre a 
geologia, o history, e o ecology deste parque nacional perto de Arco, 
Idaho. Uma unidade da High School em controlar recursos 
críticos em crateras da lua focaliza na degradação de 
características geologic, qualidade da água e do ar, e o contrapeso 
da vida da lava. As crateras do parque nacional da lua oferecem 
um dos mais melhores exemplos do volcanism basaltic no mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le idee di lezione per imparare circa la 
geologia, la storia e l'ecologia di questo parco nazionale vicino a 
Arco, Idaho. Un'unità della High School sulla gestione delle 
risorse critiche ai crateri della luna mette a fuoco su degradazione 
delle caratteristiche geologiche, qualità dell'aria e dell'acqua e 
l'equilibrio di durata di lava. I crateri del parco nazionale 
della luna offre uno degli esempi migliori del volcanism basaltico nel
mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις ιδέες μαθήματος για την εκμάθηση για τη 
γεωλογία, την ιστορία, και την οικολογία αυτού του εθνικού 
πάρκου κοντά arco, Idaho. Μια μονάδα γυμνασίου στη 
διαχείριση των κρίσιμων στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς στους κρατήρες του
φεγγαριού εστιάζει στην υποβάθμιση των γεωλογικών χαρακτηριστικών
γνωρισμάτων, του ύδατος και της ατμοσφαιρικής ποιότητας, και της 
ισορροπίας της ζωής της λάβας. Οι κρατήρες του εθνικού 
πάρκου φεγγαριών προσφέρουν ενός από τα καλύτερα παραδείγματα 
βασαλτικό volcanism στον κόσμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a las ideas de la lección para 
aprender sobre la geología, la historia, y la ecología de este 
parque nacional cerca de Arco, Idaho. Una unidad de la High 
School secundaria en el manejo de recursos críticos en los cráteres 
de la luna se centra en la degradación de características 
geológicas, calidad del agua y del aire, y el equilibrio de la vida 
de la lava. Los cráteres del parque nacional de la luna ofrecen
uno de los mejores ejemplos del volcanismo basáltico en el mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108696</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/managing-critical-resources-at-craters-of-the-moon-national-monument-a-curriculum-for-high-school-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
