<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103455</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103455</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086793</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rosenfeld's Requiem: The Triangle Fire Victims in Verse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Requiem Rosenfelds: Die Dreieck-Feuer-Opfer 
im Vers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Requiem de Rosenfeld : Les victimes du feu 
de triangle dans le vers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Requiem De Rosenfeld: As vítimas do fogo do
triângulo no verso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Requiem Del Rosenfeld: Le vittime del fuoco 
del triangolo nel verse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Requiem Rosenfeld: Τα θύματα πυρός 
τριγώνων στο στίχο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Requiem De Rosenfeld: Las víctimas del 
fuego del triángulo en verso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On March 25, 1911, a fire broke out at the Triangle Shirtwaist company in New York City. Trapped by blocked exit doors and faulty fire escapes, more than 146 workers, mostly young immigrant women, perished in the flames or jumped ten stories to their deaths. One of the worst industrial fires in U.S. history, the Triangle fire became a galvanizing symbol of industrial capitalism's excesses and the pressing need for reform. In its aftermath, a coalition of middle-class reformers and working people secured passage of landmark occupational health and safety laws. For Jewish and Italian immigrant communities of the Lower East Side, the fire was especially tragic. Poet Morris Rosenfeld, known as the "poet laureate of the slum and the sweatshop," penned this memorial to the victims four days after the fire. The  Jewish Daily Forward  printed the poem down the full length of its front page.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An März 25, 1911, brach ein Feuer bei der Dreieck
Shirtwaist Firma in New York City aus. Eingeschlossen durch 
geblockte Ausgang Türen und fehlerhafte Feuerentweichen, mehr als 146
Arbeiter, meistens junge einwandernde Frauen, umgekommen in den 
Flammen oder 10 Geschichten zu ihren Todesfällen gesprungen. 
Eins der falschsten industriellen Feuer in der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Geschichte, das Dreieckfeuer wurde ein Galvanisierensymbol der
Überflüsse des industriellen Kapitalismus und das dringende 
Bedürfnis an der Verbesserung. In seiner Nachmahd sicherten 
eine Koalition der MittelklasseReformer und Arbeitsleute 
Durchgang berufliche Gesundheit und Sicherheit des Grenzsteins der 
Gesetze. Für die jüdischen und italienischen einwandernden 
Gemeinschaften der untereren Ostseite, war das Feuer besonders 
tragisch. Dichter Morris Rosenfeld, bekannt als der 
"Dichterlaureatus des Elendsviertels und des Fabrik mit schlechten 
Arbeitsbedingungen," sperrte dieses Denkmal zu den Opfern vier Tage 
nach dem Feuer ein. Das jüdische tägliche vorwärts gedruckt 
dem Gedicht hinunter die volle Länge seiner Vorderseite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">25 mars 1911, un feu a éclaté à la compagnie 
de Chemisier de triangle à New York City. Emprisonné par les
portes bloquées de sortie et les évasions défectueuses du feu, plus
de 146 ouvriers, la plupart du temps jeunes femmes immigrées, péri 
dans les flammes ou branché dix histoires à leurs décès. Un 
des plus mauvais feux industriels dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS, le 
feu de triangle est devenu un symbole de galvanisation des excès du 
capitalisme industriel et la nécessité pressante de la réforme. 
Dans sa conséquence, une coalition des réformateurs de classe 
moyen et les personnes travaillantes ont fixé le passage des lois de 
salubrité professionnelle et de sûreté de borne limite. Pour 
les communautés immigrées juives et italiennes du côté est 
inférieur, le feu était particulièrement tragique. Le poèt 
Morris Rosenfeld, connu sous le nom de "lauréat de poèt de taudis et
de bagne," a parqué ce mémorial aux victimes pendant quatre jours 
après le feu. Le quotidien juif en avant imprimé la poésie en
bas de la pleine longueur de son page avant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Março em 25, 1911, um fogo quebrou para fora na 
companhia de Shirtwaist do triângulo em New York City. Prendido
por portas obstruídas da saída e por escapes defeituosos do fogo, 
mais de 146 trabalhadores, na maior parte mulheres immigrant novas, 
perished nas flamas ou saltado dez histórias a suas mortes. Um 
dos fogos industriais os mais maus no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS, o 
fogo do triângulo transformou-se um símbolo galvanizing de excessos 
do capitalismo industrial e a necessidade pressionando para a reforma.
Em seu aftermath, um coalition de reformers do middle-class e os
povos trabalhando fixaram a passagem de leis da saúde ocupacional e 
da segurança do marco. Para comunidades immigrant jewish e 
italianas do lado do leste mais baixo, o fogo era especial trágico. 
O poeta Morris Rosenfeld, sabido como de "o laureate poeta do 
slum e do sweatshop," penned este memorial às vítimas quatro dias 
após o fogo. O diário jewish impresso para a frente o poema 
abaixo o comprimento cheio de sua página dianteira.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 25 marzo 1911, un fuoco ha scoppiato 
all'azienda di Shirtwaist del triangolo a New York City. 
Intrappolato tramite i portelli ostruiti dell'uscita e le fughe 
difettose del fuoco, più di 146 operai, principalmente donne 
immigrate giovani, perito nelle fiamme o saltato dieci storia alle 
loro morti. Uno dei fuochi industriali più difettosi nella 
storia degli STATI UNITI, il fuoco del triangolo si è transformato in
in un simbolo di galvanizzazione degli eccessi del capitalismo 
industriale e nella necessità urgente della riforma. Nel 
relativo guaime, una coalizione dei reformers della classe media e la 
gente lavorante hanno assicurato il passaggio delle leggi 
professionale di sanità e sicurezza del limite. Per le 
Comunità immigrate ebree ed italiane del lato orientale più basso, 
il fuoco era particolarmente tragico. Il poet Morris Rosenfeld, 
conosciuto come "il laureate di poet di slum e dell'azienda che 
sfrutta la manodopera," ha rinchiuso questo memoriale alle vittime 
quattro giorni dopo il fuoco. Il quotidiano ebreo in avanti 
stampato il poem giù la lunghezza completa della relativa pagina 
anteriore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 25 Μαρτίου ..1911, μια πυρκαγιά ξέσπησε στην
επιχείρηση μπλουζών τριγώνων στην πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης. 
Παγιδευμένες από την παρεμποδισμένη έξοδο οι πόρτες και η 
ελαττωματική πυρκαγιά δραπετεύουν, περισσότεροι από 146 
εργαζόμενοι, συνήθως νέες που έχουν μεταναστεύσει γυναίκες, 
χάθηκαν στις φλόγες ή πήδησαν δέκα ιστορίες στους θανάτους 
τους. Μια από τις χειρότερες βιομηχανικές πυρκαγιές στην 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ ιστορία, το πυρ τριγώνων έγινε ένα γαλβανίζοντας 
σύμβολο των υπερβολών της βιομηχανικής κεφαλαιοκρατίας και της 
επείγουσας ανάγκης για τη μεταρρύθμιση. Στη συνέπειά του, 
ένας συνασπισμός των μεταρρυθμιστών μεσαίων τάξεων και των 
εργαζόμενων ανθρώπων εξασφάλισε τη μετάβαση των νόμων υγιεινής 
και ασφάλειας της εργασίας ορόσημων. Για τις εβραϊκές και 
ιταλικές που έχουν μεταναστεύσει κοινότητες της χαμηλότερης 
ανατολικής πλευράς, η πυρκαγιά ήταν ιδιαίτερα τραγική. Ο 
ποιητής Morris Rosenfeld, γνωστό ως "δαφνοστεφής ποιητών της
τρώγλης και του σκλαβοπάζαρο," περιέφραξε αυτό το μνημείο στα 
θύματα τέσσερις ημέρες μετά από την πυρκαγιά. Εβραϊκός ο
καθημερινός τύπωσε προς τα εμπρός το ποίημα κάτω από το πλήρες 
μήκος του του πρώτη σελίδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De marcha la 25 de 1911, un fuego explotó en la 
compañía de Shirtwaist del triángulo en New York City. 
Atrapado por las puertas bloqueadas de la salida y los escapes 
defectuosos del fuego, más de 146 trabajadores, sobre todo mujeres 
inmigrantes jóvenes, fallecido en las llamas o saltadas diez 
historias a sus muertes. Uno de los fuegos industriales peores 
de la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS, el fuego del triángulo se 
convirtió en un símbolo de la galvanización de los excesos del 
capitalismo industrial y la necesidad acuciante de la reforma. 
En sus consecuencias, una coalición de los reformadores de la 
clase media y la gente de trabajo aseguraron el paso de los leyes de 
la medicina del trabajo y de la seguridad de la señal. Para las
comunidades inmigrantes judías e italianas de la cara del este más 
baja, el fuego era especialmente trágico. El poeta Morris 
Rosenfeld, conocido como el "laureado de poeta de los tugurios y de la
fábrica de explotación," encerró este monumento a las víctimas 
cuatro días después del fuego. El diario judío adelante 
impreso el poema abajo de la longitud completa de su paginación 
delantera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086793</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103455</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/rosenfelds-requiem-the-triangle-fire-victims-in-verse</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
