<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105150</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105150</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086168</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Forcing the Resignation of Women with Minor Children Is in This Day and Age an Anachronism": Support for Change in Army Policy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Resignation der Frauen mit geringen Kindern 
zu erzwingen ist an diesem Tag und altert einen Anachronismus": 
Support für Änderung in der Armee-Politik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"forcer la démission des femmes avec les enfants 
mineurs a lieu en ce jour et vieillit un anachronisme" : Soutien
de changement de la politique d'armée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"forçar a renúncia das mulheres com crianças 
menores realiza-se neste dia e envelhece-se um anachronism": 
Sustentação para a mudança na política do exército</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"forzare la rassegnazione delle donne con i 
bambini secondari ha luogo in questo giorno ed invecchia un 
anachronism": Sostegno cambiamento nella politica dell'esercito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο καταναγκασμός της παραίτησης των γυναικών με τα 
δευτερεύοντα παιδιά είναι σε αυτήν την ημέρα και γερνά έναν 
αναχρονισμό": Υποστήριξη για την αλλαγή στην πολιτική 
στρατού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"forzar la dimisión de mujeres con los niños de 
menor importancia es en este día y envejece un anachronism": 
Ayuda para el cambio en la política del ejército</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The issue of protective legislation for women and mothers has divided reformers, labor unionists, legislators, courts, the military, and feminists since the end of the 19th century when a number of states passed statutes to limit women's work hours. At issue--equal treatment versus biological difference. During the Cold War era, this question informed the debate on the role of women in the military. Although the Women's Armed Services Integration Act of 1948 established a permanent presence for women in all branches of the armed forces, a new Army regulation in October 1949 required the discharge of female servicewomen with children under the age of 18. To guarantee passage of the Armed Forces Reserve Act of 1952, during the Korean War, a provision was dropped that would have reversed this regulation. Thus mothers of dependent children were ineligible to enlist in reserve units and were discharged after childbirth or adoption. In the following Congressional session, the Senate passed S. 1492, allowing the reinstatement of women with dependent children. The bill, however, died in the House Committee on Armed Services and failed to become law. In the following testimony to the Senate subcommittee on S. 1492, Mrs. Anna Gordon, a Reserve officer in the WAVES (Women Accepted for Volunteer Emergency Service--U.S. Navy Women's Reserve), emphasized that many mothers successfully combined motherhood and careers. She further argued that skilled, experienced women dedicated to military careers were too valuable for the nation to discard at a time of Cold War uncertainty. In the 1970s, Congress finally passed a law that allowed women with dependent children to enlist.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ausgabe der schützenden Gesetzgebung für 
Frauen und Mütter hat Reformer, Arbeitergewerkschaftler, 
Gesetzgeber, Gerichte, das Militär und die Feminist seit dem Ende des
19. Jahrhunderts als eine Anzahl von den Zuständen geteilt, die 
Gesetze zu den Stunden Arbeit der Begrenzung Frauen geführt werden. 
An der Ausgabe -- gleiche Behandlung gegen biologischen 
Unterschied. Während der Ära des kalten Krieges informierte 
diese Frage die Debatte auf der Rolle der Frauen im Militär. 
Obgleich die Service-Integration Tat der Frauen bewaffnete von 
1948 eine permanente Anwesenheit für Frauen in allen Zweigen der 
bewaffneten Kräfte herstellte, benötigte eine neue Armeregelung im 
Oktober 1949 die Entladung der Frau servicewomen mit Kindern unter dem
Alter von 18. Um Durchgang der bewaffneten Kraft-Reserve-Tat von
1952, während des koreanischen Krieges zu garantieren, wurde eine 
Bestimmung fallengelassen die diese Regelung aufgehoben haben würde. 
So waren Mütter der abhängigen Kinder untauglich, in den 
Reservemaßeinheiten einzutragen und wurden nach Geburt oder Annahme 
entladen. In der folgenden Kongreßsitzung führte der Senat S. 
1492, die Wiedereinsetzung der Frauen mit abhängigen Kindern 
erlaubend. Die Rechnung jedoch starb im Haus-Ausschuß für 
bewaffnete Dienstleistungen und konnte Gesetz werden nicht. Im 
folgenden Zeugnis zur Senatunterausschuß auf S. 1492, Mrs Anna 
Gordon, ein Reserveoffizier in den WELLEN (Frauen angenommen für 
freiwilligen Bereitschaftsdienst -- US. Reserve der 
Marine-Frauen), hervorgehoben daß viele Muttererfolgreich kombinierte
Mutterschaft und -karrieren. Sie argumentierte weiter die, die, 
die erfahrenen Frauen erfahren ist, die militärischen Karrieren 
eingesetzt wurden, war zu wertvoll für die Nation zum Ausschuß 
hintereinander der Ungewißheit des kalten Krieges. In den 
siebziger Jahren führte Kongreß ein dieses Gesetz erlaubte Frauen 
mit abhängigen Kindern schließlich, um einzutragen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La question de la législation protectrice pour 
des femmes et des mères a divisé des réformateurs, des syndicalistes
de travail, des législateurs, des cours, les militaires, et des 
féministes depuis la fin du 19ème siècle où un certain nombre 
d'états passés des statuts aux heures du travail des femmes de 
limite. À l'issue -- égalité de traitement contre la 
différence biologique. Pendant l'ère de guerre froide, cette 
question a informé la discussion sur le rôle des femmes dans les 
militaires. Bien que la Loi d'intégration des forces armées 
des femmes de 1948 ait établi une présence permanente pour des 
femmes dans tous les branchements des forces armées, un nouveau 
règlement d'armée en octobre 1949 a exigé la décharge de la 
femelle servicewomen avec des enfants sous l'âge de 18. Pour 
garantir le passage de l'acte armé de réserve de forces de 1952, 
pendant la guerre coréenne, on a lâché une disposition qui aurait 
renversé ce règlement. Ainsi les mères des enfants 
dépendants étaient inéligibles pour enrôler dans des unités de 
réserve et ont été déchargées après l'accouchement ou 
l'adoption. En session congressionnelle suivante, le sénat a 
passé S. 1492, permettant le rétablissement des femmes avec 
les enfants dépendants. La facture, cependant, est morte au 
sein du comité de Chambre des forces armées et n'est pas devenue 
loi. Dans le témoignage suivant au sous-comité de sénat sur 
S. 1492, Mme Anna Gordon, un officier de réserve dans les 
VAGUES (femmes reçues pour le service volontaire de secours -- 
États-Unis. La réserve des femmes de marine), soulignée que 
maternité avec succès combinée et carrières de beaucoup de mères.
Elle en outre a discuté cela habile, les femmes expérimentées
consacrées aux carrières militaires étaient trop valable pour la 
nation à l'écart à la fois de l'incertitude de guerre froide. 
Dans les années 70, le congrès a finalement passé à une loi 
cette les femmes permises avec les enfants dépendants pour enrôler.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A introdução da legislação protetora para 
mulheres e matrizes dividiu reformers, unionists labor, legislators, 
cortes, as forças armadas, e feministas desde o fim do 1ø século em
que um número de estados passados statutes às horas do trabalho das 
mulheres do limite. Na edição -- tratamento igual contra a 
diferença biológica. Durante a era da guerra fria, esta 
pergunta informou o debate no papel das mulheres nas forças armadas. 
Embora o ato da integração dos forças armadas das mulheres de
1948 estabelecesse uma presença permanente para mulheres em todas as 
filiais das forças armadas, um regulamento novo do exército em 
outubro 1949 requereu a descarga da fêmea servicewomen com as 
crianças sob a idade de 18. Para garantir a passagem do ato 
armado da reserva das forças de 1952, durante a guerra korean, uma 
provisão foi deixada cair que invertesse este regulamento. 
Assim as matrizes de crianças dependentes eram inelegíveis 
alistar-se em unidades da reserva e foram descarregadas após o parto 
ou o adoption. Na seguinte sessão congressional, o senate 
passou S. 1492, permitindo o reinstatement das mulheres com 
crianças dependentes. A conta, entretanto, morreu no comitê da
casa em forças armadas e não se transformou lei. No seguinte 
testimony à subcomissão do senate em S. 1492, Sra. Anna 
Gordon, um oficial da reserva nas ONDAS (mulheres aceitadas para o 
serviço de emergência voluntário -- E. U.. Reserva das 
mulheres da marinha), emfatizada que motherhood com sucesso combinado 
e carreiras de muitas matrizes. Discutiu mais mais aquela 
hábil, as mulheres experientes dedicadas às carreiras militares era 
demasiado valiosa para a nação ao descarte em um momento da 
incerteza da guerra fria. Nos 1970s, o congress passou 
finalmente a uma lei essa mulheres permitidas com crianças 
dependentes para alistar-se.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'emissione di legislazione protettiva per le 
donne e le madri ha diviso i reformers, gli unionisti di lavoro, i 
legislatori, le corti, i militari e le femministe dalla conclusione 
del diciannovesimo secolo in cui un certo numero dichiara gli 
statuti passati alle ore del lavoro delle donne di limite. 
All'edizione -- parità di trattamento contro la differenza 
biologica. Durante l'era di guerra fredda, questo problema ha 
informato il dibattito sul ruolo delle donne nei militari. Anche
se la Legge di integrazione delle forze armate delle donne di 1948 ha 
stabilito una presenza permanente per le donne in tutti i rami delle 
forze munite, una nuova regolazione dell'esercito in ottobre 1949 ha 
richiesto lo scarico di femmina servicewomen con i bambini sotto 
l'età di 18. Per garantire il passaggio della Legge munita 
della riserva delle forze di 1952, durante la guerra coreana, una 
misura è stata caduta che avrebbe invertito questa regolazione. 
Così le madri dei bambini dipendenti erano ineleggibili 
arruolare nelle unità della riserva e sono state scaricate dopo il 
parto o l'approvazione. Nella seguente sessione congressuale, il
senato ha passato la S. 1492, permettendo reintegrazione delle 
donne con i bambini dipendenti. La fattura, tuttavia, è morto 
nel comitato della Camera delle forze armate e non è riuscito a 
transformarsi in in legge. Nella seguente testimonianza al 
sottocomitato del senato sulla S. 1492, sig.ra Anna Gordon, un 
ufficiale della riserva nelle ONDE (donne accettate per servizio di 
emergenza volontario -- Stati Uniti. Riserva delle donne del blu
marino), data risalto a che maternità con successo unita e carriere 
di molte madri. Più ulteriormente ha discusso quella esperta, 
donne con esperienza dedicate alle carriere militari era troppo 
importante per la nazione a scarto alla volta di incertezza di guerra 
fredda. Negli anni 70, al congresso infine ha passato ad una 
legge quella le donne permesse con i bambini dipendenti per arruolare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ζήτημα της προστατευτικής νομοθεσίας για τις 
γυναίκες και τις μητέρες έχει διαιρέσει τους μεταρρυθμιστές, τους
ενωτικούς εργασίας, τους νομοθέτες, τα δικαστήρια, το 
στρατιωτικό, και τις φεμινίστριες από το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα 
όταν πέρασαν διάφορα κράτη τα καταστατικά στις ώρες εργασίας 
των γυναικών ορίου. Στο ζήτημα -- ίση μεταχείριση εναντίον
της βιολογικής διαφοράς. Κατά τη διάρκεια της εποχής 
ψυχρού πολέμου, αυτή η ερώτηση ενημέρωσε τη συζήτηση για το 
ρόλο των γυναικών στους στρατιωτικούς. Αν και ο νόμος 
ολοκλήρωσης των Ένοπλων Δυνάμεων των γυναικών του 1948 
καθιέρωσε μια μόνιμη παρουσία για τις γυναίκες σε όλους τους 
κλάδους των οπλισμένων δυνάμεων, ένας νέος κανονισμός στρατού 
τον Οκτώβριο του 1949 απαίτησε η απαλλαγή του θηλυκού με τα 
παιδιά κάτω από την ηλικία 18, Για να εγγυηθεί τη 
μετάβαση του οπλισμένου νόμου επιφύλαξης δυνάμεων του 1952, 
κατά τη διάρκεια του κορεατικού πολέμου, μια διάταξη έπεσαν που 
θα είχε αντιστρέψει τον παρόντα κανονισμό. Κατά συνέπεια 
οι μητέρες των εξαρτώμενων παιδιών ήταν μη εκλέξιμες για να 
στρατολογήσουν τις σε εφεδρεία μονάδες και απαλλάχθηκαν μετά από
τον τοκετό ή την υιοθέτηση. Στην ακόλουθη του Κογκρέσου 
περίοδο επικοινωνίας, η Σύγκλητος πέρασε το Θ*ς. 1492, που 
επιτρέπει την επανεγκατάσταση των γυναικών με τα εξαρτώμενα 
παιδιά. Ο λογαριασμός, εντούτοις, πέθανε στην Επιτροπή 
Βουλών των Ένοπλων Δυνάμεων και απέτυχε να γίνει νόμος. 
Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση στην υποεπιτροπή Συγκλήτου στο Θ*ς. 
1492, η κα Anna Gordon, ένας ανώτερος υπάλληλος 
επιφύλαξης στα ΚΎΜΑΤΑ (οι γυναίκες αποδέχθηκαν για την εθελοντική
υπηρεσία έκτακτης ανάγκης -- επιφύλαξη των γυναικών ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΎ
ναυτικού), υπογράμμισε ότι πολλές μητέρες συνδύασαν επιτυχώς τη
μητρότητα και τις σταδιοδρομίες. Υποστήριξε περαιτέρω αυτού
ειδικευμένου, οι πεπειραμένες γυναίκες που αφιερώθηκαν στις 
στρατιωτικές σταδιοδρομίες ήταν πάρα πολύ πολύτιμες για το 
έθνος να απορρίψει σε μια εποχή της αβεβαιότητας ψυχρού πολέμου.
Στη δεκαετία του '70, το συνέδριο πέρασε τελικά έναν νόμο 
που επέτρεψε στις γυναίκες με τα εξαρτώμενα παιδιά για να 
στρατολογήσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La aplicación la legislación protectora para las
mujeres y las madres ha dividido a reformadores, a unionistas de 
trabajo, a legisladores, a cortes, a los militares, y a feministas 
desde el final del diecinueveavo siglo en que un número de estados 
pasados los estatutos a las horas del trabajo de las mujeres del 
límite. En la edición -- igualdad de tratamiento contra 
diferencia biológica. Durante la era de la guerra fría, esta 
pregunta informó al discusión sobre el papel de mujeres en los 
militares. Aunque el acto de la integración de las fuerzas 
armadas de las mujeres de 1948 estableció una presencia permanente 
para las mujeres en todas las ramificaciones de las fuerzas armadas, 
una nueva regulación del ejército en octubre 1949 requirió la 
descarga de la hembra servicewomen con los niños bajo edad de 18. 
Para garantizar el paso del acto armado de la reserva de las 
fuerzas de 1952, durante la guerra coreana, una disposición fue 
caída que habría invertido esta regulación. Así las madres 
de niños dependientes eran inelegibles alistar en unidades de la 
reserva y fueron descargadas después de parto o de la adopción. 
En la sesión del congreso siguiente, el senado pasó S. 
1492, permitiendo el restablecimiento de mujeres con los niños 
dependientes. La cuenta, sin embargo, murió en el comité de la
casa sobre las fuerzas armadas y no pudo convertirse en ley. En 
el testimonio siguiente al subcomité del senado en S. 1492, 
señora Ana Gordon, oficial de la reserva en las ONDAS (mujeres 
validadas para el servicio de emergencia voluntario -- los E.E.U.U.. 
Reserva de las mujeres de la marina de guerra), acentuada que 
maternidad con éxito combinada y carreras de muchas madres. 
Ella discutió más lejos eso experto, las mujeres 
experimentadas dedicadas a las carreras militares era demasiado 
valiosa para la nación al descarte al mismo tiempo de la 
incertidumbre de la guerra fría. En los años 70, el congreso 
finalmente pasó una ley esa a mujeres permitidas con los niños 
dependientes para alistar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086168</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105150</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/forcing-the-resignation-of-women-with-minor-children-is-in-this-day-and-age-an-anachronism-support-for-change-in-army-policy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
