<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104735</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1651176669</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AP Calculus BC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AP Kalkül BC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Calcul de AP BC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Cálculo do Ap BC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Calcolo di Ap BC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπολογισμός AP Π.Χ.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cálculo del Ap A.C.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This curriculum covers all of the material outlined by the College Board as necessary to prepare students to pass the AP Calculus BC exam. This course is divided into two semesters and is designed to acquaint you with calculus principles such as derivatives, integrals, limits, approximation, applications and modeling, and sequences and series. During this course you will gain experience in the use of calculus methods and learn how calculus methods may be applied to practical applications.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Lehrplan umfaßt die ganze Material, das 
durch das Hochschulgremium wie benötigt, Kursteilnehmer 
vorzubereiten, die Prüfung des AP Kalküls BC zu führen umrissen 
wird. Dieser Kurs ist in zwei Semester geteilt und ist 
konzipiert, um Sie mit Kalkülgrundregeln wie Ableitungen, Integrale, 
Begrenzungen, Näherungswert, Anwendungen und Formung und Reihenfolgen
und Serie mitzuteilen. Während dieses Kurses gewinnen Sie 
Erfahrung im Gebrauch von Kalkülmethoden und erlernen, wie 
Kalkülmethoden an den praktischen Anwendungen angewendet werden 
können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce programme d'études couvre tout le matériel 
tracé les grandes lignes par le conseil d'université selon les 
besoins pour préparer des étudiants passer l'examen de calcul de AP 
BC. Ce cours est divisé en deux semestres et est conçu pour 
vous mettre au courant des principes de calcul tels que des dérivés,
des intégrales, des limites, approximation, des applications et 
modeler, et des ordres et des séries. Pendant ce cours vous 
acquerrez l'expérience de l'utilisation des méthodes de calcul et 
apprendrez comment des méthodes de calcul peuvent être appliquées 
aux applications pratiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este curriculum cobre todo o material esboçado 
pela placa de faculdade como necessário preparar estudantes para 
passar BC o exam do cálculo do AP. Este curso é dividido em 
dois semesters e projetado familiarizá-lo com os princípios do 
cálculo tais como derivatives, integrais, limites, aproximação, 
aplicações e modelar, e seqüências e série. Durante este 
curso você ganhará a experiência no uso de métodos do cálculo e 
aprenderá como os métodos do cálculo podem ser aplicados às 
aplicações práticas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma di studi tratta tutto il 
materiale descritto dal Bordo dell'università come necessario 
preparare gli allievi per passare BC il exam di calcolo di AP. 
Questo corso è diviso in due semestri ed è destinato per 
informarlo dei principii di calcolo quali i derivati, integrali, 
limiti, approssimazione, applicazioni e modellare e sequenze e serie. 
Durante questo corso guadagnerete l'esperienza di uso dei metodi
di calcolo ed imparerete come i metodi di calcolo possono essere 
applicati alle applicazioni pratiche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το πρόγραμμα σπουδών καλύπτει όλο το υλικό που 
περιγράφεται από τον πίνακα κολλεγίου για να προετοιμάσει 
ανάλογα με τις ανάγκες τους σπουδαστές για να περάσει το 
διαγωνισμό υπολογισμού AP Π.Χ.. Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων 
διαιρείται σε δύο εξάμηνα και σχεδιάζεται για να σας εξοικειώσει 
με τις αρχές υπολογισμού όπως τα παράγωγα, τα ολοκληρώματα, τα 
όρια, η προσέγγιση, οι εφαρμογές και η διαμόρφωση, και οι 
ακολουθίες και οι σειρές. Κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής της 
σειράς μαθημάτων θα αποκτήσετε την εμπειρία στη χρήση των 
μεθόδων υπολογισμού και θα μάθετε πώς οι μέθοδοι υπολογισμού 
μπορούν να εφαρμοστούν στις πρακτικές εφαρμογές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de estudios cubre todo el material 
contorneado por la tarjeta de universidad como necesaria para preparar
a estudiantes para aprobar el examen del cálculo del AP A.C.. 
Este curso se divide en dos semestres y se diseña para 
conocerle de principios del cálculo tales como derivados, los 
integrales, los límites, aproximación, las aplicaciones y el 
modelar, y las secuencias y serie. Durante este curso usted 
ganará experiencia en el uso de los métodos del cálculo y 
aprenderá cómo los métodos del cálculo se pueden aplicar a las 
aplicaciones prácticas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNKNOWN
FN:UNKNOWN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1651176669</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104735</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ap-calculus-bc</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
