<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103013</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103013</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086866</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sunshine and shadow.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sonnenschein und Schatten.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Soleil et ombre.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Luz do sol e sombra.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sole ed ombra.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηλιοφάνεια και σκιά.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sol y sombra.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Rising immigration and increasing social stratification affected the development of American cities during the mid-nineteenth century. City guides, delineating the mysteries of the metropolis, as well as newspapers, magazines, and novels presented the East's industrializing citiesNew York, Philadelphia, and Baltimoreas fractured societies. According to these publications, each was really two cities: one orderly, prosperous, and bathed in sunlight</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Steigende soziale Schichtung der Immigration und der 
Erhöhung beeinflußte die Entwicklung der amerikanischen Städte 
während des mittler-19.jahrhunderts. Die Stadtanleitungen, die 
Geheimnisse der Hauptstadt, sowie Zeitungen, die Zeitschriften und die
Romane abgrenzend stellten das industrialisierende citiesNew des 
Ostens York, Philadelphia und Baltimoreas zerbrochene Gesellschaften 
dar. Entsprechend diesen Publikationen war jede wirklich zwei 
Städte: ein regelmäßig, wohlhabend und gebadet im 
Sonnenlicht</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La stratification sociale de montée d'immigration et 
d'augmentation a affecté le développement des villes américaines 
pendant le mi-dix-neuvième siècle. Les guides de ville, 
traçant les mystères de la métropole, aussi bien que des journaux, 
des magasins, et des romans ont présenté le citiesNew 
d'industrialisation de l'est York, Philadelphie, et sociétés rompues
par Baltimoreas. Selon ces publications, chacune était vraiment
deux villes : un ordonné, prospère, et baigné au soleil</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O stratification social levantando-se do immigration e do 
aumento afetou o desenvolvimento de cidades americanas durante o 
mid-décimo nono século. As guias da cidade, delineando os 
mistérios do metropolis, as.well.as jornais, compartimentos, e 
novelas apresentaram o citiesNew industrializing York, Filadélfia, e 
sociedades fraturadas Baltimoreas do leste. De acordo com estas 
publicações, cada uma era realmente duas cidades: um em ordem,
próspero, e banhado na luz solar</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La stratificazione sociale aumentante aumentare e di 
immigrazione ha interessato lo sviluppo delle città americane durante
il metà di-diciannovesimo secolo. Le guide della città, 
delineanti i misteri del metropolis, così come i giornali, gli 
scomparti ed i romanzi hanno presentato il citiesNew 
d'industrializzazione York, Filadelfia e società fratturate 
Baltimoreas dell'est. Secondo queste pubblicazioni, ciascuno era
realmente due città: uno ordinato, prosperoso e bagnato al 
sole</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αυξανόμενη μετανάστευση και η αυξανόμενη κοινωνική 
στρωματοποίηση είχαν επιπτώσεις στην ανάπτυξη των αμερικανικών 
πόλεων κατά τη διάρκεια του μέσος-δέκατου έννατου αιώνα. 
Οι οδηγοί πόλεων, που σκιαγραφούν τα μυστήρια της 
μητρόπολης, καθώς επίσης και τις εφημερίδες, τα περιοδικά, και τα
μυθιστορήματα παρουσίασαν την ανατολική βιομηχανοποίηση 
citiesNew Υόρκη, Φιλαδέλφεια, και σπασμένες Baltimoreas 
κοινωνίες. Σύμφωνα με αυτές τις δημοσιεύσεις, κάθε μια 
ήταν πραγματικά δύο πόλεις: ένα τακτικό, ακμάζον, και 
λουσμένος στο φως του ήλιου</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La estratificación social de levantamiento de la 
inmigración y del aumento afectó el desarrollo de ciudades 
americanas durante el mediados de-diecinueveavo siglo. Las 
guías de la ciudad, delineando los misterios de la metrópoli, así 
como los periódicos, los compartimientos, y las novelas presentaron 
el citiesNew de industrialización York, Philadelphia, y sociedades 
fracturadas Baltimoreas del este. Según estas publicaciones, 
cada uno era realmente dos ciudades: uno ordenado, próspero, y 
bañado en luz del sol</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086866</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103013</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sunshine-and-shadow</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
