<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104464</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104464</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974053</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Seasonal Migrations: Monarch Butterflies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Saisonmigrationen: 
Monarch-Basisrecheneinheiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Transferts Saisonniers : Papillons de 
Monarque</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Migrações Seasonal: Borboletas Do Monarch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Espansioni Stagionali: Farfalle Del Monarca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εποχιακές μεταναστεύσεις: Πεταλούδες μοναρχών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Migraciones Estacionales: Mariposas Del 
Monarca</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Help track the monarch butterfly migration each fall and spring as the butterflies travel to and from Mexico. Report your own observations of migrating butterflies to this migration map. Through these interrelated investigations, students discover that sunlight drives all living systems and they learn about the dynamic ecosystem that surrounds and connects them. Guidelines, lessons, activities, reading connections, and interactive maps are included for each study.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfe Spur die Monarchbasisrecheneinheit Migration
jeder Fall und Frühling als der Basisrecheneinheiten Spielraum nach 
und von Mexiko. Berichten Sie Ihren eigenen Beobachtungen der 
Fortziehenbasisrecheneinheiten diese Migration Karte. Durch 
diese zusammenhängend Untersuchungen entdecken Kursteilnehmer, daß 
Tageslicht alle lebenden Systeme antreibt und sie über das dynamische
Oekosystem erlernen, das sie umgibt und anschließt. 
Korrekturlinien, Lektionen, Aktivitäten, Anschlüsse und 
interaktive Karten lesend sind für jede Studie enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Piste d'aide le transfert de papillon de monarque 
chaque chute et ressort comme voyage de papillons à et du Mexique. 
Enregistrez vos propres observations des papillons de passer à 
cette carte de transfert. Par ces investigations en 
corrélation, les étudiants découvrent que la lumière du soleil 
pilote tous les systèmes vivants et ils se renseignent sur 
l'écosystème dynamique qui les entoure et relie. Les 
directives, leçons, activités, lisant des connexions, et des cartes 
interactives sont incluses pour chaque étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Trilha da ajuda a migração da borboleta do 
monarch cada queda e mola como o curso das borboletas a e de México. 
Relate suas próprias observações de borboletas migrar a este 
mapa da migração. Com estas investigações relacionadas, os 
estudantes descobrem que a luz solar dirige todos os sistemas vivos e 
aprendem sobre o ecosystem dinâmico que os cerca e conecta. Os 
guidelines, lições, atividades, lendo conexões, e mapas interativos
são incluídos para cada estudo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pista di aiuto l'espansione della farfalla del 
monarca ogni caduta e molla come la corsa delle farfalle a e da il 
Messico. _ segnal vostro proprio osservazione migr farfalla 
questo espansione programma. Con queste indagini correlate, gli 
allievi scoprono che la luce solare guida tutti i sistemi viventi ed 
imparano circa l'ecosistema dinamico che li circonda e collega. 
La guida di riferimento, lezioni, attività, leggendo i 
collegamenti ed i programmi interattivi è inclusa per ogni studio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαδρομή οδηγιών η μετανάστευση πεταλούδων μοναρχών 
κάθε πτώση και άνοιξη ως ταξίδι πεταλούδων σε και από το 
Μεξικό. Εκθέστε τις παρατηρήσεις μεταναστεύοντας πεταλούδων
σας σε αυτόν τον χάρτη μετανάστευσης. Μέσω αυτών των 
αλληλένδετων ερευνών, οι σπουδαστές ανακαλύπτουν ότι το φως του 
ήλιου οδηγεί όλα τα συστήματα διαβίωσης και μαθαίνουν για το 
δυναμικό οικοσύστημα που τους περιβάλλει και συνδέει. Οι 
οδηγίες, μαθήματα, δραστηριότητες, διαβάζοντας τις συνδέσεις, και
τους διαλογικούς χάρτες συμπεριλαμβάνονται για κάθε μελέτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pista de la ayuda la migración de la mariposa del
monarca cada caída y resorte como el recorrido de las mariposas a y 
desde México. Señale sus propias observaciones de las 
mariposas de la migración a esta correspondencia de la migración. 
Con estas investigaciones correlacionadas, los estudiantes 
descubren que la luz del sol conduce todos los sistemas vivos y 
aprenden sobre el ecosistema dinámico que los rodea y conecta. 
Las guías de consulta, lecciones, actividades, leyendo 
conexiones, y correspondencias interactivas son incluidas para cada 
estudio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974053</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104464</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/seasonal-migrations-monarch-butterflies</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
