<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104799</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104799</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1413447839</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Livingeconomics - an instructor-customizable microeconomics principles textbook</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Livingeconomics - ein Ausbilder-customizable 
Mikrotheorie-Grundregellehrbuch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Livingeconomics - un manuel de principes de la 
micro-économie d'instructeur-customizable</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Livingeconomics - um textbook dos princípios do 
microeconomics do instrutor-customizable</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Livingeconomics - un manuale di principii di 
microeconomia dell'istruttore-customizable</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Livingeconomics - ένα εκπαιδευτικός-εξατομικεύσιμο 
εγχειρίδιο αρχών μικροοικονομίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Livingeconomics - un libro de textos de los 
principios del microeconomics del instructor-customizable</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Living Economics provides real-world stories, cutting-edge Flash animations, test banks, and online lectures for economic teachers to customize their own principles textbooks. It is intended to serve primarily those teachers who have been searching for a principles textbook that teaches economic concepts from real-world stories instead of widgets. Living Economics is inspired by the time-honored practice of learning languages through immersion rather than remembering grammatical rules.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Business</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lebende Volkswirtschaft liefert realistische 
Geschichten, Ausschnitt-Rand grelle Animationen, hat Test und 
Onlinevorträge Bankkonto, damit ökonomische Lehrer ihre eigenen 
Grundregellehrbücher anpassen. Es soll hauptsächlich jene 
Lehrer dienen, die nach einem Grundregellehrbuch gesucht haben, das 
ökonomische Konzepte von den realistischen Geschichten anstelle von 
den widgets unterrichtet. Lebende Volkswirtschaft wird durch die
altehrwürdige Praxis der erlernensprachen durch Immersion anstatt das
Erinnern an grammatische Richtlinien angespornt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les sciences économiques vivantes fournissent des
histoires réelles, animations instantanées de découpage-bord, 
l'essai encaisse, et des conférences en ligne pour que les 
professeurs économiques personnalisent leurs propres manuels de 
principes. On le destine pour servir principalement ces 
professeurs qui avaient recherché un manuel de principes qui enseigne
des concepts économiques des histoires réelles au lieu des widgets. 
Des sciences économiques vivantes sont inspirées par la 
pratique consacrée des langages d'étude par l'immersion plutôt que 
de se rappeler des règles grammaticales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A economia viva fornece histórias real-world, 
animations flash da corte-borda, o teste deposita, e lectures em linha
para que os professores econômicos customize seus próprios textbooks
dos princípios. Pretende-se servir primeiramente 2 aqueles 
professores que têm procurarado por um textbook dos princípios que 
ensinasse conceitos econômicos das histórias real-world em vez dos 
widgets. A economia viva é inspirada pela prática time-honored
de línguas de aprendizagem com a imersão melhor que recordar réguas
gramaticais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'economia vivente fornisce le storia 
nell'ambiente, le animazioni istantanee del taglio-bordo, la 
banca della prova e le conferenze in linea per gli insegnanti 
economici per personalizzare i loro propri manuali di principii. 
È inteso per servire soprattutto quegli insegnanti che stanno 
cercando un manuale di principii che insegna i concetti economici 
dalle storia nell'ambiente anziché i widgets. L'economia 
vivente è ispirata dalla pratica consacrata dei linguaggi imparanti 
through l'immersione piuttosto che ricordarsi delle regole 
grammaticali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα οικονομικά διαβίωσης παρέχουν τις πραγματικές 
ιστορίες, τις ζωτικότητες λάμψης τέμνων-ακρών, τις τράπεζες 
δοκιμής, και τις σε απευθείας σύνδεση διαλέξεις για τους 
οικονομικούς δασκάλους για να προσαρμόσουν τα εγχειρίδια αρχών 
τους. Προορίζεται να εξυπηρετηθούν πρώτιστα εκείνοι οι 
δάσκαλοι που έχουν ψάξει για τις αρχές εγχειρίδιο που διδάσκει 
τις οικονομικές έννοιες από τις πραγματικές ιστορίες αντί των 
widgets. Τα οικονομικά διαβίωσης εμπνέονται από τη 
time-honored πρακτική της εκμάθησης των γλωσσών μέσω της 
βύθισης παρά την ανάμνηση των γραμματικών κανόνων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La economía viva proporciona a las historias del 
mundo real, animaciones de destello del corte-borde, la prueba ejerce 
la actividad bancaria, y las conferencias en línea para que los 
profesores económicos modifiquen sus propios libros de textos de los 
principios para requisitos particulares. Se piensa para servir 
sobre todo a esos profesores que han estado buscando para un libro de 
textos de los principios que enseña conceptos económicos de 
historias del mundo real en vez de widgets. La economía viva es
inspirada por la práctica consagrada de lenguajes que aprenden con la
inmersión más bien que recordar reglas gramaticales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschäft</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Affaires</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Negócio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Commercio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιχείρηση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Negocio</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:K. K. FUNG
FN:K. K. FUNG
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1413447839</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104799</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/livingeconomics-an-instructor-customizable-microeconomics-principles-textbook</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
