<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106204</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106204</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087075</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The White Man's Burden": Kipling's Hymn to U.S. Imperialism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Weißen Belastung Des Mannes": 
Hymne Kiplings zum VEREINIGTE STAATEN Imperialismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Fardeau de l'Homme Blanc" : L'hymne de 
Kipling à l'impérialisme des ETATS-UNIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Burden Do Homem Branco": Hymn de Kipling 
ao imperialism de ESTADOS UNIDOS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Difficoltà Dell'Uomo Bianco": Hymn del 
Kipling ad imperialismo degli STATI UNITI</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το άσπρο ανθρώπινο φορτίο": Ύμνος Kipling 
στον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ιμπεριαλισμό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"La Carga Del Hombre Blanco": Himno de 
Kipling al imperialismo de ESTADOS UNIDOS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In February 1899, British novelist and poet Rudyard Kipling wrote a poem entitled "The White Man's Burden: The United States and The Philippine Islands." In this poem, Kipling urged the U.S. to take up the "burden" of empire, as had Britain and other European nations. Published in the February, 1899 issue of  McClure's Magazine , the poem coincided with the beginning of the Philippine-American War and U.S. Senate ratification of the treaty that placed Puerto Rico, Guam, Cuba, and the Philippines under American control. Theodore Roosevelt, soon to become vice-president and then president, copied the poem and sent it to his friend, Senator Henry Cabot Lodge, commenting that it was "rather poor poetry, but good sense from the expansion point of view." Not everyone was as favorably impressed as Roosevelt. The racialized notion of the "White Man's burden" became a euphemism for imperialism, and many anti-imperialists couched their opposition in reaction to the phrase.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Februar 1899, schrieben britischer Novelist und
Dichter Rudyard Kipling ein Gedicht, das "die weißen Belastung des 
Mannes erlaubt wurde: Die Vereinigten Staaten und die 
philippinischen Inseln." In diesem Gedicht drängte Kipling die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, die "Belastung" des Reiches, als gehabtes 
Großbritannien und andere europäische Nationen aufzunehmen. 
Veröffentlicht im Februar, stimmte Ausgabe 1899 von Zeitschrift
McClures, das Gedicht mit dem Anfang der Philippinisch-Amerikanischen 
Krieg- und VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senatbestätigung des Vertrags überein,
der Puerto Rico, Guam, Kuba und die Philippinen unter amerikanische 
Steuerung plazierte. Theodore Roosevelt, Vizepräsidenten und 
dann Präsidenten bald zu stehen, kopierte das Gedicht und schickte es
seinem Freund, Senator Henry Cabot Lodge und kommentierte, daß es 
"ziemlich schlechte Poesie war, aber gute Richtung vom Expansion 
Gesichtspunkt." Nicht jeder wurde so vorteilhaft wie Roosevelt 
beeindruckt. Racialized Begriff der "weißen Belastung des 
Mannes" wurde ein Euphemismus für Imperialismus, und viele 
Anti-Imperialisten legten ihre Opposition in der Reaktion zur Phrase 
hin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En février 1899, le romancier et le poèt 
britanniques Rudyard Kipling ont écrit une poésie intitulée "le 
fardeau de l'homme blanc : Les Etats-Unis et les îles 
philippines." En cette poésie, Kipling a invité les ETATS-UNIS
à prendre le "fardeau" de l'empire, en tant que la Grande-Bretagne 
eue et d'autres nations européennes. Édité en février, le 
numéro 1899 du magazine de McClure, la poésie a coïncidé avec le 
début de la ratification Philippin-Américaine de guerre et de sénat
des ETATS-UNIS du traité qui a placé le Porto Rico, la Guam, le 
Cuba, et les Philippines sous la commande américaine. Theodore 
Roosevelt, aller bien bientôt au vice-président et puis au 
président, a copié la poésie et l'a envoyée à son ami, le 
sénateur Henry Cabot Lodge, commentant que c'était "poésie plutôt 
faible, mais bon sens du point de vue d'expansion." Pas chacun a
été aussi favorablement impressionné que Roosevelt. 
Racialized la notion "du fardeau de l'homme blanc" est devenu un
euphémisme pour l'impérialisme, et beaucoup d'anti-impérialistes 
ont couché leur opposition dans la réaction à l'expression.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em fevereiro 1899, o novelist e o poeta 
britânicos Rudyard Kipling escreveram um poema intitulado "o burden 
do homem branco: Os estados unidos e os consoles philippine." 
Neste poema, Kipling incitou os ESTADOS UNIDOS fazer exame acima
do "burden" do império, como Grâ Bretanha tido e outras nações 
européias. Publicado no fevereiro, a introdução 1899 do 
compartimento de McClure, o poema coincidiu com o começo do 
ratification Philippine-Americano da guerra e do senate de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS do tratado que colocou Puerto Rico, Guam, Cuba, e as Filipinas 
sob o controle americano. Theodore Roosevelt, para assentar bem 
logo no vice-presidente e então no presidente, copí o poema e 
emitiu-o a seu amigo, senator Henry Cabot Alojar, comentando que era 
"poesia rather deficiente, mas sentido bom do ponto da expansão da 
vista." Não todos foi imprimido tão favoràvel quanto 
Roosevelt. Racialized a noção do burden "do homem branco" 
transformou-se um euphemism para o imperialism, e muitos 
anti-anti-imperialists couched sua oposição na reação à frase.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mese di febbraio del 1899, il romanziere ed 
il poet britannici Rudyard Kipling hanno scritto un poem intitolato 
"la difficoltà dell'uomo bianco: Unito Dichiara e le 
isole filippine." In questo poem, Kipling ha invitato gli STATI 
UNITI a prendere "la difficoltà" dell'impero, come la Gran-Bretagna 
avuta ed altre nazioni europee. Pubblicato in febbraio, 
l'emissione 1899 dello scomparto del McClure, il poem ha coinciso con 
l'inizio della ratifica Filippino-Americana del senato degli STATI 
UNITI e di guerra del trattato che ha disposto il Porto Rico, il Guam,
la Cuba e le Filippine sotto controllo americano. Theodore 
Roosevelt, presto stare bene al vice presidente ed allora al 
presidente, ha copiato il poem e lo ha trasmesso al suo amico, il 
senatore Henry Cabot Lodge, commentante che era "la poesia piuttosto 
povera, ma buon senso dal punto di vista di espansione." Non
tutto è stato impressionato favorevole quanto Roosevelt. 
Racialized la nozione della difficoltà "dell'uomo bianco" si è
transformato in in un eufemismo per l'imperialismo e molti 
anti-anti-imperialists si sono coricati la loro opposizione nella 
reazione alla frase.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Φεβρουάριο του 1899, ο βρετανικοί 
μυθιστοριογράφος και ο ποιητής Rudyard Kipling έγραψαν ένα 
ποίημα που τιτλοφορήθηκε "άσπρο ανθρώπινο φορτίο: Οι 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες και τα φιλιππινέζικα νησιά." Σε αυτό το 
ποίημα, Kipling πίεσε τις ΗΠΑ για να λάβει το "φορτίο" της 
αυτοκρατορίας, όπως είχε τη Μεγάλη Βρετανία και άλλα ευρωπαϊκά
έθνη. Δημοσιευμένο το Φεβρουάριο, το ζήτημα 1899 του 
περιοδικού McClure's, το ποίημα συνέπεσε με την αρχή του 
φιλιππινέζικος-αμερικανικών πολέμου και της επικύρωσης 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉΣ Συγκλήτου της συνθήκης που τοποθέτησε το Πουέρτο 
Ρίκο, το Γκουάμ, την Κούβα, και τις Φιλιππίνες υπό αμερικανικό 
έλεγχο. Το Theodore Roosevelt, σύντομα για να γίνει 
αντιπρόεδρος και έπειτα Πρόεδρος, αντέγραψε το ποίημα και το 
έστειλε στο φίλο του, γερουσιαστής Henry Cabot Lodge, που 
σχολιάζει ότι ήταν "μάλλον φτωχή ποίηση, αλλά καλή αίσθηση 
από την άποψη επέκτασης." Όχι ο καθένας ήταν τόσο 
ευνοϊκά εντυπωσιασμένος όσο Roosevelt. Η έννοια του 
"άσπρου ανθρώπινου φορτίου" έγινε ένας ευφημισμός για τον 
ιμπεριαλισμό, και πολλοί αντι-ιμπεριαλιστές ξάπλωσαν την 
αντίθεσή τους σε αντίδραση στη φράση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En febrero de 1899, el novelista y el poeta 
británicos Rudyard Kipling escribieron un poema titulado "la carga 
del hombre blanco: Los Estados Unidos y las islas filipinas." 
En este poema, Kipling impulsó los ESTADOS UNIDOS tomar la 
"carga" del imperio, como Gran Bretaña tenida y otras naciones 
europeas. Publicado en el febrero, la aplicación 1899 el 
compartimiento de McClure, el poema coincidió con el principio de la 
ratificación Filipino-Americana de la guerra y del senado de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS del tratado que colocó Puerto Rico, Guam, Cuba, y las 
Filipinas bajo control americano. Theodore Roosevelt, pronto 
sentir bien al vice presidente y entonces al presidente, copió el 
poema y lo envió a su amigo, senador Henry Cabot Lodge, comentando 
que era "poesía algo pobre, solamente buen sentido desde el punto de 
vista de la extensión." No cada uno fue impresionado tan 
favorable como Roosevelt. Racialized la noción carga de la "del
hombre blanco" hizo un eufemismo para el imperialismo, y muchos 
contra-imperialistas acostaron su oposición en la reacción a la 
frase.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087075</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106204</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-white-mans-burden-kiplings-hymn-to-u-s-imperialism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
