<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106474</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106474</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087416</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Avoid the Use of the Word Intervention": Wilson and Lansing on the U.S. Invasion of Mexico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"vermeiden Sie den Gebrauch von der 
Wort-Intervention": Wilson und Lansing auf der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Invasion von Mexiko</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"évitez l'utilisation de l'Intervention de mot" : 
Wilson et Lansing sur l'invasion des ETATS-UNIS du Mexique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"evite o uso da intervenção da palavra": 
Wilson e Lansing na invasão de ESTADOS UNIDOS de México</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"eviti l'uso dell'intervento di parola": 
Wilson e Lansing sull'invasione degli STATI UNITI del Messico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αποφύγετε τη χρήση της επέμβασης του Word": 
Θ*Ωηλσον και Λάνσινγκ στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ εισβολή του Μεξικού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"evite el uso de la intervención de la palabra": 
Wilson y Lansing en la invasión de ESTADOS UNIDOS de México</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1916, Francisco Villa, leader of the peasant uprisings in northern Mexico, raided Columbus, New Mexico, in an attempt to expose Mexican government collaboration with the United States. President Woodrow Wilson responded by ordering an invasion of Mexico. Five years after the beginning of the Mexican Revolution, which was characterized by hope for social change as well as death, hunger, and violence, many Mexicans did not welcome further involvement by the U.S. In the following correspondence, Secretary of State Robert Lansing and President Wilson described the need to carefully frame the invasion as a defense of U.S. borders rather than interference in the Mexican Revolution. The resulting invasion, led by General John Pershing, was a total fiasco. It failed to locate Villa and increased anti-U.S. sentiment and Mexican nationalist resolve.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1916 überfiel Francisco Landhaus, Führer der 
ländlichen Aufstiege in Nordmexiko, Columbus, New-Mexico, um 
mexikanische Regierung Zusammenarbeit mit den Vereinigten Staaten 
herauszustellen. Präsident Woodrow Wilson reagierte, indem er 
eine Invasion von Mexiko bestellte. Fünf Jahre nach dem Anfang 
der mexikanischen Umdrehung, die durch Hoffnung für Sozialänderung 
gekennzeichnet wurde, sowie Tod, Hunger und die Gewalttätigkeit, viel
Mexikaner weitere Miteinbeziehung nicht durch die US begrüßte. 
In der folgenden Korrespondenz beschrieben Staatssekretär 
Robert Lansing und Präsident Wilson die Notwendigkeit, die Invasion 
sorgfältig zu gestalten, während eine Verteidigung von VEREINIGTEN 
STAATEN anstatt Störung in der mexikanischen Umdrehung einfaßt. 
Die resultierende Invasion, geführt vom General John Pershing, 
war ein GesamtFiasko. Sie konnte Landhaus errichten 
nicht und erhöhte anti-U.S. Gefühl und mexikanischen 
nationalistischen Beschluß.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1916, la villa de Francisco, amorce des 
soulèvements ruraux au Mexique nordique, a pillé Columbus, 
Nouveau-Mexique, afin d'essayer d'exposer la collaboration mexicaine 
de gouvernement avec les Etats-Unis. Le Président Woodrow 
Wilson a répondu en commandant une invasion du Mexique. Cinq 
ans après le début de la révolution mexicaine, qui a été 
caractérisée par espoir pour le changement social comme la mort, la 
faim, et la violence, beaucoup de le Mexicain n'a pas fait bon accueil
davantage à de participation par les États-Unis. Dans la 
correspondance suivante, le secrétaire d'état Robert Lansing et le 
Président Wilson ont décrit la nécessité d'encadrer soigneusement 
l'invasion pendant qu'une défense des ETATS-UNIS encadre plutôt 
qu'interférence en révolution mexicaine. L'invasion 
résultante, menée par le Général John Pershing, était un 
fiasco total. Elle n'a pas plac la villa et a augmenté le 
sentiment d'anti-U.S. et la résolution nationaliste mexicaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1916, o villa de Francisco, líder dos 
uprisings peasant em México do norte, invadiu Columbo, Novo México, 
em uma tentativa de expo a colaboração mexicana do governo com os 
estados unidos. O presidente Woodrow Wilson respondeu 
requisitando uma invasão de México. Cinco anos após o começo
da volta mexicana, que foi caracterizado pela esperança para a 
mudança social assim como a morte, a fome, e a violência, muita o 
mexicano não deu boas-vindas a uma participação mais adicional 
pelos E. U.. Na seguinte correspondência, a secretária de 
estado Robert Lansing e o presidente Wilson descreveram a necessidade 
moldar com cuidado a invasão enquanto uma defesa de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
limita melhor que interferência na volta mexicana. A invasão 
resultante, conduzida pelo general John Pershing, era um fiasco total.
Não ficou o villa e aumentou o sentiment de anti-U.S. e o 
resolve nacionalista mexicano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1916, la villa di Francisco, capo delle 
rivolte agricole nel Messico del Nord, raided Columbus, Nuovo 
Messico, nel tentativo d'esporre la collaborazione messicana di 
governo con unito Dichiara. Il presidente Woodrow Wilson 
ha risposto ordinando un'invasione del Messico. Cinque anni dopo
l'inizio della rivoluzione messicana, che è stata caratterizzata da 
speranza per cambiamento sociale come pure la morte, la fame e la 
violenza, molta il mexicans non ha accolto favorevolmente ulteriore 
partecipazione dagli Stati Uniti. Nella seguente corrispondenza,
la segretaria di Dichiara Robert Lansing ed il presidente 
Wilson ha descritto la necessità di incorniciare con attenzione 
l'invasione mentre una difesa degli STATI UNITI borders piuttosto che 
interferenza nella rivoluzione messicana. L'invasione 
risultante, condotta dal General John Pershing, era un fiasco totale. 
Non è riuscito a posizionare la villa ed ha aumentato il 
sentimento di anti-U.S. e la risoluzione nazionalista messicana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1916, Francisco Villa, ηγέτης των εγέρσεων 
αγροτών στο βόρειο Μεξικό, επιτέθηκε το Columbus, New 
Mexico, σε μία προσπάθεια να εκτεθεί μεξικάνικη κυβερνητική 
συνεργασία με τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Ο Πρόεδρος Woodrow 
Wilson αποκρίθηκε με τη διαταγή μιας εισβολής του Μεξικού. 
Πέντε έτη μετά από την αρχή της μεξικάνικης επανάστασης, 
που χαρακτηρίστηκε από την ελπίδα για την κοινωνική αλλαγή καθώς
επίσης και το θάνατο, η πείνα, και η βία, πολλοί μεξικανοί δεν 
χαιρέτισαν την περαιτέρω συμμετοχή από τις ΗΠΑ Στην 
ακόλουθη αλληλογραφία, ο γραμματέας του κράτους Robert 
Λάνσινγκ και ο Πρόεδρος Wilson περιέγραψαν την ανάγκη να 
πλαισιώσουν προσεκτικά την εισβολή ως υπεράσπιση των ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ 
συνόρων παρά την παρέμβαση στη μεξικάνικη επανάσταση. Η 
προκύπτουσα εισβολή, που οδηγήθηκε από το στρατηγό John 
Pershing, ήταν συνολικό fiasco. Απέτυχε να εντοπίσει 
τη βίλα και το αυξανόμενο συναίσθημα αντι-ΗΠΑ και ο μεξικάνικος 
εθνικιστής επιλύει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1916, el chalet de Francisco, arranque de cinta
de las sublevaciones campesinas en México norteño, atacó Columbus, 
New México, en una tentativa de exponer la colaboración mexicana del
gobierno con los Estados Unidos. Presidente Woodrow Wilson 
respondió pidiendo una invasión de México. Cinco años 
después del principio de la revolución mexicana, que fue 
caracterizada por la esperanza del cambio social tan bien como muerte,
hambre, y la violencia, mucha el mexicano no dio la bienvenida a la 
implicación adicional por los E.E.U.U.. En la correspondencia 
siguiente, la secretaria del estado Roberto Lansing y presidente 
Wilson describieron la necesidad de enmarcar cuidadosamente la 
invasión mientras que una defensa de ESTADOS UNIDOS confina más bien
que interferencia en la revolución mexicana. La invasión que 
resultaba, conducida por general Juan Pershing, era un fiasco 
total. No pudo establecer el chalet y aumentó el sentimiento de
anti-U.S. y la resolución nacionalista mexicana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087416</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106474</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/avoid-the-use-of-the-word-intervention-wilson-and-lansing-on-the-u-s-invasion-of-mexico</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
