<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107035</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107035</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205654</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Thomas Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Τχομας Moran</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Thomas Moran</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">was one of the major landscape painters of his day, and painted some of America's most prominent natural treasures, including the Rocky Mountains, the Grand Canyon, and Yellowstone. He also arranged for the first government-sponsored survey of Yellowstone, and his images were later reported to have played a decisive role in the debate that led to the establishment of Yellowstone as the first national park in March 1872.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">war einer der Hauptlandschaftsmaler seines Tages 
und malte etwas von Amerikas vorstehendsten natürlichen Schätzen, 
einschließlich die felsigen Berge, dem Grand Canyon und Yellowstone. 
Er ordnete auch für die erste staatlich geförderte Übersicht 
von Yellowstone, und seine Bilder wurden später berichtet, eine 
entscheidende Rolle in der Debatte gespielt zu haben, die das zu die 
Einrichtung von Yellowstone als der erste Nationalpark im März 1872 
führte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">était un des peintres principaux d'horizontal de 
son jour, et a peint une partie de trésors normaux de l'Amérique les
plus en avant, y compris les montagnes rocheuses, de la gorge grande, 
et de Yellowstone. Il a également arrangé pour la première 
étude commanditée par le gouvernement de Yellowstone, et on a 
enregistré que ses images plus tard jouent un rôle décisif au cours
de la discussion que cela a menée à l'établissement de Yellowstone 
comme premier parc national en mars 1872.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">era um dos pintores principais da paisagem de seu 
dia, e pintava algum dos tesouros naturais os mais proeminentes de 
América, including as montanhas rochosas, da garganta grande, e de 
Yellowstone. Arranjou também para o primeiro exame 
government-sponsored de Yellowstone, e suas imagens foram relatadas 
mais tarde para ter jogado um papel decisive no debate que aquela 
conduziu ao estabelecimento de Yellowstone como o primeiro parque 
nacional em março 1872.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">era uno dei pittori principali di paesaggio del 
suo giorno ed ha verniciato alcuno dei tesori naturali più prominenti
dell'America, compreso le montagne rocciose, di grande canyon e di 
Yellowstone. Egualmente ha organizzato per la prima indagine 
government-sponsored di Yellowstone e le sue immagini successivamente 
sono state segnalate per svolgere un ruolo decisivo nel dibattito che 
quella ha condotto all'istituzione di Yellowstone come il primo parco 
nazionale nel mese di marzo del 1872.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ήταν ένας από τους σημαντικότερους ζωγράφους τοπίων 
της ημέρας του, και χρωμάτισε μερικών από τους πιό προεξέχοντες 
φυσικούς θησαυρούς της Αμερικής, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των δύσκολων
βουνών, το μεγάλο φαράγγι, και Yellowstone. Τακτοποίησε 
επίσης για την πρώτη χρηματοδοτούμενη από την κυβέρνηση έρευνα 
Yellowstone, και οι εικόνες του αναφέρθηκαν αργότερα για να 
έχουν διαδραματίσει έναν αποφασιστικό ρόλο στη συζήτηση που 
οδήγησε στην καθιέρωση Yellowstone ως πρώτο εθνικό πάρκο τον 
Μάρτιο του 1872.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">era uno de los pintores principales del paisaje de
su día, y pintó algo de los tesoros naturales más prominentes de 
América, incluyendo las montañas rocosas, de la barranca magnífica,
y de Yellowstone. Él también arregló para la primera encuesta
government-sponsored de Yellowstone, y sus imágenes fueron señaladas
más adelante para haber desempeñado un papel decisivo en el 
discusión que ésa condujo al establecimiento de Yellowstone como el 
primer parque nacional en marcha de 1872.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205654</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107035</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/thomas-moran</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
