<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106546</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106546</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087467</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Captured By Indians: Mary Jemison Becomes an Indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erfaßt Durch Indians: Mary Jemison wird ein
Inder</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Capturé Par Indians : Mary Jemison devient 
une Indienne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capturado Por Indians: Mary Jemison 
transforma-se um indian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bloccato Da Indians: Mary Jemison diventa un
indiano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συλλήφθείτε από Ινδούς: Θ*Μαρυ Jemison 
Becomes ένας Ινδός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capturado Por Indians: Maria Jemison hace un
indio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1753, fifteen year old Mary Jemison was captured by Indians along the Pennsylvania frontier during the Seven Years War between the French, English, and Indian peoples of North America. She was adopted and incorporated into the Senecas, a familiar practice among Iroquois and other Indian peoples seeking to replace a lost sibling or spouse. Mary married and raised a family in the decades before and after the American Revolution; many captives, once adopted and integrated into an Indian community, refused the opportunity to return home, finding life in Indian society more rewarding. In 1823 Mary Jemison related her life story to James Seaver, a doctor who lived near her home in western New York. Seaver's story of "the white woman of the Genessee," as she became known, sold over 100,000 copies in 1824.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1753 wurde fünfzehn Einjahres Mary Jemison von 
Indians entlang der Pennsylvania Grenze während der sieben Jahre War 
zwischen den französischen, englischen und indischen Völkern von 
Nordamerika erfaßt. Sie wurde in die Senecas, in eine vertraute
Praxis unter Irokesen und in andere Indervölker, die suchen, 
verlorenen Geschwister oder einen Gatten zu ersetzen angenommen und 
enthalten. Mary heiratete und hob eine Familie in den Dekaden 
vorher und nachher die amerikanische Umdrehung an; viele 
Gefangene, sobald angenommen und in eine indische Gemeinschaft 
integriert, abgelehnt der Gelegenheit, Haupt zurückzubringen, das 
Leben in der indischen belohnenden Gesellschaft finden. Mary 
1823 stand Jemison ihre Lebengeschichte auf James Seaver, ein Doktor 
in Verbindung, der nahe ihrem Haus in Westnew York lebte. 
Geschichte Seavers "der weißen Frau des Genessee,", wie sie 
bekannt wurde, verkauft über 100.000 Exemplaren 1824.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1753, quinze ans vieille Mary Jemison ont été
capturés par Indians le long de la frontière de la Pennsylvanie 
pendant les sept années font la guerre entre les peuples français, 
anglais, et indiens de l'Amérique du nord. Elle a été 
adoptée et incorporée aux Senecas, à une pratique familière parmi 
le Iroquois et à d'autres peuples d'Indien recherchant à substituer 
un enfant de mêmes parents ou un conjoint perdu. Mary a 
épousé et a élevé une famille dans les décennies avant et après la 
révolution américaine ; beaucoup de captifs, une fois 
qu'adopté et intégré dans une communauté indienne, refusée 
l'occasion de renvoyer à la maison, trouvant la vie dans la société
indienne plus récompensant. En Mary 1823 Jemison a associé sa 
histoire de la vie à James Seaver, un docteur qui a vécu près
de sa maison à New York occidental. L'histoire de Seaver "de la
femme blanche du Genessee," comme elle est devenue notoire, vendu plus
de 100.000 copies en 1824.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1753, quinze anos Mary velha Jemison foram 
capturados por Indians ao longo da fronteira de Pensilvânia durante 
os sete anos guerreiam entre os povos franceses, ingleses, e indian de
America do Norte. Foi adotada e incorporada nos senecas, em uma 
prática familiar entre o iroquois e em outros povos do indian que 
procuram substituir um sibling ou um esposo perdido. Mary casou 
e levantou uma família nas décadas before.and.after a volta 
americana; muitos cativos, uma vez que adotado e integrado em 
uma comunidade indian, recusada a oportunidade de retornar home, 
encontrando a vida na sociedade indian que recompensa. Em Mary 
1823 Jemison relacionou sua história da vida a James Seaver, um 
doutor que vivesse perto de sua HOME em New York ocidental. 
História de Seaver "da mulher branca do Genessee," como se 
tornou sabida, vendido sobre 100.000 cópias em 1824.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1753, quindici anni Mary Jemison sono stati 
bloccati da Indians lungo la frontiera della Pensilvania durante i 
sette anni fanno la guerra fra la gente francese, inglese ed indiana 
dell'America del Nord. È stata adottata ed incorporato stata 
nei senecas, in una pratica esperta fra il iroquois e nell'altra gente
dell'indiano che cerca di sostituire un fratello germano o uno sposo 
perso. Mary ha sposato ed alzato una famiglia nelle decadi prima
e dopo la rivoluzione americana; molti prigionieri, una volta 
che adottato ed integrato in una Comunità indiana, rifiutata 
l'occasione restituire domestico, trovando vita nella società indiana
che ricompensa. In Mary 1823 Jemison ha collegato la sua storia 
di vita a James Seaver, un medico che ha vissuto vicino alla sua sede 
a New York occidentale. Storia del Seaver "della donna bianca 
del Genessee," come è stato conosciuta, venduto oltre 100.000 copie 
in 1824.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1753, δεκαπέντε έτος ηλικίας Mary Jemison 
συλλήφθηκε από Ινδούς κατά μήκος των συνόρων της Πενσυλβανίας 
κατά τη διάρκεια των επτά ετών πολεμικών μεταξύ των γαλλικών, 
αγγλικών, και ινδικών λαών της Βόρειας Αμερικής. 
Υιοθετήθηκε και ενσωματώθηκε στο Senecas, μια γνωστή 
πρακτική μεταξύ iroquois και άλλων ινδικών λαών που 
επιδιώκουν να αντικαταστήσει έναν χαμένο αμφιθαλή ή έναν 
σύζυγο. Θ*Μαρυ πάντρεψε και ανέθρεψε μια οικογένεια στις 
δεκαετίες πριν και μετά από την αμερικανική επανάσταση  
πολλοί αιχμάλωτοι, μόλις υιοθετημένος και ενσωματωμένος σε 
μια ινδική κοινότητα, αρνήθηκε την ευκαιρία να επιστραφεί το 
σπίτι, βρίσκοντας τη ζωή στην ινδική κοινωνία που ανταμείβει. 
Το 1823 Mary Jemison αφορούσε την ιστορία ζωής της 
james Seaver, ένας γιατρός που έζησε κοντά στο σπίτι της 
στη δυτική Νέα Υόρκη. Ιστορία Seaver "της λευκιάς 
γυναίκας του Genessee," καθώς έγινε γνωστή, πωλημένος πάνω 
από 100.000 αντίγραφα το 1824.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1753, quince años vieja Maria Jemison fueron 
capturados por indians a lo largo de la frontera de Pennsylvania 
durante los siete años guerrean entre la gente francesa, inglesa, e 
india de Norteamérica. La adoptaron y fueron incorporada en los
senecas, la práctica familiar entre iroquois y la otra gente del 
indio que intentaba substituir a un hermano o a un esposo perdido. 
Maria casó y levantó a familia en las décadas antes y 
después la revolución americana; muchos cautivos, una vez que 
esté adoptado e integrado en una comunidad india, rechazada la 
oportunidad de volver casero, encontrando vida en la sociedad india 
que recompensa. En Maria 1823 Jemison relacionó su historia de 
la vida con James Seaver, doctor que vivió cerca de su hogar en Nueva
York occidental. Historia de Seaver "de la mujer blanca del 
Genessee," como ella se sabía, vendido sobre 100.000 copias en 1824.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087467</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106546</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/captured-by-indians-mary-jemison-becomes-an-indian</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
