<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107356</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107356</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087401</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Andrew Carnegie's Ode to Steelmaking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Andrew Carnegies Ode zur Stahlerzeugung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ode d'Andrew Carnegie's à l'aciérie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ode de Andrew Carnegie ao steelmaking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ode del Andrew Carnegie a fabbricazione 
dell'acciaio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ωδή του Andrew Carnegie's στη σιδηρουργία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Oda de Andrew Carnegie a la acería</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Known best by his knack for moneymaking, turn-of-the-century steel magnate Andrew Carnegie nonetheless found a moment to pen a one-sided poetic tribute to the "eighth wonder" of the world--steel manufacturing in his Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, plant. This brief poem reflected how he (and other contemporaries) viewed the monumental process of steelmaking. The poem was notable for its use of passive voice and the absence of workers--miners, railroad men, or blast furnace crews--from the process by which "one pound of solid steel" came to be.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gut gewußt durch seine Geschicklichkeit für 
Geldverdienen, fand Jahrhundertwendestahlmagnat Andrew Carnegie 
nichtsdestoweniger einen Moment zur Feder ein einseitiger poetischer 
Tribut zum "achten Wunder" der Welt -- Stahlherstellung in seinem 
Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Betrieb. Dieses kurze Gedicht 
reflektierte, wie er (und andere Zeitgenossen) den hervorragenden 
Prozeß der Stahlerzeugung ansahen. Das Gedicht war für seinen 
Gebrauch von passiver Stimme bemerkenswert und die Abwesenheit der 
Arbeiter -- Bergmänner, Eisenbahnmänner oder Hochofenmannschaften --
vom Prozeß, durch den "man vom festen Stahl" zerstoßen, kam zu 
sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Connu mieux par son talent pour l'acquisition de 
l'argent, le magnat en acier Andrew Carnegie de tourner-de-le-siècle 
a néanmoins trouvé un moment au crayon lecteur un hommage poétique 
recto à la "huitième merveille" du monde -- fabrication en acier à 
son Pittsburgh, Pennsylvanie, usine. Cette brève poésie a 
reflété comment lui (et d'autres contemporains) ont visualisé le 
processus monumental de l'aciérie. La poésie était notable à
son utilisation de voix passive et à l'absence des ouvriers -- 
mineurs, hommes de chemin de fer, ou haut fourneau sert d'équipier -- 
from le processus par lequel "une livre d'acier plein" est venue pour 
être.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sabido melhor por seu knack para a aquisição de 
dinheiro, o magnate de aço Andrew Carnegie de gir-$$$-$$$-SÉCULO 
nonetheless encontrou um momento à pena um tributo poético simples 
à "oitava maravilha" do mundo -- manufacturing de aço em seu 
Pittsburgh, Pensilvânia, planta. Este poema breve refletiu como
(e outros comtemporâneos) viram o processo monumental do steelmaking.
O poema era notável para seu uso da voz passiva e a ausência 
dos trabalhadores -- mineiros, homens da estrada de ferro, ou grupos 
do alto-forno -- do processo por que "uma libra do aço contínuo" 
veio ser.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Saputo il più bene dalla sua abilità per il far 
soldi, il magnate d'acciaio Andrew Carnegie di gir-de-$$$-SECOLO ciò 
nonostante ha trovato un momento alla penna un tributo poetic su un 
solo lato "all'ottavo wonder" del mondo -- manufacturing d'acciaio a 
sua Pittsburgh, Pensilvania, pianta. Questo breve poem ha 
riflesso come lui (ed altri contemporanei) hanno osservato il processo
monumental della fabbricazione dell'acciaio. Il poem era 
notevole per il relativo uso della voce passiva e l'assenza degli 
operai -- minatori, uomini della ferrovia, o squadre del forno -- dal 
processo tramite cui "una libbra di acciaio solido" è venuto essere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γνωστός καλύτερα από την ικανότητά του για 
αποδοτικούς, τον στροφή-$$$-Ο-ΑΙΏΝΑ ο μεγιστάνας Andrew 
Carnegie χάλυβα εν τούτοις βρήκε μια στιγμή για να περιφράξει 
έναν μονόπλευρο ποιητικό φόρο στη "όγδοη κατάπληξη" του κόσμου 
-- κατασκευή χάλυβα στο Πίτσμπουργκ του, Πενσυλβανία, 
εγκαταστάσεις. Αυτό το συνοπτικό ποίημα απεικόνισε πώς 
αυτός (και άλλοι σύγχρονοι) εμφάνισαν τη μνημειακή διαδικασία 
της σιδηρουργίας. Το ποίημα ήταν ξεχωριστό για τη χρήση 
παθητικής φωνής του και την απουσία εργαζομένων -- ανθρακωρύχοι, 
άτομα σιδηροδρόμου, ή πληρώματα φούρνων φυσήματος -- από τη 
διαδικασία από την οποία "μια λίβρα του στερεού χάλυβα" ήρθε να
είναι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sabido lo más mejor posible por su destreza para 
el manantial de beneficios, el magnate de acero Andrew Carnegie del 
dar vuelta-de-$$$-SIGLO no obstante encontró un momento a la pluma un
tributo poético unilateral a la "octava maravilla" del mundo -- 
fabricación de acero en su Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, planta. 
Este poema abreviado reflejó cómo él (y otros 
contemporáneos) vieron el proceso monumental de la acería. El 
poema era notable para su uso de la voz pasiva y la ausencia de los 
trabajadores -- mineros, hombres del ferrocarril, o equipos del alto 
horno alto -- del proceso por el cual "una libra de acero sólido" 
vino estar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087401</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107356</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/andrew-carnegies-ode-to-steelmaking</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
