<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106501</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106501</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206354</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Putting DNA to Work</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Setzen von von DNA, um zu arbeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mise de l'ADN pour travailler</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pondo o DNA para trabalhar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mettere DNA per funzionare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τοποθέτηση του DNA για να εργαστεί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Poner la DNA para trabajar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site looks at where DNA is found, similarities in the DNA of humans and other species, and how traits are inherited from one generation to the next. Learn how DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid), discovered 50 years ago, is used today to detect diseases, improve crops, and catch criminals. The museum has identified unique, inquiry-based activities related to this exhibit (physical and virtual) that are designed for middle and high-school students and adhere to the National Academies' National Science Education Standards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site betrachtet, wo DNA gefunden wird, 
Ähnlichkeiten in der DNA der Menschen und andere Sorte und wie 
Merkmale von einem Erzeugung zum folgenden übernommen werden. 
Vor erlernen Sie, wie DNA (Desoxyribonukleinsäure), entdeckt 50
Jahren, heute benutzt wird, um Krankheiten zu entdecken, Getreide zu 
verbessern und Verbrecher abzufangen. Das Museum hat die 
eindeutigen, Anfrage-gegründeten Aktivitäten gekennzeichnet, die auf
dieser Ausstellung in Verbindung gestanden werden (körperliche und 
virtuelle) die für mittlere und High School Kursteilnehmer konzipiert
sind und die nationalen nationalen Standards Ausbildung Wissenschaft 
der Akademien befolgen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site regarde où l'ADN est trouvée, des 
similitudes dans l'ADN des humains et d'autres espèces, et la 
façon dont des traits sont hérités d'une génération au prochain. 
Apprenez comment ADN (acide désoxyribonucléique), découverte 
il y a 50 ans, est employée aujourd'hui pour détecter les maladies, 
pour améliorer des collectes, et pour attraper des criminels. 
Le musée a identifié les seules, enquête-basées activités 
liées à cet objet exposé qui (physiques et virtuelles) sont 
conçues pour des étudiants de lycée moyen et et adhèrent aux 
normes nationales d'éducation de la Science des académies 
nationales.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local olha onde o DNA é encontrado, 
similaridades no DNA dos seres humanos e a outra espécie, e como os 
traços são herdados de uma geração ao seguinte. Aprenda como
o DNA (ácido deoxyribonucleic), descoberto 50 anos há, é usado hoje
detectar doenças, melhorar colheitas, e travar criminosos. O 
museu identificou as atividades originais, inquérito-baseadas 
relacionadas a esta exibição que (físicas e virtuais) são 
projetadas para estudantes da High School média e e aderem aos 
padrões nacionais da instrução da ciência dos academies' 
nacionais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo guarda dove il DNA è trovato, 
somiglianze nel DNA degli esseri umani e l'altra specie e come le 
caratteristiche sono ereditate da una generazione al seguente. 
Impari come il DNA (acido deoxyribonucleic), scoperto 50 anni 
fa, è usato oggi per diagnosticare le malattie, migliorare i raccolti
e per interferire i criminali. Il museo ha identificato le 
attività uniche e inchiesta-basate relative a questa esposizione che 
(fisiche e virtuali) sono progettate per gli allievi della High School
centrale ed e si aderiscono standard nazionali di formazione di 
scienza alle Accademie nazionali '.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή εξετάζει όπου το DNA βρίσκεται, 
ομοιότητες στο DNA των ανθρώπων και άλλα είδη, και το πώς τα 
γνωρίσματα κληρονομούνται από μια γενεά στην επόμενη. 
Μάθετε πώς το DNA (δεσοξυριβονουκλεϊνικό οξύ), που 
ανακαλύπτεται 50 έτη πριν, χρησιμοποιείται σήμερα για να 
ανιχνεύσει τις ασθένειες, να βελτιώσουν τις συγκομιδές, και τους 
εγκληματίες σύλληψης. Το μουσείο έχει προσδιορίσει τις 
μοναδικές, έρευνα-βασισμένες στο δραστηριότητες σχετικές με αυτό
το έκθεμα (φυσικές και εικονικές) που σχεδιάζονται για τους 
σπουδαστές μεσών και υψηλός-σχολείων και εμμένουν στα εθνικά 
πρότυπα εκπαίδευσης επιστήμης των εθνικών ακαδημιών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio mira donde se encuentra la DNA, las 
semejanzas en la DNA de seres humanos y la otra especie, y cómo los 
rasgos se heredan a partir de una generación al siguiente. 
Aprenda cómo la DNA (ácido deoxyribonucleic), descubierta hace
50 años, se utiliza hoy para detectar enfermedades, para mejorar 
cosechas, y para coger a criminales. El museo ha identificado 
las actividades únicas, pregunta-basadas relacionadas con este objeto
expuesto que (físicas y virtuales) se diseñan para los estudiantes 
de la High School media y secundaria y adhieren a los estándares 
nacionales de la educación de la ciencia de las academias nacionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206354</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106501</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/putting-dna-to-work</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
