<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107094</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107094</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087289</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Damaging Impression of Hollywood Has Spread": Movie "Czar" Eric Johnston Testifies before HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein zerstörender Eindruck von Hollywood hat" 
verbritten: Film "Zar" Eric Johnston bezeugt vor HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une impression préjudiciable de Hollywood a 
écarté" : Le film "tsar" Eric Johnston témoigne avant HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma impressão prejudicial de Hollywood 
espalhou": O filme "czar" Eric Johnston testifies antes de HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un'impressione offensiva di Hollywood si è 
sparsa": Il film "czar" Eric Johnston testimonia prima 
di HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια καταστρεπτική εντύπωση Hollywood έχει 
διαδώσει": Κινηματογράφος "Czar" Eric Johnston 
Testifies πριν από HUAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una impresión perjudicial de Hollywood se ha 
separado": La película "czar" Eric Johnston atestigua antes de 
HUAC</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC) held hearings in October 1947 on Communist activity in Hollywood. In the following testimony, Eric Johnston, a successful businessman who in 1945 succeeded Will H. Hays as President of the Motion Picture Association of America--the industry's institution for self-regulation--defended Hollywood against HUAC's attacks and complained vigorously that the "atmosphere of fear" resulting from the investigation precluded the production of "good and honest motion pictures." Although Johnston earlier had argued against the Committee's request that studio officials discharge known Communists, in November 1947, after ten screenwriters and directors who refused to cooperate with the Committee were cited for contempt of Congress, Johnston and the studio heads issued a statement that the studios would not employ Communists and would dismiss or suspend the ten. HUAC then agreed to stop investigating studios and the content of films and limited their inquiries to personnel. Although Johnston insisted that the industry did not engage in blacklisting, those in the filmmaking community who did not deny that they were Communists and refused to inform on others when questioned at HUAC hearings were prohibited from working in the industry.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Haus-Ausschuß für Un-Amerikanische 
Aktivitäten (HUAC) hielt Hörfähigkeiten im Oktober 1947 auf 
kommunistischer Aktivität in Hollywood an. Im folgenden Zeugnis
Eric Johnston, ein erfolgreicher Geschäftsmann der in 1945 gefolgtem 
Willen H. Hays, wie Präsident der Bewegung Abbildung Verbindung von 
Amerika -- die Anstalt der Industrie für Self-regulation -- 
verteidigtes Hollywood gegen Angriffe HUACs und kräftig beschwert, 
daß die "Atmosphäre der Furcht", die aus der Untersuchung 
resultiert, ausschloß die Produktion "der guten und ehrlichen 
Bewegung Abbildungen." Obgleich Johnston früh gegen den Antrag 
des Ausschusses argumentiert hatte, daß Studiobeamte bekannte 
Kommunisten, im November 1947 entladen, nachdem 10 Drehbuchautoren und 
Direktoren, die ablehnten, mit dem Ausschuß zusammenzuarbeiten, für 
Verachtung des Kongresses zitiert wurden, gaben Johnston und die 
Studioköpfe eine Anweisung heraus, daß die Studios würden nicht 
Kommunisten beschäftigen und würden die 10 entlassen oder 
verschieben. HUAC dannWAR damit einverstanden Studios, und den 
Inhalt der Filme nachzuforschen zu stoppen und begrenzte ihre Anfragen
auf Personal. Obgleich Johnston beharrte, daß die Industrie 
sich nicht beim Auf die schwarze Liste setzen engagierte, die in der 
filmmaking Gemeinschaft, die nicht verweigerte, daß sie Kommunisten 
und abgelehnt, sich auf anderen zu informieren, als gefragt an den 
HUAC Hörfähigkeiten, waren wurden verboten vom Arbeiten in der 
Industrie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le comité de Chambre des activités 
Un-Américaines (HUAC) a tenu des auditions en octobre 1947 sur 
l'activité communiste dans Hollywood. Dans le témoignage 
suivant, Eric Johnston, un homme d'affaires réussi qui dans la 
volonté réussie par 1945 H. Hays comme président de l'association 
de film cinématographique de l'Amérique -- l'établissement de 
l'industrie pour art de l'auto-portrait-regulation -- defended Hollywood contre les
attaques de HUAC et plaint vigoureusement que l'"atmosphère de la 
crainte" résultant de la recherche a exclu la production des "bons et
honnêtes films cinématographiques." Bien que Johnston plus 
tôt ait argué du fait contre la demande du Comité que les 
fonctionnaires de studio déchargent les communistes connus, en 
novembre 1947, après que dix scénaristes et directeurs qui ont 
refusé de coopérer avec le Comité aient été cités pour le 
mépris du congrès, Johnston et les têtes de studio ont émis un 
rapport que les studios n'emploieraient pas des communistes et 
écarteraient ou suspendraient les dix. HUAC a alors accepté de
cesser d'étudier les studios et la teneur des films et a limité 
leurs enquêtes au personnel. Bien que Johnston ait insisté sur
le fait que l'industrie ne s'est pas engagée dans la mise sur liste 
noire, ceux dans la communauté filmmaking qui n'a pas nié qu'elles 
étaient des communistes et refusé d'informer sur d'autres une fois 
interrogées aux auditions de HUAC ont été interdites de travailler 
dans l'industrie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O comitê da casa nas atividades Un-Americanas 
(HUAC) prendeu hearings em outubro 1947 na atividade comunista em 
Hollywood. No seguinte testimony, Eric Johnston, um homem de 
negócios bem sucedido que na vontade sucedida 1945 H. Feno como 
presidente da associação do retrato de movimento de América -- 
instituição da indústria para o self-regulation -- Hollywood 
defendido de encontro aos ataques de HUAC e queixado vigorosa que a 
"atmosfera do medo" que resulta da investigação impossibilitou a 
produção "de retratos de movimento bons e honestos." Embora 
Johnston mais cedo discutisse de encontro ao pedido do comitê que os 
oficiais do estúdio descarregam comunistas conhecidos, em novembro 
1947, depois que dez screenwriters e diretores que recusaram cooperar 
com o comitê cited para o contempt de congress, Johnston e as 
cabeças do estúdio emitiram uma indicação que os estúdios não 
empregariam comunistas e demitiriam ou suspenderiam os dez. HUAC
então concordou parar de investigar estúdios e o índice das 
películas e limitou seus inquéritos ao pessoal. Embora 
Johnston insistisse que a indústria não acoplou em por, aquelas na 
comunidade filmmaking que não negou que eram comunistas e recusado 
informar em outros quando questionados em hearings de HUAC foram 
proibidas de trabalhar na indústria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il comitato della Camera delle attività 
ONU-Americane (HUAC) ha tenuto le udienze nel mese di ottobre del 1947
su attività comunista in Hollywood. Nella seguente 
testimonianza, Eric Johnston, un uomo d'affari riuscito che nella 
volontà riuscita 1945 H. Hays come presidente dell'associazione del 
cinema dell'America -- l'istituzione dell'industria per 
autoregolazione -- Hollywood difeso contro gli attacchi del HUAC e 
protestato vigoroso che "l'atmosfera di timore" che deriva dalla 
ricerca ha precluso la produzione "di buon e cinema onesto." 
Anche se Johnston più presto aveva sostenuto contro la 
richiesta del comitato che i funzionari dell'studio scaricano i 
comunisti conosciuti, nel mese di novembre del 1947, dopo che dieci 
screenwriters e direttori che hanno rifiutato di cooperare con il 
comitato si citino per contempt del congresso, Johnston e le teste 
dell'studio hanno pubblicato un'istruzione che gli studi non 
impiegherebbero i comunisti ed allontanerebbero o sospenderebbero i 
dieci. HUAC allora ha accosentito per smettere di studiare
gli studi ed il contenuto delle pellicole ed ha limitato le loro 
inchieste ai personali. Anche se Johnston ha insistito che 
l'industria non si è agganciata nella lista nera, quelle nella 
Comunità filmmaking che non ha negato che erano comunisti e rifiutato
di informare su altri una volta interrogate alle udienze di HUAC sono 
state proibite dal funzionamento nell'industria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Επιτροπή Βουλών των αντιαμερικανικών δραστηριοτήτων 
(HUAC) πραγματοποίησε τις ακροάσεις τον Οκτώβριο του 1947 για
την κομμουνιστική δραστηριότητα σε Hollywood. Στην 
ακόλουθη κατάθεση, Eric Johnston, ένας επιτυχής 
επιχειρηματίας που το 1945 πετυχημένος Χ. Hays ως Πρόεδρο της
ένωσης ταινιών της Αμερικής -- το όργανο της βιομηχανίας 
για την αυτορύθμιση -- υπεράσπισε Hollywood ενάντια στις 
επιθέσεις HUAC και παραπονέθηκε σθεναρά ότι η "ατμόσφαιρα του 
φόβου" ως αποτέλεσμα της έρευνας απέκλεισε την παραγωγή των 
"καλών και τίμιων ταινιών." Αν και Johnston νωρίτερα 
είχε μιλήσει ενάντια στο αίτημα της Επιτροπής ότι οι ανώτεροι 
υπάλληλοι στούντιο απαλλάσσουν τους γνωστούς κομμουνιστές, τον 
Νοέμβριο του 1947, μετά από δέκα screenwriters και οι 
σκηνοθέτες που αρνήθηκαν να συνεργαστούν με την Επιτροπή 
αναφέρθηκαν για την περιφρόνηση του συνεδρίου, Johnston και τα 
κεφάλια στούντιο εξέδωσαν μια δήλωση ότι τα στούντιο δεν θα 
απασχολούσαν τους κομμουνιστές και θα απομάκρυναν ή θα ανέστελλαν
τα δέκα. HUAC συμφώνησε έπειτα να σταματήσει τα 
στούντιο και το περιεχόμενο των ταινιών και περιόρισε τις 
έρευνές τους στο προσωπικό. Αν και Johnston επέμεινε ότι
η βιομηχανία δεν συμμετείχε στην καταχώρηση στη μαύρη λίστα, 
εκείνοι στη filmmaking κοινότητα που δεν αρνήθηκε ότι ήταν 
κομμουνιστές και αρνήθηκαν να ενημερώσουν για άλλους πότε 
εξετάζονται στις ακροάσεις HUAC απαγορεύθηκαν από την εργασία 
στη βιομηχανία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El comité de la casa sobre las actividades 
Un-Americanas (HUAC) llevó a cabo audiencias en octubre de 1947 en 
actividad comunista en Hollywood. En el testimonio siguiente, 
Eric Johnston, hombre de negocios acertado que en la voluntad tenida 
éxito 1945 H. Hays como presidente de la asociación de la película 
de América -- la institución de la industria para la autoregulación
-- Hollywood defendido contra los ataques de HUAC y quejado vigoroso 
que la "atmósfera del miedo" que resultaba de la investigación 
imposibilitó la producción "de las películas buenas y honestas." 
Aunque Johnston había discutido anterior contra la petición 
del comité que los funcionarios del estudio descarguen a comunistas 
conocidos, en noviembre de 1947, después de que citaran a diez 
guionistas y directores que rechazaron cooperar con el comité para el
desprecio del congreso, Johnston y las pistas del estudio publicaron 
una declaración que los estudios no emplearían a comunistas y 
despedirían o suspenderían los diez. HUAC después acordó 
parar el investigar de los estudios y del contenido de películas y 
limitó sus preguntas al personal. Aunque Johnston insistió que
la industria no enganchó a poner, ésos en la comunidad filmmaking 
que no negó que eran comunistas y rechazado informar en otros cuando 
estaban preguntada en las audiencias de HUAC fueron prohibidas del 
trabajo en la industria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087289</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107094</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-damaging-impression-of-hollywood-has-spread-movie-czar-eric-johnston-testifies-before-huac</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
