<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107728</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107728</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087345</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Traitor to the Movement"?: A Former SDS and Women's Liberation Activist Testifies before Congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Traitor zur Bewegung"?: Ein ehemaliger 
SDS und der Frauen Befreiung-Aktivist bezeugt vor Kongreß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un traître au mouvement" ? : Un ancien 
activiste de libération de SDS et de femmes témoigne devant le 
congrès</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um traitor ao movimento"?: Uma activista 
anterior do liberation do SDS e das mulheres testifies antes do 
congress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un traitor al movimento"?: Un ex 
Attivista di liberazione delle donne e di SDS testimonia prima del 
congresso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας προδότης στη μετακίνηση";: Ένα 
προηγούμενο ενεργό στέλεχος απελευθέρωσης SDS και των γυναικών
πιστοποιεί πριν από το συνέδριο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un traidor al movimiento"?: Un activista 
anterior de la liberación del SDS y de las mujeres atestigua antes de
congreso</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) was founded in 1962 to change the world by fostering participatory democracy and personal authenticity. Heavily influenced by civil rights organizations, SDS initially operated in inner cities and college campuses to combat racism and discrimination. By the mid-1960s, many activists focused on antiwar activities as American troop involvement in Vietnam escalated. Frustrated with male domination in SDS, leftist women formed feminist splinter groups that eventually aligned with reform organizations to create a new women's liberation movement. In the following testimony before a 1970 Congressional committee investigating activist "subversion," Marjorie King, a former chairman of WITCH (Women's International Terrorist Conspiracy from Hell--a guerilla theater offshoot of SDS) described her experiences with radical groups in the Chicago area. This hearing was held a few weeks after an accidental explosion killed three young members of the revolutionary group the Weathermen, an offshoot of SDS, in a Greenwich Village townhouse where the group was manufacturing bombs. As violence coupled with police repression and infiltration signaled the end of a once nonviolent New Left, a new women's movement, also inspired by the civil rights movement, gained momentum.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer für eine demokratische 
Gesellschaft (SDS) wurden 1962 gegründet, um die Welt zu ändern, 
indem man teilnehmende Demokratie und persönliche Echtheit förderte.
Schwer beeinflußt durch Zivilrechtorganisationen, funktionierte
SDS zuerst in den Innenstädten und in den Hochschulcampus, um 
Rassismus und Unterscheidung zu bekämpfen. Bis zum den 
Mid-1960s konzentrierten viele Aktivisten auf Antikriegsaktivitäten, 
während amerikanische Truppemiteinbeziehung in Vietnam sich 
entwickelte. Frustriert mit männlicher Herrschaft in SDS, 
bildeten linksgerichtete Frauen feministische Splittergruppen, die 
schließlich mit Verbesserungorganisationen übereinstimmten, um eine 
Befreiungbewegung der neuen Frauen zu erstellen. Im folgenden 
Zeugnis vor einem nachforschenden Aktivisten "Subversion des 
Kongreßausschusses 1970," beschrieb Marjorie König, ein ehemaliger 
Vorsitzender der HEXE (internationale Terrorist-Verschwörung der 
Frauen von der Hölle -- eine Bandenkämpfertheaterabzweigung von SDS)
sie Erfahrungen mit radikalen Gruppen im Chicago Bereich. Diese 
Hörfähigkeit wurde einige Wochen nach einer versehentlichen 
Explosion beendete drei junge Bauteile der revolutionären Gruppe die 
Weathermen, eine Abzweigung von SDS, in einer Greenwich 
Villagestadtwohnung angehalten, in der die Gruppe Herstellung Bomben 
war. Wie die Gewalttätigkeit, die mit Polizei Unterdrückung 
und Infiltration verbunden wurde, dem Ende eines einmal gewaltlosen 
neuen links signalisierte, eine Bewegung der neuen Frauen, auch 
angespornt durch die Zivilrechtbewegung, gewonnenes Momentum.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des étudiants pour une société démocratique 
(SDS) ont été fondés en 1962 pour changer le monde en stimulant la 
démocratie participatoire et l'authenticité personnelle. 
Fortement influencé par des organismes de droits civiques, le 
SDS a au commencement fonctionné dans les centres urbains et les 
campus d'université pour combattre le racisme et la discrimination. 
Par le milieu des années 60, beaucoup d'activistes se sont 
concentrés sur des activités pacifistes pendant que la participation
américaine de troupe au Vietnam escaladait. Frustré avec la 
domination mâle dans le SDS, les femmes de gauche ont constitué les 
groupes féministes d'éclat qui ont par la suite aligné avec des 
organismes de réforme pour créer un mouvement de la libération des 
nouvelles femmes. Dans le témoignage suivant avant un activiste
d'investigation "subversion du comité 1970 congressionnel," le roi de
Marjorie, un ancien Président de la SORCIÈRE (conspiration 
internationale de la terroriste des femmes d'enfer -- une ramification
de théâtre de guérillero de SDS) l'a décrite des expériences avec
les groupes radicaux dans la région de Chicago. Cette audition 
a été tenue quelques semaines après une explosion accidentelle a 
détruit trois jeunes membres du groupe révolutionnaire les 
Météorologues, une ramification de SDS, dans une maison urbaine de 
village de Greenwich où le groupe était des pannes de fabrication. 
Comme la violence couplée à la police répression et 
infiltration a signalé la fin d'une nouvelle gauche une fois 
non-violente, un mouvement de nouvelles femmes, également inspiré 
par le mouvement de droits civiques, élan gagné.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes para uma sociedade democrática 
(SDS) foram fundados em 1962 para mudar o mundo promovendo a 
democracia participatory e o authenticity pessoal. Influenciado 
pesadamente por organizações das direitas civis, o SDS operou-se 
inicialmente em cidades internas e em campuses da faculdade para 
combater o racism e a discriminação. Pelos mid-1960s, muitas 
activistas focalizaram em atividades antiwar enquanto a participação
americana da tropa em Vietnam escalou. Frustrado com domination 
masculino no SDS, as mulheres leftist deram forma aos grupos 
feministas da lasca que alinharam eventualmente com as organizações 
da reforma para criar um movimento do liberation das mulheres novas. 
No seguinte testimony antes de uma activista investigando 
"subversion do comitê 1970 congressional," o rei de Marjorie, um 
presidente anterior da BRUXA (conspiracy internacional do inferno -- 
um ramo do terrorista das mulheres do teatro do guerilla do SDS) 
descreveu-a experiências com grupos radicais na área de Chicago. 
Este hearing foi prendido algumas semanas após uma explosão 
acidental matou três membros novos do grupo revolucionário os 
weathermen, um ramo do SDS, em um townhouse da vila de Greenwich onde 
o grupo fosse bombas do manufacturing. Como a violência 
acoplada com polícias repression e infiltration sinalizou o fim de 
uma esquerda nova uma vez nonviolent, um movimento das mulheres novas,
inspirado também pelo movimento das direitas civis, momentum ganho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi per una società democratica (SDS) 
sono stati fondati in 1962 per cambiare il mondo promuovendo la 
democrazia partecipe e l'autenticità personale. Influenzato 
pesante dalle organizzazioni di diritti civili, lo SDS inizialmente ha
funzionato in centri urbani e nelle città universitarie 
dell'università per combattere il razzismo e la distinzione. 
Entro i mid-1960s, molti attivisti hanno messo a fuoco sulle 
attività pacifiste mentre la partecipazione americana della truppa 
nel Vietnam ha intensificato. Frustrato con la dominazione 
maschio nello SDS, le donne di sinistra hanno formato i gruppi 
femministi della scheggia che finalmente si sono allineati con le 
organizzazioni di riforma per creare un movimento di liberazione delle
nuove donne. Nella seguente testimonianza prima di un 
attivista di studio "sovversione del comitato congressuale 1970," 
il re di Marjorie, un ex presidente della STREGA (cospirazione 
internazionale del terrorista delle donne da Inferno -- ramo del 
teatro del guerilla del a di SDS) la ha descritta esperienze con i 
gruppi radicali nella zona del Chicago. Questa udienza è stata 
tenuta alcune settimane dopo un'esplosione accidentale ha ucciso tre 
membri giovani del gruppo rivoluzionario i weathermen, un ramo di SDS,
in una casa urbana del villaggio di Greenwich in cui il gruppo era 
bombe di manufacturing. Come la violenza accoppiata con la 
polizia repressione ed infiltrazione ha segnalato la conclusione di 
nuova parte di sinistra una volta nonviolent, un movimento delle nuove
donne, anche ispirato tramite il movimento di diritti civili, 
quantità di moto guadagnata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές για μια δημοκρατική κοινωνία (SDS) 
ιδρύθηκαν το 1962 για να αλλάξουν τον κόσμο με την ενθάρρυνση 
της συμμετέχουσας δημοκρατίας και της προσωπικής αυθεντικότητας. 
Βαριά επηρεασμένο από τις οργανώσεις αστικών δικαιωμάτων, 
SDS λειτούργησε αρχικά στις πανεπιστημιουπόλεις εσωτερικών 
πόλεων και κολλεγίων για να καταπολεμήσει το ρατσισμό και τη 
διάκριση. Μέχρι τα μέσα τησδεκαετίας του '60, πολλά ενεργά
στελέχη εστίασαν στις αντιπολεμικές δραστηριότητες καθώς η 
αμερικανική συμμετοχή στρατευμάτων στο Βιετνάμ κλιμάκωσε. 
Ματαιωμένες με την αρσενική κυριαρχία σε SDS, οι 
αριστερές γυναίκες διαμόρφωσαν τις φεμινιστικές ομάδες 
θραυσμάτων που ευθυγράμμισαν τελικά με τις οργανώσεις 
μεταρρύθμισης για να δημιουργήσουν μια νέα μετακίνηση 
απελευθέρωσης των γυναικών. Στην ακόλουθη κατάθεση ενώπιον 
ενός ερευνώντας ενεργού στελέχους "ανατροπή επιτροπών του 
1970 του Κογκρέσου," ο βασιλιάς Marjorie, ένας προηγούμενος 
πρόεδρος της ΜΑΓΙΣΣΑΣ (διεθνής τρομοκρατική συνωμοσία των 
γυναικών από την κόλαση -- μια παραφυάδα θεάτρων ανταρτών 
SDS) περιέγραψε την εμπειρία της με τις ριζικές ομάδες στην 
περιοχή του Σικάγου. Αυτή η ακρόαση έγινε μερικές 
εβδομάδες αφότου σκότωσε μια τυχαία έκρηξη τρία νέα μέλη της 
επαναστατικής ομάδας οι μετεωρολόγοι, μια παραφυάδα SDS, του 
χωριού townhouse του Γκρήνουιτς όπου η ομάδα κατασκεύαζε τις 
βόμβες. Δεδομένου ότι η βία που συνδέθηκε την ορμή με την 
καταστολή και τη διήθηση αστυνομίας επεσήμανε το τέλος ενός μιά
φορά μη βίαιου νέου αριστερού, ένα νέο κίνημα των γυναικών, 
από που εμπνεύστηκε επίσης τη μετακίνηση αστικών δικαιωμάτων, 
κέρδισε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fomentando fundaron a los estudiantes para una 
sociedad democrática (SDS) en 1962 para cambiar el mundo democracia 
participante y la autenticidad personal. Influenciado 
pesadamente por organizaciones de las derechas civiles, el SDS 
funcionó inicialmente en centros urbanos y campus de la universidad 
para combatir racismo y la discriminación. Por los mediados de 
los años sesenta, muchos activistas se centraron en actividades 
pacifistas mientras que la implicación americana de la tropa en 
Vietnam se extendió. Frustrado con la dominación masculina en 
el SDS, las mujeres izquierdistas formaron los grupos feministas de la
astilla que alinearon eventual con organizaciones de la reforma para 
crear un movimiento de la liberación de las nuevas mujeres. En 
el testimonio siguiente antes de un activista que investigaba 
"subversión del comité del congreso 1970," el rey de Marjorie, un 
presidente anterior de la BRUJA (conspiración internacional del 
infierno -- un vástago del terrorista de las mujeres del teatro del 
guerrilla del SDS) la describió las experiencias con los grupos 
radicales en el área de Chicago. Esta audiencia fue llevada a 
cabo algunas semanas después de una explosión accidental mató a 
tres miembros jóvenes del grupo revolucionario los meteorólogos, un 
vástago del SDS, en una casa urbana de la aldea de Greenwich donde 
estaba bombas el grupo de la fabricación. Como la violencia 
juntada con el policía represión e infiltración señaló el final 
de una nueva izquierda una vez nonviolent, un movimiento de las nuevas
mujeres, también inspirado por el movimiento de las derechas civiles,
ímpetu ganado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087345</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107728</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-traitor-to-the-movement-a-former-sds-and-womens-liberation-activist-testifies-before-congress</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
