<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107495</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107495</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212594</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Great North American Secchi Dip-In</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Große Nordamerikanische Secchi 
Eintauchen-In</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Grand Secchi Américain du nord 
Plonger-Dans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Secchi Norte-americano Grande Mergulh-Em</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Secchi Nordamericano Grande Tuff-In</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μεγάλο βορειοαμερικανικό Secchi εμβύθιση-μέσα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Gran Secchi Norteamericano Sumergir-En</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Secchi Dip-In is a demonstration of the potential of volunteer monitors to gather environmentally important information on our lakes, rivers and estuaries. This website highlights the efforts of the Secchi Dip-In and contains lots of descriptions and photos of water quality assessment methods. Users can sign up to dip, enter their Dip-In data, find Dip-in events and view a photo gallery from this site. This is a fun useful site to demonstrate the use and importance of water quality assessment methods.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Secchi Eintauchen-In ist eine Demonstration 
des Potentials der freiwilligen Monitoren, wichtige Informationen 
über unsere Seen, Flüsse und Mündungen umweltsmäßig zu erfassen. 
Diese Web site markiert die Bemühungen des Secchi Eintauchen-In
und enthält Lots Beschreibungen und Fotos der 
Wasserqualität-Einschätzung Methoden. Benutzer können bis zum
Bad unterzeichnen, ihr Eintauchen- in den Daten, Entdeckung betreten 
Eintauchen- in den Fällen und eine Fotogalerie von dieser Site 
ansehen. Dieses ist eine nützliche Site des Spaßes, zum des 
Gebrauches und des Wertes von Wasserqualität-Einschätzung Methoden 
zu demonstrieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Secchi Plonger-Dans est une démonstration du 
potentiel des moniteurs volontaires de recueillir ambiant 
l'information importante sur nos lacs, fleuves et estuaires. Ce 
site Web met en valeur les efforts du Secchi Plonger-Dans et contient 
un bon nombre de descriptions et des photos des méthodes 
d'évaluation de qualité de l'eau. Les utilisateurs peuvent 
s'engager à plonger, à entrer dans le leur Plonger-Dans 
les données, trouvaille Plonger-dans des événements et à 
visualiser une galerie de photo de ce site. C'est un site utile 
d'amusement pour démontrer l'utilisation et l'importance des 
méthodes d'évaluation de qualité de l'eau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Secchi Mergulh-Em é uma demonstração do 
potencial dos monitores voluntários recolher ambiental a informação
importante em nossos lagos, rios e estuaries. Este Web site 
destaca os esforços do Secchi Mergulh-Em e contem lotes das 
descrições e fotos de métodos da avaliação da qualidade de água.
Os usuários podem assinar até o mergulho, entrar no seu 
Mergulh- nos dados, achado Mergulh- em eventos e ver uma galeria da 
foto deste local. Este é um local útil do divertimento para 
demonstrar o uso e a importância de métodos da avaliação da 
qualidade de água.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Secchi Tuff-In è una dimostrazione del 
potenziale dei video volontari riunire in condizioni 
ambientali le informazioni importanti sui nostri laghi, fiumi ed 
estuari. Questo Web site evidenzia gli sforzi del Secchi Tuff-In
e contiene i lotti delle descrizioni e le foto dei metodi di 
valutazione di qualità dell'acqua. Gli utenti possono firmare 
fino al tuffo, entrare nel loro Tuff- nei dati, ritrovamento Tuff- 
negli eventi ed osservare una galleria della foto da questo luogo. 
Ciò è un luogo utile di divertimento per dimostrare l'uso e 
l'importanza dei metodi di valutazione di qualità dell'acqua.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Secchi είναι εμβύθιση-μέσα μια επίδειξη της 
δυνατότητας των εθελοντικών μηνυτόρων να συγκεντρώσουν τις 
περιβαλλοντικά σημαντικές πληροφορίες για τις λίμνες, τους 
ποταμούς και τις εκβολές μας. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος δίνει 
έμφαση στις προσπάθειες του Secchi εμβύθιση-μέσα και περιέχει 
τα μέρη των περιγραφών και τις φωτογραφίες των μεθόδων 
αξιολόγησης της ποιότητας νερού. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να 
υπογράψουν μέχρι την εμβύθιση, να εισαγάγουν εμβύθιση-μέσα τα 
στοιχεία τους, να βρούν εμβύθιση- στα γεγονότα και να εμφανίσουν 
μια στοά φωτογραφιών από αυτήν την περιοχή. Αυτό είναι 
μια χρήσιμη περιοχή διασκέδασης για να καταδείξει τη χρήση και τη
σημασία των μεθόδων αξιολόγησης της ποιότητας νερού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Secchi Sumergir-En es una demostración del 
potencial de los monitores voluntarios de recopilar ambientalmente la 
información importante sobre nuestros lagos, ríos y estuarios. 
Este Web site destaca los esfuerzos del Secchi Sumergir-En y 
contiene porciones de descripciones y las fotos de los métodos del 
gravamen de la calidad del agua. Los utilizadores pueden firmar 
hasta la inmersión, entrar en su Sumergir-En los datos, hallazgo 
Sumergir-en acontecimientos y visión una galería de la foto de este 
sitio. Esto es un sitio útil de la diversión para demostrar el
uso y la importancia de los métodos del gravamen de la calidad del 
agua.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212594</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107495</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-great-north-american-secchi-dip-in</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
