<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104236</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104236</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203578</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) WarmUp Activity: The La Brea Tar Pits</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gerade-in-Zeit Unterricht (JiTT) Vorwärmung 
Aktivität: Die La Brea Teer-Gruben</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Activité De Préchauffage d'Enseignement de 
Juste-dans-Temps (JiTT) : Les Puits de Goudron de Brea de La</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Atividade Do WarmUp Do Ensino Do Apenas-em-Tempo 
(JiTT): Os Poços Do Piche De Brea Do La</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attività Di Preriscaldamento Di Insegnamento Di 
Appena-in-Tempo (JiTT): I Pozzi Del Catrame Di Brea Della La</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάνω στην ώρα δραστηριότητα WarmUp διδασκαλίας 
(JiTT): Τα κοιλώματα πίσσας Λα Brea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Actividad Del Calentamiento De la Enseñanza Del 
Apenas-en-Tiempo (JiTT): Los Huecos Del Alquitrán De Brea Del 
La</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site from SERC's Just-in-Time Teaching (JiTT) module presents JiTT warm up questions about the La Brea Tar Pits. The questions introduce the examination of tar formation, animals uncovered in tar pits and possible reasons for their extinction, and features in addition to bones that scientists observe in tar pits.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site Unterricht Gerade-in-Zeit SERCs (JiTT) 
vom Modul stellt JiTT Vorwärmung Fragen über die La Brea Teer-Gruben
dar. Die Fragen stellen die Prüfung der Teeranordnung, die 
Tiere, die in den Teergruben und in den möglichen Gründen für ihre 
Löschung freilegt werden, und die Merkmale zusätzlich zu den Knochen
vor, die Wissenschaftler in den Teergruben beobachten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site du module d'enseignement du 
Juste-dans-Temps de SERC (JiTT) présente des questions de 
préchauffage de JiTT au sujet des puits de goudron de Brea de La. 
Les questions présentent l'examen de la formation de goudron, 
des animaux découverts dans des puits de goudron et des raisons 
possibles de leur extinction, et des dispositifs en plus des os que 
les scientifiques observent dans des puits de goudron.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local dos presentes JiTT do módulo do ensino
do Apenas-em-Tempo de SERC (JiTT) aquece acima perguntas sobre os 
poços do piche de Brea do la. As perguntas introduzem a 
examinação da formação do piche, os animais descobertos em poços 
do piche e em razões possíveis para sua extinção, e as 
características além aos ossos que os cientistas observam em poços 
do piche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo dal modulo di insegnamento di 
Appena-in-Tempo dello SERC (JiTT) presenta le domande di 
preriscaldamento di JiTT circa i pozzi del catrame di Brea della La. 
Le domande introducono l'esame di formazione del catrame, gli 
animali scoperti nei pozzi del catrame e nei motivi possibili per la 
loro estinzione e le caratteristiche oltre che le ossa che gli 
scienziati osservano nei pozzi del catrame.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή από την πάνω στην ώρα ενότητα 
διδασκαλίας SERC (JiTT) παρουσιάζει τις ερωτήσεις 
προθέρμανσης JiTT για τα κοιλώματα πίσσας Λα Brea. Οι 
ερωτήσεις εισάγουν την εξέταση του σχηματισμού, των ζώων που 
αποκαλύπτονται στα κοιλώματα πίσσας και τους πιθανούς λόγους για 
την εξάλειψή τους, και των χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων πίσσας 
εκτός από τα κόκκαλα που οι επιστήμονες παρατηρούν στα κοιλώματα
πίσσας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio del módulo de la enseñanza del 
Apenas-en-Tiempo de SERC (JiTT) presenta preguntas del calentamiento 
de JiTT sobre los huecos del alquitrán de Brea del la. Las 
preguntas introducen la examinación de la formación del alquitrán, 
los animales destapados en huecos del alquitrán y razones posibles de
su extinción, y las características además de los huesos que los 
científicos observan en huecos del alquitrán.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:LAURA GUERTIN
FN:LAURA GUERTIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CATHY MANDUCA
FN:CATHY MANDUCA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203578</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104236</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/just-in-time-teaching-jitt-warmup-activity-the-la-brea-tar-pits</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
