<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105147</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105147</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213217</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">World Population Prospects: The 2002 Revision Population Database - UN Population Division</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weltbevölkerung Aussichten: Die 2002 
Änderung-Bevölkerung Datenbank - UNO Bevölkerung Abteilung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Perspectives de Population du Monde : 2002 La
Base de données de Population de Révision - Division de Population 
de l'ONU</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Prospetos Da População Do Mundo: 2002 A 
Base de dados Da População Da Revisão - Divisão Da População dos
Un</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prospetti Della Popolazione Del Mondo: 2002 
La Base di dati Della Popolazione Di Revisione - Divisione Della 
Popolazione Di NU</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προοπτικές παγκόσμιου πληθυσμού: Η βάση 
δεδομένων πληθυσμού αναθεώρησης του 2002 - τμήμα πληθυσμού των
Η.Ε</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Perspectivas De la Población Del Mundo: 2002
La Base de datos De la Población De la Revisión - División De la 
Población de la O.N.U</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The World Population Prospects allows users to change variables to learn about population prospects in the world. Users can change variables such as population, population density, location, date and variant in the basic panel to obtain basic output while a second panel allows users to obtain more detailed information such as median age, total fertility rate and population by age. There are also full country profiles, a profile of assumptions, definitions of regions, a glossary and sources. This is a site full of interesting and interactive population data from around the world.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Weltbevölkerung Aussichten erlaubt Benutzern,
Variablen zu ändern, um über Bevölkerung Aussichten in der Welt zu 
erlernen. Benutzer können Variablen wie Bevölkerung, 
Bevölkerung Dichte, Standort, Datum und Variante im grundlegenden 
Panel ändern, um grundlegende Ausgabe zu erhalten, während ein 
zweites Panel Benutzern erlaubt, ausführlichere Informationen wie 
mittleres Alter, Gesamtergiebigkeitkinetik und Bevölkerung durch 
Alter einzuholen. Es gibt auch volle Landprofile, ein Profil von
Annahmen, Definitionen von Regionen, ein Glossar und Quellen. 
Dieses ist eine Site voll der interessanten und interaktiven 
Bevölkerung Daten um von der Welt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les perspectives de population du monde permet à 
des utilisateurs de changer des variables pour se renseigner sur des 
perspectives de population dans le monde. Les utilisateurs 
peuvent changer des variables telles que la population, la densité de
population, l'emplacement, la date et la variante dans le panneau de 
base pour obtenir la sortie de base tandis qu'un deuxième panneau 
permet à des utilisateurs d'obtenir l'information plus détaillée 
telle que l'âge médian, la cadence de fertilité totale et la 
population par âge. Il y a également de pleins profils de 
pays, un profil des prétentions, des définitions des régions, un 
glossaire et des sources. C'est un site complètement des 
données intéressantes et interactives de population de partout dans 
le monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os prospetos da população do mundo permitem que 
os usuários mudem variáveis para aprender sobre prospetos da 
população no mundo. Os usuários podem mudar variáveis tais 
como a população, a densidade de população, a posição, a data e 
o variant no painel básico para obter a saída básica quando um 
segundo painel permitir que os usuários obtenham uma informação 
mais detalhada tal como a idade mediana, a taxa de fertilidade total e
a população pela idade. Há também uns perfis cheios do 
país, um perfil das suposições, umas definições das regiões, um 
glossário e umas fontes. Este é um local completamente de 
dados interessantes e interativos da população em torno do mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I prospetti della popolazione del mondo permette 
che gli utenti cambino le variabili per imparare circa i prospetti 
della popolazione nel mondo. Gli utenti possono cambiare le 
variabili quali popolazione, densità demografica, posizione, la data 
e la variante nel pannello di base per ottenere l'uscita di base 
mentre un secondo pannello permette che gli utenti ottengano le 
informazioni più dettagliate quali l'età mediana, il quoziente di 
fecondità totale e la popolazione dall'età. Ci sono egualmente
profili completi del paese, un profilo dei presupposti, definizioni 
delle regioni, un glossario e sorgenti. Ciò è un luogo in 
pieno dei dati interessanti ed interattivi della popolazione intorno 
al mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι προοπτικές παγκόσμιου πληθυσμού επιτρέπουν στους 
χρήστες για να αλλάξουν τις μεταβλητές που μαθαίνουν για τις 
προοπτικές πληθυσμών στον κόσμο. Οι χρήστες μπορούν να 
αλλάξουν τις μεταβλητές όπως ο πληθυσμός, η πυκνότητα πληθυσμών,
η θέση, η ημερομηνία και η παραλλαγή στη βασική επιτροπή για να 
λάβουν τη βασική έξοδο ενώ μια δεύτερη επιτροπή επιτρέπει στους
χρήστες για να λάβει περισσότερες αναλυτικές πληροφορίες όπως η 
μεσαία ηλικία, το συνολικό ποσοστό γονιμότητας και ο πληθυσμός 
κατά ηλικία. Υπάρχουν επίσης πλήρη σχεδιαγράμματα χωρών, 
ένα σχεδιάγραμμα των υποθέσεων, των ορισμών των περιοχών, ενός 
γλωσσαριού και των πηγών. Αυτό είναι ένα σύνολο περιοχών 
των ενδιαφερόντων και διαλογικών στοιχείων πληθυσμών από σε όλο 
τον κόσμο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las perspectivas de la población del mundo 
permiten que los utilizadores cambien variables para aprender sobre 
perspectivas de la población en el mundo. Los utilizadores 
pueden cambiar variables tales como población, densidad demogr'afica,
localización, fecha y variante en el panel básico para obtener 
salida básica mientras que un segundo panel permite que los 
utilizadores obtengan una información más detallada tal como edad 
mediana, tarifa de fertilidad total y población por edad. Hay 
también perfiles completos del país, un perfil de asunciones, 
definiciones de regiones, un glosario y fuentes. Esto es un 
sitio por completo de los datos interesantes e interactivos de la 
población alrededor del mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213217</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105147</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/world-population-prospects-the-2002-revision-population-database-un-population-division</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
