<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104809</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104809</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087382</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Among the Most Exploited": Fair Labor Standards Act and Laundry Workers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"unter ausgenutzt": Angemessene Richtlinie- 
für angemessene Arbeitsbedingungentat und Wäscherei-Arbeiter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"parmi le plus exploité" : Loi juste de 
normes de travail et ouvriers de blanchisserie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"entre o mais explorado": Ato justo dos 
padrões labor e trabalhadores da lavanderia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"fra sfruttato": Legge Di lavoro giusta di
standard ed operai della lavanderia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μεταξύ εκμεταλλευμένη": Δίκαιοι εργαζόμενοι 
νόμων και πλυντηρίων προτύπων εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"entre explotado": Acto justo de los 
estándares de trabajo y trabajadores del lavadero</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Congress passed the Fair Labor Standards Act (FLSA) on June 25, 1938, the last major piece of New Deal legislation. The act outlawed child labor and guaranteed a minimum wage of 40 cents an hour and a maximum work week of 40 hours, benefiting more than 22 million workers. Although the law helped establish a precedent for the Federal regulation of work conditions, conservative forces in Congress effectively exempted many workers, such as waiters, cooks, janitors, farm workers, and domestics, from its coverage. In October 1949, President Harry S. Truman signed into law the Fair Labor Standards Amendments of 1949, raising the minimum wage to 75 cents hour and extending coverage, but still leaving many workers unprotected. In the following statement to the 1949 Senate subcommittee on FLSA amendments, members of the laundry workers' union detailed the working conditions of laundry workers, argued that fair wages would not bankrupt commercial laundries, and called upon Congress to extend protection to laundry workers. The questioner, Senator Claude Pepper (D-Florida), a key advocate for the 1938 legislation, chaired the 1949 hearings and pushed the amendments through Senate and conference committees.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kongreß führte die angemessene Richtlinie- für 
angemessene Arbeitsbedingungentat (FLSA) an Juni 25, 1938, das letzte 
Hauptstück von Gesetzgebung des neuen Abkommens. Die Tat 
geächtete Kinderarbeit und garantiert ein minimaler Lohn von 40 Cents
ein die Stunde und eine maximale Arbeit Woche von 40 Stunden, mehr als
22 Million Arbeiter fördernd. Obgleich das geholfene Gesetz, 
einen Präzedenzfall für die Bundesverordnung der Arbeit herzustellen
bedingt, befreiten konservative Kräfte im Kongreß effektiv viele 
Arbeiter, wie Kellner, Köche, Hausmeister, Landarbeiter und 
Hausangestellte, von seiner Dichte. Im Oktober 1949, 
unterzeichnete Präsident Harry S. Truman in Gesetz die angemessenen 
Richtlinie- für angemessene Arbeitsbedingungenänderungen von 1949, 
anhob den minimalen Lohn zu einer 75-Cent-Stunde und ausdehnt Dichte, 
aber noch ließ viele Arbeiter ungeschützt. In der folgenden 
Anweisung zur Senatunterausschuß 1949 auf FLSA Änderungen, 
schilderten Bauteile des Anschlußes der Wäschereiarbeiter die 
Arbeitsbedingungen der Wäschereiarbeiter genau, argumentiert, daß 
angemessene Löhne nicht bankrotte kommerzielle Wäschereien wurden, 
und ersuchten Kongreß, um Schutz auf Wäschereiarbeiter auszudehnen. 
Der Frager, Senator Claude Pepper (D-Florida), ein 
Schlüsselfürsprecher für die Gesetzgebung 1938, saß den 1949 
Hörfähigkeiten vor und drückte die Änderungen durch Senat- und 
Konferenzausschüsse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le congrès a passé l'acte juste de normes de 
travail (FLSA) 25 juin 1938, le dernier morceau principal de 
législation de nouvelle affaire. Le travail des enfants 
proscrit par acte et garanti un salaire minimum de 40 cents par heure 
et une semaine maximum de travail de 40 heures, bénéficiant plus de 
22 millions d'ouvriers. Bien que la loi aidée à établir un 
précédent pour le règlement fédéral du travail conditionne, les 
forces conservatrices dans le congrès ont pertinemment exempté 
beaucoup d'ouvriers, tels que des serveurs, cuisiniers, portiers, 
ouvriers de ferme, et domestiques, de son assurance. En octobre 
1949, le Président Harry S. Truman a signé dans la loi les 
amendements justes de normes de travail de 1949, augmentant le salaire
minimum à l'heure de 75 cents et étendant l'assurance, mais laissant
toujours beaucoup d'ouvriers non protégés. Dans le rapport 
suivant au sous-comité 1949 de sénat sur des amendements de FLSA, 
les membres du syndicat de blanchisserie ont détaillé les conditions
de travail des ouvriers de blanchisserie, arguées du fait que les 
salaires justes  pas les blanchisseries commerciales en faillite, et 
le congrès invité pour étendre la protection aux ouvriers de 
blanchisserie. L'interpellateur, le sénateur Claude Pepper (la 
D-Floride), un avocat principal pour la législation 1938, a présidé
les 1949 auditions et a poussé les amendements par des comités de 
sénat et de conférence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O congress passou o ato justo dos padrões labor 
(FLSA) junho em 25, 1938, a última parte principal de legislação do
negócio novo. O trabalho de criança outlawed ato e garantido 
um salário mínimo de 40 centavos um a hora e uma semana máxima do 
trabalho de 40 horas, beneficiando mais de 22 milhão trabalhadores. 
Embora a lei ajudada estabelecer um precedent para o regulamento
federal do trabalho condicionasse, as forças conservadoras no 
congress exempted eficazmente muitos trabalhadores, tais como 
empregados de mesa, cozinheiros, janitors, trabalhadores de fazenda, e
domestics, de sua cobertura. Em outubro 1949, o presidente Harry
S. Truman assinou na lei as emendas justas dos padrões labor de 1949,
levantando o salário mínimo para uma hora de 75 centavos e 
estendendo a cobertura, mas deixando ainda muitos trabalhadores 
desprotegidos. Na seguinte indicação à subcomissão 1949 do 
senate em emendas de FLSA, os membros da união de trabalhadores da 
lavanderia detalharam as condições de funcionamento de trabalhadores
da lavanderia, discutidas que os salários justos  não lavanderias 
comerciais falidas, e o congress convidado para estender a proteção 
aos trabalhadores da lavanderia. O questioner, senator Claude 
Pimenta (D-D-Florida), um advogado chave para a legislação 1938, 
chaired os 1949 hearings e empurrou as emendas através dos comitês 
do senate e da conferência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il congresso ha passato la Legge Di lavoro 
giusta di standard (FLSA) il 25 giugno 1938, l'ultima parte principale
di legislazione di nuovo affare. Il lavoro del bambino 
proscritto atto e garantito uno stipendio minimo di 40 centesimi un 
l'ora e una settimana massima del lavoro di 40 ore, avvantaggianti 
più di 22 milione operai. Anche se la legge contribuita a 
stabilire un precedente per la regolazione federale di lavoro 
condiziona, le forze conservatrici nel congresso hanno esentato 
efficacemente molti operai, quali i camerieri, cuochi, janitors, 
manodopera agricola e domestics, dal relativo riempimento. Nel 
mese di ottobre del 1949, il presidente Harry S. Truman ha firmato in 
legge le correzioni Di lavoro giuste di standard di 1949, sollevanti
lo stipendio minimo ad un'ora dei 75 centesimi ed amplianti il 
riempimento, ma ancora lascianti molti operai non protetti. 
Nella seguente istruzione al sottocomitato 1949 del senato sulle
correzioni di FLSA, i membri dell'unione degli operai della lavanderia
hanno dettagliato le condizioni di lavoro degli operai della 
lavanderia, sostenute che gli stipendi giusti non lavanderie 
commerciali in fallimento ed il congresso invitato per estendere la 
protezione agli operai della lavanderia. Il questioner, il 
senatore Claude Pepper (D-Florida), un fautore chiave per la 
legislazione 1938, ha presieduto le 1949 udienze ed ha spinto le 
correzioni attraverso i comitati di congresso e del senato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το συνέδριο πέρασε το δίκαιο νόμο προτύπων εργασίας 
(FLSA) στις 25 Ιουνίου ..1938, το τελευταίο σημαντικό 
κομμάτι της νέας νομοθεσίας διαπραγμάτευσης. Η πράξη 
πρόγραψε την παιδική εργασία και εγγυήθηκε έναν βασικό μισθό 
40 σεντ μια ώρα και μια μέγιστη εβδομάδα εργασίας 40 ωρών, 
που ωφελούν περισσότερους από 22 εκατομμύριο εργαζομένους. 
Αν και ο νόμος που ενισχύθηκε να καθιερώσει ένα προηγούμενο
για τον ομοσπονδιακό κανονισμό των όρων εργασίας, συντηρητικές 
δυνάμεις στο συνέδριο απάλλαξε αποτελεσματικά πολλούς 
εργαζομένους, όπως οι σερβιτόροι, οι μάγειρες, janitors, οι 
αγρότες, και το domestics, από την κάλυψή του. Τον 
Οκτώβριο του 1949, ο Πρόεδρος Harry S. Truman υπέγραψε 
στο νόμο τις δίκαιες τροποποιήσεις προτύπων εργασίας του 1949,
που αυξάνουν το βασικό μισθό στην ώρα 75 σεντ και που 
επεκτείνουν την κάλυψη, αλλά ακόμα που αφήνουν πολλούς 
εργαζομένους μη προστατευμέούς. Στην ακόλουθη δήλωση στην 
υποεπιτροπή Συγκλήτου του 1949 στις τροποποιήσεις FLSA, τα 
μέλη του σωματείου των εργαζομένων πλυντηρίων απαρίθμησαν τις 
συνθήκες εργασίας των εργαζομένων πλυντηρίων, υποστήριξαν ότι οι
δίκαιες αμοιβές δεν θα οδηγούσαν τα εμπορικά πλυντήρια σε 
πτώχευση, και ζήτησαν από το συνέδριο για να επεκτείνουν την 
προστασία στους εργαζομένους πλυντηρίων. Ο εξεταστής, 
γερουσιαστής Claude Pepper (δ-Φλώριδα), ένας βασικός 
συνήγορος για τη νομοθεσία του 1938, προήδρευσε των ακροάσεων 
του 1949 και ώθησε τις τροποποιήσεις μέσω των επιτροπών 
Συγκλήτου και διασκέψεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El congreso pasó el acto justo de los estándares
de trabajo (FLSA) 25 de junio de 1938, el pedazo principal pasado 
de legislación del nuevo reparto. El trabajo de niño proscrito
acto y garantizado un salario mínimo de 40 centavos por hora y una 
semana máxima del trabajo de 40 horas, beneficiando a más de 22 
millones de trabajadores. Aunque la ley ayudada a establecer un 
precedente para la regulación federal del trabajo condiciona, las 
fuerzas conservadoras en congreso eximieron con eficacia a muchos 
trabajadores, tales como camareros, cocineros, porteros, trabajadores 
de granja, y domestics, de su cobertura. En octubre de 1949, 
presidente Harry S. Truman firmó en ley las enmiendas justas de los 
estándares de trabajo de 1949, levantando el salario mínimo a hora 
de 75 centavos y ampliando cobertura, pero todavía dejando muchos 
trabajadores desprotegidos. En la declaración siguiente al 
subcomité 1949 del senado en enmiendas de FLSA, los miembros de la 
unión de trabajadores del lavadero detallaron a las condiciones de 
trabajo de los trabajadores del lavadero, discutidas que los salarios 
justos  no los lavaderos comerciales arruinados, y a congreso invitado
para ampliar la protección a los trabajadores del lavadero. El 
interrogador, senador Claude Pepper (la D-Florida), abogado dominante 
para la legislación 1938, presidió las 1949 audiencias y empujó las
enmiendas a través de los comités del senado y de la conferencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087382</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104809</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/among-the-most-exploited-fair-labor-standards-act-and-laundry-workers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
