<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103509</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103509</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974100</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Peace Curriculum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Friedenslehrplan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Programme d'études de Paix</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Curriculum Da Paz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programma di studi Di Pace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόγραμμα σπουδών ειρήνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plan de estudios De la Paz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">How can we educate for peace? Five teaching units focus on nonviolence, respect for human rights and dignity, social justice and civic responsibility, global awareness, and environmental sustainability. These Units are meant to guide teachers and provide resources for their own development as peace educators. Teachers, acting as learners, should feel free to adapt these activities to make them more effective, culturally relevant, or issue-specific.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wie können wir für Frieden erziehen? Fünf
unterrichtende Maßeinheiten konzentrieren auf Gewaltlosigkeiten, 
Respekt für menschliche Rechte und Würde, Sozialgerechtigkeit und 
bürgerliche Verantwortlichkeit, globales Bewußtsein und 
Klimasustainability. Diese Maßeinheiten werden bedeutet, um 
Lehrer zu führen und Betriebsmittel für ihre eigene Entwicklung als 
Friedenserzieher zur Verfügung zu stellen. Die Lehrer, dienend 
als Anfänger, sollten frei fühlen, diese Aktivitäten anzupassen, um
sie wirkungsvoller zu bilden, kulturell relevant, oder 
Ausgabe-spezifisch.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comment pouvons-nous instruire pour la paix ? 
Cinq unités d'enseignement se concentrent sur le nonviolence, 
le respect pour des droits de l'homme et dignité, la justice sociale 
et la responsabilité civique, la conscience globale, et la 
durabilité environnementale. Ces unités sont censées pour 
guider des professeurs et pour fournir des ressources pour leur propre
développement comme éducateurs de paix. Les professeurs, 
agissant en tant qu'étudiants, devraient se sentir libres pour 
adapter ces activités pour les rendre plus pertinentes, culturelement
approprié, ou issue-spécifique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como podemos nós educar para a paz? Cinco 
unidades ensinando focalizam no nonviolence, o respeito para direitas 
humanas e dignidade, justiça social e responsabilidade civic, 
consciência global, e sustainability ambiental. Estas unidades 
são significadas guiar professores e fornecer recursos para seu 
próprio desenvolvimento como educadores da paz. Os professores,
agindo como learners, devem sentir livres adaptar estas atividades 
para fazê-las mais eficazes, culturally relevante, ou 
edição-específico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come possiamo istruire per pace? Cinque 
unità d'istruzione mettono a fuoco sul nonviolence, rispetto per i 
diritti dell'uomo e la dignità, giustizia sociale e la 
responsabilità civica, consapevolezza globale e sustainability 
ambientale. Queste unità sono significate per guidare gli 
insegnanti e fornire le risorse per il loro proprio sviluppo come 
educatori di pace. Gli insegnanti, fungenti da principianti, 
dovrebbero ritenere liberi adattare queste attività per rendere loro 
più efficace, culturalmente relativo, o issue-specifico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πώς μπορούμε να εκπαιδεύσουμε για την ειρήνη; 
Πέντε μονάδες διδασκαλίας εστιάζουν στην πολιτική της μη 
βίας, το σεβασμό των ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων και της αξιοπρέπειας,
την κοινωνική δικαιοσύνη και την πολιτική ευθύνη, τη σφαιρική 
συνειδητοποίηση, και την περιβαλλοντική ικανότητα υποστήριξης. 
Αυτές οι μονάδες προορίζονται να καθοδηγήσουν τους 
δασκάλους και να παρέχουν τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς για την 
ανάπτυξή τους ως εκπαιδευτικούς ειρήνης. Οι δάσκαλοι, που 
ενεργούν ως αρχάριοι, πρέπει να αισθανθούν ελεύθεροι να 
προσαρμόσουν αυτές τις δραστηριότητες για να τις κάνουν 
αποτελεσματικότερες, πολιτιστικά σχετικός, ή 
ζήτημα-συγκεκριμένες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Cómo podemos educar para la paz? Cinco 
unidades de enseñanza se centran en nonviolence, respecto por 
derechos humanos y dignidad, justicia social y responsabilidad 
cívica, conocimiento global, y sustainability ambiental. Estas 
unidades se significan para dirigir a profesores y para proporcionar a
los recursos para su propio desarrollo como educadores de la paz. 
Los profesores, actuando como principiantes, deben sentirse 
libres adaptar estas actividades para hacerlas más eficaces, cultural
relevante, o edicio'n-especi'fico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974100</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103509</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/peace-curriculum</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
