<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106248</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106248</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207068</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Using Primary Sources in the Classroom</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verwenden von von Primärquellen im Klassenzimmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisation des sources primaires dans la salle de
classe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usando fontes preliminares na sala de aula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Usando le sorgenti primarie nell'aula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρησιμοποίηση των αρχικών πηγών στην τάξη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usar fuentes primarias en la sala de clase</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers suggestions for using photos, documents, and other artifacts to help make history come to life for students. Suggestions include the use of inventions, uniforms, fashion, tombstones, oral histories, interviews, music, census data, land surveys, maps, blueprints, or architectural drawings, cookbooks, advertisements, and ancestors' photos, clothes, and papers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet Vorschläge für das Verwenden der Fotos, 
Dokumente an, und andere Kunstprodukte zur Hilfe lassen Geschichte zum
Leben für Kursteilnehmer kommen. Vorschläge schließen den 
Gebrauch von Erfindungen, Uniformen, Art und Weise, Finanzanzeigen, 
Mundgeschichten, Interviews, Musik, Zählungdaten, Landübersichten, 
Karten, Lichtpausen oder architektonische Zeichnungen, Kochbücher, 
Reklameanzeigen und Fotos der Vorfahren, Kleidung und Papiere ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre des suggestions pour l'usage des photos, 
documents, et d'autres objets façonnés à l'aide font l'histoire 
venir à la vie pour des étudiants. Les suggestions incluent 
l'utilisation des inventions, les uniformes, la mode, les pierres 
tombales, les histoires orales, les entrevues, la musique, les 
données de recensement, les enquêtes de terre, les cartes, les 
modèles, ou les schémas, les livres de cuisine, les annonces, et les
photos des ancêtres, les vêtements, et les articles architecturaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece sugestões para usar fotos, originais, e 
outros artifacts à ajuda fazem o history vir à vida para estudantes.
As sugestões incluem o uso das invenções, os uniformes, a 
forma, os tombstones, histories orais, entrevistas, música, dados de 
census, exames da terra, mapas, blueprints, ou desenhos, cookbooks, 
propagandas, e fotos dos antepassados, roupa, e papéis architectural.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre i suggerimenti per usando le foto, documenti
ed altri manufatti ad aiuto fanno la storia venire a vita per gli 
allievi. I suggerimenti includono l'uso delle invenzioni, 
uniformi, modo, tombstones, dati storici orali, interviste, 
musica, dati censuali, indagini della terra, programmi, modelli, o 
illustrazioni, cookbooks, pubblicità e foto degli antenati, vestiti e
carte architettonici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τις προτάσεις για τις φωτογραφίες, τα 
έγγραφα, και άλλα χειροποίητα αντικείμενα για να βοηθήσει να 
κάνει την ιστορία να έρθει στη ζωή για τους σπουδαστές. Οι 
προτάσεις περιλαμβάνουν τη χρήση των εφευρέσεων, των στολών, της 
μόδας, των ταφοπετρών, των προφορικών ιστοριών, των συνεντεύξεων,
της μουσικής, των στοιχείων απογραφής, των ερευνών εδάφους, των 
χαρτών, των σχεδιαγραμμάτων, ή των αρχιτεκτονικών σχεδίων, 
cookbooks, των διαφημίσεων, και των φωτογραφιών των προγόνων, 
των ενδυμάτων, και των εγγράφων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece las sugerencias para usar las fotos, 
documentos, y otros artefactos a la ayuda hacen que la historia viene 
a la vida para los estudiantes. Las sugerencias incluyen el uso 
de invenciones, los uniformes, manera, las piedras sepulcrales, las 
historias orales, las entrevistas, música, los datos de censo, las 
encuestas sobre la pista, las correspondencias, los modelos, o los 
gráficos, los cookbooks, los anuncios, y las fotos de los 
antepasados, las ropas, y los papeles arquitectónicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207068</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106248</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/using-primary-sources-in-the-classroom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
