<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108621</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108621</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207218</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Battle of Midway: Turning the Tide in the Pacific</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schlacht des Mittelweges: Drehen der 
Gezeiten im Pazifik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La bataille de l'allée centrale : Rotation 
de la marée dans le Pacifique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A batalha do meio do caminho: Girando a maré
no Pacífico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La battaglia di via centrale: Rotazione della
marea in Pacifico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μάχη του κεντρικού δρόμου: Στροφή της 
παλίρροιας στον Ειρηνικό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La batalla de la mitad del camino centraa: 
Dar vuelta a la marea en el Pacífico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines a pivotal World War II battle. In the spring of 1942, Japan attempted to establish a toehold in the Aleutian Islands, convert Midway into an air base for invading Hawaii, and lure the U.S. Pacific Fleet into a final battle that would finish it off. The Japanese fleet depended on radio codes that codebreakers in Hawaii and Washington, D.C. worked around the clock to interpret. This website tells how they broke the code and ended Japan's advance across the Pacific.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft eine Angelweltkriegschlacht. Im 
Früjahr von 1942, versuchte Japan, einen Ansatzpunkt in den 
Aleuten herzustellen, in einen Flughafen für das Eindringen von von 
Hawaii auf halbem Wege umzuwandeln, und die VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
pazifische Flotte in eine abschließende Schlacht anzulocken, die sie 
weg beenden würde. Die japanische Flotte hing von den 
Radiocodes ab, die codebreakers in Hawaii und in Washington, 
Gleichstrom bearbeitet um den Taktgeber, um zu deuten. Diese Web
site erklärt, wie sie den Code und den Fortschritt beendeten Japans 
über dem Pazifik brachen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine une bataille pivotale de la deuxième 
guerre mondiale. Au printemps de 1942, le Japon a essayé 
d'établir une prise dans les îles Aléouèves, de convertir à 
mi-chemin en base aérienne pour envahir Hawaï, et de leurrer la 
flotte Pacifique des ETATS-UNIS dans une bataille finale qui la 
finirait. La flotte japonaise a dépendu des codes par radio qui
des codebreakers en Hawaï et à Washington, C.C travaillé 
vingt-quatre heures sur vingt-quatre pour interpréter. Ce site 
Web indique qu'ils ont cassé le code et l'avance du Japon terminé à
travers le Pacifique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina uma batalha pivotal da segunda guerra 
mundial. Na mola de 1942, Japão tentou estabelecer um toehold 
nos consoles aleutian, converter-se a meio caminho em uma base aérea 
para invadir Havaí, e lure a frota pacífica de ESTADOS UNIDOS em uma
batalha final que a terminasse fora. A frota japonesa dependeu 
dos códigos de rádio que codebreakers em Havaí e em Washington, 
C.C. trabalhada em torno do pulso de disparo para interpretar. 
Este Web site diz como quebraram o código e o avanço de Japão
terminado através do Pacífico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina una battaglia chiave della seconda guerra 
mondiale. Nella primavera di 1942, il Giappone ha tentato di 
stabilire un toehold nelle isole aleutian, di convertirsi a metà 
strada in base aerea per l'invasione dell'Hawai e di lure la flotta 
pacifica degli STATI UNITI in una battaglia finale che la finirebbe. 
La flotta giapponese dipendeva dai codici radiofonici che 
codebreakers in Hawai e Washington, DC lavorato intorno all'orologio 
per interpretare. Questo Web site dice a come hanno rotto il 
codice e l'avanzamento del Giappone concluso attraverso il Pacifico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει έναν κεντρικό παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ μάχη. 
Την άνοιξη του 1942, η Ιαπωνία προσπάθησε να καθιερώσει 
toehold στα aleutian νησιά, να μετατρέψει τον κεντρικό δρόμο
σε μια βάση αέρα για την εισβολή της Χαβάης, και να δελεάσει τον 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ ειρηνικό στόλο σε μια τελική μάχη που θα τον τελείωνε
μακριά. Ο ιαπωνικός στόλος εξαρτήθηκε από τους ραδιο 
κώδικες εκείνα τα codebreakers στη Χαβάη και την Ουάσιγκτον, 
ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ που εργάστηκε εικοσιτέσσερεις ώρες το 
εικοσιτετράωρο για να ερμηνεύσει. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος λέει 
πώς έσπασαν τον κώδικα και τελείωσαν την πρόοδο της Ιαπωνίας 
πέρα από τον Ειρηνικό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina una batalla giratoria de la Segunda Guerra 
Mundial. En el resorte de 1942, Japón procuró establecer un 
punto de apoyo en las islas aleutian, convertir a mitad de la distancia en
una base aérea para invadir Hawaii, y engañar la flota pacífica de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en una batalla final que la acabaría apagado. La
flota japonesa dependió de los códigos de radio que los codebreakers
en Hawaii y Washington, C.C. trabajada alrededor del reloj para 
interpretar. Este Web site dice cómo rompieron el código y el 
avance de Japón terminado a través del Pacífico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207218</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108621</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-battle-of-midway-turning-the-tide-in-the-pacific</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
