<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103940</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103940</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206061</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dropping in a Microgravity Environment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fallen in eine Microgravity Umgebung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Baisse dans un environnement de Microgravité</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Deixar cair em um ambiente de Microgravity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cadendo in un ambiente di Microgravity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μείωση σε ένα περιβάλλον μικροβαρύτητας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El caer en un ambiente de Microgravity</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a competition that invites teams of students to propose, design, and build a science experiment to be performed in a microgravity drop tower facility. Representatives from selected teams will attend an expenses-paid DIME Drop Days in April 2004 at NASA Glenn Research Center in Cleveland, Ohio. The website offers details about the competition, summaries of past competitions, and archived webcasts of team activities from previous competitions. Lesson ideas on microgravity are also provided.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Konkurrenz, die Teams der Kursteilnehmer 
einlädt, ein in einem microgravity Tropfen-Aufsatzteildienst 
durchgeführt zu werden Wissenschaft Experiment vorzuschlagen, zu 
konzipieren und aufzubauen. Repräsentanten von ausgewählten 
Teams bedienen ein Unkosten-zahlende GROSCHEN Tropfen-Tage im April 
2004 in die NASA Glenn dem Forschungszentrum in Cleveland, Ohio. 
Die Web site bietet Details über die Konkurrenz, die 
Zusammenfassungen der letzten Konkurrenzen und die archivierten 
webcasts der Teamaktivitäten von den vorhergehenden Konkurrenzen an. 
Lektionideen auf microgravity werden auch zur Verfügung 
gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une concurrence qui invite des équipes 
d'étudiants à proposer, concevoir, et établir une expérience de la
science à exécuter dans un service de tour de baisse de microgravité.
Les représentants des équipes choisies assisteront à des 
jours dépense-payés d'une baisse de DIXIÈME DE DOLLAR en avril 2004
au centre de recherches de la NASA Glenn à Cleveland, Ohio. Le 
site Web offre des détails au sujet de la concurrence, des sommaires 
des concours passés, et des webcasts archivés des activités 
d'équipe des concours précédents. Des idées de leçon sur la
microgravité sont également fournies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma competição que convide equipes dos 
estudantes propôr, projetar, e construir uma experiência da ciência
a ser executada em uma facilidade da torre da gota do microgravity. 
Os representantes das equipes selecionadas atenderão a dias 
despesa-pagos de uma gota da MOEDA DE DEZ CENTAVOS em abril 2004 no 
centro de pesquisa da NASA Glenn em Cleveland, Ohio. O Web site 
oferece detalhes sobre a competição, sumários de competições 
passadas, e webcasts archived de atividades da equipe das 
competições precedentes. As idéias da lição no microgravity
são fornecidas também.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una concorrenza che invita le squadre di 
allievi a proporre, progettare e sviluppare un esperimento di scienza 
da effettuare in una funzione della torretta di goccia di 
microgravity. I rappresentanti dalle squadre selezionate 
assisteranno ai giorni spesa-expenses-paid di goccia della MONETA DA 
DIECI CENTESIMI DI DOLLARO nel mese di aprile del 2004 al centro di 
ricerca della NASA Glenn a Cleveland, Ohio. Il Web site offre i 
particolari circa la concorrenza, i sommari dei concorsi passati ed i 
webcasts archiviati delle attività della squadra dai concorsi 
precedenti. Le idee di lezione sul microgravity egualmente sono 
fornite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένας ανταγωνισμός που προσκαλεί τις ομάδες των 
σπουδαστών για να προτείνει, να σχεδιάσει, και να χτίσει ένα 
πείραμα επιστήμης που εκτελείται σε μια δυνατότητα πύργων 
απελευθέρωσης μικροβαρύτητας. Οι αντιπρόσωποι από τις 
επιλεγμένες ομάδες θα παρευρεθούν ημέρες μιας στις 
δαπάνη-πληρωμένες ΔΕΚΑΡΩΝ απελευθέρωσης τον Απρίλιο του 2004 
στο ερευνητικό κέντρο της NASA Glenn στο Κλήβελαντ, Οχάιο. 
Ο ιστοχώρος προσφέρει τις λεπτομέρειες για τον ανταγωνισμό, 
περιλήψεις των προηγούμενων ανταγωνισμών, και αρχειοθετημένος 
webcasts των δραστηριοτήτων ομάδων από τους προηγούμενους 
ανταγωνισμούς. Οι ιδέες μαθήματος σχετικά με τη 
μικροβαρύτητα παρέχονται επίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una competición que invita a equipos de 
estudiantes que propongan, diseñen, y construyan un experimento de la
ciencia que se realizará en un recurso de la torre de la gota del 
microgravity. Los representantes de los equipos seleccionados 
atenderán a días costo-pagados de una gota de la MONEDA DE DIEZ 
CENTAVOS en abril de 2004 en el centro de investigación de la NASA 
Glenn en Cleveland, Ohio. El Web site ofrece los detalles sobre 
la competición, los resúmenes de últimas competiciones, y los 
webcasts archivados de las actividades del equipo de competiciones 
anteriores. Las ideas de la lección en microgravity también se
proporcionan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206061</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103940</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/dropping-in-a-microgravity-environment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
