<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104072</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104072</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205238</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Your TV Diet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ihre Fernsehapparat Diät</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Votre Régime de TV</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sua Dieta da Tevê</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Vostra Dieta della TV</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διατροφή TV σας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Su Dieta de la TV</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson encourages students to examine their television viewing habits and to assess the impact that watching television has on their life. Students are invited to discuss a basic media literacy concept -- that media industries are driven by commercial interests, that economic factors influence the content of a media product. The lesson asks students to think about how aware they are of this relationship.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion regt Kursteilnehmer, ihre 
Fernsehenbetrachtung Gewohnheiten zu überprüfen an und die 
Auswirkung festzusetzen, die überwachendes Fernsehen auf ihrer 
Lebensdauer hat. Kursteilnehmer werden eingeladen, ein 
grundlegendes Mediabildungsgradkonzept zu behandeln --, das 
beeinflussen Media dieses ist, die, Industrien durch die 
Handelsinteressen angetrieben werden, diese ökonomische Faktoren, den
Inhalt eines Mediaproduktes. Die Lektion bittet Kursteilnehmer, 
zu denken an, wie bewußt sie von diesem Verhältnis sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon encourage des étudiants à examiner 
leurs habitudes de visionnement de télévision et à évaluer 
l'impact que la télévision d'observation a leur vie. Des 
étudiants sont invités à discuter un concept de base d'instruction 
de medias -- ce les medias que des industries sont pilotées par des 
intérêts commerciaux, ces des facteurs économiques influencent la 
teneur d'un produit de medias. La leçon demande à des 
étudiants de penser à à quel point ils avertis sont de ce rapport.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição incentiva estudantes examinar seus 
hábitos da visão da televisão e avaliar o impacto que a televisão 
prestando atenção tem em sua vida. Os estudantes são 
convidados discutir um conceito básico do literacy dos media -- esse 
os media que as indústrias são dirigidas pelos interesses 
comerciais, esses fatores econômicos influenciam o índice de um 
produto dos media. A lição pede que os estudantes pensem sobre
como ciente são deste relacionamento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione consiglia agli allievi esaminare le
loro abitudini di osservazione della televisione e valutare l'effetto 
che la televisione guardante ha sulla loro vita. Gli allievi 
sono invitati a discutere un concetto di base di literacy di media -- 
quel i media che industrie sono guidate dagli interessi commerciali, 
quei fattori economici influenzano il contenuto di un prodotto di 
media. La lezione chiede agli allievi di pensare a quanto 
informato sono di questo rapporto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα ενθαρρύνει τους σπουδαστές για να 
εξετάσει τις συνήθειες τηλεοπτικής όψης τους και για να 
αξιολογήσει επίδραση που η τηλεόραση προσοχής ασκεί στη ζωή 
τους. Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται για να συζητήσουν μια βασική 
έννοια βασικής εκπαίδευσης μέσων -- ότι οι βιομηχανίες μέσων 
οδηγούνται από τα εμπορικά ενδιαφέροντα, ότι οι οικονομικοί 
παράγοντες επηρεάζουν το περιεχόμενο ενός προϊόντος μέσων. 
Το μάθημα ζητά από τους σπουδαστές για να σκεφτεί για πόσο
γνωρίζουν αυτής της σχέσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección anima a estudiantes que examinen sus
hábitos de la visión de la televisión y evalúen el impacto que la 
televisión que mira tiene en su vida. Se invita a los 
estudiantes que discutan un concepto básico de la instrucción de los
media -- ese los media que las industrias son conducidas por los 
intereses comerciales, esos los factores económicos influencian el 
contenido de un producto de los media. La lección pide que los 
estudiantes piensen de cómo esta' enterado están de este lazo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205238</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104072</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/your-tv-diet</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
