<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105566</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105566</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203484</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Introduction to the Dinoflagellata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einleitung zum Dinoflagellata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Introduction au Dinoflagellata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Introdução ao Dinoflagellata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Introduzione al Dinoflagellata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εισαγωγή στο Dinoflagellata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Introducción al Dinoflagellata</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website features an overview of the Dinoflagellata, a large and diverse group of unicellular protists. Introductory information is displayed on the main page and links are provided to additional webpages featuring the dinoflagellate fossil record, life history and ecology, systematics and morphology. Links are also provided to other websites addressing various aspects of dinoflagellates.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site kennzeichnet einen Überblick über 
das Dinoflagellata, eine große und verschiedene Gruppe einzellige 
protists. Einleitende Informationen werden auf der Hauptseite 
angezeigt und Links werden zu den zusätzlichen Webseiten zur 
Verfügung gestellt, die den dinoflagellate Fossilsatz, die 
Lebengeschichte und -ökologie, die Systematik und die Morphologie 
kennzeichnen. Links werden auch zu anderen Web site zur 
Verfügung gestellt, die verschiedene Aspekte von dinoflagellates 
adressieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web comporte une vue d'ensemble du 
Dinoflagellata, un grand et divers groupe de protists unicellulaires. 
L'information préliminaire est affichée à la page principale 
et des liens sont fournis aux pages Web supplémentaires comportant 
l'enregistrement de fossile de dinoflagellate, l'histoire et 
l'écologie de la vie, la systématique et la morphologie. Des 
liens sont également fournis à d'autres sites Web adressant de 
divers aspects des dinoflagellates.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site caracteriza uma vista geral do 
Dinoflagellata, um grupo grande e diverso de protists unicellular. 
A informação introdutória é indicada na página principal e 
as ligações são fornecidas aos Web pages adicionais que 
caracterizam o registro do fossil do dinoflagellate, o history e o 
ecology da vida, o systematics e a morfologia. As ligações 
são fornecidas também a outros Web site que dirigem-se a vários 
aspectos dos dinoflagellates.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site caratterizza una descrizione del 
Dinoflagellata, un grande e gruppo vario dei protists unicellulari. 
Le informazioni introduttive sono visualizzate alla pagina 
principale ed i collegamenti sono forniti ai Web pagi supplementari 
che caratterizzano il record del fossile del dinoflagellate, la storia
e l'ecologia di vita, la sistematica e la morfologia. I 
collegamenti egualmente sono forniti ad altri Web site che richiamano 
le varie funzioni dei dinoflagellates.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος χαρακτηρίζει μια επισκόπηση του 
Dinoflagellata, μια μεγάλη και διαφορετική ομάδα unicellular 
protists. Οι εισαγωγικές πληροφορίες παρουσιάζονται για τη
βασική σελίδα και οι συνδέσεις παρέχονται στα πρόσθετα 
webpages που χαρακτηρίζουν το απολιθωμένες αρχείο 
dinoflagellate, την ιστορία και την οικολογία ζωής, τη 
συστηματική και τη μορφολογία. Οι συνδέσεις παρέχονται 
επίσης σε άλλους ιστοχώρους εξετάζοντας τις διάφορες πτυχές των 
dinoflagellates.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site ofrece una descripción del 
Dinoflagellata, un grupo grande y diverso de protists unicelulares. 
La información introductoria se visualiza en la paginación 
principal y las conexiones se proporcionan a los Web pages adicionales
que ofrecen el expediente del fósil del dinoflagellate, la historia y
la ecología de la vida, la sistemática y la morfología. Las 
conexiones también se proporcionan a otros Web site que tratan varios
aspectos de dinoflagellates.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BEN WAGGONER
FN:BEN WAGGONER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BRIAN SPEER
FN:BRIAN SPEER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA BERKELEY, MUSEUM OF PALEONTOLOGY
FN:UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA BERKELEY, MUSEUM OF PALEONTOLOGY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203484</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105566</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/introduction-to-the-dinoflagellata</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
