<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108724</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108724</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200784</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Calibrated Peer Review: Introduction - Why Study Geology?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kalibrierte Gleiche Zusammenfassung: 
Einleitung - Warum Studie Geologie?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Examen par les pairs Calibré : Introduction
- Pourquoi Géologie D'Étude ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Revisão De Par Calibrada: Introdução - 
Por que Geologia Do Estudo?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rassegna Di Pari Calibrata: Introduzione - 
Perchè Geologia Di Studio?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βαθμολογημένη όμοια αναθεώρηση: Εισαγωγή - 
γιατί μελετήστε τη γεωλογία;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Revisión De Par Calibrada: ¿Introducción -
Por qué Geología Del Estudio?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this activity, students read an article entitled "Why Study Geology?", then write an essay addressing points listed in the Writing Prompt. After this, students are introduced to the process of Calibrated Peer Review and evaluate their papers. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aktivität lasen Kursteilnehmer einen erlaubten 
Artikel ", warum Studie Geologie?", schreiben Sie dann einen 
Versuch, der die Punkte adressiert, die in den Schreiben Hinweis 
ausgedruckt werden. Nach diesem werden Kursteilnehmer zum 
Prozeß der kalibrierten Gleichen Zusammenfassung eingeführt und ihre
Papiere auswerten. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können 
Benutzer auf Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext
für Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette activité, les étudiants ont lu un article 
intitulé "pourquoi la géologie d'étude?", écrivez alors un 
essai adressant des points énumérés dans la demande d'écriture. 
Après ceci, des étudiants sont présentés au processus de 
l'examen par les pairs calibré et évaluent leurs papiers. À 
cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux 
informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les 
extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta atividade, os estudantes leram um artigo intitulado 
"porque a geologia do estudo?", escreva então um essay que 
dirige-se aos pontos alistados no alerta da escrita. Após este,
os estudantes são introduzidos ao processo da revisão de par 
calibrada e avalíam seus papéis. Nesta página do ponto 
começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os 
objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do 
uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da 
avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa attività, gli allievi hanno letto un articolo 
intitolato "perchè geologia di studio?", allora scriva un 
saggio che richiama i punti elencati nel richiamo di scrittura. 
Dopo questa, gli allievi sono introdotti al processo della 
revisione di pari calibrata e valutano le loro carte. A questa 
pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle 
informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto 
per le punte di istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le 
idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές διαβάζουν 
ένα άρθρο που τιτλοφορείται "γιατί γεωλογία μελέτης;", 
κατόπιν γράψτε ένα δοκίμιο εξετάζοντας τα σημεία που 
εμφανίζονται λίστα στην υπαγόρευση γραψίματος. Μετά από 
αυτό, οι σπουδαστές εισάγονται στη διαδικασία της βαθμολογημένης 
όμοιας αναθεώρησης και αξιολογούν τα έγγραφά τους. Σε 
αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν 
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta actividad, los estudiantes leyeron un artículo 
titulado "porqué la geología del estudio?", entonces escriba 
un ensayo que trata las puntas enumeradas en la guía de la escritura.
Después de esto, introducen al proceso de la revisión de par 
calibrada y evalúan a los estudiantes sus papeles. En esta 
paginación del punto de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso
a la información sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto
para las extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los 
materiales didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los 
asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:AMANDA PALMER-JULSON
FN:AMANDA PALMER-JULSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELIZABETH HEISE
FN:ELIZABETH HEISE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200784</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108724</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/calibrated-peer-review-introduction-why-study-geology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
