<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106208</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106208</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087405</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Apple Pie by the Book: Fannie Farmer vs. Catherine Beecher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Apfelkuchen durch das Buch: Fannie Landwirt 
gegen Catherine Beecher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pâté en croûte de Apple par le livre : 
Fermier de Fannie contre Catherine Beecher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Torta de Apple pelo livro: Fazendeiro de 
Fannie contra Catherine Beecher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Torta di Apple dal libro: Coltivatore di 
Fannie contro Catherine Beecher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πίτα μήλων από το βιβλίο: Αγρότης Fannie 
εναντίον της Catherine Beecher</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Empanada de Apple por el libro: Granjero de 
Fannie contra Catherine Beecher</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Prior to the introduction of "domestic science" in the late-19th century, housework --especially cooking--depended on skills passed down from mother to daughter or possessed by hired domestic labor. The domestic science (or as it later became more commonly called "home economics") movement wanted to standardize routines and recipes, thereby relieving housewives of the anxieties of inexact cooking and bringing the supposed benefits of efficiency into the home. The influence of domestic scientists on cooking can be seen dramatically by comparing an apple pie recipe from Catherine Beecher's  Domestic Receipt Book  (1846) with one from Fannie Merritt Farmer's  Boston Cooking-School Cook Book  (1905 ed.). Beecher, daughter of a prominent New England family, wrote on domestic topics (as well as on social issues, such as abolitionism, with her sister Harriet Beecher Stowe). Farmer was a leader in the movement for scientific cooking, and her  Boston Cooking-School Cook Book  helped to entrench the notion of exact measures and procedures designed to produce a uniform product.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vor der Einleitung "der inländischen 
Wissenschaft" im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert, Hausarbeit 
-- besonders kochend -- abgehangen von den Fähigkeiten geführt unten
von Mutter zu Tochter oder durch angestellte Hausangestelltarbeit 
besessen. Die inländische Wissenschaft (oder, während es 
später häufiger benannte "Hauswirtschaft" wurde), Bewegung wollte 
die Programme und Rezepte standardisieren, dadurch sieentlastet 
sieentlastet Hausfrauen von den Ängsten des ungenauen Kochens und des
Holens des angenommenen Nutzens der Leistungsfähigkeit in das Haus. 
Der Einfluß der inländischen Wissenschaftler auf das Kochen 
kann drastisch gesehen werden, indem man ein Apfelkuchenrezept 
Catherine Beechers vom inländischen Empfang Buch (1846) mit einem 
Fannie Merritt vom Koch Book (Kochen-Schule Boston des Landwirts ED 
1905) vergleicht. Beecher, Tochter einer vorstehenden 
Neu-England Familie, schrieb auf inländische Themen (sowie auf 
Sozialausgaben, wie abolitionism, mit ihrer Schwester Harriet Beecher 
Stowe). Landwirt war ein Führer in der Bewegung für das 
wissenschaftliche Kochen und ihr Boston Kochen-Schule Koch-Buch, das 
geholfen wurde, um den Begriff der genauen Masse und der Prozeduren zu
verschanzen konzipiert waren, um ein konstantes Produkt zu 
produzieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avant l'introduction "de la science domestique" en
fin du 19me siècle, les travaux domestiques -- particulièrement 
faisant cuire -- dépendus des qualifications passées vers le bas de 
la mère à la fille ou possédées par le travail loué de 
domestique. Mouvement domestique de la science (ou pendant que 
ce devenait plus tard le "économie ménagère" généralement 
appelée) a voulu normaliser des sous-programmes et des recettes, 
soulageant de ce fait des femmes au foyer des inquiétudes de faire 
cuire inexacte et d'introduire les avantages supposés de 
l'efficacité dans la maison. L'influence des scientifiques 
domestiques sur faire cuire peut être vue excessivement en comparant 
une recette de pâté en croûte de pomme du carnet de quittances 
domestique de Catherine Beecher (1846) à un du cuisinier Book (de 
Faire cuire-École de Boston du fermier de Fannie Merritt ED 1905). 
Beecher, fille d'une famille en avant de la Nouvelle Angleterre,
a écrit sur des sujets domestiques (aussi bien que sur les issues 
sociales, telles que l'abolitionism, avec sa soeur Harriet Beecher 
Stowe). Le fermier était une amorce dans le mouvement pour la 
cuisine scientifique, et son livre de cuisinier de Faire cuire-École 
de Boston aidé pour retrancher la notion des mesures exactes et des 
procédures conçues pour produire un produit uniforme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Antes da introdução "da ciência doméstica" no 
século late-19th, housework -- especial cozinhando -- dependido das 
habilidades passadas para baixo da matriz à filha ou possuídas pelo 
trabalho empregado do domestic. O movimento doméstico da 
ciência (ou enquanto se transformou mais tarde "economia home mais 
geralmente chamada") quis estandardizar as rotinas e as receitas, 
aliviando desse modo housewives das ansiedades de cozinhar inexact e 
de trazer os benefícios supostos da eficiência na HOME. A 
influência de cientistas domésticos em cozinhar pode ser vista 
dramàtica comparando uma receita da torta de maçã do livro de 
recibo doméstico de Catherine Beecher (1846) com o um do cozinheiro 
Livro da Cozinh-Escola de Boston do fazendeiro de Fannie Merritt (ed. 
1905). Beecher, filha de uma família proeminente de Nova 
Inglaterra, escreveu em tópicos domésticos (as.well.as em edições 
sociais, tais como o abolitionism, com sua irmã Harriet Beecher 
Stowe). O fazendeiro era um líder no movimento para cozinhar 
científico, e seu livro do cozinheiro da Cozinh-Escola de Boston 
ajudado entrench a noção de medidas exatas e dos procedimentos 
projetados produzir um produto uniforme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prima dell'introduzione "di scienza domestica" nel
fine del 19esimo secolo, lavori domestici -- particolarmente cucinando
-- dipesi dalle abilità passate giù dalla madre alla figlia o 
possedute dal lavoro domestico assunto. Il movimento 
domestico di scienza (o mentre più successivamente si è transformato
in "in economia domestica" più conunemente chiamata) ha desiderato 
standardizzare le procedure e le ricette, quindi allevianti le 
casalinghe delle ansie di cottura inesatta e di introdurre dei 
benefici presunti di risparmio di temi nella sede. L'influenza 
degli scienziati domestici sulla cottura può essere vista 
drammaticamente paragonando una ricetta della torta di mela dal libro 
di ricevuta domestico della Catherine Beecher (1846) ad uno dal cuoco 
Book (della Cucinare-Scuola de Boston del coltivatore di Fannie 
Merritt ed. 1905). Beecher, figlia di una famiglia prominente 
della Nuova Inghilterra, ha scritto sui soggetti domestici (così come
sulle edizioni sociali, quale il abolitionism, con la sua sorella 
Harriet Beecher Stowe). Il coltivatore era un capo nel 
movimento per la cottura scientifica ed il suo libro del cuoco della 
Cucinare-Scuola de Boston contribuito per entrench la nozione delle 
misure esatte e delle procedure destinate per produrre un prodotto 
dell'uniforme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πριν από την εισαγωγή της "οικιακής οικονομίασ" στο 
late-19th αιώνα, τα οικιακά -- ειδικά που μαγειρεύουν -- 
εξαρτήθηκαν από τις δεξιότητες κάτω από τη μητέρα στην κόρη ή 
που κατέχονται από η μισθωμένη εσωτερική εργασία που πέρασαν. 
Η εσωτερική μετακίνηση επιστήμης (ή όπως έγινε αργότερα 
συχνότερα αποκαλούμενα "βασικά οικονομικά") θέλησε να 
τυποποιήσει τις ρουτίνες και τις συνταγές, με αυτόν τον τρόπο 
ανακουφίζοντας τις νοικοκυρές των ανησυχιών του ανακριβούς 
μαγειρέματος και φέρνοντας τα υποτιθέμενα οφέλη της 
αποδοτικότητας στο σπίτι. Η επιρροή των εσωτερικών 
επιστημόνων στο μαγείρεμα μπορεί να δει εντυπωσιακά με
τη σύγκριση μιας συνταγής πιτών μήλων από το εσωτερικό βιβλίο 
παραλαβών της Catherine Beecher's (1846) με ένα από το 
βιβλίο μαγειρεύω-σχολικών Cook της Βοστώνης του αγρότη 
Fannie Merritt (1905 ΕΔ). Το Beecher, κόρη μιας 
προεξέχουσας οικογένειας της Νέας Αγγλίας, έγραψε στα εσωτερικά 
θέματα (καθώς επίσης και στα κοινωνικά ζητήματα, όπως το 
abolitionism, με την αδελφή της Harriet Beecher Stowe). 
Ο αγρότης ήταν ηγέτης στη μετακίνηση για το επιστημονικό 
μαγείρεμα, και το βιβλίο μαγειρεύω-σχολικών Cook της Βοστώνης 
της βοήθησε να περιχαρακώσει την έννοια των ακριβών μέτρων και 
των διαδικασιών με σκοπό να παραγάγουν ένα ομοιόμορφο προϊόν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes de la introducción de la "ciencia 
doméstica" en el siglo de fines del siglo diecinueve, quehacer 
doméstico -- especialmente cocinando -- dependido de las habilidades 
pasadas abajo de madre a la hija o poseídas por el trabajo empleado 
del domestic. El movimiento doméstico de la ciencia (o mientras
que se convirtió en más adelante "economía doméstica más 
comunmente llamada") deseó estandardizar las rutinas y las recetas, 
de tal modo relevando a amas de casa de las ansiedades de cocinar 
inexacto y de traer las ventajas supuestas de la eficacia en el hogar.
La influencia de científicos domésticos en cocinar puede ser 
considerada dramáticamente comparando una receta de la empanada de 
manzana del libro de recibo doméstico de Catherine Beecher (1846) con
uno del cocinero Book (de la Cocinar-Escuela de Boston del granjero de
Fannie Merritt ed. 1905). Beecher, hija de una familia 
prominente de Nueva Inglaterra, escribió en asuntos domésticos (así
como en ediciones sociales, tales como abolitionism, con su hermana 
Harriet Beecher Stowe). El granjero era un arranque de cinta en 
el movimiento para cocinar científico, y su libro del cocinero de la 
Cocinar-Escuela de Boston ayudado para atrincherar la noción de 
medidas exactas y de procedimientos diseñados para producir un 
producto uniforme.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087405</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106208</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/apple-pie-by-the-book-fannie-farmer-vs-catherine-beecher</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
