<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105077</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105077</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101277</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Break the Science Barrier - Richard Dawkins - Part 1 of 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Brechen Sie die Wissenschaft Sperre - Richard 
Dawkins - Teil 1 von 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cassez la barrière de la Science - Richard 
Dawkins - la partie 1 de 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quebre a barreira da ciência - Richard Dawkins - 
a parte 1 de 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Eliminare la barriera di scienza - Richard Dawkins
- parte 1 di 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σπάστε το εμπόδιο επιστήμης - Richard Dawkins - 
μέρος 1 3</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rompa la barrera de la ciencia - Richard Dawkins -
la parte 1 de 3</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Break the Science Barrier follows the Oxford Biologist Richard Dawkins as he meets with people who have experienced the wonders of science first-hand. We meet the astronomer who first discovered pulsars, the geneticist who invented DNA fingerprinting, a scientist who discovered a protein that causes cancer, and others. Dawkins interviews famous admirers of science such as Douglas Adams and David Attenborough, and asks them why science means so much to them. We also see how dangerous ignorance of science can be in classrooms, courts, and beyond. With so many expressing paranormal beliefs and ignorance of science, Dawkins encourages viewers to contrast these ancient superstitions with the power and beauty of our scientific achievements and understanding. For more information see: http://richarddawkins.net/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Brechen Sie die Wissenschaft Sperre folgt dem 
Oxford Biologen Richard Dawkins, wie er Leute trifft, die die Wunder 
der Wissenschaft aus erster Hand erfahren haben. Wir treffen den
Astronomen, dem erstes Pulsars entdeckte, den Genetiker, der DNA 
Fingerabdruck erfand, ein Wissenschaftler, der ein Protein, das Krebs 
verursacht und andere entdeckte. Dawkins interviewt berühmte 
Bewunderer der Wissenschaft wie Douglas Adams und David Attenborough 
und fragt sie, warum Wissenschaft soviel zu ihnen bedeutet. Wir 
sehen auch, wie gefährliche Unwissenheit der Wissenschaft in den 
Klassenzimmern, Gerichte sein kann und jenseits. Wenn so viele 
paranormal Glauben und Unwissenheit ausdrücken, der Wissenschaft, 
regt Dawkins Projektoren an, diese alten Superstitions mit der Energie
und der Schönheit unserer wissenschaftlichen Ausführungen und 
Verstehens zu kontrastieren. Zu mehr Information sehen Sie: 
http://richarddawkins.net/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cassez la barrière de la Science suit le 
biologiste Richard Dawkins d'Oxford comme il rencontre les personnes 
qui ont éprouvé les merveilles de la science de première main. 
Nous rencontrons l'astronome que le premier a découvert des 
pulsars, le généticien qui a inventé l'empreinte digitale d'ADN, un
scientifique qui a découvert une protéine qui cause le cancer, et 
d'autres. Dawkins interviewe les admirateurs célèbres de la 
science tels que Douglas Adams et David Attenborough, et leur demande 
pourquoi la science signifie tellement à eux. Nous voyons 
également à quel point l'ignorance dangereuse de la science peut 
être dans les salles de classe, cours, et là-bas. Avec 
tellement beaucoup qui expriment la conviction paranormale et 
l'ignorance de la science, Dawkins encourage des visualisateurs à 
contraster ces superstitions antiques avec la puissance et la beauté 
de nos accomplissements et arrangement scientifiques. Pour plus 
d'information voyez : http://richarddawkins.net/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quebre a barreira da ciência segue o biólogo 
Richard Dawkins de Oxford como se encontra com os povos que 
experimentaram as maravilhas da ciência first-hand. Nós 
encontramo-nos com o astrónomo que o primeiro descobriu pulsars, 
geneticist que inventou o fingerprinting do DNA, um cientista que 
descubra uma proteína que causasse o cancer, e outra. Dawkins 
entrevista admiradores famosos da ciência tais como Douglas Adams e 
David Attenborough, e pergunta-lhes porque a ciência lhes significa 
assim muito. Nós vemos também como o ignorance perigoso da 
ciência pode estar nas salas de aula, cortes, e além. Com o 
assim muitos que expressam a opinião e o ignorance paranormal da 
ciência, Dawkins incentiva visores contrastar estes superstitions 
antigos com a potência e a beleza de da nossas realizações e 
compreensão científicas. Para mais informação veja: 
http://richarddawkins.net/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Eliminare la barriera di scienza segue il biologo 
Richard Dawkins de Oxford come viene a contatto della gente che ha 
avvertito first-hand i wonders della scienza. Veniamo a contatto
dell'astronomo che il primo ha scoperto i pulsars, il genetista che ha
inventato l'impronta digitale del DNA, uno scienziato che ha scoperto 
una proteina che causa il cancro ed altre. Dawkins intervista 
gli ammiratori famosi della scienza quali Douglas Adams e David 
Attenborough e chiede loro perchè la scienza significa così tanto a 
loro. Inoltre vediamo come l'ignoranza pericolosa della scienza 
può essere in aule, corti e di là. Con tanti che esprimono la 
credenza e l'ignoranza paranormal della scienza, Dawkins consiglia ai 
visori contrapporre questi superstitions antichi con l'potenza e la 
bellezza dei del nostri successi e capire scientifici. Per le 
più informazioni veda: http://richarddawkins.net/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σπάστε το εμπόδιο επιστήμης ακολουθεί το βιολόγο 
Richard Dawkins της Οξφόρδης όπως συναντιέται με τους 
ανθρώπους που έχουν δοκιμάσει αναρωτιούνται της επιστήμης από 
πρώτο χέρι. Συναντάμε τον αστρονόμο που ο πρώτος ανακάλυψε
pulsars, ο γενετησιολόγος που έφηυρε το DNA δακτυλοσκοπώντας,
ένας επιστήμονας που ανακάλυψε μια πρωτεϊ'νη που προκαλεί τον 
καρκίνο, και άλλους. Το Dawkins παίρνει συνέντευξη από 
τους διάσημους θαυμαστές της επιστήμης όπως Ντάγκλας Adams και
ο Δαβίδ Attenborough, και τους ρωτά γιατί η επιστήμη σημαίνει 
τόσο μεγάλο μέρος σε τους. Βλέπουμε επίσης πώς η 
επικίνδυνη άγνοια της επιστήμης μπορεί να είναι στις τάξεις, 
δικαστήρια, και πέρα. Με έτσι πολλούς που εκφράζουν τις 
παραφυσικές πεποιθήσεις και την άγνοια της επιστήμης, Dawkins 
ενθαρρύνει τις εμφανίσεις για να αντιπαραβάλει αυτές τις αρχαίες 
δεισιδαιμονίες με τη δύναμη και την ομορφιά των επιστημονικών 
επιτευγμάτων και της κατανόησής μας. Για περισσότερες 
πληροφορίες δείτε: http://richarddawkins.net/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rompa la barrera de la ciencia sigue a biólogo 
Richard Dawkins de Oxford como él satisface con a gente que ha 
experimentado las maravillas de la ciencia de primera mano. 
Satisfacemos a astrónomo que el primer descubrió los 
pulsares, el genetista que inventó huella dactilar de la DNA, 
científico que descubrió una proteína que causa el cáncer, y 
otras. Dawkins se entrevista con a admiradores famosos de la 
ciencia tales como Douglas Adams y David Attenborough, y les pregunta 
porqué la ciencia significa tanto a ellos. También vemos cómo
la ignorancia peligrosa de la ciencia puede estar en las salas de 
clase, cortes, y más allá. Con tan muchos expresando creencia 
y la ignorancia paranormal de la ciencia, Dawkins anima a espectadores
que pongan en contraste estas supersticiones antiguas con la potencia 
y la belleza de nuestros logros y entender científicos. Para 
más información vea: http://richarddawkins.net/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:VIDEO_COLLECTOR
FN:VIDEO_COLLECTOR
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101277</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105077</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/break-the-science-barrier-richard-dawkins-part-1-of-3</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
