<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108769</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108769</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206758</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Genomics Primers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Genomics Zündkapseln</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Amorces de génomique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Primers De Genomics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Iniettori Di Genomics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Genomics εγχυτήρες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cartillas De Genomics</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">gives a detailed overview of the science of genetics, including the Human Genome Project. An introduction helps visitors understand genomes, DNA, genes, chromosomes, andmore. Other resources include online audio and video files about genetics and the Human Genome Project, images of genomes, current research news, a glossary, frequently asked questions, and a student page.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">gibt einen ausführlichen Überblick über die 
Wissenschaft von Genetik, einschließlich das menschliche 
Genom-Projekt. Eine Einleitung hilft Besuchern, Genome, DNA, 
Gene, Chromosomen, andmore zu verstehen. Andere Betriebsmittel 
enthalten Onlineaudio- und videodateien über Genetik und das 
menschliche Genom-Projekt, Bilder der Genome, aktuelle Forschung 
Nachrichten, ein Glossar, Fragen und um um eine Kursteilnehmerseite 
häufig gebeten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">donne une vue d'ensemble détaillée de la science
de la génétique, y compris le projet humain de génome. Une 
introduction aide des visiteurs à comprendre les génomes, ADN, 
gènes, chromosomes, andmore. D'autres ressources incluent les 
fichiers sonores et visuels en ligne au sujet de la génétique et du 
projet humain de génome, images des génomes, nouvelles actuelles de 
recherches, un glossaire, fréquemment demandé des questions, et une 
page d'étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">dá uma vista geral detalhada da ciência do 
genetics, including o projeto humano do genome. Uma introdução
ajuda a visitantes compreender os genomes, DNA, genes, chromosomes, 
andmore. Outros recursos incluem limas audio e video em linha 
sobre os genetics e o projeto humano do genome, imagens dos genomes, 
notícia atual da pesquisa, um glossário, pedido freqüentemente 
perguntas, e uma página do estudante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dà una descrizione dettagliata della scienza 
della genetica, compreso il progetto umano del genome. 
Un'introduzione aiuta gli ospiti a capire i genomes, il DNA, i 
geni, i cromosomi, andmore. Altre risorse includono gli archivi 
audio e video in linea circa la genetica ed il progetto umano del 
genome, immagini dei genomes, le notizie correnti di ricerca, un 
glossario, chiesto frequentemente le domande e una pagina 
dell'allievo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δίνει μια λεπτομερή επισκόπηση της επιστήμης της 
γενετικής, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του ανθρώπινου προγράμματος 
γονιδιώματος. Μια εισαγωγή βοηθά τους επισκέπτες να 
καταλάβουν τα γονιδιώματα, DNA, γονίδια, χρωμοσώματα, 
andmore. Αλλα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς περιλαμβάνουν 
on-line τα ηχητικά και τηλεοπτικά αρχεία για τη γενετική και το
ανθρώπινο πρόγραμμα γονιδιώματος, εικόνες των γονιδιωμάτων, 
παρούσες ερευνητικές ειδήσεις, ένα γλωσσάρι, υπέβαλε συχνά τις 
ερωτήσεις, και μια σελίδα σπουδαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">da una descripción detallada de la ciencia de la 
genética, incluyendo el proyecto humano del Genoma. Una 
introducción ayuda a visitantes a entender los genomas, DNA, 
genes, cromosomas, andmore. Otros recursos incluyen ficheros 
audio y video en línea sobre las genéticas y el proyecto humano del 
Genoma, imágenes de los genomas, noticias actuales de la 
investigación, un glosario, pedido con frecuencia preguntas, y una 
paginación del estudiante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206758</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108769</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/genomics-primers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
