<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105465</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105465</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206020</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Resources Observation System (EROS) Data Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bodenschätze-Beobachtung System (EROS) 
Rechenzentrum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Centre de Calculs de Système d'Observation de 
Ressources terrestres (EROS)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro De Dados Do Sistema Da Observação Dos 
Recursos De Terra (EROS)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro Di Dati Del Sistema Di Osservazione Delle 
Risorse terrestri (EROS)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κέντρο στοιχείων συστημάτων παρατήρησης των γήινων 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς (EROS)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro De Datos Del Sistema De la Observación De 
los Recursos terrestres (EROS)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a data management, systems development, and research field center for the U.S. Geological Survey's National Mapping Division. The EDC stores, processes, and distributes a variety of data, including cartographic, satellite, and aircraft data. The EDC's archives also hold the world's largest collection of civilian remotely sensed data covering the Earth's land masses.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Datenverwaltung, Systeme Entwicklung, und
Forschung fangen Mitte für der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
geologischen nationale abbildendie abteilung Übersicht auf. Die
EDC Speicher, Prozesse und verteilt eine Vielzahl von Daten, 
einschließlich die kartographische, Satelliten- und Flugzeugdaten. 
Die Archive des EDCs halten auch die größte Ansammlung der 
Welt der erfaßten Daten des Zivilisten entfernt an, welche die 
Landmassen der Masse umfassen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une gestion des données, un développement de
systèmes, et un centre de zone de recherches pour la Division 
traçante nationale de l'enquête géologique des ETATS-UNIS. 
Les mémoires d'EDC, processus, et distribue une variété de 
données, y compris des données cartographiques, satellites, et 
d'avion. Les archives de l'EDC contiennent également la plus 
grande collection du monde de données à distance senties de civil 
couvrant les masses de la terre de la terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">são uma gerência de dados, um desenvolvimento 
dos sistemas, e um centro do campo da pesquisa para a divisão 
traçando nacional do exame geological de ESTADOS UNIDOS. As 
lojas de EDC, processos, e distribuem uma variedade dos dados, 
including dados cartographic, satellite, e do avião. Os 
arquivos do EDC prendem também a coleção a maior do mundo dos dados
remotamente detetados do civil que cobrem as massas da terra da terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una gestione di dati, uno sviluppo dei sistemi 
e un centro del campo di ricerca per la divisione di tracciato 
nazionale dell'indagine geologica degli STATI UNITI. I depositi 
di EDC, processi e distribuisce una varietà di dati, compreso i dati 
cartografici, satelliti e del velivolo. Gli archivi del EDC 
egualmente tengono l'ampia raccolta del mondo dei dati a distanza 
percepiti del civile che trattano le masse della terra della terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια διαχείριση στοιχείων, μια ανάπτυξη 
συστημάτων, και κέντρο ερευνητικών πεδίων για το εθνικό τμήμα 
χαρτογράφησης της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ γεωλογικής έρευνας. Τα 
καταστήματα EDC, διαδικασίες, και διανέμουν ποικίλα στοιχεία, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων χαρτογραφικών, των δορυφορικών, και στοιχείων 
αεροσκαφών. Τα αρχεία του EDC κρατούν επίσης την 
παγκόσμια μεγαλύτερη συλλογή των πολιτικών μακρινά αισθανμένων 
στοιχείων που καλύπτουν τις μάζες γήινου εδάφους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una gerencia de datos, un desarrollo de los 
sistemas, y un centro del campo de la investigación para la división
que asocia nacional de la encuesta sobre geológica ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Los almacenes de EDC, procesos, y distribuyen una variedad de 
datos, incluyendo datos cartográficos, basados en los satélites, y 
del avión. Los archivos del EDC también llevan a cabo la 
colección más grande del mundo de datos remotamente detectados del 
civil que cubren las masas de la pista de la tierra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206020</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105465</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-resources-observation-system-eros-data-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
