<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103570</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103570</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086813</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Serious Questions of Fairness, Ethics, and Legality: Congress Investigates Sweepstakes Promotions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ernste Fragen der Gerechtigkeit, der Ethik und der
Legalität: Kongreß Forscht Lotterie-Förderungen Nach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Questions sérieuses de l'equitabilité, de 
l'éthique, et de la légalité : Le Congrès Étudie des 
Promotions de Sweepstakes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Perguntas sérias do fairness, dos ethics, e do 
legality: O Congress Investiga Promotions Dos Sweepstakes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Domande serie di imparzialità, dell'etica e della 
legalità: Il Congresso Studia Le Promozioni Di Lotterie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σοβαρά θέματα της δικαιοσύνης, της ηθικής, και της 
νομιμότητας: Το συνέδριο ερευνά τις προωθήσεις 
Sweepstakes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuestiones serias de la imparcialidad, de los 
éticas, y de la legalidad: El Congreso Investiga Promociones De
los Montos totales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1960s, lottery-like contests designed to publicize products through sweepstakes competitions spread rapidly. In the 19th century, every state banned lotteries--defined as competitions in which chances to win prizes were sold--to protect citizens. In 1868, Congress prohibited the distribution of lottery materials through the mail. The mid-20th century sweepstakes, however, did not require contestants to purchase tickets or products to win prizes and were thus considered legal. In 1966, the number of national sweepstakes exceeded 600 and an FTC investigation in 1968 found evidence of deception. In the following statements by Representatives John D. Dingell and Silvio O. Conte that opened a Congressional investigation in 1969, the congressmen charged that small businesses were threatened by the spread of big business-run sweepstakes and condemned deceptive practices in 'preselected winners' promotions. Their compiled data revealed that only a small fraction of advertised prizes had actually been awarded. Congress failed to pass a regulatory bill that year, and by 1998, the FTC estimated that more than 400 million sweepstakes flooded the mail annually and that consumers lost more than $40 billion each year through sweepstakes and telemarketing scams. In 1999, Congress passed the Deceptive Mail Prevention and Enforcement Act. Among other consumer protections, this Act required sweepstakes materials to clearly state odds of winning, value of prizes, and rules.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den sechziger Jahren Lotterie-wie den 
Wettbewerben konzipiert, um Produkte durch die Lotteriekonkurrenzen zu
publizieren schnell verbritten. Im 19. Jahrhundert verbot jeder 
Zustand die Lotterien -- definiert, während Konkurrenzen, in denen 
riskiert, um Preise zu gewinnen, verkauft wurden -- um Bürger zu 
schützen. 1868 verbot Kongreß die Verteilung der 
Lotteriematerialien durch die Post. Die mid-20th 
Jahrhundertlotterien jedoch benötigten nicht Kandidaten, Karten oder 
Produkte zu den Gewinnpreisen zu kaufen und galten folglich als 
zugelassen. 1966 überstieg die Zahl nationalen Lotterien 600 
und eine FTC Untersuchung in 1968 fand Beweis der Täuschung. In
den folgenden Anweisungen durch Repräsentanten John D. Dingell und 
Silvio O. Conte, die eine Kongreßuntersuchung 1969 öffneten, die 
Kongreßabgeordneten lud auf, daß Kleinbetriebe durch die Verbreitung
von grossem Geschäft-laufen lassen Lotterien und verurteilte 
irreführende Praktiken ' in den Förderungen der vorgewählten Sieger
bedroht wurden. Ihre kompilierten Daten deckten auf, daß nur 
ein kleiner Bruch der bekanntgemachten Preise wirklich zugesprochen 
worden war. Kongreß konnte einen regelnden Gesetz 
verabschieden, dem nicht Jahr und bis zum 1998, der FTC schätzte, 
daß mehr als 400 Million Lotterien die Post jährlich überschwemmten
und daß Verbraucher mehr als $40 Milliarde jedes Jahr durch Lotterien
und Televerkauf scams verloren. 1999 fungieren der Kongreß, 
der die trügerische Post-Verhinderung geführt werden und die 
Durchführung unter anderem Verbraucherschutz, diese Tat benötigten 
Lotteriematerialien, um Vorteile des Gewinnens offenbar anzugeben, 
Wert der Preise und Richtlinien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les années 60, loterie-comme des concours 
conçus pour donner de la publicité à des produits par des concours 
de sweepstakes écartés rapidement. Au 19ème siècle, chaque 
état a interdit des loteries -- définies pendant que des concours en
lesquels risque pour gagner des prix étaient vendus -- pour protéger
des citoyens. En 1868, le congrès a interdit la distribution 
des matériaux de loterie par le courrier. Les sweepstakes de 
siècle de mid-20th, cependant, n'ont pas exigé des contestants 
d'acheter des billets ou des produits aux prix de victoire et ont 
été ainsi considérés légal. En 1966, le nombre de 
sweepstakes nationaux a excédé 600 et une recherche de FTC dans 1968
a trouvé l'évidence de la déception. Dans les rapports 
suivants des représentants John D. Dingell et Silvio O. Conte qui
ont ouvert une recherche congressionnelle en 1969, les membres du 
Congrès a chargé que de petites entreprises ont été menacées par 
la diffusion de grand affaire-exécutent des sweepstakes et des 
pratiques trompeuses condamnées dans 'les promotions des gagnants 
pré-sélectionnés. Leurs données compilées ont indiqué que 
seulement une petite fraction des prix annoncés avait été 
attribuée réellement. Le congrès n'a pas passé une facture 
de normalisation que l'année, et d'ici 1998, le FTC a estimé que 
plus de 400 millions de sweepstakes ont inondé le courrier 
annuellement et que les consommateurs ont détruit tous les ans plus 
de $40 milliards par des sweepstakes et des scams de télemarketing. 
En 1999, le congrès passé l'empêchement trompeur de courrier 
et l'application agissent. Entre d'autres protections des 
consommateurs, cet acte a exigé des matériaux de sweepstakes 
d'énoncer clairement la chance du gain, la valeur des prix, et les 
règles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos 1960s, lottery-como as competições projetadas
publicize produtos através das competições dos sweepstakes 
espalhadas ràpidamente. No 1ø século, cada estado proibiu os 
lotteries -- definidos enquanto as competições em que chances para 
ganhar prêmios foram vendidas -- para proteger cidadãos. Em 
1868, o congress proibiu a distribuição de materiais do lottery 
através do correio. Os sweepstakes do século de mid-20th, 
entretanto, não requereram contestants comprar bilhetes ou produtos 
aos prêmios da vitória e foram considerados assim legal. Em 
1966, o número de sweepstakes nacionais excedeu 600 e uma 
investigação do FTC em 1968 encontrou a evidência do deception. 
Nas seguintes indicações por representantes John D. Dingell e 
Silvio O. Conte que abriram uma investigação congressional em 1969, 
congressistas carregou que as empresas de pequeno porte estiveram 
ameaçadas pela propagação de grande negócio-funcionam sweepstakes 
e práticas deceptive condemned ' em promotions dos vencedores 
preselected. Seus dados compilados revelaram que somente uma 
fração pequena de prêmios anunciados tinha sido concedida 
realmente. O congress não passou uma conta regulatory que o 
ano, e por 1998, o FTC estimasse que mais de 400 milhão sweepstakes 
inundaram o correio anualmente e que os consumidores perderam mais de 
$40 bilhões cada ano através dos sweepstakes e dos scams do 
telemarketing. Em 1999, o congress passado a prevenção 
deceptive do correio e o enforcement agem entre outros proteções de 
consumidor, materiais requeridos este ato dos sweepstakes para indicar
claramente probabilidades de ganhar, valor dos prêmios, e réguas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli anni 60, lottery-come i concorsi destinati 
per divulg i prodotti attraverso i concorsi di lotterie sparsi 
velocemente. Nel diciannovesimo secolo, ogni dichiari i 
lotteries vietati -- definiti mentre i concorsi in cui chances per 
vincere i premi sono stati venduti -- per proteggere i cittadini. 
In 1868, il congresso ha proibito la distribuzione dei materiali
di lottery attraverso la posta. Le lotterie di secolo di 
mid-20th, tuttavia, non hanno richiesto ai contestants di comprare i 
biglietti o i prodotti ai premi di vittoria e così sono state 
considerate legale. In 1966, il numero di lotterie nazionali ha 
ecceduto 600 e una ricerca di FTC in 1968 ha trovato la prova di 
inganno. Nelle seguenti istruzione dei rappresentanti John D. 
Dingell e Silvio O. Conte che hanno aperto una ricerca congressuale in
1969, i membri del Congresso si è caricato che le piccole imprese 
sono state minacciate dalla diffusione di grande commercio-fanno 
funzionare le lotterie e le pratiche ingannevoli condannate 'nelle 
promozioni dei vincitori preselezionati. I loro dati compilati 
hanno rivelato che soltanto una piccola frazione dei premi fatti 
pubblicità a realmente aveva ricevuto. Il congresso non è 
riuscito a passare una fattura regolatrice che l'anno ed entro 1998, 
il FTC ha valutato che più di 400 milione lotterie hanno sommerso 
annualmente la posta e che i consumatori hanno perso ogni anno più di
$40 miliardo attraverso le lotterie e gli scams di telemarketing. 
In 1999, il congresso passato alla prevenzione ingannevole della
posta e l'applicazione si comportano tra altre tutele del consumatore,
questa Legge hanno richiesto i materiali di lotterie dichiarare 
chiaramente le probabilità di vincita, il valore dei premi e le 
regole.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δεκαετία του '60, αγορά-όπως διαγωνισμοί με σκοπό
να κοινοποιήσουν τα προϊόντα μέσω των ανταγωνισμών sweepstakes
που διαδίδονται γρήγορα. Στο 19$ο αιώνα, κάθε κράτος 
απαγόρευσε τις λαχειοφόρες αγορές -- που ορίζονται ως οι 
ανταγωνισμοί στους οποίους οι πιθανότητες να κερδηθούν τα βραβεία
πωλήθηκαν -- για να προστατεύσει τους πολίτες. Το 1868, το
συνέδριο απαγόρευσε τη διανομή των υλικών λαχειοφόρων αγορών 
μέσω του ταχυδρομείου. Ο μέσος-20ός αιώνας sweepstakes, 
εντούτοις, δεν απαίτησε τους αγωνιζομένους για να αγοράσει τα 
εισιτήρια ή τα προϊόντα για να κερδίσει τα βραβεία και 
θεωρήθηκε έτσι νομικός. Το 1966, ο αριθμός εθνικών 
sweepstakes υπερέβη 600 και μια έρευνα FTC το 1968 
βρήκε τα στοιχεία της εξαπάτησης. Στις ακόλουθες δηλώσεις 
από Representatives John Δ. Dingell και το Silvio O. 
Conte που άρχισαν μια του Κογκρέσου έρευνα το 1969, τα μέλη 
του Κογκρέσσου χρέωσαν ότι οι μικρές επιχειρήσεις απειλήθηκαν 
από τη διάδοση του μεγάλου επιχείρηση-τρεξίματος sweepstakes 
και καταδίκασαν τις παραπλανητικές πρακτικές στις προωθήσεις 
"επιλεγμένων εκ των προτέρων νικητών". Τα μεταγλωττισμένα 
στοιχεία τους αποκάλυψαν ότι μόνο ένα μικρό μέρος των 
διαφημισμένων βραβείων είχε απονεμηθεί πραγματικά. Το 
συνέδριο απέτυχε να ψηφίσει ένα ρυθμιστικό νομοσχέδιο ότι το 
έτος, και μέχρι το 1998, το FTC υπολόγισε ότι περισσότερα 
από 400 εκατομμύριο sweepstakes πλημμύρισαν το ταχυδρομείο 
ετησίως και ότι οι καταναλωτές έχασαν κάθε έτος περισσότερων 
από $40 δισεκατομμυρίων μέσω των sweepstakes και της 
τηλεαγοράς scams. Το 1999, το συνέδριο πέρασε τον 
παραπλανητικό νόμο πρόληψης και επιβολής ταχυδρομείου. 
Μεταξύ άλλων προστασιών καταναλωτών, αυτός ο νόμος 
απαίτησε sweepstakes τα υλικά για να δηλώσει σαφώς τις 
πιθανότητες της νίκης, την αξία των βραβείων, και των κανόνων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años 60, loteri'a-como las competencias 
diseñadas para publicar productos a través de las competiciones de 
los montos totales separadas rápidamente. En el diecinueveavo 
siglo, cada estado prohibió las loterías -- definidas mientras que 
las competiciones en las cuales chances para ganar premios fueron 
vendidas -- para proteger a ciudadanos. En 1868, el congreso 
prohibió la distribución de los materiales de la lotería a través 
del correo. Los montos totales del siglo de mid-20th, sin 
embargo, no requirieron a contestants comprar boletos o productos a 
los premios del triunfo y así eran considerados legal. En 1966,
el número de montos totales nacionales excedió de 600 y una 
investigación del FTC en 1968 encontró la evidencia del engaño. 
En las declaraciones siguientes por los representantes Juan D. 
Dingell y Silvio O. Conte que abrieron una investigación del congreso
en 1969, los miembros del Congreso cargó que las pequeñas empresas 
fueran amenazadas por la extensión de grande negocio-ejecuten montos 
totales y prácticas engañosas condenadas en las ' promociones de los
ganadores pre-seleccion. Sus datos compilados revelaron que 
solamente una fracción pequeña de premios anunciacióces había sido
concedida realmente. El congreso no pudo aprobar una cuenta 
reguladora que el año, y antes de 1998, el FTC estimaba que más de 
400 millones de montos totales inundaron el correo anualmente y que 
los consumidores perdieron más de $40 mil millones cada año a 
través de montos totales y de scams del telemarketing. En 1999,
el congreso pasado la prevención engañosa del correo y la 
aplicación actúan entre otras protección al consumidor, materiales 
requeridos este acto de los montos totales para indicar claramente 
probabilidades de ganar, valor de premios, y reglas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086813</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103570</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/serious-questions-of-fairness-ethics-and-legality-congress-investigates-sweepstakes-promotions</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
