<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/674634147</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>674634147</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973921</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chemistry Games: Chirality - Chemistry 2001</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chemie-Spiele: Chirality - Chemie 2001</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Chimie : Chirality - Chimie 2001</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Do Chemistry: Chirality - Chemistry 
2001</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Chimica: Chirality - Chimica 2001</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια χημείας: Chirality - χημεία 2001</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Química: Chirality - Química 
2001</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! The Nobel Prize in Chemistry 2001 concerns work with chiral molecules. These chiral molecules can be used to control or speed up different chemical reactions. In this game you can learn the basic principles of chirality.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Der Nobelpreis in der Chemie 2001 Interessen arbeiten mit 
chiralen Molekülen. Diese chiralen Moleküle können benutzt 
werden, um unterschiedliche chemische Reaktionen zu steuern oder zu 
beschleunigen. In diesem Spiel können Sie die Grundprinzipien 
von chirality erlernen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Le prix 
Nobel en chimie 2001 soucis fonctionnent avec les molécules chirales.
Ces molécules chirales peuvent être employées pour contrôler
ou accélérer différentes réactions chimiques. Dans ce jeu 
vous pouvez apprendre les principes de base du chirality.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! O 
prêmio de nobel no chemistry 2001 interesses trabalha com moléculas 
chiral. Estas moléculas chiral podem ser usadas controlar ou 
apressar-se acima das reações químicas diferentes. Neste jogo
você pode aprender os princípios básicos do chirality.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Il premio Nobel nella chimica 
2001 preoccupazione funziona con le molecole chiral. Queste 
molecole chiral possono essere usate per controllare o accelerare le 
reazioni chimiche differenti. In questo gioco potete imparare i 
principi di base del chirality.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Το 
βραβείο Νόμπελ στη χημεία το 2001 αφορά την εργασία με τα 
chiral μόρια. Αυτά τα chiral μόρια μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν για να ελέγξουν ή να επιταχύνουν τις διαφορετικές
χημικές αντιδράσεις. Σε αυτό το παιχνίδι μπορείτε να 
μάθετε τις βασικές αρχές του chirality.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! El 
premio Nobel en química 2001 preocupaciones trabaja con las 
moléculas chiral. Estas moléculas chiral se pueden utilizar 
para controlar o para acelerar diversas reacciones químicas. En
este juego usted puede aprender los principios de base del chirality.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973921</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>674634147</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chemistry-games-chirality-chemistry-2001</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
