<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103177</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103177</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087175</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Are Literally Slaves": An Early Twentieth-Century Black Nanny Sets the Record Straight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Sind Buchstäblich Sklaven": Ein frühes
Zwanzigst-Jahrhundert Schwarz-Kindermädchen stellt den Satz gerade 
ein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Sommes Littéralement des Esclaves" : 
Une première bonne d'enfants de noir de Vingtième-Siècle 
place l'enregistrement droit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Somos Literalmente Escravos": Um nanny 
adiantado do preto de Vigésimo-Século ajusta o registro reto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Siamo Letteralmente Schiavi": Un nanny in 
anticipo di nero di Ventesimo-Secolo regola il record diritto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είμαστε κυριολεκτικά σκλάβοι": Μια πρώτη μαύρη
παραμάνα εικοστός-αιώνα θέτει το αρχείο ευθύ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Somos Literalmente Esclavos": Un nanny 
temprano del negro del Vige'simo-Siglo fija el expediente recto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In folklore the black nursemaid was seen as a dutiful, self-sacrificing black woman who loved her white family and its children every bit as much as her own. Yet the popular images of the loyal, contented black nursemaid, or "mammy," were unfortunately far from the reality for the African-American women who worked in these homes. In 1912 the  Independent  printed this quasi-autobiographical account of servant life, as related by an African-American domestic worker, which dispelled the comforting "mammy" myth.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In der Folklore wurde das schwarze nursemaid als 
dutiful gesehen und Selbst-opferte schwarze Frau, die ihre weiße 
Familie und seine Kinder jedes Bit soviel wie ihre Selbst liebte. 
Dennoch waren die populären Bilder des loyalen, 
zufriedengestellten schwarzen nursemaid oder "des mammy," leider weit 
von die Wirklichkeit für die Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Frauen, die 
in diesen Häusern arbeiteten. In 1912 das Unabhängige gedruckt
diesem quasi-autobiographischen Konto des Bedienstetlebens, wie von 
einem Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen inländischen Arbeiter in Verbindung 
gestanden, der den tröstenden "mammy" Mythus zerstreute.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le folklore le nursemaid noir a été vu en 
tant que dévoué, la femme noire de art de l'auto-portrait-sacrificing qui a aimé 
sa famille blanche et ses enfants chaque bit autant que ses propres. 
Pourtant les images populaires du fidèle, nursemaid noir 
satisfait, ou de la "maman," étaient malheureusement loin de la 
réalité pour les femmes afro-américaines qui ont travaillé dans ces 
maisons. Dans 1912 le indépendant imprimé ce compte 
quasi-autobiographique de la vie d'domestique, comme rapporté par un 
ouvrier domestique afro-américain, qui a dissipé le mythe de soulagement
de "maman".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No folklore o nursemaid preto foi visto como um 
dutiful, self-sacrificando a mulher preta que amou sua família branca
e suas crianças cada bit tanto quanto seus próprias. Contudo 
as imagens populares do nursemaid preto, ou do "mammy leal, 
satisfeito," eram infelizmente longe da realidade para as mulheres 
Africano-Americanas que trabalharam nestas HOME. Em 1912 o 
independent impresso este cliente quasi-quasi-autobiographical da vida
do empregado, como relacionado por um trabalhador doméstico 
Africano-Americano, que dispelled o mito "mammy" comforting.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel folclore il nursemaid nero è stato visto come 
un dutiful, auto-sacrificando la donna nera che amava la sua famiglia 
bianca ed i relativi bambini ogni bit tanto quanto i suoi propri. 
Tuttavia le immagini popolari del nursemaid nero, o "del mammy 
leale e contented," erano purtroppo lontano dalla realtà per le donne
Africano-Americane che hanno lavorato in queste sedi. In 1912 il
independent stampato questo cliente quasi-autobiografico di vita del 
servo, come riferito da un operaio domestico Africano-Americano, che 
ha dissipato il mito "mammy" di conforto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη λαογραφία το μαύρο nursemaid εβλέίδε ως 
υπάκουο, μόνος-θυσιάζοντας τη μαύρη γυναίκα που αγάπησε τη 
λευκιά οικογένειά της και τα παιδιά της κάθε δυαδικό ψηφίο 
τουλάχιστον την δικοί. Ακόμα οι δημοφιλείς εικόνες του 
πιστού, ικανοποιημένου μαύρου nursemaid, ή "της μαμάς," ήταν 
δυστυχώς μακριά από την πραγματικότητα για τις 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές γυναίκες που εργάστηκαν σε αυτά τα 
σπίτια. Το 1912 ο ανεξάρτητος τύπωσε αυτόν τον 
σχεδόν-αυτοβιογραφικό απολογισμό της ζωής υπαλλήλων, όπως από 
έναν αφρικανικός-αμερικανικό εσωτερικό εργαζόμενο, ο οποίος 
διάλυε τον ανακουφίζοντας μύθο "μαμών".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En folklore el nursemaid negro fue considerado como
dutiful, uno mismo-sacrificando a la mujer negra que amó a su familia
blanca y a sus niños cada dígito binario tanto como sus los propios.
Con todo las imágenes populares del nursemaid negro, o del 
"mammy leal, contento," estaban desafortunadamente lejos de la 
realidad para las mujeres Africano-Americanas que trabajaron en estos 
hogares. En 1912 la Independiente impresa esta cuenta 
cuasi-autobiogra'fica de la vida del criado, según lo relacionado por
un trabajador doméstico Africano-Americano, que disipó el mito 
"mammy" confortante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087175</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103177</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-are-literally-slaves-an-early-twentieth-century-black-nanny-sets-the-record-straight</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
