<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103357</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103357</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211258</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration: Satellite Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale ozeanische und atmosphärische Leitung: 
Satellit-Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gestion océanique et atmosphérique nationale : 
Homepage de Satellite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Administração oceanic e atmosférica nacional: 
Homepage Do Satélite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gestione oceanica ed atmosferica nazionale: 
Homepage Del Satellite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ωκεάνεια και ατμοσφαιρική διοίκηση: 
Δορυφορική αρχική σελίδα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Administración oceánica y atmosférica nacional:
Homepage Del Satélite</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">NOAA's National Environmental Satellite, Data and Information Service (NESDIS) operates satellites and manages the processing and distribution of data and images these satellites produce daily. The primary user of satellite data and images is the National Weather Service. This clearinghouse website offers a vast amount of information gathered from NOAA satellites. Users can link to spotlighted information, NOAA satellite programs and information satellite organizations. This site also contains daily satellite images and image galleries.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NOAAs nationaler Klimasatellit, Daten und 
Informationsdienst (NESDIS) läßt Satelliten laufen und handhat die 
Verarbeitung und Verteilung von Daten und von Bildern, die diese 
Satelliten täglich produzieren. Der wichtige Benutzer von 
Satellitendaten und von Bildern ist der nationale Wetter-Service. 
Diese Verrechnungszentraleweb site bietet eine beträchtliche 
Menge Informationen erfaßt von den NOAA Satelliten an. Benutzer
können mit angestrahlten Informationen, NOAA Satellitenprogrammen und
Informationen Satellitorganisationen binden. Diese Site enthält
auch tägliche Satellitenbilder und Bildgalerien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le satellite environnemental national de NOAA, les
données et le service d'information (NESDIS) actionne des satellites 
et contrôle le traitement et distribution des données et des images 
que ces satellites produisent quotidiennement. L'utilisateur 
primaire des données et des images satellites est le national 
Survivent à au service. Ce site Web de chambre de 
compensation offre une vaste quantité de l'information recueillie des
satellites de NOAA. Les utilisateurs peuvent joindre à 
l'information mise en lumière, aux programmes de NOAA et aux 
organismes satellites de satellite de l'information. Ce site 
contient également des images satellites quotidiennes et des galeries
d'image.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O satélite ambiental nacional de NOAA, os dados e
o serviço de informação (NESDIS) operam satélites e controlam 
processar e distribuição dos dados e das imagens que estes 
satélites produzem diariamente. O usuário preliminar de dados 
e de imagens satellite é o serviço nacional do tempo. Este Web
site do clearinghouse oferece uma quantidade de informação vasta 
recolhida dos satélites de NOAA. Os usuários podem ligar à 
informação spotlighted, aos programas de NOAA e às organizações 
satellite do satélite da informação. Este local contem 
também imagens satellite diárias e galerias da imagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il satellite ambientale nazionale del NOAA, i dati
ed il servizio d'informazione (NESDIS) fa funzionare i satelliti e 
gestisce elaborare e distribuzione dei dati e delle immagini che 
questi satelliti producono giornalmente. L'utente primario dei 
dati e delle immagini satelliti è il servizio nazionale del tempo. 
Questo Web site della stanza di compensazione offre una grande 
quantità di informazioni riunita dai satelliti di NOAA. 
Gli utenti possono collegarsi alle informazioni messe in luce, 
ai programmi di NOAA ed alle organizzazioni satelliti del satellite 
delle informazioni. Questo luogo egualmente contiene le immagini
satelliti quotidiane e le gallerie di immagine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο εθνικό περιβαλλοντικό δορυφόρος NOAA, το στοιχείο
και η υπηρεσία πληροφοριών (NESDIS) ενεργοποιούν τους 
δορυφόρους και διαχειρίζονται την επεξεργασία και τη διανομή των 
στοιχείων και των εικόνων που αυτοί οι δορυφόροι παράγουν 
καθημερινά. Ο αρχικός χρήστης των δορυφορικών στοιχείων και
των εικόνων είναι η εθνική καιρική υπηρεσία. Αυτός ο 
ιστοχώρος γραφείων συμψηφισμού προσφέρει ένα απέραντο ποσό 
πληροφοριών που συγκεντρώνεται από τους δορυφόρους NOAA. 
Οι χρήστες μπορούν να συνδέσουν με τις πληροφορίες, τα 
δορυφορικά προγράμματα NOAA και τις δορυφορικές οργανώσεις 
πληροφοριών. Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει επίσης τις 
καθημερινές δορυφορικές εικόνες και τις στοές εικόνας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El satélite ambiental nacional de NOAA, los datos
y el servicio informativo (NESDIS) funciona los satélites y maneja el
proceso y distribución de datos y de imágenes que estos satélites 
producen diariamente. El utilizador primario de datos y de 
imágenes basados en los satélites es el servicio nacional del 
tiempo. Este Web site de la cámara de compensación ofrece una 
cantidad de información extensa recolectada de los satélites de 
NOAA. Los utilizadores pueden conectar a la información puesta 
de relieve, a los programas de NOAA y a las organizaciones basados en 
los satélites del satélite de la información. Este sitio 
también contiene imágenes basadas en los satélites diarias y 
galerías de la imagen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211258</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103357</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-oceanic-and-atmospheric-administration-satellite-homepage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
