<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105827</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105827</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086070</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Democracy Can't Live in These Houses": Senator Paul Douglas Advocates a Federal Housing Program to Clear Slum Areas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Demokratie kann nicht in diesen Häusern leben": 
Senator Paul Douglas Advocates ein Bundeswohnungsbauprogramm zu 
den freien Elendsviertel-Bereichen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la "démocratie ne peut pas vivre dans ces 
Chambres" : Le sénateur Paul Douglas Advocates un programme de 
logement fédéral aux régions claires de taudis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">a "democracia não pode viver nestas casas": 
Senator Paul Douglas Advogar um programa de carcaça federal às
áreas desobstruídas do slum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la democrazia non può vivere in queste Camere": 
Il senatore Paul Douglas Advocates un programma di alloggiamento
federale alle zone libere de slum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η δημοκρατία δεν μπορεί να ζήσει σε αυτά τα σπίτια":
Ο γερουσιαστής Paul Ντάγκλας υποστηρίζει ένα 
ομοσπονδιακό πρόγραμμα κατοικίας για να καθαρίσει τις περιοχές 
τρωγλών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "democracia no puede vivir en estas casas": 
Senador Paul Douglas Advocates un programa de cubierta federal a
las áreas claras de los tugurios</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Federal Housing Administration, established in 1934, helped middle-income families buy new homes and improve existing ones. Federal loans for low-cost housing, however, became available only after passage of the Wagner-Steagle Housing Act of 1937, and then only in modest amounts. To address a growing crisis, President Harry S. Truman, as part of his "Fair Deal" initiative, called for new slum clearance and housing legislation. Despite accusations of "socialized housing" and opposition from the real estate and construction industries, on July 15, 1949, Truman signed into law a bill providing $1.5 billion in loans and grants.Available to localities, this money would, in the President's words, "open up the prospect of decent homes in wholesome surroundings for low-income families now living in the squalor of the slums." In the following article published just prior to the bill's passage, Illinois Senator Paul Douglas, a professor of economics and former New Deal supporter, argued for effective legislation. Despite the law's progressive intent, urban renewal programs ultimately destroyed formerly vibrant neighborhoods. These programs were also used throughout the South and in Northern cities to strengthen segregation by relocating African-Americans away from white school districts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Bundesgehäuse-Leitung, hergestellt 1934, half
neuen Häusern des mittleren Einkommenfamilien Kaufes und verbessert 
das Existieren. Bundesdarlehen für preiswertes Gehäuse wurden 
jedoch nur nachdem Durchgang der Wagner-Steagle Gehäuse-Tat von 1937 
und dann nur in den bescheidenen Mengen vorhanden. Um eine 
wachsende Krise, verlangte Präsident Harry S. Truman, als Teil seiner
Initiative "des angemessenen Abkommens" zu adressieren, neuen 
Elendsviertelabstand und Unterbringung Gesetzgebung. Trotz der 
Anklagen "des sozialisierten Gehäuses" und der Opposition von den 
Immobilien und vom Baugewerbe, auf Juli 15, 1949, Truman, das in 
Gesetz wurde eine unterzeichnet wurde, Rechnung, die $1.5 Milliarde in
den Darlehen und grants.Available zu den Stellen, dieses Geld, in den 
Wörtern des Präsidenten bereitstellt, "erschließen die Aussicht der
annehmbaren Häuser in den gesunden Umlagerungen für die mit 
niedrigem Einkommenfamilien, die jetzt leben im Squalor der 
Elendsviertel." Im folgenden Artikel veröffentlichte gerade vor
dem Durchgang der Rechnung, Illinois Senator Paul Douglas, ein 
Professor der Volkswirtschaft und des ehemaligen Verfechters des neuen
Abkommens, argumentiert für wirkungsvolle Gesetzgebung. Trotz 
der progressiven Absicht des Gesetzes zerstörten städtische 
Erneuerungprogramme schließlich früher vibrant Nachbarschaften. 
Diese Programme wurden auch während des Südens und in den 
Nordstädte verwendet, um Abtrennung zu verstärken, indem man 
Afrikanisch-Amerikaner weg von den weißen Schulebezirken verlagerte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La gestion de logement fédéral, établie en 
1934, a aidé de nouvelles maisons de revenu d'achat moyen de familles
et améliore celles existantes. Les prêts fédéraux pour le 
logement peu coûteux, cependant, sont devenus disponibles seulement 
après le passage de l'acte de logement de Wagner-steagle de 1937, 
et puis seulement dans des montants modestes. Pour adresser une 
crise croissante, le Président Harry S. Truman, en tant qu'élément 
de sa initiative "d'affaire juste", a nécessité le nouveau 
dégagement de taudis et législation de loger. En dépit des 
accusations "du logement eu une vie sociale" et de l'opposition des 
immobiliers et des industries du bâtiment, sur 15 juillet 1949, 
Truman signé dans la loi une facture fournissant $1.5 milliards en 
prêts et grants.Available aux localités, cet argent , dans les mots 
du président, "ouvrent la perspective des maisons décentes dans des 
environnements sains pour les familles de faible revenu vivant 
maintenant dans la misère noire de taudis." Dans l'article 
suivant a édité juste avant le passage de la facture, le sénateur 
Paul Douglas, un professeur de l'Illinois des sciences économiques et
de l'ancien défenseur de nouvelle affaire, plaidé pour la 
législation pertinente. En dépit de l'intention progressive de
la loi, les programmes urbains de renouvellement finalement ont 
détruit autrefois les voisinages vibrants. Ces programmes 
ont été également employés dans tous les Sud et dans les 
villes nordiques pour renforcer la ségrégation en replaçant des 
Afro-Américains loin des zones blanches d'école.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A administração de carcaça federal, 
estabelecida em 1934, ajudou a HOME novas da compra média das 
famílias da renda e melhora existir. Os empréstimos federais 
para a carcaça low-cost, entretanto, tornaram-se disponíveis somente
depois que passagem do ato da carcaça de Wagner-Steagle de 1937, e 
então somente em quantidades modestas. Para dirigir-se a uma 
crise crescente, o presidente Harry S. Truman, como a parte de sua 
"iniciativa do negócio justo", chamou-se para o afastamento novo do 
slum e legislação abrigar. Apesar dos accusations "da carcaça
socializada" e da oposição da propriedade real e das indústrias de 
construção, julho em 15, 1949, em Truman assinado na lei uma conta 
que fornece $1.5 bilhões nos empréstimos e grants.Available aos 
localities, este dinheiro , nas palavras do presidente, "abre acima do
prospeto de HOME decent em arredors wholesome para as famílias 
low-income que vivem agora no squalor dos slums." No seguinte 
artigo publicou apenas antes da passagem da conta, senator Paul 
Douglas de Illinois, um professor da economia e do supporter anterior 
do negócio novo, discutido para a legislação eficaz. Apesar 
da intenção progressiva da lei, os programas urbanos da renovação 
destruíram finalmente anteriormente vizinhanças vibrant. Estes
programas foram usados também durante todo o sul e em cidades do 
norte strengthen o segregation relocating Africano-Americanos away dos
distritos brancos da escola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La gestione di alloggiamento federale, stabilita 
in 1934, ha aiutato le nuove sedi di reddito del buy centrale delle 
famiglie e migliora quei esistenti. I prestiti federali per 
alloggiamento a basso costo, tuttavia, sono diventato disponibili solo
dopo il passaggio della legge sugli alloggi di Wagner-Steagle di 1937 
ed allora soltanto negli importi modesti. Per richiamare una 
crisi crescente, il presidente Harry S. Truman, come componente della 
sua "iniziativa di affare giusto", ha richiesto nuovo spazio de slum e
legislazione di alloggio. Malgrado le accuse di "ha 
socializzato l'alloggiamento" e l'opposizione dal bene immobile e 
dalle industrie edilizie, il 15 luglio 1949, Truman ha firmato in 
legge una fattura che fornisce $1.5 miliardo nei prestiti e 
grants.Available alle località, questi soldi, nelle parole del 
presidente, "apre il prospetto delle sedi decent nei dintorni sani per
le famiglie low-income ora che vivono nello squalor di slums." 
Nel seguente articolo ha pubblicato appena prima del passaggio 
della fattura, il senatore Paul Douglas, un professore dell'Illinois 
di economia e del sostenitore precedente di nuovo affare, discusso per
legislazione efficace. Malgrado l'intenzione progressiva della 
legge, i programmi urbani di rinnovamento infine hanno 
distrutto precedentemente le vicinanze vibrant. Questi 
programmi egualmente sono stati usati durante il sud ed in città 
nordiche per rinforzare la segregazione riassegnando gli 
Africano-Americani via dai distretti bianchi della scuola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ομοσπονδιακή διοίκηση κατοικίας, που καθιερώθηκε το 
1934, βοήθησε τις μεσαίου εισοδήματος οικογένειες να αγοράσουν
τα νέα σπίτια και να βελτιώσουν τους υπάρχοντες αυτούς. Τα 
ομοσπονδιακά δάνεια για τις εργατικές κατοικίες, εντούτοις, 
διατέθηκαν μόνο μετά από τη μετάβαση του νόμου κατοικίας 
ωαγνερ- Steagle του 1937, και έπειτα μόνο στα μέτρια ποσά. 
Για να εξετάσει μια αυξανόμενη κρίση, ο Πρόεδρος της 
πρωτοβουλίας Harry S. Truman, ως τμήμα "δίκαιης 
διαπραγμάτευσής του", απαίτησε τη νέες εκκαθάριση τρωγλών και τη
νομοθεσία στέγασης. Παρά τις κατηγορίες της 
"κοινωνικοποιημένης κατοικίασ" και της αντίθεσης από την ακίνητη 
περιουσία και τους κλάδους των οικοδομικών και τεχνικών έργων, 
στις 15 Ιουλίου ..1949, Truman που υπογράφεται στο νόμο 
ένας λογαριασμός που παρέχει $1,5 δισεκατομμύρια στα δάνεια 
και τις επιχορηγήσεις διαθέσιμες στις τοποθεσίες, αυτά τα 
χρήματα, στις λέξεις του Προέδρου, "θα άνοιγε την προοπτική των 
κόσμιων σπιτιών στα θρεπτικά περίχωρα για τις χαμηλού 
εισοδήματος οικογένειες που ζουν τώρα στο squalor των τρωγλών."
Στο ακόλουθο άρθρο που δημοσιεύθηκε ακριβώς πριν από τη 
μετάβαση του λογαριασμού, το Ιλλινόις γερουσιαστής Paul 
Ντάγκλας, ένας καθηγητής των οικονομικών και προηγούμενος νέος 
υποστηρικτής διαπραγμάτευσης, υποστήριξε την αποτελεσματική 
νομοθεσία. Παρά προοδευτικό τον προσηλωμένο του νόμου, τα 
προγράμματα αστικής ανανέωσης κατέστρεψαν τελικά στο παρελθόν 
τις δονούμενες γειτονιές. Αυτά τα προγράμματα 
χρησιμοποιήθηκαν επίσης σε όλο το νότο και στις βόρειες πόλεις 
για να ενισχύσουν το διαχωρισμό με τον επανεντοπισμό 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανών μακρυά από τις άσπρες σχολικές περιοχές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La administración de cubierta federal, 
establecida en 1934, ayudó a nuevos hogares de la renta de la compra 
media de las familias y mejora el existir. Los préstamos 
federales para la cubierta barata, sin embargo, llegaron a estar 
disponibles solamente después del paso del acto de la cubierta de 
Wagner-Steagle de 1937, y entonces solamente en cantidades modestas. 
Para tratar una crisis cada vez mayor, presidente Harry S. 
Truman, como parte de su iniciativa del "reparto justo", llamó para 
la nueva separación de los tugurios y legislación el contener. 
A pesar de acusaciones de la "cubierta socializada" y de la 
oposición de las propiedades inmobiliarias y de las industrias de 
construcción, 15 de julio de 1949, Truman firmado en ley una 
cuenta que proporcionaba a $1.5 mil millones en préstamos y a 
grants.Available a los lugares, este dinero , en las palabras del 
presidente, "abre la perspectiva de hogares decentes en los 
alrededores sanos para las familias de ingreso bajo ahora que vivían 
en la mugre de los tugurios." En el artículo siguiente publicó
apenas antes del paso de la cuenta, senador Paul Douglas, profesor de 
Illinois de la economía y del partidario anterior del nuevo reparto, 
discutido para la legislación eficaz. A pesar de el intento 
progresivo de la ley, los programas urbanos de la renovación 
destruyeron en última instancia antes vecindades vibrantes. 
Estos programas también fueron utilizados a través del sur y 
en ciudades norteñas para consolidar la segregación volviendo a 
poner a Africano-Americanos lejos de los districtos blancos de la 
escuela.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086070</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105827</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/democracy-cant-live-in-these-houses-senator-paul-douglas-advocates-a-federal-housing-program-to-clear-slum-areas</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
