<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107925</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107925</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087032</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Real Estate Industry Lobby and Public Housing in the 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Immobilien-Industrie-Vorhalle und das 
allgemeine Gehäuse in den dreißiger Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'entrée de secteur immobilier et le logement 
public dans les années 30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O lobby da indústria de propriedade real e a 
carcaça pública nos 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ingresso di industria di bene immobile e 
l'edilizia popolare nei 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το λόμπι βιομηχανίας ακίνητων περιουσιών και η 
δημόσια κατοικία στη δεκαετία του '30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El pasillo de la industria de propiedades 
inmobiliarias y la cubierta pública en los años 30</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Urban reformers in the late-nineteenth and early-twentieth centuries had long pointed with horror to the unsanitary and inadequate conditions in which millions of Americans lived, particularly in large cities. But it took the severe economic crisis of the Great Depression to force the federal government to intervene directly in the housing market, and even then the response was often only half-hearted. In the 1930s, access to public housing was highly desirable, and early residents preferred their new homes, which offered bright and well-appointed alternatives to their previous substandard residences. The sharpest criticisms of public housing, however, came from builders and realtors who feared competition and argued that public housing was too appealing and would decrease home ownership. The most influential of the anti-public housing lobbies was the National Association of Real Estate Boards (NAREB). In this 1935 report to the board, NAREB president Walter S. Schmidt argued against public housing on economic and ideological grounds.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Städtische Reformer in den spät-19. und 
früh-zwanzigsten Jahrhunderten hatten lang mit Grausigkeit auf die 
unhygienischen und unzulänglichen Bedingungen, in denen Millionen 
Amerikaner lebten, besonders in den großen Städte gezeigt. 
Aber sie nahm die strenge Wirtschaftskrise des großen 
Tiefstands, um die Bundesregierung zu erzwingen, um direkt in den 
Gehäusemarkt einzugreifen, und glättet dann die Antwort war häufig 
nur halbherzig. In den dreißiger Jahren war Zugriff zum 
allgemeinen Gehäuse in hohem Grade wünschenswert, und frühe 
Bewohner bevorzugten ihre neuen Häuser, die die hellen und 
gut-festgesetzten Alternativen ihren vorhergehenden nicht der Norm 
entsprechenden Wohnsitzen anboten. Die schärfsten Kritiken des 
allgemeinen Gehäuses jedoch kamen von den Erbauern und von den 
Realtors, die Konkurrenz fürchteten und argumentierten, daß 
allgemeines Gehäuse auch gefiel und würden Eigenheimbesitz 
verringern. Das einflußreichste der Anti-Öffentlichkeit 
Gehäusevorhallen war die nationale Verbindung der Immobilien-Bretter 
(NAREB). In diesem Report 1935 zum Brett, argumentierte NAREB 
Präsident Walter S. Schmidt gegen allgemeines Gehäuse auf 
ökonomischem und ideologischem Boden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les réformateurs urbains aux tard-dix-neuvième et
tôt-vingtième siècles s'étaient longtemps dirigés avec l'horreur 
aux conditions antihygiéniques et insatisfaisantes en lesquelles les 
millions d'Américains ont vécu, en particulier dans de grandes 
villes. Mais elle a pris la crise économique grave de la grande
dépression pour forcer le gouvernement fédéral pour intervenir 
directement sur le marché du logement, et égalise alors la réponse 
était souvent seulement hésitante. Dans les années 30, 
l'accès au logement public était fortement souhaitable, et les 
premiers résidants ont préféré leurs nouvelles maisons, qui ont 
offert des solutions de rechange lumineuses et bien-désignées à 
leurs résidences inférieures précédentes. Les critiques les 
plus pointues du logement public, cependant, sont venues des 
constructeurs et des agents immobiliers qui ont craint la concurrence 
et ont argué du fait que le logement public en appelait trop et 
diminueraient le propriétaire de logement. Le plus influent des
entrées de logement d'anti-public était l'association nationale des 
panneaux de immobiliers (NAREB). Dans cet état 1935 au panneau,
le Président Walter S. Schmidt de NAREB a discuté contre le logement
public pour les raisons économiques et idéologiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os reformers urbanos nos tarde-décimos nonos e 
cedo-vigésimos séculos tinham apontado por muito tempo com horror 
às condições unsanitary e inadequadas em que os milhões dos 
americanos viveram, particularmente em cidades grandes. Mas fêz
exame da crise econômica severa do depression grande para forçar o 
governo federal para intervir diretamente no mercado de carcaça, e 
nivela então a resposta era frequentemente somente half-hearted. 
Nos 1930s, o acesso à carcaça pública era altamente 
desejável, e os residentes adiantados preferiram suas HOME novas, que
ofereceram alternativas brilhantes e bem-apontadas a suas residências
substandard precedentes. Os criticisms os mais afiados da 
carcaça pública, entretanto, vieram dos construtores e dos realtors 
que temeram a competição e discutiram que a carcaça pública estava
apelando demasiado e diminuíram a posse home. O mais 
influential dos lobbies da carcaça do anti-público era a 
associação nacional das placas da propriedade real (NAREB). 
Neste relatório 1935 à placa, o presidente Walter S. Schmidt 
de NAREB discutiu de encontro à carcaça pública em terras 
econômicas e ideological.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I reformers urbani nei in ritardo-diciannovesimi e
presto-ventesimi secoli lungamente avevano indicato con l'orrore ai 
termini antigienici ed inadeguati in cui milioni di Americani hanno 
vissuto, specialmente in grandi città. Ma ha preso la crisi 
economica severa della depressione grande per forzare il governo 
federale per intervenire direttamente nel mercato degli alloggi e 
perfino allora la risposta era spesso soltanto incerto. Nei 
1930s, l'accesso ad edilizia popolare era altamente desiderabile ed i 
residenti in anticipo hanno preferito le loro nuove sedi, che hanno 
offerto le alternative luminose e bene-nominate alle loro residenze 
inferiori alla media precedenti. Le critiche più taglienti di 
edilizia popolare, tuttavia, sono venuto dai costruttori e dai 
realtors che hanno temuto la concorrenza ed hanno sostenuto che 
l'edilizia popolare ugualmente stava facendo appello e farebbero 
diminuire la proprietà domestica. L'più influente degli 
ingressi dell'alloggiamento del anti-pubblico era l'associazione 
nazionale dei Bordi del bene immobile (NAREB). In questo 
rapporto 1935 al bordo, il presidente Walter S. Schmidt di 
NAREB ha parlato contro edilizia popolare per i motivi economici ed 
ideologici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αστικοί μεταρρυθμιστές στους πρόσφατος-δέκατους 
έννατους και πρόωρος-εικοστούς αιώνες είχαν δείξει από καιρό 
με τη φρίκη τους unsanitary και ανεπαρκείς όρους στους οποίους 
τα εκατομμύρια Αμερικανών έζησαν, ιδιαίτερα στις μεγάλες πόλεις.
Αλλά πήρε την αυστηρή οικονομική κρίση της μεγάλης 
οικονομικής κρίσης για να αναγκάσει την ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση 
για να επεμβει άμεσα στην αγορά κατοικίας, και ακόμα και τότε η 
απάντηση ήταν συχνά μόνο απρόθυμη. Στη δεκαετία του '30, η
πρόσβαση στη δημόσια κατοικία ήταν ιδιαίτερα επιθυμητή, και οι 
πρώτοι κάτοικοι προτίμησαν τα νέα σπίτια τους, τα οποία 
πρόσφεραν τις φωτεινές και καλά-διορισμένες εναλλακτικές λύσεις 
στις προηγούμενες κάτω του μετρίου κατοικίες τους. Οι 
αιχμηρότερες κριτικές της δημόσιας κατοικίας, εντούτοις, 
προήλθαν από τους οικοδόμους και τα realtors που ο 
φοβισμένος ανταγωνισμός και υποστήριξε ότι η δημόσια 
κατοικία ήταν επίσης ελκυστική και θα μείωνε τη βασική 
ιδιοκτησία. Ο επιδρύτερος των αντι-δημόσιων λόμπι κατοικίας
ήταν η εθνική ένωση των πινάκων ακίνητων περιουσιών (NAREB). 
Σε αυτήν την έκθεση του 1935 στον πίνακα, NAREB 
Πρόεδρος walter S. Schmidt μίλησε ενάντια στη δημόσια 
κατοικία για οικονομικούς και ιδεολογικούς λόγους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los reformadores urbanos en los tarde-diecinueveavo
y temprano-vige'simos siglos habían señalado de largo con horror a 
las condiciones antihigiénicas e inadecuadas en las cuales millones 
de americanos vivieron, determinado en ciudades grandes. Pero 
tomó la crisis económica severa de la gran depresión para forzar el
gobierno federal para intervenir directamente en el mercado de 
cubierta, e iguala entonces la respuesta era a menudo solamente poco 
entusiasta. En los años 30, el acceso a la cubierta pública 
era altamente deseable, y los residentes tempranos prefirieron sus 
nuevos hogares, que ofrecieron alternativas brillantes y 
bien-designados a sus residencias inferiores al nivel normal 
anteriores. Las críticas más sostenidas de la cubierta 
pública, sin embargo, vinieron de los constructores y de los realtors
que temieron la competición y discutieron que la cubierta pública 
abrogara también y disminuirían la propiedad casera. El más 
influyente de los pasillos de la cubierta del contra-pu'blico era la 
asociación nacional de las tarjetas de las propiedades inmobiliarias 
(NAREB). En este informe 1935 a la tarjeta, presidente Walter S.
Schmidt de NAREB discutió contra la cubierta pública en los 
argumentos económicos e ideológicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087032</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107925</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-real-estate-industry-lobby-and-public-housing-in-the-1930s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
