<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105316</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105316</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209943</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Triangle Circumcenter </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dreieck Circumcenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Triangle Circumcenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Triângulo Circumcenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Triangolo Circumcenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τρίγωνο Circumcenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Triángulo Circumcenter</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The applet shows a triangle which the user can resize by dragging any of its vertices. It shows the three perpendicular bisectors of the sides and the point where they intersect - the circumcenter. These track the changes in the triangle in real time. It shows that the circumcenter may lie outside the triangle. The associated web page describes the properties of the circumcenter and points out that it the center of the triangle's circumcircle. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der applet zeigt einem Dreieck, welches der 
Benutzer die Größe neu bestimmen kann, indem er irgendwelche seiner 
Gipfel schleppt. Er zeigt die drei Senkrechtbisectors der Seiten
und des Punktes, in dem sie schneiden - das circumcenter. Diese 
spüren die Änderungen im Dreieck in der Istzeit auf. Sie 
zeigt, daß das circumcenter außerhalb des Dreiecks liegen kann. 
Die verbundene Webseite beschreibt die Eigenschaften des 
circumcenter und unterstreicht daß es die Mitte des circumcircle des 
Dreiecks. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit 
einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch 
im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'applet montre à une triangle ce que 
l'utilisateur peut remettre à la côte en traînant n'importe lequel 
de ses sommets. Il montre les trois bisectors perpendiculaires 
des côtés et du point où ils intersectent - le circumcenter. 
Ceux-ci dépistent les changements de la triangle en temps 
réel. Il prouve que le circumcenter peut se trouver en dehors 
de la triangle. La page Web associée décrit les 
propriétés du circumcenter et précise qu'il le centre du 
circumcircle de la triangle. L'applet peut être agrandi à la 
taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de 
classe. Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant
peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la 
maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion 
exigée. Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif 
de manuel de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O applet mostra a um triângulo qual o usuário 
pode resize arrastando alguns de seus vertices. Mostra os três 
bisectors perpendiculares dos lados e do ponto onde se cruzam - o 
circumcenter. Estes seguem as mudanças no triângulo no tempo 
real. Mostra que o circumcenter pode se encontrar fora do 
triângulo. O Web page associado descreve as propriedades do 
circumcenter e indica que ele o centro do circumcircle do triângulo. 
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il applet mostra ad un triangolo quale l'utente 
può ridimensionare trascinando c'è ne dei relativi vertici. 
Mostra i tre bisectors perpendicolari dei lati e del punto in 
cui intersecano - il circumcenter. Questi rintracciano i 
cambiamenti nel triangolo in tempo reale. Indica che il 
circumcenter può trovarsi fuori del triangolo. Il Web page 
collegato descrive le proprietà del circumcenter e precisa che esso 
il centro del circumcircle del triangolo. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το applet εμφανίζει ένα τρίγωνο που ο χρήστης 
μπορεί να επαναταξινομήσει με το σύρσιμο οποιωνδήποτε από 
vertices του. _ αυτός εμφανίζω ο τρεις κάθετος ψησεθτορς ο
πλευρά και ο σημείο όπου αυτός κόβω - ο θηρθuμθεντερ. 
Αυτοί ακολουθούν τις αλλαγές στο τρίγωνο στον πραγματικό 
χρόνο. Δείχνει ότι το circumcenter μπορεί να βρεθεί έξω
από το τρίγωνο. Σχετική ιστοσελίδας περιγράφει τις 
ιδιότητες του circumcenter και επισημαίνει ότι αυτό το κέντρο 
του τριγώνου circumcircle. Το Applet μπορεί να 
διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El applet muestra a triángulo cuál puede volver 
a clasificar según el tamaño el utilizador arrastrando cualesquiera 
de sus cimas. Muestra los tres bisectors perpendiculares de las 
caras y de la punta donde se intersecan - el circumcenter. 
Éstos siguen los cambios en el triángulo en tiempo real. 
Muestra que el circumcenter puede mentir fuera del triángulo. 
El Web page asociado describe las características del 
circumcenter y precisa que él el centro del circumcircle del 
triángulo. El applet se puede agrandar a la talla de la 
pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala de clase. 
El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede tenerle 
acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209943</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105316</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/triangle-circumcenter</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
