<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104173</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104173</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087489</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Clear Everything with Sidney": Hillman's Conservative Critics Say It with Limericks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"frei alles mit Sidney": Hillmans 
konservative Kritiker sagen es mit Limericks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"clair tout avec Sidney" : Les critiques 
conservateurs de Hillman le disent avec des Limericks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"desobstruído tudo com Sidney": Os 
críticos conservadores de Hillman dizem-no com Limericks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"libero tutto con Sidney": I critici 
Conservatori dell'Hillman lo dicono con Limericks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Καθαρίστε όλα με το Sidney": Hillman οι 
συντηρητικοί κριτικοί το λένε με τα πεντάστιχα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"claro todo con Sidney": Los críticos 
conservadores de Hillman lo dicen con Limericks</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Labor leader Sidney Hillman emerged as a powerful national figure during the Great Depression, in part because of his role as a leader of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO), but even more because of his ties to President Franklin Roosevelt and other New Dealers. In 1944 Republican presidential candidate Thomas E. Dewey charged that the CIO and Hillman's Political Action Committee (PAC) dominated Roosevelt. Part of the evidence for this (unfounded) charge was the rumor--given some credibility by its publication in the  New York Times --that Roosevelt had told party leaders to "Clear it with Sidney" before selecting a vice-presidential candidate in 1944. Particularly rabid on the subject were the newspapers owned by the anti-New Dealer William Randolph Hearst. Hearst's  New York Journal-American  even sponsored a "Sidney Limerick Contest." These winning entries gave a flavor of the sharp antagonism and prejudices that the nation's most politically influential labor leader aroused.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gewerkschaftsführer Sidney Hillman tauchte als 
leistungsfähige nationale Abbildung während des großen Tiefstands, 
im Teil wegen seiner Rolle als Führer des Kongresses der 
Industrieverbände (CIO), aber sogar mehr wegen seiner Gleichheit zum 
Präsidenten Franklin Roosevelt und andere neue Händler auf. In
1944 lud republikanischer Präsidentenanwärter Thomas E. Dewey auf, 
daß der CIO und Hillmans politische Tätigkeit Ausschuß (PAC) 
Roosevelt beherrschte. Der Teil des Beweises für diese 
(unbegründete) Ladung war das Gerücht -- etwas Glaubwürdigkeit 
durch seine Publikation in den New York Zeiten gegeben -- dieses 
Roosevelt hatte erklärt den Parteiführern "frei es mit Sidney", 
bevor er einen Vize-präsidentenanwärter 1944 auswählte. Auf 
dem Thema waren die Zeitungen besonders rasend, die vom Anti-Neuen 
Händler William Randolph Hearst besessen wurden. New York 
Hearsts Journal-Amerikanisches sogar gefördert einem "Sidney Limerick
Wettbewerb." Diese gewinnenden Einträge gaben ein Aroma des 
scharfen Antagonismus und der Vorurteile, die der einflußreiche 
Gewerkschaftsführer der Nation am politischsten weckte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le dirigeant syndical Sidney Hillman a émergé 
comme figure nationale puissante pendant la grande dépression, en 
partie en raison de son rôle en tant qu'amorce du congrès des 
organismes industriels (CIO), mais encore plus en raison de ses 
cravates au Président Franklin Roosevelt et d'autres nouveaux 
distributeurs. Dans le E. présidentiel républicain de Thomas 
du candidat 1944 Dewey a chargé que le Comité d'action 
politique de CIO et de Hillman (PAC) a dominé Roosevelt. Une 
partie de l'évidence pour cette charge (non fondée) était la rumeur
-- donnée de la crédibilité par sa publication dans les temps de 
New York -- ce Roosevelt l'avait dit à des amorces de partie "claires
avec Sidney" avant de choisir un candidat vice-présidentiel en 1944. 
Particulièrement rabiques sur le sujet étaient les journaux 
possédés par l'anti-Nouveau distributeur William Randolph Hearst. 
Journal-Américain de New York de Hearst même commandité un 
"concours de Sidney Limerick." Ces entrées de gain ont donné
une saveur de l'antagonisme et des préjudices pointus que le 
dirigeant syndical influent de la nation le plus politiquement a 
réveillés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O líder labor Sidney Hillman emergiu como uma 
figura nacional poderosa durante o depression grande, na parte por 
causa de seu papel como um líder do congress das organizações 
industriais (CIO), mas mesmo mais por causa de seus laços ao 
presidente Franklin Roosevelt e outros negociantes novos. Em 
1944 o candidato presidencial republicano Thomas E. Dewey carregou que
o comitê de ação política de CIO e de Hillman (PAC) dominou 
Roosevelt. A parte da evidência para esta carga (unfounded) era
o boato -- dado algum credibility por sua publicação nos tempos de 
New York -- esse Roosevelt tinha-o dito aos líderes do partido 
"desobstruídos com Sidney" antes de selecionar um candidato 
vice-presidencial em 1944. Particularmente rabid no assunto eram
os jornais possuídos pelo negociante anti-Novo William Randolph 
Hearst. Jornal-Americano de New York de Hearst patrocinado mesmo
de "uma competição Sidney Limerick." Estas entradas ganhando 
deram um sabor do antagonism e dos preconceitos afiados que o líder 
labor influential da nação o mais polìtica despertou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il capo di lavoro Sidney Hillman è emerso
come figura nazionale potente durante la depressione grande, in parte 
a causa del suo ruolo come capo del congresso delle 
organizzazioni industriali (CIO), ma ancor più a causa dei suoi 
legami al presidente Franklin Roosevelt ed altri nuovi commercianti. 
In 1944 candidati presidenziali Repubblicani Thomas E. Dewey si è
caricato che il comitato di azione politica dell'Hillman e di CIO 
(PAC) ha dominato Roosevelt. La parte della prova per questa 
carica (non fondata) era la voce -- data una certa credibilità dalla 
relativa pubblicazione nei tempi de New York -- quel Roosevelt lo 
aveva detto a capi del partito "liberi con Sidney" prima della 
selezione del candidato vice-presidenziale in 1944. 
Particolarmente rabbiosi sull'oggetto erano i giornali posseduti
dal anti-Nuovo commerciante William Randolph Hearst. 
Giornale-Americano de New York del Hearst persino patrocinato 
"un concorso di Sidney Limerick." Queste entrate di vincita 
hanno dato un sapore dell'antagonismo e dei pregiudizi taglienti che 
il capo di lavoro influente della nazione ha destato il più 
politicamente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ηγέτης Sidney Hillman εργασίας προέκυψε ως 
ισχυρός εθνικός αριθμός κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης 
οικονομικής κρίσης, εν μέρει λόγω του ρόλου του ως ηγέτης του 
συνεδρίου των βιομηχανικών οργανώσεων (CIO), αλλά ακόμη και 
περισσότερο λόγω των δεσμών του στον Πρόεδρο Franklin 
Roosevelt και άλλους νέους εμπόρους. Το 1944 ο 
δημοκρατικός προεδρικός υποψήφιος Thomas E. Dewey χρέωσε 
ότι η Επιτροπή πολιτικής ενέργειας CIO και hillman (PAC) 
εξουσίασε Roosevelt. Μέρος των στοιχείων για αυτήν την 
(αβάσιμη) δαπάνη ήταν η φήμη -- λαμβάνοντας υπόψη κάποια 
αξιοπιστία από τη δημοσίευσή του στους New York Times -- 
ότι Roosevelt είχε πει στους αρχηγούς κομμάτων για "να τα 
καθαρίσει με το Sidney" πρίν επιλέγει έναν κακία-προεδρικό 
υποψήφιο σε 1944, Ιδιαίτερα rabid στο θέμα ήταν οι 
εφημερίδες που ήταν κύριες από τον αντι-νέο έμπορο William 
Randolph Hearst. Η Νέα Υόρκη περιοδικό-Αμερικανός του 
Hearst υποστήριξε ακόμη και το "Sidney Limerick 
Contest." Αυτές οι κερδίζοντας καταχωρήσεις έδωσαν μια 
γεύση του αιχμηρών ανταγωνισμού και των προκαταλήψεων που ο 
ηγέτης εργασίας του έθνους ο πιό πολιτικά επιδρών ξύπνησε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El arranque de cinta de trabajo Sidney Hillman 
emergió como figura nacional de gran alcance durante la gran 
depresión, en parte debido a su papel como arranque de cinta del 
congreso de las organizaciones industriales (CIO), pero aún más 
debido a sus lazos a presidente Franklin Roosevelt y otros nuevos 
distribuidores. En 1944 el candidato presidencial republicano 
Thomas E. Dewey cargó que el comité de acción política de CIO y de
Hillman (PAC) dominara Roosevelt. La parte de la evidencia para 
esta carga (infundada) era la rumor -- dada una cierta credibilidad 
por su publicación en los tiempos de Nueva York -- ese Roosevelt lo 
había dicho a arranques de cinta del partido "claros con Sidney" 
antes de seleccionar a un candidato vice-presidencial en 1944. 
Determinado rabiosos en el tema eran los periódicos poseídos 
por el distribuidor contra-Nuevo Guillermo Randolph Hearst. 
Diario-Americano de Nueva York de Hearst incluso patrocinado una
"competencia de Sidney Limerick." Estas entradas que ganaban 
dieron un sabor del antagonismo y de los prejudicar sostenidos que el 
arranque de cinta de trabajo influyente de la nación despertó lo 
más político posible.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087489</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104173</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/clear-everything-with-sidney-hillmans-conservative-critics-say-it-with-limericks</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
