<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108346</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108346</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206487</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Nat Turner: A Troublesome Property</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationaler Turner: Eine Unangenehme 
Eigenschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Turner national : Une Propriété 
Ennuyeuse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Turner Nat: Uma Propriedade Incômoda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Turner Nazionale: Una Proprietà Noiosa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικός τορναδόρος: Μια ενοχλητική ιδιοκτησία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Turner Nacional: Una Característica 
Molesta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the companion website of a film that examines the story of Turner and his revolt and how that story has been re-told repeatedly since 1831. Turner, a slave and preacher in Virginia, led a slave rebellion that resulted in the murder of more than 50 slave owners and their family members. Learn about the impact of the rebellion and about the film and individuals who made it.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Begleiterweb site eines Filmes, der die 
Geschichte von Turner und von seinem Aufruhr überprüft und wie diese
Geschichte wiederholt seit 1831 wiedergeholt worden ist. Turner,
ein Sklave und Prediger in Virginia, führten einen Sklavenaufstand, 
der den Mord an mehr als 50 Sklaveninhabern und an ihren Familie 
Bauteilen ergab. Erlernen Sie über die Auswirkung des Aufstands
und über den Film und die Einzelpersonen, die ihn bildeten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est le site Web de compagnon d'un film qui examine
l'histoire de Turner et de sa révolte et de la façon dont cette 
histoire re-told à plusieurs reprises depuis 1831. Turner, 
un slave et le prédicateur en Virginie, ont mené une rébellion
slave qui a eu comme conséquence le meurtre de plus de 50 
propriétaires slaves et de leurs membres de famille. 
Renseignez-vous au sujet de l'impact de la rébellion et sur le 
film et les individus qui l'ont faite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é o Web site do companheiro de uma película que 
examine a história de Turner e de sua revolta e de como essa 
história re-told repetidamente desde 1831. Turner, um escravo e
o preacher em Virgínia, conduziram a uma rebelião slave que 
resultasse no assassinato de mais de 50 proprietários slave e de seus
membros da família. Aprenda sobre o impacto da rebelião e 
sobre a película e os indivíduos que a fizeram.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è il Web site del compagno di una pellicola che 
esamina la storia di Turner e della sua sommossa e di come quella 
storia re-told ripetutamente dal 1831. Turner, uno schiavo ed il
preacher nella Virginia, hanno condotto una ribellione slave che ha 
provocato l'omicidio di più di 50 proprietari slave e dei loro membri
della famiglia. Impari circa l'effetto della ribellione e 
circa la pellicola e gli individui che la hanno fatta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ο ιστοχώρος συντρόφων μιας ταινίας που εξετάζει
την ιστορία του τορναδόρου και της επανάστασής του και πώς 
εκείνη η ιστορία έχει επαναλήφθουν επανειλημμένα από τον 
τορναδόρο 1831, έναν σκλάβο και έναν ιεροκήρυκα στη 
Βιρτζίνια, οδήγησε μια εξέγερση σκλάβων που οδήγησε στη 
δολοφονία περισσότερων από 50 ιδιοκτητών σκλάβων και των 
οικογενειακών μελών τους. Μάθετε για τον αντίκτυπο της 
εξέγερσης και για την ταινία και τα άτομα που το έκαναν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es el Web site del compañero de una película que
examine la historia de Turner y de su rebelión y de cómo esa 
historia re-told en varias ocasiones desde 1831. Turner, un 
esclavo y el predicador en Virginia, condujeron una rebelión auxiliar
que dio lugar al asesinato de más de 50 propietarios auxiliares y de 
sus miembros de la familia. Aprenda sobre el impacto de la 
rebelión y sobre la película y los individuos que la hicieron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206487</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108346</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nat-turner-a-troublesome-property</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
