<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108330</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108330</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206520</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">LifeWorks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">LifeWorks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">LifeWorks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">LifeWorks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">LifeWorks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">LifeWorks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">LifeWorks</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores careers in health and medical sciences. See interviews with more than 70 professionals -- a chemist, dentist, dietician, epidemiologist, lab technologist, medical illustrator, microbiologist, nurse, pharmacist, social worker, veterinarian, and others. Learn what their typical workday involves and why they chose their career. Find out which careers match your interests and skills.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht Karrieren in der Gesundheit und in den 
medizinischen Wissenschaften. Sehen Sie Interviews mit mehr als 
70 Fachleuten -- ein Chemiker, ein Zahnarzt, ein Diätetiker, ein 
Kenner der epidemischen Krankheiten, ein Labortechnologe, ein 
medizinischer Illustrator, ein Biologe, eine Krankenschwester, ein 
Apotheker, ein Sozialarbeiter, ein Tierarzt und andere. Erlernen
Sie, was ihr typischer Arbeitstag miteinbezieht und warum sie ihre 
Karriere wählten. Finden Sie heraus, dem Karrieren Ihre 
Interessen und Fähigkeiten zusammenbringen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore des carrières dans la santé et les 
sciences médicales. Voir les entrevues avec plus de 70 
professionnels -- un chimiste, un dentiste, un diététicien, un 
épidémiologue, un technologue de laboratoire, un illustrateur 
médical, un microbiologiste, une infirmière, un pharmacien, un 
ouvrier social, un vétérinaire, et autres. Apprenez ce que 
leur jour ouvrable typique implique et pourquoi elles ont choisi leur 
carrière. Découvrez que les carrières apparient vos 
intérêts et qualifications.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora carreiras na saúde e em ciências 
médicas. Veja entrevistas com os mais de 70 profissionais -- um
químico, um dentista, um dietista, um epidemiólogo, um technologist 
do laboratório, um illustrator médico, um microbiologist, uma 
enfermeira, um pharmacist, um trabalhador social, um veterinarian, e 
um outro. Aprenda o que seu workday típico envolve e porque 
escolheu sua carreira. Encontre para fora que as carreiras 
combinam seus interesses e habilidades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora le carriere nelle scienze igienico 
sanitarie. Veda le interviste con più di 70 professionisti -- 
un chimico, un dentista, un dietista, un epidemiologo, un tecnologo 
del laboratorio, un illustrator medico, un microbiologo, 
un'infermiera, un farmacista, un operaio sociale, un veterinario e gli
altri. Impari che cosa il loro workday tipico coinvolge e 
perchè hanno scelto la loro carriera. Scopra che le carriere 
abbinano i vostri interessi ed abilità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά τις σταδιοδρομίες στην υγεία και τις ιατρικές 
επιστήμες. Δείτε τις συνεντεύξεις με περισσότερους
από 70 επαγγελματίες -- ένας φαρμακοποιός, ένας οδοντίατρος, 
ένας διαιτολόγος, ένας επιδημιολόγος, ένας τεχνικός 
εργαστηρίων, ένας ιατρικός εικονογράφος, ένας μικροβιολόγος, μια
νοσοκόμα, ένας φαρμακοποιός, ένας κοινωνικός λειτουργός, ένας 
κτηνίατρος, και άλλοι. Μάθετε τι η χαρακτηριστική εργάσιμη 
ημέρα τους περιλαμβάνει και γιατί επέλεξαν τη σταδιοδρομία τους. 
Ανακαλύψτε ποιες σταδιοδρομίες ταιριάζουν με τα ενδιαφέροντα
και τις δεξιότητές σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora carreras en salud y ciencias médicas. 
Vea las entrevistas con más de 70 profesionales -- un químico,
un dentista, un dietético, un epidemiólogo, un tecnólogo del 
laboratorio, un ilustrador médico, un microbiólogo, una enfermera, 
un farmacéutico, un trabajador social, un veterinario, y otros. 
Aprenda lo que implica su día laborable típico y porqué 
eligieron su carrera. Descubra que las carreras corresponden con
sus intereses y habilidades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206520</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108330</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lifeworks</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
