<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107614</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107614</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207195</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fort Pickens and the Outbreak of the Civil War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fort Pickens und der Ausbruch des Bürgerkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fort Pickens et la manifestation de la guerre 
civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fort Pickens e o outbreak da guerra civil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pickens forte e lo scoppio della guerra 
civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οχυρό Pickens και το ξέσπασμα του εμφύλιου πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fortaleza Pickens y el brote de la guerra civil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts what happened in the Pensacola Bay just before the Civil War. U.S. Army Lieutenant Adam Slemmer knew his 51 troops could not defend all four of their forts if Southern troops attacked, so on the day Florida seceded from the Union, he moved all his troops into one: Fort Pickens. They watched across the channel as as Southern soldiers then moved into the other forts. And when the demand to surrender was delivered, Slemmer refused.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt nach, was in der Pensacola Bucht geschah, 
kurz bevor der Bürgerkrieg VEREINIGTE STAATEN Armee-Leutnant Adam 
Slemmer wußte, daß seine 51 Truppen nicht alle vier ihrer Forts 
verteidigen konnten, wenn die südlichen angegriffenen Truppen, also 
am Tag Florida vom Anschluß seceded, er verschoben alle seine Truppen
in eine: Fort Pickens. Sie überwachten über der Führung
wie, während südliche Soldaten dann in die anderen Forts umzogen. 
Und als die Nachfrage zum zu übergeben geliefert wurde, lehnte 
Slemmer ab.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte ce qui s'est produit dans le compartiment 
de Pensacola juste avant que le lieutenant Adam Slemmer 
d'armée des ETATS-UNIS de guerre civile ait su que ses 51 troupes ne 
pourraient pas défendre chacun des quatre de leurs forts si les 
troupes méridionales attaquées, ainsi le jour la Floride 
faite cécession de l'union, il entraient toutes ses troupes
dans une : Fort Pickens. Ils ont observé à travers le 
canal comme pendant que les soldats méridionaux puis entraient dans 
les autres forts. Et quand la demande à rendre a été fournie,
Slemmer a refusé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts o que aconteceu na baía de Pensacola 
imediatamente antes que o tenente Adam Slemmer do exército de ESTADOS
UNIDOS da guerra civil soube que suas 51 tropas não poderiam defender
todos os quatro de seus forts se as tropas do sul atacadas, assim que 
no dia Florida seceded da união, ele moveram todas suas tropas em 
uma: Fort Pickens. Prestaram atenção através da 
canaleta como enquanto os soldados do sul a seguir se moveram nos 
outros forts. E quando a demanda a se render foi entregada, 
Slemmer recusou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta che cosa è accaduto nella baia di 
Pensacola appena prima che il tenente Adam Slemmer dell'esercito degli
STATI UNITI di guerra civile ha saputo che la sue 51 truppa non 
potrebbe difendere tutti e quattro le dei loro forts se le truppe del 
sud attacate, in modo da il giorno Florida seceded dall'unione, lui ha
entrato tutte le sue truppe in una: Pickens forte. 
Hanno guardato attraverso la scanalatura come mentre i soldati 
del sud quindi hanno entrato negli altri forts. E quando la 
richiesta da cedere è stata trasportata, Slemmer ha rifiutato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δεύτερες καταμετρήσεις τι συνέβη στον κόλπο 
Pensacola αμέσως πριν από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο. Ο 
υπολοχαγός Adam Slemmer ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ στρατού ήξερε 51 
στρατεύματά ότι του δεν θα μπορούσαν να υπερασπίσουν και τα 
τέσσερα από τα οχυρά τους εάν τα νότια στρατεύματα επιτέθηκαν, 
έτσι την ημέρα η Φλώριδα από την Ένωση, κίνησε όλα τα 
στρατεύματά του σε ένα: Οχυρό Pickens. Πρόσεξαν 
πέρα από το κανάλι όπως ως νότιοι στρατιώτες κατόπιν κινημένος
στα άλλα οχυρά. Και όταν η απαίτηση για να παραδοθεί 
παραδόθηκε, Slemmer αρνήθηκε.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo qué sucedió en la bahía de 
Pensacola momentos antes que el teniente Adán Slemmer del ejército 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS de la guerra civil sabía que sus 51 tropas no 
podrían defender los cuatro de sus fortalezas si las tropas 
meridionales atacadas, así que en el día la Florida seceded de la 
unión, él movieron a todas sus tropas en una: Fortaleza 
Pickens. Miraron a través del canal como mientras que los 
soldados meridionales después se movieron en las otras fortalezas. 
Y cuando la demanda a entregarse fue entregada, Slemmer 
rechazó.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207195</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107614</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fort-pickens-and-the-outbreak-of-the-civil-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
