<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108112</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108112</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Photojournalism: A Record of War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Photojournalism: Ein Satz des Krieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Photojournalism : Un enregistrement de 
guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Photojournalism: Um registro da guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Photojournalism: Un record della guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Photojournalism: Ένα αρχείο του πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Photojournalism: Un expediente de la guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores how and why war has been photographed and affords students an opportunity to see bias within war reporting. In addition to analyzing war photographs, students learn about Mathematics and Statisticsew Brady's process for photographing the Civil War and how photographic equipment has improved over time.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht wie und warum Krieg fotografiert worden 
ist und leistet sich Kursteilnehmer eine Gelegenheit, innerhalb des 
Kriegberichtes schräg zu sehen. Zusätzlich zum Analysieren der
Kriegfotographien, erlernen Kursteilnehmer über Mathematik- und 
Statisticsewbradys Prozeß für das Fotografieren des Bürgerkrieges 
und wie fotographische Ausrüstung Überzeit verbessert hat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore comment et pourquoi la guerre a été 
photographiée et a les moyens des étudiants une occasion de voir de 
biais dans l'enregistrement de guerre. En plus d'analyser des 
photographies de guerre, les étudiants se renseignent sur le 
procédé de mathématiques et de Statisticsew Brady pour 
photographier la guerre civile et comment le matériel photographique 
a amélioré le temps fini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora como e porque a guerra foi fotografada e 
tem recursos para estudantes uma oportunidade de ver diagonalmente 
dentro do relatório da guerra. Além a analisar fotografias da 
guerra, os estudantes aprendem sobre o processo da matemática e do 
Statisticsew Brady para fotografar a guerra civil e como o equipamento
fotográfico melhorou o tempo excedente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora come e perchè la guerra è stata 
fotografata e si permette gli allievi un'occasione vedere di sbieco 
all'interno della segnalazione di guerra. Oltre che analizzare 
le fotografie di guerra, gli allievi imparano circa il procedimento di
Statisticsew e di matematica Brady per fotografare la guerra civile e 
come l'apparecchiatura fotografica ha migliorato col tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξερευνά πώς και γιατί ο πόλεμος έχει φωτογραφιστεί 
και παρέχει στους σπουδαστές μια ευκαιρία να δει 
διαγωνίως μέσα στην πολεμική υποβολή έκθεσης. Εκτός από 
την ανάλυση των πολεμικών φωτογραφιών, οι σπουδαστές μαθαίνουν 
για τα μαθηματικά και τη διαδικασία Statisticsew Brady για τον
εμφύλιο πόλεμο και πώς ο φωτογραφικός εξοπλισμός έχει βελτιωθεί
κατά τη διάρκεια του χρόνου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora cómo y porqué se ha fotografiado la 
guerra y produce a estudiantes una oportunidad de ver al sesgo dentro 
de señalar de la guerra. Además de analizar las fotografías 
de la guerra, los estudiantes aprenden sobre el proceso de las 
matemáticas y de Statisticsew Brady para fotografiar la guerra civil 
y cómo el equipo fotográfico ha mejorado en un cierto plazo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206937</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108112</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/photojournalism-a-record-of-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
