<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107584</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107584</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205805</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Winslow Homer in the National Gallery of Art</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Winslow Homer in der nationalen Galerie der kunst</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Winslow Homer dans la galerie nationale de l'art</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Winslow Homer na galeria nacional da arte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Winslow Homer nella galleria nazionale di arte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Winslow Όμηρος στην εθνική στοά της τέχνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Winslow Homer en la galería nacional del arte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features one of America's treasured 19th century artists. Follow the career and works of this self-taught painter from Civil War battlefields and farmlands to the North Sea fishing village of Cullercoats, the rocky coast of Maine, the Adirondacks, and the Caribbean. See 35 high-resolution images of his paintings. (Zoom in for a closeup of brush strokes and details.)  See video clips about his life (1836-1910).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale eins Amerikas der gehüteten 19. 
Jahrhundertkünstler. Folgen Sie der Karriere und den Arbeiten 
dieses self-taught Malers von den Bürgerkrieg-Schlachtfeldern und 
-ackerland zum Nordseefischendorf von Cullercoats, zur felsigen Küste
von Maine, zum Adirondacks und zu den Karibischen Meeren. Sehen 
Sie 35 hochauflösende Bilder seiner Anstriche. (Zoom innen für
eine Nahaufnahme der Bürste Schlagmänner und der Sonderkommandos.) 
Sehen Sie videoclips über seine Lebensdauer (1836-1910).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dispositifs un artistes prisés du siècle de 
l'Amérique des 19èmes. Suivez la carrière et les travaux de 
ce peintre de art de l'auto-portrait-taught des champs de bataille et des champs de
guerre civile au village du nord de pêche maritime de 
Cullercoats, à la côte rocheuse du Maine, à l'Adirondacks, et aux 
Caraïbes. Voir les 35 images à haute résolution de ses 
peintures. (zoom dedans pour un plan rapproché des rappes et 
des petits groupes de brosse.) Voir les clips visuels au sujet 
de sa vie (1836-1910).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">características uma artistas estimados do século
de América de 1øs. Siga a carreira e os trabalhos deste pintor
self-taught dos campos de batalha e das terras da guerra civil à vila
da pesca de mar norte de Cullercoats, à costa rochosa de Maine, ao 
Adirondacks, e às Caraíbas. Veja 35 imagens high-resolution de
suas pinturas. (zoom dentro para um closeup de cursos e de 
detalhes da escova.) Veja os grampos video sobre sua vida 
(1836-1910).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratteristiche una artisti apprezzati di secolo 
dell'America dei diciannovesimi. Segua la carriera e gli 
impianti di questo pittore self-taught dai campi di battaglia e dai 
terreni coltivabili di guerra civile al villaggio di pesca del Mare 
del Nord di Cullercoats, al litorale roccioso della Maine, al 
Adirondacks ed ai Caraibi. Veda 35 immagini ad alta definizione 
delle sue pitture. (zoom dentro per un primo piano dei colpi e 
dei particolari della spazzola.) Veda le video clip circa la sua
vita (1836-1910).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει μιας από της Αμερικής οι καλλιτέχνες του 
19$ου αιώνα. Παρακολουθήστε τη σταδιοδρομία και τις εργασίες
αυτού του αυτοδίδακτου ζωγράφου από τα πεδία μάχες και τα 
καλλιεργήσιμα εδάφη εμφύλιου πολέμου στο χωριό αλιείας Βόρειας 
Θάλασσας Cullercoats, η δύσκολη ακτή του Maine, του 
Adirondacks, και των Καραϊβικών Θαλασσών. Δείτε
35 υψηλής ευκρίνειας εικόνες των έργων ζωγραφικής του. 
(Ζουμ μέσα για μια κινηματογράφηση σε πρώτο πλάνο των 
κτυπημάτων και των λεπτομερειών βουρτσών.) Δείτε 
τους τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες για τη ζωή του (1836-1910).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">características una artistas atesorados del siglo
de América de los diecinueveavo. Siga la carrera y los trabajos
de este pintor autodidacta de campos de batalla y de tierras de 
labrantío de la guerra civil a la aldea de la pesca de Mar del Norte 
de Cullercoats, a la costa rocosa de Maine, al Adirondacks, y al 
Caribe. Vea 35 imágenes de alta resolución de sus pinturas. 
(zoom adentro para un primer de los movimientos y de los 
detalles del cepillo.) Vea los clips video sobre su vida 
(1836-1910).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205805</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107584</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/winslow-homer-in-the-national-gallery-of-art</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
