<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103207</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103207</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211492</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Paleoceanography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Paleoceanography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Paleoceanography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Paleoceanography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Paleoceanography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Paleoceanography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paleoceanography</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This National Climate Data Center collection features links to climate data derived from ocean records. These include CLIMAP (sea surface temperature reconstructions), SPECMAP (a reconstruction based on planktonic counts and isotopic values and age and sea surface temperature models), Relative sea level, Calcium carbonate, and Foraminifera (shelled marine microorganisms) data proxies.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese 
Staatsangehörig-Klima-Rechenzentrumansammlung kennzeichnet Links zu 
den Klimadaten, die von den Ozeansätzen berechnet werden. Diese
Vollmächte schließen CLIMAP 
(Seeoberflächentemperaturrekonstruktionen), SPECMAP (eine 
Rekonstruktion basiert auf planktonic Zählimpulsen und isotopischen 
Werten und Alter und Seeoberflächentemperaturmodellen), der relativen
Meeresspiegel, Kalziumkarbonat und Foraminifera (geschälte 
Marinemikroorganismen) Daten ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette collection du centre de calculs de climat de
national comporte des liens aux données de climat dérivées des 
enregistrements d'océan. Ceux-ci des procurations incluent 
CLIMAP (reconstructions de température de surface de mer), SPECMAP 
(une reconstruction basée sur des comptes planktonic et des valeurs 
et des modèles isotopiques d'âge et de température de surface de 
mer), niveau de la mer, carbonate de calcium, et données relatifs de 
Foraminifera (micro-organismes marins écossés).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta coleção do centro de dados do clima do 
nacional caracteriza as ligações aos dados do clima derivados dos 
registros do oceano. Estes incluem CLIMAP (reconstructions da 
temperatura de superfície do mar), SPECMAP (um reconstruction baseado
em contagens planktonic e em valores e em modelos isotopic da idade e 
da temperatura de superfície do mar), proxies o nível de mar, o 
carbonato de cálcio, e dos dados relativos de Foraminifera 
(microorganisms marinhos descascados).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa accumulazione del centro di dati di clima 
del cittadino caratterizza i collegamenti ai dati di clima derivati 
dai record dell'oceano. Questi includono CLIMAP (ricostruzioni 
di temperatura in superficie del mare), SPECMAP (una ricostruzione 
basata sui conteggi planktonic e sui valori e sui modelli isotopici di
temperatura in superficie del mare e di età), procure il livello del 
mare, il carbonato di calcio e di dati relativi di Foraminifera 
(microorganismi marini sgranati).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η εθνική κεντρική συλλογή στοιχείων κλίματος 
χαρακτηρίζει τις συνδέσεις με τα στοιχεία κλίματος που προκύπτουν
από τα ωκεάνια αρχεία. Αυτοί περιλαμβάνουν CLIMAP 
(αναδημιουργίες θερμοκρασίας επιφάνειας θάλασσας), SPECMAP (μια
αναδημιουργία βασισμένη στις planktonic αριθμήσεις και τις 
ισοτοπικά τιμές και τα μοντέλα ηλικίας και θερμοκρασίας 
επιφάνειας θάλασσας), τη σχετική στάθμη θάλασσας, το ανθρακικό 
άλας ασβεστίου, και (ξεφλουδισμένοι θαλάσσιοι μικροοργανισμοί) τα
πληρεξούσια στοιχείων Foraminifera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta colección del centro de datos del clima del 
nacional ofrece conexiones a los datos del clima derivados de 
expedientes del océano. Éstos incluyen CLIMAP 
(reconstrucciones de la temperatura superficial del mar), SPECMAP (una
reconstrucción basada en cuentas planktonic y valores y modelos 
isotópicos de la edad y de la temperatura superficial del mar), los 
poderes nivel del mar, el carbonato de calcio, y de los datos 
relativos de Foraminifera (microorganismos marinas descascados).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION- WORLD WIDE DATA CENTER FOR PALEOCLIMATOLOGY
FN:NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC ADMINISTRATION- WORLD WIDE DATA CENTER FOR PALEOCLIMATOLOGY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211492</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103207</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/paleoceanography</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
