<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108547</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108547</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211176</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Missing Angle Puzzles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fehlende Winkel-Puzzlespiele</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Puzzles Manquants d'Angle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enigmas Faltantes Do Ângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Puzzle Mancanti Di Angolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ελλείποντες γρίφοι γωνίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rompecabezas Que falta Del Ángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson lays some of the ground work for eventually writing two column proofs. In the lesson students use known geometric facts to solve for missing angles. Students are asked to identify the key concepts required for the solution and to record the a path for finding the measure of a particular angle. Key concepts include the sum of the measures of the interior angles of a triangle and quadrilateral, parallel line relationships, and what can and cannot be assumed from a drawing.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion legt etwas von der Grundarbeit für 
zwei Spaltebeweise schließlich schreiben. In der Lektion 
verwenden die Kursteilnehmer bekannte geometrische Tatsachen, um für 
fehlende Winkel zu lösen. Kursteilnehmer werden, die 
Schlüsselkonzepte zu kennzeichnen gebeten, die für die Lösung und 
den Pfad für das Finden des Masses eines bestimmten Winkels zu 
speichern benötigt werden. Schlüsselkonzepte schließen die 
Summe der Masse der Innenwinkel eines Dreiecks und des Vierecks, 
paralleles instanzielle Rang- und Weisungsbeziehungen ein, und was 
Dose und nicht von einer Zeichnung angenommen werden kann.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon étend une partie du travail au sol 
pour écrire par la suite deux preuves de colonne. Dans la 
leçon les étudiants emploient des faits géométriques connus pour 
résoudre pour des angles manquants. Des étudiants sont 
invités à identifier les concepts principaux priés pour la solution
et à enregistrer une voie d'accès pour trouver la mesure d'un angle 
particulier. Les concepts principaux incluent la somme des 
mesures des angles intérieurs d'une triangle et d'un quadrilatère, 
ligne rapports parallèle, et ce que le bidon et ne peut pas être 
assumé d'un schéma.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição coloca algum do trabalho à terra 
para eventualmente escrever duas provas da coluna. Na lição os
estudantes usam fatos geométricos sabidos resolver para ângulos 
faltantes. Os estudantes são pedidos para identificar os 
conceitos chaves requeridos para a solução e para gravar um trajeto 
para encontrar a medida de um ângulo particular. Os conceitos 
chaves incluem a soma das medidas dos ângulos interior de um 
triângulo e de um quadrilateral, linha relacionamentos paralela, e o 
que a lata e não pode ser suposta de um desenho.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione pone alcuno del lavoro al suolo per
finalmente la scrittura delle due prove della colonna. Nella 
lezione gli allievi usano i fatti geometrici conosciuti per risolvere 
per gli angoli mancanti. Gli allievi sono chiesti di 
identificare i concetti chiave richiesti per la soluzione e di 
registrare un percorso per l'individuazione della misura di un angolo 
particolare. I concetti chiave includono la somma delle misure 
degli angoli interni di un triangolo e di un quadrilateral, la riga 
rapporti parallela e che cosa la latta e non può essere presupposta 
da un'illustrazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα βάζει μερικών από την επίγεια 
εργασία για τελικά να γράψει δύο αποδείξεις στηλών. Στο 
μάθημα οι σπουδαστές χρησιμοποιούν τα γνωστά γεωμετρικά γεγονότα
για να λύσουν για την απώλεια των γωνιών. Οι σπουδαστές 
καλούνται να προσδιορίσουν τις βασικές έννοιες που απαιτούνται 
για τη λύση και να καταγράψουν ένα μονοπάτι για την εύρεση του 
μέτρου μιας ιδιαίτερης γωνίας. Οι βασικές έννοιες 
περιλαμβάνουν το ποσό των μέτρων των εσωτερικών γωνιών ενός 
τριγώνου και τετράπλευρων, παράλληλων σχέσεων γραμμών, και τι 
μπορεί και δεν μπορεί να υποτεθεί από ένα σχέδιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección pone algo del trabajo de tierra para
eventual escribir dos pruebas de la columna. En la lección los 
estudiantes utilizan hechos geométricos sabidos para solucionar para 
los ángulos que falta. Piden los estudiantes identificar los 
conceptos dominantes requeridos para la solución y registrar un 
camino para encontrar la medida de un ángulo determinado. Los 
conceptos dominantes incluyen la suma de las medidas de los ángulos 
interiores de un triángulo y de un cuadrilátero, línea lazos 
paralela, y qué la lata y no se puede asumir de un gráfico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JEFF HOLCOMB
FN:JEFF HOLCOMB
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211176</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108547</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/missing-angle-puzzles</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
