<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107917</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107917</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086911</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Business of a Factory": A Journalist's Portrait</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das Geschäft einer Fabrik": Portrait Eines
Journalisten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les affaires d'une usine" : La Verticale 
D'un Journaliste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o negócio de uma fábrica": Retrato De um 
Journalist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"commercio di una fabbrica": Ritratto Del
Giornalista</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η επιχείρηση ενός εργοστασίου": Το πορτρέτο 
ενός δημοσιογράφου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el negocio de una fábrica": Retrato De un 
Periodista</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1897,  Scribner's  published a series of articles on "The Conduct of Great Business." This article by Philip Hubert on a New England textile mill conveyed some of the sense of wonder that Americans felt at the enormous new factories suddenly emerging in what had been primarily an agricultural nation. Although other contemporaries--both agrarian radicals and trade unionists--viewed the new industrial behemoths with skepticism or even horror, middle-class observers like Hubert celebrated the achievements of the capitalists who organized and managed these vast and complex enterprises. Hubert had little interest in or sympathy for the thousands of workers who toiled in the textile mill that he visited, echoing the view that the "character of the machinery" was more important than "the character of the hands." But his account, including a vivid description of the mill at quitting time, captured the sheer size and dehumanizing impact on workers of the new industrial enterprises.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1897 Scribners veröffentlicht einer Reihe 
Artikeln auf "der Führung des großen Geschäfts." Dieser 
Artikel durch Philip Hubert auf einem Neu-England Textiltausendstel 
übermittelte etwas von der Richtung des Wunders, daß Amerikaner an 
den enormen neuen Fabriken fühlten, die plötzlich auftauchen in, was
hauptsächlich ein Agrarstaat gewesen war. Obgleich andere 
Zeitgenossen -- landwirtschaftliche Radikale und Gewerkschaftler -- 
die neuen industriellen behemoths mit Skepsis oder sogar Grausigkeit 
ansahen, feierten Mittelklassebeobachter wie Hubert die Ausführungen 
der Kapitalisten, die diese beträchtlichen und komplizierten 
Unternehmen organisierten und handhatten. Hubert hatte wenig 
Interesse an oder Sympathie für die Tausenden der Arbeiter, die im 
Textiltausendstel abplagten, das er besuchte und die Ansicht 
Echo ausgaben, daß das "Zeichen der Maschinerie" war wichtiger als 
"das Zeichen der Hände." Aber seins Konto, einschließlich eine
klare Beschreibung des Tausendstels am Beenden von von Zeit, erfaßte 
die blosse Größe und die entmenschlichende Auswirkung auf Arbeiter 
der neuen Industrieunternehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1897, Scribner édité une série d'articles 
sur "la conduite de grandes affaires." Cet article par 
Philip Hubert sur un moulin de textile de la Nouvelle Angleterre a
donné une partie du sens de la merveille que les Américains se sont 
sentis aux énormes nouvelles usines émergeant soudainement dans ce 
qui avait été principalement une nation agricole. Bien que 
d'autres contemporains -- les radicaux agraires et les syndicalistes 
-- aient visualisé les nouveaux behemoths industriels avec le 
scepticisme ou même l'horreur, les observateurs de classe moyenne 
comme Hubert ont célébré les accomplissements des capitalistes qui 
ont organisé et ont contrôlé ces vastes et complexes entreprises. 
Hubert a eu peu d'intérêt dans ou sympathie pour les milliers 
d'ouvriers qui travaillent fort dans le moulin de textile qu'il a 
visité, faisant écho la vue que le "caractère des machines" était 
plus important que "le caractère des mains." Mais sien compte, 
y compris une description vive du moulin à quitter le temps, a 
capturé la taille fine et l'impact de déshumanisation sur des 
ouvriers des nouvelles entreprises industrielles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1897, Scribner publicado uma série dos artigos
"na conduta do negócio grande." Este artigo por Philip Hubert 
em um moinho de textile de Nova Inglaterra fêz saber a algum do 
sentido da maravilha que os americanos sentiram nas fábricas novas 
enormes que emergem de repente em o que tinha sido primeiramente uma 
nação agricultural. Embora outros comtemporâneos --  radicais
agrarian e os unionists de comércio -- vissem os behemoths 
industriais novos com skepticism ou mesmo horror, os observadores do 
middle-class como Hubert comemoraram as realizações dos capitalistas
que organizaram e controlaram estas empresas vastas e complexas. 
Hubert teve pouco interesse em ou sympathy para os milhares dos 
trabalhadores que labutam no moinho de textile que visitou, ecoando a 
vista que o "caráter da maquinaria" era mais importante do que "o 
caráter das mãos." Mas his cliente, including uma descrição 
vívida do moinho em parar o tempo, capturou o tamanho sheer e o 
impacto dehumanizing em trabalhadores das empresas industriais novas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1897, Scribner pubblicato una serie di articoli
"sul comportamento del commercio grande." Questo articolo da 
Philip Hubert su un laminatoio della tessile della Nuova Inghilterra 
ha trasportato alcuno del senso di wonder che gli Americani hanno 
ritenuto alle nuove fabbriche enormi che emergono improvvisamente in 
che cosa era stato soprattutto una nazione agricola. Anche se 
altri contemporanei -- sia radicali agrari che sindacalisti -- hanno 
osservato i nuovi behemoths industriali con scetticismo o persino 
l'orrore, gli osservatori della classe media come Hubert hanno 
celebrato i successi dei capitalisti che hanno organizzato e gestito 
queste imprese ampie e complesse. Hubert ha avuto poco interesse
in o compassione per le migliaia di operai che lavorano duramente nel 
laminatoio della tessile che ha visitato, echeggiante la vista che "il
carattere del macchinario" era più importante "del carattere delle 
mani." Ma suo cliente, compreso una descrizione chiara del 
laminatoio a rinunciare il tempo, ha bloccato il formato puro e 
l'effetto di disumanizzazione sugli operai di nuove imprese 
industriali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1897, Scribner δημοσιευμένος μια σειρά άρθρων 
σχετικά με "τη συμπεριφορά της μεγάλης επιχείρησης." Αυτό 
το άρθρο από τον Philip Hubert σε έναν υφαντικό μύλο της 
Νέας Αγγλίας μεταβίβασε μερικών από την αίσθηση της κατάπληξης 
που Αμερικανοί αισθάνθηκαν στα τεράστια νέα εργοστάσια ξαφνικά 
αναδυόμενος σε αυτό που ήταν πρώτιστα γεωργικό έθνος. Αν 
και άλλοι σύγχρονοι -- και αγροτικοί ριζοσπάστες και 
συνδικαλιστές -- εμφάνισαν τα νέα βιομηχανικά behemoths με το 
σκεπτικισμό ή ακόμα και τη φρίκη, οι παρατηρητές μεσαίων τάξεων
όπως το Hubert γιόρτασαν τα επιτεύγματα των κεφαλαιοκρατών που 
οργάνωσαν και διαχειρίστηκαν αυτές τις απέραντες και σύνθετες 
επιχειρήσεις. Ο Hubert είχε λίγη ενδιαφέρον για ή 
συμπόνοια για χιλιάδες εργαζόμενοι που κοπίασαν στον υφαντικό 
μύλο που επισκέφτηκε, αντηχώντας την όψη ότι ο "χαρακτήρας των 
μηχανημάτων" ήταν σημαντικότερος από "το χαρακτήρα των χεριών." 
Αλλά ο απολογισμός του, συμπεριλαμβανομένης μιας ζωηρής 
περιγραφής του μύλου στην εγκατάλειψη του χρόνου, συνέλαβε το 
καθαρό μέγεθος και τον αποκτηνώνοντας αντίκτυπο στους 
εργαζομένους των νέων βιομηχανικών επιχειρήσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1897, Scribner publicado una serie de 
artículos sobre "la conducta del gran negocio." Este artículo 
de Philip Hubert en un molino del textil de Nueva Inglaterra 
transportó algo del sentido de la maravilla que los americanos se 
sentían en las fábricas nuevas enormes que emergían repentinamente 
en cuál había sido sobre todo una nación agrícola. Aunque 
otros contemporáneos -- los radicales agrarios y los unionistas 
comerciales -- vieron los behemoths industriales nuevos con 
escepticismo u horror, los observadores de la clase media como Hubert 
celebraron los logros de los capitalistas que ordenaron y manejaron 
estas empresas extensas y complejas. Hubert tenía poco interés
en o condolencia para los millares de trabajadores que trabajan en el 
molino del textil que él visitó, produciendo eco la visión que el 
"carácter de la maquinaria" era más importante que "el carácter de 
las manos." Pero el suyo cuenta, incluyendo una descripción 
viva del molino en salir tiempo, capturó la talla escarpada y el 
impacto de deshumanización en los trabajadores de las nuevas empresas
industriales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086911</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107917</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-business-of-a-factory-a-journalists-portrait</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
