<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104330</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104330</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">AP Environmental Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AP Klimawissenschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science Environnementale de AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência Ambiental do Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza Ambientale di Ap</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιβαλλοντική επιστήμη AP</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia Ambiental del Ap</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to the NROC Advanced Placement (AP) Environmental Science course. This curriculum covers all of the material outlined by the College Board as necessary to prepare students to pass the AP Environmental Science exam. This course is designed to acquaint you with the physical, ecological, social, and political principles of environmental science. The scientific method is used to analyze and understand the inter-relationships between humans and the natural environment. The course shows how ecological realities and the material desires of humans often clash, leading to environmental degradation and pollution. The course covers the following topics: Earth's Systems, Human Population Dynamics, Natural Resources, Environmental Quality, Global Changes, and Environment and Society.

Upon completion of this course you will:

    * know and understand the levels of the ecological hierarchy
    * appreciate the integration of natural processes that govern the natural world
    * appreciate the importance of maintaining a sustaining biosphere for the continued presence of a human population on the earth
    * understand the pragmatic and realistic difficulties of integrating human societal needs without further compromising ecological processes
    * become familiar with the ecological background to global environmental problems
    * realize the consequences of our individual and joint actions upon the biosphere</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zum NROC hochentwickelten Plazierung 
(AP) Klimawissenschaft Kurs. Dieser Lehrplan umfaßt die ganze 
Material, das durch das Hochschulgremium wie benötigt, Kursteilnehmer
vorzubereiten, das AP Klimawissenschaft Prüfung zu führen umrissen 
wird. Dieser Kurs ist konzipiert, um Sie mit den körperlichen, 
ökologischen, Sozial- und politischen Grundregeln der 
Klimawissenschaft mitzuteilen. Die wissenschaftliche Methode 
wird verwendet, um die Verwandtschaft zwischen Menschen und der 
natürlichen Umgebung zu analysieren und zu verstehen. Der Kurs 
zeigt, wie ökologische Wirklichkeiten und die materiellen Wünsche 
der Menschen häufig zusammenstoßen und führt zu Klimaverminderung 
und Verunreinigung. Der Kurs umfaßt die folgenden Themen: 
Bedeckten Systeme, menschliche Bevölkerung Dynamik, 
Naturresourcen, Klimaqualität, globale Änderungen und Umgebung und 
Society.Upon Beendigung dieses Kurses mit Erde, den Sie werden: 
* wissen Sie und verstehen Sie, daß die Stufen der 
ökologischen Hierarchie * schätzen Sie die Integration der 
natürlichen Prozesse, die die natürliche Welt regeln * den Wert des 
Beibehaltens einer unterstützenden Biosphäre für die anhaltende 
Anwesenheit einer menschlichen Bevölkerung auf der Masse * verstehen 
Sie die pragmatischen und realistischen Schwierigkeiten der 
Integrierung der menschlichen gesellschaftlichen Notwendigkeiten ohne 
weitere vergleichende ökologische Prozesse * geworden vertraut mit 
dem ökologischen Hintergrund zu den globalen Umweltproblemen * 
verwirklichen die Konsequenzen unserer Einzelperson und Verbindung 
Tätigkeiten nach der Biosphäre schätzen</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue au cours environnemental de 
perfectionnement de la Science du placement de NROC (AP). Ce 
programme d'études couvre tout le matériel tracé les grandes lignes
par le conseil d'université selon les besoins pour préparer des 
étudiants passer à AP l'examen environnemental de la Science. 
Ce cours est conçu pour vous mettre au courant des principes 
physiques, écologiques, sociaux, et politiques de la science 
environnementale. La méthode scientifique est employée pour 
analyser et comprendre les corrélations entre les humains et 
l'environnement normal. Le cours montre comment les réalités 
écologiques et les désirs matériels des humains s'opposent souvent,
menant à la dégradation et à la pollution environnementales. 
Le cours couvre les sujets suivants : Ont mis à la terre 
des systèmes, la dynamique humaine de population, des ressources 
naturelles, la qualité environnementale, l'accomplissement global de 
changements, et d'environnement et de Society.Upon de ce cours que 
vous  : * savez et comprenez que les niveaux de la hiérarchie 
écologique * appréciez l'intégration des processus normaux qui 
régissent le monde normal * apprécient l'importance de mettre à 
jour une biosphère soutenante pour la présence continue d'une 
population humaine sur la terre * comprenez les difficultés 
pragmatiques et réalistes d'intégrer les besoins sociaux humains 
sans encore d'autres processus écologiques compromettants * 
familiarisée avec le fond écologique aux problèmes écologiques 
globaux * réalisent les conséquences de nos actions d'individu et de
joint sur la biosphère</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda ao curso ambiental avançado da ciência
da colocação de NROC (AP). Este curriculum cobre todo o 
material esboçado pela placa de faculdade como necessário preparar 
estudantes para passar ao AP o exam ambiental da ciência. Este 
curso é projetado familiarizá-lo com os princípios físicos, 
ecological, sociais, e políticos da ciência ambiental. O 
método científico é usado analisar e compreender os 
inter-relationships entre seres humanos e o ambiente natural. O 
curso mostra como as realidades ecological e os desejos materiais dos 
seres humanos clash frequentemente, conduzindo à degradação e à 
poluição ambientais. O curso cobre os seguintes tópicos: 
Ligaram à terra sistemas, a dinâmica humana da população, 
recursos naturais, a qualidade ambiental, a conclusão global das 
mudanças, e do ambiente e do Society.Upon deste curso que você : 
* saiba e compreenda que os níveis da hierarquia ecological * 
aprecie a integração dos processos naturais que governam o mundo 
natural * apreciam a importância de manter um biosphere sustentando 
para a presença continuada de uma população humana na terra * 
compreenda as dificuldades pragmatic e realísticas de integrar 
necessidades societal humanas sem processos ecological comprometendo 
mais adicionais * tornada familiar com o fundo ecological aos 
problemas ambientais globais * realizam as conseqüências de nossas 
ações do indivíduo e da junção em cima do biosphere</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto al corso ambientale avanzato di scienza 
di disposizione di NROC (AP). Questo programma di studi tratta 
tutto il materiale descritto dal Bordo dell'università come 
necessario preparare gli allievi per passare al AP il exam ambientale 
di scienza. Questo corso è destinato per informarlo dei 
principii fisici, ecologici, sociali e politici della scienza 
ambientale. Il metodo scientifico è usato per analizzare e 
capire le correlazioni fra gli esseri umani e l'ambiente naturale. 
Il corso mostra come le realtà ecologiche ed i desideri 
materiali degli esseri umani clash spesso, conducendo alla 
degradazione ed all'inquinamento ambientali. Il corso riguarda i
seguenti soggetti: Hanno interrato i sistemi, il dynamics umano 
della popolazione, le risorse naturali, la qualità ambientale, il 
completamento globale dei cambiamenti e dell'ambiente e di 
Society.Upon di questo corso che dovrà: * sappia e che capisca 
che i livelli della gerarchia ecologica * apprezzi l'integrazione dei 
processi naturali che governano il mondo naturale * apprezzano 
l'importanza di effettuare una biosfera sostenente per la presenza 
continuata di una popolazione umana sulla terra * capisca le 
difficoltà pragmatiche e realistiche di integrata dei bisogni sociali
umani senza ulteriori processi ecologici di compromesso * diventata 
esperta con i precedenti ecologici ai problemi ambientali globali * 
realizzano le conseguenze delle nostre azioni del giunto e 
dell'individuo sulla biosfera</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στην προηγμένη NROC σειρά μαθημάτων 
επιστήμης τοποθέτησης (AP) περιβαλλοντική. Αυτό το 
πρόγραμμα σπουδών καλύπτει όλο το υλικό που περιγράφεται από 
τον πίνακα κολλεγίου για να προετοιμάσει ανάλογα με τις ανάγκες 
τους σπουδαστές για να περάσει τον περιβαλλοντικό διαγωνισμό 
επιστήμης AP. Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων σχεδιάζεται για να 
σας εξοικειώσει με τις φυσικές, οικολογικές, κοινωνικές, και 
πολιτικές αρχές της περιβαλλοντικής επιστήμης. Η 
επιστημονική μέθοδος χρησιμοποιείται για να αναλύσει και να 
καταλάβει τις αλληλεξαρτήσεις μεταξύ των ανθρώπων και του φυσικού
περιβάλλοντος. Η σειρά μαθημάτων επιδεικνύει πώς οι 
οικολογικές πραγματικότητες και οι υλικές επιθυμίες των ανθρώπων 
διαφωνούν συχνά, οδηγώντας στην περιβαλλοντικές υποβάθμιση και τη
ρύπανση. Η σειρά μαθημάτων καλύπτει τα ακόλουθα θέματα: 
Γήινα συστήματα, ανθρώπινη δυναμική πληθυσμού, φυσικά 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, περιβαλλοντική ποιότητα, παγκόσμιες 
αλλαγές, και περιβάλλον και κοινωνία Με την ολοκλήρωση 
αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων: * να ξέρουν και να καταλάβουν 
τα επίπεδα της οικολογικής ιεραρχίας * εκτιμούν την ολοκλήρωση 
των φυσικών διαδικασιών που κυβερνούν το φυσικό κόσμο * εκτιμούν
ότι η σημασία μια βιόσφαιρα στήριξης για τη συνεχή παρουσία 
ενός ανθρώπινου πληθυσμού στη γη * καταλαβαίνει τις πραγματικές 
και ρεαλιστικές δυσκολίες τις ανθρώπινες κοινωνικές ανάγκες 
χωρίς περαιτέρω οικολογικές διαδικασίες συμβιβασμού * γίνοντας 
γνωστή με το οικολογικό υπόβαθρο στα σφαιρικά περιβαλλοντικά 
προβλήματα * πραγματοποιεί τις συνέπειες των μεμονωμένων και 
κοινών ενεργειών μας επάνω στη βιόσφαιρα</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recepción al curso ambiental avanzado de la 
ciencia de la colocación de NROC (AP). Este plan de estudios 
cubre todo el material contorneado por la tarjeta de universidad como 
necesaria para preparar a estudiantes para aprobar el AP el examen 
ambiental de la ciencia. Este curso se diseña para conocerle de
los principios físicos, ecológicos, sociales, y políticos de la 
ciencia ambiental. El método científico se utiliza para 
analizar y para entender las correlaciones entre los seres humanos y 
el ambiente natural. El curso muestra cómo las realidades 
ecológicas y los deseos materiales de seres humanos clash a menudo, 
conduciendo a la degradación y a la contaminación ambientales. 
El curso cubre los asuntos siguientes: Conectaron a tierra
sistemas, dinámica humana de la población, recursos naturales, 
calidad ambiental, la terminación global de los cambios, y del 
ambiente y de Society.Upon de este curso que usted : * sepa y 
entienda que los niveles de la jerarquía ecológica * aprecie la 
integración de los procesos naturales que gobiernan el mundo natural 
* aprecian la importancia de mantener una biosfera que sostiene para 
la presencia continuada de una población humana en la tierra * 
entienda las dificultades pragmáticas y realistas de integrar 
necesidades societal humanas sin otros procesos ecológicos de 
compromiso * llegada a ser familiar con el fondo ecológico a los 
problemas ambientales globales * realizan las consecuencias de 
nuestras acciones del individuo y del empalme sobre la biosfera</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
FN:MONTEREY INSTITUTE FOR TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATION AND UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104330</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ap-environmental-science</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
