<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104522</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104522</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086103</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Drug Him Through the Street": Hughsey Childes Describes Turn-of-the-Century Sharecropping</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Droge er durch die Straße": Hughsey 
Childes Beschreibt Jahrhundertwendeznszsharecropping</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"drogue il par la rue" : Hughsey Childes 
Décrit Le Métayage de Tourner-de-le-Siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"droga ele através da rua": Hughsey Childes
Descreve Um Sharecropping De Gir-$$$-$$$-Século</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"droga lui tramite la via": Hughsey Childes 
Descrive La Mezzadria Di Gir-de-$$$-Secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τον ναρκώστε μέσω της οδού": Το Hughsey 
Childes περιγράφει sharecropping στροφή-$$$-Ο-ΑΙΏΝΑ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"droga él a través de la calle": Hughsey 
Childes Describe Aparcería Del Dar vuelta-de-$$$-Siglo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The sharecropping system that emerged in the South in the last three decades of the 19th century afforded southern black families a certain measure of control over their daily lives and labor. But the white landowners were able to use the legal mechanisms of sharecropping to assure control over the largely African-American workforce that toiled on the farms. Here Hughsey Childes, interviewed by historian Charles Hardy in 1984, described what seems like a matter of fact exchange in which the white landowner cheated the black sharecropper. But when the sharecropper got a little wise and withheld some of the crop from the landlord, the punishment was swift and final.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Sharecroppingsystem, das im Süden in den 
letzten drei Dekaden des 19. Jahrhunderts auftauchte, leistete sich 
südliche schwarze Familien ein bestimmtes Maß Steuerung über ihren 
täglichen Lebensdauern und Arbeit. Aber die weißen 
Grundbesitzer konnten, die zugelassenen Einheiten von Sharecropping zu
benutzen, um Steuerung über der groß Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen 
Mannschaft zu versichern, die auf den Bauernhöfen abplagte. 
Hier beschrieb Hughsey Childes, interviewt vom Historiker 
Charles, der 1984 robust ist, was wie eine Tatsache Austausch scheint,
in der der weiße Grundbesitzer das schwarze sharecropper betrog. 
Aber, als das sharecropper wenig klug und etwas von dem Getreide
vom Hauswirt zurückgehalten erhielt, war die Bestrafung schnell und 
abschließend.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le système de métayage qui a émergé dans les 
Sud dans les trois dernières décennies du 19ème siècle a 
eu les moyens les familles noires méridionales par certaine mesure de
contrôle des leurs vies et travail quotidiens. Mais les 
propriétaires fonciers blancs pouvaient employer les mécanismes 
légaux du métayage pour assurer le contrôle de la main d'oeuvre en 
grande partie afro-américaine qui travaille fort aux fermes. Ici 
Hughsey Childes, interviewé par l'historien Charles robuste en 1984, 
a décrit ce qui semble comme une question d'échange de fait dans 
laquelle le propriétaire foncier blanc a triché le métayer noir.
Mais quand le métayer a obtenu sage et retenu une partie de 
la collecte au propriétaire, la punition était rapide et finale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O sistema do sharecropping que emergiu no sul nas 
últimas três décadas do 1ø século teve recursos para famílias 
pretas do sul um determinada medida do controle sobre seus vidas e 
trabalho diários. Mas os latifundiários brancos podiam  usar 
os mecanismos legais do sharecropping assegurar o controle sobre o 
workforce pela maior parte Africano-Americano que labuta nas fazendas.
Aqui Hughsey Childes, entrevistado pelo historian Charles hardy 
em 1984, descreveu o que parece como uma matéria da troca do fato em 
que o latifundiário branco fêz batota o sharecropper preto. 
Mas quando o sharecropper começou um pouco sábio e retido 
alguma da colheita do landlord, a punição era rápida e final.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il sistema di mezzadria che è emerso nel sud 
nelle ultime tre decadi del diciannovesimo secolo si è permesso le 
famiglie nere del sud un determinata misura di controllo sopra le loro
vite e lavoro quotidiani. Ma i latifondisti bianchi 
potevano usare i meccanismi legali della mezzadria per assicurare il 
controllo sopra la mano d'opera in gran parte Africano-Americana che 
lavora duramente sui poderi. Qui Hughsey Childes, intervistato 
dallo storico Charles hardy in 1984, ha descritto che cosa sembra come
un aspetto dello scambio di fatto in cui il latifondista bianco ha 
truffato lo sharecropper nero. Ma quando lo sharecropper ha 
ottenuto un piccolo saggio e ritenuto alcuno del raccolto dal 
proprietario, la punizione era rapida e finale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το sharecropping σύστημα που προέκυψε στο νότο στις 
τελευταίες τρεις δεκαετίες του 19$ου αιώνα άντεξε οικονομικά στις
νότιες οικογένειες μαύρων ένα ορισμένο μέτρο του ελέγχου κατά 
τη διάρκεια των καθημερινών ζωών και της εργασίας τους. 
Αλλά τα άσπρα landowners ήταν σε θέση να χρησιμοποιήσουν
τους νομικούς μηχανισμούς sharecropping για να βεβαιώσουν τον 
έλεγχο του κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού 
εργατικού δυναμικού που κοπίασε στα αγροκτήματα. Εδώ 
Hughsey Childes, που πέρασε από συνέντευξη από τον ιστορικό
Charles Hardy το 1984, περιέγραψε τι φαίνεται όπως ένα 
θέμα ανταλλαγής γεγονότος στο οποίο ο λευκός γαιοκτήμονας 
εξαπάτησε το μαύρο επίμορτο καλλιεργητή. Αλλά όταν ο 
επίμορτος καλλιεργητής πήρε λίγο σοφός και παρακρατημένος 
μερικών από τη συγκομιδή από τον ιδιοκτήτη, η τιμωρία ήταν 
γρήγορη και τελική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El sistema de la aparcería que emergió en el sur
en las tres décadas pasadas del diecinueveavo siglo produjo a 
familias negras meridionales a cierta medida de control sobre sus 
vidas y trabajo diarios. Pero los terratenientes blancos podían
utilizar los mecanismos legales de la aparcería para asegurar control
sobre la mano de obra en gran parte Africano-Americana que trabaja en 
las granjas. Aquí Hughsey Childes, entrevistado con por el 
historiador Charles robusto en 1984, describió qué se parece como 
una cuestión de intercambio del hecho en la cual el terrateniente 
blanco engañó el sharecropper negro. Pero cuando el 
sharecropper consiguió un poco sabio y retenida algo de la cosecha 
del propietario, el castigo era rápido y final.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086103</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104522</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/drug-him-through-the-street-hughsey-childes-describes-turn-of-the-century-sharecropping</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
