<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104480</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104480</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206226</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NIST Time and Frequency Information</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NIST Zeit und Frequenz-Informationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Temps de NIST et information de fréquence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tempo do NIST e informação da freqüência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tempo del NIST e le informazioni di frequenza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πληροφορίες χρόνου NIST και συχνότητας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tiempo del NIST e información de la frecuencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides information, tools, and services for timekeeping and frequency measurement. Visitors can download time-setting software for their computer, read about how time is synchronized at radio stations across the country, and monitor the performance of the Global Positioning System (GPS) satellites.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Informationen, Hilfsmittel und Services 
für Timekeeping und Frequenzmessen zur Verfügung. Besucher 
können die Zeit-Einstellung der Software für ihren Computer 
downloaden, gelesen über, wie Zeit an den Radiostationen über dem 
Land synchronisiert wird, und die Leistung der globalen Satelliten der
Navigationsanlage (GPS) überwachen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit l'information, des outils, et des services
pour la mesure timekeeping et de fréquence. Les visiteurs 
peuvent télécharger temps-placer le logiciel pour leur ordinateur, 
eu connaissance de la façon dont le temps est synchronisé aux 
stations par radio à travers le pays, et surveiller l'exécution des 
satellites globaux du système de positionnement (GPS).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece a informação, as ferramentas, e os 
serviços para a medida timekeeping e de freqüência. Os 
visitantes podem download o tempo-ajuste do software para seu 
computador, lido sobre como o tempo é sincronizado nas estações de 
rádio através do país, e monitorar o desempenho dos satélites 
globais do sistema posicionando (GPS).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le informazioni, gli strumenti ed i 
servizi per la misura di frequenza e timekeeping. Gli ospiti 
possono trasferire la tempo-regolazione dal sistema centrale verso i 
satelliti del software per il loro calcolatore, letto su come il tempo
è sincronizzato alle stazioni radiofoniche attraverso il paese e 
controllare le prestazioni dei satelliti globali del sistema 
posizionante (GPS).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις πληροφορίες, τα εργαλεία, και τις 
υπηρεσίες για και τη μέτρηση συχνότητας. Οι επισκέπτες 
μπορούν να μεταφορτώσουν το λογισμικό χρόνος-τιμής τών 
παραμέτρων για τον υπολογιστή τους, που διαβάζεται για το πώς ο 
χρόνος είναι συγχρονισμένος στους ραδιοσταθμούς σε ολόκληρη τη 
χώρα, και ελέγχουν την απόδοση των δορυφόρων σφαιρικών 
τοποθετώντας συστημάτων (ΠΣΤ).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a la información, a las herramientas,
y a los servicios para la medida el timekeeping y de la frecuencia. 
Los visitantes pueden descargar tiempo-fijar el software para su
ordenador, leído sobre cómo el tiempo se sincroniza en las 
estaciones de radio a través del país, y vigilar el funcionamiento 
de los satélites globales del sistema de colocación (GPS).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206226</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104480</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nist-time-and-frequency-information</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
