<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82781</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82781</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3981</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Catch your bus</string>
            <string language="sv">Catch your bus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fangen Sie Ihren Bus ab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Attrapez votre bus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Trave sua barra-ônibus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Interferisca il vostro bus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πιάστε το διάδρομό σας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Coja su megabus</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With this learning resource, expressions of time are practiced. Through simple animations and short statements the student hears several different ways of expressing time. The objective is to catch the bus whose departure time is visible in the square. Through clicking on the man in the square the student learns what time it is. By clicking the buttons the student hears four different route alternatives and how long it takes to get to the bus station with each and every route. The student should choose the route that takes him or her to the station the exact time when the bus leaves the station. If you choose the correct route, there is an animation where the passenger steps on the bus and off he goes. The wrong choice results in the bus leaving without passengers. The program gives the user constantly random hours to work which means practicing different hours of the day. The departure time of the bus varies, too.</string>
            <string language="sv">Med lärobjektet övas tidsuttrycken. Genom enkla animationer och korta yttranden hör eleven flera olika sätt att uttrycka klockslag.
Målet är att hinna med bussen vars avgångstid syns i rutan. Genom att klicka på mannen i rutan får eleven veta vad klockan är. Genom att klicka på knapparna hör eleven fyra olika ruttalternativ och hur lång tid det tar att komma till bussstationen med var och en rutt. Eleven ska välja den rutt som tar honom eller henne till stationen exakt det klockslag bussen avgår. Väljer man rätt rutt ser man en animation där passageraren stiger på bussen och åker iväg. Väljer man fel åker bussen iväg utan passagerare. Programmet lottar hela tiden ut nya klockslag, vilket betyder att man i uppgiften går igenom olika klockslag. Också bussens avgångstid varierar.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit diesem erlernenhilfsmittel werden Ausdrücke 
der Zeit geübt. Durch einfache Animationen und kurze 
Anweisungen hört der Kursteilnehmer einige unterschiedliche Methoden 
des Ausdrückens von von Zeit. Das Lernziel ist, den Bus 
abzufangen dessen Abfahrtszeit im Quadrat sichtbar ist. Durch 
das Klicken auf dem Mann im Quadrat erlernt der Kursteilnehmer, welche
Zeit es ist. Indem er die Tasten anklickt, hört der 
Kursteilnehmer vier unterschiedliche Wegalternativen und wie lang es 
nimmt, um an den Busbahnhof mit jedem Weg zu gelangen. Der 
Kursteilnehmer sollte den Weg wählen, der ihn oder sie zur Station 
die genaue Zeit nimmt, als der Bus die Station verläßt. Wenn 
Sie den korrekten Weg wählen, gibt es eine Animation, wohin der 
Passagier auf den Bus tritt und er ausgeht. Die auserlesenen 
Resultate des Unrechtes im Bus, der ohne Passagiere verläßt. 
Das Programm gibt die gelegentlichen Stunden des Benutzers 
ständig zur Arbeit, die übende unterschiedliche Stunden des Tages 
bedeutet. Die Abfahrtszeit des Busses verändert sich, auch.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec cette ressource d'étude, des expressions du
temps sont pratiquées. Par des animations simples et des 
rapports courts l'étudiant entend plusieurs différentes voies 
d'exprimer le temps. L'objectif est d'attraper le bus dont le 
temps de départ est visible dans la place. En cliquant
sur l'homme dans la place l'étudiant apprend que quelle heure elle 
est. En cliquant les boutons l'étudiant entend quatre 
solutions de rechange différentes d'itinéraire et combien de temps 
elle prend pour obtenir à la gare routière avec chaque itinéraire. 
L'étudiant devrait choisir l'itinéraire qui lui prend à la 
station le temps exact où le bus part de la station. Si vous 
choisissez l'itinéraire correct, il y a une animation où le passager
fait un pas sur le bus et hors fonction il va. Les résultats 
bien choisis de mal dans le bus partant sans passagers. Le 
programme donne les heures constamment aléatoires d'utilisateur au 
travail qui signifie différentes heures de pratique du jour. La
période de départ du bus change, aussi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com este recurso de aprendizagem, as expressões 
do tempo são praticadas. Com os animations simples e as 
indicações curtas o estudante ouve diversas maneiras diferentes de 
expressar o tempo. O objetivo é travar a barra-ônibus cuja a 
hora de partida é visível no quadrado. Com estalar no homem no
quadrado o estudante aprende que hora é. Estalando as teclas o 
estudante ouve quatro alternativas diferentes da rota e quanto tempo 
faz exame para começar à estação de barra-ônibus com cada rota. 
O estudante deve escolher a rota que faz exame dele ou dela à 
estação o tempo exato em que a barra-ônibus sae da estação. 
Se você escolher a rota correta, há um animation aonde o 
passageiro pise na barra-ônibus e se apague. Os resultados bem 
escolhidos do erro na barra-ônibus que sae sem os passageiros. 
O programa dá as horas constantemente aleatórias do usuário 
ao trabalho que significa horas diferentes praticando do dia. A 
época de partida da barra-ônibus varia, demasiado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con questa risorsa imparante, le espressioni di 
tempo si esercitano in. Con le animazioni semplici e le 
istruzione corte l'allievo sente vari modi di esprimere il tempo. 
L'obiettivo è interferire il bus di cui il tempo di partenza è
visibile nel quadrato. Con scattarsi sull'uomo nel quadrato 
l'allievo impara che quando è. Scattando i tasti l'allievo 
sente quattro alternative differenti dell'itinerario e quanto tempo 
prende per ottenere all'autostazione con ogni itinerario. 
L'allievo dovrebbe scegliere l'itinerario che gli occorre alla 
stazione tempo esatto in cui il bus lascia la stazione. Se 
scegliete l'itinerario corretto, ci è una animazione dove il 
passeggero fa un passo sul bus e si spegne. I risultati choice 
di torto nel bus che va senza passeggeri. Il programma dà le 
ore costantemente casuali dell'utente a lavoro che significa le ore 
differenti esercitantesi del giorno. Il periodo di partenza del 
bus varia, anche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς εκμάθησης, οι 
εκφράσεις του χρόνου ασκούνται. Μέσω των απλών ζωτικοτήτων
και των σύντομων δηλώσεων ο σπουδαστής ακούει διάφορους 
διαφορετικούς τρόπους το χρόνο. Ο στόχος είναι να πιαστεί 
ο διάδρομος ο ο οποίος χρόνος αναχώρησης είναι ορατός στο 
τετράγωνο. Μέσω του κρότου στο άτομο στο τετράγωνο ο 
σπουδαστής μαθαίνει τι ώρα είναι. Με τον κρότο των 
κουμπιών ο σπουδαστής ακούει τέσσερις διαφορετικές εναλλακτικές 
λύσεις διαδρομών και πόσο καιρό πολύ παίρνει για να φτάσει στο 
σταθμό διαδρόμων με κάθε διαδρομή. Ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να 
επιλέξει τη διαδρομή που σε παίρνει στο σταθμό ο ακριβής χρόνος 
όταν αφήνει ο διάδρομος το σταθμό. Εάν επιλέγετε τη σωστή
διαδρομή, υπάρχει μια ζωτικότητα όπου τα βήματα επιβατών στο 
διάδρομο και από πηγαίνει. Η λανθασμένη επιλογή οδηγεί στο
διάδρομο φεύγοντας χωρίς επιβάτες. Το πρόγραμμα δίνει στο 
χρήστη τις συνεχώς τυχαίες ώρες στην εργασία που σημαίνει τις 
διαφορετικές ώρες της ημέρας. Ο χρόνος αναχώρησης του 
διαδρόμου ποικίλλει, επίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con este recurso que aprende, las expresiones del
tiempo se practican. Con animaciones simples y declaraciones 
cortas el estudiante oye varias diversas maneras de expresar tiempo. 
El objetivo es coger el megabus que hora de salida es visible en
el cuadrado. Con hacer clic en el hombre en el cuadrado el 
estudiante aprende que cuándo es. Haciendo clic los botones el 
estudiante oye cuatro diversos alternativas de la ruta y cuánto 
tiempo toma para conseguir al término de autobuses con cada ruta. 
El estudiante debe elegir la ruta que lleva lo o la a la 
estación el tiempo exacto en que el megabus sale de la estación. 
Si usted elige la ruta correcta, hay una animación adonde el 
pasajero camina en el megabus y él se apaga. Los resultados 
bien escogidos del mal en el megabus que se va sin los pasajeros. 
El programa da las horas constantemente al azar del utilizador 
al trabajo que significa diversas horas practicantes del día. 
La época de salida del megabus varía, también.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3981</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="sv">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A game-like exercise about the hours of the day</string>
            <string language="sv">Spelliknande övning i klockslagen</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82781</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/catch_your_bus_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
