<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82487</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82487</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1558</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Virtual walk in London – Virtuaalikävely Lontoossa</string>
            <string language="en">Virtual walk in London</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Virtueller Weg in London</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Promenade virtuelle à Londres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Caminhada virtual em Londres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Camminata virtuale a Londra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικονικός περίπατος στο Λονδίνο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caminata virtual en Londres</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Aihio näyttää miten digitaalikuvien avulla voidaan luoda haasteellinen ympäristö tärkeiden tienneuvomistilanteiden dialogien opiskeluun.
Alkutilanteessa oppilas seisoo British Museumin portilla; täältä hänen tulisi päästä saamiaan ohjeita seuraamalla Covent Garden Marketille. Hän näkee kaiken aikaa kuvaruudulla edessään saman näkymän kuin reittiä oikeasti kävelevä näkisi. Oppilaan tulee kulkea kaikista matkan varrella eteen tulevista risteyksistä neuvottuun suuntaan. Ruudulla on näkyvissä eri suuntiin osoittavia nuolinäppäimiä,  ja niitä painelemalla oppilas ohjaa itseään  kohti haluttua päämäärää. Samalla hän saa opastajalta luontevasti brittiläistä kulttuuritietoa, joka liittyy matkan varrella vastaan tuleviin paikkoihin, rakennuksiin jne. Oppilasta pyydetään myös napauttamaan joitakin reitillä näkyviä kohteita (esim. kulkuneuvoja, kylttejä, rakennuksia), jolloin hän väistämättä kiinnittää huomiota ympärillä näkemäänsä. Ohjelma kommentoi mahdollisia virheitä suullisesti ja palauttaa eksyneet lähtöruutuun.</string>
            <string language="en">In this task digital pictures are used to create an environment for learning how to give directions in English. When starting the task the student is standing at the gate of the British Museum and he/she is supposed to get to Covent Garden Market by following the given instructions. He/she will all the time see on the screen the same view as a person walking there for real would. The student has to follow all the instructions very carefully. There are cursor moving keys pointing at different directions on the screen and by clicking on them the student gets into the wanted direction. In addition he/she will also get British cultural information on the places, building etc on the way. The student is also asked to click on some of the spots on the way (for example means of transportation, street signs, buildings etc.) which makes him/her pay attention to what can be seen around. The programme gives feedback on the mistakes and returns the lost person to the start.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aufgabe werden digitale Abbildungen 
benutzt, um zu erstellen eine Umgebung für das Lernen, wie man 
Richtungen auf englisch gibt. Wenn er die Aufgabe beginnt, steht
der Kursteilnehmer am Gatter des britischen Museums und he/she soll an
Covent Garten-Markt durch nach die erteilten Anweisungen gelangen. 
He/she willen die ganze Zeit sehen auf den Bildschirm die 
gleiche Ansicht, die eine Person, die dort für reales geht wurde. 
Der Kursteilnehmer muß alle Anweisungen sehr sorgfältig 
befolgen. Es gibt die beweglichen Tasten des Cursors, die auf 
unterschiedliche Richtungen auf den Bildschirm zeigen und indem er auf
ihnen klickt, erhält der Kursteilnehmer in die gewünschte Richtung. 
Zusätzlich erhält he/she auch britische kulturelle 
Informationen über die Plätze und baut usw. auf der Methode auf. 
Der Kursteilnehmer wird auch gebeten, einige der Punkte auf der 
Methode an zu klicken (zum Beispiel Transportmittel, Straße 
unterzeichnet, Gebäude usw..) welche Marken him/her Bezahlung 
Aufmerksamkeit zu, was herum gesehen werden kann. Das Programm 
gibt Feedback auf den Fehlern und bringt die verlorene Person zum 
Anfang zurück.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En cela chargez les images digitales sont
utilisés pour créer un environnement pour apprendre comment donner 
des directions en anglais. En commençant le charger 
l'étudiant se tient à la porte du musée britannique et he/she est 
censé obtenir au marché de jardin de Covent par après les 
instructions données. La volonté de He/she tout le temps 
voient sur l'écran la même vue qu'une personne marchant là pour 
vrai . L'étudiant doit suivre toutes les instructions très 
soigneusement. Il y a des clés mobiles de curseur se dirigeant 
à différentes directions sur l'écran et en cliquant sur 
elles l'étudiant entre dans la direction voulue. En outre 
he/she obtiendra également l'information culturelle britannique sur 
les endroits, établissant etc.. sur le chemin. L'étudiant est 
également invité à cliquer sur certaines des taches sur 
le chemin (par exemple les moyens de transport, rue signe, les 
bâtiments etc...) quelle attention de salaire des marques 
him/her à ce que peut être vu autour. Le programme donne le 
feedback sur les erreurs et retourne la personne perdue au début.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta tarefa os retratos digitais são usados 
criar um ambiente para aprender como dar sentidos em inglês. Ao
começar a tarefa o estudante está estando na porta do museu 
britânico e he/she é suposto para começar ao mercado do jardim de 
Covent depois das instruções dadas. He/she querem toda a hora 
vêem na tela a mesma vista que uma pessoa que anda lá para real . 
O estudante tem que seguir todas as instruções muito com 
cuidado. Há umas chaves moventes do cursor que apontam em 
sentidos diferentes na tela e estalando neles o estudante começa no 
sentido querido. Além he/she começará também a informação 
cultural britânica nos lugares, construindo etc. na maneira. O 
estudante é pedido também para estalar sobre alguns dos pontos na 
maneira (para meios do exemplo de transporte, a rua assina, os 
edifícios etc..) que atenção do pagamento dos makes him/her a
o que pode ser visto ao redor. O programa dá o feedback nos 
erros e retorna a pessoa perdida ao começo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa operazione le immagini digitali sono 
usate per creare un ambiente per imparare come dare i sensi in 
inglese. Nell'iniziare l'operazione l'allievo sta levandosi in 
piedi al cancello del museo britannico e he/she è supposto per 
ottenere al mercato del giardino di Covent tramite dopo le date 
istruzioni. He/she vogliono tutto il tempo vedono sullo schermo 
la stessa vista come una persona che cammina là per reale. 
L'allievo deve seguire molto con attenzione tutte le istruzioni.
Ci sono tasti commoventi del cursore che indicano ai sensi 
differenti sullo schermo e scattandosi su loro l'allievo entra nel 
senso desiderato. In più he/she egualmente otterrà le 
informazioni culturali britanniche sui posti, sviluppanti ecc sul 
modo. L'allievo egualmente è chiesto di scattare sopra alcuni 
dei punti sul modo (per esempio il mezzo di trasporto, via firma, 
costruzioni ecc.) quale attenzione di paga di marche him/her a 
che cosa può essere visto intorno. Il programma dà le risposte
sugli errori e restituisce la persona persa all'inizio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την στοιχειώδη εργασία οι ψηφιακές εικόνες 
χρησιμοποιούνται για να δημιουργήσουν ένα περιβάλλον για την 
εκμάθηση πώς να δώσουν τις κατευθύνσεις στα αγγλικά. Κατά 
έναρξη της στοιχειώδους εργασίας τη σπουδαστής στέκεται στην 
πύλη του βρετανικού μουσείου και υποτίθεται για να φτάσει στην 
αγορά κήπων Covent με την ακολουθία των δεδομένων οδηγιών. 
Θα δει όλη την ώρα στην οθόνη την ίδια όψη 
όπως ένα πρόσωπο που περπατά εκεί για πραγματικό. Ο 
σπουδαστής πρέπει να ακολουθήσει όλες τις οδηγίες πολύ 
προσεκτικά. Υπάρχουν κινούμενα πλήκτρα δρομέων που 
δείχνουν στις διαφορετικές κατευθύνσεις στην οθόνη και με τον 
κρότο σε τις ο σπουδαστής παίρνει στην επιθυμητή κατεύθυνση. 
Επιπλέον θα πάρει επίσης τις βρετανικές πολιτιστικές 
πληροφορίες για τις θέσεις, στηριγμένος κ.λπ... στον τρόπο. 
Ο σπουδαστής καλείται επίσης να χτυπήσει επιτόπου μερικά 
από στον τρόπο (παραδείγματος χάριν μέσα της μεταφοράς, των 
σημαδιών οδών, των κτηρίων κ.λπ....) ποιοι τύποι αυτός/η 
προσοχή αμοιβής της σε αυτά που μπορεί να δει γύρω. 
Το πρόγραμμα δίνει την ανατροφοδότηση στα λάθη και 
επιστρέφει το χαμένο πρόσωπο στην έναρξη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta tarea los cuadros digitales se utilizan 
para crear un ambiente para aprender cómo dar direcciones en inglés.
Al comenzar la tarea el estudiante está estando parado en la 
puerta del museo británico y he/she es supuesto para conseguir al 
mercado del jardín de Covent por después de las instrucciones dadas.
He/she quieren toda la hora ven en la pantalla la misma visión 
que una persona que recorría allí para verdadero . El 
estudiante tiene que seguir todas las instrucciones muy 
cuidadosamente. Hay claves móviles del cursor que señalan en 
diversas direcciones en la pantalla y haciendo clic en ellas el 
estudiante consigue en la dirección deseada. Además he/she 
también conseguirá la información cultural británica sobre los 
lugares, construyendo el etc en la manera. Piden el estudiante 
también hacer clic encendido algunos de los puntos en la manera (por 
ejemplo los medios del transporte, calle firman, los edificios etc.) 
qué atención de la paga de las marcas him/her a lo que puede 
ser visto alrededor. El programa da feedback en los errores y 
vuelve a persona perdida al comienzo.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1558</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="fi">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Englannin kielen kuullunymmärtäminen ja tien neuvomiseen liittyvät ilmaisut</string>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension and giving directions in English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82487</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/lontoo/co1_15.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
