<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/629188271</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>629188271</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>15168</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">L'Unione Europea e la sua anima musicale</string>
            <string language="en">The European Union and its musical soul</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der europäische Anschluß und seine musikalische 
Seele</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'union européenne et sa âme musicale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A união européia e sua alma musical</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Ευρωπαϊκή Ένωση και η μουσική ψυχή του</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La unión europea y su alma musical</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Questo LO aiuta ad insegnare i nomi dei compositori, delle danze e degli strumenti musicali che tutti condividiamo e che più ci rappresentano, dalle austere sfumature del nord ai toccanti ritmi del sud del nostro continente multicolore. Si tratta di un cruciverba da completare. Gli studenti saranno in grado di cliccare sul bottone " Controlla" per vedere se le loro risposte sono corrette. Se non riescono ad andare avanti, c'è un bottone "Suggerimento" che è possibile cliccare per ottenere una lettera. Per procedere, gli studenti devono cliccare sul numero dello schema per leggere la definizione. Il cruciverba valuta la conoscenza degli studenti sull'anima musicale dell'U.E, chiedendo loro di dare le soluzioni alle seguenti dodici definizioni: 1. il compositore tedesco che scrisse il famoso "Clavicembalo ben temperato"  2. Il compositore ungherese autore delle "Rapsodie ungheresi" e della famosa " Ninnananna" 3. una tipica composizione Portoghese malinconica 4. il nome del paese di Fryderyk Chopin 5. il nome di un musicista italiano che visse al tempo di Mozart 6. il cognome del compositore dell'inno dell'U.E. 7. compositore polacco famoso per le sue "Polacche" 8. tipico strumento a fiato scozzese 9. affascinante danza spagnola che usa ventagli e nacchere per sottolineare il movimento delle braccia 10. danza e canzone greca, particolarmente caratteristica dell'isola di Creta  11. compositore austriaco nato a Salisburgo il 27 gennaio 1756 12. compose Aida, Ernani, e Falstaff</string>
            <string language="en">This LO helps teaching the names of the composers, of the dances and of the musical instruments which we all share and most represent us, from the austere northern nuances to the touching southern rhythms of our multicoloured continent. It is a crossword to complete. Students will be able to click on the “Check” button to see if their answers are correct. If they can’t go on, there is a “Hint” button possible to be clicked in order to get a letter. To procede, students must click on the number on the grid to read the clue definition.

The crossword tests students’ knowledge on the E.U. musical soul, asking them to give the solutions to the following twelve definitions:
1.	the German composer who wrote the famous Well-Tempered Clavier.
2.	the Hungarian composer author of the "Hungarian Dances" and the famous "Lullaby"
3.	a typical Portuguese melancholic song
4.	the name of Fryderyk Chopin's country
5.	the name of an Italian musician who lived at the time of Mozart
6.	surname of the composer of the European Union Anthem
7.	Polish composer famous for his "Polonaises"
8.	Typical Scottish wind instrument
9.	Fascinating Spanish dance which uses fans and castanets to underline the movements of the arms.
10.	Greek song and dance, particularly characteristic of the Isle of Crete
11.	Austrian composer born in Salzburg on January 27th, 1756.
12.	He composed Aida, Ernani and Falstaff.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">date</string>
            <string language="en">dates</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">canzoni popolari</string>
            <string language="en">folk songs</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">strumenti</string>
            <string language="en">instruments</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">ritmi</string>
            <string language="en">rhythm</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">Chopin</string>
            <string language="en">Chopin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">fado</string>
            <string language="en">fado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">flamenco</string>
            <string language="en">flamenco</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">Verdi</string>
            <string language="en">Verdi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">Liszt</string>
            <string language="en">Liszt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">nacchere</string>
            <string language="en">castanets</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses multicoloured die NIEDRIGEN Hilfen, welche 
die Namen der Komponisten, der Tänze und der Musikinstrumente 
unterrichten, welchen wir aller Anteil und die meisten uns darstellen,
von den strengen Nordnuancen zu den rührenden südlichen Rhythmen von
unserem Kontinent. Es ist ein Kreuzworträtsel, zum 
durchzuführen. Kursteilnehmer können, das?Check an zu klicken?
knöpfen Sie, um zu sehen, wenn ihre Antworten korrekt sind. 
Wenn sie can?t weitergehen, gibt es ein?Hint? knöpfen Sie
möglich geklickt zu werden, um ein Zeichen zu erhalten. Zum 
procede müssen Kursteilnehmer die Zahl auf dem Rasterfeld an klicken,
um die Kreuzworträtsel-Testkursteilnehmer des Anhaltspunkts 
definition.The zu lesen? Wissen auf der E.U. musikalischen 
Seele, sie, um den Lösungen zu den folgenden zwölf definitions:1. 
den deutschen Komponisten zu geben, der dem berühmten Gut-Gemilderten
Clavier.2. den ungarischen Komponistautor der "ungarischen Tänze" 
schrieb und um um das berühmte "Lullaby"3 bitten. ein typisches
portugiesisches melancholic song4. der Name von Fryderyk Chopins 
country5. der Name eines italienischen Musikers, der zu der Zeit des 
Mozart6. Familiennameen des Komponisten des europäischen Anschlußes 
Anthem7 lebte. Polnischer Komponist berühmt für sein 
"Polonaises"8. Typischer schottischer Wind instrument9. 
Faszinierender Spanischtanz, der Ventilatoren und Kastagnetten 
benutzt, um die Bewegungen des arms.10 zu unterstreichen. 
Griechisches Lied und Tanz, besonders charakteristisch von der 
Insel von Crete11. Österreichischer Komponist geboren in 
Salzburg an Januar 27., 1756.12. Er bestand Aida, Ernani und 
Falstaff.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce BASSES aides enseignant les noms des 
compositeurs, des danses et des instruments musicaux ce qui nous toute
la part et les la plupart nous représentons, des nuances nordiques 
austères aux rythmes méridionaux émouvants de notre continent 
multicolore. C'est des mots croisé à terminer. Les 
étudiants pourront cliquer sur le ?Check ? boutonnez 
pour voir si leurs réponses sont correctes. Si elles can?t 
continuent, il y a-t-il un ?Hint ? boutonnez possible d'être 
cliqué afin de recevoir une lettre. Au procede, les 
étudiants doivent cliquer sur le nombre sur la grille pour 
lire les étudiants d'essais de mots croisé de l'indice 
definition.The ? la connaissance sur l'âme musicale d'E.U., 
demandant eux pour donner aux solutions aux douze definitions:1. 
suivants le compositeur allemand qui a écrit au Clavier.2. 
Bien-Gâché célèbre l'auteur hongrois de compositeur "des danses 
hongroises" et le "Lullaby"3 célèbre. un song4. melancholic 
portugais typique le nom de country5. de Fryderyk Chopin le nom d'un 
musicien italien qui a vécu au moment du nom de famille de Mozart6. 
du compositeur de l'union européenne Anthem7. Compositeur 
polonais célèbre pour son "Polonaises"8. Vent écossais 
typique instrument9. Danse fascinante d'Espagnol qui utilise des
ventilateurs et des castagnettes pour souligner les mouvements
de l'arms.10. Chanson grecque et danse, particulièrement 
caractéristiques de l'île de Crete11. Compositeur autrichien 
né à Salzbourg le 27 janvier, 1756.12. Il a composé Aida, 
Ernani et Falstaff.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este as ajudas BAIXAS que ensinam os nomes dos 
compositores, das danças e dos instrumentos musicais quais nós toda 
a parte e a maioria nos representamos, dos nuances do norte austere 
aos ritmos do sul tocantes do nosso multicoloured o continente. 
É um crossword a terminar. Os estudantes poderão  
estalar sobre o?Check? abotoe para ver se suas respostas 
estiverem corretas. Se can?t forem sobre, há um?Hint? 
abotoe possível ser estalado a fim começar uma letra. Ao
procede, os estudantes devem estalar sobre o número na grade para ler
os estudantes dos testes do crossword do indício definition.The? 
conhecimento na alma musical de E.U., pedindo os para dar às 
soluções aos seguintes doze definitions:1. o compositor alemão que 
escreveu ao Clavier.2. Bem-Moderado famoso o autor hungarian do 
compositor "das danças hungarian" e o "Lullaby"3 famoso. um 
song4. melancholic portuguese típico o nome de country5. de Fryderyk 
Chopin o nome de um músico italiano que vivesse na altura do 
sobrenome de Mozart6. do compositor da união européia Anthem7. 
Compositor polonês famoso para seu "Polonaises"8. Vento 
scottish típico instrument9. Dança fascinante do espanhol que 
usa ventiladores e castanets sublinhar os movimentos do arms.10. 
Canção grega e dança, particularmente características do 
isle de Crete11. Compositor austrian carregado em Salzburg 
janeiro em 27os, 1756.12. Compôs Aida, Ernani e Falstaff.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το LO βοηθά τα ονόματα των συνθετών, των 
χορών και των μουσικών οργάνων που όλοι μοιραζόμαστε και τα 
περισσότερα μας αντιπροσωπεύουν, από τις αυστηρές βόρειες 
αποχρώσεις στους να αγγίξουν νότιους ρυθμούς της πολύχρωμης 
ηπείρου μας. Είναι ένα σταυρόλεξο για να ολοκληρώσει. 
Οι σπουδαστές θα είναι σε θέση να χτυπήσουν στο ?Check; 
κουμπί που βλέπει εάν οι απαντήσεις τους είναι 
σωστές. Εάν can?t συνεχίζονται, υπάρχει ένα ?Hint; 
κουμπί πιθανό να χτυπηθεί προκειμένου να αποκτηθεί μια 
επιστολή. Στο procede, οι σπουδαστές πρέπει να χτυπήσουν 
στον αριθμό στο πλέγμα για να διαβάσουν τον καθορισμό ένδειξης 
Οι σπουδαστές δοκιμών σταυρόλεξων; γνώση σχετικά με 
τη μουσική ψυχή της ΕΕ, που ζητά τους για να δώσει τις λύσεις στα
ακόλουθα δώδεκα definitions:1. ο γερμανικός συνθέτης που 
έγραψε στο διάσημο καλά-μετριασμένο Clavier.2. τον ουγγρικό 
συγγραφέα συνθετών των "ουγγρικών χορών" και του διάσημου 
"Lullaby"3. ένα χαρακτηριστικό πορτογαλικό μελαγχολικό 
song4. το όνομα country5. Fryderyk chopin το όνομα ενός
ιταλικού μουσικού που έζησε κατά την διάρκεια του επωνύμου 
Mozart6. του συνθέτη της Ευρωπαϊκής Ένωσης Anthem7. 
Πολωνικός συνθέτης διάσημος για "Polonaises"8 του. 
Χαρακτηριστικός σκωτσέζικος αέρας instrument9. 
Συναρπαστικός ισπανικός χορός που χρησιμοποιεί τους 
ανεμιστήρες και τις καστανιέτες για να υπογραμμίσει τις 
μετακινήσεις του ελληνικών τραγουδιού arms.10. και του χορού, 
ιδιαίτερα χαρακτηριστικές του νησιού Crete11. Αυστριακός 
συνθέτης γεννημένος στο Σάλτζμπουργκ στις 27$ Ιανουαρίου, 
1756.12. Σύνθεσε Aida, Ernani και Falstaff.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este las ayudas BAJAS que enseñaban los nombres 
de los compositores, de las danzas y de los instrumentos musicales 
cuáles toda la parte y la mayoría nos representamos, de los matices 
norteños austeros a los ritmos meridionales conmovedores de nuestro 
multicoloured el continente. Es un crucigrama a terminar. 
¿Los estudiantes podrán hacer clic encendido el?Check? 
abotone para ver si sus respuestas están correctas. ¿Si 
can?t continúan, hay un?Hint? abotone posible ser hecho clic 
para conseguir una carta. ¿Al procede, los estudiantes deben 
hacer clic encendido el número en la rejilla para leer a los 
estudiantes de las pruebas del crucigrama de la pista definition.The? 
conocimiento en el alma musical de E.U., pidiendo los para dar a
las soluciones a los doce definitions:1. siguientes el compositor 
alemán que escribió a Clavier.2. Bien-Templado famoso el autor 
húngaro del compositor de las "danzas húngaras" y el "Lullaby"3 
famoso. un song4. melancholic portugués típico el nombre de 
country5. de Fryderyk Chopin el nombre de un músico italiano que 
vivió a la hora del apellido de Mozart6. del compositor de la unión 
europea Anthem7. Compositor polaco famoso por su "Polonaises"8. 
Viento escocés típico instrument9. Danza fascinadora del
español que utiliza los ventiladores y los castanets para subrayar 
los movimientos del arms.10. Canción griega y danza, 
determinado características de la isla de Crete11. Compositor 
austríaco llevado en Salzburg de enero el 27, 1756.12. Él 
compuso Aida, Ernani y Falstaff.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Daten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Volksliede</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Instrumente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rhythmus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chopin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">fado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Flamenco</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verdi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Liszt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kastagnetten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dates</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">chansons folkloriques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">instruments</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">rythme</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chopin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">flamenco</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Verdi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Liszt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">castagnettes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">datas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">canções populares</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">instrumentos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ritmo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Chopin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">flamenco</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Verdi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Liszt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">castanets</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ημερομηνίες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λαϊκά τραγούδια</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">όργανα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ρυθμός</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Chopin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">fado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">flamenco</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Verdi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Liszt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">καστανιέτες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">fechas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">canciones populares</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">instrumentos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ritmo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Chopin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">fado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">flamenco</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Verdi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Liszt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">castanets</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lusi;Prof. Noemi;;;
FN:Prof. Noemi Lusi
ORG:Italy
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>15168</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lusi;Noemi;;;
FN:Noemi Lusi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2006-05-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:de Gennaro;Carmen;;;
FN:Carmen de Gennaro
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-08</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:de Gennaro;Carmen;;;
FN:Carmen de Gennaro
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-08</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>web page</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>manager</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>parent</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>counsellor</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>other</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>professional development</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>distance education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>library</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>educational administration</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>other</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">11-U</string>
            <string language="en">&gt; 11</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Obiettivi didattici e pedagogici. Gli studenti rivedranno le loro conoscenze sull'anima musicale dell'U.E., imparando i nomi dei compositori, degli strumenti musicali, e delle danze del nostro continente. Campo di approccio pedagogico: 14-25
Tempo: 45 minuti Procedura: gli studenti possono lavorare individualmente, in coppie o in gruppi di 3-4. Possono leggere tutte le definizioni all'inizio e poi provare a rispondere usando i bottoni di controllo e suggerimento se hanno bisogno di aiuto. Questo LO può essere usato da altri insegnanti in molti modi 



differenti secondo la situazione didattica, gli obiettivi, gruppi di età, pre-conoscenze, numero di alunni nella classe, numero dei computer nel laboratorio, tempo di esecuzione, ecc.</string>
            <string language="en">Instructional and Pedagogical Objectives

Students will revise their knowledge on the musical soul of the European Union., learning names of composers, musical instruments and dances of our continent.

 Pedagogical Approach
Age range: 11-25
Timing     : 45 minutes.
The procedure :
students can work individually, in pairs or in groups of 3-4. They can read all the definitions first and then start answering using the check and the hint button if they need help. This LO may be used by other teachers in many different ways depending on their teaching situation, their objective, age group, previous knowledge, number of students in the class, number of computers in the lab, given timing etc.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>220</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">classical music</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>593</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">history of music</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>664</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">instrumental music</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>856</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">music</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>857</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">music composer</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>858</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">music education</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>862</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">musical instrument</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>629188271</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://myeurope.eun.org/shared/data/myeurope/2005/los/02/noemi6-en/lo6-en.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
