<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82750</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82750</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3985</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Comparison in action</string>
            <string language="sv">Comparison in action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vergleich in der Tätigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comparaison dans l'action</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comparação na ação</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Confronto nell'azione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σύγκριση στην ενέργεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comparación en la acción</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The idea with the learning object is to practice the different forms of comparison. Since the student is to solve the exercise through clues, there will also be game-like features in the learning scenario. By clicking the pictures of different persons, the student will hear descriptions of these people. The student task is to place the persons in correct sequence (for example, youngest-oldest) based on the information he or she hears. The student can listen to the descriptions as many times as needed. To check the exercise, you click the word "Control". If the student has placed persons correctly, the description of the persons will be heard again and their names are visible on the screen.
</string>
            <string language="sv">Idén med lärobjektet är att öva komparationsformer. Eftersom eleven ska lösa uppgiften genom tips kommer också spelliknande drag med i bilden.
Genom att klicka på bilder av olika personer hör eleven personerna beskrivas. Eleven ska placera personerna i rätt ordningsföljd (t.ex. youngest-oldest) på basis av den info han eller hon hör. Man får lyssna på beskrivningarna så många gånger det behövs. Genom att klicka på ’Kontrollera’ kan man kontrollera uppgiften. Har eleven placerat personerna korrekt hörs beskrivningen av personerna på nytt och deras namn syns i rutan.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Idee mit der erlernennachricht ist, die 
unterschiedlichen Formulare des Vergleiches zu üben. Da der 
Kursteilnehmer die Übung durch Anhaltspunkte lösen soll, gibt es 
auch Spiel-wie Merkmale im erlernendrehbuch. Indem er die 
Abbildungen der unterschiedlichen Personen anklickt, hört der 
Kursteilnehmer Beschreibungen dieser Leute. Die 
Kursteilnehmeraufgabe ist, die Personen in die korrekte Reihenfolge zu
legen (zum Beispiel, jung-am ältesten) auf den Informationen ihn 
basiert, oder sie hört. Der Kursteilnehmer kann zu den 
Beschreibungen hören bis zu erforderliche Mal. Um die Übung zu
überprüfen, klicken Sie das Wort "Steuerung" an. Wenn der 
Kursteilnehmer Personen richtig plaziert hat, wird die Beschreibung 
der Personen wieder gehört und ihre Namen sind auf dem Bildschirm 
sichtbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'idée avec l'objet d'étude est de pratiquer les 
différentes formes de la comparaison. Puisque l'étudiant doit 
résoudre l'exercice par des indices, il y aura également jeu-comme 
des dispositifs dans le scénario d'étude. En cliquant 
les images de différentes personnes, l'étudiant entendra des 
descriptions de ces personnes. L'étudiant chargent doit 
placer les personnes dans l'ordre correct (par exemple, jeune-vieux) 
basé sur l'information l'ou elle entend. L'étudiant peut 
écouter les descriptions autant de fois aussi nécessaires. 
Pour contrôler l'exercice, vous cliquez le mot 
"commande". Si l'étudiant a placé des personnes correctement, 
la description des personnes sera entendue encore et leurs noms sont 
visibles sur l'écran.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A idéia com o objeto de aprendizagem é praticar 
os formulários diferentes da comparação. Desde que o 
estudante deve resolver o exercício com os indícios, haverá também
jogo-como características no scenario de aprendizagem. 
Estalando os retratos de pessoas diferentes, o estudante ouvirá
descrições destes povos. A tarefa do estudante é colocar as 
pessoas na seqüência correta (para o exemplo, novo-a mais velha) 
baseada na informação o ou ouve-se. O estudante pode escutar 
as descrições tantas como vezes tão needed. Para verificar o 
exercício, você estala a palavra "controle". Se o estudante 
colocar pessoas corretamente, a descrição das pessoas estará ouvida
outra vez e seus nomes são visíveis na tela.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'idea con l'oggetto imparante è esercitarsi 
nelle forme differenti del confronto. Poiché l'allievo deve 
risolvere l'esercitazione con gli indizii, ci egualmente sarà 
gioco-come le caratteristiche nel piano d'azione imparante. 
Scattando le immagini delle persone differenti, l'allievo 
sentirà le descrizioni di questa gente. L'operazione 
dell'allievo è di disporre le persone nella sequenza corretta (per 
esempio, giovane-il più vecchio) basata sulle informazioni lui o si 
sente. L'allievo può ascoltare le descrizioni altretante volte 
necessarie. Per controllare l'esercitazione, scattate la parola 
"controllo". Se l'allievo ha disposto correttamente le persone, 
la descrizione delle persone sarà sentita ancora ed i loro nomi sono 
visibili sullo schermo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιδέα με το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης είναι να ασκηθούν 
οι διαφορετικές μορφές της σύγκρισης. Δεδομένου ότι ο 
σπουδαστής πρόκειται να λύσει την άσκηση μέσω των ενδείξεων, θα 
υπάρξουν επίσης game-like χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα στο 
σενάριο εκμάθησης. Με τον κρότο των εικόνων των 
διαφορετικών προσώπων, ο σπουδαστής θα ακούσει τις περιγραφές 
αυτών των ανθρώπων. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία σπουδαστών είναι
να τοποθετήσουν τα πρόσωπα στη σωστή ακολουθία (παραδείγματος 
χάριν, νέος-την παλαιότερη) βασισμένη στις πληροφορίες που 
ακούει. Ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να ακούσει τις περιγραφές τόσο
πολλοί χρόνοι όπως απαιτούνται. Για να ελέγξετε την 
άσκηση, χτυπάτε τη λέξη "έλεγχοσ". Εάν ο σπουδαστής έχει 
τοποθετήσει τα πρόσωπα σωστά, η περιγραφή των προσώπων θα 
ακουστεί πάλι και τα ονόματά τους είναι ορατά στην οθόνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La idea con el objeto que aprende es practicar las
diversas formas de comparación. Puesto que el estudiante debe 
solucionar el ejercicio con pistas, también habrá juego-como 
características en el decorado que aprende. Haciendo clic los 
cuadros de diversas personas, el estudiante oirá descripciones de 
esta gente. La tarea del estudiante es colocar a las personas en
la secuencia correcta (por ejemplo, joven-el ma's viejo) basada en la 
información lo o ella oye. El estudiante puede escuchar las 
descripciones tantas veces tan necesarias. Para controlar el 
ejercicio, usted hace clic la palabra "control". Si el 
estudiante ha colocado a personas correctamente, la descripción de 
las personas será oída otra vez y sus nombres son visibles en la 
pantalla.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3985</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="sv">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Functional exercise in the English language forms of comparison</string>
            <string language="sv">Funktionell övning i engelskans komparationsformer</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82750</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/comparisons_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
