<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82928</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82928</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The talking clock</string>
            <string language="sv">Den talande klockan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der sprechentaktgeber</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'horloge parlante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O pulso de disparo falando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'orologio di comunicazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ομιλούν ρολόι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El reloj que habla</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A game-like multimedia learning object for learning how to tell the time. By clicking 'Play' the student hears a brief spoken text that contains an expression of time. The student should pick out that expression of time and click the clock-face, first on the place of the hour hand and then on that of the minute hand. After the student has clicked on the correct place the clock automatically shows the time. A wrong reply prompts the student to try again and the student also hears the time again. The learning object covers various time expressions (for example ”a quarter past”,”a quarter to”,” twenty minutes past”) and consolidates such established expressions in the target language.


</string>
            <string language="sv">Ett spelliknande multimedia-lärobjekt för inlärning av klockslag.
Genom att klicka på ’Play’ hör eleven ett avsnitt tal som innehåller ett klockslag. Eleven ska urskilja klockslaget och klicka på urtavlan, först på timvisarens och sedan på minutvisarens plats När eleven klickat på rätt ställe ställer klockan in sig själv. Vid fel svar uppmanas eleven att försöka igen och eleven får också höra klockslaget på nytt. Lärobjektet täcker olika tidsuttryck (t.ex. ”kvart över”, ”kvart före”, ”tjugo över”) och befäster dylika etablerade uttryck i elevens språk.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">A Spiel-wie die Multimedia, die Nachricht für 
das Lernen erlernen, wie man die Zeit erklärt. Indem er ' Spiel
' anklickt, hört der Kursteilnehmer einen kurzen gesprochenen Text, 
der einen Ausdruck der Zeit enthält. Der Kursteilnehmer sollte 
diesen Ausdruck der Zeit und das Taktgeber-Gesicht anklicken, zuerst 
auf dem Ort der Stunde Hand und dann auf dem der minuziösen Hand 
auswählen. Nachdem der Kursteilnehmer an den korrekten Platz 
geklickt hat, zeigt der Taktgeber automatisch die Zeit. Eine 
falsche Antwort fordert den Kursteilnehmer auf, noch einmal zu 
versuchen und der Kursteilnehmer hört auch die Zeit wieder. Die
erlernennachricht umfaßt verschiedene Zeitausdrücke (zum Beispiel?a 
Viertelpast??a Viertel zu?? Zwanzig Minuten hinter?) und 
vereinigt solche hergestellte Ausdrücke in der Zielsprache.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">A jeu-comme des multimédia apprenant l'objet 
pour apprendre comment dire le temps. En cliquant le 
'jeu 'l'étudiant entend un bref texte parlé qui contient une 
expression de temps. L'étudiant devrait sélectionner 
qu'expression de temps et clique le horloge-visage, d'abord 
sur l'endroit de la main d'heure et puis sur cela de la main 
minutieuse. Après que l'étudiant ait cliqué sur 
l'endroit correct l'horloge montre automatiquement le temps. Une
réponse fausse incite l'étudiant à essayer encore et l'étudiant 
entend également le temps encore. L'objet d'étude couvre de 
diverses expressions de temps (par exemple past? quart de ?a, quart de
?a à ? ? vingt minutes après ?) et consolide de telles 
expressions établies dans la langue cible.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A jogo-como os multimedia que aprendem o objeto 
para aprender como dizer o tempo. Estalando ' o jogo ' o 
estudante ouve um texto falado breve que contenha uma expressão do 
tempo. O estudante deve escolher para fora dessa expressão do 
tempo e estalar a pulso de disparo-cara, primeiramente no lugar da 
mão da hora e então naquele da mão minuciosa. Depois que o 
estudante estalou sobre o lugar correto o pulso de disparo mostra 
automaticamente o tempo. Uma resposta errada alerta o estudante 
tentar outra vez e o estudante ouve também o tempo outra vez. O
objeto de aprendizagem cobre várias expressões do tempo (para o 
past? do quarto do?a do exemplo, quarto do?a a?? vinte minutos 
após?) e consolida tais expressões estabelecidas na língua de
alvo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A gioco-come le multimedia che imparano oggetto 
per imparare come dire al tempo. Scattando 'il gioco 'l'allievo 
sente un breve testo parlato che contiene un'espressione di tempo. 
L'allievo dovrebbe selezionare quell'espressione di tempo e 
scattare la orologio-faccia, in primo luogo sul posto della mano di 
ora ed allora su quello della mano minuscola. Dopo che l'allievo
scatti sopra il posto corretto l'orologio mostra automaticamente il 
tempo. Una risposta errata spinge l'allievo a provare ancora e 
l'allievo egualmente sente ancora il tempo. L'oggetto imparante 
riguarda le varie espressioni di tempo (per esempio past? quarto di?a,
quarto di?a a?? venti minuti oltre?) e consolida tali 
espressioni stabilite nella lingua di arrivo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Game-like πολυμέσα που μαθαίνουν το αντικείμενο για
την εκμάθηση πώς να πει το χρόνο. Με τον κρότο "του 
παιχνιδιού" ο σπουδαστής ακούει ένα συνοπτικό προφορικό κείμενο
που περιέχει μια έκφραση του χρόνου. Ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να
διαλέξει ότι έκφραση του χρόνου και χτυπά το ρολόι-πρόσωπο, 
πρώτα στη θέση του χεριού ώρας και έπειτα σε ετοιμότητα αυτήν 
μικρό. Αφότου έχει χτυπήσει ο σπουδαστής στη σωστή θέση 
το ρολόι εμφανίζει αυτόματα το χρόνο. Μια λανθασμένη 
απάντηση προτρέπει το σπουδαστή για να προσπαθήσει πάλι και ο 
σπουδαστής ακούει επίσης το χρόνο πάλι. Το αντικείμενο 
εκμάθησης καλύπτει τις διάφορες χρονικές εκφράσεις 
(παραδείγματος χάριν ?a τέταρτο past?, τέταρτο ?a;,; 
είκοσι λεπτά από μπροστά;) και παγιώνει τέτοιες 
καθιερωμένες εκφράσεις στη γλώσσα στόχο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A juego-como el objeto que aprende de las 
multimedias para aprender cómo decir el tiempo. Haciendo clic 
el ' juego ' el estudiante oye un texto hablado abreviado que contenga
una expresión del tiempo. El estudiante debe seleccionar esa 
expresión del tiempo y hacer clic la reloj-cara, primero en el lugar 
de la mano de la hora y entonces en el de la mano minuciosa. 
Después de que el estudiante haya hecho clic encendido el lugar
correcto el reloj muestra automáticamente el tiempo. Una 
contestación incorrecta incita a estudiante intentar otra vez y el 
estudiante también oye el tiempo otra vez. ¿El objeto que 
aprende cubre las varias expresiones del tiempo (por ejemplo past? 
cuarto del?a, cuarto del?a a?? veinte minutos más allá de?) 
y consolida tales expresiones establecidas en la lengua 
objetivo.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="sv">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Active exercise of telling time and listening comprehension</string>
            <string language="sv">Aktiv övning av klockslag och hörförståelse</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82928</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/talande_klockan_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
