<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82606</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82606</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4504</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Phone phrases</string>
            <string language="sv">Telefonfraser</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rufen Sie Phrasen an</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Téléphonez les expressions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Phone frases</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Telefoni le frasi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τηλεφωνήστε στις φράσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Telefone las frases</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The students' task is to pick structures from telephone phrases that they should learn as so called automatic phrases. The learning object contains a large amount of useful phrases, for example for the working life. At same time, the students learn to pick out expressions from speech. The student is to fill in the table based on what he or she hears. By clicking the three phones the student hears phrases that are common in telephone calls, phrases used when someone regrets that a person is not available (for example ”I'm m afraid she's out of town all week”, "she’ll be back on Monday”, “I’m sorry, he is on the other line, would you like to hold?”). In the table underneath the phones there are some words already completed and the student is to complete each row by forming complete sentences based on what he or she has heard. The fields in the table react on each click by changing text. If you click "Control" the program checks the exercise. The correct phrases will be locked and they are heard spoken.

</string>
            <string language="sv">Eleverna ska, ur telefonfraser, plocka ut strukturer som de borde lära sig som s.k. automatiska fraser.  Lärobjektet innehåller en mängd användbara fraser, t.ex. för arbetslivet. På samma gång lär sig eleverna plocka ut uttryck ur tal.
Eleven ska fylla i tabellen på basis av vad han eller hon hör. Genom att klicka på de tre telefonerna hör eleven fraser som är vanliga i telefonsamtal, fraser som används när man beklagar att någon inte är anträffbar (t.ex. ”I’m afraid she’s out of town all week”, she’ll be back on Monday.”, “I’m sorry, he is on the other line, would you like to hold?”). I tabellen under telefonerna finns några ord färdigt och eleven ska komplettera varje rad genom att bilda fullständiga meningar på basis av det han eller hon hört. Fälten i tabellen reagerar på varje klick genom att byta text. Om man klickar på ’Kontrollera’ kontrollerar programmet  uppgiften. De korrekta fraserna låser sig och hörs talade.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Aufgabe der Kursteilnehmer ist, Strukturen von
den Telefonphrasen auszuwählen, die sie als sogenannte automatische 
Phrasen erlernen sollten. Die erlernennachricht enthält eine 
große Menge nützliche Phrasen, z.B. für das Berufsleben. Zur 
gleichen Zeit erlernen die Kursteilnehmer, Ausdrücke von der Rede 
auszuwählen. Der Kursteilnehmer soll die Tabelle ausfüllen, 
die basiert auf, was er oder sie hören. Indem er die drei 
Telefone anklickt, hört der Kursteilnehmer Phrasen, die in den 
Telefonanrufen geläufig sind, die verwendeten Phrasen, wenn jemand 
bedauert, daß eine Person nicht vorhanden ist (zum Beispiel das 
ängstlich?I'm m ist sie aus Stadt heraus alle Woche?, "she?ll 
ist zurück am Montag?, das traurige?I?m, ist er auf der anderen
Zeile, wurde Sie mag anhalten??). In der Tabelle unter die 
Telefone gibt es einige Wörter, die bereits durchgeführt werden und 
der Kursteilnehmer soll jede Reihe durchführen, indem er die 
kompletten Programmsätze bildet, die basieren auf, was er oder sie 
gehört haben. Fängt in der Tabelle reagieren auf 
jedem Klicken indem das Ändern des Textes auf. Wenn Sie 
"Steuerung" anklicken, überprüft das Programm die Übung. Die 
korrekten Phrasen sind verschlossen und ihnen werden gesprochen 
gehört.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants chargent doit 
sélectionner des structures des expressions de téléphone qu'ils 
devraient apprendre en tant que prétendues expressions automatiques. 
L'objet d'étude contient une grande quantité d'expressions 
utiles, par exemple pendant la vie active. En même temps, les 
étudiants apprennent à sélectionner des expressions de la parole. 
L'étudiant doit compléter la table basée sur ce que lui ou 
elle entend. En cliquant les trois téléphones 
l'étudiant entend les expressions qui sont communes dans les appels 
téléphoniques, expressions utilisées quand quelqu'un regrette 
qu'une personne ne soit pas disponible (par exemple le ?I'm m effrayé
elle est hors de ville toute la semaine ?, le "she?ll soit de 
retour le lundi ?, ?I?m désolé, il est sur l'autre ligne,  
vous aiment se tenir ? ?). Dans la table sous les téléphones 
il y a quelques mots déjà terminés et l'étudiant doit terminer 
chaque ligne en formant des phrases complètes basées sur ce que lui 
ou elle a entendu. Les zones dans la table réagissent sur 
chaque clic en changeant le texte. Si vous 
cliquez la "commande" le programme contrôle l'exercice. 
Les expressions correctes seront verrouillées et elles sont 
entendues parlées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A tarefa dos estudantes é escolher estruturas 
das frases do telefone que devem aprender como assim que das frases 
automáticas chamadas. O objeto de aprendizagem contem uma 
quantidade grande de frases úteis, para o exemplo para a vida de 
funcionamento. Ao mesmo tempo, os estudantes aprendem escolher 
para fora das expressões do discurso. O estudante deve 
preencher a tabela baseada em o que ou se ouvem. Estalando os 
três telefones o estudante ouve as frases que são comuns em 
atendimentos de telefone, frases usadas quando alguém lamenta que uma
pessoa não está disponível (para o?I'm m do exemplo receoso é fora
da cidade toda a semana?, o "she?ll esteja para trás em 
segunda-feira?, ?I?m pesaroso, está na outra linha,  você 
gosta de prender??). Na tabela debaixo dos telefones há algumas
palavras terminadas já e o estudante deve terminar cada fileira dando
forma às sentenças completas baseadas em o que ou se ouviram. 
Os campos na tabela reagem em cada clique mudando o texto. 
Se você estalar o "controle" o programa verifica o exercício. 
As frases corretas serão locked e são ouvidas faladas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'operazione degli allievi è di selezionare le 
strutture dalle frasi del telefono che dovrebbero imparare come 
cosiddette frasi automatiche. L'oggetto imparante contiene una 
grande quantità di frasi utili, per esempio per la vita attiva. 
Allo stesso tempo, gli allievi imparano selezionare le 
espressioni da discorso. L'allievo deve riempire la tabella 
basata su che cosa lui o lei si sente. Scattando i tre telefoni 
l'allievo sente le frasi che sono comuni nelle telefonate, frasi usate
quando qualcuno si rammarica che una persona non sia disponibile (per 
esempio?I'm m. impaurito è dalla città tutta la settimana?, 
"lo she?ll è indietro il lunedì?, ?I?m spiacente, è 
sull'altra riga, voi gradisce tenere??). Nella tabella sotto i 
telefoni ci sono alcune parole già completate e l'allievo deve 
completare ogni fila formando le frasi complete basate su che cosa lui
o lei si è sentita. I campi nella tabella reagiscono su ogni 
scatto cambiando il testo. Se scattate "il controllo" il 
programma controlla l'esercitazione. Le frasi corrette saranno 
locked e sono sentite parlate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η στοιχειώδης εργασία των σπουδαστών είναι να 
επιλέξουν τις δομές από τις τηλεφωνικές φράσεις που πρέπει να 
μάθουν ως αποκαλούμενες αυτόματες φράσεις. Το αντικείμενο 
εκμάθησης περιέχει ένα μεγάλο ποσό χρήσιμων φράσεων, 
παραδείγματος χάριν για την οικονομικά ενεργή ζωή. Στον 
ίδιο χρόνο, οι σπουδαστές μαθαίνουν να διαλέγουν τις εκφράσεις 
από την ομιλία. Ο σπουδαστής πρόκειται να συμπληρώσει τον 
πίνακα βασισμένο σε αυτό που ακούει. Με τον κρότο των 
τριών τηλεφώνων ο σπουδαστής ακούει τις φράσεις που είναι 
κοινές στα τηλεφωνήματα, φράσεις χρησιμοποιούμενες όταν λυπάται 
κάποιος για το ότι ένα πρόσωπο δεν είναι διαθέσιμο 
(παραδείγματος χάριν ?I'm μ φοβισμένο της από την πόλη όλη η 
εβδομάδα;, "she?ll να είστε πίσω τη Δευτέρα;, ?I?m θλιβερός, είναι στην άλλη γραμμή, θα επιθυμούσε να 
κρατήσει ??). Στον πίνακα κάτω από τα τηλέφωνα υπάρχουν
μερικές λέξεις που ολοκληρώθηκαν ήδη και ο σπουδαστής πρόκειται 
να ολοκληρώσει κάθε σειρά με τη διαμόρφωση των πλήρων προτάσεων 
βασισμένων σε αυτό που έχει ακούσει. Τα πεδία στον πίνακα 
αντιδρούν σε κάθε στιγμιαίο πάτημα με την αλλαγή του κειμένου. 
Εάν χτυπάτε "τον έλεγχο" το πρόγραμμα ελέγχει την άσκηση. 
Οι σωστές φράσεις θα κλειδωθούν και ακούγονται προφορικός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La tarea de los estudiantes es escoger las 
estructuras de las frases del teléfono que deben aprender como frases
automáticas supuestas. El objeto que aprende contiene una 
cantidad grande de frases útiles, por ejemplo para la vida laboral. 
En la misma hora, los estudiantes aprenden seleccionar 
expresiones del discurso. El estudiante debe completar el vector
basado en lo que él o ella oye. Haciendo clic los tres 
teléfonos el estudiante oye las frases que son comunes en llamadas 
telefónicas, frases usadas cuando alguien lamenta que una persona no 
esté disponible (por ejemplo el?I'm m asustado ella es fuera de 
ciudad toda la semana?, el "she?ll esté detrás el lunes?, 
?I?m apesadumbrado, él está en la otra línea,  usted tiene 
gusto de sostener??). En el vector por debajo de los teléfonos 
hay algunas palabras terminadas ya y el estudiante debe terminar cada 
fila formando las sentencias completas basadas en lo que él o ella ha
oído. Los campos en el vector reaccionan en cada tecleo 
cambiando el texto. Si usted hace clic "control" el programa 
controla el ejercicio. Las frases correctas serán bloqueadas y 
se oyen habladas.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4504</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-03-09</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>special education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
            <string language="sv">&gt; 16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Adult students with basic command of English</string>
            <string language="sv">Vuxenstudenter med baskunskaper i engelska</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>712</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Latin</string>
                <string language="sv">latin</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82606</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/telefonfraser_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
