<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82546</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82546</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>4503</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Frasi al telefono</string>
            <string language="en">Telephone phrases</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Telefonphrasen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expressions de téléphone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Frases do telefone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τηλεφωνικές φράσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Frases del teléfono</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">L’alunno deve costruire delle tabelle con frasi che dovrebbero essere imparate in  modo da poter essere formate automaticamente. L’oggetto di apprendimento consiste in diverse frasi utili da poter essere usate al telefono, ad esempio, nel rispondere a telefono mentre si è al lavoro. Nell’ascoltare delle frasi complete, l’alunno imparerà a ricavare queste frasi e strutture da un flusso di informazioni. Il compito dell’alunno è di costruire una tabella di frasi al telefono  basata su quello che sente. Invece di vedere frasi finite, l’alunno vede una tabella incompleta e tre telefoni. Cliccando sui telefoni, l’alunno ascolta le risposte usate spesso per indicare che la persona che si sta cercando di raggiungere telefonicamente non è disponibile ( es. “Mi dispiace ma è fuori città tutta la settimana. Tornerà lunedì”, “Mi dispiace ma è occupato su un’altra linea. Vuole attendere?”. L’alunno deve prendere la frase corretta e completare la tabella costruendo le frasi che ha sentito. Il testo nei campi predisposti nella tabella cambia quando si clicca sui campi. Nel cliccare sul pulsante di controllo, il programma verificherà lo svolgimento corretto dell’esercizio. Le frasi corrette appariranno sullo schermo e le frasi complete saranno lette ad alta voce.</string>
            <string language="en">The learner has to build the structure table with phrases that should be learnt so that they could be formed automatically. The learning object consists of several useful telephone phrases to be used, for example, when answering the telephone at work. While listening to long sentences, the learner will also learn to pick up these phrases or structures from a flow of information.
The learner’s task is to build the telephone phrase table based on what he/she hears. Instead of seeing the completed sentences, the learner can see an incomplete table and three telephones. By clicking on the telephones, the learner hears responses often used to indicate that the person whom the caller is trying to reach is not available (e.g. “I’m afraid she’s out of town all week. She’ll be back on Monday.”, “I’m sorry, he is on the other line.  Would you like to hold?”). The learner has to pick up the correct phrases from the sentences and then complete each line in the table by constructing the phrases he/she has heard. The text in the fields of the table changes when the fields are clicked on. By clicking on the Check button, the program will verify that the exercise is done correctly.  The correct phrases will appear on the screen and the complete sentences will be read aloud.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anfänger muß die Strukturtabelle mit 
Phrasen aufbauen, die erlernt werden sollten, damit sie automatisch 
gebildet werden konnten. Die erlernennachricht besteht aus 
einigen nützlichen verwendet zu werden Telefonphrasen, z.B. wenn sie 
das Telefon an der Arbeit beantwortet. Beim Hören zu den langen
Programmsätzen, der Anfänger auch erlernt, aufzuheben, soll diese 
Phrasen oder Strukturen von einem Fluß der information.The learner?s 
Aufgabe die Telefonphrase Tabelle aufbauen, die basiert auf, was 
he/she hört. Anstatt, die abgeschlossenen Programmsätze zu 
sehen, kann der Anfänger eine unvollständige Tabelle und drei 
Telefone sehen. Indem er an den Telefonen klickt, hört der 
Anfänger die Antworten, die häufig verwendet werden, um anzuzeigen, 
daß die Person, die das aufrufende Programm versucht, zu erreichen, 
nicht vorhanden ist (z.B.?I?m ängstlichshe?s aus Stadt heraus alle 
Woche. She?ll ist zurück am Montag?, das traurige?I?m, 
ist er auf der anderen Zeile. Wurden Sie mögen anhalten??). 
Der Anfänger muß die korrekten Phrasen von den Programmsätzen
aufheben und jede Zeile in der Tabelle, indem das Konstruieren der 
Phrasen he/she, dann durchzuführen gehört hat. Der Text in 
fängt von den Tabelle Änderungen auf, wenn werden geklickt 
an auffängt. Indem es auf der Überprüfung Taste 
klickt, überprüft das Programm, daß die Übung richtig erfolgt ist.
Die korrekten Phrasen erscheinen auf dem Bildschirm und die 
kompletten Programmsätze werden laut gelesen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant doit construire la table de structure 
avec les expressions qui devraient être apprises de sorte qu'elles 
aient pu être formées automatiquement. L'objet d'étude se 
compose de plusieurs expressions utiles de téléphone à utiliser, 
par exemple, en répondant au téléphone au travail. Tout en 
écoutant de longues phrases, l'étudiant apprendra également à 
reprendre ces expressions ou structures d'un écoulement des learner?s
d'information.The chargent doit construire la table 
d'expression de téléphone basée sur ce que he/she entend. Au 
lieu de voir les phrases réalisées, l'étudiant peut voir une table 
inachevée et trois téléphones. En cliquant aux 
téléphones, l'étudiant entend des réponses souvent employées pour
indiquer que la personne que le visiteur essaye d'atteindre n'est pas 
disponible (par exemple les she?s effrayés de ?I?m hors de la ville 
toute la semaine. She?ll soit de retour lundi ?, ?I?m 
désolé, il est sur l'autre ligne. vous aimez se tenir ? ?). 
L'étudiant doit prendre les expressions correctes des phrases 
et terminer alors chaque ligne dans la table en construisant les 
expressions he/she a entendu. Le texte dans les domaines de la 
table change quand les zones sont cliquées en fonction. 
En cliquant sur le bouton de contrôle, le programme 
vérifiera que l'exercice est fait correctement. Les expressions
correctes apparaîtront sur l'écran et les phrases complètes seront 
lues à haute voix.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O learner tem que construir a tabela da estrutura 
com frases que devem ser aprendidas de modo que pudessem ser dados 
forma automaticamente. O objeto de aprendizagem consiste em 
diversas frases úteis do telefone a ser usadas, para o exemplo, ao 
responder ao telefone no trabalho. Ao escutar sentenças longas,
o learner aprenderá também escolher acima estas frases ou estruturas
de um fluxo da tarefa dos learner?s de information.The devem construir
a tabela da frase do telefone baseada em o que he/she se ouve. 
Em vez de ver as sentenças terminadas, o learner pode ver uma 
tabela incompleta e três telefones. Estalando nos telefones, o 
learner ouve as respostas usadas frequentemente indicar que a pessoa 
quem o chamador está tentando alcançar não está disponível (por 
exemplo she?s receosos do?I?m fora da cidade toda a semana. 
She?ll esteja para trás em segunda-feira?, ?I?m pesaroso,
está na outra linha. você gosta de prender??). O 
learner tem que escolher acima as frases corretas das sentenças e 
para terminar então cada linha na tabela construindo as frases he/she
ouviu-se. O texto nos campos da tabela muda quando os campos 
são estalados sobre. Estalando na tecla da verificação, o 
programa verificará que o exercício está feito corretamente. 
As frases corretas aparecerão na tela e as sentenças completas
serão lidas alto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να χτίσει τον πίνακα δομών με τις 
φράσεις που πρέπει να μαθευτούν έτσι ώστε να μπορούν να 
διαμορφωθούν αυτόματα. Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης αποτελείται
από διάφορες χρήσιμες τηλεφωνικές φράσεις που χρησιμοποιούνται, 
παραδείγματος χάριν, κατά το απάντηση του τηλεφώνου στην 
εργασία. Ακούοντας τις μακροχρόνιες προτάσεις, ο αρχάριος 
θα μάθει επίσης να παίρνει αυτές τις φράσεις ή δομές από μια 
ροή των πληροφοριών Η στοιχειώδης εργασία learner?s 
είναι να χτιστεί ο πίνακας τηλεφωνικής φράσης βασισμένος σε 
αυτό που ακούει. Αντί να δει τις ολοκληρωμένες 
προτάσεις, ο αρχάριος μπορεί να δει ελλιπή πίνακα και
τρία τηλέφωνα. Με τον κρότο στα τηλέφωνα, ο αρχάριος 
ακούει τις απαντήσεις που χρησιμοποιούνται συχνά για να δείξουν 
ότι το πρόσωπο σπου ο επισκέπτης προσπαθεί να φθάσει δεν είναι 
διαθέσιμο (π.χ. ?I?m φοβισμένο she?s από την πόλη όλη η 
εβδομάδα. Το She?ll είναι πίσω τη Δευτέρα;, ?I?m θλιβερός, είναι στην άλλη γραμμή. Θα επιθυμούσατε 
να κρατήσετε το ??). Ο αρχάριος πρέπει να πάρει τις 
σωστές φράσεις από τις προτάσεις και να ολοκληρώσει έπειτα κάθε
γραμμή στον πίνακα με την κατασκευή των φράσεων που έχει 
ακούσει. Το κείμενο στα πεδία του πίνακα αλλάζει όταν 
χτυπιούνται επάνω τα πεδία. Με τον κρότο στο κουμπί 
ελέγχου, το πρόγραμμα θα ελέγξει ότι η άσκηση γίνεται σωστά. 
Οι σωστές φράσεις θα εμφανιστούν στην οθόνη και οι πλήρεις 
προτάσεις θα διαβαστούν μεγαλοφώνως.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El principiante tiene que construir el vector de 
la estructura con las frases que deben ser aprendidas de modo que 
pudieran ser formadas automáticamente. El objeto que aprende 
consiste en varias frases útiles del teléfono que se utilizarán, 
por ejemplo, al contestar al teléfono en el trabajo. Mientras 
que escucha las sentencias largas, el principiante también aprenderá
tomar estas frases o estructuras de un flujo de la tarea de los 
learner?s de information.The son construir el vector de la frase del 
teléfono basado en lo que oye he/she. En vez de ver las 
sentencias terminadas, el principiante puede ver un vector incompleto 
y tres teléfonos. Haciendo clic en los teléfonos, el 
principiante oye las respuestas usadas a menudo para indicar que la 
persona a que el llamador está intentando alcanzar no está 
disponible (e.g. los she?s asustados del?I?m fuera de la ciudad toda 
la semana. She?ll esté detrás el lunes?, ?I?m 
apesadumbrado, él está en la otra línea. usted tiene gusto 
de sostener??). El principiante tiene que tomar las frases 
correctas de las sentencias y entonces terminar cada línea en el 
vector construyendo las frases he/she ha oído. El texto en los 
campos del vector cambia cuando los campos se hacen clic encendido. 
Haciendo clic en el botón del cheque, el programa verificará 
que el ejercicio está hecho correctamente. Las frases correctas
aparecerán en la pantalla y las sentencias completas serán leídas 
en voz alta.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>4503</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-03-09</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-14</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-14</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-14</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Congedo;Fiorenza;;;
FN:Fiorenza Congedo
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-14</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>special education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">14-U</string>
            <string language="en">&gt; 14</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Abilità di base di inglese al lavoro: come dire che qualcuno non è disponibile, es. è a una riunione, in vacanza, ecc</string>
            <string language="en">Basic English skills at work: how to tell that somebody is not available, e.g., he/she is in a meeting, on holiday, etc.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>712</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">Latin</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82546</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/telepphone_phrases_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
