<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82453</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82453</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1772</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Accento di parola</string>
            <string language="en">Word stress</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wortdruck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Effort de mot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Stress da palavra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πίεση λέξης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tensión de la palabra</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Questo oggetto di apprendimento guida l'attenzione dell'allievo a notare su quale sillaba cade l'accento principale. Ciò è essenziale quando si tratta di acquisire una pronuncia da parlante nativo e la metrica in inglese. Sei parole appaiono scritte sullo schermo ed ogni parola ha un tasto "Play" vicino ad essa. Cliccando sul tasto "Play", "Gioca" l'allievo sente una parola pronunciata. L'idea è identificare la sillaba su cui cade l'accento principale e trascinare un contrassegno (una barra rossa) sotto quella sillaba. Le risposte possono essere controllate cliccando sul tasto del controllo. Se l'esercitazione sembra inizialmente troppo difficile, le risposte corrette sono anche disponibili cliccando sul tasto di Risolvi. Di conseguenza, gli allievi possono in primo luogo familiarizzarsi con l'esercitazione e ascoltare semplicemente le parole e, successivamente, verificare che cosa hanno imparato. Un'altra opzione, naturalmente, è provare a risolvere direttamente l'esercitazione.</string>
            <string language="en">This learning object directs the learner’s attention to noticing on which syllable the main stress is. This is essential when trying to achieve native-like pronunciation and prosody in English. 

Six words appear written on the screen and each word has a Play button next to it. By clicking on a Play button the learner hears a word pronounced. The idea is to identify the syllable on which the main stress falls and drag a mark (a red bar) under that syllable. The answers can be checked by clicking on the Check button. If the exercise seems too difficult at first, the correct answers are also available by clicking on the Solve button. Therefore, the learners can first familiarize themselves with the exercise and just listen to the words and later they can test what they have learned. Another option, of course, is to try and solve the exercise right away.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese erlernennachricht verweist die learner?s 
Aufmerksamkeit zum Beachten auf, welcher Silbe der Hauptdruck ist. 
Dieses ist wesentlich beim Versuchen, gebürtig-wie Aussprache 
zu erzielen und prosody auf englisch. Sechs Wörter sehen auf 
den Bildschirm geschrieben aus und jedes Wort hat eine Spieltaste nahe
bei ihm. Indem er auf einer Spieltaste klickt, hört der 
Anfänger ein ausgesprochenes Wort. Die Idee ist, die Silbe zu 
kennzeichnen, auf die der Hauptdruck fällt und schleppt eine 
Markierung (einen roten Stab) unter dieser Silbe. Die Antworten 
können überprüft werden, indem man auf der Überprüfung Taste 
klickt. Wenn die Übung anfangs zu schwierig scheint, sind die 
korrekten Antworten auch vorhanden, indem sie auf der lösentaste 
klicken. Folglich können die Anfänger mit der Übung zuerst 
sich vertraut machen und zu den Wörtern gerade zu hören und später 
können sie prüfen, was sie erlernt haben. Eine andere Option 
soll selbstverständlich die Übung sofort versuchen und lösen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet objet d'étude dirige l'attention de learner?s
à noter sur quelle syllabe l'effort principal est. Il est 
essentiel en essayant réaliser c'indigène-comme la prononciation et 
la prosodie en anglais. Six mots semblent écrits sur l'écran
et chaque mot a un bouton de jeu à côté de lui. En 
cliquant sur un bouton de jeu l'étudiant entend un mot 
prononcé. L'idée est d'identifier la syllabe sur laquelle 
l'effort principal tombe et traîne une marque (une barre rouge) sous 
cette syllabe. Les réponses peuvent être contrôlées en 
cliquant sur le bouton de contrôle. Si l'exercice 
semble trop difficile au début, les réponses correctes sont 
également disponibles en cliquant sur le bouton de solution. 
Par conséquent, les étudiants peuvent d'abord se familiariser 
avec l'exercice et écouter juste les mots et plus tard ils peuvent 
tester ce qu'ils ont appris. Une autre option, naturellement, 
doit essayer et résoudre l'exercice tout de suite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este objeto de aprendizagem dirige a atenção dos
learner?s a observar em que sílaba o stress principal é. Isto 
é essencial ao tentar de conseguir nativo-como a pronunciação e 
prosody em inglês. Seis palavras parecem escritas na tela e 
cada palavra tem uma tecla do jogo ao lado dela. Estalando em 
uma tecla do jogo o learner ouve uma palavra pronunciada. A 
idéia é identificar a sílaba em que o stress principal cai e 
arrasta uma marca (uma barra vermelha) sob essa sílaba. As 
respostas podem ser verificadas estalando na tecla da verificação. 
Se o exercício parecer demasiado difícil no início, as 
respostas corretas estão também disponíveis estalando na tecla 
resolver. Conseqüentemente, os learners podem primeiramente 
familiarizar-se com o exercício e para escutar apenas as palavras e 
mais tarde podem testar o que aprenderam. Uma outra opção, 
naturalmente, deve tentar afastado e resolver a direita do exercício.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης κατευθύνει την προσοχή 
learner?s στην παρατήρηση σε ποια συλλαβή η βασική πίεση 
είναι. Αυτό είναι ουσιαστικό κατά το προσπάθεια να 
επιτύχει την εγγενής-όπως προφορά και την προσωδία στα αγγλικά. 
Έξι λέξεις εμφανίζονται γραπτές στην οθόνη και κάθε λέξη 
έχει ένα κουμπί παιχνιδιού δίπλα σε την. Με τον κρότο σε 
ένα κουμπί παιχνιδιού ο αρχάριος ακούει μια λέξη έντονη. 
Η ιδέα είναι να προσδιοριστεί η συλλαβή στην οποία οι 
βασικές πτώσεις πίεσης και σέρνουν ένα σημάδι (μια κόκκινη 
ράβδος) κάτω από εκείνη την συλλαβή. Οι απαντήσεις 
μπορούν να ελεγχθούν με τον κρότο στο κουμπί ελέγχου. Εάν 
η άσκηση φαίνεται πάρα πολύ δύσκολη πρώτα, οι σωστές 
απαντήσεις είναι επίσης διαθέσιμες με τον κρότο στο Solve 
κουμπί. Επομένως, οι αρχάριοι μπορούν πρώτα να 
εξοικειωθούν με την άσκηση και να ακούσουν ακριβώς τις λέξεις και
πιό πρόσφατος μπορούν να εξετάσουν τι έχουν μάθει. Μια 
άλλη προαιρετική δυνατότητα, φυσικά, είναι να δοκιμαστεί και να 
λυθεί το δικαίωμα άσκησης μακριά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este objeto que aprende dirige la atención de los
learner?s a notar en qué sílaba es la tensión principal. Esto
es esencial al intentar de alcanzar nativo-como la pronunciación y 
prosody en inglés. Seis palabras aparecen escritas en la 
pantalla y cada palabra tiene un botón del juego al lado de ella. 
Haciendo clic en un botón del juego el principiante oye una 
palabra pronunciada. La idea es identificar la sílaba en la 
cual la tensión principal baja y arrastra una marca (una barra roja) 
bajo esa sílaba. Las respuestas pueden ser controladas haciendo
clic en el botón del cheque. Si el ejercicio se parece 
demasiado difícil al principio, las respuestas correctas están 
también disponibles haciendo clic en el botón del solucionar. 
Por lo tanto, los principiantes pueden primero familiarizarse 
con el ejercicio y apenas escuchar las palabras y pueden probar más 
adelante lo que han aprendido. Otra opción, por supuesto, es 
intentar y solucionar el ejercicio enseguida.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1772</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-27</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-U</string>
            <string language="en">&gt; 10</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Esercitarsi a trovare e localizzare l'accento di parola in inglese</string>
            <string language="en">To practice finding and placing the word stress in English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82453</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/word_stress_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
