<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/674547751</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>674547751</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>15207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Premi Nobel in Fisiologia e Medicina -  Alcuni vincitori Europei</string>
            <string language="en">Nobel Prize in Physiology and Medicine - Some European Winners</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nobelpreis in der Physiologie und in der Medizin -
einige europäische Sieger</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Prix Nobel dans la physiologie et la médecine - 
quelques gagnants européens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Prêmio de nobel no physiology e na medicina - 
alguns vencedores europeus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βραβείο Νόμπελ στη φυσιολογία και την ιατρική - 
μερικοί ευρωπαϊκοί νικητές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Premio Nobel en la fisiología y la medicina - 
algunos ganadores europeos</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">La scienza e la tecnologia some imprese costruite da persone di differenti paesi e culture. Questo LO suggerisce una dimensione culturale dell'insegnamento/apprendimento della scienza e della tecnologia attraverso lo studio di numerosi contributi resi da scienziati ed inventori di diversi paesi Europei. Si impareranno anche differenti concetti scientifici e tecnologici e scoperte praticando la lettura della lingua inglese. SI tratta di un quiz sui Premi Nobel Europei per la Scienza e la Tecnologia. Il quiz ha un link con un sito in cui gli studenti possono ricercare le informazioni necessarie per rispondere alle domande.</string>
            <string language="en">Science and technology as enterprises built by people from different countries and cultures.
This LO suggests teaching/learning science and technology intercultural dimension through the study of several contributions made by scientists and inventors from different European countries. They will also learn different scientific and technological concepts and artefacts while practicing English reading.
It is composed of 1 quiz about European Nobel Prizes in Physiology and Medicine. The quiz has one hyperlink to a site were students can search the necessary information to answer the questions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie als Unternehmen, die 
von den Leuten aus unterschiedlichen Ländern und cultures.This 
NIEDRIG ist aufgebaut werden, schlägt teaching/learning Wissenschaft 
und interkulturelles Maß der Technologie durch die Studie einiger 
Beiträge vor, die von den Wissenschaftlern und von den Erfindern von 
den unterschiedlichen europäischen Ländern gebildet werden. 
Sie erlernen auch unterschiedliche wissenschaftlichen und 
technologischen Konzepte und die Kunstprodukte, während übendes 
englisches reading.It aus 1 Quiz über europäische Nobelpreise in der
Physiologie und in der Medizin besteht. Der Quiz hat einen 
Hypertext-Link zu einer Site waren Kursteilnehmer kann die notwendigen
Informationen suchen, um die Fragen zu beantworten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et la technologie comme entreprises 
établies par des personnes de différents pays et de cultures.This 
BAS suggère la science de teaching/learning et la dimension 
interculturelle de technologie par l'étude de plusieurs contributions
apportées par des scientifiques et des inventeurs à partir de 
différents pays européens. Ils apprendront également 
différents concepts et objets façonnés scientifiques et 
technologiques tandis que reading.It anglais de pratique se compose de
1 jeu au sujet des prix Nobel européens dans la physiologie et la 
médecine. Le jeu a un hyperlien à un site étaient des 
étudiants peut rechercher l'information nécessaire pour répondre 
aux questions.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A ciência e a tecnologia como as empresas 
construídas por povos dos países diferentes e do cultures.This 
BAIXOS sugerem a ciência de teaching/learning e a dimensão 
intercultural da tecnologia com o estudo de diversas contribuições 
feitas por cientistas e por inventores dos países europeus 
diferentes. Aprenderão também conceitos diferentes e artefacts
científicos e technological quando reading.It inglês praticando for 
composto de 1 quiz sobre prêmios de nobel europeus no physiology e na
medicina. O quiz tem um hyperlink a um local era estudantes pode
procurarar a informação necessária para responder às perguntas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία ως επιχειρήσεις που χτίζονται 
από τους ανθρώπους από τις διαφορετικές χώρες και τους 
πολιτισμούς Αυτό το LO προτείνει/επιστήμη και τεχνολογία
εκμάθησης διαπολιτισμική διάσταση μέσω της μελέτης διάφορων 
συνεισφορών που γίνονται από τους επιστήμονες και τους εφευρέτες 
από τις διαφορετικές ευρωπαϊκές χώρες. Θα μάθουν επίσης 
τις διαφορετικά επιστημονικά και τεχνολογικά έννοιες και τα 
χειροποίητα αντικείμενα ενώ εν ενεργεία αγγλική ανάγνωση 
Αποτελείται από 1 διαγωνισμό γνώσεων για τα ευρωπαϊκά 
βραβεία Νόμπελ στη φυσιολογία και την ιατρική. Ο 
διαγωνισμός γνώσεων έχει έναν σύνδεσμο υπερ-κειμένου σε μια 
περιοχή ήταν σπουδαστές μπορεί να ψάξει τις απαραίτητες 
πληροφορίες για να απαντήσει στις ερωτήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La ciencia y la tecnología como empresas 
construidas por la gente de diversos países y de cultures.This BAJOS 
sugiere ciencia de teaching/learning y la dimensión intercultural de 
la tecnología con el estudio de varias contribuciones hechas por los 
científicos y los inventores de diversos países europeos. 
También aprenderán diversos conceptos y los artefactos 
científicos y tecnológicos mientras que reading.It inglés 
practicante se compone de 1 concurso sobre los premios Nobel europeos 
en fisiología y medicina. El concurso tiene un hyperlink a un 
sitio era estudiantes puede buscar la información necesaria para 
contestar a las preguntas.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Reis;Pedro;;;
FN:Pedro Reis
ORG:Esc. Sup. Educ. de Santarém
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>15207</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Reis;Pedro;;;
FN:Pedro Reis
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2006-05-23</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:de Gennaro;Carmen;;;
FN:Carmen de Gennaro
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:de Gennaro;Carmen;;;
FN:Carmen de Gennaro
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-15</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>web page</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">U-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Questo LO può essere usato in differenti contesti secondo l'età degli studenti e la loro conoscenza della lingua inglese. Questa lezione richiede circa tre ore. 1. Gli studenti lavorano in gruppi di 2-3. Esaminano tutto il quiz e cercano di rispondere alle domande. In caso di dubbio, possono usare il sito suggerito come fonte di informazioni su Premi Nobel e i loro contributi alla scienza e alla tecnologia. 2. Gli studenti valutano i loro risultati cognitivi facendo il quiz. 3 Basandosi sul sito suggerito, ogni gruppo di studenti può preparare un documento su uno scienziato ( vita e scoperte) di un diverso paese, che sarà condiviso con la classe.</string>
            <string language="en">This LO can be used in different settings accordingly with students’ age and knowledge of English. This lesson takes about 3 hours.
1. Students work in groups of 2-3. They go through the quiz and try to answer the questions. In case of any doubt, they can use the suggested site as a source of information about Nobel Prizes and their contributions to science and technology.
2. Students evaluate their learning results by doing the quiz.
3. Based on the suggested site, each group of students can prepare a paper, on a scientist (her/his life and work) from a different country, that will be shared with the class.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/DerivativeWorks" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1143</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">sciences</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>801</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">medicine</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>594</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">history of science</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1292</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">technology</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>595</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">history of technology</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>674547751</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://myeurope.eun.org/shared/data/myeurope/2005/los/05/pedro/nobel-medicine/medicine.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
