<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82676</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82676</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3987</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Finding your way around Helsinki</string>
            <string language="sv">Finding your way around Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Finden Ihrer Methode um Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Trouver votre chemin autour de Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Encontrando sua maneira em torno de Helsínquia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Individuazione del vostro modo intorno ad 
Helsinki</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εύρεση του τρόπου σας γύρω από το Ελσίνκι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Encontrar su manera alrededor de Helsinki</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The student makes his way in Helsinki city area using a ”speaking map”. The learning object visualizes how a simple micro world can be applied in the language studies. The student's task is to enter the role of tourist and move on an authentic map with the aid of instructions. (For example, ”Go from the harbor to the Main Square and buy some ice-cream.”,” Show where the museum of modern art, Kiasma, is located”). The instructions are built-in in a story. The student points at objects by clicking them on the map. If the click is correct, a route will show up on the screen. Sometimes, you will stop in order to admire a special point of interest; by clicking a tourist destination, the student will see a photo. Erroneous clicks are followed by a comment. This way, the student is exposed to spoken English even if he or she would click here and there on the map in random fashion.
</string>
            <string language="sv">Eleven tar sig fram i Helsingfors centrum med hjälp av en ”talande karta”. Lärobjektet åskådliggör hur man kan tillämpa en enkel mikrovärld i språkstudierna.
Elevens uppgift är att leva sig in i turistens roll och röra sig på en äkta karta med hjälp av instruktioner. (T.ex. ”Gå från hamnen till Salutorget och köp glass.”, ”Visa var museet för nutidskonst, Kiasma, är”). Instruktionerna är inbakade i en berättelse. Eleven pekar på föremål genom att klicka på dem på kartan. Om klickningen är korrekt dyker det upp en rutt i rutan. Ibland stannar man för att beundra någon sevärdhet; genom att klicka på något turistmål, ser eleven ett foto av det. Klickar man fel hörs en kommentar. På detta sätt utsätts eleven för talad engelska också om han eller hon på måfå skulle klicka här och där på kartan</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kursteilnehmer bildet seine Methode im 
Helsinki Stadtbereich mit einer?speaking Karte?. Die 
erlernennachricht macht sichtbar, wie eine einfache Mikrowelt in den 
Sprachenstudien aufgetragen werden kann. Die Aufgabe des 
Kursteilnehmers ist, die Rolle des Touristen einzutragen und auf einer
authentischen Karte mit dem Hilfsmittel von Anweisungen sich zu 
verschieben. (zum Beispiel, kaufen?Go vom Hafen zum Hauptquadrat
und irgendeine Eiscreme?? Zeigen Sie, wo das Museum der modernen
kunst, Kiasma? lokalisiert wird). Die Anweisungen sind in einer 
Geschichte eingebaut. Der Kursteilnehmer zeigt auf Nachrichten, 
indem er sie auf der Karte anklickt. Wenn das Klicken korrekt 
ist, stellt ein Weg oben auf dem Bildschirm dar. Manchmal 
stoppen Sie, um einen speziellen Punkt des Interesses zu bewundern; 
indem er eine touristische Zieleinheit anklickt, sieht der 
Kursteilnehmer ein Foto. Fehlerhaftes Klicken wird von einem 
Kommentar gefolgt. Auf diese Weise, der Kursteilnehmer wird 
gesprochenes Englisch ausgesetzt, selbst wenn er oder sie klicken hier
und dort auf der Karte auf gelegentliche Art und Weise wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant fait sa voie dans la zone de ville de 
Helsinki en utilisant une carte ?speaking ?. L'objet d'étude 
visualise comment un monde micro simple peut être appliqué dans les 
études de langage. L'étudiant chargent doit écrire le 
rôle du touriste et se déplacer sur une carte authentique à l'aide 
des instructions. (par exemple, le ?Go du port à la place 
principale et achètent une certaine glace ? ? Montrez où le 
musée de l'art moderne, Kiasma, est localisé ?). Les 
instructions sont intégrées dans une histoire. L'étudiant se 
dirige aux objets en les cliquant sur la carte. Si le 
clic est correct, un itinéraire apparaîtra sur l'écran. 
Parfois, vous cesserez afin d'admirer un point spécial 
d'intérêt ; en cliquant une destination de touristes, 
l'étudiant verra une photo. Des clics incorrects sont 
suivis d'un commentaire. De cette façon, l'étudiant est 
exposée à l'anglais parlé même si lui ou elle cliquerait ici
et là sur la carte de mode aléatoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O estudante faz sua maneira na área da cidade de
Helsínquia usando um mapa?speaking?. O objeto de aprendizagem 
visualiza como um micro mundo simples pode ser aplicado nos estudos da
língua. A tarefa do estudante é incorporar o papel do turista 
e mover-se em um mapa authentic com o dae (dispositivo automático de 
entrada) das instruções. (para o exemplo, o?Go do porto ao 
quadrado principal e compra algum ice-cream.?? Mostre onde o 
museu da arte moderna, Kiasma, é encontrado?). As instruções 
são internas em uma história. O estudante aponta em objetos 
estalando os no mapa. Se o clique estiver correto, uma rota 
mostrará acima na tela. Às vezes, você parará a fim admirar 
um ponto especial do interesse; estalando um destino tourist, o 
estudante verá uma foto. Os cliques errôneos são seguidos por
um comentário. Esta maneira, o estudante é exposta a inglês 
falado mesmo se ou  estalam aqui e lá no mapa na forma aleatória.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo fa il suo modo nella zona della città 
de Helsinki usando un programma?speaking?. L'oggetto imparante 
visualizza come un micro mondo semplice può essere applicato negli 
studi di linguaggio. L'operazione dell'allievo è di fornire il 
ruolo del turista e di muoversi su un programma autentico con l'aiuto 
delle istruzioni. (per esempio, il?Go dal porto al quadrato 
principale e compra un certo gelato?? Mostri dove il museo 
dell'arte moderna, Kiasma, è individuato?). Le istruzioni sono 
incorporate in una storia. L'allievo indica agli oggetti 
scattandoli sul programma. Se lo scatto è corretto, un 
itinerario rivelerà sullo schermo. A volte, smetterete per 
ammirare un punto speciale di interesse; scattando una 
destinazione turistica, l'allievo vedrà una foto. Gli scatti 
errati sono seguiti da un commento. Questo modo, l'allievo è 
esposto all'inglese parlato anche se lui o lei si scatta qui e là sul
programma di modo casuale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σπουδαστής κάνει τον τρόπο του στην περιοχή πόλεων 
του Ελσίνκι χρησιμοποιώντας έναν ?speaking χάρτη;. Το 
αντικείμενο εκμάθησης απεικονίζει πώς ένας απλός κόσμος 
μικροϋπολογιστών μπορεί να εφαρμοστεί στις γλωσσικές μελέτες. 
Η στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή είναι να εισαγάγει το 
ρόλο του τουρίστα και να κινηθεί σε έναν αυθεντικό χάρτη με την 
ενίσχυση των οδηγιών. (Παραδείγματος χάριν, ?Go από το 
λιμάνι βασικό στον τετραγωνικό και αγοράζουν κάποιο παγωτό;,; 
Εμφανίστε όπου το μουσείο της μοντέρνας τέχνης, Kiasma, 
βρίσκεται;). Οι οδηγίες είναι ενσωματωμένες σε μια ιστορία.
Ο σπουδαστής δείχνει στα αντικείμενα με τον κρότο τους στο 
χάρτη. Εάν το στιγμιαίο πάτημα είναι σωστό, μια διαδρομή 
θα παρουσιάσει στην οθόνη. Μερικές φορές, θα σταματήσετε 
προκειμένου να θαυμαστεί ένα ειδικό σημείο ενδιαφέροντος  
με τον κρότο ενός τόπου προορισμού τουριστών, ο σπουδαστής
θα δει μια φωτογραφία. Τα λανθασμένα στιγμιαία 
πατήματα ακολουθούνται από ένα σχόλιο. Αυτός ο τρόπος, ο 
σπουδαστής εκτίθεται στα προφορικά αγγλικά ακόμα κι αν θα 
χτυπούσε εδώ και εκεί στο χάρτη στην τυχαία μόδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El estudiante hace su manera en área de la 
ciudad de Helsinki usando una correspondencia?speaking?. El 
objeto que aprende visualiza cómo un mundo micro simple se puede 
aplicar en los estudios del lenguaje. La tarea del estudiante es
incorporar el papel del turista y moverse en una correspondencia 
auténtica con la ayuda de instrucciones. ¿(por ejemplo, el?Go 
del puerto al cuadrado principal y compra un poco de helado?? 
Muestre donde el museo del arte moderno, Kiasma, se localiza?). 
Las instrucciones están incorporadas en una historia. El 
estudiante señala en los objetos haciéndolos clic en la 
correspondencia. Si el tecleo está correcto, una ruta mostrará
para arriba en la pantalla. A veces, usted parará para admirar 
una punta especial del interés; haciendo clic una destinación 
turística, el estudiante verá una foto. Los tecleos erróneos 
son seguidos por un comentario. Esta manera, el estudiante se 
expone a inglés hablada incluso si él o ella  hace clic aquí y 
allí en la correspondencia en la manera al azar.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3987</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-17</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="sv">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">English listening comprehension and expressions connected to instructions on finding your way
</string>
            <string language="sv">Engelsk hörförståelse samt uttryck i samband med väganvisningar</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82676</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/finding_your_way_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
