<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/785942990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>785942990</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1559</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Flying with prepositions - prepositioharjoitus</string>
            <string language="en">Flying with Prepositions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fliegen mit Präpositionen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voler avec des prépositions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Voar com preposições</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Volando con le preposizioni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πέταγμα με τις προθέσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El volar con preposiciones</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Aihio havainnollistaa animaatioiden ja visualisoinnin käyttöä prepositioiden opiskelussa. Sen tavoitteena on liittää prepositiot visuaalisiin ja auditiivisiin mielikuviin toiminnan kautta.
Aihion pohjana on animaatio, jossa lentokone lentää pilvisellä taivaalla, ja oppilaan tulee valita painiketta napauttamalla se prepositioilmaus, joka sopii lentokoneen lentorataan. Prepositioiden merkitystä havainnollistetaan näyttämällä animaatioita, joissa koneen lentorata vaihtelee, esim. suoraan pilven läpi  (through the cloud), pilven ali (under the cloud), pilven ympäri (around the cloud) jne.
Ohjelma kommentoi jokaista oikeaa suoritusta puhutuin kommentein, joissa prepositiorakenne tulee mainittua. Väärällä valinta johtaa koneen maahansyöksyyn.</string>
            <string language="en">In this task animation and visualisation is used to learn prepositions. The idea is to match prepositions with visual and auditive images. In the animation an airplane is flying in the cloudy sky and the student’s task is to choose the right preposition to fit the flight path of the plane. The meaning of the prepositions is made clearer by using an animation where the flight path of the airplane changes, for example, through the cloud, under the cloud, around the cloud etc. After every correct answer the student gets a spoken comment where the preposition is used. If the wrong answer is given the plane will crash.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>collection</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Aufgabe wird Animation und 
Sichtbarmachung verwendet, um Präpositionen zu erlernen. Die 
Idee ist, Präpositionen mit den Sicht- und auditive Bildern 
zusammenzubringen. In der Animation fliegt ein Flugzeug in den 
bewölkten Himmel und die student?s Aufgabe ist, die rechte 
Präposition zu beschließen, um den Flugweg der Fläche zu passen. 
Die Bedeutung der Präpositionen wird Reiniger gebildet, indem 
man eine Animation verwendet, in der der Flugweg des Flugzeuges z.B. 
durch die Wolke, unter der Wolke, um die Wolke usw. ändert. 
Nachdem jede korrekte Antwort der Kursteilnehmer einen 
gesprochenen Kommentar erhält, in dem die Präposition verwendet 
wird. Wenn die falsche Antwort gegeben wird, bricht die Fläche 
ab.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En cela chargez l'animation et la 
visualisation est employée pour apprendre des prépositions. 
L'idée est d'apparier des prépositions avec des images 
visuelles et auditive. Dans l'animation un avion vole dans le 
ciel nuageux et les student?s chargent doit choisir la bonne 
préposition pour adapter la voie d'accès de vol de l'avion. La
signification des prépositions est faite à clairifiant en utilisant 
une animation où la voie d'accès de vol de l'avion change, par 
exemple, par le nuage, sous le nuage, autour du nuage etc... 
Après que chaque réponse correcte l'étudiant obtienne un 
commentaire parlé où la préposition est utilisée. Si la 
réponse fausse est donnée l'avion s'écrasera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta tarefa o animation e o visualisation são 
usados aprender preposições. A idéia é combinar 
preposições com as imagens visuais e auditive. No animation um
avião está voando no céu cloudy e a tarefa dos student?s é 
escolher a preposição direita caber o trajeto de vôo do plano. 
O meaning das preposições é feito a clearer usando um 
animation onde o trajeto de vôo do avião mude, para o exemplo, 
através da nuvem, sob a nuvem, em torno da nuvem etc.. Depois 
que cada resposta correta o estudante começa um comentário falado 
onde a preposição esteja usada. Se a resposta errada for dada 
o plano deixará de funcionar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa operazione animazione e la 
visualizzazione è usata per imparare le preposizioni. L'idea è
abbinare le preposizioni con le immagini visive ed auditive. 
Nella animazione un aeroplano sta volando nel cielo nuvoloso e 
l'operazione degli student?s è di scegliere la giusta preposizione 
per misura il percorso di volo dell'aereo. Il significato delle 
preposizioni è reso a pulitore usando una animazione dove il percorso
di volo dell'aeroplano cambia, per esempio, attraverso la nube, sotto 
la nube, intorno alla nube ecc. Dopo che ogni risposta corretta 
l'allievo ottenga un commento parlato dove la preposizione è usata. 
Se la risposta errata è data l'aereo si arresterà.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την στοιχειώδη εργασία η ζωτικότητα και η 
απεικόνιση χρησιμοποιούνται για να μάθουν τις προθέσεις. Η 
ιδέα είναι να ταιριαχτούν με οι προθέσεις τις οπτικές και 
ακουστικές εικόνες. Στη ζωτικότητα ένα αεροπλάνο πετά στο 
νεφελώδη ουρανό και η στοιχειώδης εργασία student?s είναι να 
επιλεχτεί η σωστή πρόθεση για να εγκαταστήσει το μονοπάτι πτήσης
του αεροπλάνου. Η έννοια των προθέσεων καθίσταται σαφές με 
τη χρησιμοποίηση μιας ζωτικότητας όπου το μονοπάτι πτήσης του 
αεροπλάνου αλλάζει, παραδείγματος χάριν, μέσω του σύννεφου, 
κάτω από το σύννεφο, γύρω από το σύννεφο κ.λπ.... Μετά 
από κάθε σωστή απάντηση ο σπουδαστής παίρνει ένα προφορικό 
σχόλιο όπου η πρόθεση χρησιμοποιείται. Εάν η λανθασμένη 
απάντηση είναι το αεροπλάνο θα συντρίψει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta tarea la animación y la visualización se
utiliza para aprender preposiciones. La idea es corresponder con
preposiciones con imágenes visuales y auditive. En la 
animación un aeroplano está volando en el cielo nublado y la tarea 
de los student?s es elegir la preposición derecha para caber el 
camino de vuelo del plano. El significado de las preposiciones 
es hecho clarificante usando una animación donde el camino de vuelo 
del aeroplano cambia, por ejemplo, a través de la nube, bajo la nube,
alrededor de la nube etc. Después de que cada respuesta 
correcta el estudiante consiga un comentario hablado donde se utiliza 
la preposición. Si se da la respuesta incorrecta el plano se 
estrellará.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1559</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>web page</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-15</string>
            <string language="fi">9-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Englannin prepositiorakenteiden harjoittelu</string>
            <string language="en">Practicing English prepositions</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>785942990</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/preposition_plane/c1pl01.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
