<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82763</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82763</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3977</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Audio Grammar</string>
            <string language="sv">AudioGrammar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Audiogrammatik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Grammaire Sonore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gramática Audio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Grammatica Audio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηχητική γραμματική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gramática Audio</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This learning object demonstrates a many-sided way to teach the student to grasp structural information in the target language. The learning object also demonstrates how new technology can impact on the traditional grammar tuition. The student will build the scheme based on what he or she hears. The material is in the form of interrogative clauses which are used to inquire for the preferences of the different persons. The students don't see complete sentences but an uncomplete scheme and the picture of 6-8 people talking. By clicking on the persons the student hears a question that only fits in on one line in the scheme. The fields in the scheme respond to each click by exchanging the text in the field and by doing this the student builds the lines with the questions he or she hears. A click on "Control" causes the program to examine the exercise. The sentences the student has built up will be heard spoken and are also visible on the screen.</string>
            <string language="sv">Detta lärobjekt demonstrerar ett mångsidigt sätt att lära eleven uppfatta strukturell information på målspråket. Lärobjektet demonstrerar också hur ny teknologi kan inverka på den traditionella grammatikundervisningen. 

Eleven ska bygga upp schemat på basis av vad han eller hon hör. Som material finns frågesatser, men vilka man frågar efter olika personers preferenser. Eleverna ser inte hela meningar utan ett ofullständigt schema samt bilden på 6–8 talande personer. Genom att klicka på personerna hör eleven en fråga som endast passar in på en rad i schemat. Fälten i schemat reagerar på varje klickande genom att byta ut sin text och på så sätt bygger eleven upp raderna med de frågor han eller hon hör. Genom att klicka på ’Kontrollera’ granskar programmet uppgiften. De meningar som eleven byggt upp rätt hörs talade och syns i rutan.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese erlernennachricht zeigt eine viel-mit Seiten 
versehene Methode, den Kursteilnehmer zu unterrichten, strukturelle 
Informationen in der Zielsprache zu fassen. Die 
erlernennachricht zeigt auch, wie neue Technologie auf den 
traditionellen Grammatikunterricht sich auswirken kann. Der 
Kursteilnehmer baut den Entwurf auf, der basiert auf, was er oder sie 
hören. Das Material ist in Form von fragenden Klauseln, die 
verwendet werden, um sich für die Präferenzen der unterschiedlichen 
Personen zu erkundigen. Die Kursteilnehmer sehen nicht komplette
Programmsätze aber einen uncomplete Entwurf und die Abbildung der 
Unterhaltung der Leute 6-8. Indem er auf den Personen klickt, 
hört der Kursteilnehmer eine Frage, die nur innen auf einer Zeile im 
Entwurf paßt. Fängt im Entwurf reagieren auf jedes 
Klicken indem das Austauschen des Textes in auffangene auf und 
indem er dies tut, baut der Kursteilnehmer die Zeilen mit den Fragen 
er auf, oder sie hört. Ein Klicken auf "Steuerung" veranläßt 
das Programm, die Übung zu überprüfen. Den Programmsätzen, 
die der Kursteilnehmer aufgebaut hat, werden gesprochen gehört und 
sind auch auf dem Bildschirm sichtbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet objet d'étude démontre une voie beaucoup 
de-dégrossie d'enseigner l'étudiant à saisir l'information 
structurale dans la langue cible. L'objet d'étude démontre 
également comment la nouvelle technologie peut effectuer sur 
l'instruction traditionnelle de grammaire. L'étudiant établira
l'arrangement basé sur ce que lui ou elle entend. Le matériel 
est sous forme de clauses interrogatives qui sont employées pour 
s'enquérir pour les préférences des différentes personnes. 
Les étudiants ne voient pas des phrases complètes mais un 
arrangement d'uncomplete et l'image de parler des personnes 6-8. 
En cliquant sur les personnes l'étudiant entend une 
question qui s'adapte seulement dedans sur une ligne dans 
l'arrangement. Les zones dans l'arrangement répondent à chaque
clic en permutant le texte dans le domaine et en faisant ceci 
l'étudiant établit les lignes avec les questions il ou elle entend. 
Un clic sur la "commande" fait examiner le programme 
l'exercice. Les phrases que l'étudiant s'est accumulé seront 
entendues parlées et sont également visibles sur l'écran.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este objeto de aprendizagem demonstra uma maneira 
muito-tom o partido ensinar o estudante agarrar a informação 
estrutural na língua de alvo. O objeto de aprendizagem 
demonstra também como a tecnologia nova pode impactar na taxa de 
matrícula tradicional da gramática. O estudante construirá o 
esquema baseado em o que ou se ouvem. O material está no 
formulário das cláusulas interrogativas que são usadas inquirir 
para as preferências das pessoas diferentes. Os estudantes não
vêem sentenças completas mas um esquema do uncomplete e o retrato de
falar dos povos 6-8. Estalando nas pessoas o estudante ouve uma 
pergunta que caiba somente dentro em uma linha no esquema. Os 
campos no esquema respondem a cada clique trocando o texto no campo e 
fazendo isto o estudante constrói as linhas com as perguntas ele ou 
ouve-se. Um clique no "controle" faz com que o programa examine 
o exercício. As sentenças que o estudante construiu acima da 
vontade sejam ouvidas faladas e são também visíveis na tela.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo oggetto imparante dimostra un modo 
molto-parteggiato insegnare l'allievo afferrare le informazioni 
strutturali nella lingua di arrivo. L'oggetto imparante 
egualmente dimostra come la nuova tecnologia può avere effetto su 
sulle tasse scolastiche tradizionali di grammatica. L'allievo 
svilupperà lo schema basato su che cosa lui o lei si sente. Il 
materiale è sotto forma di le clausole interrogative che sono usate 
per domandare per le preferenze delle persone differenti. Gli 
allievi non vedono le frasi complete ma uno schema del uncomplete e 
l'immagine di comunicazione della gente 6-8. Scattandosi sulle 
persone l'allievo sente una domanda che si adattare soltanto dentro su
una riga nello schema. I campi nello schema rispondono ad ogni 
scatto scambiando il testo nel campo e facendo questo l'allievo 
sviluppa le righe con le domande lui o si sente. Uno scatto "su 
controllo" induce il programma ad esaminare l'esercitazione. Le 
frasi che l'allievo si è accumulato saranno sentite parlate e sono 
egualmente visibili sullo schermo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης καταδεικνύει έναν 
πολύπλευρο τρόπο να διδαχθεί ο σπουδαστής για να πιάσει τις 
δομικές πληροφορίες στη γλώσσα στόχο. Το αντικείμενο 
εκμάθησης καταδεικνύει επίσης πώς η νέα τεχνολογία μπορεί να 
επηρεάσει στην παραδοσιακή εκπαίδευση γραμματικής. Ο 
σπουδαστής θα χτίσει το σχέδιο βασισμένο σε αυτό που ακούει. 
Το υλικό είναι υπό μορφή ερωτηματικών προτάσεων που 
χρησιμοποιούνται για να ερευνήσουν για τις προτιμήσεις των 
διαφορετικών προσώπων. Οι σπουδαστές δεν βλέπουνε τις 
πλήρεις προτάσεις αλλά ένα σχέδιο uncomplete και την εικόνα 
της ομιλίας ανθρώπων 6-8. Με τον κρότο στα πρόσωπα ο 
σπουδαστής ακούει μια ερώτηση που ταιριάζει μόνο σε μια γραμμή 
στο σχέδιο. Τα πεδία στο σχέδιο αποκρίνονται σε κάθε 
στιγμιαίο πάτημα με την ανταλλαγή του κειμένου στο πεδίο και με 
να κάνει αυτό ο σπουδαστής χτίζει τις γραμμές με τις ερωτήσεις 
που ακούει. Ένα στιγμιαίο πάτημα "στον έλεγχο" προκαλεί το
πρόγραμμα για να εξεταστεί η άσκηση. Οι προτάσεις που ο 
σπουδαστής έχει ενισχύσει θα ακουστούν προφορικός και είναι 
επίσης ορατές στην οθόνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este objeto que aprende demuestra una manera 
mucho-echada a un lado de enseñar al estudiante a agarrar la 
información estructural en la lengua objetivo. El objeto que 
aprende también demuestra cómo la nueva tecnología puede afectar la
cuota tradicional de la gramática. El estudiante construirá el
esquema basado en lo que él o ella oye. El material está en la
forma de cláusulas interrogativas que se utilicen para investigar 
para las preferencias de las diversas personas. Los estudiantes 
no ven sentencias completas sino un esquema del uncomplete y el cuadro
de hablar de las personas 6-8. Haciendo clic en las personas el 
estudiante oye una pregunta que quepa solamente adentro en una línea 
en el esquema. Los campos en el esquema responden a cada tecleo 
intercambiando el texto en el campo y haciendo esto el estudiante 
construye las líneas con las preguntas él o ella oye. Un 
tecleo en "control" hace el programa examinar el ejercicio. Las 
sentencias que el estudiante se ha acumulado serán oídas habladas y 
son también visibles en la pantalla.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3977</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-11</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="sv">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An exercise about the English language elementary clause structure and word order.</string>
            <string language="sv">Övning av engelskans elementära satsstruktur samt av ordföljden</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82763</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/audio_grammar_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
