<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82400</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82400</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1757</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">Priorità bassa comune</string>
            <string language="en">Common background</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geläufiger Hintergrund</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fond commun</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fundo comum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινό υπόβαθρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fondo común</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">L'allievo ascolta le descrizioni di otto diverse persone dove viene fornito un ricco lessico sulle informazioni personali (es. età, nazionalità, città natale, hobby). Dopo avere ascoltato le descrizioni, l'allievo deve accoppiare i personaggi alle descrizioni fornite. Diversi personaggi possono avere mólto  in comune, ma l'idea è trovare abbastanza caratteristiche comuni in modo da poterle scindere in quattro serie di accoppiamenti. Oltre che esercitazione pratica di lessico e attività di comprensione orale, L'allievo deve essere in grado di prendere  decisioni ed applicare le informazioni per completare l'esercitazione.</string>
            <string language="en">The learner hears the descriptions of eight different people where a lot of vocabulary related to personal information is given (e.g., age, nationality, home town, hobbies).  After listening to the descriptions, the learner has to pair up the characters based on these descriptions.  Several characters may have a lot in common, but the idea is to find enough common features so that they can be split up into four sets of pairs.  In addition to vocabulary practice and listening comprehension, the learner has to be able to make decisions and apply information in order to complete the exercise.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Anfänger hört die Beschreibungen von acht 
unterschiedlichen Leuten, in denen eine Menge Wortschatz in Verbindung
gestanden auf persönlichen Informationen gegeben wird (z.B., Alter, 
Nationalität, Heimatstadt, Liebhabereien). Nachdem er zu den 
Beschreibungen gehört hat, muß der Anfänger herauf die Zeichen 
zusammenpassen, die auf diesen Beschreibungen basieren. Einige 
Zeichen können im Common viel haben, aber die Idee ist, genügende 
geläufigen Merkmale zu finden, damit sie oben in vier einsetzen Paare
aufgespaltet werden können. Zusätzlich zur Wortschatzpraxis 
und zu hörendem Erfassen muß der Anfänger können, Entscheidungen 
zu treffen und Informationen anzuwenden, um die Übung durchzuführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant entend les descriptions de huit 
personnes différentes où beaucoup de vocabulaire lié à 
l'information personnelle est indiqué (par exemple, âge, 
nationalité, ville natale, passe-temps). Après avoir écouté 
les descriptions, l'étudiant doit appareiller vers le haut des 
caractères basés sur ces descriptions. Plusieurs caractères 
peuvent avoir beaucoup en commun, mais l'idée est de trouver assez de
dispositifs communs de sorte qu'ils puissent être fractionnés dans 
quatre ensembles de paires. En plus de pratique en matière de 
vocabulaire et de compréhension d'écoute, l'étudiant doit pouvoir 
prendre des décisions et appliquer l'information afin de terminer 
l'exercice.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O learner ouve as descrições de oito povos 
diferentes onde os muitos do vocabulário relacionados à informação
pessoal são dados (por exemplo, idade, nacionalidade, a cidade home, 
os passatempos). Após escutar as descrições, o learner tem 
que emparelhar-se acima dos caráteres baseados nestas descrições. 
Diversos caráteres podem ter muito na terra comum, mas a idéia
é encontrar bastante características comuns de modo que possam ser 
rachadas acima em quatro jogos dos pares. Além à prática do 
vocabulário e à compreensão escutando, o learner tem que poder  
fazer decisões e aplicar a informação a fim terminar o exercício.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αρχάριος ακούει τις περιγραφές οκτώ διαφορετικών 
ανθρώπων όπου πολύ λεξιλόγιο σχετικό με τις προσωπικές 
πληροφορίες δίνεται (π.χ., ηλικία, υπηκοότητα, βασική πόλη, 
χόμπι). Μετά από να ακούσει τις περιγραφές, ο αρχάριος 
πρέπει να ζευγαρώσει επάνω τους χαρακτήρες βασισμένους σε αυτές 
τις περιγραφές. Διάφοροι χαρακτήρες μπορούν να έχουν πολύ 
από κοινού, αλλά η ιδέα είναι να βρεθούν αρκετά κοινά 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα έτσι ώστε μπορούν να χωριστούν σε 
τέσσερα σύνολα ζευγαριών. Εκτός από την πρακτική 
λεξιλογίου και την κατανόηση ακούσματος, ο αρχάριος πρέπει να 
είναι σε θέση να λάβει τις αποφάσεις και να εφαρμόσει τις 
πληροφορίες προκειμένου να ολοκληρωθεί η άσκηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El principiante oye las descripciones de ocho 
diversas personas donde los muchos de vocabulario relacionados con la 
información personal se dan (e.g., edad, nacionalidad, la ciudad 
natal, las manías). Después de escuchar las descripciones, el 
principiante tiene que emparejar encima de los caracteres basados en 
estas descripciones. Varios caracteres pueden tener mucho en 
campo común, pero la idea es encontrar bastantes características 
comunes para poderlas dividirse en cuatro conjuntos de pares. 
Además de práctica del vocabulario y de comprensión que 
escucha, el principiante tiene que poder tomar decisiones y aplicar la
información para terminar el ejercicio.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1757</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-U</string>
            <string language="en">&gt; 9</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Esercitazione di comprensione orale; lessico relativo alle informazioni personali (biodati); pratica di presa di decisioni</string>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension practice; vocabulary related to personal information (biodata); practices decision-making</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82400</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>audio/basic</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/common_background_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
