<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223051</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223051</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio4/index.htm</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio4/index.htm</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio4/index.htm</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Electric systems and the electrical connections of HEPAC devices</string>
            <string language="fi">Sähköjärjestelmät ja LVI-teknisten laitteiden sähkökytkennät</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elektrische Systeme und die elektrischen 
Anschlüsse der HEPAC Einheiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Systèmes électriques et les connexions 
électriques des dispositifs de HEPAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sistemas elétricos e as conexões elétricas de 
dispositivos de HEPAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sistemi elettrici ed i collegamenti elettrici dei 
dispositivi di HEPAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηλεκτρικά συστήματα και οι ηλεκτρικές συνδέσεις των 
συσκευών HEPAC</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sistemas eléctricos y las conexiones eléctricas 
de los dispositivos de HEPAC</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Electric systems and the electrical connections of HEPAC devices learning object describes the progress of electricity entering a detached house starting from power plants and ending in applications in houses and the connections of these. The material can be used to study a general electricity supply system and an electricity supply system in a detached house. The material contains tasks related to the subject and links. The house technology web learning material is suitable both as support for contact teaching and for independent web study.</string>
            <string language="fi">Sähköjärjestelmät ja LVI-teknisten laitteiden sähkökytkennät -oppimisaihio kuvaa pientaloon tulevan sähkön kulun alkaen voimalaitoksilta ja päätyen talokohtaisiin käyttökohteisiin sekä niiden kytkentöihin. Aineiston avulla voidaan tutkia yleistä sähkönjakelujärjestelmää ja pientalon sähkönjakelujärjestelmää. Materiaali sisältää aiheeseen liittyviä tehtäviä sekä linkkejä. Talotekniikan verkko-oppimateriaali sopii sekä lähiopetuksen tueksi että itsenäiseen
verkko-opiskeluun. Materiaalissa on käytössä selaimen Flash -laajennus</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die elektrischen Systeme und die elektrischen 
Anschlüsse der HEPAC Einheiten, die Nachricht erlernen, beschreibt 
den Fortschritt von Elektrizität ein abgetrenntes Haus betretend, das
von den Kraftwerken beginnt und in den Anwendungen in den Häusern 
beendet und von diesen das Anschluß. Das Material kann benutzt 
werden, um ein allgemeines Elektrizität Zubehörsystem und ein 
Elektrizität Zubehörsystem in einem abgetrennten Haus zu studieren. 
Das Material enthält die Aufgaben, die auf dem Thema und den 
Links in Verbindung gestanden werden. Das erlernenmaterial des 
Haustechnologiewebs ist beide als Support für Kontaktunterricht und 
für unabhängige Web-Studie verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les systèmes électriques et les connexions 
électriques des dispositifs de HEPAC apprenant l'objet décrit le 
progrès de l'électricité entrant dans une maison isolée à partir 
des centrales et terminant dans les applications dans les maisons et 
le connexion de ces derniers. Le matériel peut être employé 
pour étudier un circuit d'alimentation général de l'électricité 
et un circuit d'alimentation de l'électricité dans une maison 
isolée. Le matériel contient charge connexe au sujet 
et aux liens. Le matériel d'étude de Web de technologie de 
maison convient tous les deux en tant que soutien pour l'enseignement 
de contact et d'étude indépendante de Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os sistemas elétricos e as conexões elétricas 
dos dispositivos de HEPAC que aprendem o objeto descrevem o progresso 
da eletricidade que entra em uma casa destacada que começa das 
plantas de potência e que termina nas aplicações nas casas e o 
conexão destes. O material pode ser usado estudar um sistema de
fonte geral da eletricidade e um sistema de fonte da eletricidade em 
uma casa destacada. O material contem as tarefas relacionadas ao
assunto e às ligações. O material de aprendizagem do Web da 
tecnologia da casa é apropriado ambos como a sustentação para o 
ensino do contato e para o estudo independente do Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I sistemi elettrici ed i collegamenti elettrici 
dei dispositivi di HEPAC che imparano l'oggetto descrive il progresso 
di elettricità che entra in una casa detached a partire dalle 
centrali elettriche e che si conclude nelle applicazioni nelle case ed
il collegamento di questi. Il materiale può essere usato per 
studiare un sistema di rifornimento generale di elettricità e un 
sistema di rifornimento di elettricità in una casa detached. Il
materiale contiene le mansioni relative all'oggetto ed ai 
collegamenti. Il materiale imparante di Web di tecnologia della 
casa è adatto entrambi come sostegno per insegnamento del contatto e 
lo studio indipendente di Web.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα ηλεκτρικά συστήματα και οι ηλεκτρικές συνδέσεις των
συσκευών HEPAC που μαθαίνουν το αντικείμενο περιγράφουν την 
πρόοδο της ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας που μπαίνει σε ένα αποσυνδεμένο 
σπίτι που αρχίζουν από τις εγκαταστάσεις παραγωγής ενέργειας και
που τελειώνουν στις εφαρμογές στα σπίτια και τις συνδέσεις αυτοί.
Το υλικό μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να μελετήσει ένα 
γενικό σύστημα ανεφοδιασμού ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας και ένα 
σύστημα ανεφοδιασμού ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας σε ένα αποσυνδεμένο 
σπίτι. Το υλικό περιέχει τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες 
σχετικές με το θέμα και τις συνδέσεις. Το υλικό εκμάθησης 
Ιστού τεχνολογίας σπιτιών είναι κατάλληλο και οι δύο ως 
υποστήριξη για τη διδασκαλία επαφών και για την ανεξάρτητη μελέτη
Ιστού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los sistemas eléctricos y las conexiones 
eléctricas de los dispositivos de HEPAC que aprenden el objeto 
describen el progreso de la electricidad que entra en una casa 
separada que comienza de las centrales eléctricas y que termina en 
aplicaciones en casas y la conexión de éstos. El material se 
puede utilizar para estudiar un sistema de fuente general de la 
electricidad y un sistema de fuente de la electricidad en una casa 
separada. El material contiene las tareas relacionadas con el 
tema y las conexiones. El material que aprende del Web de la 
tecnología de la casa es conveniente ambos como ayuda para la 
enseñanza del contacto y para el estudio independiente del Web.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7935662B-EBF6-6C66-199B-6B574079B8AC</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7935662B-EBF6-6C66-199B-6B574079B8AC</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ilkka Mäkitalo
n:Mäkitalo;Ilkka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:02.49Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>demonstration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>160</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1289</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>161</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio4/index.htm</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio4/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
