<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222859</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222859</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,1329,1528,21094,19155,57897</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,1329,1528,21094,19155,57897</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,1329,1528,21094,19155,57897</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Athletics</string>
            <string language="fi">Yleisurheilu</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Athletik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Athlétisme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Athletics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Atletismo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αθλητισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Atletismo</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Athletics consist of sports based on walking, running, jumping and throwing. Exercises created in the past few years, stemming from the core areas of the sport and child development to children’s equipment and rules with various applications, make athletics a fun and easy sport to teach and learn while taking account of versatile sporting skills. The website aims to give the teacher a picture of athletics among today’s children and young people, while providing tips and lesson models for physical education in schools. The website contains instructions for teachers, descriptions of equipment required in various sports and different sporting environments, and guidelines for each age group as well as exercise tips to develop the necessary skills required in athletics.</string>
            <string language="fi">Yleisurheilu koostuu lajeista, joiden perusta on kävelemisessä, juoksemisessa, hyppäämisessä ja heittämisessä. Viime vuosina luodut lajin ydinkohdista ja lapsen kehityksestä lähtevät harjoitteet sekä lasten välineistö ja säännöt eri sovelluksineen tekevät yleisurheilusta monipuoliset liikuntataidot huomioivan, hauskan mutta myös helpon lajin opettaa ja oppia. Verkkosivustolla pyritään antamaan opettajalle kuva nykypäivän lasten ja nuorten yleisurheilusta sekä vinkkejä ja tuntimalleja koulun liikuntatunneille. Sivusto sisältää ohjeita opettajalle, kuvauksia eri lajeissa ja erilaisissa urheiluympäristöissä tarvittavista välineistä sekä vuosiluokittain jäsennettyjä ohjeita yleisurheilussa tarvittavien taitojen kehittämiseksi ja harjoitusvinkkejä.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Athletik besteht aus dem Sport, der auf dem Gehen,
dem Laufen, dem Springen und dem Werfen basiert. Die Übungen, 
die in den letzten Jahren, die Kernbereiche des Sports und der 
Kindentwicklung zu den children?s Ausrüstung und die Richtlinien 
abstammend mit verschiedenen Anwendungen erstellt werden, lassen 
Athletik einen Spaß und einen einfachen Sport beim Berücksichtigen 
der vielseitigen begabt sporting Fähigkeiten unterrichten und 
erlernen. Die Web site zielt darauf ab, dem Lehrer eine 
Abbildung von Athletik unter today?s Kindern und jungen Leuten zu 
geben, beim Zur Verfügung stellen von von Spitzen und von von 
Lektionmodellen für Leibeserziehung in den Schulen. Die Web 
site enthält Anweisungen für Lehrer, die Beschreibungen der 
Ausrüstung benötigt im verschiedenen Sport und in den 
unterschiedlichen sporting Umgebungen und die Korrekturlinien für 
jede Altersklasse, sowie Übung neigt, um die notwendigen Fähigkeiten
zu entwickeln, die in der Athletik benötigt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'athlétisme se composent des sports basés sur 
marcher, exécuter, brancher et jeter. Les exercices créés en 
dernières années, provenant des domaines de noyau du sport et du 
développement d'enfant aux children?s matériel et des règles avec 
de diverses applications, font à athlétisme un amusement et un sport
facile pour enseigner et apprendre tout en tenant compte des 
qualifications sportives souples. Le site Web vise à donner au 
professeur une image de l'athlétisme parmi des enfants de today?s et 
des jeunes, tout en fournissant des extrémités et des modèles de 
leçon pour l'éducation physique dans les écoles. Le site Web 
contient des instructions pour des professeurs, des descriptions de 
matériel exigées dans divers sports et différents environnements 
sportifs, et des directives pour chaque catégorie d'âge comme 
l'exercice incline pour développer les qualifications nécessaires 
exigées en athlétisme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O athletics consiste nos esportes baseados em 
andar, em funcionar, em saltar e em jogar. Os exercícios 
criados no passado poucos anos, stemming das áreas do núcleo do 
esporte e do desenvolvimento da criança aos children?s equipamento e 
das réguas com as várias aplicações, fazem a athletics um 
divertimento e um esporte fácil para ensinar e aprender ao fazer 
exame do cliente de habilidades ostentando versáteis. O Web 
site aponta dar ao professor um retrato do athletics entre crianças 
dos today?s e povos novos, ao fornecer pontas e modelos da lição 
para a instrução física nas escolas. O Web site contem 
instruções para professores, descrições do equipamento requeridas 
em vários esportes e em ambientes ostentando diferentes, e guidelines
para cada grupo de idade assim como o exercício derruba para 
desenvolver as habilidades necessárias requeridas no athletics.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'atletismo consiste degli sport basati sul 
camminare, sul funzionare, sul salto e sul gettare. Le 
esercitazioni create nel passato pochi anni, provenenti dalle zone di 
nucleo dello sport e dello sviluppo del bambino ai children?s 
apparecchiatura e dalle regole con le varie applicazioni, rendono 
all'atletismo un divertimento e uno sport facile per insegnare ed 
imparare mentre tengono conto delle abilità di sport versatili. 
Il Web site mira a dare all'insegnante un'immagine 
dell'atletismo fra i bambini dei today?s ed i giovani, mentre fornisce
le punte ed i modelli di lezione per la formazione fisica in scuole. 
Il Web site contiene le istruzioni per gli insegnanti, le 
descrizioni di apparecchiatura richieste in vari sport ed ambienti di 
sport differenti e la guida di riferimento per ogni gruppo d'età come
pure l'esercitazione si capovolge per sviluppare le abilità 
necessarie richieste in atletismo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αθλητισμός αποτελείται από τον αθλητισμό βασισμένο 
στο περπάτημα, το τρέξιμο, το άλμα και τη ρίψη. Οι ασκήσεις
που δημιουργούνται στο παρελθόν λίγα έτη, που προέρχονται από 
τους τομείς πυρήνων της ανάπτυξης αθλητισμού και παιδιών στον 
εξοπλισμό children?s και τους κανόνες με διάφορες εφαρμογές, 
κάνουν τον αθλητισμό μια διασκέδαση και έναν εύκολο αθλητισμό 
για να διδάξουν και να μάθουν λαμβάνοντας υπόψη τις 
ευπροσάρμοστες αθλητικές δεξιότητες. Ο ιστοχώρος στοχεύει 
να δώσει στο δάσκαλο μια εικόνα του αθλητισμού μεταξύ των 
παιδιών today?s και των νέων, παρέχοντας τις άκρες και τα 
μοντέλα μαθήματος για τη φυσική αγωγή στα σχολεία. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις εντολές για τους δασκάλους, τις περιγραφές
του εξοπλισμού που απαιτούνται στο διάφορο αθλητισμό και τα 
διαφορετικά αθλητικά περιβάλλοντα, και τις οδηγίες για τις άκρες 
κάθε ομάδας ηλικίας καθώς επίσης και άσκησης για να αναπτύξουν 
τις απαραίτητες δεξιότητες που απαιτούνται στον αθλητισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El atletismo consiste en los deportes basados en 
recorrer, ejecutarse, saltar y lanzar. Los ejercicios creados en
el pasado pocos años, proviniendo las áreas de la base del deporte y
del desarrollo del niño a los children?s equipo y las reglas con 
varias aplicaciones, hacen atletismo una diversión y un deporte 
fácil para enseñar y para aprender mientras que toman cuenta de 
habilidades que se divierten versátiles. El Web site apunta dar
al profesor un cuadro del atletismo entre niños de los today?s y la 
gente joven, mientras que proporciona a extremidades y a los modelos 
de la lección para la educación física en escuelas. El Web 
site contiene las instrucciones para los profesores, las descripciones
del equipo requeridas en varios deportes y diversos ambientes que se 
divierten, y las guías de consulta para cada categoría de edad tan 
bien como el ejercicio inclina para desarrollar las habilidades 
necesarias requeridas en atletismo.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen Urheiluliitto
n:Suomen Urheiluliitto
org:Suomen Urheiluliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A9134D7C-AE57-B804-8A41-E94AD94C6324</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A9134D7C-AE57-B804-8A41-E94AD94C6324</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:44:14.80Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,507,19640</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>107</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>974</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,1329,1528,21094,19155,57897</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,1329,1528,21094,19155,57897</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
