<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235301</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235301</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/koripallo</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/koripallo</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/koripallo</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Basketball</string>
            <string language="fi">Koripallo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Basketball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Basket-ball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Basketball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pallacanestro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καλαθοσφαίριση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Baloncesto</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Basketball offers an excellent opportunity for physical education to practise team play and being a part of a group. The purpose of the website is to provide quick and efficient support for the teacher to plan and implement the content of lessons. The website presents the equipment required in basketball and the rules of the game. It also provides instructions outlined by age group, as well as tips for various practices and forms of the game, with the purpose of helping the teacher to choose appropriate teaching content.</string>
            <string language="fi">Koripallo tarjoaa koululiikuntaan mainion mahdollisuuden harjoitella joukkuepelaamista ja ryhmässä toimimista. Verkkosivuston tarkoituksena on, että opettaja löytäisi nopeasti ja tehokkaasti tuen oppituntiensa sisällön suunnitteluun ja toteutukseen. Sivustolla esitellään koripallossa tarvittavat välineet ja lajin säännöt, sekä annetaan vuosiluokittain jäsennettyjä ohjeita ja vinkkejä erilaisiin harjoituksiin ja pelimuotoihin, joiden tarkoituksena on auttaa opettajaa tarkoituksenmukaisten opetussisältöjen valitsemisessa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Basketball bietet eine ausgezeichnete Gelegenheit 
an, damit Leibeserziehung Teamspiel und Sein ein Teil einer Gruppe 
übt. Der Zweck der Web site ist, schnelle und leistungsfähige 
Unterstützung für den Lehrer zu geben, zum des Inhalts von Lektionen
zu planen und einzuführen. Die Web site stellt die Ausrüstung 
dar, die im Basketball und in den Richtlinien des Spiels benötigt 
wird. Sie liefert auch die Anweisungen, die von der Altersklasse
umrissen werden, sowie neigt für verschiedene Praxis und Formulare 
des Spiels, mit dem Zweck des Helfens des Lehrers, passenden 
unterrichtenden Inhalt zu wählen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le basket-ball procure une excellente occasion à 
l'éducation physique de pratiquer le jeu d'équipe et être une 
partie d'un groupe. Le but du site Web est de fournir le support
rapide et efficace pour le professeur pour projeter et mettre en 
application la teneur des leçons. Le site Web présente le 
matériel exigé dans le basket-ball et les règles du jeu. Il 
fournit également des instructions tracées les grandes lignes par la
catégorie d'âge, comme incline pour différentes pratiques et formes
du jeu, en vue d'aider le professeur à choisir le contenu 
d'enseignement approprié.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O basketball oferece uma oportunidade excelente 
para que a instrução física pratique o jogo da equipe e ser uma 
parte de um grupo. A finalidade do Web site é fornecer a 
sustentação rápida e eficiente para o professor para planear e 
executar o índice das lições. O Web site apresenta o 
equipamento requerido no basketball e nas réguas do jogo. 
Fornece também as instruções esboçadas pelo grupo de idade, 
assim como derruba para vários práticas e formulários do jogo, com 
a finalidade de ajudar o professor escolher o índice ensinando 
apropriado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La pallacanestro offre un'opportunità eccellente 
affinchè la formazione fisica si eserciti nel gioco della squadra e 
nell'essere una parte di un gruppo. Lo scopo del Web site è 
fornire il supporto rapido ed efficiente per l'insegnante per 
progettare ed effettuare il contenuto delle lezioni. Il Web site
presenta l'apparecchiatura richiesta nella pallacanestro e nelle 
regole del gioco. Egualmente fornisce le istruzioni descritte 
dal gruppo d'età, come pure si capovolge per varie pratiche e forme 
del gioco, allo scopo di l'assistenza dell'insegnante scegliere il 
soddisfare d'istruzione adatto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η καλαθοσφαίριση προσφέρει μια άριστη ευκαιρία για τη 
φυσική αγωγή στο παιχνίδι και την ύπαρξη ομάδων πρακτικής ένα 
μέρος μιας ομάδας. Ο σκοπός του ιστοχώρου είναι να 
παρασχεθεί η γρήγορη και αποδοτική υποστήριξη για το δάσκαλο για 
να προγραμματίσει και να εφαρμόσει το περιεχόμενο των μαθημάτων. 
Ο ιστοχώρος παρουσιάζει τον εξοπλισμό που απαιτείται στην 
καλαθοσφαίριση και τους κανόνες του παιχνιδιού. Παρέχει 
επίσης τις οδηγίες που περιγράφονται κατά ομάδα ηλικίας, καθώς 
επίσης και τις άκρες για τις διάφορες πρακτικές και τις μορφές 
του παιχνιδιού, με σκοπό τη βοήθεια του δασκάλου για να επιλεχτεί
το κατάλληλο περιεχόμενο διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El baloncesto ofrece una oportunidad excelente 
para que la educación física practique el juego del equipo y ser una
parte de un grupo. El propósito del Web site es proporcionar a 
la ayuda rápida y eficiente para el profesor para planear y para 
poner el contenido en ejecucio'n de lecciones. El Web site 
presenta el equipo requerido en baloncesto y las reglas del juego. 
También proporciona a las instrucciones contorneadas por la 
categoría de edad, tan bien como inclina para las varias prácticas y
formas del juego, con el propósito de ayudar al profesor a elegir el 
contenido de enseñanza apropiado.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen Koripalloliitto
n:Suomen Koripalloliitto
org:Suomen Koripalloliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/4DC61F08-AFDE-20F9-A9DA-4BF697DD78DF</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/4DC61F08-AFDE-20F9-A9DA-4BF697DD78DF</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:35:53.25Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/prime102.aspx</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>987</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1285</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>974</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/koripallo</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/perusopetus/liikunta/opetusmateriaalit_eri_lajeista/koripallo</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
