<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223027</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223027</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www2.edu.fi//oikeinkirjoitus</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www2.edu.fi//oikeinkirjoitus</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www2.edu.fi//oikeinkirjoitus</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pidä suomi siistinä (Keep your Finnish pure)</string>
            <string language="fi">Pidä suomi siistinä</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pidä suomi siistinä (halten Sie Ihr finnisches 
reines)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Siistinä de suomi de Pidä (gardez votre pur 
finlandais)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Siistinä do suomi de Pidä (mantenha seu puro 
finnish)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Siistinä di suomi di Pidä (mantenga il vostro 
puro finlandese)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Siistinδ suomi Pidδ (κρατήστε φινλανδικό 
καθαρό σας)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Siistinä del suomi de Pidä (guarde su puro 
finlandés)</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">“Keep your Finnish pure” contains exercises to help pupils improve their Finnish spelling. There are three theme areas: initial letters, compound words and punctuation. First the pupils do an initial test and according to the points from that they are guided to do tasks suitable for their level. There are three levels of difficulty, and tips are provided for doing some of the tasks. There is no need to register for the service, but the advantage with registering is that the tasks can be continued from where the pupil was left on the previous occasion, and the completed levels and certificates are stored in the language school’s archives</string>
            <string language="fi">Pidä suomi siistinä sisältää harjoituksia, jotka auttavat oppilasta parantamaan suomen kielen oikeinkirjoitustaan. Aihealueita on kolme: alkukirjaimet, yhdyssanat ja välimerkit. Ensiksi oppilas tekee alkutestin, jonka pistemäärän mukaan hänet ohjataan tekemään tasolleen sopivia tehtäviä. Vaikeustasoja on kolme, ja joidenkin tehtävien tekemiseen on tarjolla vinkkejä. Palveluun ei ole pakko rekisteröityä, mutta rekisteröitymisestä on se etu, että tehtäviä voi jatkaa siitä, mihin on edellisellä kerralla jäänyt, ja suoritetut tasot ja diplomit jäävät kielikoulun arkistoon</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">?Keep Ihr finnisches reines? enthält 
Übungen, um Pupillen zu helfen, ihre finnische Rechtschreibung zu 
verbessern. Es gibt drei Themabereiche: Ausgangszeichen, 
zusammengesetzte Wörter und Interpunktion. Zuerst führen die 
Pupillen einen Ausgangstest durch und entsprechend den Punkten von dem
werden sie geführt, um die Aufgaben zu tun, die für ihre Stufe 
verwendbar sind. Es gibt drei Stufen Schwierigkeit, und Spitzen 
werden für das Tun einige der Aufgaben zur Verfügung gestellt. 
Es gibt keine Notwendigkeit, für den Service zu registrieren, 
aber der Vorteil mit dem Registrieren ist, daß die Aufgaben 
fortgesetzt werden können von, wo die Pupille bei der vorhergehenden 
Gelegenheit gelassen wurde, und die abgeschlossenen Stufen und die 
Bescheinigungen werden in den Sprachenschool?s Archiven gespeichert</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">?Keep votre pur finlandais ? contient des 
exercices pour aider des pupilles à améliorer leur épellation 
finlandaise. Il y a trois zones de thème : lettres 
initiales, mots composés et ponctuation. D'abord les pupilles 
font un premier essai et selon les points de cela qu'elles sont 
guidées pour faire charge approprié à leur niveau. 
Il y a trois niveaux de difficulté, et des extrémités sont 
données pour faire une partie de charge. Il n'y a 
aucun besoin de s'inscrire au service, mais l'avantage avec 
l'enregistrement est que charge peut être continué d'où la
pupille a été laissée sur l'occasion précédente, et les niveaux 
et les certificats réalisés sont enregistrés dans les archives de 
school?s de langage</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">?Keep seu puro finnish? contem exercícios 
para ajudar às pupilas melhorar sua soletração finnish. Há 
três áreas do tema: letras iniciais, palavras compostas e 
pontuação. Primeiramente as pupilas fazem um teste inicial e 
de acordo com os pontos disso são guiadas para fazer as tarefas 
apropriadas para seu nível. Há três níveis da dificuldade, e
as pontas são fornecidas fazendo algumas das tarefas. Não há 
nenhuma necessidade registar para o serviço, mas a vantagem com 
registar é que as tarefas podem ser continuadas de onde a pupila foi 
deixada na ocasião precedente, e os níveis e os certificados 
terminados são armazenados nos arquivos dos school?s da língua</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">?Keep il vostro puro finlandese? contiene 
le esercitazioni per aiutare le pupille a migliorare la loro 
ortografia finlandese. Ci sono tre zone di tema: lettere 
iniziali, parole composte e punteggiatura. In primo luogo le 
pupille effettuano una prova iniziale e secondo i punti da quello sono
guidate per fare le mansioni adatte a loro livello. Ci sono tre 
livelli della difficoltà e le punte sono fornite per fare alcune 
delle mansioni. Non ci è necessità di registrare per il 
servizio, ma il vantaggio con il registro è che le mansioni possono 
essere continuate da dove la pupilla è stata lasciata nell'occasione 
precedente ed i livelli ed i certificati completati sono memorizzati 
negli archivi degli school?s di linguaggio</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">?Keep τα φιλανδικά σας καθαρά; περιέχει τις 
ασκήσεις για να βοηθήσει τους μαθητές να βελτιώσουν τη φινλανδική
ορθογραφία τους. Υπάρχουν τρεις περιοχές θέματος: 
αρχικές επιστολές, σύνθετες λέξεις και στίξη. Πρώτα 
οι μαθητές κάνουν μια αρχική δοκιμή και σύμφωνα με τα σημεία 
από αυτό καθοδηγούνται για να κάνουν τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες 
κατάλληλες για το επίπεδό τους. Υπάρχουν τρία επίπεδα 
δυσκολίας, και οι άκρες παρέχονται για να κάνουν μερικών από τις
στοιχειώδεις εργασίες. Δεν υπάρχει καμία ανάγκη να 
καταχωρήσει για την υπηρεσία, αλλά το πλεονέκτημα με την 
καταχώρηση είναι ότι οι στοιχειώδεις εργασίες μπορούν να 
συνεχιστούν από όπου ο μαθητής αφέθηκε στην προηγούμενη 
περίπτωση, και τα ολοκληρωμένα επίπεδα και τα πιστοποιητικά 
καταχωρούνται στα γλωσσικά school?s αρχεία</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿?Keep su puro finlandés? contiene 
ejercicios para ayudar a pupilas a mejorar su deletreo finlandés. 
Hay tres áreas del tema: cartas iniciales, palabras 
compuestas y puntuación. Primero las pupilas hacen una prueba 
inicial y según las puntas de eso se dirigen para hacer las tareas 
convenientes para su nivel. Hay tres niveles de dificultad, y 
las extremidades se proporcionan para hacer algunas de las tareas. 
No hay necesidad de colocarse para el servicio, pero la ventaja 
con la colocación es que las tareas pueden ser continuadas de donde 
la pupila fue dejada en la ocasión anterior, y los niveles y los 
certificados terminados se salvan en los archivos de los school?s del 
lenguaje</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Tiina Vuolteenaho
n:Vuolteenaho;Tiina
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Avence Oy
n:Avence Oy
org:Avence Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Heli Alku
n:Alku;Heli
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Kirsti Merta
n:Merta;Kirsti
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/2C185F64-D163-AF7D-7965-81866389AAE6</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/2C185F64-D163-AF7D-7965-81866389AAE6</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:25.48Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>assessment</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>493</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1051</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>845</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>556</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1018</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1410</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www2.edu.fi//oikeinkirjoitus</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www2.edu.fi//oikeinkirjoitus</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
