<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222699</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222699</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/fysiikka</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/fysiikka</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/fysiikka</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Upper secondary distance learning – Physics</string>
            <string language="fi">Etälukio - Fysiikka</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obersekundarabstand Lernen? Physik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude de distance secondaire deuxième cycle ? 
Physique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem de distância secundária superior? 
Física</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparare di distanza superiore-secondario? 
Fisica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια από απόσταση εκμάθηση; 
Φυσική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿El aprender de distancia superior-secundario? 
Física</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is the online material for the 1st course in physics in the upper secondary school.  The course is common to all, providing a basis for studying physics and natural sciences in general. The course does not replace the textbook, but supplements it. The objective has been to utilise the interactive ability of the online material, which is a great benefit of the online material compared to the material in textbooks. Interactivity in this course requires that the browser supports the Java, Flash and Shockwave technologies. The website contains flash animations, which open automatically in pop-up windows. To make the website work in the desired way, please allow pop-up windows in your browser.</string>
            <string language="fi">Tämä on lukion fysiikan 1. kurssin www-aineisto. Kurssi on kaikille yhteinen ja antaa pohjaa fysiikan ja yleensä luonnontieteiden opiskelulle. Kurssi ei korvaa oppikirjaa vaan täydentää sitä. Tavoitteena on ollut hyödyntää www-aineiston kykyä vuorovaikutteisuuteen, mikä on www-aineiston suuri etu verrattuna oppikirjan materiaaliin. Vuorovaikutteisuus tässä kurssissa edellyttää, että selaimessa on tuki
Java-, Flash- ja Shockwave-tekniikoille. Sivusto sisältää flash-animaatioita, jotka avautuvat automaattisesti ponnahdusikkunoihin. Jotta saat sivuston toimimaan toivotulla tavalla, salli ponnahdusikkunat selaimessasi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist das Onlinematerial für den 1. Kurs in
der Physik in der obersekundarschule. Der Kurs ist für alle 
geläufig und stellt eine Grundlage für das Studieren von von Physik 
und von von natürlichen Wissenschaften im allgemeinen zur Verfügung.
Der Kurs ersetzt nicht das Lehrbuch, aber ergänzt es. Das
Lernziel ist gewesen, die interaktive Fähigkeit des Onlinematerials 
zu verwenden, das ein großer Nutzen des Onlinematerials ist, das mit 
dem Material in den Lehrbüchern verglichen wird. Wechselwirkung
in diesem Kurs benötigt, daß die Datenbanksuchroutine die Java, 
Blitz- und Shockwavetechnologien unterstützt. Die Web site 
enthält grelle Animationen, die sich automatisch in den pop-up 
Fenstern öffnen. Um die Web site Arbeit in der gewünschten 
Methode zu bilden, erlauben Sie bitte pop-up Fenstern in Ihrer 
Datenbanksuchroutine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est le matériel en ligne pour le 1er cours de 
la physique dans l'école secondaire deuxième cycle. Le cours 
est commun à tous, fournissant une base pour étudier la physique et 
les sciences normales en général. Le cours ne substitue pas le
manuel, mais le complète. L'objectif a été d'utiliser les 
capacités interactives du matériel en ligne, qui est un grand 
avantage du matériel en ligne comparé au matériel en manuels. 
L'interactivité dans ce cours exige que le navigateur supporte 
les technologies de Java, d'instantané et d'onde de choc. Le 
site Web contient les animations instantanées, qui s'ouvrent 
automatiquement dans les fenêtres instantanées. Pour faire le 
travail de site Web de la voie désirée, permettez s'il vous plaît 
aux fenêtres instantanées dans votre navigateur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é o material em linha para o 1o curso na 
física na escola secundária superior. O curso é comum a tudo,
fornecendo uma base para estudar a física e ciências naturais no 
general. O curso não substitui o textbook, mas suplementa-o. 
O objetivo foi utilizar a abilidade interativa do material em 
linha, que é um benefício grande do material em linha comparado ao 
material nos textbooks. O interactivity neste curso requer que o
browser suporta as tecnologias de Java, de flash e de shockwave. 
O Web site contem os animations flash, que abrem automaticamente
em janelas pop-up. Façam o trabalho do Web site na maneira 
desejada, permita por favor que as janelas pop-up em seu browser.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è il materiale in linea per il primo corso 
nella fisica nella scuola superiore-secondaria. Il corso è 
comune a tutti, fornendo una base per studiare la fisica e le scienze 
naturali in generale. Il corso non sostituisce il manuale, ma lo
completa. L'obiettivo è stato utilizzare l'abilità interattiva
del materiale in linea, che è un notevole beneficio del materiale in 
linea confrontato al materiale in manuali. L'interattività in 
questo corso richiede che il browser sostiene le tecnologie del Java, 
dell'istantaneo e di shockwave. Il Web site contiene le 
animazioni istantanee, che si aprono automaticamente in finestre 
pop-up. Facciano il lavoro di Web site nel modo voluto, permetta
prego che le finestre pop-up in vostro browser.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι το σε απευθείας σύνδεση υλικό για τη 1$η 
σειρά μαθημάτων στη φυσική στην ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια 
εκπαίδευση. Η σειρά μαθημάτων είναι κοινή για όλους, που 
παρέχουν μια βάση για τη φυσική και τις φυσικές επιστήμες 
γενικά. Η σειρά μαθημάτων δεν αντικαθιστά το εγχειρίδιο, 
αλλά το συμπληρώνει. Ο στόχος ήταν να χρησιμοποιηθεί η 
διαλογική δυνατότητα του σε απευθείας σύνδεση υλικού, το οποίο 
είναι ένα μεγάλο όφελος του σε απευθείας σύνδεση υλικού έναντι
στο υλικό στα εγχειρίδια. Η αλληλεπίδραση σε αυτήν την 
σειρά μαθημάτων απαιτεί ότι ο ξεφυλλιστής υποστηρίζει τις 
τεχνολογίες της Ιάβας, λάμψης και shockwave. Ο ιστοχώρος 
περιέχει τις ζωτικότητες λάμψης, οι οποίες ανοίγουν αυτόματα στα
υπερεμφανιζόμενα Windows. Για να κάνετε την εργασία 
ιστοχώρου με τον επιθυμητό τρόπο, παρακαλώ επιτρέψτε στα 
υπερεμφανιζόμενα Windows στον ξεφυλλιστή σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Éste es el material en línea para el 1r curso 
en la física en la escuela superior-secundaria. El curso es 
común a todos, proporcionando a una base para estudiar la física y 
ciencias naturales en general. El curso no substituye el libro 
de textos, sino lo suple. El objetivo ha sido utilizar la 
capacidad interactiva del material en línea, que es una gran ventaja 
del material en línea comparado al material en libros de textos. 
La interactividad en este curso requiere que el browser utilice 
las tecnologías de Java, del flash y de la onda de choque. El 
Web site contiene las animaciones de destello, que se abren 
automáticamente en ventanas pop-up. Hagan el trabajo del Web 
site de la manera deseada, permita por favor que las ventanas pop-up 
en su browser.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Olavi Lappalainen
n:Lappalainen;Olavi
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Vesa Rantanen
n:Rantanen;Vesa
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/70511323-2499-64DD-1AC1-44CCA3FA12C5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/70511323-2499-64DD-1AC1-44CCA3FA12C5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:22.46Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/fysiikka/index.html</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>875</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>978</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/fysiikka</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/fysiikka</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
