<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223087</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223087</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Upper secondary distance learning – German</string>
            <string language="fi">Etälukio - saksa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obersekundarabstand Lernen? Deutsch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude de distance secondaire deuxième cycle ? 
Allemand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem de distância secundária superior? 
Alemão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparare di distanza superiore-secondario? 
Tedesco</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια από απόσταση εκμάθηση; 
Γερμανικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿El aprender de distancia superior-secundario? 
Alemán</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <language>de</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The online material for German language in upper secondary distance learning includes the course titles in accordance with the curriculum for upper secondary schools:  1. How do you do, nice to meet you; 2. This is how we do things; 3. Leisure time and hobbies; 4. At home and abroad; 5. Then and now. The subject matter of the content is described on the starting page of each course. The skills levels are entered in connection with the texts and exercises. The material includes plenty of sound files with instructions on the bottom of the page under ‘Instructions’. For progress in the studies, you can use course navigation on the right-hand side of the page, which contains the text and exercise pages of the open course. On the bottom of each page, there is a progress button which will take you to the next page in the subject content. You can also browse the content by using the site map on the main level. The site map shows the entire content of the German language site on the same page.</string>
            <string language="fi">Etälukion saksan verkkomateriaali sisältää lukion opetussuunnitelman mukaiset kurssinimikkeet:  1. Hyvää päivää, hauska tutustua; 2. Näin asiat hoituvat; 3. Vapaa-aika ja harrastukset; 4. Meillä ja muualla 
5. Ennen ja nyt. Kunkin kurssin aloitussivulla on kerrottu sisällön aihepiirit. Tekstien ja tehtävien yhteyteen on merkitty niiden taitotasot. Materiaaliin kuuluu runsaasti äänitiedostoja, joiden kuunteluohjeet löytyvät sivun alalaidan kohdasta Ohjeet. Opiskelun etenemiseen voit käyttää kurssinavigointia, joka sivun oikeassa laidassa sisältää avoinna olevan kurssin teksti- ja tehtäväsivut. Kunkin sivun alareunassa on etenemispainike, joka vie sinut asiasisällössä seuraavalle sivulle. Voit myös selata sisältöä käyttämällä päätason sivukarttaa, jossa näkyy kerralla koko saksan sivuston sisältö.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Onlinematerial für deutsche Sprache im 
obersekundarabstand Lernen schließt die Kursnamen in Übereinstimmung
mit dem Lehrplan für obersekundarschulen ein: 1. Wie, 
Sie, nett, Sie zu treffen; 2. Dieses ist, wie wir Sachen 
tun; 3. Freizeit und Liebhabereien; 4. Im In- 
und Ausland; 5. Dann und jetzt. Das Thema des 
Inhalts wird auf der beginnenden Seite jedes Kurses beschrieben. 
Die Fähigkeiten Stufen sind in Zusammenhang mit den Texten und 
den Übungen eingetragen. Das Material schließt viel der 
stichhaltigen Dateien mit Anweisungen in der Unterseite der Seite 
unter?Instructions? ein. Für Fortschritt in den Studien, 
können Sie Kursnavigation auf der rechten Seite der Seite verwenden, 
die die Text- und Übungsseiten des geöffneten Kurses enthält. 
Auf der Unterseite jeder Seite, gibt es eine Fortschritttaste, 
die Sie zur folgenden Seite im vorbehaltlichen Inhalt nimmt. Sie
können den Inhalt auch durchstöbern, indem Sie die Site-Karte auf 
der Hauptstufe verwenden. Die Site-Karte zeigt den gesamten 
Inhalt der deutschen Sprachensites auf der gleichen Seite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matériel en ligne pour la langue allemande 
dans l'étude de distance secondaire deuxième cycle inclut les titres
de cours selon le programme d'études pour les écoles secondaires 
deuxième cycle : 1. Comment  vous , gentil de vous 
rencontrer ; 2. C'est comment nous faisons des choses ; 
3. Temps libre et passe-temps ; 4. Ici et 
ailleurs ; 5. Puis et maintenant. Les thèmes du 
contenu sont décrits à la page commençante de chaque cours. 
Les niveaux de qualifications sont écrits en liaison avec les 
textes et les exercices. Le matériel inclut l'abondance des 
fichiers sains avec des instructions sur le bas de la page sous des 
?Instructions ?. Pour le progrès dans les études, vous pouvez 
utiliser la navigation de cours du côté droit de la page, qui 
contient les pages des textes et d'exercice du cours ouvert. Sur
le bas de chaque page, il y a un bouton de progrès qui vous portera 
à la prochaine page dans le contenu. Vous pouvez également 
parcourir le contenu en utilisant la carte de site au niveau 
principal. La carte de site montre la teneur entière du site de
langue allemande à la même page.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O material em linha para a língua alemão na 
aprendizagem de distância secundária superior inclui os títulos do 
curso de acordo com o curriculum para escolas secundárias superiores:
1. Como  você , agradável para encontrar-se com o; 
2. Isto é como nós fazemos coisas; 3. Tempo 
de lazer e passatempos; 4. Na HOME e no exterior; 5.
Então e agora. A matéria sujeita do índice é descrita 
na página começando de cada curso. Os níveis de habilidades 
são incorporados em relação aos textos e aos exercícios. O 
material inclui a abundância de limas sadias com instruções no 
fundo da página sob?Instructions?. Para o progresso nos 
estudos, você pode usar a navegação do curso no lado right-hand da 
página, que contem as páginas do texto e do exercício do curso 
aberto. No fundo de cada página, há uma tecla do progresso que
faça exame de você à página seguinte no índice sujeito. 
Você pode também browse o índice usando o mapa de local no 
nível principal. O mapa de local mostra o índice inteiro do 
local alemão da língua na mesma página.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il materiale in linea per la lingua tedesca 
nell'imparare di distanza superiore-secondario include i titoli di 
corso in conformità con il programma di studi per le scuole 
superiori-secondarie: 1. Come, piacevole per venirli a 
contatto; 2. Ciò è come facciamo le cose; 3. 
Tempo libero ed hobby; 4. Nel paese ed all'estero; 
5. Allora ed ora. Il tema del soddisfare è 
descritto alla pagina cominciante di ogni corso. I livelli di 
abilità sono inseriti in relazione ai testi ed alle esercitazioni. 
Il materiale include l'abbondanza degli archivi sani con le 
istruzioni sulla parte inferiore della pagina sotto i?Instructions?. 
Per progresso negli studi, potete usare il percorso di corso dal
lato destro della pagina, che contiene le pagine di esercitazione e 
del testo del corso aperto. Sulla parte inferiore di ogni 
pagina, ci è un tasto di progresso che li prenderà alla pagina 
seguente nel contenuto. Potete anche passare in rassegna il 
soddisfare usando il programma di luogo al livello principale. 
Il programma di luogo mostra l'intero contenuto del luogo di 
lingua tedesca alla stessa pagina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σε απευθείας σύνδεση υλικό για τη γερμανική γλώσσα
στην ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια από απόσταση εκμάθηση περιλαμβάνει 
τους τίτλους σειράς μαθημάτων σύμφωνα με το πρόγραμμα σπουδών 
για την ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση: 1. Τι κάνετε, 
συμπαθητικός να σας συναντήσει  2. Έτσι κάνουμε τα πράγματα
3. Ελεύθερος χρόνος και χόμπι  4. Στο σπίτι και στο 
εξωτερικό  5. Έπειτα και τώρα. Το περιεχόμενο του 
περιεχομένου περιγράφεται στην αρχική σελίδα κάθε σειράς 
μαθημάτων. Τα επίπεδα δεξιοτήτων εισάγονται σχετικά με τα 
κείμενα και τις ασκήσεις. Το υλικό περιλαμβάνει την αφθονία
των υγιών αρχείων με τις οδηγίες για το κατώτατο σημείο της 
σελίδας κάτω από ?Instructions;. Για την πρόοδο στις 
μελέτες, μπορείτε να χρησιμοποιήσετε τη ναυσιπλοϊ'α σειράς 
μαθημάτων στη δεξιά πλευρά της σελίδας, η οποία περιέχει τις 
σελίδες κειμένων και άσκησης της ανοικτής σειράς μαθημάτων. 
Στο κατώτατο σημείο κάθε σελίδας, υπάρχει ένα κουμπί 
προόδου που θα σας πάρει στην επόμενη σελίδα στα περιεχόμενα. 
Μπορείτε επίσης να περιοδεύσετε το περιεχόμενο με τη 
χρησιμοποίηση του χάρτη περιοχών στο βασικό επίπεδο. Ο 
χάρτης περιοχών εμφανίζει ολόκληρο περιεχόμενο της γερμανικής 
γλωσσικής περιοχής στην ίδια σελίδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El material en línea para el lenguaje alemán en
aprender de distancia superior-secundario incluye los títulos del 
curso de acuerdo con el plan de estudios para las escuelas 
superiores-secundarias: 1. Cómo lo haga usted , agradable
satisfacerle; 2. Éste es cómo hacemos cosas; 3. 
Tiempo libre y manías; 4. En el país y en el 
extranjero; 5. Entonces y ahora. El tema del 
contenido se describe en la paginación que comienza de cada curso. 
Los niveles de habilidades se incorporan en la conexión con los
textos y los ejercicios. El material incluye el un montón de 
ficheros de los sonidos con instrucciones en el fondo de la 
paginación bajo?Instructions?. Para el progreso en los 
estudios, usted puede utilizar la navegación del curso en la cara 
derecha de la paginación, que contiene las paginaciones del texto y 
del ejercicio del curso abierto. En el fondo de cada 
paginación, hay un botón del progreso que le llevará a la 
paginación siguiente en el contenido sujeto. Usted puede 
también hojear el contenido usando la correspondencia de sitio en el 
nivel principal. La correspondencia de sitio muestra el 
contenido entero del sitio alemán del lenguaje en la misma 
paginación.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katri Oldendorff
n:Oldendorff;Katri
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:al et
n:et;al
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7D4A1601-F174-2BFA-6703-584BB47C9DA7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7D4A1601-F174-2BFA-6703-584BB47C9DA7</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:39.85Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>image</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>548</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1353</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
