<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223057</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223057</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.kuluttajaliitto.fi/talousaapinen</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.kuluttajaliitto.fi/talousaapinen</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.kuluttajaliitto.fi/talousaapinen</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Finnish Consumers’ Association :: ABC of economy</string>
            <string language="fi">Suomen Kuluttajaliitto :: Talousaapinen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Finnischen Verbraucher? Verbindung:: ABC
der Wirtschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Consommateurs Finlandais ? ABC de 
l'association :: de l'économie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Consumidores Finnish? ABC da 
associação:: da economia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I Consumatori Finlandesi? ABC di 
associazione:: di economia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι φινλανδικοί καταναλωτές; Ένωση :: ABC 
της οικονομίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Los Consumidores Finlandeses? ABC de la 
asociación:: de la economía</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The subjects of the ABC of economy can be used in the national core curriculum in basic education, e.g., in the Responsibility for the environment, welfare and sustainable future subject entity . They are also suitable as part of the teaching in mathematics and environmental and natural studies. The material consists of games and idea material sections. In the games section, the teacher can guide the pupils to play independently or use the games as learning tasks in teaching. The subjects of the games are related to money, personal finance, society and mathematics. The idea material section includes tips and ideas for the teaching of economy-related subjects in class. The pages of the ABC of economy also includes tips for parents or other adults who want to help children to learn to manage their own money matters. The Smart shopper page encourages children and young people to engage in sensible spending. The material also includes links related to the subject. The tasks of the learning material can be used in support of teaching in class and online.</string>
            <string language="fi">Talousaapisen aiheita voidaan käyttää hyödyksi valtakunnallisen Perusopetuksen opetussuunnitelman perusteissa muun muassa aihekokonaisuudessa Vastuu ympäristöstä, hyvinvoinnista ja kestävästä tulevaisuudesta. Ne soveltuvat myös osaksi matematiikan sekä ympäristö- ja luonnontiedon opetusta. Materiaali koostuu pelit- ja ideamateriaaliosista. Pelit-osioissa opettaja voi ohjata oppilaat pelaamaan itsenäisesti tai käyttää pelejä opetuksessa oppimistehtävinä. Pelien aiheet liittyvät rahaan, henkilökohtaiseen talouteen, yhteiskuntaan ja matematiikkaan. Ideamateriaali-osiossa on vinkkejä ja ideoita talouteen liittyvien aiheiden opetukseen oppitunneilla. Talousaapisen sivuille on koottu vinkkejä myös vanhemmille tai muille aikuisille, jotka haluavat auttaa lasta oppimaan oman rahan käytön hallintaa. Fiksu shoppailija -sivu kannustaa lapsia ja nuoria järkevään rahankäyttöön. Aineisto sisältää myös aiheeseen liittyviä linkkejä. Oppimateriaalin tehtäviä voidaan käyttää sekä tuntiopetuksen tukena että verkossa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Themen des ABCS der Wirtschaft können im 
nationalen Kernlehrplan in der grundlegenden Ausbildung z.B. in der 
Verantwortlichkeit für die Umgebung, die Wohlfahrt und die stützbare
zukünftige vorbehaltliche Instanz benutzt werden. Sie sind auch
als Teil des Unterrichts in der Mathematik und in den Klima- und 
natürlichen Studien verwendbar. Das Material besteht aus 
Spielen und Idee Materialkapiteln. Im Spielkapitel kann der 
Lehrer die Pupillen zum Spiel unabhängig führen oder die Spiele als 
erlernenaufgaben beim Unterrichten benutzen. Die Themen der 
Spiele hängen mit Geld, persönlicher Finanzierung, Gesellschaft und 
Mathematik zusammen. Das Idee materielle Kapitel schließt 
Spitzen und Ideen für den Unterricht der Wirtschaft-in Verbindung 
stehenden Themen in der Kategorie ein. Die Seiten des ABCS der 
Wirtschaft schließt auch Spitzen für Eltern oder andere Erwachsene 
ein, die Kindern helfen möchten zu erlernen, ihre eigenen Geldstoffe 
zu handhaben. Die intelligente Käuferseite regt Kinder und 
junge Leute an, sich in der vernünftigen Ausgabe zu engagieren. 
Das Material schließt auch die Links ein, die auf dem Thema in 
Verbindung gestanden werden. Die Aufgaben des erlernenmaterials 
können zur Unterstützung in der Kategorie online unterrichten 
verwendet werden und.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les sujets du ABC de l'économie peuvent être 
utilisés dans le programme d'études national de noyau dans 
l'éducation de base, par exemple, dans la responsabilité de 
l'environnement, du bien-être et de la future entité soumise 
soutenable. Ils sont également appropriés en tant qu'élément
de l'enseignement dans les mathématiques et les études 
environnementales et normales. Le matériel se compose des jeux 
et des sections de matériel d'idée. Dans la section de jeux, 
le professeur peut guider les pupilles au jeu indépendamment ou 
utiliser les jeux pendant qu'apprenant charge dans 
l'enseignement. Les sujets des jeux sont liés à l'argent, aux 
finances personnelles, à la société et aux mathématiques. La
section matérielle d'idée inclut des extrémités et des idées pour
l'enseignement des sujets économie-connexes dans la classe. Les
pages du ABC de l'économie inclut également des extrémités pour 
les parents ou d'autres adultes qui veulent aider des enfants à 
apprendre à contrôler leurs propres sujets d'argent. La page 
futée de client encourage des enfants et des jeunes à s'engager dans
la dépense sensible. Le matériel inclut également des liens 
liés au sujet. Charge du matériel d'étude peut être
utilisé à l'appui de l'enseignement dans la classe et en ligne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os assuntos do ABC da economia podem ser usados no
curriculum nacional do núcleo na instrução básica, por exemplo, na
responsabilidade para o ambiente, o bem-estar e a entidade sujeita 
futura sustainable. São também apropriados como a parte do 
ensino na matemática e em estudos ambientais e naturais. O 
material consiste em jogos e em seções do material da idéia. 
Na seção dos jogos, o professor pode guiar as pupilas ao jogo 
independentemente ou usar os jogos como tarefas de aprendizagem em 
ensinar. Os assuntos dos jogos são relacionados ao dinheiro, 
às finanças pessoais, à sociedade e à matemática. A seção
material da idéia inclui pontas e idéias para o ensino de assuntos 
economia-relacionados na classe. As páginas do ABC da economia 
incluem também pontas para os pais ou os outros adultos que querem 
ajudar a crianças aprender controlar suas próprias matérias do 
dinheiro. A página esperta do cliente incentiva crianças e 
povos novos acoplar na despesa sensible. O material inclui 
também as ligações relacionadas ao assunto. As tarefas do 
material de aprendizagem podem ser usadas na sustentação de ensinar 
na classe e em linha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli argomenti di ABC di economia possono essere 
usati nel programma di studi nazionale di nucleo nella formazione di 
base, per esempio, nella responsabilità dell'ambiente, del benessere 
e dell'entità tematica futura sostenibile. Sono egualmente 
adatti come componente dell'insegnamento nella matematica e negli 
studi ambientali e naturali. Il materiale consiste dei giochi e 
delle sezioni del materiale di idea. Nella sezione dei giochi, 
l'insegnante può guidare indipendentemente le pupille a gioco o usare
i giochi come mansioni imparanti nell'istruzione. Gli argomenti 
di giochi sono collegati con soldi, la finanza personale, la società 
e la matematica. La sezione materiale di idea include le punte e
le idee per l'insegnamento degli oggetti economia-relativi nel codice 
categoria. Le pagine del ABC di economia egualmente include le 
punte per i genitori o altri adulti che desiderano aiutare i bambini 
ad imparare gestire i loro propri argomenti dei soldi. La pagina
astuta del cliente consiglia ai bambini ed ai giovani agganciarsi in 
spesa ragionevole. Il materiale egualmente include i 
collegamenti relativi all'oggetto. Le mansioni del materiale 
imparante possono essere usate a sostegno dell'istruzione nel codice 
categoria ed in linea.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα θέματα του ABC της οικονομίας μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν στο εθνικό πρόγραμμα σπουδών πυρήνων στη βασική 
εκπαίδευση, π.χ., στην ευθύνη για το περιβάλλον, την ευημερία και 
τη βιώσιμη μελλοντική υπαγόμενη οντότητα. Είναι επίσης 
κατάλληλοι ως τμήμα της διδασκαλίας στα μαθηματικά και τις 
περιβαλλοντικές και φυσικές μελέτες. Το υλικό αποτελείται 
από τα παιχνίδια και τα υλικά τμήματα ιδέας. Στο τμήμα 
παιχνιδιών, ο δάσκαλος μπορεί να καθοδηγήσει τους μαθητές για να 
παίξει ανεξάρτητα ή να χρησιμοποιήσει τα παιχνίδια ως εκμαθήσεις
των στοιχειωδών εργασιών στη διδασκαλία. Τα θέματα των 
παιχνιδιών συσχετίζονται με τα χρήματα, την προσωπική 
χρηματοδότηση, την κοινωνία και τα μαθηματικά. Το υλικό 
τμήμα ιδέας περιλαμβάνει τις άκρες και τις ιδέες για τη 
διδασκαλία των οικονομία-σχετικών με τον θεμάτων στην κλάση. 
Οι σελίδες του ABC της οικονομίας περιλαμβάνουν επίσης 
τις άκρες για τους γονείς ή άλλους ενηλίκους που θέλουν να 
βοηθήσουν τα παιδιά για να μάθουν να διαχειρίζονται τα θέματα 
χρημάτων τους. Η έξυπνη σελίδα αγοραστών ενθαρρύνει τα 
παιδιά και τους νέους για να συμμετέχει στα λογικά έξοδα. 
Το υλικό περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις συνδέσεις σχετικές με το 
θέμα. Οι στοιχειώδεις εργασίες του υλικού εκμάθησης 
μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν υπέρ της διδασκαλίας στην κλάση και 
on-line.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los temas del ABC de la economía se pueden 
utilizar en el plan de estudios nacional de la base en la educación 
básica, e.g., en la responsabilidad del ambiente, del bienestar y de 
la entidad sujeta futura sostenible. Son también convenientes 
como parte de la enseñanza en matemáticas y estudios ambientales y 
naturales. El material consiste en juegos y secciones del 
material de la idea. En la sección de los juegos, el profesor 
puede dirigir las pupilas al juego independientemente o utilizar los 
juegos como tareas que aprenden en la enseñanza. Los temas de 
los juegos se relacionan con el dinero, las finanzas personales, la 
sociedad y las matemáticas. La sección material de la idea 
incluye extremidades y las ideas para la enseñanza de temas 
economi'a-relacionados en clase. Las paginaciones del ABC de la 
economía también incluyen las extremidades para los padres u otros 
adultos que desean ayudar a niños a aprender manejar sus propias 
materias del dinero. La paginación elegante del comprador anima
a niños y a gente joven que enganchen al gasto sensible. El 
material también incluye las conexiones relacionadas con el tema. 
Las tareas del material que aprende se pueden utilizar en la 
ayuda de la enseñanza en clase y en línea.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen Kuluttajaliitto
n:Suomen Kuluttajaliitto
org:Suomen Kuluttajaliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen Kuluttajaliitto
n:Suomen Kuluttajaliitto
org:Suomen Kuluttajaliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Finanssialan Keskusliitto
n:Finanssialan Keskusliitto
org:Finanssialan Keskusliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/8D4CC4E8-5377-CCF2-C79B-2CE3FEEFF119</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/8D4CC4E8-5377-CCF2-C79B-2CE3FEEFF119</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:40.57Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>educational game</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>parent</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">8-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>784</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>388</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>267</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>599</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>839</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>490</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>430</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>790</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.kuluttajaliitto.fi/talousaapinen</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.kuluttajaliitto.fi/talousaapinen</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
