<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222915</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.kaspaikka.fi/keke/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.kaspaikka.fi/keke/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.kaspaikka.fi/keke/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Craft Place – Sustainable development</string>
            <string language="fi">Käspaikka -  Kestävä kehitys</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fertigkeit-Platz? Stützbare Entwicklung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Endroit de Métier ? Développement 
soutenable</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lugar Do Ofício? Desenvolvimento 
sustainable</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Posto Del Mestiere? Sviluppo sostenibile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θέση τεχνών; Βιώσιμη ανάπτυξη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Lugar Del Arte? Desarrollo sostenible</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The website contains excellent working ideas and links for the textile and clothing industry with the theme ‘sustainable development’. The material is part of the studies in material knowledge and is also suitable for use as a cross-curricular theme for the entire clothing sector. The Keke website has plenty of material suitable for students of different levels and can be used both as actual learning material and as sections of web courses. The website is also suitable for differentiated teaching: there is material for all levels from special students to those who have passed the upper secondary school. The teacher may guide students in the selection of material. The teacher’s desk contains plenty of good material to assist the teacher.</string>
            <string language="fi">Sivulle on koottu tekstiili- ja vaatetusalan kannalta hyviä kestävään kehitykseen liittyviä työskentelyideoita ja linkkejä. Aineisto kuuluu materiaalituntemuksen opintoihin, soveltuu myös läpäisyaiheeksi koko vaatetusalalle. Keke -sivuilla on runsaasti eri tasoisille opiskelijoille soveltuvaa materiaalia, jota voidaan käyttää niin varsinaisena oppimateriaalina kuin verkkokurssienkin osina. Sivusto sopii myös opetuksen eriyttämiseen, aineistoa on erityisopiskelijoista lukion suorittaneisiin asti. Opettaja voi ohjata opiskelijoita käytettävän aineiston valinnassa. Opettajan pöydällä on paljon hyvää materiaalia opettajan avuksi.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">kierrätysmateriaalit</string>
            <string language="en">kierrätysmateriaalit</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Web site enthält ausgezeichnete Arbeitsideen 
und Links für die Textil- und Kleidungsindustrie mit der?sustainable 
Entwicklung des Themas?. Das Material ist ein Teil der Studien 
im materiellen Wissen und ist auch für Gebrauch als 
Kreuzlehrplanthema für den gesamten Kleidung Sektor verwendbar. 
Die Keke Web site hat viel von materiellem verwendbarem für 
Kursteilnehmer der unterschiedlichen Stufen und kann als 
tatsächliches erlernenmaterial und als Kapitel der Web-Kurse 
verwendet werden. Die Web site ist auch für unterschiedenen 
Unterricht verwendbar: es gibt für alle Stufen von den 
speziellen Kursteilnehmern zu denen materiell, die die 
obersekundarschule geführt haben. Der Lehrer kann 
Kursteilnehmer in die Auswahl des Materials führen. Der 
teacher?s Schreibtisch enthält viel des guten Materials, um den 
Lehrer zu unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web contient d'excellents idées et liens 
fonctionnants pour l'industrie du textile et de l'habillement avec le 
développement ?sustainable de thème ?. Le matériel fait 
partie des études dans la connaissance matérielle et est également 
approprié pour l'usage comme thème croix-curriculaire pour le 
secteur entier d'habillement. Le site Web de Keke a l'abondance 
d'approprié matériel aux étudiants de différents niveaux et peut 
être utilisé en tant que matériel d'étude réel et comme sections 
des cours de Web. Le site Web est également approprié à 
l'enseignement différencié : il y a matériel pour tous les 
niveaux des étudiants spéciaux à ceux qui ont passé l'école 
secondaire deuxième cycle. Le professeur peut guider des 
étudiants dans la sélection du matériel. Le bureau de 
teacher?s contient l'abondance du bon matériel pour aider le 
professeur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site contem idéias e as ligações 
trabalhando excelentes para a indústria de textile e de roupa com o 
desenvolvimento?sustainable do tema?. O material é parte dos 
estudos no conhecimento material e é também apropriado para o uso 
como um tema cruz-cross-curricular para o setor inteiro da roupa. 
O Web site de Keke tem a abundância de apropriado material para
estudantes de níveis diferentes e pode ser usado  como o material de 
aprendizagem real e como seções de cursos do Web. O Web site 
é também apropriado para o ensino diferenciado: há material 
para todos os níveis dos estudantes especiais àqueles que passaram a
escola secundária superior. O professor pode guiar estudantes 
na seleção do material. A mesa dos teacher?s contem a 
abundância do material bom para ajudar ao professor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web site contiene le idee ed i collegamenti di 
funzionamento eccellenti per l'industria tessile e dell'abbigliamento 
con lo sviluppo?sustainable di tema?. Il materiale fa parte 
degli studi nella conoscenza materiale ed è egualmente adatto ad uso 
come tema traversa-d'insegnamento per l'intero settore dei vestiti. 
Il Web site di Keke ha abbondanza di adatto materiale ad allievi
dei livelli differenti e può essere usato sia come materiale 
imparante reale che come sezioni dei corsi di Web. Il Web site 
è egualmente adatto ad insegnamento differenziato: ci è 
materiale per tutti i livelli dagli allievi speciali a coloro che ha 
passato la scuola superiore-secondaria. L'insegnante può 
guidare gli allievi nella selezione di materiale. Lo scrittorio 
dei teacher?s contiene l'abbondanza di buon materiale per aiutare 
l'insegnante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις άριστες ιδέες και τις 
συνδέσεις εργασίας για την υφαντική και βιομηχανία ιματισμού με 
τη ?sustainable ανάπτυξη θέματος;. Το υλικό είναι μέρος 
των μελετών στην υλική γνώση και είναι επίσης κατάλληλο για τη 
χρήση ως διαγώνιος-διδακτικό θέμα για τον ολόκληρο τομέα του 
ιματισμού. Ο ιστοχώρος Keke έχει την αφθονία του υλικού 
κατάλληλη για τους σπουδαστές των διαφορετικών επιπέδων και 
μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί και ως πραγματικό υλικό εκμάθησης και ως
τμήματα των σειρών μαθημάτων Ιστού. Ο ιστοχώρος είναι 
επίσης κατάλληλος για τη διαφοροποιημένη διδασκαλία: 
υπάρχει υλικός για όλα τα επίπεδα από τους ειδικούς 
σπουδαστές σε εκείνοι που έχουν περάσει την ανώτερη 
δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση. Ο δάσκαλος μπορεί να καθοδηγήσει 
τους σπουδαστές στην επιλογή του υλικού. Το γραφείο 
teacher?s περιέχει την αφθονία του καλού υλικού για να 
βοηθήσει το δάσκαλο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site contiene ideas y las conexiones de 
trabajo excelentes para la industria de textil y de la confección con
el desarrollo?sustainable del tema?. El material es parte de los
estudios en conocimiento material y es también conveniente para el 
uso como tema cruz-del plan de estudios para el sector entero de la 
ropa. El Web site de Keke tiene un montón de conveniente 
material para los estudiantes de diversos niveles y se puede utilizar 
como material que aprende real y como secciones de los cursos del Web.
El Web site es también conveniente para la enseñanza 
distinguida: hay material para todos los niveles de estudiantes 
especiales a los que han pasado la escuela superior-secundaria. 
El profesor puede dirigir a estudiantes en la selección del 
material. El escritorio de los teacher?s contiene un montón de 
buen material para asistir al profesor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kierrätysmateriaalit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">kierrätysmateriaalit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">kierrätysmateriaalit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">kierrätysmateriaalit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">kierrδtysmateriaalit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">kierrätysmateriaalit</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katri Arohonka
n:Arohonka;Katri
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B213E585-DCA6-7BF4-8B99-CF394622A12E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/B213E585-DCA6-7BF4-8B99-CF394622A12E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-02T00:12:31.81Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-18</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Tarttuva 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>787</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>388</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>225</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1304</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.kaspaikka.fi/keke/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.kaspaikka.fi/keke/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
