<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/79006</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>79006</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/englanti</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/englanti</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Etälukio - englanti</string>
            <string language="en">Upper secondary distance learning – English</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obersekundarabstand Lernen? Englisch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étude de distance secondaire deuxième cycle ? 
Anglais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem de distância secundária superior? 
Inglês</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparare di distanza superiore-secondario? 
Inglese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια από απόσταση εκμάθηση; 
Αγγλικά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿El aprender de distancia superior-secundario? 
Inglés</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Sivusto sisältää kurssit 1. Minä ja muut, 2. Viestintä ja vapaa-aika, 3. Opiskelu ja työ, 4. Yhteiskunta ja ympäröivä maailma, 5. Kulttuuri, 6. Tiede, talous ja tekniikka, 7. Luonto ja kestävä kehitys, 8. Yhteinen maailma ja kansainvälistyminen sekä johdanto- ja kirjoitelmakurssit. Etälukion englannin verkkomateriaali tukee etä- ja itseopiskelijaa lukio-opintojen suorittamisessa. Materiaali noudattaa uusia Aikuisten lukiokoulutuksen perusteita. Englannin verkkomateriaalien uudistaminen on vielä kesken, mutta tavoitteena on saada kaikki kurssit uudistettua vuoden 2007 loppuun mennessä.</string>
            <string language="en">The website contains the courses 1. I and others, 2. Communication and leisure time, 3. Studies and work, 4. Society and the surrounding world, 5. Culture, 6. Science, economy and technology, 7. Nature and sustainable development, 8. Our common world and internationalisation, and introductory and writing courses. The web material in upper secondary distance learning supports both distance learning and self study in their upper secondary studies. The material follows the new principles of upper secondary education for adults. The renewal of the English online material is still unfinished, but we aim to have all  courses revised by the end of 2007.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Web site enthält die Kurse 1. I und 
andere, 2. Kommunikation und Freizeit, 3. Studien und 
Arbeit, 4. Gesellschaft und die umgebende Welt, 5. Kultur,
6. Wissenschaft, Wirtschaft und Technologie, 7. Natur und 
stützbare Entwicklung, 8. Unsere geläufige Welt und 
internationalisation und einleitende und Schreiben Kurse. Das 
Web-Material im obersekundarabstand Lernen unterstützt das Abstand 
Lernen und Selbststudie in ihren obersekundarstudien. Das 
Material folgt den neuen Grundregeln der obersekundarausbildung für 
Erwachsene. Die Erneuerung des englischen Onlinematerials ist 
noch unfertig, aber wir zielen darauf ab, alle Kurse zu haben, die 
Ende 2007 verbessert werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web contient les cours 1. I et 
d'autres, 2. Transmission et temps libre, 3. Études et 
travail, 4. Société et le monde environnant, 5. Culture,
6. La Science, économie et technologie, 7. Nature et 
développement soutenable, 8. Notre monde et internationalisation 
commune, et cours préliminaires et d'écriture. Le matériel de
Web dans l'étude de distance secondaire deuxième cycle supporte 
l'étude de distance et l'étude d'art de l'auto-portrait dans leurs études 
secondaires deuxième cycle. Le matériel suit les nouveaux 
principes de l'éducation secondaire deuxième cycle pour des adultes.
Le renouvellement du matériel en ligne anglais est encore non 
fini, mais nous visons à avoir tous les cours révisés vers la fin 
de 2007.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site contem os cursos 1. I e outro, 
2. Tempo de uma comunicação e de lazer, 3. Estudos e 
trabalho, 4. Sociedade e o mundo circunvizinho, 5. 
Cultura, 6. Ciência, economia e tecnologia, 7. 
Natureza e desenvolvimento sustainable, 8. Nosso mundo e 
internationalisation comum, e cursos introdutórios e da escrita. 
O material do Web na aprendizagem de distância secundária 
superior suporta  a aprendizagem de distância e o estudo do self em 
seus estudos secundários superiores. O material segue os 
princípios novos da instrução secundária superior para adultos. 
A renovação do material em linha inglês é ainda unfinished, 
mas nós apontamos ter todos os cursos revisados para o fim de 2007.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web site contiene i corsi 1. I ed altri,
2. Comunicazione e tempo libero, 3. Studi e lavoro, 4. 
Società ed il mondo circostante, 5. Coltura, 6. 
Scienza, economia e tecnologia, 7. Natura e sviluppo 
sostenibile, 8. Il nostro mondo ed internationalisation comune e
corsi di scrittura ed introduttivi. Il materiale di Web 
nell'imparare di distanza superiore-secondario sostiene sia imparare 
di distanza che lo studio di auto nei loro studi superiori-secondarii.
Il materiale segue i nuovi principii di formazione 
superiore-secondaria per gli adulti. Il rinnovamento del 
materiale in linea inglese è ancora non finito, ma miriamo ad avere 
tutti i corsi modificati per la fine di 2007.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις σειρές μαθημάτων 1. Ι 
και άλλοι, επικοινωνία 2. και ελεύθερος χρόνος, 3. μελέτες και 
εργασία, κοινωνία 4. και ο περιβάλλων κόσμος, 5. καλλιεργήστε, 
επιστήμη 6., οικονομία και τεχνολογία, 7. φύση και βιώσιμη 
ανάπτυξη, 8. ο κοινοί κόσμος και η διεθνοποίησή μας, και 
εισαγωγικές και σειρές μαθημάτων γραψίματος. Το υλικό 
Ιστού στην ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια από απόσταση εκμάθηση 
υποστηρίζει και την από απόσταση εκμάθηση και τη μόνη μελέτη 
στις ανώτερες δευτεροβάθμιες μελέτες τους. Το υλικό 
ακολουθεί τις νέες αρχές της ανώτερης δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης
για τους ενηλίκους. Η ανανέωση του αγγλικού σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση υλικού είναι ακόμα ατελής, αλλά στοχεύουμε να 
διοργανώσουμε όλες τις σειρές μαθημάτων που αναθεωρούνται μέχρι 
το τέλος του 2007.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site contiene los cursos 1. I y 
otros, 2. Comunicación y tiempo libre, 3. Estudios y 
trabajo, 4. Sociedad y el mundo circundante, 5. Cultura, 
6. Ciencia, economía y tecnología, 7. Naturaleza y 
desarrollo sostenible, 8. Nuestro mundo e internationalisation 
común, y cursos introductorios y de la escritura. El material 
del Web en aprender de distancia superior-secundario utiliza aprender 
de distancia y estudio del uno mismo en sus estudios 
superiores-secundarios. El material sigue los nuevos principios 
de la educación superior-secundaria para los adultos. La 
renovación del material en línea inglés sigue siendo inacabada, 
pero apuntamos tener todos los cursos revisados antes de fin de 2007.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Maini Knuuttila
n:Knuuttila;Maini
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eeva Tuokko
n:Tuokko;Eeva
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jim McWhirr
n:McWhirr;Jim
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Maija Ojutkangas
n:Ojutkangas;Maija
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Twinkle Oy
n:Twinkle Oy
org:Twinkle Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/E8F03047-623E-2095-8F78-F4C9D02C82AC</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/E8F03047-623E-2095-8F78-F4C9D02C82AC</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Susanna Venemies
n:Venemies;Susanna 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-04-03T20:03:18.77Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/englanti/#</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>709</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1411</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>79006</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/englanti</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
