<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222520</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/common_background</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/common_background</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/common_background</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Common background</string>
            <string language="fi">Common background</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geläufiger Hintergrund</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fond commun</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fundo comum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Priorità bassa comune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινό υπόβαθρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fondo común</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The pupil hears presentations of eight people, containing a large quantity of vocabulary related to personal particulars (including age, nationality, place of residence, hobbies). After listening to the presentations, the pupil has to group the individuals according to common characteristics. Many of the people may have something in common, but the aim is to find connecting factors on the basis of which the individuals can be divided specifically into four groups of two. In addition to vocabulary practice and aural comprehension, the pupil must be able to draw conclusions and apply knowledge for solving a task. The task is challenging, and therefore the instructions urge pupils to take notes while listening to make solving it easier. The material is downloaded onto a computer, after which it can be used without an Internet connection.</string>
            <string language="fi">Oppilas kuulee kahdeksan henkilön esittelyt, joissa esiintyy runsaasti henkilötietosanastoa (mm. ikä, kansallisuus, asuinpaikka, harrastukset). Kuunneltuaan esittelyt, oppilaan on ryhmiteltävät henkilöt yhteisten ominaisuuksien mukaan. Useammilla henkilöillä voi olla jotain yhteistä, mutta tarkoituksena on löytää sellaiset yhdistävät tekijät, joiden perusteella henkilöt voidaan jakaa nimenomaan neljään kahden hengen ryhmään. Sanastoharjoittelun ja kuullunymmärtämisen lisäksi oppilaan on pystyttävä tekemään päätelmiä ja soveltamaan tietoa tehtävän ratkaisemiseksi. Tehtävä on haastava ja siksi ohjeessa kehotetaankin tekemään muistiinpanoja kuuntelun aikana, jotta ratkaiseminen helpottuisi. Aineisto ladataan tietokoneelle, minkä jälkeen sitä voidaan käyttää ilman Internet-yhteyttä.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schüler hört die Darstellungen von acht 
Leuten und enthält eine große Quantität Wortschatz in Verbindung 
gestanden auf persönlichen Einzelheiten (einschließlich Alter, 
Nationalität, Wohnsitz, Liebhabereien). Nachdem sie zu den 
Darstellungen gehört hat, muß die Pupille die Einzelpersonen 
entsprechend geläufigen Eigenschaften gruppieren. Viele der 
Leute können etwas im Common haben, aber das Ziel ist, anschließende
Faktoren zu finden, auf der Grundlage von die die Einzelpersonen in 
vier Gruppen von zwei spezifisch geteilt werden können. 
Zusätzlich zur Wortschatzpraxis und zum Ohrenerfassen muß die 
Pupille können, Zusammenfassungen zu zeichnen und Wissen für das 
Lösen einer Aufgabe anzuwenden. Die Aufgabe ist schwierig und 
folglich drängen die Anweisungen Schüler, Anmerkungen beim Hören zu
nehmen, um einfacher zu bilden, sie lösend. Das Material wird 
auf einen Computer downloadet, nachdem kann es ohne einen 
Internet-Anschluß benutzt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'élève entend des présentations de huit 
personnes, contenant une grande quantité de vocabulaire liée aux 
conditions particulières personnelles (âge y compris, nationalité, 
domicile, passe-temps). Après avoir écouté les 
présentations, la pupille doit grouper les individus selon des 
caractéristiques communes. Plusieurs du peuple peuvent avoir 
quelque chose en commun, mais le but est de trouver les facteurs se 
reliants sur la base dont les individus peuvent être divisés 
spécifiquement en quatre groupes de deux. En plus de pratique 
en matière de vocabulaire et de compréhension auditive, la pupille 
doit pouvoir tirer des conclusions et appliquer la connaissance pour 
résoudre un charger. Le charger est provocant, et donc 
les instructions invitent des élèves à prendre des notes tout en 
écoutant pour faciliter le résolvant. Le matériel est 
téléchargé sur un ordinateur, après quoi il peut être utilisé 
sans connexion d'Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O aluno ouve as apresentações de oito povos, 
contendo uma quantidade grande do vocabulário relacionada aos 
detalhes pessoais (idade including, nacionalidade, lugar de 
residência, passatempos). Após escutar as apresentações, a 
pupila tem que agrupar os indivíduos de acordo com características 
comuns. Muitos dos povos podem ter algo na terra comum, mas o 
alvo é encontrar fatores conectando na base de que os indivíduos 
podem ser divididos especificamente em quatro grupos de dois. 
Além à prática do vocabulário e à compreensão aural, a 
pupila deve poder  desenhar conclusões e aplicar o conhecimento para 
resolver uma tarefa. A tarefa é challenging, e 
conseqüentemente as instruções incitam os alunos fazer exame de 
notas ao escutar para fazer resolvendo a mais fácil. O material
downloaded em um computador, depois do qual pode ser usado sem uma 
conexão do Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo sente lle presentazioni di otto genti, 
contenenti una grande quantità di vocabolario relativa ai particolari
personali (età compresa, nazionalità, luogo di residenza, hobby). 
Dopo avere ascoltato le presentazioni, la pupilla deve 
raggruppare gli individui secondo le caratteristiche comuni. 
Molte della gente possono avere qualcosa il in comune, ma lo 
scopo è trovare i fattori di collegamento in base a cui gli individui
possono essere divisi specificamente in quattro gruppi di due. 
Oltre che pratica di vocabolario e la comprensione sonora, la 
pupilla deve potere dissipare le conclusioni ed applicare la 
conoscenza per risolvere un'operazione. L'operazione è 
challenging e quindi le istruzioni invitano gli allievi a prendere le 
note mentre ascoltano per rendere risolvendola più facile. Il 
materiale è trasferito su un calcolatore, dopo di che può essere 
usato senza un collegamento del Internet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο μαθητής παρακολουθεί τις παρουσιάσεις οκτώ 
ανθρώπων, που περιέχουν μια μεγάλη ποσότητα λεξιλογίου σχετική 
με τις προσωπικές λεπτομέρειες (συμπεριλαμβανομένης της ηλικίας, 
της υπηκοότητας, της κατοικίας, των χόμπι). Μετά από να 
ακούσει τις παρουσιάσεις, ο μαθητής πρέπει να ομαδοποιήσει τα 
άτομα σύμφωνα με τα κοινά χαρακτηριστικά. Πολλοί από τους 
ανθρώπους μπορούν να έχουν κάτι από κοινού, αλλά ο στόχος 
είναι να βρεθούν οι συνδέοντας παράγοντες βάσει των οποίων τα 
άτομα μπορούν να διαιρεθούν συγκεκριμένα σε τέσσερις ομάδες 
δύο. Εκτός από την πρακτική λεξιλογίου και την ακουστική 
κατανόηση, ο μαθητής πρέπει να είναι σε θέση να συναγάγει τα 
συμπεράσματα και να εφαρμόσει τη γνώση για την επίλυση μιας 
στοιχειώδους εργασίας. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία είναι 
προκλητική, και επομένως οι μαθητές ώθησης οδηγιών για να 
ληφθούν οι σημειώσεις ακούοντας για να κάνει την επίλυση του 
ευκολότερου. Το υλικό μεταφορτώνεται επάνω σε έναν 
υπολογιστή, και μετά μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί χωρίς μια σύνδεση 
με το Διαδίκτυο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La pupila oye las presentaciones de ocho 
personas, conteniendo una cantidad grande de vocabulario relacionada 
con los detalles personales (edad incluyendo, nacionalidad, domicilio,
las manías). Después de escuchar las presentaciones, la pupila
tiene que agrupar a los individuos según características comunes. 
Muchas de la gente pueden tener algo en campo común, pero la 
puntería es encontrar los factores que conectan en base de los cuales
los individuos pueden ser divididos específicamente en cuatro grupos 
de dos. Además de práctica del vocabulario y de comprensión 
aural, la pupila debe poder trazar conclusiones y aplicar el 
conocimiento para solucionar una tarea. La tarea es desafiadora,
y por lo tanto las instrucciones impulsan a pupilas tomar notas 
mientras que escuchan para hacer solucionándola más fácil. El
material se descarga sobre un ordenador, después de lo cual puede ser
utilizado sin una conexión del Internet.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet OY
n:Lingonet OY
org:Lingonet OY
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/62756091-152B-3D2E-9CA2-0F3FE1120A1E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/62756091-152B-3D2E-9CA2-0F3FE1120A1E</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:25.58Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>750</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/common_background</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/common_background</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
