<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223101</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223101</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/lukujonot2/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/lukujonot2/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/lukujonot2/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Number sequences</string>
            <string language="fi">Lukujonot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zahlreihenfolgen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ordres de nombre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Seqüências do número</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sequenze di numero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ακολουθίες αριθμού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Secuencias del número</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Number sequences is an object of the AbacoMath game supporting the learning of mathematics, which contains tasks illustrating number sequences, quantity and ordinal numbers. The aim of the tasks is to lead the learner through the aid of experiences and visualisation towards abstraction. The object is suitable for use in remedial and general mathematics teaching. The tasks of the AbacoMath game have been conceived and scripted on the basis of a rehabilitative method developed under Hendrik Radatz and Ursula Chaudhur. The application has been implemented with Flash technology, and so the program requires a browser with Flash support in order to work.</string>
            <string language="fi">Lukujonot on matematiikan oppimista tukevan AbacoMath-pelin aihio, joka sisältää lukujonoja, lukumäärää ja järjestyslukuja havainnollistavia tehtäviä. Tehtävien tavoite on johdattaa oppija kokemusten ja visualisoinnin avulla kohti abstraktiota. Aihio sopii käytettäväksi matematiikan erityis- ja yleisopetuksessa. AbacoMath-pelin tehtävät on ideoitu ja käsikirjoitettu Hendrik Radatzin ja Ursula Chaudhurin johdolla kehitetyn kuntouttamismenetelmän pohjalta. Sovellus on toteutettu Flash-tekniikalla, ja se tarvitsee toimiakseen selaimen, jossa on Flash-tuki.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zahlreihenfolgen ist eine Nachricht des AbacoMath 
Spiels, welches das Lernen von Mathematik unterstützt, die die 
Aufgaben enthält, die Zahlreihenfolgen, Quantität und Ordnungszahlen
veranschaulichen. Das Ziel der Aufgaben ist, den Anfänger durch
das Hilfsmittel von Erfahrungen und von Sichtbarmachung in Richtung 
zur Abstraktion zu führen. Die Nachricht ist für Gebrauch im 
fehlerbehebenden und allgemeinen Mathematikunterricht verwendbar. 
Die Aufgaben des AbacoMath Spiels sind begriffen worden und 
scripted auf der Grundlage von eine rehabilitierende Methode, die 
unter Hendrik Radatz und Ursula Chaudhur entwickelt wird. Die 
Anwendung ist mit greller Technologie eingeführt worden und also 
benötigt das Programm eine Datenbanksuchroutine mit grellem Support, 
um zu arbeiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les ordres de nombre est un objet du jeu 
d'AbacoMath supportant l'étude des mathématiques, qui contiennent 
chargent illustrer des ordres de nombre, la quantité et des 
nombres ordinaux. Le but du charge est de mener 
l'étudiant par l'aide des expériences et de la visualisation vers 
l'abstraction. L'objet convient pour l'usage dans l'enseignement
réparateur et général de mathématiques. Charge du 
jeu d'AbacoMath ont été conçus et préétablirs sur la base d'une 
méthode réhabilitative développée sous Hendrik Radatz et Ursula 
Chaudhur. L'application a été mise en application avec la 
technologie instantanée, et ainsi le programme exige d'un navigateur 
avec le support instantané afin de travailler.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As seqüências do número são um objeto do jogo 
de AbacoMath que suporta a aprendizagem da matemática, que contem as 
tarefas que ilustram seqüências do número, quantidade e números 
ordinais. O alvo das tarefas é conduzir ao learner através do 
dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) das experiências e do 
visualisation para o abstraction. O objeto é apropriado para o 
uso no ensino corretivo e geral da matemática. As tarefas do 
jogo de AbacoMath conceived e scripted na base de um método 
rehabilitative desenvolvido sob Hendrik Radatz e Ursula Chaudhur. 
A aplicação foi executada com tecnologia flash, e assim que o 
programa requer um browser com sustentação flash a fim trabalhar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le sequenze di numero è un oggetto del gioco di 
AbacoMath che sostiene imparare della matematica, che contiene le 
mansioni che illustrano le sequenze di numero, la quantità ed i 
numeri ordinali. Lo scopo delle mansioni è condurre il 
principiante attraverso il sussidio delle esperienze e della 
visualizzazione verso l'astrazione. L'oggetto è adatto ad uso 
nell'insegnamento correttivo e generale di matematica. Le 
mansioni del gioco di AbacoMath sono state concepite e scripted in 
base ad un metodo rieducativo messo a punto sotto Hendrik Radatz ed 
Ursula Chaudhur. L'applicazione è stata effettuata con 
tecnologia istantanea ed in modo da il programma richiede un browser 
con supporto istantaneo per funzionare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ακολουθίες αριθμού είναι ένα αντικείμενο του 
παιχνιδιού AbacoMath που υποστηρίζει την εκμάθηση των 
μαθηματικών, τα οποία περιέχουν τις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες που 
επεξηγούν τις ακολουθίες αριθμού, την ποσότητα και τους τακτικούς
αριθμούς. Ο στόχος των στοιχειωδών εργασιών είναι να 
οδηγηθεί ο αρχάριος μέσω της ενίσχυσης της εμπειρίας και της 
απεικόνισης προς την αφαίρεση. Το αντικείμενο είναι 
κατάλληλο για τη χρήση στη θεραπευτική και γενική διδασκαλία 
μαθηματικών. Οι στοιχειώδεις εργασίες του παιχνιδιού 
AbacoMath έχουν συλλήφθουν και προκαθορισμένος βάσει μιας 
αποκατάστασης μεθόδου που αναπτύσσεται κάτω από το Hendrik 
Radatz και την Ursula Chaudhur. Η εφαρμογή έχει 
εφαρμοστεί με την τεχνολογία λάμψης, και έτσι το πρόγραμμα 
απαιτεί έναν ξεφυλλιστή με την υποστήριξη λάμψης προκειμένου να 
λειτουργήσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las secuencias del número son un objeto del juego 
de AbacoMath que utiliza aprender de las matemáticas, que contiene 
las tareas que ilustran secuencias del número, cantidad y números 
ordinales. La puntería de las tareas es conducir al 
principiante a través de la ayuda de experiencias y de la 
visualización hacia la abstracción. El objeto es conveniente 
para el uso en la enseñanza remediadora y general de las 
matemáticas. Las tareas del juego de AbacoMath se han concebido
y scripted en base de un método rehabilitativo desarrollado bajo 
Hendrik Radatz y Ursula Chaudhur. La aplicación se ha puesto en
ejecucio'n con tecnología de destello, y así que el programa 
requiere un browser con la ayuda de destello para trabajar.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jan Rosnell
n:Rosnell;Jan
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anni Lampinen
n:Lampinen;Anni
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Marja Dräger
n:Dräger;Marja
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Juha-Pekka Huikuri
n:Huikuri;Juha-Pekka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Janomedia
n:Janomedia
org:Janomedia
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Huikuri Interactive
n:Huikuri Interactive
org:Huikuri Interactive
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/09D5012E-AC6D-C2F1-E210-B73E656A0ECF</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/09D5012E-AC6D-C2F1-E210-B73E656A0ECF</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:04.30Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>special education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-9</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ei mainintaa</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>875</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1227</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>339</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>461</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>790</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>905</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/lukujonot2/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/lukujonot2/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
