<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222961</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222961</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/word_stress_and_meaning</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/word_stress_and_meaning</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/word_stress_and_meaning</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Word stress and meaning</string>
            <string language="fi">Word stress and meaning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wortdruck und -bedeutung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Effort et signification de mot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Stress e meaning da palavra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sforzo e significato di parola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πίεση και σημασία λέξης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tensión y significado de la palabra</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The purpose of the learning object is to teach the pupil to examine the prosody of a sentence: since the way a sentence is spoken sometimes has a considerable effect on its meaning. The pupil sees during the task in two columns four or five speech bubbles/bars in each one. A sentence is heard from the bars when the pupil clicks them. The sentences on the left are the same, but the sentence stress varies. The pupil’s task is to move the bars alongside each other in such a way that the sentence on the left gets a reaction with a suitable meaning next to the same. The correct sentences are displayed by clicking the Check button and the pupil hears the sentence pair spoken. A points calculator shows the pupil’s result. The learning object is a downloadable application.</string>
            <string language="fi">Oppimisaihion tarkoituksena on opettaa oppilasta tarkkailemaan lauseen prosodiikkaa: sillä, miten lauseen sanoo, on joskus suurikin vaikutus sen merkitykseen. Oppilas näkee tehtävän aikana kahdessa sarakkeessa neljä tai viisi puhekuplaa/palkkia kummassakin. Palkeista kuuluu lause, kun oppilas napauttaa niitä. Vasemmanpuoleiset lauseet ovat sanasisällöltään samoja, mutta lausepaino vaihtelee. Oppilaan tehtävä on siirtää palkit vierekkäin siten, että vasemmanpuoleinen lause saa vierelleen merkitykseltään sopivan reaktion.Oikeat lauseet tulevat näkyviin Tarkista-painikkeen napautuksella ja oppilas kuulee lauseparin puhuttuna. Pistelaskuri näyttää oppilaan tuloksen. Oppimisaihio on ladattava sovellus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Zweck der erlernennachricht ist, die Schüler
zu unterrichten, das prosody eines Programmsatzes zu überprüfen: 
da die Methode, die ein Programmsatz gesprochen wurde, manchmal 
ein beträchtliches auf seiner Bedeutung bewirken läßt. Die 
Schüler sieht während die Aufgabe in zwei Spalten vier oder fünf 
Rede bubbles/bars in jedem. Ein Programmsatz wird von den 
Stäben gehört, wenn die Pupille sie anklickt. Die 
Programmsätze auf dem links sind dieselben, aber der 
Programmsatzdruck verändert sich. Die pupil?s Aufgabe ist, die 
Stäbe neben einander zu verschieben, so daß der Programmsatz auf dem
links eine Reaktion mit einer verwendbaren Bedeutung nahe bei 
demselben erhält. Die korrekten Programmsätze werden 
angezeigt, indem man die Überprüfung Taste anklickt und die Schüler
hört das gesprochene Programmsatzpaar. Ein Punktrechner zeigt 
das pupil?s Resultat. Die erlernennachricht ist eine 
downloadableanwendung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de l'objet d'étude est d'enseigner 
l'élève à examiner la prosodie d'une phrase : puisque la 
voie que une phrase est parlée parfois fait effet un considérable 
sur sa signification. L'élève voit pendant le charger dans 
deux colonnes quatre ou cinq la parole bubbles/bars dans chacun. 
Une phrase est entendue des barres quand la pupille les 
clique. Les phrases du côté gauche sont identiques, 
mais l'effort de phrase change. Les pupil?s chargent doit
déplacer les barres à côté de l'un l'autre de telle manière que 
la phrase du côté gauche obtienne une réaction à une signification
appropriée à côté de la même chose. Les phrases correctes 
sont affichées en cliquant le bouton de contrôle et 
l'élève entend la paire de phrase parlée. Une calculatrice de
points montre le résultat de pupil?s. L'objet d'étude est une 
application downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A finalidade do objeto de aprendizagem é ensinar
o aluno examinar o prosody de uma sentença: desde que a maneira
que uma sentença é falada às vezes manda um considerável efetuar 
em seu meaning. O aluno vê durante a tarefa em duas colunas 
quatro ou cinco o discurso bubbles/bars em cada. Uma sentença 
está ouvida das barras quando a pupila as estala. As sentenças
na esquerda são as mesmas, mas o stress da sentença varia. A 
tarefa dos pupil?s é mover as barras ao lado de se de tal maneira que
a sentença na esquerda começa uma reação com um meaning apropriado
ao lado do mesmo. As sentenças corretas são indicadas 
estalando a tecla da verificação e o aluno ouve o par da sentença 
falado. Uma calculadora dos pontos mostra o resultado dos 
pupil?s. O objeto de aprendizagem é uma aplicação 
downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo dell'oggetto imparante è insegnare 
l'allievo esaminare il prosody di una frase: poiché il modo che
una frase è parlata a volte fa effetto un considerevole sul relativo 
significato. L'allievo vede durante l'operazione in due colonne 
quattro o cinque il discorso bubbles/bars in ogni. Una frase è 
sentita dalle barre quando la pupilla le scatta. Le frasi a 
sinistra sono le stesse, ma lo sforzo di frase varia. 
L'operazione dei pupil?s è di spostargli le barre im modo tale 
che la frase a sinistra ottiene una reazione con un significato adatto
vicino allo stesso. Le frasi corrette sono visualizzate 
scattando il tasto del controllo e l'allievo sente l'accoppiamento di 
frase parlato. Un calcolatore dei punti mostra il risultato dei 
pupil?s. L'oggetto imparante è un'applicazione downloadable.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σκοπός του αντικειμένου εκμάθησης είναι να διδαχθεί
ο μαθητής για να εξετάσει την προσωδία μιας πρότασης: από 
τον τρόπο που μια πρόταση μιλιέται μερικές φορές έχει μια 
ιδιαίτερη επίδραση στην έννοιά του. Ο μαθητής 
βλέπει κατά τη διάρκεια της στοιχειώδους εργασίας δύο 
ράβδους στηλών τέσσερα ή πέντε σε λεκτικές φυσαλίδες/σε 
καθεμία. Μια πρόταση λαμβάνεται νέα από τις ράβδους όταν 
τις χτυπά ο μαθητής. Οι προτάσεις στο αριστερό είναι οι 
ίδιες, αλλά η πίεση πρότασης ποικίλλει. Η στοιχειώδης 
εργασία pupil?s είναι να κινηθούν οι ράβδοι η μια παράλληλα με
την άλλη κατά τέτοιο τρόπο ώστε η πρόταση στο αριστερό παίρνει
μια αντίδραση με μια κατάλληλη έννοια δίπλα στο ίδιο πράγμα. 
Οι σωστές προτάσεις παρουσιάζονται με τον κρότο του 
κουμπιού ελέγχου και ο μαθητής ακούει το ζευγάρι πρότασης 
προφορικό. Ένας υπολογιστής σημείων εμφανίζει αποτέλεσμα 
pupil?s. Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης είναι μια 
τηλεκατεγραφόμενη εφαρμογή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El propósito del objeto que aprende es enseñar 
a la pupila a examinar el prosody de una sentencia: puesto que 
la manera que una sentencia se habla a veces hace que un considerable 
efectúe en su significado. La pupila ve durante la tarea en dos
columnas cuatro o cinco el discurso bubbles/bars en cada. Una 
sentencia se oye de las barras cuando la pupila las hace clic. 
Las sentencias a la izquierda son iguales, pero la tensión de 
la sentencia varía. La tarea de los pupil?s es mover las barras
junto a uno a de una manera tal que la sentencia a la izquierda 
consiga una reacción con un significado conveniente al lado igual. 
Las sentencias correctas son visualizadas haciendo clic el 
botón del cheque y la pupila oye el par de la sentencia hablado. 
Una calculadora de las puntas muestra el resultado de los 
pupil?s. El objeto que aprende es una aplicación downloadable.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet Oy
n:Lingonet Oy
org:Lingonet Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/19C4E545-76C4-0444-3318-36607A3E8030</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/19C4E545-76C4-0444-3318-36607A3E8030</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:25.64Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>556</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>709</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>238</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/word_stress_and_meaning</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/word_stress_and_meaning</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
