<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio3/index.htm</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio3/index.htm</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio3/index.htm</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Installation of heating systems</string>
            <string language="fi">Lämmitysjärjestelmien asentaminen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Installation der Heizsysteme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Installation des systèmes de chauffage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Instalação de sistemas de heating</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Installazione dei sistemi di riscaldamento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εγκατάσταση των συστημάτων θέρμανσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Instalación de los sistemas de calefacción</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Installation of heating systems learning material is intended as a support for contact teaching in, for example, the study of the basic house technology skills or HEPAC installation jobs study modules. The website is suitable for the study of the bases of installation as online teaching. The learning material is based on the investigative learning method and provides the student with learning problems, i.e., exercises and tasks. The website contains practical installation pictures which can be used to look for solutions to problems. The content of the website is meant as a tool and introduction to thinking, which is examined in greater depth with other written study material. The website also contains instructions for the teacher for use of the learning object.</string>
            <string language="fi">Lämmitysjärjestelmien asentaminen -oppimateriaali on tarkoitettu lähiopetuksen tueksi esimerkiksi talotekniikan perustaitojen tai LVI-asennustyöt-opintokokonaisuuksien opiskelussa. Sivusto soveltuu asentamisen perusteiden opiskeluun verkko-opetuksena. Oppimateriaali perustuu tutkivan oppimisen menetelmälle ja tarjoaa opiskelijalle oppimisongelmia eli harjoituksia ja tehtäviä. Sivusto sisältää käytännön asennuskuvia, joiden avulla ongelmiin voidaan etsiä ratkaisuja. Sivuston sisältö on tarkoitettu ajattelun työkaluksi ja johdannoksi, jota syvennetään muulla kirjallisella oppimateriaalilla. Sivusto sisältää myös ohjeet opettajalle oppimisaihion käyttöä varten. Sivustolla on käytössä selaimen Flash -laajennus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Installation der Heizsysteme, die Material 
erlernen, wird beabsichtigt, während ein Support für 
Kontaktunterricht innen, z.B., die Studie der grundlegenden 
Haustechnologiefähigkeiten oder HEPAC Installation Jobs Module 
studieren. Die Web site ist für die Studie der Unterseiten der 
Installation verwendbar, wie online unterrichtend. Das 
erlernenmaterial basiert auf der Untersuchungserlernenmethode und 
versieht den Kursteilnehmer mit erlernenproblemen d.h. Übungen und 
Aufgaben. Die Web site enthält praktische Installation 
Abbildungen, die benutzt werden können, um nach Lösungen zu den 
Problemen zu suchen. Der Inhalt der Web site wird als 
Hilfsmittel und Einleitung in ein Denken bedeutet, das tiefgehender 
mit anderem schriftlichem Studie Material überprüft wird. Die 
Web site enthält auch Anweisungen für den Lehrer für Gebrauch von 
der erlernennachricht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'installation des systèmes de chauffage apprenant
le matériel est destinée pendant qu'un soutien de l'enseignement de 
contact dedans, les travaux par exemple, d'étude des qualifications 
de base de technologie de maison ou d'installation de HEPAC étudient 
des modules. Le site Web convient à l'étude des bases de 
l'installation comme en ligne enseignant. Le matériel d'étude 
est basé sur la méthode d'étude investigatrice et fournit à 
l'étudiant des problèmes d'étude, c.-à-d., s'exerce et 
charge. Le site Web contient les images pratiques 
d'installation qui peuvent être employées pour rechercher des 
solutions aux problèmes. La teneur du site Web est signifiée 
comme outil et introduction à la pensée, qui est examinée plus en 
détail avec l'autre matériel écrit d'étude. Le site Web 
contient également des instructions pour le professeur pour l'usage 
de l'objet d'étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A instalação dos sistemas de heating que aprendem
o material é pretendida enquanto uma sustentação para o ensino do 
contato em, para o exemplo, os trabalhos do estudo das habilidades 
básicas da tecnologia da casa ou da instalação de HEPAC estuda os 
módulos. O Web site é apropriado para o estudo das bases da 
instalação como em linha ensinando. O material de aprendizagem
é baseado no método de aprendizagem investigative e fornece o 
estudante com os problemas de aprendizagem, isto é, exercícios e 
tarefas. O Web site contem os retratos práticos da instalação
que podem ser usados procurar soluções aos problemas. O 
índice do Web site é significado como uma ferramenta e uma 
introdução a pensar, que é examinado em uma profundidade mais 
grande com o outro material escrito do estudo. O Web site contem
também instruções para o professor para o uso do objeto de 
aprendizagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'installazione dei sistemi di riscaldamento che 
imparano il materiale è intesa mentre un sostegno insegnamento del 
contatto dentro, i lavori dell'installazione di HEPAC o sulle abilità
di base di tecnologia della casa per esempio, di studio studia i 
moduli. Il Web site è adatto a studio sulle basi di 
installazione come in linea insegnando. Il materiale imparante 
è basato sul metodo imparante investigativo e fornisce all'allievo i 
problemi imparanti, cioè, esercitazioni e mansioni. Il Web site
contiene le immagini pratiche dell'installazione che possono essere 
usate per cercare le soluzioni ai problemi. Il contenuto del Web
site è significato come uno strumento ed introduzione a pensare, che 
è esaminato nella profondità più grande con l'altro materiale 
scritto di studio. Il Web site egualmente contiene le istruzioni
per l'insegnante per uso dell'oggetto imparante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εγκατάσταση του υλικού εκμάθησης συστημάτων 
θέρμανσης προορίζεται ως υποστήριξη για τη διδασκαλία επαφών, 
παραδείγματος χάριν, στη μελέτη των βασικών δεξιοτήτων 
τεχνολογίας σπιτιών ή οι εργασίες εγκαταστάσεων HEPAC 
μελετούν τις ενότητες. Ο ιστοχώρος είναι κατάλληλος για τη 
μελέτη των βάσεων της εγκατάστασης ως σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
διδασκαλία. Το υλικό εκμάθησης είναι βασισμένο στην 
εξεταστική μέθοδο εκμάθησης και παρέχει στο σπουδαστή τα 
μαθησιακά προβλήματα, δηλ., τις ασκήσεις και τις στοιχειώδεις 
εργασίες. Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις πρακτικές εικόνες 
εγκαταστάσεων που μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για να ψάξουν τις 
λύσεις στα προβλήματα. Το περιεχόμενο του ιστοχώρου 
σημαίνουν ως εργαλείο και εισαγωγή στη σκέψη, η οποία εξετάζεται
σε μεγαλύτερο βάθος με άλλο γραπτό υλικό μελέτης. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιέχει επίσης τις οδηγίες για το δάσκαλο για τη 
χρήση του αντικειμένου εκμάθησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La instalación de los sistemas de calefacción que
aprenden el material se piensa mientras que una ayuda para la 
enseñanza del contacto adentro, los trabajos por ejemplo, del estudio
de las habilidades básicas de la tecnología de la casa o de la 
instalación de HEPAC estudia los módulos. El Web site es 
conveniente para el estudio de las bases de la instalación como en 
línea enseñando. El material que aprende se basa en el método
que aprende investigador y provee del estudiante los problemas que 
aprenden, es decir, ejercicios y tareas. El Web site contiene 
los cuadros prácticos de la instalación que se pueden utilizar para 
buscar soluciones a los problemas. El contenido del Web site se 
significa como una herramienta e introducción al pensamiento, que se 
examina en mayor profundidad con el otro material escrito del estudio.
El Web site también contiene las instrucciones para el profesor
para el uso del objeto que aprende.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jari Lehtikangas
n:Lehtikangas;Jari
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Trelin mediapalvelut
n:Trelin mediapalvelut
org:Trelin mediapalvelut
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pertti Krankkala
n:Krankkala;Pertti
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/5F75ECF5-5CBD-5B2A-3516-B98571D42650</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/5F75ECF5-5CBD-5B2A-3516-B98571D42650</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ilkka Mäkitalo
n:Mäkitalo;Ilkka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:02.55Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>tool</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>exploration</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>161</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1309</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>160</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio3/index.htm</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/lvi/aihio3/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
