<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222638</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222638</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/arjenilot</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/arjenilot</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/arjenilot</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Everyday delights study material</string>
            <string language="fi">Arjen ilot -oppimateriaali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tägliches Freuden Studie Material</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Matériel journalier d'étude de plaisirs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Material diário do estudo dos prazeres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Materiale giornaliere di studio di piaceri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθημερινό υλικό μελέτης απολαύσεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Material diario del estudio de los placeres</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <language>ru</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Everyday delights web learning material is topical supplementary material that complements Russian textbooks, and is designed to inspire and maintain interest in studying Russian. It is targeted at upper secondary school pupils and adult students and is suitable for various levels: from beginners to the more advanced. The material contains video clips, linguistic phrases and personal interviews. The video clip file is saved onto a computer (contains precise instructions for saving and viewing the video file). Also contains a variety of exercises, including aural comprehensions, vocabulary exercises, practising usage situations and speech phrases.</string>
            <string language="fi">Arjen ilot -verkko-oppimateriaali on venäjän oppikirjoja täydentävä ja ajankohtainen oheismateriaali, jonka tarkoitus on innostaa ja ylläpitää mielenkiintoa venäjän opiskeluun. Se on suunnattu lukiolaisille ja aikuisopiskelijoille ja soveltuu eri tasoille: alkeista edistyneemmille. Materiaali sisältää videoleikkeitä, kielellisiä fraaseja ja henkilöhaastatteluja. Videoleiketiedosto tallennetaan tietokoneelle (sisältää tarkat ohjeet videotiedoston tallentamista ja katsomista varten). Sisältää myös monipuolisia harjoituksia, mm. kuullun ymmärtämisiä, sanastoharjoituksia, kielenkäyttötilanteiden ja puhefraasien harjoittelua.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das erlernenmaterial des täglichen Freuden Webs 
ist aktuelles Ergänzungsmaterial, das russische Lehrbücher ergänzt,
und ist konzipiert, Interesse anzuspornen und beizubehalten, an, 
Russen zu studieren. Es wird an den obersekundarschuleschülern 
und an den Erwachsenkursteilnehmern gezielt und ist für verschiedene 
Stufen verwendbar: von den Anfängern zum hochentwickelteren. 
Das Material enthält videoclips, linguistische Phrasen und 
persönliche Interviews. Die videoclipdatei wird auf einen 
Computer gesichert (enthält exakte Anweisungen für Einsparung und 
Betrachtung die videodatei). Enthält auch eine Vielzahl von 
Übungen, einschließlich Ohrenerfassen, Wortschatzübungen, übende 
Verbrauchsituationen und Redephrasen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matériel d'étude de Web journalier de 
plaisirs est un matériel supplémentaire topique qui complète les 
manuels russes, et est conçu pour inspirer et mettre à jour 
l'intérêt en étudiant le russe. Il est visé aux élèves 
d'école et aux étudiants secondaires deuxième cycle d'adulte et 
convient pour différents niveaux : des débutants au plus 
avançé. Le matériel contient les clips visuels, les 
expressions linguistiques et les entrevues personnelles. Le 
fichier visuel de clip est sauvegardé sur un ordinateur (contient des
instructions précises pour l'économie et le visionnement le fichier 
visuel). Contient en outre une variété d'exercices, y compris 
des compréhensions auditives, des exercices de vocabulaire, des 
situations de pratique d'utilisation et des expressions de la parole.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O material de aprendizagem do Web diário dos 
prazeres é o material suplementar tópico que complementa os 
textbooks russian, e é projetado inspirar e manter o interesse em 
estudar o russian. É alvejado nos alunos da escola secundária 
e em estudantes superiores do adulto e é apropriado para vários 
níveis: dos novatos ao mais avançado. O material contem 
os grampos video, frases lingüísticas e entrevistas pessoais. 
A lima video do grampo é conservada em um computador (contem 
instruções precisas para o saving e a visão a lima video). 
Contem também uma variedade dos exercícios, including 
compreensões aural, exercícios do vocabulário, situações 
praticando do uso e frases do discurso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il materiale imparante di Web giornaliere di 
piaceri è materiale supplementare d'attualità che complementa i 
manuali russi ed è destinato ad ispirare ed effettuare l'interesse 
nello studiare il Russo. È designato agli allievi della scuola 
ed agli allievi superiori-secondarii dell'adulto ed è adatto per vari
livelli: dai principianti all'più avanzato. Il materiale 
contiene le video clip, le frasi linguistiche e le interviste 
personali. Il video archivio della clip è salvato su un 
calcolatore (contiene le istruzioni precise per il saving e 
l'osservazione il video archivio). Egualmente contiene una 
varietà di esercitazioni, compreso le comprensioni sonore, le 
esercitazioni di vocabolario, le situazioni esercitantesi di uso e le 
frasi di discorso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το καθημερινό υλικό εκμάθησης Ιστού απολαύσεων είναι
επίκαιρο συμπληρωματικό υλικό που συμπληρώνει τα ρωσικά 
εγχειρίδια, και σχεδιάζεται για να εμπνεύσει και να διατηρήσει το 
ενδιαφέρον για τη μελέτη των ρωσικών. Στοχεύει στους 
ανώτερους μαθητές δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης και τους ενήλικους 
σπουδαστές και είναι κατάλληλος για τα διάφορα επίπεδα: 
από τους αρχαρίους σε πιό προηγμένη. Το υλικό 
περιέχει τους τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες, τις γλωσσικές φράσεις και 
τις προσωπικές συνεντεύξεις. Το τηλεοπτικό αρχείο 
συνδετήρων σώζεται επάνω σε έναν υπολογιστή (περιέχει τις 
ακριβείς οδηγίες για τη διάσωση και την όψη του τηλεοπτικού 
αρχείου). Επίσης περιέχει ποικίλες ασκήσεις, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των ακουστικών κατανοήσεων, των ασκήσεων 
λεξιλογίου, των καταστάσεων χρήσης άσκησης και των λεκτικών 
φράσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El material que aprende del Web diario de los 
placeres es el material suplementario tópico que complementa los 
libros de textos rusos, y se diseña inspirar y mantener interés en 
estudiar ruso. Se apunta en las pupilas de la escuela y los 
estudiantes superiores-secundarios del adulto y es conveniente para 
los varios niveles: de principiantes al más avanzado. El 
material contiene los clips video, las frases lingüísticas y las 
entrevistas personales. El fichero video del clip se salva sobre
un ordenador (contiene las instrucciones exactas para el ahorro y la 
visión el fichero video). También contiene una variedad de 
ejercicios, incluyendo comprensiones aurales, ejercicios del 
vocabulario, situaciones practicantes del uso y frases del discurso.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anne Lindholm
n:Lindholm;Anne
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet Oy
n:Lingonet Oy
org:Lingonet Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:al et
n:et;al
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/F7787C69-4C94-0B23-3857-D7D9C528D09B</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/F7787C69-4C94-0B23-3857-D7D9C528D09B</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:21.92Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1115</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>461</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>709</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/arjenilot</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/arjenilot</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
