<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/80339</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>80339</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/fysiikka/sahko/electricity_8/home.htm</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/fysiikka/sahko/electricity_8/home.htm</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Puolijohteet - transistorien käytännön sovelluksia</string>
            <string language="en">Semiconductors – practical applications of transistors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Halbleiter? praktische Anwendungen der 
Transistoren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Semi-conducteurs ? applications pratiques 
des transistors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Semicondutores? aplicações práticas dos 
transistor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Semiconduttori? applicazioni pratiche dei 
transistori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ημιαγωγοί; πρακτικές εφαρμογές των 
κρυσταλλολυχνιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Semiconductores? aplicaciones prácticas 
de transistores</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Oppimisaihio on tarkoitettu perusopetuksen fysiikan sähköopin opiskeluun ja kertaukseen. Aihio sopii parhaiten verkossa tapahtuvaan ryhmätyöskentelyyn, mutta sitä voidaan hyödyntää myös itsenäisessä opiskelussa. Sivusto sisältää opettajan ohjeet ja ehdotuksen opiskelun kuluksi. Sivuston käyttö edellyttää selaimelta Macromedia Shockwave -laajennusta. Oppilaiden olisi hyvä tuntea etukäteen virta ja jännite. Koulussa oppilaiden tulisi lisäksi olla jo tutustunut piirilevyn ja komponenttien käyttöön. Aihiossa oppilas tutustuu ensin teoriaan, tekee kokeet transistorista kytkimenä ja vahvistimena ja testaa lopuksi tietonsa.</string>
            <string language="en">The learning object is intended for the study and revision of theory of electricity in basic physics teaching. The object is best suited to online group work, but it can also be utilised in independent study. The website contains the teacher’s instructions and a suggestion for the progress of study. Use of the website requires a Macromedia Shockwave add-on in the browser. It would be good for the pupils to be familiar in advance with current and voltage. At school, the pupils ought in addition to have already learnt about use of a circuit board and components. In the object, the pupil first learns about theory, performs tests concerning a transistor as a switch and amplifier and finally tests his/her knowledge.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">alkeispiirit</string>
            <string language="fi">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die erlernennachricht ist für die Studie und die
Änderung der Theorie von Elektrizität im grundlegenden 
Physikunterricht bestimmt. Die Nachricht wird gut entsprochen, 
um Arbeit online zu gruppieren, aber sie kann in der unabhängigen 
Studie auch verwendet werden. Die Web site enthält die 
teacher?s Anweisungen und einen Vorschlag für den Fortschritt der 
Studie. Gebrauch von der Web site benötigt einen Macromedia 
Shockwavezusatz in der Datenbanksuchroutine. Es würde gut für 
die Pupillen sein, im voraus mit Strom und Spannung vertraut zu sein. 
An der Schule sollen die Schüler zusätzlich zu über Gebrauch 
von einer Leiterplatte und Bestandteilen bereits erlernt haben. 
In der Nachricht erlernt die Schüler zuerst über Theorie, 
führt die Tests hinsichtlich sind eines Transistors wie ein Schalter 
und ein Verstärker durch und prüft schließlich seins/ihr Wissen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'objet d'étude est destiné pour l'étude et la
révision de la théorie de l'électricité dans l'enseignement de 
base de physique. L'objet est plus adapté pour grouper en ligne
le travail, mais il peut également être utilisé dans l'étude 
indépendante. Le site Web contient les instructions de 
teacher?s et une suggestion pour le progrès de l'étude. 
L'utilisation du site Web exige une adjonction d'onde de choc de
Macromedia dans le navigateur. Il serait bon que les pupilles 
soient au courant à l'avance du courant et de la tension. À 
l'école, les élèves doivent en plus de s'être déjà renseignés 
sur l'utilisation d'une carte et des composants. Dans l'objet, 
l'élève d'abord se renseigne sur la théorie, réalise des essais au
sujet d'un transistor comme un commutateur et un amplificateur et 
teste finalement sa connaissance.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objeto de aprendizagem é pretendido para o 
estudo e a revisão da teoria da eletricidade no ensino básico da 
física. O objeto é servido melhor para agrupar em linha o 
trabalho, mas pode também ser utilizado no estudo independente. 
O Web site contem as instruções dos teacher?s e uma sugestão 
para o progresso do estudo. O uso do Web site requer um add-on 
do shockwave de Macromedia no browser. Seria bom para as pupilas
ser familiar adiantado com a corrente e a tensão. Na escola, os
alunos ought além já ter aprendido sobre o uso de uma placa e de 
componentes de circuito. No objeto, o aluno primeiramente 
aprende sobre a teoria, executa os testes a respeito de um transistor 
como um interruptor e um amplificador e testa finalmente his/her 
conhecimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'oggetto imparante è inteso per lo studio e la 
revisione della teoria di elettricità nell'insegnamento di base di 
fisica. L'oggetto è più adatto in linea raggruppare il lavoro,
ma può anche essere utilizzato nello studio indipendente. Il 
Web site contiene le istruzioni dei teacher?s e un suggerimento per il
progresso dello studio. L'uso del Web site richiede un'adjunta 
di shockwave di Macromedia nel browser. Sarebbe in anticipo 
buono affinchè le pupille abbia familiarità con la corrente e la 
tensione. Alla scuola, gli allievi devono oltre che già 
imparare circa uso di un bordo e dei componenti del circuito. 
Nell'oggetto, l'allievo in primo luogo impara circa la teoria, 
effettua le prove riguardo ad un transistore come un interruttore e un
amplificatore ed infine verifica la sua conoscenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το αντικείμενο εκμάθησης προορίζεται για τη μελέτη και
την αναθεώρηση της θεωρίας της ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας στη βασική 
διδασκαλία φυσικής. Το αντικείμενο είναι καταλληλότερο για 
να ομαδοποιήσει on-line την εργασία, αλλά μπορεί επίσης να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί στην ανεξάρτητη μελέτη. Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει
τις οδηγίες teacher?s και μια πρόταση για την πρόοδο της 
μελέτης. Η χρήση του ιστοχώρου απαιτεί shockwave 
Macromedia πρόσθετο στον ξεφυλλιστή. Θα ήταν καλό για 
τους μαθητές για να εξοικειωθεί εκ των προτέρων με το ρεύμα και 
την τάση. Στο σχολείο, οι μαθητές πρέπει εκτός από να 
έχουν μάθει ήδη για τη χρήση ενός πίνακα κυκλωμάτων και των 
συστατικών. Στο αντικείμενο, ο μαθητής μαθαίνει αρχικά για 
τη θεωρία, εκτελεί τις δοκιμές σχετικά με μια κρυσταλλολυχνία ως 
διακόπτη και ενισχυτή και εξετάζει τελικά τη γνώση του/της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objeto que aprende se piensa para el estudio y
la revisión de la teoría de la electricidad en la enseñanza básica
de la física. El objeto se satisface lo más mejor posible en 
línea para agrupar el trabajo, pero puede también ser utilizado en 
estudio independiente. El Web site contiene las instrucciones de 
los teacher?s y una sugerencia para el progreso del estudio. El 
uso del Web site requiere una agregación de la onda de choque de 
Macromedia en el browser. Sería bueno que las pupilas sean 
familiar por adelantado con la corriente y el voltaje. En la 
escuela, las pupilas ought además de haber aprendido ya sobre uso de 
una tarjeta y de los componentes de circuito. En el objeto, la 
pupila primero aprende sobre teoría, realiza pruebas referentes a un 
transistor como un interruptor y un amplificador y finalmente prueba 
su conocimiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">alkeispiirit</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Oppomedia Oy
n:Oppomedia Oy
org:Oppomedia Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/CB7624DB-170F-15FE-253D-5F19216A8074</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/CB7624DB-170F-15FE-253D-5F19216A8074</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anna-Elina Häkkilä
n:Häkkilä;Anna-Elina 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-04-09T19:44:02.31Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>project</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Creative commons Nimeä-epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>411</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>978</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>80339</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/fysiikka/sahko/electricity_8/home.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
