<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/virtuaalikoulu/lahdeesiin</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/virtuaalikoulu/lahdeesiin</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/virtuaalikoulu/lahdeesiin</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lähde esiin – Source presented</string>
            <string language="fi">Lähde esiin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lähde esiin? Quelle stellte sich dar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Esiin de Lähde ? Source présentée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esiin de Lähde? A fonte apresentou-se</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esiin di Lähde? La sorgente si è 
presentata</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Lδhde esiin; Πηγή που παρουσιάζεται</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Esiin de Lähde? La fuente presentó</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The website offers schools a complete teaching package on criticism of sources. Pithy texts are supplemented by exercises that the pupils can do independently or in class with the other pupils. The site provides assistance in the critical examination of the Internet and other information sources, and inspires individualistic thinking. The website contains three themes with exercises: criticism of sources, ethics and plagiarism, and copyright. The website is available free-of-charge and is suitable for all subjects. The teaching package is best suited in general and vocational upper secondary schools, but it can also be used in the upper grades of comprehensive schools. Contains teacher’s materials.</string>
            <string language="fi">Lähde esiin –verkkosivut tarjoavat kouluille valmiin opetuspaketin lähdekritiikistä. Ytimekkäitä tekstejä täydentävät harjoitukset, joita oppilas voi ratkoa itsenäisesti tai luokassa muiden kanssa. Sivut opastavat netin ja muiden tietolähteiden kriittiseen tarkasteluun ja innostavat omaan ajatteluun. Lähde esiin sisältää kolme teemaa harjoituksineen: lähdekritiikki,etiikka ja plagiointi sekä tekijänoikeus. Maksuton Lähde esiin on tarkoitettu kaikkiin oppiaineisiin. Opetuspaketti sopii parhaiten lukioon ja ammatilliseen peruskoulutukseen, mutta sitä voidaan hyödyntää myös peruskoulun ylemmillä luokilla. Sisältää opettajan materiaalin.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Web site bietet Schulen ein komplettes 
unterrichtendes Paket auf Kritik von Quellen an. Markige Texte 
werden durch Übungen ergänzt, die die Pupillen in der Kategorie mit 
den anderen Pupillen unabhängig oder tun können. Die Site 
unterstützt in der kritischen Prüfung des Internets und anderer 
Informationsquellen und spornt das individualistische Denken an. 
Die Web site enthält drei Themen mit Übungen: Kritik von
Quellen, Ethik und plagiarism und copyright. Die Web site ist 
frei-von-aufladen und sind verwendbar für alle Themen vorhanden. 
Das unterrichtende Paket wird gut in den allgemeinen und 
beruflichen obersekundarschulen entsprochen, aber es kann in den 
oberen Graden der kompletten Schulen auch benutzt werden. 
Enthält teacher?s Materialien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le site Web offre à des écoles un module 
d'enseignement complet sur la critique des sources. Des textes 
vigoureux sont complétés par les exercices que les pupilles peuvent 
faire indépendamment ou dans la classe avec les autres pupilles. 
Le site fournit l'aide dans l'examen critique de l'Internet et 
d'autres émetteurs d'informations, et inspire la pensée 
individualiste. Le site Web contient trois thèmes avec des 
exercices : critique des sources, l'éthique et le plagiat, 
et le copyright. Le site Web est disponible libre-de-chargent et
conviennent à tous les sujets. Le module d'enseignement est 
plus adapté en général les écoles secondaires deuxième cycle et 
professionnelles, mais il peut également être utilisé dans les 
catégories supérieures des écoles d'enseignement secondaire. 
Contient des matériaux de teacher?s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Web site oferece a escolas um pacote ensinando 
completo no criticism das fontes. Os textos pithy são 
suplementados pelos exercícios que as pupilas podem fazer 
independentemente ou na classe com as outras pupilas. O local 
fornece o auxílio na examinação crítica do Internet e de outras 
fontes de informação, e inspira pensar individualistic. O Web 
site contem três temas com exercícios: criticism das fontes, o
ethics e o plagiarism, e o copyright. O Web site está 
disponível livre-$$$-CARREGA e é apropriado para todos os assuntos. 
O pacote ensinando é servido melhor em escolas secundárias 
superiores gerais e vocacionais, mas pode também ser usado nas 
classes superiores de escolas detalhadas. Contem materiais dos 
teacher?s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Web site offre a scuole un pacchetto 
d'istruzione completo sulla critica delle sorgenti. I testi 
vigorosi sono completati dalle esercitazioni che le pupille possono 
fare indipendentemente o nel codice categoria con le altre pupille. 
Il luogo fornisce l'assistenza nell'esame critico del Internet e
di altre sorgenti di informazioni ed ispira pensare individualistic. 
Il Web site contiene tre temi con le esercitazioni: 
critica delle sorgenti, etica e plagiarism e copyright. Il
Web site è disponibile libero-de-si carica ed è adatto a tutti gli 
oggetti. Il pacchetto d'istruzione è più adatto in scuole 
superiori-secondarie generali e professionali, ma può anche essere 
usato nei gradi superiori delle scuole complete. Contiene i 
materiali dei teacher?s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα σχολεία προσφορών ιστοχώρου μια πλήρης συσκευασία 
διδασκαλίας στην κριτική των πηγών. Τα μυελώδη κείμενα 
συμπληρώνονται με τις ασκήσεις που οι μαθητές μπορούν να κάνουν 
ανεξάρτητα ή στην κλάση με τους άλλους μαθητές. Η περιοχή 
παρέχει τη βοήθεια στην κρίσιμη εξέταση του Διαδικτύου και άλλων
πηγών πληροφοριών, και εμπνέει την ατομικιστική σκέψη. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιέχει τρία θέματα με τις ασκήσεις: κριτική 
των πηγών, της ηθικής και της λογοκλοπής, και των πνευματικών 
δικαιωμάτων. Ο ιστοχώρος είναι διαθέσιμος δωρεάν και είναι
κατάλληλος για όλα τα θέματα. Η συσκευασία διδασκαλίας 
είναι καταλληλότερη γενικά και επαγγελματική ανώτερη 
δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση, αλλά μπορεί επίσης να χρησιμοποιηθεί 
στις ανώτερες τάξεις των μονοτάξιων σχολείων. Περιέχει 
teacher?s τα υλικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Web site ofrece a escuelas un conjunto de 
enseñanza completo en la crítica de fuentes. Los textos 
sustanciales son suplidos por los ejercicios que las pupilas pueden 
hacer independientemente o en clase con las otras pupilas. El 
sitio proporciona a ayuda en la examinación crítica del Internet y 
de otras fuentes de información, e inspira el pensamiento 
individualista. El Web site contiene tres temas con ejercicios: 
crítica de fuentes, el ética y plagio, y copyright. 
El Web site está disponible libre-de-carga y es conveniente 
para todos los temas. El conjunto de enseñanza se satisface lo 
más mejor posible en escuelas superiores-secundarias generales y 
vocacionales, pero puede también ser utilizado en los grados 
superiores de institutos integrados. Contiene los materiales de 
los teacher?s.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:al et
n:et;al
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Olli Lehtonen
n:Lehtonen;Olli
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ruotsin kouluverkko
n:Ruotsin kouluverkko
org:Ruotsin kouluverkko
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Kolla Källan -projekti
n:Kolla Källan -projekti
org:Kolla Källan -projekti
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/94E0FBDE-5A0F-E307-FDE0-77743A6035D5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/94E0FBDE-5A0F-E307-FDE0-77743A6035D5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:41:28.84Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">14-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Tarttuva 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>288</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1093</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1094</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>697</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>287</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>441</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/virtuaalikoulu/lahdeesiin</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/virtuaalikoulu/lahdeesiin</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
