<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/235332</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>235332</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/119544_paikkatieto.pdf</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/119544_paikkatieto.pdf</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/119544_paikkatieto.pdf</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Support material on geographic information for geography teachers in upper secondary school</string>
            <string language="fi">Paikkatiedon tukimateriaali lukion maantieteen opettajille</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfsmaterial auf geographischen Informationen 
für Geographielehrer in der obersekundarschule</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Matériel de support sur l'information 
géographique pour des professeurs de géographie à l'école 
secondaire deuxième cycle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Material de sustentação na informação 
geográfica para professores da geografia na escola secundária 
superior</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Materiale di sostegno sulle informazioni 
geografiche per gli insegnanti di geografia a scuola 
superiore-secondaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υλικό υποστήριξης στις γεωγραφικές πληροφορίες για 
τους δασκάλους γεωγραφίας στην ανώτερη δευτεροβάθμια εκπαίδευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Material de ayuda en la información geográfica 
para los profesores de la geografía en escuela superior-secundaria</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A basic pack on geographic information for the upper secondary school teacher, in PDF format. It examines the bases of geographic information, the basic functions of software and various applications of and sources of information on geographic information from the viewpoint of schools. The work offers information for both the beginner and the teacher who is already familiar with the subject: it is suitable as background material when planning the teaching for an area study course as part of upper secondary school geography, or for applied GIS and cartography courses.</string>
            <string language="fi">Pdf-muodossa julkaistu lukion opettajan peruspaketti paikkatiedosta. Se käsittelee paikkatiedon perusteita, ohjelmistojen perustoimintoja sekä paikkatiedon sovellusmahdollisuuksia ja tietolähteitä koulumaailman näkökulmasta. Teos tarjoaa tietoa niin aloittelevalle kuin jo aiheeseen tutustuneelle opettajalle: se sopii taustamateriaaliksi lukion maantieteen aluetutkimuskurssin tai soveltavien GIS- ja kartografiakurssien opetusta suunniteltaessa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein grundlegender Satz auf geographischen 
Informationen für den obersekundarschulelehrer, im pdf Format. 
Es überprüft die Unterseiten der geographischen Informationen,
der grundlegenden Funktionen der Software und der verschiedenen 
Anwendungen von und der Quellen der Informationen über geographische 
Informationen von der Veranschaulichung der Schulen. Die Arbeit 
bietet Informationen für den Anfänger und den Lehrer an, der bereits
mit dem Thema vertraut ist: es ist als Hintergrundmaterial 
verwendbar, wenn man den Unterricht für einen Bereich Studie Kurs als
Teil der obersekundarschulegeographie oder für angewandte GIS und 
Cartographykurse plant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un paquet de base sur l'information géographique
pour le professeur secondaire deuxième cycle d'école, dans le format
de pdf. Il examine les bases d'information géographique, de 
fonctions de base de logiciel et de diverses applications de et de 
sources d'information sur l'information géographique du point de vue 
des écoles. Le travail offre l'information pour le débutant et
le professeur qui est déjà au courant du sujet : il convient 
comme matière de base en projetant l'enseignement pour un cours 
d'étude de zone en tant qu'élément de la géographie secondaire 
deuxième cycle d'école, ou pour des GIs et des cours 
appliqués de cartographie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um bloco básico na informação geográfica para
o professor superior da escola secundária, no formato do pdf. 
Examina as bases da informação geográfica, das funções 
básicas do software e de várias aplicações de e de fontes da 
informação na informação geográfica do viewpoint das escolas. 
O trabalho oferece a informação para  o novato e o professor 
que é já familiar com o assunto: é apropriado como o material
de fundo ao planear o ensino para um curso do estudo da área como a 
parte da geografia superior da escola secundária, ou para SOLDADOS e 
cursos aplicados do cartography.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un pacchetto di base sulle informazioni 
geografiche per l'insegnante superiore-secondario della scuola, nel 
formato del pdf. Esamina le basi delle informazioni geografiche,
delle funzioni di base di software e di varie applicazioni di e delle 
sorgenti delle informazioni sulle informazioni geografiche dal punto 
di vista delle scuole. Il lavoro offre le informazioni per sia 
il principiante che l'insegnante che ha una conoscenza di già con 
l'oggetto: è adatto come materiale di base quando progetta 
l'insegnamento per un corso di studio di zona come componente della 
geografia superiore-secondaria della scuola, o per i GIS ed i corsi 
applicati di cartografia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα βασικό πακέτο στις γεωγραφικές πληροφορίες για 
τον ανώτερο δάσκαλο δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης, με τη μορφή 
PDF. Εξετάζει τις βάσεις των γεωγραφικών πληροφοριών, τις
βασικές λειτουργίες του λογισμικού και τις διάφορες εφαρμογές και
τις πηγές πληροφοριών για τις γεωγραφικές πληροφορίες από την 
άποψη των σχολείων. Η εργασία προσφέρει τις πληροφορίες και
για τον αρχάριο και για το δάσκαλο που εξοικειώνεται ήδη με το 
θέμα: είναι κατάλληλο ως υλικό υποβάθρου κατά την 
προγραμματισμό της διδασκαλίας για μια σειρά μαθημάτων μελέτης 
περιοχής ως τμήμα της ανώτερης γεωγραφίας δευτεροβάθμιας 
εκπαίδευσης, ή για τις εφαρμοσμένες σειρές μαθημάτων GIS και 
χαρτογραφίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un paquete básico en la información geográfica
para el profesor superior-secundario de la escuela, en formato del 
pdf. Examina las bases de la información geográfica, de las 
funciones básicas del software y de las varias aplicaciones de y de 
las fuentes de la información sobre la información geográfica del 
punto de vista de escuelas. El trabajo ofrece la información 
para el principiante y el profesor que es ya familiar con el tema: 
es conveniente como material de base al planear la enseñanza 
para un curso del estudio del área como parte de la geografía 
superior-secundaria de la escuela, o para los SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN EL
EJÉRCITO y los cursos aplicados de la cartografía.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ilkka Blomqvist
n:Blomqvist;Ilkka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Tino Johansson
n:Johansson;Tino
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/974CA4AD-035E-CAEC-1D7E-7F4FBBE6B565</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/974CA4AD-035E-CAEC-1D7E-7F4FBBE6B565</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katja Pajuluoma
n:Pajuluoma;Katja 
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:36:11.14Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1353</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>875</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>540</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>176</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1141</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1272</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/119544_paikkatieto.pdf</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>application/pdf</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/instancedata/prime_product_julkaisu/oph/embeds/119544_paikkatieto.pdf</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
