<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222530</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222530</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;26945</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;26945</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;26945</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Volleyball</string>
            <string language="fi">Lentopallo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Volleyball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Volleyball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Volleyball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Volleyball</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πετοσφαίριση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Voleibol</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The various forms and ball tricks of volleyball provide interesting activity for everyone from preschoolers to active players. The purpose of the website is for the teacher to find quickly and effectively support for the planning and implementation of the content of his/her lessons. The website contains various game developments organised by age-group, game rules with applications, sample lessons, ball tricks and skill performances to motivate pupils as well as instructions for starting the game and for obtaining the right equipment. The website also contains video clips which can only be viewed with Macromedia Flash-player.</string>
            <string language="fi">Lentopallon erilaiset pelimuodot ja pallotemput tarjoavat mielenkiintoista toimintaa aina esiluokkalaisista lajia aktiivisesti harrastaviin asti. Verkkosivuston tarkoituksena on, että opettaja löytäisi nopeasti ja tehokkaasti tuen oppituntiensa sisällön suunnitteluun ja toteutukseen. Sivusto sisältää vuosiluokittain jäsennettyjä erilaisia pelikehittelyitä, pelisäännöt sovelluksineen, mallioppitunteja, oppilaita motivoivia pallotemppuja ja taitosuorituksia sekä ohjeita pelin aloittamiselle ja oikeiden pelivälineiden hankkimiselle. Sivusto sisältää myös videoleikkeitä, joiden katseluun tarvitaan Macromedian Flash-player.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die verschiedenen Formulare und die Kugeltricks 
des Volleyball stellen interessante Aktivität für jeder von den 
Vorschülern zu den aktiven Spielern zur Verfügung. Der Zweck 
der Web site ist, damit der Lehrer schnell findet und effektiv für 
die Planung und die Implementierung des Inhalts sein/ihr Lektionen 
unterstützt. Die Web site enthält die verschiedenen 
Spielentwicklungen, die durch Altersklasse organisiert werden, ordnet 
Spiel mit Anwendungen, Beispiellektionen an, betrügt Kugel und 
Fähigkeit Leistungen, um Pupillen sowie Anweisungen für das Beginnen
des Spiels und für das Erhalten der rechten Ausrüstung zu 
motivieren. Die Web site enthält auch videoclips, die mit 
Macromedia Blitz-Spieler nur angesehen werden können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les divers formes et tours de boule du volleyball 
fournissent l'activité intéressante pour chacun des élèves du 
cours préparatoire aux joueurs actifs. Le but du site Web est 
pour que le professeur trouve rapidement et à supporte pertinemment 
pour la planification et la mise en place de la teneur de ses leçons.
Le site Web contient de divers développements de jeu organisés
par le groupe d'âge, le jeu règne avec des applications, leçons 
d'échantillon, la boule dupe et les exécutions de compétence pour 
motiver des pupilles aussi bien que des instructions pour commencer le
jeu et pour obtenir le matériel droit. Le site Web contient 
également les clips visuels qui peuvent seulement être visualisés 
avec le Flash-joueur de Macromedia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os vários formulários e truques da esfera do 
volleyball fornecem atividade interessante para todos dos preschoolers
aos jogadores ativos. A finalidade do Web site é para que o 
professor encontre rapidamente e suporte eficazmente para o 
planeamento e a execução do índice de his/her lições. O Web
site contem os vários desenvolvimentos do jogo organizados pelo 
age-group, o jogo governa com as aplicações, lições da amostra, a 
esfera enganam e os desempenhos da habilidade para motivate as pupilas
as.well.as instruções para começar o jogo e para obter o 
equipamento direito. O Web site contem também os grampos video 
que podem somente ser vistos com Flash-jogador de Macromedia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le vari forme e trucchi della sfera di volleyball 
forniscono l'attività interessante per tutto dai preschoolers ai 
giocatori attivi. Lo scopo del Web site è affinchè 
l'insegnante trovi rapidamente e da contributo efficacemente alla 
progettazione ed all'implementazione del contenuto delle sue lezioni. 
Il Web site contiene i vari sviluppi del gioco organizzati dalla
fascia d'età, il gioco regola con le applicazioni, lezioni del 
campione, la sfera inganna e le prestazioni di abilità per motivare 
le pupille così come le istruzioni per iniziare il gioco e per 
ottenere l'apparecchiatura di destra. Il Web site egualmente 
contiene le video clip che possono essere osservate soltanto con il 
Flash-giocatore di Macromedia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι διάφορα μορφές και τα τεχνάσματα σφαιρών της 
πετοσφαίρισης παρέχουν την ενδιαφέρουσα δραστηριότητα για το 
καθένα από τα preschoolers στους ενεργούς φορείς. Ο 
σκοπός του ιστοχώρου είναι για το δάσκαλο να βρεί γρήγορα και 
αποτελεσματικά υποστήριξη για τον προγραμματισμό και την εφαρμογή 
του περιεχομένου των μαθημάτων του/της. Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει
τις διάφορες εξελίξεις παιχνιδιών που οργανώνονται από την 
κλάση, κανόνες παιχνιδιών με τις εφαρμογές, τα μαθήματα 
δειγμάτων, τα τεχνάσματα σφαιρών και τις αποδόσεις ικανότητας για
να παρακινήσουν τους μαθητές καθώς επίσης και τις οδηγίες για την
έναρξη του παιχνιδιού και για τη λήψη του σωστού εξοπλισμού. 
Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει επίσης τους τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες 
που μπορούν μόνο να εμφανιστούν με τον στιγμιαίος-φορέα 
Macromedia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las varios formas y trucos de la bola del voleibol
proporcionan a la actividad interesante para cada uno de preschoolers 
a los jugadores activos. El propósito del Web site está para 
que el profesor encuentre rápidamente y utilice con eficacia para las
hojas de operación (planning) y la puesta en práctica del contenido 
de su lecciones. El Web site contiene los varios progresos del 
juego ordenados por el grupo de misma edad, el juego gobierna con las 
aplicaciones, lecciones de la muestra, la bola trampea y los 
funcionamientos de la habilidad para motivar pupilas así como las 
instrucciones para comenzar el juego y para obtener el equipo derecho.
El Web site también contiene los clips video que se pueden ver 
solamente con el Flash-jugador de Macromedia.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Suomen lentopalloliitto
n:Suomen lentopalloliitto
org:Suomen lentopalloliitto
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/008CCA11-3DA7-F2F0-92D8-B953D3F620BB</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/008CCA11-3DA7-F2F0-92D8-B953D3F620BB</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Annika Ranta
n:Ranta;Annika 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:43:18.81Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>guide</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498,507,19640</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1285</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>974</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;26945</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/page.asp?path=498;1329;1528;21094;19155;26945</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
