<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223003</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/turvallisuus</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/turvallisuus</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/turvallisuus</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Security sector study material: Identification of risk factors as well as prevention of disaster, accident and damage situations</string>
            <string language="fi">Turvallisuusalan oppimateriaali: Vaaratekijöiden tunnistaminen sekä onnettomuus-, tapaturma- ja vahinkotilanteiden ennaltaehkäisy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sicherheit Sektor-Studie Material: 
Kennzeichen der Gefahr Faktoren sowie Verhinderung der Unfall-, 
Unfall- und Beschädigungssituationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Matériel d'étude de secteur de sécurité : 
Identification des facteurs de risque aussi bien que la 
prévention des situations de désastre, d'accidents et de dommages</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Material do estudo do setor da segurança: 
Identificação de fatores de risco as.well.as a prevenção de 
situações do disastre, do acidente e dos danos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Materiale di studio del settore di sicurezza: 
Identificazione dei fattori di rischio così come la prevenzione
delle situazioni di disastro, di incidente e di danni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υλικό μελέτης τομέα της ασφάλειας: 
Προσδιορισμός των παραγόντων κινδύνου καθώς επίσης και 
πρόληψη των καταστάσεων καταστροφής, ατυχήματος και ζημίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Material del estudio del sector de la seguridad: 
Identificación de los factores de riesgo así como la 
prevención de las situaciones del desastre, del accidente y del 
daños</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The skills of people working in the security sector include effective identification of risk factors. By identifying time disaster, damage and accident risks, it is possible to prevent the occurrence of harmful events. Identification skill is practised only through work experience. You can use this study material simulating the work environment to practise these skills already prior to starting work tasks during your studies.

This learning material also contains theoretical information on identifying risk factors and risk management as well as statistical information on the commonest risk factors. The learning material is targeted at vocational secondary basic education in the security sector.

Four different targets can be chosen in the exercise: an industrial property, store, school and railway station.</string>
            <string language="fi">Turvallisuusalalla työskentelevien ammattitaitoon kuuluu tehokas vaaratekijöiden tunnistaminen. Tunnistamalla ajoissa onnettomuus-, vahinko- ja tapaturmavaarat pystytään ennalta ehkäisemään haittatapahtumien toteutuminen. Tunnistamistaito harjaantuu vain työkokemuksen kautta. Tämän työympäristöä simuloivan oppimateriaalin avulla voit harjoitella näitä taitoja jo ennen työtehtävien aloittamista opintojesi aikana. 

Tämä oppimateriaali sisältää myös teoriatietoa vaaratekijöiden tunnistamisesta, riskienhallinnasta sekä tilastotietoa yleisimmistä riskitekijöistä. Oppimateriaali on suunnattu ammatillisen toisen asteen turvallisuusalan peruskoulutukseen. 

Harjoituksessa on valittavana neljä erilaista kohdetta: teollisuuskiinteistö, myymälä, koulu ja rautatieasema.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Fähigkeiten der Leute, die im Sicherheit 
Sektor arbeiten, schließen wirkungsvolles Kennzeichen der Gefahr 
Faktoren ein. Indem man Zeitunfall, Beschädigung und 
Unfallgefahren kennzeichnet, ist es möglich, das Auftreten der 
schädlichen Fälle zu verhindern. Kennzeichenfähigkeit wird 
nur durch Arbeit Erfahrung geübt. Sie können dieses Studie 
Material benutzen die Arbeit Umgebung simulierend, um diese 
Fähigkeiten bereits vor beginnenden Tätigkeiten während Ihres 
studies.This zu üben erlernend, daß Material auch theoretische 
Informationen über das Kennzeichnen von von Gefahr Faktoren und von 
von Risikomanagement sowie statistische Informationen über die 
geläufigsten Gefahr Faktoren enthält. Das erlernenmaterial 
wird an der beruflichen grundlegenden zweitensausbildung in der 
Sicherheit sector.Four gezielt, das unterschiedliche Ziele in der 
Übung gewählt werden können: ein gewerbliches Eigentum, ein 
Speicher, eine Schule und ein Bahnhof.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les qualifications des personnes travaillant dans
le secteur de sécurité incluent l'identification pertinente des 
facteurs de risque. En identifiant le désastre de temps, des 
dommages et des risques d'accidents, il est possible d'empêcher 
l'occurrence des événements nocifs. La compétence 
d'identification est pratiquée seulement par l'expérience 
professionnelle. Vous pouvez utiliser ce matériel d'étude 
simulant l'environnement de travail pour pratiquer ces qualifications 
déjà avant de commencer le travail charge pendant votre 
studies.This apprenant que le matériel contient également 
l'information théorique sur identifier les facteurs de risque et la 
gestion des risques aussi bien que l'information statistique sur les 
facteurs de risque les plus communs. Le matériel d'étude est 
visé à l'éducation de base secondaire professionnelle dans la 
sécurité sector.Four que différentes cibles peuvent être choisies 
dans l'exercice : une propriété industrielle, une mémoire, 
une école et une gare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As habilidades dos povos que trabalham no setor 
da segurança incluem a identificação eficaz de fatores de risco. 
Identificando o disastre do tempo, os danos e riscos do 
acidente, é possível impedir a ocorrência de eventos prejudiciais. 
A habilidade da identificação é praticada somente com a 
experiência de trabalho. Você pode usar este material do 
estudo que simula o ambiente do trabalho para praticar estas 
habilidades já antes das tarefas de trabalho começando durante seu 
studies.This que aprende que o material contem também a informação 
teórica em identificar fatores de risco e gerência de risco 
as.well.as a informação estatística nos fatores de risco os mais 
comuns. O material de aprendizagem é alvejado na instrução 
básica secundária vocacional na segurança sector.Four que os alvos 
diferentes podem ser escolhidos no exercício: uma propriedade 
industrial, uma loja, uma escola e uma estação railway.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le abilità della gente che lavora nel settore di
sicurezza includono l'identificazione efficace dei fattori di rischio.
Identificando il disastro di tempo, danni e rischi di incidente,
è possibile impedire il caso degli eventi nocivi. L'abilità 
dell'identificazione si esercita in soltanto con esperienza di lavoro.
Potete usare questo materiale di studio che simulate l'ambiente 
del lavoro per esercitarsi in queste abilità già prima dei compiti 
lavorativi comincianti durante il vostro studies.This che imparate che
il materiale egualmente contiene le informazioni teoriche 
sull'identificare i fattori di rischio e la gestione di rischio così 
come le informazioni statistiche sui fattori di rischio più comuni. 
Il materiale imparante è designato a formazione di base 
secondaria professionale nella sicurezza sector.Four che gli obiettivi
differenti possono essere scelti nell'esercitazione: una 
proprietà industriale, un deposito, una scuola e una stazione 
ferroviaria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι δεξιότητες των ανθρώπων που εργάζονται στον τομέα 
της ασφάλειας περιλαμβάνουν τον αποτελεσματικό προσδιορισμό των 
παραγόντων κινδύνου. Με τον προσδιορισμό της χρονικής 
καταστροφής, οι κίνδυνοι ζημίας και ατυχήματος, αυτό είναι 
δυνατοί να αποτρέψουν το περιστατικό των επιβλαβών γεγονότων. 
Η ικανότητα προσδιορισμού ασκείται μόνο μέσω της 
επαγγελματικής εμπειρίας. Μπορείτε να χρησιμοποιήσετε αυτό 
το υλικό μελέτης που μιμείται το περιβάλλον εργασίας για να 
ασκήσετε αυτές τις δεξιότητες ήδη πριν από την έναρξη των 
καθηκόντων κατά τη διάρκεια των μελετών σας Αυτό το υλικό 
εκμάθησης περιέχει επίσης τις θεωρητικές πληροφορίες για τον 
προσδιορισμό των παραγόντων κινδύνου και της διαχείρισης κινδύνου
καθώς επίσης και τις στατιστικές πληροφορίες για τους πιό 
κοινούς παράγοντες κινδύνου. Το υλικό εκμάθησης στοχεύει 
στην επαγγελματική δευτεροβάθμια βασική εκπαίδευση στον τομέα της
ασφάλειας Τέσσερις διαφορετικοί στόχοι μπορούν να 
επιλεχτούν στην άσκηση: μια βιομηχανική ιδιοκτησία, ένα 
κατάστημα, ένα σχολείο και ένας σιδηροδρομικός σταθμός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las habilidades de la gente que trabaja en el 
sector de la seguridad incluyen la identificación eficaz de los 
factores de riesgo. Identificando desastre del tiempo, el daños
y los riesgos del accidente, es posible prevenir la ocurrencia de 
acontecimientos dañosos. La habilidad de la identificación se 
practica solamente con experiencia profesional. Usted puede 
utilizar este material del estudio que simula el ambiente del trabajo 
para practicar estas habilidades ya antes de tareas de trabajo que 
comienzan durante su studies.This que aprende que el material también
contiene la información teórica sobre identificar a factores de 
riesgo y a la gerencia de riesgo así como la información 
estadística sobre los factores de riesgo más comunes. El 
material que aprende se apunta en la educación básica secundaria 
vocacional en la seguridad sector.Four que diversas blancos se pueden 
elegir en el ejercicio: una propiedad industrial, un almacén, 
una escuela y un ferrocarril.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Raija Viljamaa
n:Viljamaa;Raija
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Sami Tikkanen
n:Tikkanen;Sami
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Ulriikka Savela-Huovinen
n:Savela-Huovinen;Ulriikka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Datafisher Oy
n:Datafisher Oy
org:Datafisher Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A6BCE86B-319C-5D6C-B608-489489FF9990</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/A6BCE86B-319C-5D6C-B608-489489FF9990</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:24.30Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>role play</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/turvallisuus/kayttoehdot.html</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1163</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1369</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1022</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1116</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/turvallisuus</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/turvallisuus</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
