<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/79498</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>79498</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/2_9_hajotelmat/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/2_9_hajotelmat/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/2_9_hajotelmat/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Decompositions of numbers 2-9</string>
            <string language="fi">Lukujen 2-9 hajotelmat</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aufspaltung von Zahlen 2-9</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Décompositions des numéros 2-9</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Decompositions dos números 2-9</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decomposizioni dei numeri 2-9</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποσυνθέσεις των αριθμών 2-9</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Descomposiciones de números 2-9</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This learning material comprises a collection of learning objects practising decompositions of numbers 2-9 as sums and remainders. Sums or remainders can be practised on all numbers between 2-9, either with bead lines, open hands or decomposition cards. Choose from the menu first the method, then the number, the decompositions of which are to be practised. More precise instructions are shown on the screen next to the task. The object forms part of the set of tasks in the AbacoMath game supporting the learning of mathematics. The aim of the tasks is to lead the learner through the aid of experiences and visualisation towards abstraction. The object is suitable for use in remedial and general mathematics teaching. The tasks of the AbacoMath game have been conceived and scripted on the basis of a rehabilitative method developed under Hendrik Radatz and Ursula Chaudhur. The application has been implemented with Flash technology, and so the program requires a browser with Flash support in order to work.</string>
            <string language="fi">Tämä oppimateriaali koostuu kokoelmasta oppimisaihioita, joissa harjoitellaan lukujen 2-9 hajotelmia summina ja erotuksina. Kaikista luvuista välillä 2-9 voidaan harjoitella summia tai erotuksia joko helmijonoilla, avoimilla käsillä tai hajotelmakorteilla. Valitse valikosta ensin metodi, sitten luku, jonka hajotelmia harjoitellaan. Tarkemmat ohjeet näkyvät ruudulla tehtävän ohessa. Aihio on osa matematiikan oppimista tukevan AbacoMath-pelin tehtäväsarjaa. Tehtävien tavoite on johdattaa oppija kokemusten ja visualisoinnin avulla kohti abstraktiota. Aihio sopii käytettäväksi matematiikan erityis- ja yleisopetuksessa. AbacoMath-pelin tehtävät on ideoitu ja käsikirjoitettu Hendrik Radatzin ja Ursula Chaudhurin johdolla kehitetyn kuntouttamismenetelmän pohjalta. Sovellus on toteutettu Flash-tekniikalla, joten ohjelma tarvitsee toimiakseen selaimen, jossa on Flash-tuki.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">hajotelmat</string>
            <string language="fi">vähennyslaskut</string>
            <string language="fi">yhteenlaskut</string>
            <string language="en">vähennyslaskut</string>
            <string language="en">yhteenlaskut</string>
            <string language="en">hajotelmat</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses erlernenmaterial enthält eine Ansammlung 
von den erlernennachrichten, die Aufspaltung von Zahlen 2-9 als Summen
und Reste üben. Summen oder Reste können auf allen Zahlen 
zwischen 2-9 geübt werden, jedes mit Kornzeilen, den geöffneten 
Händen oder den Aufspaltungkarten. Wählen Sie vom Menü zuerst
die Methode, dann die Zahl, dessen Aufspaltung geübt werden soll. 
Exaktere Anweisungen werden auf dem Bildschirm nahe bei der 
Aufgabe gezeigt. Die Nachricht stellt Teil des Sets von Aufgaben
im AbacoMath Spiel dar, welches das Lernen von Mathematik 
unterstützt. Das Ziel der Aufgaben ist, den Anfänger durch das
Hilfsmittel von Erfahrungen und von Sichtbarmachung in Richtung zur 
Abstraktion zu führen. Die Nachricht ist für Gebrauch im 
fehlerbehebenden und allgemeinen Mathematikunterricht verwendbar. 
Die Aufgaben des AbacoMath Spiels sind begriffen worden und 
scripted auf der Grundlage von eine rehabilitierende Methode, die 
unter Hendrik Radatz und Ursula Chaudhur entwickelt wird. Die 
Anwendung ist mit greller Technologie eingeführt worden und also 
benötigt das Programm eine Datenbanksuchroutine mit grellem Support, 
um zu arbeiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce matériel d'étude comporte une collection des 
objets d'étude pratiquant des décompositions des numéros 2-9 comme 
sommes et restes. Des sommes ou les restes peuvent être 
pratiqués sur tous les nombres entre 2-9, l'un ou l'autre avec des 
lignes de petit programme, des mains ouvertes ou des cartes de 
décomposition. Choisissez du menu d'abord la méthode, puis le 
nombre, dont les décompositions doivent être pratiquées. Des 
instructions plus précises sont montrées sur l'écran à côté du 
charger. Les formes d'objet partie de l'ensemble de 
charge dans le jeu d'AbacoMath supportant l'étude des 
mathématiques. Le but du charge est de mener 
l'étudiant par l'aide des expériences et de la visualisation vers 
l'abstraction. L'objet convient pour l'usage dans l'enseignement
réparateur et général de mathématiques. Charge du 
jeu d'AbacoMath ont été conçus et préétablirs sur la base d'une 
méthode réhabilitative développée sous Hendrik Radatz et Ursula 
Chaudhur. L'application a été mise en application avec la 
technologie instantanée, et ainsi le programme exige d'un navigateur
avec le support instantané afin de travailler.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este material de aprendizagem compreende uma 
coleção dos objetos de aprendizagem que praticam decompositions dos 
números 2-9 como somas e restantes. As somas ou os restantes 
podem ser praticados em todos os números entre 2-9, um ou outro com 
linhas do grânulo, mãos abertas ou cartões do decomposition. 
Escolha do menu primeiramente o método, então o número, os 
decompositions de que devem ser praticados. Umas instruções 
mais precisas são mostradas na tela ao lado da tarefa. O objeto
dá forma à parte do jogo das tarefas no jogo de AbacoMath que 
suporta a aprendizagem da matemática. O alvo das tarefas é 
conduzir ao learner através do dae (dispositivo automático de 
entrada) das experiências e do visualisation para o abstraction. 
O objeto é apropriado para o uso no ensino corretivo e geral da
matemática. As tarefas do jogo de AbacoMath conceived e 
scripted na base de um método rehabilitative desenvolvido sob Hendrik
Radatz e Ursula Chaudhur. A aplicação foi executada com 
tecnologia flash, e assim que o programa requer um browser com 
sustentação flash a fim trabalhar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo materiale imparante contiene una collezione
gli oggetti imparanti che si esercitano nelle decomposizioni dei 
numeri 2-9 come le somme e resti. Le somme o i resti possono 
esercitarsi in su tutti i numeri fra 2-9, il uno o il altro con le 
righe del branello, le mani aperte o le schedi di decomposizione. 
Scelga dal menu in primo luogo il metodo, allora il numero, le 
decomposizioni di cui devono esercitarsi in. Le istruzioni più 
precise sono indicate sullo schermo vicino all'operazione. 
L'oggetto fa dell'insieme delle mansioni nel gioco di AbacoMath 
che sostiene imparare della matematica. Lo scopo delle mansioni 
è condurre il principiante attraverso il sussidio delle esperienze e 
della visualizzazione verso l'astrazione. L'oggetto è adatto ad
uso nell'insegnamento correttivo e generale di matematica. Le 
mansioni del gioco di AbacoMath sono state concepite e scripted in 
base ad un metodo rieducativo messo a punto sotto Hendrik Radatz ed 
Ursula Chaudhur. L'applicazione è stata effettuata con 
tecnologia istantanea ed in modo da il programma richiede un browser 
con supporto istantaneo per funzionare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το υλικό εκμάθησης περιλαμβάνει μια συλλογή της 
εκμάθησης αντιτίθεται τις αποσυνθέσεις των αριθμών 2-9 ως ποσά
και υπόλοιπα. Τα ποσά ή τα υπόλοιπα μπορούν να ασκηθούν σε
όλους τους αριθμούς μεταξύ 2-9, είτε με τις γραμμές χαντρών, 
τα ανοικτές χέρια είτε τις κάρτες αποσύνθεσης. Επιλέξτε 
από τον κατάλογο επιλογής πρώτα τη μέθοδο, κατόπιν ο αριθμός, 
οι αποσυνθέσεις του οποίου πρόκειται να ασκηθούν. Οι 
ακριβέστερες οδηγίες εμφανίζονται στην οθόνη δίπλα στη 
στοιχειώδη εργασία. Το αντικείμενο αποτελεί μέρος του 
συνόλου στοιχειωδών εργασιών στο παιχνίδι AbacoMath που 
υποστηρίζει την εκμάθηση των μαθηματικών. Ο στόχος των 
στοιχειωδών εργασιών είναι να οδηγηθεί ο αρχάριος μέσω της 
ενίσχυσης της εμπειρίας και της απεικόνισης προς την αφαίρεση. 
Το αντικείμενο είναι κατάλληλο για τη χρήση στη θεραπευτική
και γενική διδασκαλία μαθηματικών. Οι στοιχειώδεις εργασίες
του παιχνιδιού AbacoMath έχουν συλλήφθουν και προκαθορισμένος 
βάσει μιας αποκατάστασης μεθόδου που αναπτύσσεται κάτω από το 
Hendrik Radatz και την Ursula Chaudhur. Η εφαρμογή 
έχει εφαρμοστεί με την τεχνολογία λάμψης, και έτσι το πρόγραμμα 
απαιτεί έναν ξεφυλλιστή με την υποστήριξη λάμψης προκειμένου να 
λειτουργήσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este material que aprende abarca una colección de
los objetos que aprenden que practican descomposiciones de números 
2-9 como sumas y restos. Las sumas o los restos se pueden 
practicar en todos los números entre 2-9, cualquier con las líneas 
del grano, las manos abiertas o las tarjetas de la descomposición. 
Elija del menú primero el método, entonces el número, las 
descomposiciones de el cual deben ser practicadas. Instrucciones
más exactas se muestran en la pantalla al lado de la tarea. El 
objeto forma la parte del conjunto de tareas en el juego de AbacoMath 
que utiliza aprender de las matemáticas. La puntería de las 
tareas es conducir al principiante a través de la ayuda de 
experiencias y de la visualización hacia la abstracción. El 
objeto es conveniente para el uso en la enseñanza remediadora y 
general de las matemáticas. Las tareas del juego de AbacoMath 
se han concebido y scripted en base de un método rehabilitativo 
desarrollado bajo Hendrik Radatz y Ursula Chaudhur. La 
aplicación se ha puesto en ejecucio'n con tecnología de destello, y 
así que el programa requiere un browser con la ayuda de destello para
trabajar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">vähennyslaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">yhteenlaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">hajotelmat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">vähennyslaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">yhteenlaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">hajotelmat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">vähennyslaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">yhteenlaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">hajotelmat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">vähennyslaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">yhteenlaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">hajotelmat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">vδhennyslaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">yhteenlaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">hajotelmat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">vähennyslaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">yhteenlaskut</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">hajotelmat</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jan Rosnell
n:Rosnell;Jan
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Marja Dräger
n:Dräger;Marja
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anni Lampinen
n:Lampinen;Anni
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Juha-Pekka Huikuri
n:Huikuri;Juha-Pekka
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Huikuri Interactive
n:Huikuri Interactive
org:Huikuri Interactive
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Janomedia
n:Janomedia
org:Janomedia
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/D6A20DD2-8A7E-EB56-6E4D-008FA576C0A8</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/D6A20DD2-8A7E-EB56-6E4D-008FA576C0A8</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:04.40Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>special education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-8</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ei mainintaa</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1227</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>790</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/2_9_hajotelmat/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/2_9_hajotelmat/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
