<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/158642</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>158642</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>ILMoE</catalog>
            <entry>ILMoE1070</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Do We Really Need All Those Products?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Benötigen Wir Wirklich Alle Jene Produkte?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avons-nous besoin Vraiment de Tous Ces Produits ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nós Necessitamos Realmente Todos Aqueles 
Produtos?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Realmente Abbiamo bisogno Di Tutti Quei Prodotti?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρειαζόμαστε πραγματικά όλα εκείνα τα προϊόντα;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Realmente Necesitamos Todos Esos Productos?</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">There are many products advertised on television, radio, newspaper and other media. Though cigarettes and alcohol are used worldwide, many countries in recent years have created laws against advertising these products in the mass media. Cigarettes can cause cancer and are addictive, while alcohol can cause liver damage and cancer too. But there are many other products that are really useful, helpful or healthy being advertised every day. Do we need them all? How many products that are advertised today could we really live without? In this activity the learners will explore how some products which are not really necessary for day-to-day life are advertised.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">lesson plan</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">interactive activity</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">advertisement</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">t.v. shopping</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Es gibt viele Produkte, die auf Fernsehen, Radio, Zeitung 
und anderen Media bekanntgemacht werden. Obwohl Zigaretten und 
Spiritus weltweit benutzt wird, haben viele Länder in den letzten 
Jahren Gesetze gegen das Bekanntmachen dieser Produkte in den 
Massenmedia erstellt. Zigaretten können Krebs verursachen und 
sind süchtig machend, während Spiritus Leberbeschädigung und -krebs
auch verursachen kann. Aber es gibt viele andere Produkte, die 
wirklich nützlich sind, nützlich oder gesundes bekanntmachend jeden 
Tag. Benötigen wir sie alle? Wieviele Produkte, die heute
bekanntgemacht werden, konnten wir leben wirklich außen? In 
dieser Aktivität erforschen die Anfänger, wie einige Produkte, die 
nicht für Alltagslebensdauer wirklich notwendig sind, bekanntgemacht 
werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Il y a beaucoup de produits annoncés à la télévision, 
à la radio, au journal et à d'autres medias. Bien que des 
cigarettes et l'alcool soient utilisés dans le monde entier, beaucoup
de pays ces dernières années ont créé des lois contre annoncer ces
produits dans les mass media. Les cigarettes peuvent causer le 
cancer et sont provoquant une dépendance, alors que l'alcool peut 
causer les dommages et le cancer de foie aussi. Mais il y a 
beaucoup d'autres produits qui sont vraiment utiles, utiles ou sains 
étant annoncés chaque jour. Avons-nous besoin d'eux tous ? 
Combien de produits qui sont annoncés aujourd'hui pourraient 
nous vivent vraiment en dehors ? Dans cette activité les 
étudiants exploreront comment quelques produits qui ne sont pas 
vraiment nécessaires pour la vie de jour en jour sont annoncés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Há muitos produtos anunciados na televisão, no rádio, 
no jornal e nos outros media. Embora os cigarros e o álcool 
são usados worldwide, muitos países em anos recentes criaram leis de
encontro a anunciar estes produtos nos media maciços. Os 
cigarros podem causar o cancer e são addictive, quando o álcool 
puder causar os danos e o cancer do fígado demasiado. Mas há 
muitos outros produtos que são realmente úteis, úteis ou saudáveis
sendo anunciado cada dia. Nós necessitamo-los todos? 
Quantos produtos que são anunciados hoje poderiam nós vivem 
realmente without? Nesta atividade os learners explorarão como 
alguns produtos que não são realmente necessários para a vida 
cotidiana são anunciados.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ci sono molti prodotti fatti pubblicità a sulla 
televisione, sulla radio, sul giornale e su altri media. Benchè
le sigarette e l'alcool siano usati universalmente, molti paesi negli 
ultimi anni hanno creato le leggi contro la pubblicità dei questi 
prodotti nei mass-media. Le sigarette possono causare il cancro 
e sono addictive, mentre l'alcool può causare danni ed il cancro del 
fegato anche. Ma ci sono molti altri prodotti che sono realmente
utili, utili o sani che sono fatti pubblicità ogni giorno. Li 
abbiamo bisogno di tutti? Quanti prodotti che sono fatti 
pubblicità a oggi potrebbero noi realmente vivono senza? In 
questa attività i principianti esploreranno come alcuni prodotti che 
non sono necessari realmente per vita giornaliera sono fatti 
pubblicità a.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπάρχουν πολλά προϊόντα που διαφημίζονται στην 
τηλεόραση, το ραδιόφωνο, την εφημερίδα και άλλα μέσα. Αν 
και τα τσιγάρα και το οινόπνευμα χρησιμοποιούνται παγκοσμίως, 
πολλές χώρες τα τελευταία χρόνια έχουν δημιουργήσει τους νόμους
ενάντια στη διαφήμιση αυτών των προϊόντων στα μαζικής 
επικοινωνίας μέσα. Τα τσιγάρα μπορούν να προκαλέσουν τον 
καρκίνο και είναι εθιστικά, ενώ το οινόπνευμα μπορεί να 
προκαλέσει τη ζημία και τον καρκίνο συκωτιού επίσης. Αλλά 
υπάρχουν πολλά άλλα προϊόντα που είναι πραγματικά χρήσιμα, 
χρήσιμα ή υγιής που διαφημίζεται κάθε ημέρα. Τους 
χρειαζόμαστε όλοι; Πόσα προϊόντα που διαφημίζονται σήμερα
θα μπορούσαν εμείς ζουν πραγματικά χωρίς; Σε αυτήν την 
δραστηριότητα οι αρχάριοι θα εξερευνήσουν πώς μερικά προϊόντα 
που δεν είναι πραγματικά απαραίτητα για την καθημερινή ζωή 
διαφημίζονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hay muchos productos anunciacióces en la televisión, la 
radio, el periódico y otros media. Aunque los cigarrillos y el 
alcohol se utilizan por todo el mundo, muchos países en años 
recientes han creado leyes contra la publicidad de estos productos en 
los medioses de comunicación. Los cigarrillos pueden causar el 
cáncer y son adictivos, mientras que el alcohol puede causar daño y 
el cáncer del hígado también. Pero hay muchos otros productos
que son realmente útiles, provechosos o sanos siendo anunciado cada 
día. ¿Los necesitamos todos? ¿Cuántos productos que se 
anuncian hoy podrían nosotros realmente viven fuera? En esta 
actividad los principiantes explorarán cómo se anuncian algunos 
productos que no son realmente necesarios para la vida cotidiana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lektionplan</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">interaktive Aktivität</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reklameanzeige</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">t.v. Einkaufen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">plan de leçon</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">activité interactive</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">publicité</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">achats de t.v.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">planta da lição</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">atividade interativa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">propaganda</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">shopping de t.v.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">programma di lezione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">attività interattiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">pubblicità</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">shopping di t.v.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχέδιο μαθήματος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">διαλογική δραστηριότητα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">διαφήμιση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αγορές TV</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">plan de la lección</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">actividad interactiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">anuncio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">compras de t.v.</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Israel Ministry of Education
n:Israel Ministry of Education
org:Israel Ministry of Education
end:vcard</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-02-20</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>ILMoE</catalog>
            <entry>ILMoE1070</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Israel Ministry of Education
n:Israel Ministry of Education
org:Israel Ministry of Education
end:vcard</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-02-20</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>enquiry-oriented activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="en">15-18</string>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-18</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">=© 2003 Eric Cohen Books, Ltd. All rights reserved. http://www.ecb.co.il/ecbonline/termsofuse.html</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1071</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">reading</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>926</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">oral</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1410</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">writing skills</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>673</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">internet skills</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>158642</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.ecb.co.il/ecbonline/discovery/productsTG.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
