<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/26787</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>26787</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_6855</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_6855</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_6855</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">6.891 Computational Evolutionary Biology, Fall 2004 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">6.891 Berechnungsentwicklungsbiologie, Fall
2004 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">6.891 Biologie Évolutionnaire de calcul, 
Automne 2004 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">6.891 Biologia Evolucionária 
Computacional, Queda 2004 (Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">6.891 Biologia Evolutiva Di calcolo, Caduta
2004 (Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">6.891 Η υπολογιστική εξελικτική βιολογία, πτώση του 
2004 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">6.891 Biología Evolutiva De cómputo, 
Caída 2004 (Mit)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "Why has it been easier to develop a vaccine to eliminate polio than to control influenza or AIDS? Has there been natural selection for a  language gene ? Why are there no animals with wheels? When does  maximizing fitness  lead to evolutionary extinction? How are sex and parasites related? Why don t snakes eat grass? Why don t we have eyes in the back of our heads? How does modern genomics illustrate and challenge the field?  This course analyzes evolution from a computational, modeling, and engineering perspective. The course has extensive hands-on laboratory exercises in model-building and analyzing evolutionary data."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Electrical Engineering and Computer Science</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">evolutionary extinction</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">AIDS</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">modern genomics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">polio vaccine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">parasites</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">hands-on</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">polio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Evolutionary Biology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">vaccine</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">influenza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">sex</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">evolution from a computational  modeling  and engineering perspective</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">analyzing evolutionary data</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web 
site (http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute 
of Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "warum ist es einfacher gewesen, einen Impfstoff 
zu entwickeln, um Poliomyelitis als zu beseitigen, Grippe oder AIDS zu
steuern? Hat es natürliche Auswahl für ein Sprachengen 
gegeben? Warum gibt es keine Tiere mit Rädern? Wann, 
Eignung maximierend führt zu Entwicklungslöschung? Wie werden 
Geschlecht und Parasiten in Verbindung gestanden? Warum ziehen 
Sie t Schlangen essen Gras an? Warum ziehen Sie t an, das wir 
Augen in der Rückseite unserer Köpfe haben? Wie 
veranschaulicht modernes genomics und fordert auffangene heraus? 
Dieser Kurs analysiert Entwicklung von einem Berechnungs und 
formt, und führt Perspektive aus. Der Kurs hat umfangreiche 
Blindeinschub Laborübungen im Model-building und im Analysieren von 
von Entwicklungsdaten."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "pourquoi 
a-t-il été plus facile de développer un vaccin pour éliminer la 
poliomyélite que pour contrôler la grippe ou le SIDA ? Y 
a-t-il eu sélection normale pour un gène de langage ? Pourquoi
y a-t-il aucuns animaux avec des roues ? Quand maximisant la 
forme physique mène à l'extinction évolutionnaire ? Comment 
le sexe et les parasites sont-ils associés ? Pourquoi mettez 
les serpents de t mangent l'herbe ? Pourquoi mettez t que nous 
avons des yeux dans le dos de nos têtes ? Comment est-ce que la
génomique moderne illustre et défie la zone ? Ce cours analyse
l'évolution d'un de calcul, modelant, et machinant la perspective. 
Le cours a des exercices à commande manuelle étendus de 
laboratoire la modélisation et en analysant des données 
évolutionnaires."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "por que foi mais fácil desenvolver uma 
vacina para eliminar a poliomielite do que para controlar o influenza 
ou o AIDS? Houve uma seleção natural para um gene da língua? 
Por que há nenhuns animais com rodas? Quando maximizing a
aptidão conduzir à extinção evolucionária? Como o sexo e os
parasites são relacionados? Por que don serpentes de t comem a 
grama? Por que don t que nós temos os olhos na parte traseira 
de nossas cabeças? Como o genomics moderno ilustra e desafia o 
campo? Este curso analisa a evolução de um computacional, 
modelando, e projetando o perspective. O curso tem exercícios 
hands-on extensivos do laboratório no model-building e em analisar 
dados evolucionários."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "perchè è stato più facile da sviluppare 
un vaccino per eliminare la poliomelite che gestire la riossidazione o
il AIDS? Ci è stato selezione naturale per un gene di 
linguaggio? Perchè è ci nessun animali con le rotelle? 
Quando elevando la idoneità conduce ad estinzione evolutiva? 
Come il sesso ed i parassiti sono riferiti? Perchè 
indossi i serpenti di t mangiano l'erba? Perchè indossi la t 
che abbiamo occhi nella parte posteriore delle nostre teste? 
Come il genomics moderno illustra e sfida il campo? Questo
corso analizza lo sviluppo da un di calcolo, modellando e costruendo 
la prospettiva. Il corso ha vaste esercitazioni hands-on del 
laboratorio nel model-building e nell'analizzare i dati evolutivi."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Γιατί είναι ευκολότερο να αναπτυχθεί ένα εμβόλιο για να 
αποβάλει την πολιομυελίτιδα από για να ελέγξει τη γρίπη ή το 
AIDS; Έχει υπάρξει φυσική επιλογή για ένα γλωσσικό 
γονίδιο; Γιατί δεν υπάρχει κανένα ζώο με τις ρόδες; 
Πότε η μεγιστοποίηση της ικανότητας οδηγεί στην εξελικτική 
εξάλειψη; Πώς το φύλο και τα παράσιτα αφορούν; Γιατί
φορέστε τα φίδια τ τρώει τη χλόη; Γιατί φορέστε το τ που 
έχουμε τα μάτια στο πίσω μέρος των κεφαλιών μας; Πώς 
σύγχρονο genomics επεξηγεί και προκαλεί το πεδίο; Αυτή η
σειρά μαθημάτων αναλύει την εξέλιξη από έναν υπολογιστικό, μια 
διαμόρφωση, και μια προοπτική εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής. Η 
σειρά μαθημάτων πραγματοποιεί τις εκτενείς εμπράγματες 
εργαστηριακές ασκήσεις model-building και την ανάλυση των 
εξελικτικών στοιχείων."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
¿"por qué ha sido más fácil desarrollar una vacuna para 
eliminar poliomielitis que controlar gripe o el SIDA? ¿Ha habido
selección natural para un gene del lenguaje? ¿Por qué hay 
ningunos animales con las ruedas? ¿Cuándo maximizando aptitud 
conduce a la extinción evolutiva? ¿Cómo se relacionan el sexo 
y los parásitos? ¿Por qué ponga las serpientes de t comen la 
hierba? ¿Por qué ponga t que tenemos ojos en la parte 
posteriora de nuestras cabezas? ¿Cómo el genomics moderno 
ilustra y desafía el campo? Este curso analiza la evolución de
un de cómputo, modelando, y dirigiendo perspectiva. El curso 
tiene ejercicios con manos extensos del laboratorio en construcción 
de maquetas y analizar datos evolutivos."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elektrotechnik und Informatik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Entwicklungslöschung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">AIDS</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">modernes genomics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Poliomyelitisimpfstoff</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Parasiten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blindeinschub</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Poliomyelitis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Entwicklungsbiologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Impfstoff</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grippe</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschlecht</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Entwicklung von einer Berechnungsformenund 
ausführenperspektive</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Analysieren von von Entwicklungsdaten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Électrotechnique et informatique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">extinction évolutionnaire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">SIDA</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">génomique moderne</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">vaccin de poliomyélite</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">parasites</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">à commande manuelle</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">poliomyélite</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Biologie Évolutionnaire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">vaccin</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">grippe</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">sexe</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">évolution d'une perspective modelante et machinante de
calcul</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">analyse des données évolutionnaires</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Engenharia elétrica e informática de</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">extinção evolucionária</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">AIDS</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">genomics moderno</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">vacina da poliomielite</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">parasites</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">hands-on</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">poliomielite</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Biologia Evolucionária</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">vacina</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">influenza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sexo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">evolução de um perspective modelando e projetando 
computacional</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">analisando dados evolucionários</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ingegneria elettrica ed informatica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">estinzione evolutiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">AIDS</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">genomics moderno</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">vaccino di poliomelite</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">parassiti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">hands-on</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">poliomelite</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Biologia Evolutiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">vaccino</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">riossidazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sesso</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sviluppo da una prospettiva modellante e d'ingegneria 
di calcolo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">analizzare i dati evolutivi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηλεκτρική εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική και πληροφορική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξελικτική εξάλειψη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">AIDS</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σύγχρονο genomics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εμβόλιο πολιομυελίτιδας</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παράσιτα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εμπράγματος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πολιομυελίτιδα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εξελικτική βιολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εμβόλιο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">γρίπη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">φύλο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξέλιξη από μια υπολογιστική προοπτική διαμόρφωσης και 
εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ανάλυση των εξελικτικών στοιχείων</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ingeniería eléctrica e informática</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">extinción evolutiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">SIDA</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">genomics moderno</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">vacuna de la poliomielitis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">parásitos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">con manos</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">poliomielitis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Biología Evolutiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">vacuna</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">gripe</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sexo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">evolución de una perspectiva que modela y que dirige 
de cómputo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">analizar datos evolutivos</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>411</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">electrical engineering</string>
                <string language="sv">elektroteknik</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>256</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">computer science</string>
                <string language="sv">datavetenskap</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_6855-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_6855-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:47:45.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T06:01:13.22Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_6855</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Electrical-Engineering-and-Computer-Science/6-891Fall-2004/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
