<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/29835</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>29835</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_7434</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7434</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7434</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">3.A27 Case Studies in Forensic Metallurgy, Fall 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">3.A27 Fallstudien in der gerichtlichen 
Metallurgie, Fall 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">études de cas 3.A27 en métallurgie légale, 
automne 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">estudos de caso 3.A27 no metallurgy forensic, 
queda 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">inchieste 3.A27 in metallurgia legale, caduta 
2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">3.A27 Περιπτωσιολογικές μελέτες στη δικανική 
μεταλλουργία, πτώση του 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">estudios de caso 3.A27 en la metalurgia forense, 
caída 2007 (MIT)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "TV programs such as "Law and Order" show how forensic experts are called upon to give testimony that often determines the outcome of court cases. Engineers are one class of expert who can help display evidence in a new light to solve cases. In this seminar you will be part of the problem-solving process, working through both previously solved and unsolved cases. Each week we will investigate cases, from the facts that make up each side to the potential evidence we can use as engineers to expose culprits. The cases range from disintegrating airplane engines to gas main explosions to Mafia murders. This seminar will be full of discussions about the cases and creative approaches to reaching the solutions. The approach is hands-on so you will have a chance to participate in the process, not simply study it. Some background reading and oral presentation are required."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">failure</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">fracture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">fatigue</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">stainless steel</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">corrosion</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">soldering</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">catastrophic failure</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">welding</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">aluminum</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Materials Science and Engineering</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">oxidation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">brazing</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">case studies</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">seminar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Welding Technology/Welder</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web 
site (http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute 
of Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "Fernsehapparat Programme wie" Gesetz und Ordnung
"zeigen, wie um gerichtliche Experten ersucht werden, um Zeugnis zu 
geben, das häufig das Resultat der Gerichtfälle feststellt. 
Ingenieure sind eine Kategorie Experte, die helfen kann, Beweis 
in einem neuen Licht anzuzeigen, um Fälle zu lösen. In diesem 
Seminar sind Sie ein Teil der problemlösenden gelösten und 
ungelösten Fälle des Prozesses und arbeiten durch beide vorher. 
Jede Woche forschen wir Fälle, von den Tatsachen nach, die jede
Seite zum möglichen Beweis bilden, den, wir als Ingenieure verwenden 
können, um Angeklagte herauszustellen. Die Fälle reichen von 
auflösenden Flugzeugmaschinen bis zu Gashauptleitungexplosionen bis 
zu Mafiamorden. Dieses Seminar ist von den Diskussionen über 
die Fälle und von den kreativen Annäherungen zum Erreichen der 
Lösungen voll. Die Annäherung ist Blindeinschub, also haben 
Sie eine Wahrscheinlichkeit, am Prozeß teilzunehmen, ihn nicht 
einfach zu studieren. Irgendein Hintergrundmesswert und 
Munddarstellung werden benoetigt."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : les 
"programmes de TV tels que" la loi et la commande "montrent comment 
des experts légaux sont invités pour donner le témoignage qui 
détermine souvent les résultats des affaires en jugement. Les 
ingénieurs sont une classe d'expert qui peut aider à afficher 
l'évidence dans une nouvelle lumière pour résoudre des cas. 
Dans cette conférence vous ferez partie des cas précédemment 
résolus et non résolus de résolution des problèmes de processus, 
travaillant par tous les deux. Chaque semaine nous étudierons 
des cas, des faits qui composent chaque côté à l'évidence 
potentielle que nous pouvons employer comme ingénieurs pour exposer 
des coupables. Les caisses s'étendent des moteurs de 
désintégration d'avion aux explosions de conduite de gaz aux 
meurtres de Mafia. Cette conférence sera pleine des discussions
au sujet des caisses et des approches créatrices à atteindre les 
solutions. L'approche est à commande manuelle ainsi vous aurez 
une chance de participer au processus, l'étudier pas simplement. 
Une certaines lecture de fond et présentation orale sont 
exigées."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: da "os programas tevê tais como" a lei e a 
ordem "mostram como os peritos forensic são convidados para dar o 
testimony que determina frequentemente o resultado de casos de corte. 
Os coordenadores são uma classe do perito que pode ajudar 
indicar a evidência em uma luz nova para resolver casos. Neste 
seminário você será parte dos exemplos previamente resolvidos e 
unsolved problem-solving do processo, trabalhando com ambos. 
Cada semana nós investigaremos casos, dos fatos que fazem acima
cada lado à evidência que potencial nós podemos se usar como 
coordenadores expo culpados. Os casos variam dos motores 
disintegrating do avião às explosões do cano principal de gás aos 
assassinatos do mafia. Este seminário estará cheio das 
discussões sobre os casos e de aproximações creativas a alcançar 
as soluções. A aproximação é hands-on assim que você terá
uma possibilidade participar no processo, para estudá-lo não 
simplesmente. Algumas leitura do fundo e apresentação oral 
são requeridas."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "i programmi della TV quali" legge ed ordine
"mostrano come gli esperti legali sono invitati per dare la 
testimonianza che determina spesso il risultato dei casi di corte. 
Gli assistenti tecnici sono un codice categoria dell'esperto che
può contribuire a visualizzare la prova ad una nuova luce per 
risolvere i casi. In questo seminario farete parte dei casi 
precedentemente risolti e non risolti per la risoluzione di problemi 
di processo, funzionando con entrambi. Ogni settimana studieremo
i casi, dai fatti che compongono ogni lato alla prova che potenziale 
possiamo usare come assistenti tecnici per esporre i colpevoli. 
I casi variano dai motori di disintegrazione dell'aeroplano alle
esplosioni della conduttura di gas agli omicidi della Mafia. 
Questo seminario sarà pieno delle discussioni circa i casi e 
dei metodi creativi a raggiungere le soluzioni. Il metodo è 
hands-on in modo da avrete una probabilità partecipare al processo, 
studiarlo non semplicemente. Una certe lettura della priorità 
bassa e presentazione orale sono richieste."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
Τα "προγράμματα TV όπωσ" ο νόμος και η τάξη 
"επιδεικνύουν πώς οι δικανικοί εμπειρογνώμονες καλούνται για να 
δώσουν την κατάθεση που καθορίζει συχνά την έκβαση των 
δικαστικών υποθέσεων. Οι μηχανικοί είναι μια κλάση του 
εμπειρογνώμονα που μπορεί να βοηθήσει να παρουσιάσει τα στοιχεία 
σε ένα νέο φως για να λύσει τις περιπτώσεις. Σε αυτό το 
σεμινάριο θα είστε μέρος της διαδικασίας επίλυσης προβλήματος, 
που λειτουργεί και μέσω των προηγουμένως λυμένων και άλυτων 
περιπτώσεων. Κάθε εβδομάδα θα ερευνήσουμε τις περιπτώσεις, 
από τα γεγονότα που αποτελούν κάθε πλευρά στα πιθανά στοιχεία 
που μπορούμε να χρησιμοποιήσουμε ως μηχανικούς για να εκθέσουμε 
τους ενόχους. Οι περιπτώσεις κυμαίνονται από τις 
αποσυνθέτοντας μηχανές αεροπλάνων ως τις αέριο βασικές 
εκρήξεις ως τις δολοφονίες μαφίας. Αυτό το σεμινάριο θα 
είναι πλήρες των συζητήσεων για τις περιπτώσεις και των 
δημιουργικών προσεγγίσεων στην επίτευξη των λύσεων. Η 
προσέγγιση είναι εμπράγματη έτσι θα έχετε μια πιθανότητα να 
συμμετέχετε στη διαδικασία, όχι απλά μελέτη αυτό. Κάποιες
ανάγνωση υποβάθρου και προφορική παρουσίαση απαιτούνται."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: los 
"programas de la TV tales como" ley y orden "muestran cómo invitan a 
los expertos forenses para dar el testimonio que determina a menudo el
resultado de los procesos legales. Los ingenieros son una clase 
del experto que puede ayudar a visualizar evidencia en una nueva luz 
para solucionar casos. En este seminario usted será parte de 
los casos previamente solucionados y sin resolver problem-solving del 
proceso, trabajando con ambos. Cada semana investigaremos casos,
de los hechos que hacen para arriba cada cara a la evidencia potencial
que podemos utilizar como ingenieros para exponer a culpables. 
Los casos se extienden de los motores de desintegración del 
aeroplano a las explosiones del gasóleo a los asesinatos de la 
Mafia. Este seminario será lleno de discusiones sobre los 
casos y de acercamientos creativos a alcanzar las soluciones. El
acercamiento es con manos así que usted tendrá una ocasión de 
participar en el proceso, estudiarlo no simplemente. Se 
requieren alguna lectura del fondo y presentación oral."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausfall</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bruch</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ermüdung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">rostfreier Stahl</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Korrosion</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weichlöten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">verhängnisvoller Ausfall</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schweißen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aluminium</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Material-Wissenschaft und Technik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Oxidation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bronzieren</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fallstudien</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Seminar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schweißen Technology/Welder</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">panne</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">rupture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fatigue</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">acier inoxydable</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">corrosion</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">soudure</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">panne catastrophique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">soudure</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">aluminium</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Science des matériaux et ingénierie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">oxydation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">soudure</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">études de cas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">conférence</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Soudure Technology/Welder</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">falha</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fratura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fatiga</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">aço inoxidável</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">corrosão</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">solda</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">falha catastrófica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">welding</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">alumínio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e engenharia de materiais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oxidação</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">soldar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">estudos de caso</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">seminário</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Welding Technology/Welder</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">guasto</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">frattura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">affaticamento</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">acciaio inossidabile</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">corrosione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">saldatura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">guasto catastrofico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">saldatura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">alluminio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza ed ingegneria dei materiali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ossidazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">brasatura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">inchieste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">seminario</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Saldatura Technology/Welder</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποτυχία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σπάσιμο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">κούραση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ανοξείδωτος χάλυβας</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">διάβρωση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">συγκόλληση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">καταστροφική αποτυχία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">συγκόλληση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αργίλιο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική υλικών</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">οξείδωση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">συγκόλληση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιπτωσιολογικές μελέτες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σεμινάριο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τεχνολογία/οξυγονοκολλητής συγκόλλησης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incidente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">fractura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">fatiga</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">acero inoxidable</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">corrosión</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el soldar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incidente catastrófico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">soldadura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">aluminio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia material e ingeniería</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">oxidación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el cubrir con bronce</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">estudios de caso</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">seminario</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Soldadura Technology/Welder</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>788</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">materials engineering</string>
                <string language="sv">materialvetenskap</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7434-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7434-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:52:26.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T06:09:21.34Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_7434</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Materials-Science-and-Engineering/3-A27Fall-2007/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
