<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/26154</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>26154</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_6650</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_6650</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_6650</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">12.753 Geodynamics Seminar, Spring 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">12.753 Geodynamik-Seminar, Frühling 2006 
(MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">12.753 Conférence de Géodynamique, Le 
Printemps 2006 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">12.753 Seminário Do Geodynamics, Mola 2006 
(Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">12.753 Seminario Di Geodynamics, Primavera 
2006 (Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">12.753 Σεμινάριο γεωδυναμικής, άνοιξη του 2006 
(MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">12.753 Seminario De la Geodinámica, Resorte
2006 (Mit)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "In this year s Geodynamics Seminar, we will explore the depth and breadth of scientific research related to Earth s present and past ice-sheets, glaciers and sea-ice, as well as extraterrestrial planetary ice.  Invited speakers have been chosen from experts in the current frontiers in ice-related research, including planetary ice, climate records from polar and tropical ice cores, the Snowball Earth, subglacial volcanoes, ice rheology, ice sheet modeling, ice microkinetics, glacial erosion and tectonics, subglacial life and polar remote sensing.  A field trip to Iceland in Summer 2006 will allow us to view some of the island s ice caps and glacial geology, the exposed mid Atlantic Ridge and evidence of ice-volcano interactions."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">subglacial life and polar remote sensing</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">mid-atlantic ridge</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Earth  Atmospheric  and Planetary Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">present and past ice-sheets</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">glacial geology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">ice-related research</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">iceland</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Geology/Earth Science  General</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">subglacial volcanoes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">extraterrestrial planetary ice</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">ice microkinetics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Snowball Earth</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">sea-ice</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">glacial erosion and tectonics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">ice sheet modeling</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">climate records: polar and tropical ice cores</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">planetary ice</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">glaciers</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">ice rheology</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web site
(http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute of 
Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "in diesem Jahr s Geodynamik-Seminar, erforschen 
wir die Tiefe und die Breite der wissenschaftlichen Forschung in 
Verbindung gestanden auf vorhandenen Masse s und den letzten 
Eis-Blättern, Gletscher und Meer-Eis, der sowie extraterrestrial 
planetarisches Eis. Eingeladene Lautsprecher sind von den 
Experten in den aktuellen Grenzen in Eis-in Verbindung stehender 
Forschung, einschließlich planetarisches Eis, Klimasätze von den 
polaren und tropischen Eiskernen, die Snowball Masse, subglacial 
Vulkane, Eisrheologie, Eisblattformung, Eis microkinetics, Glazial- 
Abnutzung und Tectonics, subglacial Lebensdauer und polare 
Fernabfragung gewählt worden. Eine auffangenreise nach 
Island an Sommer 2006 erlaubt uns, einige der Eisschutzkappen der 
Insel s und der Glazial- Geologie, der herausgestellten mittleren 
atlantischen Kante und des Beweises der Eis-Vulkan Interaktionen 
anzusehen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "dans 
cette conférence de géodynamique de l'année s, nous explorerons la 
profondeur et la largeur de la recherche scientifique liées à la 
terre s et aux glace-feuilles passées, glaciers et mer-glace, aussi 
bien que la glace planétaire extraterrestre. Des haut-parleurs 
invités ont été choisis des experts en matière de frontières 
actuelles dans la recherche glace-connexe, y compris la glace 
planétaire, les enregistrements de climat des noyaux polaires et 
tropicaux de glace, la terre de Snowball, les volcans subglacial, 
la rhéologie de glace, modeler de feuille de glace, le microkinetics 
de glace, l'érosion et la tectonique glaciaire, la vie subglacial et 
télédétection polaire. Un voyage de zone vers l'Islande en 
été 2006 nous permettra de visualiser certains des chapeaux de glace
de l'île s et la géologie glaciaire, la mi arête atlantique 
exposée et évidence des interactions de glace-volcan."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "neste seminário do geodynamics do ano s, 
nós exploraremos a profundidade e a largura da pesquisa científica 
relacionadas à terra s atual e às gelo-folhas passadas, geleiras e 
mar-gelo, as.well.as o gelo planetário extraterrestrial. Os 
altofalantes convidados foram escolhidos dos peritos nas fronteiras 
atuais em pesquisa gelo-relacionada, including o gelo planetário, os 
registros do clima dos núcleos polares e tropicais do gelo, a terra 
de Snowball, vulcões subglacial, rheology do gelo, modelar da folha 
do gelo, microkinetics do gelo, erosão e tectonics glacial, vida 
subglacial e detetar remoto polar. Um desengate de campo a 
Islândia no verão 2006 permitirá que nós v alguns dos tampões de 
gelo do console s e a geologia glacial, o cume atlantic mid exposto e 
evidência de interações do gelo-vulcão."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "in questo seminario di geodynamics di anno 
s, esploreremo la profondità e la larghezza di ricerca scientifica 
relative a terra s presente ed ai ghiaccio-fogli passati, ghiacciai e 
mare-ghiaccio, così come ghiaccio planetario extraterrestrial. 
Gli altoparlanti invitati sono stati scelti dagli esperti nelle 
frontiere correnti nella ricerca ghiaccio-relativa, compresi ghiaccio 
planetario, record di clima dai nuclei polari e tropicali del 
ghiaccio, la terra di Snowball, vulcani subglacial, la reologia del 
ghiaccio, modellistica del foglio del ghiaccio, microkinetics del 
ghiaccio, erosione e la tettonica glaciale, vita subglacial e 
telerilevamento polare. Un viaggio di campo in Islanda di estate
2006 permetterà che noi osserviamo alcuni degli calotte di ghiaccio 
dell'isola s e la geologia glaciale, la metà di cresta atlantica 
esposta e prova delle interazioni del ghiaccio-vulcano."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Σε αυτό το σεμινάριο γεωδυναμικής έτους s, θα 
ερευνήσουμε το βάθος και το εύρος της επιστημονικής έρευνας 
σχετικά με τα πάγος-φύλλα γήινων s παρόντος και παρελθόντος, 
τους παγετώνες και τον θάλασσα-πάγο, καθώς επίσης και τον 
εξωγήινο πλανητικό πάγο. Οι προσκεκλημένοι ομιλητές έχουν 
επιλεχτεί από τους εμπειρογνώμονες στα παρόντα σύνορα στην 
πάγος-σχετική με τον έρευνα, συμπεριλαμβανομένου του πλανητικού 
πάγου, αρχεία κλίματος από τους πολικούς και τροπικούς πυρήνες 
πάγου, τη γη χιονιών, τα σχεδόν πολικά ηφαίστεια, τη ρεολογία 
πάγου, τη διαμόρφωση φύλλων πάγου, το microkinetics πάγου, την
παγετώδη διάβρωση και την τεκτονική, τη σχεδόν πολική ζωή και 
την πολική τηλεπισκόπηση. Ένα ταξίδι πεδίων στην Ισλανδία 
το καλοκαίρι 2006 θα επιτρέψει σε μας για να εμφανίσει μερικών 
από τα καλύμματα πάγου νησιών s και την παγετώδη γεωλογία, 
την εκτεθειμένα μέσα ατλαντικά κορυφογραμμή και τα στοιχεία των 
αλληλεπιδράσεων πάγος-ηφαιστείων."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: "en 
este seminario de la geodinámica del año s, exploraremos la 
profundidad y la anchura de la investigación científica relacionadas
con la tierra s presente y las últimas hielo-hojas, glaciares y 
mar-hielo, así como el hielo planetario extraterrestre. Los 
altavoces invitados se han elegido de expertos en las fronteras 
actuales en la investigación hielo-relacionada, incluyendo el hielo 
planetario, los expedientes del clima de memorias polares y tropicales
del hielo, la tierra de Snowball, los volcanes subglacial, rheology 
del hielo, el modelar de la hoja del hielo, microkinetics del hielo, 
erosión y tectónica glacial, vida subglacial y detección alejada 
polar. Un disparo al campo a Islandia en el verano 2006 
permitirá que visión algunos de los casquillos de hielo de la isla s
y la geología glacial, el canto atlántico mediados de expuesto y 
evidencia de las interacciones del hielo-volca'n."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">subglacial Lebensdauer und polare Fernabfragung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">mittler-atlantische Kante</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse atmosphärische und planetarische Wissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">anwesende und letzte Eis-Blätter</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Glazial- Geologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eis-in Verbindung stehende Forschung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Island</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geology/Earth Wissenschaft General</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">subglacial Vulkane</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">extraterrestrial planetarisches Eis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eis microkinetics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Snowball Masse</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Meer-Eis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Glazial- Abnutzung und Tectonics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eisblattformung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Klimasätze: polare und tropische Eiskerne</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">planetarisches Eis</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gletscher</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eisrheologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la vie subglacial et télédétection polaire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">arête mi-atlantique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les sciences atmosphériques et planétaires de la 
terre</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">glace-feuilles actuelles et passées</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">géologie glaciaire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">recherche glace-connexe</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Islande</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Général de la Science de Geology/Earth</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">volcans subglacial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">glace planétaire extraterrestre</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">microkinetics de glace</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La terre de Snowball</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">mer-glace</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">érosion et tectonique glaciaires</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">modeler de feuille de glace</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">enregistrements de climat : noyaux polaires et 
tropicaux de glace</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">glace planétaire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">glaciers</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">rhéologie de glace</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">vida subglacial e detetar remoto polar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">cume mid-mid-atlantic</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências atmosféricas e planetárias da terra</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">gelo-folhas atuais e passadas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">geologia glacial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">pesquisa gelo-relacionada</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Islândia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">General Da Ciência De Geology/Earth</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">vulcões subglacial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">gelo planetário extraterrestrial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">microkinetics do gelo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Terra De Snowball</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">mar-gelo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">erosão e tectonics glacial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">modelar da folha do gelo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">registros do clima: núcleos polares e tropicais 
do gelo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">gelo planetário</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">geleiras</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">rheology do gelo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">vita subglacial e telerilevamento polare</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">cresta metà di-atlantica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze atmosferiche e planetarie della terra</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ghiaccio-fogli attuali e passati</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">geologia glaciale</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ricerca ghiaccio-relativa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">l'Islanda</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Generalità Di Scienza Di Geology/Earth</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">vulcani subglacial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ghiaccio planetario extraterrestrial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">microkinetics del ghiaccio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Terra Di Snowball</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">mare-ghiaccio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">erosione e tettonica glaciali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">modellistica del foglio del ghiaccio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">record di clima: nuclei polari e tropicali del 
ghiaccio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ghiaccio planetario</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ghiacciai</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">reologia del ghiaccio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχεδόν πολική ζωή και πολική τηλεπισκόπηση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μέσος-ατλαντική κορυφογραμμή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γήινες ατμοσφαιρικές και πλανητικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πάγος-φύλλα παρόντος και παρελθόντος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παγετώδης γεωλογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πάγος-σχετική με το έρευνα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ισλανδία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γεωλογία/γήινη επιστήμη γενικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχεδόν πολικά ηφαίστεια</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξωγήινος πλανητικός πάγος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">microkinetics πάγου</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γη χιονιών</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">θάλασσα-πάγος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παγετώδεις διάβρωση και τεκτονική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">διαμόρφωση φύλλων πάγου</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αρχεία κλίματος: πολικοί και τροπικοί πυρήνες πάγου</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πλανητικός πάγος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παγετώνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ρεολογία πάγου</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">vida subglacial y detección alejada polar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">canto mediados de-atla'ntico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias atmosféricas y planetarias de la tierra</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">actuales y últimas hielo-hojas</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">geología glacial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">investigación hielo-relacionada</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Islandia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">General De la Ciencia De Geology/Earth</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">volcanes subglacial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">hielo planetario extraterrestre</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">microkinetics del hielo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tierra De Snowball</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">mar-hielo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">erosión y tectónica glaciales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el modelar de la hoja del hielo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">expedientes del clima: memorias polares y 
tropicales del hielo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">hielo planetario</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">glaciares</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">rheology del hielo</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>469</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">exploration of the earth</string>
                <string language="sv">jordens utforskande</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_6650-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_6650-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:46:11.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T05:52:58.02Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_6650</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Earth--Atmospheric--and-Planetary-Sciences/12-753Spring-2006/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
