<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104322</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104322</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086865</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Suffrage On Stage: Marie Jenney Howe Parodies the Opposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stimmrecht Auf Stadium: Marie Jenney Howe 
Parodien die Opposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Suffrage Sur L'Étape : Marie Jenney Howe 
parodie l'opposition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Suffrage No Estágio: Marie Jenney Howe 
parodies a oposição</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Suffrage Sulla Fase: Marie Jenney Howe 
parodies l'opposizione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ψήφος στη σκηνή: Το Marie Jenney Howe 
διακωμωδεί την αντίθεση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sufragio En Etapa: Marie Jenney Howe parodia
la oposición</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1920, after more than seventy years of struggle, the Nineteenth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. While nineteenth-century suffrage campaigns gained partial voting rights for women in twenty states, beginning in 1910 the push for suffrage took on a new urgency under the National American Woman Suffrage Association (NAWSA) and the more radical National Woman's Party (NWP). Their campaigns reached wide audiences, in part because suffragists had learned to spread their messages through imaginative use of various media. Drawing on domestic traditions of parlor plays and dramatic tableaux, suffragists used brief plays and monologues to enliven their own meetings and to enlist new members through performances at women's clubs and community theaters. Marie Jenney Howe wrote this  Antisuffrage Monologue  for the drama group of the New York Woman's Suffrage Party and other suffrage organizations. In it, she parodied anti-suffragist arguments that relied on stereotypes of female dependence, irrationality, and delicacy even as they also warned that women voters would exert too much power. Howe, a Unitarian minister, later founded Heterodoxy, a group of women intellectuals and radicals in New York City's Greenwich Village.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1920 nachdem mehr als siebzig Jahre Kampf, die 
19.änderung zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit Frauen das Recht 
bewilligte zu wählen. Während 19.-Jahrhundert Stimmrecht die 
gewonnenen teilweisen wählenden Rechte für Frauen in Zwanzig 
Zuständen wirbt, anfangend in 1910 nahm der Stoß für Stimmrecht auf
einer neuen Dringlichkeit unter der nationalen amerikanischen 
Frau-Stimmrecht-Verbindung (NAWSA) und der radikaleren nationalen 
Partei der Frau (NWP). Ihre Kampagnen erreichten breite
Publikum, im Teil, weil suffragists erlernt hatten, ihre Meldungen 
durch phantasiereichen Gebrauch von verschiedenen Media zu verbreiten.
Zeichnend auf inländische Traditionen der Wohnzimmerspiele und 
der drastischen Verzeichnisse, verwendeten suffragists kurze Spiele 
und Monologe, um ihre eigenen Sitzungen zu beleben und neue Bauteile 
durch Leistungen an den Vereinen der Frauen und an den 
Gemeinschaftstheatern einzutragen. Marie Jenney Howe schrieb 
diesen Antisuffrage Monolog für die Dramagruppe der der New York 
Stimmrecht-Partei Frau und anderer Stimmrechtorganisationen. 
In ihm parodied sie anti-suffragist Argumente, die auf 
Stereotypen der weiblichen Abhängigkeit, des irrationality und der 
Zartheit beruhten, selbst als sie auch warnten, daß Frauwähler zu 
viel Energie anwenden würden. Howe, ein Unitarian Minister, 
neueres gegründetes Heterodoxy, eine Gruppe Frauintellektuelle und 
-radikale im Greenwich Village Der New York Stadt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1920, après que plus de soixante-dix ans de 
lutte, le dix-neuvième amendement à la constitution des ETATS-UNIS 
ait accordé à des femmes la droite de voter. Tandis que le 
suffrage de dix-neuvième-siècle fait campagne droit de vote partiel 
gagné pour des femmes dans vingt états, commençant dans 1910 la 
poussée pour le suffrage a pris une nouvelle urgence sous 
l'association américaine nationale de suffrage de femme (NAWSA) et la
partie de la femme nationale plus radicale (NWP). Leurs 
campagnes ont atteint les assistances larges, en partie parce que les 
suffragettes avaient appris à écarter leurs messages par 
l'utilisation imaginative de divers medias. Dessinant sur des 
traditions domestiques des jeux de salon et des tableaux 
excessifs, les suffragettes avaient l'habitude de brefs jeux et 
monologues pour animer leurs propres réunions et pour enrôler de 
nouveaux membres par des exécutions aux clubs des femmes et aux 
théâtres de la communauté. Marie Jenney Howe a écrit ce 
Monologue d'Antisuffrage pour le groupe de drame de la partie du 
suffrage de la femme de New York et d'autres organismes de suffrage. 
Dans lui, elle a parodié les arguments d'anti-suffragette qui se 
sont fondés sur des stéréotypes de la dépendance, d'irrationality,
et de délicatesse femelles même pendant qu'ils avertissaient 
également que les électrices de femmes exerceraient trop de 
puissance. Howe, un ministre unitarien, une plus défunte 
Hétérodoxie fondée, un groupe d'intellectuelles de femmes et radicaux
dans le village de Greenwich de la ville de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1920, depois que mais de setenta anos do 
esforço, a décima nona emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
concedeu a mulheres a direita votar. Quando um suffrage de 
décimo-século fizer campanha as direitas votando parciais ganhas 
para mulheres em vinte estados, começando em 1910 o impulso para o 
suffrage fêz exame em um urgency novo sob a associação americana 
nacional do suffrage da mulher (NAWSA) e o partido da mulher nacional 
mais radical (NWP). Suas campanhas alcançaram audiências 
largas, na parte porque os suffragists tinham aprendido espalhar suas 
mensagens com o uso imaginative de vários media. Desenhando em 
tradições domésticas de jogos da sala de estar e de quadros 
dramáticos, os suffragists usaram jogos e monologues breves enliven 
suas próprias reuniões e alistar membros novos com os desempenhos em
clubes das mulheres e em teatros da comunidade. Marie Jenney 
Howe escreveu este monologue de Antisuffrage para o grupo do drama do 
partido do suffrage da mulher de New York e de outras organizações 
do suffrage. Nele, parodied os argumentos do anti-suffragist que
confiaram em stereotypes da dependência, do irrationality, e do 
delicacy fêmeas mesmo enquanto advertiram também que os eleitores 
das mulheres exerceriam demasiada potência. Howe, um ministro 
de Unitarian, Heterodoxy fundado mais atrasado, um grupo de 
intelectuais e de radicais das mulheres na vila de Greenwich da cidade
de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1920, dopo che più di settanta anni di lotta, 
la diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI UNITI 
assegni a donne la destra votare. Mentre il suffrage di 
diciannovesimo-secolo fa una campagna diritti di voto parziali 
guadagnati per le donne in venti dichiara, cominciando in 1910
la spinta per suffrage ha intrapreso una nuova urgenza sotto 
l'associazione americana nazionale di suffrage della donna (NAWSA) ed 
il partito della donna nazionale più radicale (NWP). Le loro 
campagne hanno raggiunto i pubblici larghi, in parte perché i 
suffragists avevano imparato spargere i loro messaggi con uso 
immaginativo di vari media. Dissipando sulle tradizioni 
domestiche dei giochi del salone e dei tableaux drammatici, i 
suffragists hanno usato i brevi giochi e monologues per enliven le 
loro proprie riunioni e per arruolare i nuovi membri con le 
prestazioni ai randelli delle donne ed ai teatri della Comunità. 
Marie Jenney Howe ha scritto questo monologue di Antisuffrage 
per il gruppo di dramma del partito di suffrage della donna de New 
York e di altre organizzazioni di suffrage. In esso, parodied 
gli argomenti di anti-suffragist che hanno contato sugli stereotipi di
dipendenza, del irrationality e della squisitezza femminili proprio 
mentre egualmente hanno avvertito che gli elettori delle donne 
impiegherebbero troppa potenza. Howe, un ministro di 
Unitarian, Heterodoxy fondato successivo, un gruppo degli 
intellettuali e dei radicali delle donne nel villaggio di Greenwich 
della città de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1920, μετά από περισσότερο από εβδομήντα έτη 
προσπάθειας, τη δέκατη έννατη τροποποίηση στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
σύνταγμα που χορηγείται τις γυναίκες το δικαίωμα να ψηφίσει. 
Ενώ οι εκστρατείες ψήφου δέκατος-αιώνα κέρδισαν τα μερικά
δικαιώματα ψήφου για τις γυναίκες σε είκοσι κράτη, αρχίζοντας το
1910 η ώθηση για την ψήφο πήρε μια νέα επείγουσα ανάγκη κάτω
από την εθνική αμερικανική ένωση ψήφου γυναικών (NAWSA) και 
το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος περισσότερης ριζικής εθνικής γυναίκας 
(NWP). Οι εκστρατείες τους έφθασαν στα ευρέα ακροατήρια, 
εν μέρει επειδή suffragists είχαν μάθει να διαδίδουν τα 
μηνύματά τους μέσω της επινοητικής χρήσης των διάφορων μέσων. 
Επισύροντας την προσοχή στις εσωτερικές παραδόσεις 
παιχνιδιών αιθουσών και δραματικών εικόνων, suffragists 
χρησιμοποίησαν τα συνοπτικούς παιχνίδια και τους μονολόγους για να
αναζωογονήσουν τις συνεδριάσεις τους και για να στρατολογήσουν τα 
νέα μέλη μέσω των αποδόσεων τα κοινοτικά θέατρα των γυναικών 
στις λέσχες και. Το Marie Jenney Howe έγραψε αυτόν 
τον μονόλογο Antisuffrage για την ομάδα δράματος του 
συμβαλλόμενου μέρους ψήφου της γυναίκας της Νέας Υόρκης και 
άλλων οργανώσεων ψήφου. Σε το, διακωμώδησε τα ορίσματα 
αντι-σuφφραγηστ που στηρίχθηκαν στα στερεότυπα της θηλυκού 
εξάρτησης, του παραλογισμού, και της λιχουδιάς ακόμη και 
δεδομένου ότι επίσης προειδοποίησαν ότι οι ψηφοφόροι γυναικών 
θα ασκούσαν πάρα πολλή δύναμη. Howe, ένας ενωτικός 
υπουργός, πιό πρόσφατη ιδρυμένη ετεροδοξία, μια ομάδα 
διανοούμενων και ριζοσπαστών γυναικών στο χωριό του Γκρήνουιτς 
της πόλης της Νέας Υόρκης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1920, después de que más de setenta años de 
lucha, la diecinueveavo enmienda a la constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
concediera a mujeres la derecha de votar. Mientras que el 
sufragio del diecinueveavo-siglo hace campaña los derechos al voto 
parciales ganados para las mujeres en veinte estados, comenzando en 
1910 el empuje para el sufragio adquirió una nueva urgencia bajo la 
asociación americana nacional del sufragio de la mujer (NAWSA) y 
partido de la mujer nacional más radical (NWP). Sus campañas 
alcanzaron a audiencias anchas, en parte porque los suffragists 
habían aprendido separar sus mensajes con el uso imaginativo de 
varios media. Trazando en tradiciones domésticas de los juegos 
de la sala y de los cuadros dramáticos, los suffragists utilizaron 
juegos y monólogos abreviados para enliven sus propias reuniones y 
para alistar a nuevos miembros con funcionamientos en los clubs de las
mujeres y los teatros de la comunidad. Marie Jenney Howe 
escribió este monólogo de Antisuffrage para el grupo del drama del 
partido del sufragio de la mujer de Nueva York y de otras 
organizaciones del sufragio. En él, ella parodió los 
argumentos del anti-suffragist que confiaron en estereotipos de la 
dependencia, del irrationality, y de la delicadeza femeninos incluso 
mientras que también advirtieron que los votantes de las mujeres 
ejercieran demasiada potencia. Howe, ministro de Unitarian, un 
Heterodoxy fundado más último, un grupo de intelectuales y de 
radicales de las mujeres en la aldea de Greenwich de la ciudad de 
Nueva York.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086865</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104322</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/suffrage-on-stage-marie-jenney-howe-parodies-the-opposition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
