<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108384</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108384</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973962</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reading and Writing Poetry</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lese-und Schreibenpoesie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Poésie de lecture et d'écriture</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Poesia da leitura e da escrita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poesia di scrittura e della lettura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποίηση ανάγνωσης και γραψίματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Poesía de la lectura y de la escritura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This booklet is a collection of opinions of nearly 50 important poets from 25 countries in 5 continents on the best ways to present poetry to secondary school pupils. It is mainly intended for use in teacher training programmes, to bring to methods of teaching poetry two important dimensions: the creative perspective of poets themselves, as well as the perspective of different cultures regarding the reading and writing of poetry.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Broschüre ist eine Ansammlung Meinungen von
fast 50 wichtigen Dichtern aus 25 Ländern in 5 Kontinenten auf den 
besten Methoden, Poesie Sekundärschulepupillen darzustellen. Es
ist hauptsächlich für Gebrauch in den Ausbildung der 
Lehrerprogrammen, zu den Methoden des Unterrichtens Poesie von von 
zwei wichtigen Maßen zu holen bestimmt: die kreative 
Perspektive der Dichter selbst, sowie die Perspektive der 
unterschiedlichen Kulturen betreffend sind den Messwert und das 
Schreiben von Poesie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce livret est une collection d'avis de presque 50 
poèts importants de 25 pays dans 5 continents sur les meilleures 
voies de présenter la poésie aux pupilles d'école secondaire. 
On le destine principalement pour l'usage dans des programmes de
formation de professeur, d'apporter aux méthodes d'enseigner à 
poésie deux dimensions importantes : la perspective créatrice 
des poèts elles-mêmes, aussi bien que la perspective de différentes
cultures concernant la lecture et l'écriture de la poésie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este livreto é uma coleção das opiniões de 
quase 50 poetas importantes de 25 países em 5 continentes nas mais 
melhores maneiras apresentar a poesia às pupilas da escola 
secundária. Pretende-se principalmente para o uso em programas 
de treinamento do professor, trazer aos métodos de ensinar a poesia 
duas dimensões importantes: o perspective creativo dos poetas 
ele mesmo, as.well.as o perspective das culturas diferentes a respeito
da leitura e da escrita da poesia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo libretto è una collezione di opinioni di 
quasi 50 poets importanti da 25 paesi in 5 continenti sui modi 
migliori presentare la poesia alle pupille della scuola secondaria. 
Pricipalmente è inteso per uso nei programmi di formazione 
dell'insegnante, portare ai metodi di istruzione alla poesia delle due
dimensioni importanti: la prospettiva creativa dei poets essi 
stessi, così come la prospettiva delle colture differenti per quanto 
riguarda la lettura e la scrittura della poesia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το βιβλιάριο είναι μια συλλογή των απόψεων 
σχεδόν 50 σημαντικών ποιητών από 25 χώρες σε 5 ηπείρους στους
καλύτερους τρόπους να παρουσιαστεί η ποίηση στους μαθητές 
δευτεροβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης. Προορίζεται κυρίως για τη χρήση
στα προγράμματα κατάρτισης εκπαιδευτικών, να φέρει στις μεθόδους 
στην ποίηση δύο σημαντικές διαστάσεις: η δημιουργική 
προοπτική των ποιητών οι ίδιοι, καθώς επίσης και η προοπτική των
διαφορετικών πολιτισμών σχετικά με την ανάγνωση και το γράψιμο 
της ποίησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este librete es una colección de opiniones de 
casi 50 poetas importantes a partir de 25 países en 5 continentes en 
las mejores maneras de presentar poesía a las pupilas de la escuela 
secundaria. Se piensa principalmente para el uso en programas de
entrenamiento de profesor, de traer a los métodos de enseñar a 
poesía dos dimensiones importantes: la perspectiva creativa de 
poetas ellos mismos, así como la perspectiva de diversas culturas con
respecto la lectura y a la escritura de la poesía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973962</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108384</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/reading-and-writing-poetry</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
