<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105151</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105151</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212801</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">This Land is Our Land</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Land ist unser Land</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette terre est notre terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta terra é nossa terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa terra è la nostra terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το έδαφος είναι το έδαφός μας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta pista es nuestra pista</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Throughout history, as the concepts of empire and nation-states took hold, individual countries secured their borders and tried to keep unwanted migrants out. As we enter the 21st century Anwarul K. Chowdhury, an Under-Secretary of the United Nations, says, 'The first step towards examining the road to peace should start with an appreciation of the changing nature of conflicts. Gone are days of war between states for conquest, extension of spheres of influence in the name of ideology ... Today's wars are about settling border disputes....' In these lessons students confront that issue. Students begin by discussing why people cross borders and the rights people have when they enter another country. Students will discover the factors that determine the location of borders through the examination of maps, cartoons, and primary source documents. After completing this introductory activity, students will analyze a chart comparing the economic situation in the neighboring countries of Zimbabwe and Botswana, and predict what economic problems each country has. They will then view segments of the WIDE ANGLE film 'Border Jumpers' (2005) to understand why these economic problems exist, develop further arguments for those streaming into Botswana from Zimbabwe and for those in Botswana itself, and compare them to their own predictions. As a culminating activity, students will work in groups to develop a presentation for a simulation of the 17th Annual Nobel Peace Prize Forum. Their presentations will be shared with their classmates, and, if desired, sent to the United Nations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während der Geschichte als die Konzepte des 
Reiches und der Nation-Zustände nahm Einfluß, sicherten einzelne 
Länder ihre Ränder und versuchten, unerwünschte Wanderer heraus zu 
halten. Da wir das 21. Jahrhundert Anwarul K. Chowdhury 
erreichen, sagt ein Under-Secretary der vereinigten Nationen, ' der 
erste Jobstep in Richtung zum Überprüfen der Straße zum Frieden 
sollte mit einer Anerkennung der ändernden Natur von 
$überschneidungen beginnen. Gegangen Tage des Krieges zwischen 
Zuständen für Eroberung, Extension der Bereiche des Einflusses im 
Namen der Ideologie... Heutige Kriege sind über vereinbarenden 
Rand diskutiert....' In diesen Lektionen konfrontieren 
Kursteilnehmer diese Ausgabe. Kursteilnehmer fangen an, indem 
sie behandeln, warum Leutekreuzränder und die Rechtleute haben, wann 
sie ein anderes Land kommen. Kursteilnehmer entdecken die 
Faktoren, die den Standort der Ränder durch die Prüfung der Karten, 
der Karikaturen und der Primärquelldokumente feststellen. 
Nachdem sie diese einleitende Aktivität durchgeführt haben, 
analysieren Kursteilnehmer ein Diagramm, welches die wirtschaftliche 
Lage in Anliegerstaat von Zimbabwe und von Botswana vergleicht und 
sagen, welche Wirtschaftsprobleme jedes Land hat voraus. Sie 
sehen dann Segmente des Weitwinkelfilmes ' Rand-der Überbrücker 
(2005) an um zu verstehen, warum diese Wirtschaftsprobleme existieren,
entwickeln weitere Argumente für die, die in Botswana von Zimbabwe 
strömen und für die in Botswana selbst und vergleichen sie mit ihren
eigenen Vorhersagen. Als kulminierende Aktivität arbeiten 
Kursteilnehmer in den Gruppen, um eine Darstellung für eine 
Simulation des 17. jährlichen Nobel Friedenspreis-Forums zu 
entwickeln. Ihre Darstellungen werden mit ihren Mitschülern 
geteilt und, wenn sie gewünscht werden, geschickt zu den Nationen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À travers l'histoire, car les concepts de l'empire
et des nation-états ont pris la prise, les différents pays ont fixé
leurs cadres et ont essayé d'enpêcher d'entrer les migrants non 
désirés. Car nous écrivons le 21ème siècle Anwarul K. 
Chowdhury, un under-Secretary des Nations Unies, dit, 'la première 
étape vers examiner la route à la paix devrait commencer par une 
appréciation de la nature changeante des conflits. Allés sont 
des jours de la guerre entre les états pour la conquête, extension 
des sphères de l'influence au nom de l'idéologie... Les 
guerres d'aujourd'hui sont au sujet de cadre d'arrangement 
conteste....' Dans ces leçons les étudiants confrontent cette 
issue. Les étudiants commencent en discutant pourquoi les 
cadres en travers de personnes et les personnes de droites ont quand 
ils entrent dans un autre pays. Les étudiants découvriront les
facteurs qui déterminent l'emplacement des cadres par l'examen des 
cartes, des dessins animés, et des documents de source primaires. 
Après avoir terminé cette activité préliminaire, les 
étudiants analyseront un diagramme comparant la situation économique
dans les pays voisins du Zimbabwe et du Botswana, et prévoient quels 
problèmes économiques chaque pays a. Ils visualiseront alors 
des segments cavaliers de cadre de film GRAND-ANGULAIRE les '(2005) 
pour comprendre pourquoi ces problèmes économiques existent, 
développent d'autres arguments pour ceux coulant en le Botswana du 
Zimbabwe et pour ceux au Botswana lui-même, et les comparent à leurs
propres prévisions. Comme activité culminante, les étudiants 
travailleront dans les groupes pour développer une présentation pour
une simulation du 17ème forum annuel de prix de paix Nobel. 
Leurs présentations seront partagées avec leurs camarades de 
classe, et, si désirées, envoyées aux Nations Unies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante todo o history, como os conceitos do 
império e dos nação-estados fêz exame da preensão, os países 
individuais fixaram suas beiras e tentaram-nas manter para fora 
emigrantes não desejados. Porque nós incorporamos o século 
XXI Anwarul K. Chowdhury, um under-Secretary das nações unidas, diz,
' a primeira etapa para examinar a estrada à paz deve começar com 
uma apreciação da natureza em mudança dos conflitos. São 
idos os dias da guerra entre estados para o conquest, extensão das 
esferas da influência no nome do ideology... As guerras de hoje
são sobre a beira estabelecindo-se disputam....' Nestas 
lições os estudantes confrontam essa edição. Os estudantes 
começam discutindo porque as beiras transversais dos povos e os povos
das direitas têm quando entram em um outro país. Os estudantes
descobrirão os fatores que determinam a posição das beiras através
da examinação dos mapas, dos cartoons, e de originais de fonte 
preliminares. Após ter terminado esta atividade introdutória, 
os estudantes analisarão uma carta que compara a situação 
econômica nos países neighboring de Zimbabwe e de Botswana, e 
predizem que problemas econômicos cada país tem. Verão então
segmentos as ligações em ponte da beira da película LARGA do 
ÂNGULO ' (2005) para compreender porque estes problemas econômicos 
existem, desenvolvem uns argumentos mais adicionais para aqueles que 
fluem em Botswana de Zimbabwe e para aqueles em Botswana próprio, e 
comparam-nos a suas próprias predições. Como uma atividade 
culminando, os estudantes trabalharão nos grupos para desenvolver uma
apresentação para uma simulação do 17o forum anual do prêmio da 
paz de Nobel. Suas apresentações serão compartilhadas com 
seus classmates, e, se desejadas, emitidas às nações unidas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Attraverso la storia, poichè i concetti 
dell'impero e di nation-dichiarare hanno preso la stretta, i diversi 
paesi hanno assicurato i loro bordi ed hanno provato ad impedire di 
entrare i migranti indesiderabili. Poichè entriamo nel 
ventunesimo secolo Anwarul K. Chowdhury, un under-Secretary delle 
Nazioni Unite, ad esempio, 'il primo punto verso esaminare la strada a
pace dovrebbe cominciare con un apprezzamento della natura cambiante 
dei conflitti. Sono andati i giorni della guerra in mezzo 
dichiara per la conquista, estensione delle sfere di influenza 
in nome dell'ideologia... Le odierne guerre sono circa il bordo 
di sedimentazione disputa....' In queste lezioni allievi 
confrontano quell'edizione. Gli allievi cominciano discutendo 
perchè i bordi trasversali della gente e la gente di diritti hanno 
quando entrano in un altro paese. Gli allievi scopriranno i 
fattori che determinano la posizione dei bordi attraverso l'esame dei 
programmi, dei fumetti e dei documenti di origine primari. Dopo 
avere completato questa attività introduttiva, gli allievi 
analizzeranno una tabella che confronta la situazione economica nei 
paesi limitrofi dello Zimbabwe e del Botswana e predicono che problemi
economici ogni paese ha. Allora osserveranno i segmenti i 
ponticelli del bordo della pellicola GRANDANGOLARE '(2005) per capire 
perchè questi problemi economici esistono, sviluppano ulteriori 
argomenti per quelli che effluiscono in Botswana dallo Zimbabwe e per 
quelli nel Botswana in se e le confrontano alle loro proprie 
previsioni. Come attività di culminazione, gli allievi 
lavoreranno nei gruppi per sviluppare una presentazione per una 
simulazione della diciassettesima tribuna annuale del premio di pace 
Nobel. Le loro presentazioni saranno ripartite con i loro 
classmates e, se volute, saranno trasmesse alle Nazioni Unite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια της ιστορίας, καθώς οι έννοιες 
της αυτοκρατορίας και τα έθνη κράτη πήραν τη λαβή, οι 
μεμονωμένες χώρες εξασφάλισαν τα σύνορά τους και προσπάθησαν να 
κρατήσουν τους ανεπιθύμητους μετανάστες έξω. Καθώς 
εισάγουμε το 21$ο αιώνα Anwarul Κ. Chowdhury, ένας 
υφυπουργός των Ηνωμένων Εθνών, λέει, "το πρώτο βήμα προς την 
εξέταση του δρόμου στην ειρήνη πρέπει να αρχίσει με μια εκτίμηση
της μεταβαλλόμενης φύσης των συγκρούσεων. Πηγαίνουν τις 
ημέρες του πολέμου μεταξύ των κρατών για την κατάκτηση, η 
επέκταση των σφαιρών της επιρροής στο όνομα των σημερινών 
πολέμων ιδεολογίας... είναι για την επίλυση των διαφωνιών 
συνόρων...." Σε αυτά τα μαθήματα οι σπουδαστές 
αντιμετωπίζουν εκείνο το ζήτημα. Οι σπουδαστές αρχίζουν με 
τη συζήτηση γιατί τα διαγώνια σύνορα ανθρώπων και οι άνθρωποι 
δικαιωμάτων έχουν πότε μπαίνουν σε μια άλλη χώρα. Οι 
σπουδαστές θα ανακαλύψουν τους παράγοντες που καθορίζουν τη θέση 
των συνόρων μέσω της εξέτασης των χαρτών, των κινούμενων 
σχεδίων, και των αρχικών εγγράφων πηγής. Μετά από να 
ολοκληρώσουν αυτήν την εισαγωγική δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές θα
αναλύσουν ένα διάγραμμα συγκρίνοντας την οικονομική κατάσταση 
στις γειτονικές χώρες της Ζιμπάπουε και της Μποτσουάνα, και θα 
προβλέψουν ποια οικονομικά προβλήματα κάθε χώρα έχει. Θα 
εμφανίσουν έπειτα τα τμήματα μνήμης της WIDE.ANGLE ταινίας 
"άλτες συνόρων" (2005) για να καταλάβουν γιατί αυτά τα 
οικονομικά προβλήματα υπάρχουν, αναπτύσσουν τα περαιτέρω 
ορίσματα για εκείνους που ρέουν στην Μποτσουάνα από τη Ζιμπάπουε
και για εκείνους στην Μποτσουάνα η ίδια, και τους συγκρίνουν με 
τις προβλέψεις τους. Σαν καταλήγοντας δραστηριότητα, οι 
σπουδαστές θα εργαστούν κατά ομάδες για να αναπτύξουν μια 
παρουσίαση για μια προσομοίωση του 17$ου ετήσιου φόρουμ βραβείων 
ειρήνης Νόμπελ. Οι παρουσιάσεις τους θα μοιραστούν με τους 
συμμαθητές τους, και, εάν επιδιώκονται, θα σταλούν στα Ηνωμένα 
Έθνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A través de la historia, como los conceptos del 
imperio y de nacio'n-estados se arraigaron, los países aseguraron sus
fronteras e intentaron guardar a nómadas indeseados hacia fuera. 
Pues incorporamos el siglo XXI Anwarul K. Chowdhury, un 
under-Secretary de los Naciones Unidas, dice, ' el primer paso de 
progresión hacia examinar el camino a la paz debe comenzar con un 
aprecio de la naturaleza que cambia de conflictos. Se van los 
días de la guerra entre los estados para la conquista, extensión de 
esferas de la influencia en el nombre de la ideología... Las 
guerras de hoy están sobre la frontera que coloca disputan....' 
En estas lecciones los estudiantes enfrentan esa edición. 
Los estudiantes comienzan discutiendo porqué las fronteras 
cruzadas de la gente y la gente de las derechas tienen cuando entran 
en otro país. Los estudiantes descubrirán los factores que 
determinan la localización de fronteras a través de la examinación 
de correspondencias, de historietas, y de documentos de fuente 
primarios. Después de terminar esta actividad introductoria, 
los estudiantes analizarán una carta que compara la situación 
económica en los países vecinos de Zimbabwe y de Botswana, y 
predicen qué problemas económicos tiene cada país. Entonces 
opinión segmentos puentes de la frontera de la película GRANANGULAR 
los ' (2005) para entender porqué existen estos problemas 
económicos, desarrollan otros argumentos para ésos que fluyen en 
Botswana de Zimbabwe y para ésos en Botswana sí mismo, y los 
comparan a sus propias predicciones. Como actividad que culmina,
los estudiantes trabajarán en grupos para desarrollar una 
presentación para una simulación del 17mo foro anual del premio de 
la paz Nobel. Sus presentaciones serán compartidas con sus 
classmates, y, si están deseadas, enviadas a los Naciones Unidas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MIRLA MORRISON
FN:MIRLA MORRISON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212801</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105151</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/this-land-is-our-land</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
