<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105189</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105189</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206609</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Capital Language Resource Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Volksvermögen-Sprachenhilfsmittel-Mitte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre de Ressource de Langage de Capital 
National</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro Do Recurso Da Língua Do Capital Nacional</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro Delle Risorse Di Linguaggio Del Capitale 
Nazionale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κέντρο των γλωσσικών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς εθνικού 
κεφαλαίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro Del Recurso Del Lenguaje Del Capital 
Nacional</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features The Essentials of Language Teaching, an online publication that examines the goals and methods of teaching a foreign language. The publication examines how to plan lessons, motivate students, assess learning, and how to teach listening, speaking, writing, grammar, and culture. Elsewhere on the site, Teacher's Corner includes answers to questions on classroom management, teaching culture, vocabulary activities, and learning a foreign language.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet die Wesensmerkmale des 
Sprachunterrichtes, eine Onlinepublikation, die die Ziele und die 
Methoden des Unterrichtens einer Fremdsprache überprüft. Die 
Publikation überprüft, wie man Lektionen plant, Kursteilnehmer 
motiviert, das Lernen festsetzt und wie man das Hören, das Sprechen, 
das Schreiben, Grammatik und Kultur unterrichtet. Anderwohin auf
der Site, schließt Ecke des Lehrers Antworten zu den Fragen über 
Klassenzimmermanagement, unterrichtende Kultur, Wortschatzaktivitäten
und das Lernen einer Fremdsprache ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte les bases de l'enseignement des langues, 
une publication en ligne qui examine les buts et les méthodes 
d'enseigner une langue étrangère. La publication examine 
comment projeter des leçons, motiver des étudiants, évaluer 
l'étude, et comment enseigner l'écoute, parler, écrire, la 
grammaire, et la culture. Ailleurs sur le site, le coin du 
professeur inclut des réponses aux questions sur la gestion de salle 
de classe, la culture d'enseignement, les activités de vocabulaire, 
et apprendre une langue étrangère.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza os fundamentos da instrução de 
línguas, uma publicação em linha que examine os objetivos e os 
métodos de ensinar uma língua extrangeira. A publicação 
examina como planear lições, motivate estudantes, avaliar a 
aprendizagem, e como ensinar escutar, falar, escrever, gramática, e 
cultura. Em outra parte no local, o canto do professor inclui 
respostas às perguntas na gerência da sala de aula, na cultura 
ensinando, nas atividades do vocabulário, e em aprender uma língua 
extrangeira.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza il necessario di insegnamento delle 
lingue, una pubblicazione in linea che esamina gli obiettivi ed i 
metodi di istruzione della lingua straniera. La pubblicazione 
esamina come progettare le lezioni, motivare gli allievi, valutare 
imparare e come insegnare ascoltare, parlare, la scrittura, la 
grammatica e la coltura. Altrove sul luogo, il angolo 
dell'insegnante include le risposte alle domande sulla gestione 
dell'aula, sulla coltura d'istruzione, sulle attività di vocabolario 
e sull'imparare una lingua straniera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει τα προϊόντα πρώτης ανάγκης της 
διδασκαλίας γλωσσών, μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση δημοσίευση που 
εξετάζει τους στόχους και τις μεθόδους μια ξένη γλώσσα. Η 
δημοσίευση εξετάζει πώς να προγραμματίσει τα μαθήματα, να 
παρακινήσει τους σπουδαστές, να αξιολογήσει την εκμάθηση, και πώς
να διδάξει το άκουσμα, την ομιλία, το γράψιμο, τη γραμματική, και
τον πολιτισμό. Αλλού στην περιοχή, η γωνία του δασκάλου 
περιλαμβάνει τις απαντήσεις στις ερωτήσεις στη διαχείριση τάξεων,
τον πολιτισμό διδασκαλίας, τις δραστηριότητες λεξιλογίου, και την 
εκμάθηση μιας ξένης γλώσσας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece el esencial de la instrucción de lenguas, 
una publicación en línea que examine las metas y los métodos de 
enseñar un idioma extranjero. La publicación examina cómo 
planear lecciones, motivar a estudiantes, evaluar aprender, y cómo 
enseñar escuchar, el discurso, escribir, la gramática, y la cultura.
A otra parte en el sitio, la esquina del profesor incluye 
respuestas a las preguntas sobre la gerencia de la sala de clase, la 
cultura de enseñanza, actividades del vocabulario, y aprender un 
idioma extranjero.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206609</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105189</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-capital-language-resource-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
