<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106880</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106880</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212300</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Stratospheric Ozone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stratospheric Ozon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Ozone Stratosphérique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ozônio Stratospheric</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ozono Stratosferico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στρατοσφαιρικό όζον</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ozono Estratosférico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Animations clips from NASA's Scientific Visualization Studio are used to help guide students through an introductory tutorial on stratospheric ozone. Students then explore observational data from ozone-sondes, TOMS, and UARS measurements to learn about changes in stratospheric ozone over the past several decades. Measurements and model predictions are also used to help students understand future stratospheric ozone recovery scenarios.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Animationclips vom wissenschaftlichen 
Sichtbarmachung-Studio der NASAS werden benutzt, um 
Anleitungkursteilnehmern durch einen einleitenden Tutorial auf 
stratospheric Ozon zu helfen. Kursteilnehmer erforschen dann 
Beobachtungsdaten vom Ozon-sondes, TOMS und UARS von den Messen, um 
über Änderungen im stratospheric Ozon-Überschuß zu erlernen die 
Vergangenheit einige Dekaden. Messen und Modellvorhersagen 
werden auch verwendet, um Kursteilnehmern zu helfen, zukünftige 
stratospheric Ozon-Wiederanlaufdrehbücher zu verstehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des clips d'animations du studio scientifique de 
la visualisation de la NASA sont utilisés pour aider des étudiants 
de guide par un cours d'instruction préliminaire sur l'ozone 
stratosphérique. Les étudiants explorent alors des données 
d'observation du l'ozone-sondes, des mesures de TOMS, et d'UARS pour 
se renseigner sur des changements d'excédent stratosphérique de 
l'ozone le passé plusieurs décennies. Des mesures et les 
prévisions de modèle sont également employées pour aider des 
étudiants à comprendre de futurs scénarios stratosphériques de 
reprise de l'ozone.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os grampos dos animations do estúdio científico 
do visualization da NASA são usados ajudar a estudantes da guia com 
um tutorial introdutório no ozônio stratospheric. Os 
estudantes exploram então dados observational do ozônio-sondes, das 
medidas de TOMS, e de UARS para aprender sobre mudanças no excesso 
stratospheric do ozônio o passado diversas décadas. As medidas
e as predições do modelo são usadas também ajudar a estudantes 
compreender os scenarios stratospheric futuros da recuperação do 
ozônio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le clip di animazioni dall'studio scientifico di 
visualizzazione della NASA sono utilizzate per aiutare gli allievi 
della guida con una lezione privata introduttiva su ozono 
stratosferico. Gli allievi allora esplorano i dati 
d'osservazione da ozono-sondes, dalle misure di UARS e di TOMS per 
imparare circa i cambiamenti nell'eccedenza stratosferica dell'ozono 
l'esperienza parecchie decadi. Le misure e le previsioni del 
modello egualmente sono usate per aiutare gli allievi a capire i piani
d'azione stratosferici futuri di recupero dell'ozono.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συνδετήρες ζωτικοτήτων από το επιστημονικό 
στούντιο απεικόνισης της NASA χρησιμοποιούνται για να βοηθήσουν
τους σπουδαστές οδηγών μέσω ενός εισαγωγικού σεμιναρίου στο 
στρατοσφαιρικό όζον. Οι σπουδαστές ερευνούν έπειτα τα 
παρατηρητικά στοιχεία από τα οζονόμετρα, τις μετρήσεις TOMS, 
και UARS που μαθαίνουν για τις αλλαγές στο στρατοσφαιρικό όζον 
κατά τη διάρκεια των προηγούμενων αρκετών δεκαετιών. Οι 
μετρήσεις και οι πρότυπες προβλέψεις χρησιμοποιούνται επίσης για 
να βοηθήσουν τους σπουδαστές να καταλάβουν τα μελλοντικά 
στρατοσφαιρικά σενάρια αποκατάστασης όζοντος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los clips de las animaciones del estudio 
científico de la visualización de la NASA se utilizan para ayudar a 
estudiantes de la guía con una guía introductoria en el ozono 
estratosférico. Los estudiantes entonces exploran datos de 
observación del ozono-sondes, de las medidas de TOMS, y de UARS para 
aprender sobre cambios en excedente estratosférico del ozono el 
pasado varias décadas. Las medidas y las predicciones del 
modelo también se utilizan para ayudar a estudiantes a entender los 
decorados estratosféricos futuros de la recuperación del ozono.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MACKAY
FN:ROBERT MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212300</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106880</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/stratospheric-ozone</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
