<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104488</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104488</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087069</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Vagrant in Fiction: Emblematic American?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Vagabund in der Erfindung: 
Symbolischer Amerikaner?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le vagabond dans la fiction : Américain 
Emblématique ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O vagrant no fiction: Americano Emblematic?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il vagrant nel romanzo: Americano 
Emblematic?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το vagrant στη μυθιστοριογραφία: Εμβληματικοσ' 
Αμερικανός;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El vagabundo en la ficción: ¿Americano 
Emblematic?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Vagrancy was one of the most troubling signs of the Great Depression of the 1930s. Then, as now, those who had food and shelter were confronted by the sight and appeals of those who did not. Shabby men sought food or work on the doorsteps of private homes while men, women, and children stood in the breadlines of municipal relief agencies. Vagrants gathered in "hobo jungles" on the outskirts of town as beggars on the streets appealed to more prosperous passersby. Middle-class observers viewed vagrants with suspicion, empathy, concern, fear, and sometimes even a twinge of envy. For some stolidly holding on to traditional values of work and success, the "bum" was suspect, potentially a con artist.In a very different response, novelist John Dos Passos made the vagrant a symbol of the derailed promise of the American dream in this vignette "Vag," which ended his monumental  U.S.A . trilogy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vagrancy war einer des Bemühens der Zeichen des großen 
Tiefstands der dreißiger Jahre. Dann, als jetzt, wurden die, 
die Nahrung und Schutz hatten, durch den Anblick und die Anklänge von
denen konfrontiert, die nicht. Schäbige Männer gesuchte 
Nahrung oder Arbeit über die Türstufen der privaten Häuser, 
während Männer, Frauen und Kinder in den breadlines der städtischen
Entlastung Agenturen standen. Vagabunde erfaßten "in den 
Hobodschungeln" auf dem Randgebiet der Stadt, während Bettler auf
den Straßen wohlhabenderen Passanten gefielen. 
Mittelklassebeobachter sahen Vagabunde mit Misstrauen an, 
empathy, Interesse, Furcht und glätten manchmal einen Twinge des 
Neides. Für etwas zu den traditionellen Werten der Arbeit und 
des Erfolges stolidly an anhalten, war der "Gammler", möglicherweise 
ein Betrüger artist.In eine sehr andere Antwort, Novelist John DOS 
Passos vermutlich defekt, das den Vagabund ein Symbol von der 
entgleisten Versprechung des amerikanischen Traums in diesem vignette 
"Vag," gebildet wurde, das sein hervorragendes USA beendete. 
Trilogie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le vagabondage était un de préoccuper des signes de la 
grande dépression des années 30. Puis, en tant que maintenant,
ceux qui ont eu la nourriture et l'abri ont été confrontés à la 
vue et aux appels de ceux qui pas . Nourriture ou emploi 
recherchée par hommes minables sur les seuils des maisons privées 
tandis que les hommes, les femmes, et les enfants se tenaient dans les
breadlines des agences municipales de soulagement. Les vagabonds
se sont réunis dans des "jungles de hobo" sur les périphéries de la
ville pendant que les mendiants sur les rues faisaient appel à des 
passants plus prospères. Les observateurs de classe moyen ont 
visualisé des vagabonds avec le soupçon, empathie, souci, 
crainte, et égalisent parfois un élancement d'envie. Pour se 
tenir stolidly en fonction sur des valeurs traditionnelles de travail 
et de succès, le "clochard" était suspect, potentiellement un escroc
artist.In une réponse très différente, DOS Passos de John de 
romancier fait le vagabond un symbole de la promesse déraillée du 
rêve américain dans cette vignette "Vag," qui a terminé les ses 
Etats-Unis monumentaux. trilogie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O vagrancy era um de incomodar sinais do depression grande
dos 1930s. Então, como agora, aqueles que tiveram o alimento e 
o abrigo foram confrontados pela vista e pelas apelações daquelas 
que não . Homens shabby alimento ou trabalho procurado nos 
doorsteps de HOME confidenciais quando os homens, as mulheres, e as 
crianças estiveram nos breadlines de agências municipais do relevo. 
Os vagrants recolheram do "em selvas hobo" nos outskirts da 
cidade enquanto os pedintes nas ruas apelaram a uns transeuntes mais 
prósperos. Os observadores do middle-class viram vagrants com 
suspeita, empathy, interesse, medo, e nivelam às vezes um twinge do 
envy. Para algum stolidly prender sobre aos valores tradicionais
do trabalho e do sucesso, o "bum" era suspeito, potencial um con 
artist.In uma resposta muito diferente, Dos Passos de John do novelist
feito o vagrant um símbolo da promessa descarrilhada do sonho 
americano neste vignette "Vag," que terminou seus EUA monumental. 
trilogia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il vagrancy era uno del disturbarsi i segni della 
depressione grande dei 1930s. Allora, come ora, coloro che ha 
avuto l'alimento e riparo sono stati confrontati dalla vista e dagli 
appelli di coloro che non. Alimento o impiego cercato uomini 
miseri sui gradini della porta delle sedi riservate mentre gli uomini,
le donne ed i bambini si sono levati in piedi nei breadlines delle 
agenzie comunali di rilievo. I vagrants hanno riunito 
"nelle giungle del hobo" sui outskirts della città mentre i 
mendicanti sulle vie hanno fatto appello ai passersby più prosperosi.
Gli osservatori della classe media hanno osservato i vagrants 
con sospetto, empathy, preoccupazione, timore ed a volte livellano un 
twinge di invidia. Per una certa stolidly tenuta sopra ai 
valori tradizionali di lavoro e di successo, "il bum" era sospetto, 
potenzialmente un con artist.In una risposta molto differente, il DOS 
Passos del John del romanziere reso al vagrant un simbolo della 
promessa fatta deragliare del sogno americano in questo vignette 
"Vag," che ha concluso i suoi S.U.A. monumental. trilogy.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η επαιτεία ήταν ένα από τα ενοχλώντας σημάδια της 
μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης της δεκαετίας του '30. Κατόπιν, 
όπως τώρα, εκείνοι που είχαν τα τρόφιμα και τη στέγη ήρθαν 
αντιμέτωποι από τη θέα και τις εκκλήσεις εκείνοι που όχι. 
Οι shabby άνδρες αναζήτησαν τα τρόφιμα ή εργασία για τα 
κατώφλια των ιδιωτικών σπιτιών ενώ οι άνδρες, οι γυναίκες, και 
τα παιδιά στάθηκαν στα breadlines των δημοτικών αντιπροσωπειών 
ανακούφισης. Το Vagrants σύλλεξε στις "ζούγκλες hobo" 
στα περίχωρα της πόλης όπως οι επαίτες στις οδούς απευθύνθηκαν 
στους πιό ακμάζοντες περαστικούς. Οι παρατηρητές μεσαίας 
τάξης εμφάνισαν vagrants με την υποψία, το ενσυναίσθημα, την 
ανησυχία, το φόβο, και μερικές φορές ακόμη και έναν πόνο του 
φθόνου. Για κάποια stolidly διατήρηση τις παραδοσιακές 
αξίες της εργασίας και της επιτυχίας, ο "άχρηστοσ" ήταν ύποπτος,
ενδεχομένως ένας καλλιτέχνης con Σε μια πολύ διαφορετική
απάντηση, ο μυθιστοριογράφος John Dos Passos έκανε το 
vagrant ένα σύμβολο της εκτροχιασμένης υπόσχεσης του 
αμερικανικού ονείρου σε αυτό το σύντομο χρονογράφημα "VAG," 
που τελείωσε μνημειακό U.S.A του. τριλογία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La vagancia era una de preocupar muestras de la gran 
depresión de los años 30. Entonces, como ahora, las súplicas 
de los enfrentaron los que tenían el alimento y abrigo la vista y que
no lo hicieron. Alimento o trabajo buscado hombres lamentables 
sobre los umbrales de hogares privados mientras que los hombres, las 
mujeres, y los niños estaban parados en los breadlines de las 
agencias municipales de la relevación. Los vagabundos 
recolectaron en "selvas del hobo" en las cercanías de la ciudad 
mientras que los mendigos en las calles abrogaron a traseúntes más 
prósperos. Los observadores de la clase media vieron a 
vagabundos con la suspicacia, empathy, la preocupación, miedo, e 
igualan a veces una punzada de la envidia. Para cierto stolidly 
aferrarse a los valores tradicionales del trabajo y del éxito, el 
"vago" era sospechado, potencialmente un con artist.In una 
respuesta muy diversa, DOS Passos de Juan del novelista hecho el 
vagabundo un símbolo de la promesa hecha descarrilar del sueño 
americano en este vignette "Vag," que terminó los sus E.E.U.U. 
monumentales. trilogía.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087069</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104488</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-vagrant-in-fiction-emblematic-american</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
