<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086696</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">One Year in the Life of Thomas Minor, Connecticut Farmer, 1668.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Jahr im Leben des Thomas Untersatzes, 
Connecticut Landwirt, 1668.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un an dans la vie du mineur de Thomas, fermier du 
Connecticut, 1668.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um ano na vida do menor de Thomas, fazendeiro de 
Connecticut, 1668.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un anno nella vita del minore del Thomas, 
coltivatore del Connecticut, 1668.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα έτος στη ζωή του Thomas Minor, αγρότης του 
Κοννέκτικατ, 1668.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un año en la vida del menor de edad de Thomas, 
granjero de Connecticut, 1668.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Thomas Minor was born in England and came to New England in 1630. By 1668, when this selection from his journal was written, Minor, his wife Grace, and their children were living in what is now Stonington, a town on the Connecticut coast. Indians lived nearby, and the journal shows Minor and his family interacting with them. Minor was a farmer, and he also had a number of public responsibilities. These included town treasurer, leader of the militia, selectman, and brander of horses. He also participated in church and in town meetings. This selection records one year in Minor's life. He began the year in March, as people in England and New England did until the mid-eighteenth century. While his spelling is idiosyncratic and therefore difficult to read, the journal is a valuable record of how written English looked at that time--and probably also of how Minor pronounced his words.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Thomas Untersatz war in England geboren und kam nach 
Neu-England 1630. Bis zum 1668 als diese Auswahl von seinem 
Journal geschrieben wurden, lebten Untersatz, seine Frau Anmut und 
ihre Kinder in was jetzt Stonington ist, eine Stadt auf der 
Connecticut Küste. Inder lebten in der Nähe und das Journal 
zeigt den Untersatz und seine Familie, die auf sie einwirken. 
Untersatz war ein Landwirt und er hatte auch eine Anzahl von 
allgemeinen Verantwortlichkeiten. Diese schlossen 
Stadtschatzmeister, Führer der Miliz, Selectman und brander der 
Pferde ein. Er nahm auch an der Kirche und an den Stadtsitzungen
teil. Diese Auswahl speichert ein Jahr im Leben des Untersatzes.
Er fing das Jahr im März an, wie Leute in England und in 
Neu-England bis das mittler-achtzehnte Jahrhundert. Während 
seine Rechtschreibung und folglich schwierig zu lesen idiosynkratisch 
ist, ist das Journal ein wertvoller Satz von, wie schriftliches 
Englisch zu dieser Zeit schaute -- und vermutlich auch von, wie gering
seine Wörter aussprach.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mineur de Thomas est né en Angleterre et est venu en 
Nouvelle Angleterre en 1630. À côté de 1668, quand cette 
sélection à partir de son journal ont été écrits, le mineur, son 
grace d'épouse, et leurs enfants vivaient dans ce qui est maintenant 
Stonington, une ville sur la côte du Connecticut. Les Indiens 
ont vécu tout près, et le journal montre le mineur et sa famille 
agissant l'un sur l'autre avec eux. Le mineur était un fermier,
et il a également eu un certain nombre de responsabilités publiques.
Celles-ci ont inclus le trésorier de ville, l'amorce de la 
milice, le selectman, et le brander des chevaux. Il a également
participé dans l'église et aux réunions de ville. Cette 
sélection enregistre un an dans la vie du mineur. Il a 
commencé l'année en mars, comme le faisaient les gens en Angleterre 
et en Nouvelle Angleterre jusqu'au mi-dix-huitième siècle. 
Tandis que son épellation est idiosyncratique et donc difficile
à lire, le journal est un enregistrement valable de à quel point 
l'anglais écrit a regardé à ce moment-là -- et probablement aussi 
de la façon dont mineur a prononcé ses mots.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O menor de Thomas foi carregado em Inglaterra e veio a 
Nova Inglaterra em 1630. Por 1668, quando esta seleção de seu 
jornal foram escritos, o menor, seu grace da esposa, e suas crianças 
estava vivendo em o que é agora Stonington, uma cidade na costa de 
Connecticut. Os indians viveram próximo, e o jornal mostra o 
menor e a sua família que interagem com eles. O menor era um 
fazendeiro, e teve também um número de responsabilidades públicas. 
Estes incluíram o treasurer da cidade, o líder da milícia, o 
selectman, e o brander dos cavalos. Participou também na igreja
e em reuniões da cidade. Esta seleção grava um ano na vida do
menor. Começou o ano em março, como os povos em Inglaterra e 
em Nova Inglaterra  até o mid-décimo oitavo século. Quando 
sua soletração for idiosyncratic e conseqüentemente difícil de 
ler, o jornal é um registro valioso de como o inglês escrito olhou 
essa época -- e provavelmente também de como menor pronunciou suas 
palavras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il minore del Thomas è stato sopportato in Inghilterra ed
è venuto in Nuova Inghilterra in 1630. Entro 1668, quando 
questa selezione dal suo giornale sono stati scritti, il minore, la 
sua tolleranza della moglie ed i loro bambini stava vivendo in che 
cosa ora è Stonington, una città sul litorale del Connecticut. 
Gli indiani hanno vissuto qui vicino ed il giornale mostra il 
minore e la sua famiglia che si interagiscono con loro. Il 
minore era un coltivatore ed egualmente ha avuto un certo numero di 
responsabilità pubbliche. Questi hanno incluso il tesoriere 
della città, il capo della milizia, il selectman ed il brander
dei cavalli. Egualmente ha partecipato a chiesa ed alle riunioni
della città. Questa selezione registra un anno nella vita del 
minore. Ha cominciato l'anno in marzo, come la gente in 
Inghilterra ed in Nuova Inghilterra fino al metà di-diciottesimo 
secolo. Mentre la sua ortografia è idiosyncratic e quindi 
difficile leggere, il giornale è un record importante di come 
l'inglese scritto ha guardato quel periodo -- e probabilmente anche di
quanto secondario ha pronunciato le sue parole.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Thomas Minor γεννήθηκε στην Αγγλία και ήρθε στη
Νέα Αγγλία το 1630. Από 1668, όταν γράφτηκε αυτή η 
επιλογή από το περιοδικό του, ο ανήλικος, η επιείκεια συζύγων 
του, και τα παιδιά τους ζούσαν σε αυτό που είναι τώρα 
Stonington, μια πόλη στην ακτή του Κοννέκτικατ. Ινδοί 
έζησαν εδώ κοντά, και το περιοδικό εμφανίζει τον ανήλικο και 
οικογένειά του που αλληλεπιδρούν με τους. Ο ανήλικος ήταν 
αγρότης, και είχε επίσης διάφορες δημόσιες ευθύνες. Αυτοί
περιέλαβαν τον πόλης ταμία, ηγέτης της πολιτοφυλακής, 
selectman, και brander των αλόγων. Συμμετείχε επίσης 
στην εκκλησία και στις πόλης συνεδριάσεις. Αυτή η επιλογή 
καταγράφει ένα έτος στη ζωή του ανηλίκου. Αρχισε το έτος 
το Μάρτιο, δεδομένου ότι οι άνθρωποι στην Αγγλία και τη Νέα 
Αγγλία έκαναν μέχρι το μέσος-δέκατο όγδοο αιώνα. Ενώ η 
ορθογραφία του είναι ιδιοσυγκρασιακή και επομένως δύσκολος να 
διαβάσει, το περιοδικό είναι ένα πολύτιμο αρχείο για το πώς τα 
γραπτά αγγλικά κοίταξαν εκείνη την περίοδο -- και πιθανώς 
επίσης για το πώς ο ανήλικος πρόφερε τις λέξεις του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El menor de edad de Thomas nació en Inglaterra y vino a 
Nueva Inglaterra en 1630. Antes de 1668, cuando esta selección 
de su diario fueron escritos, el menor de edad, su tolerancia de la 
esposa, y sus niños vivía en cuál ahora es Stonington, una ciudad 
en la costa de Connecticut. Los indios vivieron cerca, y el 
diario muestra al menor de edad y a su familia que obran 
recíprocamente con ellos. El menor de edad era granjero, y él 
también tenía un número de responsabilidades públicas. 
Éstos incluyeron el tesorero de la ciudad, el arranque de cinta
de la milicia, el selectman, y el brander de caballos. Él 
también participó en iglesia y en reuniones de la ciudad. Esta
selección registra un año en la vida del menor de edad. Él 
comenzó el año en marcha, como la gente en Inglaterra y Nueva 
Inglaterra lo hizo hasta el mediados de-de'cimo octavo siglo. 
Mientras que su deletreo es idiosincrásico y por lo tanto 
difícil de leer, el diario es un expediente valioso de cómo el 
inglés escrito miraba -- y probablemente también de cómo es de 
menor importancia pronunció sus palabras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086696</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104693</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/one-year-in-the-life-of-thomas-minor-connecticut-farmer-1668</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
