<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108021</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108021</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202787</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Homerun Hoopla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Homerun Hoopla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Homerun Hoopla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Homerun Hoopla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Homerun Hoopla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Homerun Hoopla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Homerun Hoopla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This lesson is designed for students to gather and analyze data about baseball figures. The student will use the Internet or other resources to collect statistical data on the top five home run hitters for the current season as well as their career home run totals. The students will graph the data and determine if it is linear or non-linear.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Lektion ist konzipiert, damit Kursteilnehmer
Daten über Baseballabbildungen erfassen und analysieren. Der 
Kursteilnehmer benutzt das Internet oder andere Betriebsmittel, um 
statistische Daten bezüglich der oberen fünf Hauptdurchlauf hitters 
während der aktuellen Jahreszeit, sowie zu sammeln ihr Karrierehaus 
Gesamtmengen laufen lassen. Die Kursteilnehmer stellen die Daten
graphisch dar und stellen fest, wenn es linear oder nicht linear ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon est conçue pour que des étudiants 
recueillent et pour analysent des données au sujet des chiffres de 
base-ball. L'étudiant emploiera l'Internet ou d'autres 
ressources pour rassembler des données statistiques sur les cinq 
cogneurs à la maison principaux de passage pour la saison actuelle
comme leur maison de carrière exécutent des totaux. Les 
étudiants représenteront graphiquement les données et 
détermineront si elle est linéaire ou non linéaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição é projetada para que os estudantes 
recolham e analisem dados sobre figuras do baseball. O estudante
usará o Internet ou outros recursos coletar dados estatísticos nos 
cinco hitters home superiores do funcionamento para a estação atual 
assim como sua HOME da carreira funciona totais. Os estudantes 
representarão graficamente os dados e determinarão se for linear ou 
non-linear.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione è destinata affinchè gli allievi 
riunisca e per analizzare i dati circa le figure di baseball. 
L'allievo userà il Internet o altre risorse per raccogliere i 
dati statistici sui cinque hitters domestici principali di 
funzionamento per la stagione corrente come pure la loro sede di 
carriera fa funzionare i totali. Gli allievi rappresenteranno 
graficamente i dati e determineranno se è lineare o non lineare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μάθημα σχεδιάζεται για τους σπουδαστές για να 
συγκεντρώσει και να αναλύσει τα στοιχεία για τους αριθμούς 
μπέιζ-μπώλ. Ο σπουδαστής θα χρησιμοποιήσει το Διαδίκτυο ή 
άλλα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς για να συλλέξουν τα στατιστικά 
στοιχεία όσον αφορά το κορυφαίο σπίτι πέντε τρέχουν τα 
hitters για την παρούσα εποχή καθώς επίσης και το σπίτι 
σταδιοδρομίας τους τρέχει τα σύνολα. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
δώσουν με γραφική παράσταση τα στοιχεία και θα καθορίσουν εάν 
είναι γραμμικά ή μη γραμμικά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección se diseña para que a los 
estudiantes recopilen y analicen datos sobre figuras del béisbol. 
El estudiante utilizará el Internet u otros recursos para 
recoger datos estadísticos sobre los cinco hitters caseros superiores
del funcionamiento para la estación actual tan bien como su hogar de 
la carrera ejecuta totales. Los estudiantes representarán los 
datos gra'ficamente y se determinarán si es linear o no linear.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ANNE WALTERS
FN:ANNE WALTERS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202787</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108021</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/homerun-hoopla</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
