<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106274</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106274</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212675</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Olympic Region Harmful Algal Blooms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Olympische Region-Schädliche Algenblüte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Fleurs D'algues Nocives de Région Olympique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As Flores Algal Prejudiciais Da Região Olympic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le Fioriture D'alghe Nocive Di Regione Olimpica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ολυμπιακές επιβλαβείς φυκώδεις ανθίσεις περιοχών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las Floraciones Algal Dañosas De la Región 
Olímpica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is the website of the Olympic Region Harmful Algal Bloom (ORHAB) partnership, which was organized to develop collaboration and cooperation among federal, state and local management agencies, coastal Indian tribes, marine resource-based businesses, public interest groups, and academic institutions. The ORHAB partnership investigates the origins of blooms of toxic algae, monitors where and when the blooms occur, assesses the environmental conditions conducive to blooms and toxification of intertidal shellfish populations, and explores methods that can be used to reduce HAB impacts on humans and the environment. Information in this website is organized into the following categories: Home, About ORHAB, HAB impacts, project plan, partnerships, benefits, meetings, gallery, sustaining ORHAB, education, and outreach.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist die Web site der olympische 
Region-schädlichen Algenblüte (ORHAB) Teilhaberschaft, die 
organisiert wurde, um Zusammenarbeit und Mitarbeit unter Bundes zu 
entwickeln, Zustand und lokale Managementagenturen, indische 
Küstenstämme, Marinehilfsmittel gründeten Geschäfte, allgemeine 
Interesse Gruppen und akademische Anstalten. Die ORHAB 
Teilhaberschaft die Ursprung der Blüte der giftigen Algen, Monitoren 
in denen nachforscht und wenn die Blüte auftritt, die 
Klimabedingungen festsetzt, die zur Blüte und zum toxification der 
intertidalen Schalentierbevölkerungen förderlich sind und Methoden 
erforscht, die verwendet werden können, um HAB Auswirkungen auf 
Menschen und die Umgebung zu verringern. Informationen in dieser
Web site werden in die folgenden Kategorien organisiert: Haupt, 
über ORHAB, übertreffen HAB Auswirkungen, Projektplan, 
Teilhaberschaften, Nutzen, Sitzungen, Galerie, unterstützendes ORHAB,
Ausbildung und.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est le site Web de l'association d'algues nocive
de la fleur de région olympique (ORHAB), qui a été organisée pour 
développer la collaboration et la coopération de fédéral, état et
les agences locales de gestion, tribus indiennes côtières, ressource
marine ont basé des entreprises, des groupes d'intérêt publics, et 
des établissements d'universitaire. L'association d'ORHAB étudie
les origines des fleurs des algues toxiques, moniteurs où et quand 
les fleurs se produisent, évalue les conditions environnementales 
favorisant des fleurs et le toxification des populations intertidales 
de mollusques et crustacés, et explore les méthodes qui peuvent 
être employées pour réduire des impacts de HAB sur les humains et 
l'environnement. L'information dans ce site Web est organisée 
en catégories suivantes : À la maison, au sujet d'ORHAB, les 
impacts de HAB, plan de projet, associations, avantages, réunions, la
galerie, ORHAB soutenant, éducation, et dépassent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é o Web site da parceria algal prejudicial 
da flor da região olympic (ORHAB), que foi organizada para 
desenvolver a colaboração e a cooperação entre federal, estado e 
as agências locais da gerência, tribes indian litorais, recurso 
marinho basearam negócios, grupos de interesse públicos, e 
instituições academic. A parceria de ORHAB investiga as 
origens das flores das algas tóxicas, monitores onde e quando as 
flores ocorrerem, avalia as circunstâncias ambientais conducive às 
flores e ao toxification de populações intertidal do marisco, e 
explora os métodos que podem ser usados reduzir impactos de HAB em 
seres humanos e no ambiente. A informação neste Web site é 
organizada nas seguintes categorias: Home, sobre ORHAB, os 
impactos de HAB, planta do projeto, parcerias, benefícios, reuniões,
galeria, ORHAB sustentando, instrução, e excedem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è il Web site della regione che olimpica 
l'associazione d'alghe nociva della fioritura (ORHAB), che è stata 
organizzata per sviluppare la collaborazione e la cooperazione fra 
federale, dichiara ed agenzie locali della gestione, delle 
tribù indiane litoranee, dei commerci basati risorsa marina, dei 
gruppi di interesse comune pubblici e delle istituzioni accademiche. 
L'associazione di ORHAB studia le origini delle fioriture delle 
alghe tossiche, video in cui e quando le fioriture accadono, valuta le
condizioni ambientali tendenti alle fioriture ed al toxification delle
popolazioni intercotidali dei crostacei ed esplora i metodi che 
possono essere usati per ridurre gli effetti di HAB sugli esseri umani
e sull'ambiente. Le informazioni in questo Web site sono 
organizzate nelle seguenti categorie: Domestici, circa ORHAB, 
gli effetti di HAB, il programma di progetto, le associazioni, i 
benefici, le riunioni, la galleria, ORHAB sostenente, formazione e 
superano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι ο ιστοχώρος της ολυμπιακής συνεργασίας 
άνθισης περιοχών επιβλαβούς φυκώδους (ORHAB), η οποία 
οργανώθηκε για να αναπτύξει τη συνεργασία και τη συνεργασία 
μεταξύ ομοσπονδιακού, του κράτους και των τοπικών διοικητικών 
αντιπροσωπειών, των παράκτιων ινδικών φυλών, των θαλασσίων 
resource-based επιχειρήσεων, των δημόσιων ομάδων ενδιαφέροντος,
και των ακαδημαϊκών οργάνων. Η συνεργασία ORHAB 
ερευνά την προέλευση των ανθίσεων των τοξικών αλγών, ελέγχει 
όπου και πότε οι ανθίσεις εμφανίζονται, αξιολογεί τις 
περιβαλλοντικές συνθήκες συμβάλλουσες στις ανθίσεις και το 
toxification των διπαλιρροιακών πληθυσμών οστρακόδερμων, και 
ερευνά τις μεθόδους που μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για να 
μειώσουν τις επιδράσεις HAB στους ανθρώπους και το περιβάλλον. 
Οι πληροφορίες σε αυτόν τον ιστοχώρο οργανώνονται στις 
ακόλουθες κατηγορίες: Η "Οικία", για ORHAB, HAB 
επηρεάζει, σχέδιο προγράμματος, συνεργασίες, οφέλη, 
συνεδριάσεις, στοά, στήριξη ORHAB, εκπαίδευση, και ξεπερνά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Éste es el Web site de la sociedad algal dañosa 
de la floración de la región olímpica (ORHAB), que fue ordenada 
para desarrollar la colaboración y la cooperación entre federal, 
estado y las agencias locales de la gerencia, tribus indias costeras, 
recurso marina basaron a negocios, a grupos de interés públicos, y a
instituciones académicas. La sociedad de ORHAB investiga los 
orígenes de las floraciones de las algas tóxicas, monitores donde y 
cuando ocurren las floraciones, evalúa las condiciones ambientales 
conducentes a las floraciones y al toxification de las poblaciones 
intertidal de los crustáceos, y explora los métodos que se pueden 
utilizar para reducir impactos de HAB en los seres humanos y el 
ambiente. La información en este Web site se ordena en las 
categorías siguientes: Caseros, sobre ORHAB, los impactos de 
HAB, plan del proyecto, sociedades, ventajas, reuniones, galería, 
ORHAB que sostiene, educación, y exceden.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:OLYMPIC REGION HARMFUL ALGAL BLOOM (ORHAB) PARTNERSHIP
FN:OLYMPIC REGION HARMFUL ALGAL BLOOM (ORHAB) PARTNERSHIP
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212675</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106274</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-olympic-region-harmful-algal-blooms</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
